
   
   
      
         
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 15</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Aug. 15, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            The
cover editorial on terrorism says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">radicals</ENAMEX>
hate the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> because of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">America's</ENAMEX> peacekeeping efforts in the region.
Compared to other Western <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> is extremely hard on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>, which draws the ire of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX>. A related piece forecasts scary "new terrorism," including
biological or poison <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas</ENAMEX> attacks within the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and "cyber-attacks"
that could crash the world's financial and communications systems ... A
piece laments the "woes" of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madeleine Albright</ENAMEX>, whose opinions on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>,
and even her pet eastern <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> are ignored by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>, and
other policymakers. She seems to have "less leverage at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> than
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyists</ENAMEX>."

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 31</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 14, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
package is split between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> bimbroglio and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX> bombings: On both
scores <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is stressed. On the home front, a piece suggests new evasion
tactics for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, including the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger</ENAMEX> Defense"--it's my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX>. On
the bombing front, an article says that since it's tough to guard against
terrorist attacks, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> should muscle up for a crackdown afterward.
Another piece retraces <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s perilous journey in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> to track down <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saudi</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">multimillionaire Osama Bin Laden</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suspect</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX> bombings.
(
                  Slate
               's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Explainer</ENAMEX>"
also scopes out <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bin Laden</ENAMEX>.) ... Like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Magazine</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNR</ENAMEX> also recaps <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '60s</TIMEX> trajectory from "heady liberal optimism" to
black power and anti-war frenzy. End result? <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> graduated from a "culture
of toil, sacrifice, saving, and abstinence" to a "culture of consumption,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">lifestyle</ENAMEX>, and quality of life."

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times Magazine</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 16</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 14, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
package gushes over the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WNBA</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Sport You Can Love</ENAMEX>." <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> piece follows a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Liberty</ENAMEX> road trip, admiring the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX>'s genuine camaraderie, warmth, and
sheer joy, and calling each game "a celebration of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> power." Another admires
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s basketball for discouraging "ladylike behavior" and promoting "raucous
... uninhibited female intensity." ... An essay warns that the rise in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">intermarriage</ENAMEX> is excluding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX>. Instead of melting into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> brown <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> may remain <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> beige (white-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX>) and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> black.
... An article wonders why <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> are still fighting the battles of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1968</TIMEX> while <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Europeans</ENAMEX>, for whom those battles were much more intense (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Prague</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">spring</TIMEX>), have moved on. Conclusion: <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Europeans</ENAMEX> separate
democracy and culture and so did not let the political fights of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">'68</NUMEX> spill into
a cultural war. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>, who don't separate the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>, have transmitted the
tensions of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">'68</NUMEX> to issues of education, religion, race, and sexuality.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 17</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 11, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's cover
story focuses on the gay "conversion" controversy. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Exodus International</ENAMEX>, among
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sponsors</ENAMEX> of the recent round of gay conversion ads, claims it converts <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX>
percent of its gay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> to heterosexuality. But, as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">notes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Exodus</ENAMEX>' own ex-gay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founders</ENAMEX> fell in love, left their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wives</ENAMEX> for each
other, and quit. A related piece, based on polls, says that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> back gay
rights in theory but dislike public displays of gay affection. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of
the gay magazine Out urges <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gays</ENAMEX> to mingle more with straights and not
wall themselves in the "gay ghetto."

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's cover story drools over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Glenn</ENAMEX>, calling his upcoming
Discovery mission "a timely reminder that we can still have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroes</ENAMEX>." Why is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASA</ENAMEX> letting the old <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bird</ENAMEX> lift off? Space travel mimics the effects of aging
(bone weakening, sleep disruption, etc.), and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASA</ENAMEX> wants to know if a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">77-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">astronaut</ENAMEX> will suffer the same disabilities.

            Both
magazines squeeze in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last-minute</TIMEX> pieces on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">African</ENAMEX> bombings but save plenty
of space for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's angle: How does the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> legal team
prep a probable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liar</ENAMEX> against a known <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liar</ENAMEX>? Answer: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Smear Monica</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's scoop: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>'s report to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> will be pared down
to cover only <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kiss</ENAMEX> goodbye to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> of work on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitewater</ENAMEX>,
Travelgate, etc. ... <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>'s blander package has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> revelation: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tripp</ENAMEX> kept <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">80</NUMEX>-100
pages of contemporaneous notes about what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX> said, a "skeleton key" for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> to "reconstruct" the affair.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News & World Report</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 17</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 11, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            A huge
package celebrates great inventors of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 th century</TIMEX>, from
household names such as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wright</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Edward Teller</ENAMEX> to obscurities
such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Philo Farnsworth</ENAMEX>, who invented the television at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 22</TIMEX> only to
have RCA copy him, bully him, and reap the economic rewards. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inventor</ENAMEX> is
dissed: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander Fleming</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientist</ENAMEX> of "mundane skills,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">accidentally</ENAMEX> discovered penicillin, but it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ernst Chain</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard Florey</ENAMEX>
who actually made penicillin a lifesaving <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fleming</ENAMEX> happily took the
credit. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX> predicts that living machines will be the great invention of the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21 st century</TIMEX>. ... The cover
package on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">embassy</ENAMEX> bombings suggests that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-American Saudi</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">millionaire Osama Bin Ladin</ENAMEX> could have funded the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bombers</ENAMEX>. It also notes the
rise of "cushion-shot terrorism": <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Terrorists</ENAMEX> increasingly attack peripheral
targets, because major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">targets</ENAMEX> are too well protected.

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 17</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 11, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            A piece
argues that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> have grossly overstated the importance of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> in
molding their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. In fact, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are shaped mostly by other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>,
who serve as role <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">models</ENAMEX> and guides for living. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Children</ENAMEX> tend to resemble
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> only because they share genes, not because they are influenced by them.
Evidence: Adopted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> have as much in common with random <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> as with
their adoptive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>. ... An article warns that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s stock market
conditions dangerously resemble those of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1929</TIMEX>. Inflation is low, growth is
slowing, the world economy is uncertain, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> are ignoring repeated
warnings by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Greenspan</ENAMEX> must stop merely warning and start
acting, raising interest rates enough to stop the market euphoria. A recession
is inevitable, and we need <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> intervention to ensure it's a mild <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>.

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nation</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 24 and 31</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 11, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            The
cover story weighs the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">prospect</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Jackson</ENAMEX> presidential candidacy. The Reverend is second to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> in opinion polls, drawing <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">12 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> support,
and he may be the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> who could bring attention to progressive/labor
issues. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Snags: 1</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX> is increasingly friendly with Wall Streeters, an
alliance that troubles many lefties; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) he will certainly lose; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) he may
lack the selflessness required to build an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> that would endure after
his loss. Why would he run? Because he is desperate to remain important.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kate</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Galbraith</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
