
   
   
      
         
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 5</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Sept. 5, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            The
cover editorial reassures <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> that a global depression
is highly unlikely as long as the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> economy stays strong. Since the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> can still lower interest rates or cut taxes to prevent a slump,
there is little to worry about. The essay takes pains to note that current woes
are not the fault of the free market system and that protectionism and
regulation are not the answers. ... An article describes the modernization of the perfume and air
freshener industries. While <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> once mined scents from natural sources
such as "the anuses of a mongoose-like <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animal</ENAMEX> called a civet," they now
use computers and chemical synthesis to create new scents: After sampling odors
and digitizing their chemical makeup, scent-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">creators</ENAMEX> change various elements to
derive a new smell. ... The obituary mourns the death, at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">84</NUMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Otto</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wichterle</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inventor</ENAMEX> of the soft contact lens. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Czech</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wichterle</ENAMEX>, at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time
a political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoner</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazis</ENAMEX>, discovered a polymer that lets the lens
remain moist while in contact with the eye. His technique, invented in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1961</TIMEX>,
was bought by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bausch</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lomb</ENAMEX>. Although <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> use soft contact
lenses <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wichterle</ENAMEX> wore glasses his whole life.

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times Magazine</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 6</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, Sept. 3, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
story criticizes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>'s unwavering pursuit of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s
pedantic, religious, exacting personality led him to drag out a case that other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> would have ended quickly. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> tidbits: He's not brilliant but is
the hardest-working <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> in the legal system, he wanted desperately to be a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice</ENAMEX>, and his "tin ear" for politics has hurt him in previous
cases. ... A story defends <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joyce Maynard</ENAMEX>, whose forthcoming memoir
describes her affair with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J.D. Salinger</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maynard</ENAMEX> may be self-obsessed, but what
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> isn't? If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salinger</ENAMEX> had written about her, "who would shed a tear for the
violated privacy of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joyce Maynard</ENAMEX>, purveyor of minor novels and contributor to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX>?" (For more on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maynard</ENAMEX> and her memoir, see "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Book Club</ENAMEX>" in

                  Slate
               .) ... An essay argues that treatment is our best bet
in the drug war. Treatment is cheaper and far more effective than interdiction,
but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> won't spend money on it for fear of looking soft on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>. (See
this 
                  Slate
                "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dialogue</ENAMEX>" for
more on the subject.)

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 7</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Sept. 1, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> cover
package focuses on the role of incoming <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Viktor Chernomyrdin</ENAMEX>,
portraying him as sympathetic to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist</ENAMEX> interests. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Minor</ENAMEX> problem: After
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> went to press, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communists</ENAMEX>, who control <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parliament</ENAMEX>, blocked
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chernomyrdin</ENAMEX>'s confirmation. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russia 1</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Old Media</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0</NUMEX>.) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russia</ENAMEX>
coverage includes sketches of the new <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> plus a profile
of shady <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">oligarch</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Berezovsky</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's cover
piece examines a new book claiming that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> have a scant role in shaping
their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. In fact, it's genetics and your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peers</ENAMEX> that make you who you
are: How your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> raise you matters little. ( The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> wrote
about this topic <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month ago</TIMEX>.) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> buys the argument in part but
maintains that good parenting is still important.

            A
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> essay titled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"So Much for Globalization</ENAMEX>" argues that the
failure of democracy and free markets in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> will mark the end of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">world</ENAMEX>'s faith in globalization. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Eight</NUMEX> pages <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later</TIMEX>, a tribute to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Princess</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>
emphasizes her embodiment of, yes, globalization: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Globalization</ENAMEX> has
become <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the decade</TIMEX>'s most overused word, but at its heart, it embodies a real
truth: technology has made this a planet of shared experiences."

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 7</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Sept. 1, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            A piece
describes the breakdown of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s "communications machine."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisers</ENAMEX>, who used to protect him by spinning and covering up his
wrongdoing, have turned skeptical. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> is suddenly alone. ...
A profile of thriller <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novelist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen King</ENAMEX> finds him surprisingly ordinary: a
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">salt</ENAMEX> of the earth <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who cooks his own dinners, plays tennis with his son,
marvels at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> cards, and harbors a passion for books. (The piece is pegged to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bag of Bones</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> novel under his new,
extremely lucrative contract with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scribner</ENAMEX>.)

            

               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 7</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Sept. 1, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
story on the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">30 th</NUMEX> anniversary of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1968</TIMEX> reprises the standard
Standard line that the anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">establishment kids</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '60s</TIMEX> have grown up
to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hypocrites</ENAMEX>. The anti-draft <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protestors</ENAMEX> who trumpeted "Power to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX>"
were college-educated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elitists</ENAMEX> themselves, and these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebels</ENAMEX> of yesteryear now
embrace the system as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>. ... Also on the theme of lefty
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hypocrisy</ENAMEX>, a piece derides the "steep decline of liberal moralism." How is it,
the piece asks, that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> who relentlessly vilified <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> have suddenly
decided that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s lying is irrelevant?

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 14 & 21</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Aug. 29, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            A story
says <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> are wrong to fear that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> resignation will lead to
disastrous midterm election results. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> lost many <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">seats</ENAMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>'s
resignation because of a struggling economy, not because of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX>. It's too
late for strong <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> to emerge <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voter turnout</ENAMEX> won't be
depressed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s departure. Thus, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> should go. ... The
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">TRB"</ENAMEX> column scolds <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> for claiming <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is no
longer effective: "Since when do we kick <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidents</ENAMEX> out of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> because they
are no longer effective?... <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Truman</ENAMEX> was a laughingstock in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1948</TIMEX>, but he stayed in office. ... Perhaps no <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">duck</ENAMEX> was lamer than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Iran-Contra</ENAMEX>, yet resignation was never a serious issue."

            More Flytrap
...

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stevenson</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
