
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Television
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wendy</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Story of Painting</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sundays</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 p.m. EDT/PDT</TIMEX>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> swoon over the eccentric <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">67-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Carmelite</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nun</ENAMEX>'s survey of Western
painting. "Nothing this good in the genre has come out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kenneth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Civilisation</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a quarter-century ago</TIMEX>," says the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Wilson</ENAMEX>. The self-taught <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sister</ENAMEX> is said to be charmingly
enthusiastic, and to "awaken an appreciation for a sweeping spectrum of art ...
for the average schmo" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Megan Rosenfeld</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Reviewers</ENAMEX>
predict the ratings for her series will surpass <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Hughes</ENAMEX>' similar
show <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last spring</TIMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> plugs the program.)

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ally McBeal</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Mondays</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 p.m. EDT/PDT</TIMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ambivalent</ENAMEX> reviews
for a drama about an insecure twentysomething female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> say it
"respects the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>'s intelligence" with well-drawn <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> and a
"healthy cynicism" about lawyering (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caryn James</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ).
But it also uses unfunny gimmicks, particularly a running gag of dramatizing,
on-screen, the protagonist's fantasies. (See <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX>'s site for the
show.)

            

               Movies
            

            

               
                  She's So Lovely
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miramax Films</ENAMEX>). A movie by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nick</ENAMEX>
Cassavetes, from a screenplay by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Cassavetes</ENAMEX>, who died in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>.
The film is deemed a gesture more of sentiment than of artistry. Critics
discern little logic in the story, in which <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Travolta</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sean</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Penn</ENAMEX>) duel over an alcoholic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin Wright Penn</ENAMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>' motives
are also damned as obscure. "[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Y</ENAMEX>]<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">ou</ENAMEX> might wonder whether <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15 or 20</NUMEX> pages of
[script] ... hadn't fallen out," says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mathews</ENAMEX>. But a handful of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> admire <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Penn's</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Travolta</ENAMEX>'s "big, headstrong
performances," and proclaim the film "a huge-hearted emotional fairy tale"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Maslin</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ). (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edelstein</ENAMEX>'s review in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>, and here for the
official site.)

            

               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cineplex Film Properties</ENAMEX>). Another <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Sundance Grand Jury</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Prize</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX>--this one by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rookie director</ENAMEX> and part-time <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sommelier</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nossiter</ENAMEX>--generates critical excitement. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nossiter</ENAMEX>'s script about an affair
between a homeless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Suchet</ENAMEX>) and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lisa Harrow</ENAMEX>) who mistakes
him for a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">filmmaker</ENAMEX> is called "elegant" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daphne Merkin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yorker</ENAMEX> ), and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Suchet</ENAMEX> is said to give "a virtuoso turn" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Anderson</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dissenting</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holden</ENAMEX> calls the film a formulaic, "overly schematic exercise in cinematic
hide-and-seek."

            

               Books
            

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farewell Symphony</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edmund White</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Knopf</ENAMEX>). As with the earlier
installments of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>'s semiautobiographical trilogy ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Boy's Own Story</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Beautiful Room Is Empty</ENAMEX> ), <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> dwell on the graphic gay sex
scenes and on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>'s promiscuity (he estimates having had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,000</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partners</ENAMEX>). It "might have been more honestly called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hilly Buttocks I Have</ENAMEX>
Known ," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Wolcott</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> . Those who
don't dismiss it as salacious gossip laud its revelations about gay <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>, especially the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Merrill</ENAMEX>, and its depiction of the ravages of
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX>. "[A] powerful critique of the lifestyle [he] once eulogized," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bawer</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post Book World</ENAMEX> .

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Black</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">One Nation</ENAMEX>, Indivisible
               , by Stephan
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abigail Thernstrom</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simon & Schuster</ENAMEX>). A mammoth new tract on race by a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Manhattan Institute</ENAMEX> pundit. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Foes</ENAMEX> of
affirmative action extol the book--part history, part policy analysis--as a
devastating blow to race-based programs. "[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX>]he most far-ranging,
information-rich analysis of our seismic racial shifts since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gunnar Myrdal</ENAMEX>'s
An <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Dilemma of 1944</ENAMEX>," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Sleeper</ENAMEX> in the Wall Street
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> . In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Book Review</ENAMEX> , however, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicholas Lemann</ENAMEX>
says, "To assume the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Myrdal</ENAMEX> mantle means speaking in a calm, clear, generous
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">voice</ENAMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Black</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">White</ENAMEX> does this only intermittently. ...
[The book is] <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pugnacious</ENAMEX> and angry to the point of occasional bitterness and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sarcasm</ENAMEX>."

            
               Recent
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment</ENAMEX>" columns
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">27:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">G.I.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane</ENAMEX> ;

            

               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Mimic</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Already Dead:</ENAMEX>
A <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Gothic</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Denis Johnson</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">One Best</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Way</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frederick Winslow Taylor</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Enigma of Efficiency</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kanigel</ENAMEX>;

            
               Music -- The
Dance , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fleetwood Mac</ENAMEX>;

            

               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Good News</ENAMEX> (UPN).

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">20:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cop</ENAMEX>
Land ;

            
               Movie -- The Full
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monty</ENAMEX> ;

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Music -- Be Here</ENAMEX>
Now , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oasis</ENAMEX>;

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> -- <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1776</TIMEX> ;

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> -- On the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Town</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wallace</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNT</ENAMEX>);

            
               Books -- A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Fan</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Notes</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frederick Exley</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Misfit: The Strange Life of Frederick</ENAMEX>
Exley , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Yardley</ENAMEX>;

            

               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Apaches</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lorenzo Carcaterra</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">13:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Conspiracy</ENAMEX>
Theory ;

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Love</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Serenade</ENAMEX> ;

            

               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vibe</ENAMEX> and The 
               Keenen 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ivory</ENAMEX>

               Wayans 
               Show ;

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Event/Television</ENAMEX> --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garth Brooks</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central Park</ENAMEX>/ <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garth Brooks Live</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBO</ENAMEX>);

            
               Art --"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sculpture of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angkor</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ancient Cambodia: Millennium of Glory"</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simenon</ENAMEX>: A
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Biography</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pierre Assouline</ENAMEX>, translated by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jon Rothschild</ENAMEX>;

            

               Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Dispatches From the Freud Wars: Psychoanalysis and Its</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Passions</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Forrester</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie -- Career
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Girls</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- In the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Company</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Men</ENAMEX> ;

            

               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Spawn</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Our Guys</ENAMEX>: The
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Glen Ridge Rape and the Secret Life of the Perfect Suburb</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bernard</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lefkowitz</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Faith</ENAMEX> or
Fear<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">: How Jews Can Survive in a Christian America</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elliott Abrams</ENAMEX>;

            
               Death --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burroughs</ENAMEX>;

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Opera</ENAMEX> -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Palestrina</ENAMEX> .

            

               --Compiled by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Franklin Foer</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> .
            

         
      
   
