
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Movies
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">G.I. Jane</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hollywood Pictures</ENAMEX>). After panning <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Demi Moore</ENAMEX>'s
performances in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Scarlet Letter</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Striptease</ENAMEX> as stolid and
humorless, most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> say that this movie revives her career. Cast as an
indomitable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who endures hellish training with an all-male <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Navy</ENAMEX> squadron,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moore "</ENAMEX>becomes perversely spectacular" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Maslin</ENAMEX>, the New York
Times ) and transcends the movie's "banal <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">premises</ENAMEX> and predictable
conclusion" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Schickel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> ). But some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> find the
fascination of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ridley Scott</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alien</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thelma & Louise</ENAMEX> )
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moore</ENAMEX>'s suffering hopelessly sadistic. And others say she is as humorless
as ever. (See <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarah Kerr</ENAMEX>'s review in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">G.I. Jane</ENAMEX> site.)

            

               
                  Mimic
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dimension Films</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Reviewers</ENAMEX> are divided over whether this
unusually dark horror film--starring <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mira Sorvino</ENAMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientist</ENAMEX> who hatches
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">killer cockroaches</ENAMEX>--represents <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B-movie</ENAMEX> brilliance or garden-variety trash. Some
praise <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guillermo Del Toro</ENAMEX> for manipulating Gothic conventions and
sprinkling the film with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> imagery and allusions to classic films. He
manages, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Turan</ENAMEX>, to "bring a sense of
style to the genre's oldest tricks." Others say that his efforts to shock
outweigh his attempts to build suspense. "[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX>]othing more than a standard-issue
big-bug item," says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Variety</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Todd McCarthy</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here for the
Mimic site.)

            

               Books
            

            

               
                  Already <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dead</ENAMEX>: A <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> Gothic
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Denis Johnson</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HarperCollins</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Praise</ENAMEX>, for the most part, for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Denis Johnson</ENAMEX>'s crime novel
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about</NUMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nietzsche</ENAMEX>-quoting vagabond who agrees to help a New Age marijuana
farmer kill his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>. It's "a sort of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen King</ENAMEX> novel for highbrows" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Book Review</ENAMEX> ) that combines "existential
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bleakness</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Ulin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsday</ENAMEX> ) and "breezy silliness" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Kent</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post Book World</ENAMEX> ). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michiko Kakutani</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dissents</ENAMEX>, calling <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Already Dead</ENAMEX> "simultaneously pretentious, sentimental,
bubble-headed and gratuitously violent."

            
               
                  The
One <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Best Way: Frederick Winslow Taylor and the Enigma of Efficiency</ENAMEX>
               , by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Kanigel</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Viking</ENAMEX>). This biography of the original apostle of "scientific
management" and industrial efficiency is dismissed as fairly conventional, but
it does spark a debate over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Taylor</ENAMEX>'s legacy. Left-leaning <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> such as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">historian Jackson Lears</ENAMEX>, writing in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX> , say that the
widespread adoption of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Taylor</ENAMEX>'s theories amounted to "a horror story" in which
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cold-blooded</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> stripped <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> of their last shreds of autonomy.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Conservatives</ENAMEX> call <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Taylor</ENAMEX>'s vision benign. "It certainly came in handy when
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> was rampant," writes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Will</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Book</ENAMEX>
Review .

            

               Music
            

            
               
                  The
Dance
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fleetwood Mac</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reprise</ENAMEX>). The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">'70s</NUMEX> supergroup reunites for a
concert album, ending <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 years</TIMEX> of feuding. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX>' doubts about whether the
middle-aged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rockers</ENAMEX> have any staying power are overcome; they praise <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Fleetwood</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mac</ENAMEX>'s new songs, their <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">'70s</NUMEX> sound notwithstanding. "For these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> purveyors
of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Me-Generation romantic angst</ENAMEX>, the thrill is clearly not gone," says the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elysa Gardner</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> comb the new songs for details
about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>'s squabbles: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fleetwood Mac</ENAMEX> airs "every piece of dirty laundry
they had" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jim Farber, Entertainment Weekly</ENAMEX> ). (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Audio</ENAMEX> and video clips are
available here.)

             

            

               Television
            

            
               
                  Good
News
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UPN</ENAMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Mondays</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 p.m. EDT/PDT</TIMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> say <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UPN</ENAMEX>'s new series about
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">preacher</ENAMEX> may be the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>-decent show.
It "has heart and charm and not just the usual gag reflex," says the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Shales</ENAMEX>. The rest of the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UPN</ENAMEX> lineup--debuting a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">month</TIMEX> before other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX>' fall programs--consists mostly of sitcoms that are
generally condemned for mindlessness and tastelessness. Especially reviled is
Hitz , starring trash-talking comedian <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Dice Clay</ENAMEX>, which suffers
from too many penis jokes and a "gratingly loud laugh track" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caryn James</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ). (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UPN</ENAMEX> plugs
its shows.)

            

               Update
            

            Plaudits
follow pans for the revival of the musical On the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Town</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Corliss</ENAMEX> says, "It's like a vivid old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yorker cartoon</ENAMEX>, animated by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tex Avery</ENAMEX>. ... It works terrifically," and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Observer</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Heilpern</ENAMEX> says it "has us ... falling in love
with the city all over again."

            
               Recent
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment</ENAMEX>" columns
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">20:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cop</ENAMEX>
Land ;

            
               Movie -- The Full
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monty</ENAMEX> ;

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Music -- Be Here</ENAMEX>
Now , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oasis</ENAMEX>;

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> -- <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1776</TIMEX> ;

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> -- On the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Town</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wallace</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNT</ENAMEX>);

            
               Books -- A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Fan</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Notes</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frederick Exley</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Misfit: The Strange Life of Frederick</ENAMEX>
Exley , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Yardley</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Apaches</ENAMEX> ,
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lorenzo Carcaterra</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">13:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Conspiracy</ENAMEX>
Theory ;

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Love</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Serenade</ENAMEX> ;

            

               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vibe</ENAMEX> and The 
               Keenen 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ivory</ENAMEX>

               Wayans 
               Show ;

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Event/Television</ENAMEX> --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garth Brooks</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central Park</ENAMEX>/ <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garth Brooks Live</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBO</ENAMEX>);

            
               Art --"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sculpture of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angkor</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ancient Cambodia: Millennium of Glory"</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simenon</ENAMEX>: A
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Biography</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pierre Assouline</ENAMEX>, translated by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jon Rothschild</ENAMEX>;

            

               Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Dispatches From the Freud Wars: Psychoanalysis and Its</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Passions</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Forrester</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie -- Career
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Girls</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- In the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Company</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Men</ENAMEX> ;

            

               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Spawn</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Our Guys</ENAMEX>: The
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Glen Ridge Rape and the Secret Life of the Perfect Suburb</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bernard</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lefkowitz</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Faith</ENAMEX> or
Fear<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">: How Jews Can Survive in a Christian America</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elliott Abrams</ENAMEX>;

            
               Death --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burroughs</ENAMEX>;

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Opera</ENAMEX> -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Palestrina</ENAMEX> .

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- Mrs.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brown</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX>
Maps ;

            
               Architecture --National
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Airport</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stewart</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Just Desserts: The Unauthorized Biography</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oppenheimer</ENAMEX>;

            

               Book -- A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Book of Memories</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Nadas</ENAMEX>, translated by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ivan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sanders</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Imre Goldstein</ENAMEX>.

            

               --Compiled by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Franklin Foer</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> .
            

         
      
   
