
   
   
      
         
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 8</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Aug. 8, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            The
Panglossian cover editorial welcomes a stock market slump: "[A] modest
drop in share prices could be exactly what is needed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">right now</TIMEX>." Stocks remain
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">overvalued</ENAMEX>, and a harmless fall now will prevent a tragic fall <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later</TIMEX>. A true
crash is unlikely, argues the piece. ... A story examines the growing business of international
Internet medical prescriptions. If you live in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> where <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Viagra</ENAMEX> is
banned, you can order the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> from an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American pharmacy</ENAMEX>'s Web site by giving a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">credit</ENAMEX> card number and minimal personal information. Legislation banning the
practice seems inevitable. ... A story says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox Sports Net</ENAMEX> is eating
into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESPN</ENAMEX>'s market. By buying local sports <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX> instead of relying on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">national</ENAMEX> programming, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX> gives <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> more coverage of their home <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESPN</ENAMEX>) is kicking itself for not having done the same
thing.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity Fair</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 1998</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 7, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Three</TIMEX>
stories about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VF</ENAMEX> excerpts a new book by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joyce Maynard</ENAMEX>, who
chronicles the affair she had with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J.D. Salinger</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early '70s</TIMEX>. She was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX>,
he was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">53</NUMEX>. Tasty morsels: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salinger</ENAMEX> got so frustrated at her inability to
have intercourse (it was stress-related) that he brought her to a naturopathic
practitioner in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> (it didn't work). <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salinger</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Agey</ENAMEX> wellness mania
led him to purge after eating <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">unhealthy foods</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salinger</ENAMEX> worked on his
fiction <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> (despite not having published in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>), and his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> holds
a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>-sized vault of unseen manuscripts. (For a 
                  Slate
                take on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maynard</ENAMEX>, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alex Beam</ENAMEX>'s "I Was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Teen-Ager</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>.") ... A story
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">profiles Stephen Glass</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> fired for fabricating
articles. Glass' former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> say he was pathologically insecure and too
eager to please. He lied up until the bitter end, even in the face of damning
evidence. ... 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VF</ENAMEX> interviews <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Wolfe</ENAMEX> about his new novel, A
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Man</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Full</TIMEX> , due to be published <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this fall</TIMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">700</NUMEX> page work centers on a
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">debt-ridden Atlanta</ENAMEX> aristocrat. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolfe</ENAMEX> seems very conservative, very arrogant,
very foppish, and very genuine.

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times Magazine</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 9</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 6, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
story examines claims that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Raymond Carver</ENAMEX>'s short stories were more a
product of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carver</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> than of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carver</ENAMEX> himself. Yes, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gordon Lish</ENAMEX> used
a heavy hand in shaping <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carver</ENAMEX>'s early voice (rewriting long passages,
violently cutting text, changing the tone). But this does not differ from what,
for example, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ezra Pound</ENAMEX> did to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T.S. Eliot</ENAMEX>'s work. Besides, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carver</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later</TIMEX> (many
say better) stories were entirely his own. The piece notes that authorship is
always a collaborative process to some degree, be it with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouse</ENAMEX>, etc.
... An article covers the forthcoming <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">whale hunt</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Makah</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> state <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Native American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tribe</ENAMEX> is fighting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">environmentalists</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> for the right to resume hunting a few <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">whales</ENAMEX> a year, an old Makah
tradition. Not an old <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Makah</ENAMEX> tradition: the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.50</NUMEX>-caliber <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">rifle</ENAMEX> they will use in
the hunt. ... A story profiles new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian Coalition</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy Tate</ENAMEX>,
a k a the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralph Reed</ENAMEX>'s shadow. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Tate</ENAMEX> lacks the political savvy of his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">predecessor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reed</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> say <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tate</ENAMEX>'s unrelenting focus on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gays</ENAMEX> will hurt
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">coalition</ENAMEX> in the long run.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 10</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 4, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            They're loony for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> piece cover package includes an hour-by<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">-hour</TIMEX> account of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Starr</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">machinations</ENAMEX> to secure <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>'s testimony, including a behind-the-scenes look
at the meeting that sealed the deal. (<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Key</ENAMEX> to success: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> brought
a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">46-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">female colleague</ENAMEX> to guide <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX> through the sensitive parts of
her story.) Other features: a breakdown of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s options ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> likes
the idea of a public apology but thinks <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> would never go for it);
a recapping and analysis of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s evidence, as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> understands it; a
prediction that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> will do nothing before elections; and a piece
claiming the scandal has ruined any chance for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to burnish his legacy
before he leaves <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>--he simply doesn't have the political clout anymore.
... 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's more modest package adds this nugget: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">team</ENAMEX> ... has discussed indicting the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> for obstruction while he is
still in office, but holding off on the trial until he is a private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen</ENAMEX>,"
when a conviction would be easier to obtain. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> also runs an essay
from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">loyalist</ENAMEX>-cum-moralist <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX>, who urges the prez to
come clean. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX> thinks <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has been hurt by confiding in only a
small circle and cutting off many of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisers</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">steroids</ENAMEX> aren't just for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> anymore. Teen-age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> are
taking them to improve performance and win college athletic scholarships. How
do you know if your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> is on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">steroids</ENAMEX>? Her breasts shrink and her voice
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">deepens</ENAMEX>.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> runs a rant bemoaning the glitzification of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hamptons</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s recent visit marked the final straw for a quiet community besieged by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rich</ENAMEX> and gaudy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">outsiders</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News & World Report</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 10</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 4, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
News ' scandal package delivers much the same info as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's in far less space. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> piece argues that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">middle America</ENAMEX> just wants the scandal over with and wants <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to stay in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>. ... A story says <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">anthropologists</ENAMEX> are redefining themselves. Having
slipped too far into the sheltered and irrelevant world of academia,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">anthropologists</ENAMEX> now strive to make a difference: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">anthropologist</ENAMEX> hired by a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">slaughterhouse</ENAMEX> helped explain meatpacker society to factory <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supervisors</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 10</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 4, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            A story
looks at life in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambodia</ENAMEX>, post-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pol Pot</ENAMEX>. While the genocide has ended, random
killing by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policemen</ENAMEX> continues. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hun Sen</ENAMEX> ignores election results and
intimidates his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> but still has <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> support. Latest outrage: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hun Sen</ENAMEX>
inducted several former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khmer Rouge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> into the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cambodian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX>.
... A piece celebrates amateur astronomy. It doesn't take a huge
telescope or federal funding to make important discoveries--it just takes
patience and luck. The godfather of amateur cosmology: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Dobson</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monk</ENAMEX> who
would tote his "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dobsonian</ENAMEX>" (a cheap, powerful telescope) to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street corners</ENAMEX> and
convince <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passers-by</ENAMEX> to stargaze.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stevenson</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
