
   
   
      
         
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 10</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Jan. 10</TIMEX>)
            

            Another
cover editorial about the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX> crisis. This one disapproves of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Monetary Fund</ENAMEX>'s bailout. The recession it's supposed to prevent
might never have happened, and rescuing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">financiers</ENAMEX> who make mistakes encourages
them to make the same errors again. A <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX>-page package on tourism notes that it
accounts for <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX> of the world economy (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3.6 trillion</NUMEX> per year). Big
dilemma: how to prevent desirable vacation spots from being ruined. (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>'s new
tourism slogan: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">From Nebuchadnezzar</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2,400 years</TIMEX> of peace
and prosperity.") A story describes the latest Web-encryption device: digital
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">watermarking</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Subtle</ENAMEX> number patterns within digitized pictures and music let
their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> bust bootleggers. Also, an article praises the ongoing Lunar
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prospector</ENAMEX> mission. It's quick (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22 months</TIMEX> to develop) and cheap (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">only $63</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX>). The directive: Find <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> in the moon's polar craters.

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 26</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 9</TIMEX>)
            

            More
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> bashing. The cover story repeats the shopworn criticism that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> is evil because its second-rate software crushes better programs. An
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> worries that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Turner</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1-billion</NUMEX> donation will let him dictate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX>
policy. For instance, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Turner's</ENAMEX> donation might fund projects to fight world
hunger with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">buffalo meat</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Turner</ENAMEX> owns <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX> of all bison in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>). Also, an essay bucks the trend by trashing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>' new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Getty</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum</ENAMEX>: The art collection lacks any show-stoppers, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Meier</ENAMEX>'s
entrance façade resembles "a prefab <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">grain silo</ENAMEX> with lots of cutouts."

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity Fair</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 1998</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 9</TIMEX>)
            

            A profile
argues that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> secretly hates politics. His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> bred him to be
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, and he does his duty as a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>, but he'd rather be doing almost
anything else. The piece reaffirms the cliché that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> is a warm, funny guy
behind his wooden exterior. An essay wishes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> would
ditch its new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sections</ENAMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dining In</ENAMEX>," "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fine Arts</ENAMEX>," etc., help <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">advertisers</ENAMEX> more
than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>, and make the paper unwieldy to read. Also, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity Fair</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dubs Brown University</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jet-Set Ivy</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Super-rich</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">super-hip students</ENAMEX> (called
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Euros</ENAMEX>," even when not <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX>) drive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ferraris</ENAMEX>, wear <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chanel</ENAMEX>, and hit <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">weekends</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brown</ENAMEX> attracts the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> of the rich and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">famous</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana Ross</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kate</ENAMEX>
Capshaw, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamar Alexander</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Itzhak Perlman</ENAMEX>), and its grads dominate the music and
Web-publishing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">industries</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times Magazine</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 11</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 8</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
story deplores local television news shows' obsession with titillation and
ratings. Local news panders to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> by showing crime and disaster footage,
ignoring education and politics. Responsible conclusion: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Local</ENAMEX> news should try
to balance shocking video with serious stories. A conversation between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ralph</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reed</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX> finds them agreeing that scandals don't hurt
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>, and partisanship annoys <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reed</ENAMEX> says he models himself after
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Luther King Jr.</ENAMEX>, while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX> ridicules <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> for praising the
sitcom character <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellen</ENAMEX>. ("It's not a moral issue, it's just stupid.") Also, a
story asserts that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX> 49ers' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Young</ENAMEX> is the best quarterback
ever, statistically speaking. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Young</ENAMEX> owns <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19</NUMEX> best-ever <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seasons</TIMEX> for a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">quarterback</ENAMEX>, and is the highest-rated passer of all time. But 49ers <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> will
always love <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Montana</ENAMEX> more.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 12</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 6</TIMEX>)
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Seinfeld</ENAMEX>
cover mourns the passing of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seinfeld</ENAMEX> . Inside are an exclusive interview with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seinfeld</ENAMEX> (he says he's not
interested in money), a history of the show (it claims the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992-93 season</TIMEX> is the
best), and a piece on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>'s now shaky future ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seinfeld</ENAMEX> 's
departure may end <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX><TIMEX TYPE="TIME">-night</TIMEX> dominance). Conflict-of-interest watch:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seinfeld</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time/Warner</ENAMEX> product. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> counters by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">interviewing Larry David</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seinfeld</ENAMEX> 's co-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">creator</ENAMEX> and "dark <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX>."
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX>, which did a cover story on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kennedy</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">siblings</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only six months ago</TIMEX>, puts him on the cover again. The package offers thumbnail
profiles of all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RFK</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, as well as a schematic explaining ski <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX>.
Essays in both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> argue that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> was a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who will be
unfairly remembered for sleeping with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby sitter</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> tracks the comeback of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Express</ENAMEX>. Hurt in the early
'90s by no-fee credit-card <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amex</ENAMEX> is back on the rise. Why? Better
customer perks (like discounts and air <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">miles</NUMEX>), advertising geared toward
younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> (including commercials featuring <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Seinfeld</ENAMEX>), and
corporate downsizing.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> wonders if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VW</ENAMEX>'s reintroduction of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beetle</ENAMEX> will work. The new
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> is cute, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> of the old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Beetle</ENAMEX> hate the new front-mounted engine and
high price (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">around $19,000</NUMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VW</ENAMEX> hopes nostalgia and slick marketing will sell
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News & World Report</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 12</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 6</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
package is an ode to fat. Included: a claim that fat's OK for your body
as long as you exercise; interviews with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chef</ENAMEX> and a nutritionist (both
cautiously pro-fat); and a rundown of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fatty cuisine</ENAMEX> in other cultures,
including <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pâté de foie gras</ENAMEX>, crispy <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">duck</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Ukrainian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salted pork fat</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yum</ENAMEX>.
(See 
                  Slate
               's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dialogue</ENAMEX>" on fat.) A story explains the publishing industry's new survival techniques.
Huge advances are history, and better technology lets <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">publishers</ENAMEX> ship books
faster and track sales more closely. Also, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX> finds a vacation hotbed: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fidel Castro</ENAMEX> has successfully boosted
tourism to raise funds for his ailing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. While <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> can't legally
go, the rest of the world flocks to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX>'s beaches, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">nightclubs</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prostitutes</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 12</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 6</TIMEX>)
            

            A writer
chronicles his own long bout with depression, a period when he couldn't eat and
was afraid to stand up or shower. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Medication</ENAMEX>, especially the anxiety-reliever
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Xanax</ENAMEX>, is much praised. Surprising fact: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Psychosurgery</ENAMEX> is still performed on
the desperately ill. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cingulotomies</ENAMEX>" destroy <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">centimeter</NUMEX>-wide patches of brain
tissue. The requisite <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> piece describes the economic theory behind the
antitrust case. The market sometimes locks in an inferior high-tech product
(e.g., <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MS-DOS</ENAMEX>) because the network advantages of using the inferior product
(more available software) outweigh its technological disadvantages. This
creates a monopoly. The theory, propounded by an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economist</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian Arthur</ENAMEX>,
annoys classical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> because it denies the principle that the best
product always wins. A story recounts the strange rivalry between top figure
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">skaters Michelle Kwan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tara Lipinski</ENAMEX>. The basic issue: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pre</ENAMEX>-adolescent
skaters, who have the highest strength-to-size ratio, are the best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jumpers</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Breasts</ENAMEX> and hips hinder performance. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kwan</ENAMEX>, who's been through
puberty, is struggling in a way her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rival</ENAMEX> isn't.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mother Jones</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 1998</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 30</TIMEX>)
            

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">magazine</ENAMEX>'s cover
package takes on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX> "pulls strings" in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> and other
world <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capitals</ENAMEX>, "cheats" by coercing software <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pirates</ENAMEX> into signing deals with
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, and "lies" about his business intentions, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> says. One
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> doubts that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> or any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitor</ENAMEX> can curb <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>,
another alleges that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> intends to compile dossiers on all PC <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX>,
and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a third</NUMEX> reports on how the ad <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wieden & Kennedy</ENAMEX> transformed
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s image from nerdy to cool. An article calls for cleaving <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX> new
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s most populous <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> to restore representative
democracy to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Senate</ENAMEX>.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stevenson</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
