
   
   
      
         
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 3</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Oct. 3, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            The
cover editorial urges careful treatment of the world's
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Monetary Fund</ENAMEX> must bail out <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> when their failure
might spur a worldwide <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">depression</ENAMEX> (as in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX>). But in some relatively harmless
cases (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>) we should let <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> fail--otherwise gambling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> will
never learn their lesson. ... A story attempts to explain the drastic fall in crime in
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>. Small saviors: new crime-fighting ideas (computerized
databases, the "broken window" theory), more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policemen</ENAMEX> on the beat, and the end
of the crack epidemic. Big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">savior</ENAMEX>: the decrease in the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> aged <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15</TIMEX>
to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX>.

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 19</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Oct. 3, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            The
cover story says the spread of suburbs has spurred the
rise of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">right</ENAMEX>. Back when <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">evangelicals</ENAMEX> inhabited rural
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX>, they were never forced to confront cultural <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX>. Now that they
live in diverse suburbs, they have become <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">separatists</ENAMEX>. Alarmed by cultural
differences, they have started home schooling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and running for political
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>. ... A story says that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> is suffering another huge brain
drain. Smart, educated <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX> who just recently achieved middle-class comfort
refuse to return to poverty now that the economy has collapsed. So they are
fleeing the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> in droves.

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times Magazine</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 4</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, Oct. 1, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
story describes the chaos of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Azerbaijan</ENAMEX>, a former <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">republic</ENAMEX> holding the
rights to an oil lode in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Caspian Sea</ENAMEX>. Capital city <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baku</ENAMEX> is "rampant with
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">ham-handed Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spies</ENAMEX>, as well as <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gangsters</ENAMEX> (known for their proud
display of chest hair), black-eyed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chechen</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">revolutionaries</ENAMEX>, paranoid <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">diplomats</ENAMEX>, fanatical <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iranian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX> and financial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speculators</ENAMEX> of various
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">nationalities</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Baku</ENAMEX>'s foray into capitalism has wrought violence, instability,
and corruption, but <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> are still investing. ... A story
tracks photography's growing legitimacy as an art form. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metropolitan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum of Art</ENAMEX> has been steadily adding to its once meager collection, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">photography</ENAMEX> has become "the medium of the moment." Because <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">amateurs</ENAMEX>
own cameras and take pictures, photography sometimes gets little respect from
snobby <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museums</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 5</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Sept. 29, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> goes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oprah</ENAMEX>-overboard with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> articles on the talk show <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX> and her
new movie of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Toni Morrison</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beloved</ENAMEX> (about a runaway <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slave</ENAMEX> dealing with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">motherhood</ENAMEX>). Making <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beloved</ENAMEX> was a deeply emotional experience for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Winfrey</ENAMEX>, but what isn't? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morrison</ENAMEX> at first disliked the film, but she is now a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX>. ... 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's cover story: Home schooling--it's not just
for <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">zealots</ENAMEX> anymore! <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">About 1.5 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are home schooled, and many parents
insist it keeps their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> engaged in hands-on learning. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's
dubious list of recent home schoolees: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jessica DuBroff</ENAMEX>, the 7-year-old pilot
whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> crashed; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rebecca Sealfon</ENAMEX>, the national spelling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bee champion</ENAMEX> with
bizarre social tics; and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hanson</ENAMEX>, the teen<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">-idol</ENAMEX> pop <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> with great hair.

            Both mags
run wine stories. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> covers the wine industry's push to make
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> drink more <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> produces more <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX> than any <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> save
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX>, yet we rank near the bottom in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX> consumption. The
Wine <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Market Council</ENAMEX> will launch a media <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">campaign</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX>. Meanwhile,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> salutes the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wines</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chile</ENAMEX>. High quality and cheap, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chilean</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wines</ENAMEX>
are now the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>-most popular imports, behind only <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Italian</ENAMEX>
vintages.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News & World Report</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 5</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Sept. 29, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
story ranks <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMOs</ENAMEX>. Top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fallon Community Health Plan</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Finger Lakes</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blue Choice</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>), and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tufts Health Plan</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maine</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Hampshire</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rhode Island</ENAMEX>). An accompanying article profiles <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community Medical Alliance</ENAMEX>, a small HMO
that stresses prevention over treatment and which even makes house calls.
... A story explains <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>'s plummeting fertility rate: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Women</ENAMEX> in
their <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late 20s</TIMEX> don't want to sacrifice their independence to marriage and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">motherhood</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> don't help to bring up <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX>, and nannies are frowned
upon, so motherhood can ruin a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>'s career. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>'s fertility rate is now
"one of the lowest in the world." ... Bummer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dept.</ENAMEX>: Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> now
rent drug-sniffing <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> to search their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teens</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedrooms</ENAMEX>. Drug-dog
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rental</ENAMEX> (for home or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>) is a growing industry: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> rental facility
explains, "We give <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> another out. If somebody says, 'Hey, try this,' the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>
can say, 'But what if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> show up <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>?' "

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 5</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Sept. 29, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            "The Talk
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Town</ENAMEX>" runs essays on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Toni Morrison</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Malcolm</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">James</ENAMEX>
Salter, and others. All are pro-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morrison</ENAMEX>: "This is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slaughtergate</ENAMEX>. A sustained, bloody, arrogant coup d'etat. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Presidency</ENAMEX> is
being stolen from us. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> know it." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malcolm</ENAMEX>: "Since the object of
[<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s investigation] was to turn the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> against the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>, those of
us who deplored the investigation from the start can only take satisfaction in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s bungling--in this time of few satisfactions." ... The fall books
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">section</ENAMEX> includes articles on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eudora Welty</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Raymond Carver</ENAMEX> (a "prairie
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">existentialist"</ENAMEX>) and reviews much new fiction.

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nation</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 12</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Sept. 29, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            The
cover story argues
that devolution of power from the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> is an
opportunity for progressives. Giving power to local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> encourages
experimentation that the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> can learn from. Examples cited: state
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco</ENAMEX> lawsuits, local anti-pollution taxes, higher minimum wages, campaign
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">finance</ENAMEX> reform at the state level, and better local mass transit. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Drawback:</ENAMEX>
Progressive policies make a community less "business friendly," so surrounding
areas reap the economic benefits.

            

               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 5</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Sept. 29, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
story claims that "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hollywood Beats Harvard</ENAMEX>" in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>.
Originally a bastion for Ivy League wonks such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ira</ENAMEX>
Magaziner, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> is now cozier with <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Coast</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elites</ENAMEX>: the
Thomasons, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Spielberg</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbra Streisand</ENAMEX>, etc. ... A story praises
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miss America</ENAMEX> pageant for having "tilted the tiara from left to right." The
new <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miss America</ENAMEX> is a born-again <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> who says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> should resign and
whose cause is <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diabetes</ENAMEX> awareness. The last <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miss America</ENAMEX> "held progressive
views" and supported <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> research. Apparently even diseases are partisan.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stevenson</ENAMEX>
            

            More Flytrap
...

         
      
   
