
   
   
      
         
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 7</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, March 7</TIMEX>)
            

            Echoing
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX> , the cover editorial applauds <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMOs</ENAMEX> for reducing medical
inflation. Suggestion for improvement: unregulated competition, which would
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">force HMOs</ENAMEX> to compete over quality as well as price. ... A story deplores the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s plans to control
encryption software on the Internet. Federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> want the right to read
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">encrypted</ENAMEX> messages, much as they currently have the right to tap phones. A free
market for encryption is a better idea: It would produce more reliable
encryption software and protect electronic commerce from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times Magazine</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 8</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 5</TIMEX>)
            

            Yet
another special issue. The subject is--we're not kidding--business
travel as a way of life. Sixteen features look at the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">nomadic</ENAMEX> ennui of the
frequent business <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traveler</ENAMEX>. An article claims <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airports</ENAMEX> are our new <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>: The
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort Worth</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airport</ENAMEX> is bigger than <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Executives</ENAMEX> can fly in, eat
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">meals</ENAMEX>, get a massage, hold meetings, and stay overnight--all without leaving
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">terminal</ENAMEX>. A story says <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">execs</ENAMEX> are high-end <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX>' best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>. They
eat faster than most and drink overpriced liquor--on the expense account,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">natch</ENAMEX>. A piece marvels at the popularity of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX>-disaster novels
( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Airframe , Mayday</ENAMEX> ) in airport <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bookstores</ENAMEX>, theorizing that
fictional air terror must "inoculate a troubled mind with a homeopathic dose of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">angst</ENAMEX>." Also, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> tries to break his personal record of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">West</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">86 th Street</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX>, to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Connecticut Avenue</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>, in
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one hour and 47 minutes</TIMEX>. Keys to success: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sit</ENAMEX> in a front seat on the shuttle
and dictate an optimum route to cabbies.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 9</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 3</TIMEX>)
            

            A
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">blockbuster 75 th -anniversary</ENAMEX> issue. Among the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly 200</NUMEX> pages of
hagiography: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) letters to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harpo Marx</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salvador Dalí</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">William</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randolph Hearst</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Sinatra</ENAMEX> ("as usual your information stinks," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank</ENAMEX>
wrote in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1961</TIMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) an array of great cover images; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's most and
least prescient comments (in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1983</TIMEX>, a prediction that the paparazzi would
kill a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the royal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, and in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1933</TIMEX>, a prediction that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> was
destined for obscurity); and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) a list of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> neologisms ("socialite,"
"televangelist," and "<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX>"). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's two best-selling issues
were both on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Princess</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Di</ENAMEX>'s death. The worst-selling issue? A <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> cover on the
black cultural renaissance.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 9</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 3</TIMEX>)
            

            On the
cover: A smiling <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX> proclaims, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Why We Will Win</ENAMEX>." Inside: A story
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tracks Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s growing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">D.C. PR</ENAMEX> campaign: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> is visiting <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> this
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX> for schmoozing and a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> hearing. (For <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX> diary in

                  Slate
               , click here.) In an interview, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> reiterates the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> line, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">We</ENAMEX>
need to keep innovating to stay alive." ... 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> offers a
detailed account of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathleen Willey</ENAMEX> episode, supposedly consistent with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX>'s deposition in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> case. After <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX> said, "I'm really
kind of desperate. The bottom line is, I need a job," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> allegedly fondled
her breasts and placed her hand against his erect penis. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX> pulled away
when there was a knock at the door of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s private study. ...
Just when you thought you were safe, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> finds yet another health
scare: your malicious thyroid. Thyroid problems can be hard to detect and can
cause severe, unexplained depression.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News & World Report</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 9</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 3</TIMEX>)
            

            A
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Jekyll-and-Hyde</ENAMEX> cover package rehashes the usual praise and criticism for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMOs</ENAMEX>.
An article cheers <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMOs</ENAMEX> for cutting costs to both big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>. A former medical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> slams <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMOs</ENAMEX> for making heartless, profit-motivated decisions.
... A story worries that foreign exchange <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> might gain
weapons-building knowledge at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Students</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Korea</ENAMEX>
(some learning nuclear physics) currently go unwatched once they enter the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX>. ... Also, tax
advice: Claim lots of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dependents</ENAMEX> and don't get married (tax laws favor
singles).

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 9</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 3</TIMEX>)
            

            An
absolutely terrifying article describes the old <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> bioweapons program and
speculates that rogue <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> are now employing its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX>. Chilling
descriptions of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bioweapons</ENAMEX> abound: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Veepox</ENAMEX>," a cross between <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">smallpox</ENAMEX> and a
brain virus, and "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ebolapox</ENAMEX>," a cross between <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">smallpox</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ebola</ENAMEX>--as fatal as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ebola</ENAMEX> and as contagious as <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">smallpox</ENAMEX>. The bioweapons could be deployed quickly,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">surreptitiously</ENAMEX>, and cheaply; and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> is totally unprepared to deal with
them. (The article is by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hot Zone</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Preston</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX> of
biological horror stories.) ... An essay pegged to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> scandal
mourns the end of loyalty. Presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX> used to fall on their swords for
their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX>; now they stab him in the back. Why? We are a "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Free Agent Nation":</ENAMEX>
Shifting, fluid acquaintanceships have replaced <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>, lifelong loyalties.
Perfect example: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>, but no really close
ones. (
                  Slate
               's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>" has strong views on this article.
Click here.)
... A profile of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Wright</ENAMEX> says she will make sure the Paula
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> trial is narrowly focused and extremely short (perhaps <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only a week</TIMEX>).
Those hoping for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> of tawdry sex revelations will be disappointed.

            

               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 9</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 3</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
story says the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> case has exposed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">feminists</ENAMEX>' partisan agenda. The piece
chews over the much chewed-over comparison between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarence Thomas</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Feminists</ENAMEX> denounced <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX> but defend <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>.) (For

                  Slate
               's ruminations on this topic, see this "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Gist</ENAMEX>.") ... Also,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX> is no longer a feminist icon: She's now "the very model of the
Victorian little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>, denying it happened, blaming the floozies, absolving
her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> of blame." ... An article claims that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Armey</ENAMEX> will not be
the next <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>, despite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heir</ENAMEX> apparent <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Paxon</ENAMEX> clearing the
path by resigning. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Armey</ENAMEX> doesn't schmooze well enough with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> and has a
fatal flaw: He's bad on TV talk shows. ... A story says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> are
itching to start impeachment hearings once <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX> finishes his
investigation. They just need a few <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> votes so they can claim
bipartisan support.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stevenson</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
