
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Art
            

            

               "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Picasso: The Early Years</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1892-1906</TIMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">National Gallery of Art</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wonder Bread</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>"--<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 11 to 25</TIMEX>--ending in
his cubist period. The question is whether the world needs another <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Picasso</ENAMEX> show
less than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> after the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum of Modern Art</ENAMEX>'s grand exhibition of his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">portraiture</ENAMEX>. Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> are happy to reconsider the maligned "blue period,"
which is now deemed "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Picasso</ENAMEX> at his most accessible" by the Wall Street
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deborah Solomon</ENAMEX> ("you don't need to know the first thing about
line or form to be deeply moved by them"). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX>
Kimmelman, on the other hand, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">curators</ENAMEX> confuse "precociousness with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">originality</ENAMEX>" and quantity with quality: These "endless shows ... numb <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Picasso</ENAMEX>'s art, making obeisance routine, like genuflecting in church." (The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Gallery</ENAMEX> plugs the show at its site.)

            

               Movies
            

            

               
                  Anaconda
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sony Pictures</ENAMEX>). A classic example of the high-low
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">two-step</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anaconda</ENAMEX> is both No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> at the box office and earning a
qualified critical approbation for its self-referentially campy chic. Playing
an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">obsessive</ENAMEX> dedicated to trapping a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">40-foot-long</NUMEX> snake in the middle of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jon Voight</ENAMEX> leads a group of unsuspecting documentary filmmakers
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer Lopez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric Stoltz</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Ice Cube</ENAMEX>) to their deaths. The movie "has,
like the killing-machine <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">beast</ENAMEX> itself, the brutal efficiency of
single-mindedness" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Terrence Rafferty</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Voight</ENAMEX>'s
overwrought performance has a "kitschy glory" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Morgenstern</ENAMEX>, the Wall
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Street Journal</ENAMEX> ). It all harks back to the "kind of retro, eek! eek!
production that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studios</ENAMEX> don't often make anymore, now that movies about
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tornadoes</ENAMEX> and invasions by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX> have become too expensive to be taken
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">humorously</ENAMEX>." (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lisa Schwarzbaum</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Entertainment Weekly</ENAMEX>). (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anaconda</ENAMEX> site serves up stills and clips.)

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grosse Pointe Blank</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buena Vista Pictures</ENAMEX>). Heaps of praise for
the movie's preposterous premise: An introspective hit <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> returns home for a
high-school reunion. The film itself "doesn't always make a whole lot of
sense," says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Turan</ENAMEX>, "but seeing a vehicle
this outlandish is reward enough by itself." Credit goes to co-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>
Cusack, who "brings his droll intelligence to bear on a worthy comic invention,
... turning every dialogue scene into a colloquy for ardent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">obsessives</ENAMEX>"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morgenstern</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> ). But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cusack</ENAMEX> can't sustain the
freshness of the original idea: The film "isn't nearly as clever as it thinks
it is" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rafferty</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> ).

            

               Theater
            

            
               
                  An
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Daughter</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cort Theatre</ENAMEX>). Mixed reviews for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wendy Wasserstein</ENAMEX>'s
comedy based on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zoe Baird</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kimba Wood</ENAMEX> incidents, with recognizable
caricatures of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Naomi Wolf</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Sullivan</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsday</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Winer</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wasserstein</ENAMEX> has matured into "her own bright,
eloquent and great-hearted version of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bernard Shaw</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York</ENAMEX>
Times ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben Brantley</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wasserstein</ENAMEX> "may be saying something about a world
that reduces <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to sound bites ... [but] is also working principally in
bite-size slices of sound, sentiment and humor." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> 's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lloyd Rose</ENAMEX> says that "[t]he play is antic as all get-out, but it doesn't go
anywhere--it just hops frantically up and down in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> place."

            

               Books
            

            

               
                  Naked
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Sedaris</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Little, Brown and Co.</ENAMEX>). Commercial and
critical success for the gay housecleaner-turned-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humorist</ENAMEX>'s collection of
essays--<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">seventh</NUMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> best-seller list. Critics
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">applaud Sedaris</ENAMEX>' tendency to mock both himself (the title essay is about his
stint at a nudist <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX>) and others (he titles a piece about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who picked
him up hitchhiking "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Planet of the Apes</ENAMEX>"). The book is a "wedding of funny and
mean, and Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sedaris</ENAMEX> does have a way with venom" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Craig Seligman</ENAMEX>, the New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times Book Review</ENAMEX> ).

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blue Flower</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Penelope Fitzgerald</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Houghton Mifflin</ENAMEX>). Adulation for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Booker</ENAMEX> Prize-winning <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>'s historical novel about the romantic
life of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> Romantic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Novalis</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1772-1801</TIMEX>). "It is quite an
astonishing book, a masterpiece," says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Book Review</ENAMEX> 's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Hofmann</ENAMEX>. "I can think of no better introduction to the Romantic era."
"She is the finest <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> alive," says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> '
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Eder</ENAMEX>. Praise also goes to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fitzgerald</ENAMEX>'s command of dialogue: "The
conversations are many-voiced, sharp-witted and finely tuned enough to allow
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> to hear plangent undernotes and to feel the intoxicating buzz that
good talk emits" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucy Hughes-Hallett</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunday</ENAMEX> 
               Times ).

            
               
                  Gut
Symmetries
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeanette Winterson</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Knopf</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> previously
considered <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Winterson</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Written on the Body , Sexing the Cherry</ENAMEX> ) the
rising <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">superstar</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> fiction, but her latest novel prompts a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">re-evaluation</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Reviewers</ENAMEX> call it pretentious and filled with inaccurate
references to theoretical physics, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walt Whitman</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kabbalah</ENAMEX>. There is
"too much flexing of stylistic muscle," says the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert</ENAMEX>
Alter. "It is a notable example of what happens when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> discount the
centrality of narrative to fiction," says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsday</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Cryer</ENAMEX>.

            

               
                  Inventions of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> Hare: Poems <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1909-1917</TIMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T.S. Eliot</ENAMEX>,
edited by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Ricks</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harcourt Brace</ENAMEX>). <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> publication
of these never-published <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">39</NUMEX> poems occasioned accusations of misogyny,
sordidness, and racism (one of the poems is titled "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King Bolo</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Black</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kween</ENAMEX>"). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Reviewers</ENAMEX> predict that the collection's <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> will kick
off a wave of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eliot</ENAMEX>-bashing. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Book Review</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicholas</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jenkins</ENAMEX> says the poetry "articulates with dreamlike clarity not the perfections
of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> culture, but its chronic anguish ... of fascinations
and sicknesses widely shared." In the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Poirier</ENAMEX>
attacks <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ricks</ENAMEX>' annotations to the poems as "adventurism." The notes, says
Poirer, are unnecessarily complicated and obscure; Ricks "ignores or distorts
the plain evidence. ... Such annotative energies are generated not out of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eliot</ENAMEX>'s need to be explained [but] from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ricks</ENAMEX>'s need to dazzle."

            

               Television
            

            

               
                  Gun
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 p.m. EST</TIMEX>/PST). Praise for the idea behind
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert Altman</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>-episode dramatic series: Each installment has a
different premise, a different big-name <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> (including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Altman</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">James</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Foley</ENAMEX>), and different big-name <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rosanna Arquette</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carrie Fisher</ENAMEX>)--but
the same prop: <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a pearl-handled</NUMEX> semiautomatic. Pans for the outcome. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosenberg</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> calls the recurring gun conceit
"ridiculous." Episodes reviewed so far are dismissed as failed attempts at
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> satire. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clips from Gun</ENAMEX> are
available at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s site for the show.)

            

               
                  Fired Up
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9:30 p.m. EST</TIMEX>/PST). Yet another
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">undeserving</ENAMEX> sitcom takes the coveted slot between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seinfeld</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ER</ENAMEX> --the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> to do so. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYPD Blue</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sharon Lawrence</ENAMEX>
plays a newly unemployed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">publicist</ENAMEX> forced to move in with her former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Shales</ENAMEX> says the "whole premise is achingly
unlikely." "Once again, we find barely-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">scraping</NUMEX>-by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Manhattanites</ENAMEX> living in a
posh pad" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Roush</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> ). (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here for the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Fired Up</ENAMEX> site.)

            

               Updates
            

            The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>
wave of reviews of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inventing the Abbotts</ENAMEX> accords the film more merits than the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> wave did. "This is an intelligent and absorbing romantic drama,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">beautifully</ENAMEX> mounted, emotionally saturated," says <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Denby</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanley Kauffmann</ENAMEX> says performances by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joaquin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Phoenix</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Liv Tyler</ENAMEX> make the movie: "All the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> caught me up so warmly
that I stopped feeling guilty about liking this corny picture." ...

               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Simon</ENAMEX> objects to raves about the latest A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Doll</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> revival, especially those that praise <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet McTeer</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nora</ENAMEX>: "She lets
her hands flutter like <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tibetan</ENAMEX> prayer wheels in a gale, outcoos a turtledove in
heat, and flings herself about as if playing racquetball with her own
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>-foot-plus <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX>. This is what is known nowadays as rethinking the classics."
... The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Kiss</ENAMEX> controversy continues. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> 's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Yardley</ENAMEX> defends his attack on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathryn Harrison</ENAMEX>'s incest memoir against
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novelist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tobias Wolff</ENAMEX>'s claims that he was motivated by his animus toward
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">memoir</ENAMEX> as a genre: "The truth, as opposed to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolff</ENAMEX>'s self-serving fantasy, is
that my objections to <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">'The Kiss</ENAMEX>' have absolutely nothing to do with its being a
memoir per se, or even with its being one of those 'personal writings that have
recently found favor with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>.' My objections are based entirely and
exclusively in the simple, inescapable reality that <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">'The Kiss'</ENAMEX> is an
irredeemably rotten book. Per se." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yardley</ENAMEX> adds that when he said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight years</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ago</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tobias Wolff</ENAMEX>'s memoir was not as good as his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Geoffrey</ENAMEX>'s, that
was also a purely literary judgment.

            
               Recent
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment</ENAMEX>" columns:
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9:</TIMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> -- A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Doll</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saint</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Paradise</ENAMEX>
Road ;

            
               Movie -- Inventing
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abbotts</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- That Old</ENAMEX>
Feeling ;

            
               Book --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen Ginsberg</ENAMEX>
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1926-1997</TIMEX>);

            
               Book -- After the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madness</ENAMEX>: A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Own Prison Memoir</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sol Wachtler</ENAMEX>;

            

               Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- The Big Picture</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Douglas Kennedy</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2:</TIMEX>

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texaco</ENAMEX> ,
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patrick Chamoiseau</ENAMEX>, translated by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rose-Myriam RÃ</ENAMEX>©jouis and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Val Vinokurov</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Wayne</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Politics of Celebrity</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garry Wills</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Divorce</ENAMEX>
Culture , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara Dafoe Whitehead</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- When the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sons</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Heaven Meet the Daughters</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fernanda Eberstadt</ENAMEX>;

            
               Movie -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Devil</ENAMEX>'s
Own ;

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Chasing</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amy</ENAMEX> ;

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Young Man From Atlanta</ENAMEX> .

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">26:</TIMEX>

            
               Event -- The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">69 th Academy Awards</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Art --"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">1997 Biennial</ENAMEX>
Exhibition" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitney Museum of American Art</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>);

            
               Art --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willem de</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kooning</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1904-1997</TIMEX>);

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Liar</ENAMEX>
Liar ;

            

               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Crash</ENAMEX> ;

            

               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Selena</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Godfather</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Book -- The Coming
Conflict with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ross H. Munro</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Bernstein</ENAMEX>;

            

               Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Radical Son: A Journey Through Our Times</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Horowitz</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">19:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie -- Return of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Jedi</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Special Edition</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">City of</ENAMEX>
Industry ;

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Opera</ENAMEX> -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackie</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> ;

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Antony</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cleopatra</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX>:
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Novellas</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Leavitt</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- Deadly
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Feasts: Tracking the Secrets of a Terrifying New Plague</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rhodes</ENAMEX>;

            

               Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Resurrection: The Struggle</ENAMEX> for a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Russia</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Remnick</ENAMEX>;

            

               Book -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Three-Arched Bridge</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ismail Kadare</ENAMEX>, translated by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Hodgson</ENAMEX>.

            
               --Compiled by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Franklin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foer</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> .
            

         
      
   
