
   
   
      
         
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 23</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, May 23</TIMEX>)
            

            Reversing
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Economist</ENAMEX> 's previous position, the cover editorial calls for action against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>: "If
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> has broken the law, it should be punished. If it now poses an unfair
threat to new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, then its power should be curbed." Because the price
for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Windows</ENAMEX> has more than doubled since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX> and because the apparent monopoly
might "stifle services that would emerge with competition," the editorial
concludes that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> could be bad for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX>. ... A story finds
another industry at a crossroads: horse <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> exported <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$64</NUMEX>
million worth of horse <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX> for human consumption in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, but protest groups
and proposed anti-horse-meat legislation are quickly eradicating the business.
... An article claims that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi Arabia</ENAMEX> boasts a thriving black
market for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Viagra</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-impotence</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> is illegal there but when smuggled
in can bring <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">up to $80</NUMEX> per pill.

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 8</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 22, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            A cover
package debunks the conventional wisdom that the high-tech industry doesn't
know how to play the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> game. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Silicon Valley</ENAMEX> supports an influential,
though high-minded, political action <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">TechNet</ENAMEX>--to sway the
government's position on encryption, Internet taxation, and shareholder
lawsuits. Meanwhile, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> has bought a stable of aggressive, big-name
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyists</ENAMEX>. It pays former <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Committee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Haley Barbour</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$600,000</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> and employs a slew of ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">congressmen</ENAMEX>. ... A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> attacks the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>' condescending attitude toward <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>'s
recent nuclear tests. The posturing of hostile <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> justifies <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>'s own
show of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times Magazine</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 24</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 21, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
story describes the epidemic of psycho-cognitive <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">illness</ENAMEX> among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> adopted from eastern <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> orphanages. The afflicted
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 20 percent</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18,000</NUMEX> adopted--are incapable of forming
emotional bonds with their new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>, probably because the absence of
attention and affection in infancy stunted brain development. They are often
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">vicious</ENAMEX>, deceitful, and mentally slow. Lesson for all working <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Children</ENAMEX>
require regular emotional and physical engagement with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>. ... An
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> says that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> and arms <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealers</ENAMEX> use gun shows to skirt firearms
laws. If you claim you are adding to your private gun collection, you can buy
whatever <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> you want from shows without a waiting period or paperwork.
Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> sold at shows are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">killers</ENAMEX>, not hunting or target-shooting
weapons. ... A piece recounts the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Scrabble</ENAMEX> showdown between the world's
best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> and a computer programmed with all the words in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Scrabble</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dictionary</ENAMEX>. The computer won--barely. The human <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> found <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three nine</NUMEX>-letter
words in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AEEGINTRS</ENAMEX>. Can you? (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Answer</ENAMEX>: gratinees, agentries, reseating.)

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 25</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 19, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX> page
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Sinatra</ENAMEX> cover package routs <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> has articles
about his incomparable music, surprisingly impressive film career, hipness, and
relations with the powerful. An article says his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara</ENAMEX>
will squabble over his <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$200 million</NUMEX> estate. Old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shirley MacLaine</ENAMEX> writes
an adoring letter to him that begins "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dear Bedeviled Poet of Song ...</ENAMEX>" There
are also dozens of fabulous pictures. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> page package regrets
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sinatra</ENAMEX> didn't die as he lived: fighting. Both mags downplay his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">thuggishness</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> agree that
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> exploded nukes in order to boost its self-esteem and that there is no
imminent threat of conflict with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's coup: a
satellite photo of the test site.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> says that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> could be crippled by huge losses on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asian</ENAMEX>
derivatives. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> have already written off <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">hundreds of millions</NUMEX> in
bad <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">derivatives</ENAMEX>, and that's just the beginning. (The article does not
adequately explain what a derivative is, but no one ever has.) ... A
piece claims <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>'s plan to wire all <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">classrooms</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">libraries</ENAMEX> to the
Internet is in trouble. The scheme, paid for by a telephone surcharge, is
costing more than anticipated, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> in both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> are condemning the
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> tax." Why should the feds pay for something most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> would do anyway?
... A piece hyping the movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Godzilla</ENAMEX> says the new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monster</ENAMEX> is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">leaner</ENAMEX>, faster, and less scaly than his '50s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">predecessor</ENAMEX>. The new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Godzilla</ENAMEX> also
has no nuclear breath.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News & World Report</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 25</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 19, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            The short <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sinatra</ENAMEX>
package concludes that he was an "outstanding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thug</ENAMEX>." ... The
cover story says that the national drop in murders has been
caused by the decline of crack. The viciously addictive, lucrative drug fueled
violence in ways that other <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> don't. Smarter policing and more imprisonment
also contributed to falling crime rates. Property crime is falling because
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> carry less cash and use more car alarms. ... An article says that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern Ireland</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Protestants</ENAMEX> are leery of the
peace accord, because its amnesty provision will free many jailed <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bombers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assassins</ENAMEX>.

             

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 25</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 19, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            A long
profile of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin Netanyahu</ENAMEX> depicts him as pompous, mean, adulterous,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">arrogant</ENAMEX>, deceitful, and cheap. His key influence is his father <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benzion</ENAMEX>, a
fierce, tyrannical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectual</ENAMEX> who has nothing but suspicion and hatred for
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arabs</ENAMEX>. Conclusion: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX>'s entire goal is to preserve his own power, and he
doesn't care if that ends the peace process. The piece includes incredible
quotes about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX> from his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">allies</ENAMEX> : "He's not fooling anyone";
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> don't like such <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>"; "He is not a very trustworthy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>." ...
A piece says <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrities</ENAMEX> suck up to radio talk show <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Imus</ENAMEX> because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Imus</ENAMEX> has the power to make their books best sellers. (He's nearly
as important to book sales as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oprah Winfrey</ENAMEX>.) Many donate <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5,000</NUMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Imus</ENAMEX>'
charity in hopes that he'll tout their book. ... There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> short
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sinatra</ENAMEX> appreciations in "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Talk of the Town</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Duchin</ENAMEX> quotes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank</ENAMEX>'s advice
to him: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kid</ENAMEX>, don't waste your time with these bums. You got stardust on your
shoulders." A photo shows the shockingly ugly living <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sinatra</ENAMEX>'s '70s
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">house.</ENAMEX>

            

               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 25</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 19, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
cover stories applaud congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> for finally turning on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gingrich et al.</ENAMEX> won't cooperate with him anymore, won't be quiet about his
wrongdoing, and will make the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> election a referendum on his "political
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cynicism</ENAMEX> and ... abuse of office." ... A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> interviews <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.J. Simpson</ENAMEX>
about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simpson</ENAMEX> says that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> shouldn't waste millions
investigating <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s sex life and that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> should be excused if he did
have sex with a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>: "A <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22, 23-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> who has her mind set on a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> is more in control than the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>." ... The
editorial argues that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> foreign policy is as feckless and incoherent as it
was in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late '70s</TIMEX>. Evidence: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>'s nukes, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> negotiations
debacle, failure of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> weapon inspections, etc.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David</ENAMEX>
Plotz
            

         
      
   
