
   
   
      
         
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 22</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Nov. 22</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
editorial worries that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> economic reform is tenuous. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next two years</TIMEX>,
which are critical to a stable capitalist future, will require unwavering
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Yeltsin</ENAMEX>. A study suggests a novel form of health care:
Let your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> get sick. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Children</ENAMEX> who get illnesses like <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">malaria</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diabetes</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">asthma</ENAMEX> and aren't treated for them have more resistance to <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX> in later
life. Also, an article follows <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald's</ENAMEX> attempts to enter the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> market.
The "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Maharaja Mac</ENAMEX>" is made from mutton, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> can top it with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sauces</ENAMEX>
like "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">McMasala</ENAMEX>" and "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McImli</ENAMEX>." So far, sales are slow.

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 8</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, Nov. 21</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
story mocks movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alec Baldwin</ENAMEX>'s quest for campaign-finance reform. (He
took a bus trip through the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Northeast</ENAMEX> promoting the cause.) Problem: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Baldwin</ENAMEX>
doesn't seem to know much about the subject, or to want to talk about it. He's
contemplating a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> run. An article questions <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS News</ENAMEX>' use of former Sen.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondent</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s patriotic "essays" (on the disabled,
good sportsmanship, etc.) look suspiciously like campaign spots for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>
race. Other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> protest his free air time. Also, wary praise for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Housing and Urban Development</ENAMEX>'s new welfare-reform plan. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agency installs</ENAMEX> computers in public-housing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">projects</ENAMEX> so that jobless residents
can do telemarketing from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times Magazine</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 23</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, Nov. 20</TIMEX>)
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Benjamin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX>'s peace-through-strength <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">coalition</ENAMEX> may dominate <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> politics for
a long time. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>'s secular elite hates <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX>;
ultra-orthodox <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>, to whom he panders; and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Middle Eastern</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">North African</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">unite behind Bibi</ENAMEX>'s patriotism and distrust of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arabs</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX> says
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israelis</ENAMEX> "no longer share the values of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>--religious freedom, the
civility of political discourse, democratic values ... [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX>'s election]
was the victory of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Judaism</ENAMEX> over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>." A profile of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Webster Hubbell</ENAMEX>, the
former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adviser</ENAMEX> jailed for tax evasion, finds a sad, humbled figure.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hubbell</ENAMEX>, who still supports <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, is now a "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultant</ENAMEX>" making big bucks off
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>-referred <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>. Independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Counsel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Starr</ENAMEX> suspects the cash is
hush money. Also, a story rejects the conventional wisdom that overpopulation
is imminent. It argues that birth rates are falling across the world, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX> will soon begin to shrink.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 24</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Nov. 18</TIMEX>)
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX> on both covers.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's superior package emphasizes <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> hopes that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>'s
military will strike <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>. (Quote from senior <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX>: "We're just
waiting for him to do something stupid so we can whack him.") <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> also
runs a disturbing report from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baghdad</ENAMEX>, where <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> commando units proved their
battle-readiness by gutting a live <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> on television while chanting, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Our God</ENAMEX>,
our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>, our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>!" A nifty <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-page map in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> describes
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>'s military as seriously diminished since the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gulf War</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX>
also publishes a dispatch from a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> weapons <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspector</ENAMEX>: "[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">W</ENAMEX>]<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">hile</ENAMEX> they delayed
us from entering some <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX>, we have seen <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> burning documents and
throwing the embers into a river." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's explanation of the science of
toxic weapons trumps <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> excerpts the
forthcoming memoir of former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">bomber</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilot</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kelly Flinn</ENAMEX>, who was
discharged for adultery. She claims the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX> treated her unfairly and that
her commanding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> gave her no guidance. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX> says the case was
less about adultery and more about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flinn</ENAMEX>'s subsequent lying and cover-up. Also
in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , an essay by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Rodham Clinton</ENAMEX> argues that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
foreign aid and investment will improve human rights.

            

               Time interviews <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deborah Eappen</ENAMEX>, grieving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louise</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woodward au</ENAMEX> pair case. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eappen</ENAMEX> remains convinced of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woodward</ENAMEX>'s guilt, and is
stunned at her negligible punishment. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louise</ENAMEX> took away <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew</ENAMEX> and the judge
took away justice." Also in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> , trend-spotting: the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kabbalah</ENAMEX>, a brand of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> mysticism
employing numerology and the code-breaking of sacred texts, is drawing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrity converts</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madonna</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Roseanne</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laura Dern</ENAMEX>, among others).

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 24</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Nov. 18</TIMEX>)
            

            A story
follows the gruesome trail of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Swango</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> suspected of poisoning
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid-'80s</TIMEX>, surgical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">resident</ENAMEX> Swango
was investigated after <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> died suspiciously. Later, he was convicted of
poisoning <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">paramedic colleagues</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">arsenic</ENAMEX>. Even so, he landed subsequent
jobs as a paramedic and a medical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">resident</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> didn't thoroughly
investigate his background). In every case, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> and patients
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mysteriously</ENAMEX> fell ill or died. He's currently in jail for a minor fraud charge.
An essay examines <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Napoleon</ENAMEX>'s mixed legacy: Alone of history's great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>,
Napoleon inspires ambivalence (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> adoration, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British loathing</ENAMEX>). Conclusion:
He deserves credit for inventing the merit-based <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> and restoring glamour to
military service; criticism for destroying <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> with his self-aggrandizing,
idiotic wars.

            

               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 24</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Nov. 18</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
story blasts <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Cohen</ENAMEX> for blocking the promotion of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">General</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Terry Schwalier</ENAMEX>. Schwalier was in command of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saudi</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arabian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">barracks</ENAMEX> where a terrorist bombing killed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">airmen</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last June</TIMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> claims <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schwalier</ENAMEX> did everything right, and that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cohen</ENAMEX> simply sought a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scapegoat</ENAMEX>. A story gushes over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Largent</ENAMEX>, a former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NFL</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Largent</ENAMEX> is devoutly religious, looks like a male model, and stood <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporter</ENAMEX> of the attempted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> coup (even after it failed). An essay by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William J. Bennett</ENAMEX> condemns <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s recent comparison of gay rights
to civil rights: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Homosexuality</ENAMEX> should not be socially validated, for reasons
rooted in custom and tradition, natural law and teleology, morality and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">faith</ENAMEX>."

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nation</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 1</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Nov. 18</TIMEX>)
            

            The
cover story rails against the growing commercialization of public
television. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> now licenses tie-in products to the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Learningsmith</ENAMEX>" retail
chain; signs pre-production deals with huge <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AT&T</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US West</ENAMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>; and lets <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">underwriters</ENAMEX> announce their sponsorship with
commercial-like spots. An editorial points out that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX>'s current
naughty actions (lying, subjugating his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>, developing <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> of mass
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">destruction</ENAMEX>) earned him <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> support in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '80s</TIMEX>. Also, an editorial chides the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Smithsonian</ENAMEX> for running a rosy exhibit on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Alaskan</ENAMEX> pipeline--sponsored by,
among others, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British Petroleum</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Exxon</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pipeline</ENAMEX>'s negative
environmental impact and the ravages of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Valdez spill</ENAMEX> are downplayed.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity Fair</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 1997</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Nov. 18</TIMEX>)
            

            A
posthumous profile of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dodi Fayed</ENAMEX> says he was childish, profligate, unreliable,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">paranoid</ENAMEX>, and drug-using. His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> totally controlled him, his much-touted
involvement in film production has been wildly exaggerated, and his affair with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX> would have fallen apart, as his many other glam romances did. A story
marvels at <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">New Yorkers</ENAMEX>' conspicuous consumption, which far outdoes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '80s</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grotesque</ENAMEX> examples: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20,000</NUMEX> watches, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$14,000</NUMEX> bags, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5,800</NUMEX> bottles of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX>, and
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3,000</NUMEX> sweaters are popular items, and some thirtysomethings are purchasing
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10-million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartments</ENAMEX>-- with cash . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity Fair</ENAMEX> exhaustively
chronicles the events at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brooklyn</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">70 th precinct</NUMEX>, where the
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Plunger Cops" assaulted Abner Louima</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Bruder</ENAMEX>, one of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX>
accused, tells his story, blaming the others. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Louima</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> are depicted as
shameless money- and publicity-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">seekers</ENAMEX>. A piece about Internet gossip <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Drudge</ENAMEX> depicts him as a charming, naive young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who made a terrible mistake
in reporting that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sidney Blumenthal</ENAMEX> beat his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blumenthal</ENAMEX>'s lawsuit may well ruin <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Drudge</ENAMEX> and threaten Internet free
speech.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stevenson</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
