
   
   
      
         
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 26</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Sept. 26, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            The
cover editorial urges <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> to reform its banking system.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> must quit dithering and revive consumer confidence. If
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> sinks into depression, it will take the rest of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX> with it. The
editorial also warns <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Reserve</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Greenspan</ENAMEX> not to lower
interest rates too soon: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rate</ENAMEX> cuts are a powerful weapon, to be saved for a
true emergency. ... An editorial welcomes the growth of domestic
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">services</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">butlers</ENAMEX>, nannies, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cooks</ENAMEX>, etc. The piece pooh-poohs the notion that
this trend increases inequality. In fact, demand for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">servants</ENAMEX> helps low-skill
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> who might otherwise go jobless. ... An essay praises prewar
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> pop <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">lyricists</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cole Porter</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Irving Berlin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ira Gershwin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">et al.</ENAMEX>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hemmed</ENAMEX> in by censors and given to subtlety, these poets said "I love you"
without actually saying it. During the war and after it, directness became the
fashion, and lyrics lost their sophistication. Can any postwar song match this
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">prewar stanza</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lyricist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leon Robin</ENAMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Venus de Milo/ Was</ENAMEX> noted for her
charms/ But strictly between us/ You're cuter than <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Venus</ENAMEX>/ And what's more,
you've got arms"?

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 12</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, Sept. 25, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
story says that science increasingly tolerates faith and meaning. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Science</ENAMEX> had
become linked to the notion that the universe has no purpose, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX>
are starting to argue that scientific phenomena are more meaningful than
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">random</ENAMEX>. ... An essay says <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>'s thirst for impeachment stems
partly from a yen for parliamentary politics. Our system gridlocks when a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> becomes powerless. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> is simply ejected from office
when he or she can no longer lead, no harm done. ... "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TRB</ENAMEX>" urges
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">feminists</ENAMEX> to reconsider: Should invasions of privacy really be necessary for
sexual harassment cases? Perhaps social sanctions can stop boorish behavior
more effectively than laws can. Such a shift would enable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">feminists</ENAMEX> not to look
like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hypocrites</ENAMEX> when they defend <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times Magazine</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 27</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, Sept. 24, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Three</TIMEX>
profiles. The cover story assesses the kinder, gentler <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Steinbrenner</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yankees</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> no longer fires <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three weeks</TIMEX> into <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the season</TIMEX>, and his
relationship with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> is now intense but cordial. All
this makes for a winning <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX>. Steinbrenner may sell the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yanks</ENAMEX> soon to avoid
being the bad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who moves the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> out of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Yankee Stadium</ENAMEX>. ... A piece
on former <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Weld</ENAMEX> attributes his recent political
burnout to lack of ambition. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sharp</ENAMEX>, wry, and likable, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weld</ENAMEX> quickly sank from a
well-respected governorship to a failed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> run to a failed bid to be
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ambassador</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>. Now he's content to practice law and write mediocre
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fiction</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mackerel by Moonlight</ENAMEX> comes out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this month</TIMEX>). ... A story
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">profiles Todd Solondz</ENAMEX>, nerdy and independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of Welcome to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dollhouse</ENAMEX> and the forthcoming Happiness . Happiness shows
sympathy for a pedophile--one reason the original <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">distributor</ENAMEX> dropped it.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 28</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Sept. 22, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> move to the
"pox on all your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX>" stance. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> says that we've entered "slime
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>" in the scandal, with no one safe from partisan smears. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> agrees
and seeks an exit strategy to end the mess. Its conclusion: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> should make
a deal for censure now, before he loses even more leverage. He "faces a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">75%</NUMEX>
chance that he will be impeached by the full <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> and put on trial in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> both profile the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s new team
of spiritual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisers</ENAMEX>, including the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rev.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gordon MacDonald</ENAMEX>--a reformed
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adulterer</ENAMEX> who wrote a book about his sins. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> offers thumbnail
sketches of prominent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Judiciary Committee</ENAMEX>, the body
deciding <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s fate. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barney Frank</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mass.</ENAMEX>, will "log some of the best
sound bites," while <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Rogan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX>, "could emerge as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> for
consensus."

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> says that space tourism has a new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">proponent</ENAMEX>: former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">astronaut</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buzz</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aldrin</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aldrin</ENAMEX>'s ShareSpace <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> hopes to use jumbo<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">-jet-style spacecraft</ENAMEX> to
bring <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX> to orbiting space <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News & World Report</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 28</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Sept. 22, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            The
cover story focuses on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX>. Most of the women <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
News quotes think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> should take more of a stand, and they are
frustrated by her failure to make a statement about her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s behavior. An
accompanying poll finds that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">48 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">respondents</ENAMEX> think the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintons</ENAMEX>'
relationship is "a practical business and political relationship," while <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX>
percent deem it "a loving marriage that has troubles." ... Much praise for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s new documentary on the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX>-part
series, a pet project of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Turner</ENAMEX>, is evenhanded, thorough, and
captivating.

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 28</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Sept. 22, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            An essay
describes how <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s current woes stem from his endorsement of
laws that let <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> look into the background of accused sexual harassers.
These laws, which allowed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> to investigate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s sexual
history, were never fair. As for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>, his strategy is to "shore up a
questionable legal case with reams of graphic sexual material." ... An
interesting article goes behind the scenes in the development of a new sitcom.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">creators</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sports Night</ENAMEX> (premiering on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this fall</TIMEX>) at first
fought the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX>, refusing to include a laugh <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">track</ENAMEX> or dumb down their
script. Soon, however, they were won over to sitcom logic--the cautious
thinking that relies on past successes and renders most TV shows identical.

            More Flytrap
...

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stevenson</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
