
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Architecture
            

            
               New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amsterdam Theater</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>). For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> have derided
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>'s plans to clean up <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Times Square</ENAMEX> as mere <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disneyfication</ENAMEX>. But they are
more sanguine when it comes to the restoration of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1903</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Amsterdam</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX>. It is now "one of the grandest and most mind-bendingly ornate theaters
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, an eclectic melange of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Art Nouveau</ENAMEX> and other turn-of-the-century
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ornamentation</ENAMEX> and a triumph of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">restorer</ENAMEX>'s art," says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bruce</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Handy</ENAMEX>. Not all skepticism has been banished, however. "This <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> has the
potential to become one of the most culturally important in urban <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>. ...
Or it could simply be a bright but chuckleheaded exercise in consumerism"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herbert Muschamp</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ). (To learn more about the New
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Amsterdam,</ENAMEX> click here.)

            

               Event
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Cannes</ENAMEX>
International <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Film Festival</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>). Predictably, the film festival's
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">50 th</NUMEX> anniversary is an overhyped bash; and predictably, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">kvetch</ENAMEX>. "[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX>]he supposed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX> of honor--the films--are in danger of being
relegated to a secondary role as the free-wheeling fest becomes the real star
of the show," says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Variety</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Williams</ENAMEX>. Complaints: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) There are
too many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sylvester Stallone</ENAMEX> continues to try to win
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">acceptance</ENAMEX> as a serious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) the movies stink. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Only two</NUMEX> have received
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">acclaim: Welcome to Sarajevo</ENAMEX> , starring <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woody Harrelson</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marisa Tomei</ENAMEX>
as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> who save <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bosnian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">orphans</ENAMEX>; and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ang Lee</ENAMEX>'s adaptation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moody's</ENAMEX> The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ice Storm</ENAMEX> . Flops include The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brave</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnny Depp</ENAMEX>'s
directorial debut. (See <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cannes</ENAMEX>' surprisingly subdued official site for more on
the festivities.)

            

               Movies
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Father</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Day</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner Brothers</ENAMEX>). Despite performances by certified
funny <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin Williams</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Billy Crystal</ENAMEX> (each plays a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> convinced he is
the real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nastassja Kinski</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>), most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> say, this remake of
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1983</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> comedy <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Les Comp√</ENAMEX>®res is unfunny. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Williams</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crystal</ENAMEX> "do
the old married <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> shtick so well they should open a joint bank account"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Anderson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsday</ENAMEX> ). But the script is heavier on sentimental
musing on parenthood than it is on humor. "[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX>]hese <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> great comics are poorly
served by the picture's ... domestic respectability. Family values are fine, in
their place, but this is the wrong place" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Terrence Rafferty</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yorker</ENAMEX> ). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Maslin</ENAMEX>, however, dissents:
"[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX>]here are some slow patches and formulaic touches, but that's a fair trade
for the fun of watching Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Williams</ENAMEX> and Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crystal</ENAMEX> make an irresistible comic
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">team</ENAMEX>." (See the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Father</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Day</ENAMEX> site.)

            
               
                  The
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Fifth</NUMEX> Element
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia Pictures</ENAMEX>). The high-kitsch sci-fi blockbuster,
set in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23 rd century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> and directed by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> schlockmeister
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luc Besson</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Femme Nikita</ENAMEX> ), augurs not only the end of the world but,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> predict, the end of culture. "[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX>]he annihilation of everything <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cannes</ENAMEX>
has stood for" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Owen Gleiberman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Entertainment Weekly</ENAMEX> ). "A spectacular
triumph of style over <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">substance</ENAMEX>," says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rita</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kempley</ENAMEX>. Kudos go to its cartoonish set and the elaborate costumes by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jean-Paul</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gaultier</ENAMEX>. The plot, in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Willis</ENAMEX> and scantily clad model Milla
Jovovich save the planet, is ridiculed as even more implausible than usual.
"How can filmmakers devote <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>, even <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> of their lives to such
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">overwrought</ENAMEX>, crumbling nonsense<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Denby</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> ). (See <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edelstein</ENAMEX>'s similarly negative review. Visit The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Fifth Element</ENAMEX> site.)

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Designated Mourner</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First Look Pictures</ENAMEX>). Raves for this adaptation of
a play by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wallace Shawn</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">My Dinner With Andre</ENAMEX> ), which
features <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX> holding forth on the decay of high culture ("like
a surreal extended edition of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Charlie Rose Show</ENAMEX> ," writes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holden</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ). The script "flows along seamlessly ...
[and] has a measured elegance," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holden</ENAMEX>. Praise also goes to comedian <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nichols</ENAMEX>' film-acting debut: His "timing is flawless, his speech peppered with
strange pauses through which we grasp the full weight of his irony, derision,
and sheer incredulity at the peculiarity of the human phenomena that surround
him" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leslie Camhi</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Village Voice</ENAMEX> ). (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarah Kerr</ENAMEX>
argues that the movie is merely pretentious.)

            

               Television
            

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Odyssey</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 18 and 19</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 p.m. EDT/PDT</TIMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> trash <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Homer</ENAMEX>'s
epic-turned-sweeps-month-stunt. With a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$43 million</NUMEX> budget, it is, minute for
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minute</TIMEX>, the most expensive TV show ever, and also features a shocking amount of
sex--as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Odysseus, Armand Assante</ENAMEX> sleeps with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Penelope</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Greta Scacchi</ENAMEX>), Circe
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bernadette Peters</ENAMEX>), and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Calypso</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanessa Williams</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's Ginia
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bellafante</ENAMEX> says the show "seesaws--often uncomfortably--between earnestness and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">camp</ENAMEX>." This Odysseus "seems to be on a very long journey to find his missing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Prozac</ENAMEX>." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Watch</ENAMEX> previews and join <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Odyssey</ENAMEX> chat on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>'s site.)

            

               Books
            

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Courage to Stand Alone: Letters From Prison and Other Writings</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wei</ENAMEX>
Jingsheng, translated and edited by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kristina M. Torgeson</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Viking</ENAMEX>). Writings by
the imprisoned <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activist</ENAMEX> are granted a place "among the
classics of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 th century</TIMEX> literature of dissent, alongside the
writings of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figures</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vaclav Havel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vladmir Bukovsky</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam Michnik</ENAMEX>"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Bernstein</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ). The collection mainly consists
of letters, written from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>, pleading the case for
democracy. "[<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>]espite the impossible circumstances under which they were
written, they are an extraordinary and moving record of a courageous,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">compassionate</ENAMEX> and obstinate mind dedicated to democratic principles and the
amelioration of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s harsh fate" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judith Shapiro</ENAMEX>, the New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times Book Review</ENAMEX> ).

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Bind</ENAMEX>: When <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Work Becomes Home and Home Becomes Work</ENAMEX>
               , by Arlie
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russell Hochschild</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metropolitan Books/Henry Holt & Co.</ENAMEX>). Mostly positive
reviews for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Berkeley</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sociologist</ENAMEX>'s latest work, in which she argues that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> put in ever longer <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> at work not because they must but because they
prefer it to home. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Book Review</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicholas Lemann</ENAMEX>
praises the book: "Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hochschild</ENAMEX> writes in a calm, understanding tone that
tends to disguise how truly subversive and depressing her message is." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ann</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hulbert</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hochschild</ENAMEX> overstates her case: "The truth is that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">home</ENAMEX> hasn't
suddenly become work. It has always been work--endless work."

            

               Theater
            

            

               
                  Candide
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Gershwin Theatre</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>). Another extravagant
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">musical</ENAMEX>, more unkind reviews. For the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> time in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25 years</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harold</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prince</ENAMEX> revives the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1956</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leonard Bernstein-Lillian Hellman-Richard Wilbur</ENAMEX>
version of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Voltaire</ENAMEX>'s novel. The problem with this production: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prince</ENAMEX> sets
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Candide</ENAMEX> in a traveling carnival and includes elaborate stunts like
artificial flying <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">falcons</ENAMEX>, thereby substituting "spectacle ... for satire ...
without an iota of anarchy or inspiration," says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lahr</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben Brantley</ENAMEX> says that "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Candide</ENAMEX> is
truly one of the best of all possible musicals, but only if you close your
eyes."

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum</ENAMEX>
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newseum</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arlington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Va.</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gannett</ENAMEX>'s effort at self-aggrandizing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">philanthropy</ENAMEX> is dismissed as self-aggrandizing propaganda. Located across the
street from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newseum's</ENAMEX> collection consists
partly of artifacts from great moments in journalism (e.g., <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward R. Murrow</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">microphone</ENAMEX>) and partly of high-tech interactive games meant to depict the
workings of a newspaper (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Miracle</ENAMEX> ). "You get more feeling for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> business from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Planet</ENAMEX> panels in an old
Superman comic" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Allen</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Ferguson</ENAMEX> says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> "is a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50 million</NUMEX> testament to the terrifying
insecurity that lurks at the heart of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> journalism." (See the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newseum</ENAMEX> site.)

            

               Updates
            

            In The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louis Menand</ENAMEX> praises <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Philip Roth</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pastoral</ENAMEX>. It is about "the same irony and the same agony" as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Portnoy</ENAMEX>'s
Complaint --the excesses of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1960s</TIMEX>--but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Pastoral</ENAMEX> is
"darker, difficult, more mature."... The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly Standard</ENAMEX> 's Pia
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catton</ENAMEX> argues that the FDR
monument "misrepresents and diminishes the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>" because it lacks the
grandeur of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jefferson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> monuments. It "is as
accessible and gentle as your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">garden</ENAMEX>."

            
               Recent
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment</ENAMEX>" columns
            

            May
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7:</TIMEX>

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mason</ENAMEX> &
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dixon</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Pynchon</ENAMEX>;

            

               Book/<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Television</ENAMEX> -- <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">American Visions: The Epic History of Art in</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Hughes</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Visions</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>);

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Echo</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ward</ENAMEX> Just;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Reading</ENAMEX> in
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dark</TIMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seamus Deane</ENAMEX>;

            

               Architecture --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franklin Delano Roosevelt Memorial</ENAMEX>;

            
               Television -- The
Last <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Don</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX>);

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Children of</ENAMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Revolution</ENAMEX> ;

            

               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Breakdown</ENAMEX> .

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30:</TIMEX>

            

               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Volcano</ENAMEX> ;

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michele</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School Reunion</ENAMEX> ;

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pop</ENAMEX> -- Share My
World , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary J. Blige</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- Locked in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Reich</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- Anything
Your <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Little Heart Desires: An American Family Story</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patricia</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bosworth</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hystories</ENAMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hysterical Epidemics</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Modern Media</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elaine Showalter</ENAMEX>;

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Titanic</ENAMEX> ;

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> -- The
Little <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Foxes</ENAMEX> ;

            

               Dance --"In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Honor of the Divine</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lou Harrison</ENAMEX>," the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Morris Dance</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Group</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">23:</TIMEX>

            
               Book -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gospel</ENAMEX>
According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Son</ENAMEX>, by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman Mailer</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
Pastoral , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Philip Roth</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">W.B. Yeats</ENAMEX>:
A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Life</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apprentice Mage</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1865-1914</TIMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">R.F. Foster</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Purple</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick Moody</ENAMEX>;

            
               Television -- In the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gloaming</ENAMEX> ;

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Opera</ENAMEX> -- The Ring of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nibelung</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Murder at</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1600</TIMEX> ;

            

               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Kissed</ENAMEX> .

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">16:</TIMEX>

            
               Art --"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Picasso: The</ENAMEX>

            

               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Anaconda</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grosse</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Pointe Blank</ENAMEX> ;

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> -- An
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Daughter</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Naked</ENAMEX> ,
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Sedaris</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blue</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flower</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Penelope Fitzgerald</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- Gut
Symmetries , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeanette Winterson</ENAMEX>;

            

               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Inventions</ENAMEX> of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> Hare: Poems <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1909-1917</TIMEX> , by T.S.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eliot</ENAMEX>, edited by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Ricks</ENAMEX>.

            

               --Compiled by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Franklin Foer</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> .
            

         
      
   
