
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Books
            

            

               
                  Personal History
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katharine Graham</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Knopf</ENAMEX>). Nobody has
anything negative to say about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">owner</ENAMEX>'s
autobiography. The reviews differ only in emphasis. Some argue that the "iron
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">lady"</ENAMEX> spins an inspirational feminist tale--"the story of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pioneer</ENAMEX>," says the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Lehmann-Haupt</ENAMEX>. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jill Ker Conway</ENAMEX> says the book throws more light on the "psychology of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, and the profound changes brought by the women's movement, than a dozen
tomes filled with psychological jargon." Others are drawn to the gossipy
details (did <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Graham</ENAMEX> really sleep with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adlai Stevenson</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night</TIMEX> before he
died?) and her candor (on such subjects as her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s suicide). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Zoglin</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Graham</ENAMEX> chronicles her life with
"more honest self-analysis than probably any other media <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mogul</ENAMEX> ever." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Random House</ENAMEX> touts the book at its site.)

            

               
                  What It Means to Be a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Libertarian: A Personal Interpretation</ENAMEX>
               , by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Murray</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Broadway Books</ENAMEX>). Has <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Murray</ENAMEX> persuasively reconciled the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> conflicting traditions in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> conservatism--faith in the free market
and faith in tradition? In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Krauthammer</ENAMEX> says
"yes." Subsequent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX> disagree. "[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX>]<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">o editor</ENAMEX> has asked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX> to address
the tricky questions that are customarily lobbed at the high school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">junior</ENAMEX> who
reads his first <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ayn Rand</ENAMEX> novel," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Ledbetter</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Village</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Voice</ENAMEX> . "Libertarianism of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX>'s variety is a philosophy for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">winners</ENAMEX>, for
the same reason that 'Born <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Free</ENAMEX>' is a song about <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">lions</ENAMEX>, not the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> they
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">prey on</ENAMEX>," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louis Menand</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Review of</ENAMEX> 
               Books , also
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">savaging Murray</ENAMEX>'s facts and his logic. Even the conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> is skeptical: "The sheer magnitude of the problems that government
now fumbles with may militate against" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX>'s vision of private efforts
filling the void. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> was unimpressed as well. See <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weisberg</ENAMEX>'s review. Read excerpts of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX>'s book at his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publisher</ENAMEX>'s site.)

            
               
                  Do
the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Windows Open</ENAMEX>?
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julie Hecht</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Random House</ENAMEX>). Yet another
self-obsessed, neurotic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">narrator</ENAMEX> ("<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diane Keaton</ENAMEX> playing a health-food fiend
addicted to <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Xanax</ENAMEX>"--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michiko Kakutani</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ) makes her
debut in a collection of short stories. But the paranoid rantings of an <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">East</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hampton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">photographer</ENAMEX> are said to transcend shtick. "She's like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">naturalist</ENAMEX> at
a tide pool, but instead of examining shrimp and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sand crabs</ENAMEX>, she tracks loss,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">entropy</ENAMEX> and the ravages of aging," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laurie Stone</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Village</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Voice</ENAMEX> . In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Book Review</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Frank</ENAMEX> says that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hecht</ENAMEX> writes some of the "freshest and loveliest colloquial speech to grace
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> fiction in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time</TIMEX>."

            

               Movies
            

            

               
                  Gridlock'd
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Polygram Filmed Entertainment/Gramercy Pictures</ENAMEX>). The
last movie starring slain rapper <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tupac Shakur</ENAMEX> ( Juice , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Poetic</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX> ) is deemed an authentic portrayal of junkie life. The twist: The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">villain</ENAMEX> is the welfare system. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Addicts Shakur</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Roth</ENAMEX> want to kick their
habit but are stymied by unhelpful social-service <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reviewers</ENAMEX> also
seize the opportunity to imbue <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shakur</ENAMEX>'s meager oeuvre with an aura of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Dean</ENAMEX>-ish tragedy. Gridlock'd , in particular, bespeaks unfulfilled
potential. Then there is the "perplexing chasm [that] separated the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> Tupac
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shakurs</ENAMEX>": the gangsta rapper (bad <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tupac</ENAMEX>) and empathetic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> (good <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tupac</ENAMEX>)
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Corliss</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>). The wistful conclusion: "[<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">P</ENAMEX>]erhaps films would have
allowed him to evade the gangsta rap typecasting forced on him by the music
industry" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Harrington</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX>). (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here for the official Gridlock'd site.)

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Waiting for Guffman</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Castle Rock/Sony Pictures Classics</ENAMEX>). A
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mockumentary</ENAMEX>--same genre, same <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">producers</ENAMEX>, and some of the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> as
This Is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spinal Tap</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1984</TIMEX>), though on a different topic: the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">musical</ENAMEX> and amateur theatrics. Reviews praise <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Guffman</ENAMEX> 's spoofs of show
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tunes</ENAMEX> and its <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">digs</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Midwestern</ENAMEX> life, but rate it a notch below the cult
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">classic</ENAMEX>. "The subject may not be as universal as loud music played badly," says
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Wloszczyna</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Guffman</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX> has stills and video.)

            

               Art
            

            

               "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Willem de Kooning: The Late Paintings, the 1980s"</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum of Modern</ENAMEX>
Art, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>). Is the abstract <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">expressionist</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">late work a last hurrah</TIMEX>, in the
tradition of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matisse</ENAMEX>'s paper cutouts? Is it senile doodling? Or is it a cynical
scheme perpetrated by his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ex-wife</ENAMEX> and assistants to force an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alzheimer</ENAMEX>'s-afflicted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> to turn out schlock for cash? <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> are
titillated by the biographical mysteries surrounding <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">de Kooning</ENAMEX>'s 1980s
paintings, but maintain a genteel focus on the paintings themselves.
Conclusion: The paintings are shockingly genteel, too. New 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York</ENAMEX> 's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Stevens</ENAMEX> perceives transcendental old-age art about old age itself: "[H]e
seems to empty out his art, like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who wants to give everything away
before he dies." The 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Calvin Tomkins</ENAMEX> finds such
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">serenity</ENAMEX> incongruous with the rest of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">de Kooning</ENAMEX>'s career: "What's missing is
the melodrama of vulgarity. The messy, vicious slathers of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pigment</ENAMEX>, the
turbulence and turmoil ... [are the] essential elements of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">de Kooning</ENAMEX>'s
greatness." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MoMA's</ENAMEX> site plugs the show.)

            

               Theater
            

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Men</ENAMEX>
Are <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">From Mars, Women Are From Venus</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gershwin Theater</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>).
"About as entertaining as having <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> drawn," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Marks</ENAMEX> in a vicious
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> pan of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Gray</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX> show (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> monologue, half
audience participation) based on his best-selling advice book about gender
roles and personal growth. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> dismiss it as tedious psychobabble. But,
says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Variety</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg Evans</ENAMEX>, "[j]udging by his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> in attendance (mostly
young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couples</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> nudging one another and mouthing, 'That is so
true')," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gray</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Elmer Gantry</ENAMEX> routine "seems to work."

            

               Event
            

            
               "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">On</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cultural Power</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilson-Brustein Discussion</ENAMEX> ," moderated by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anna</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deavere Smith</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Town Hall</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> hyped the face-off between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> theater <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Brustein</ENAMEX> and black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">playwright</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">August Wilson</ENAMEX>
over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afrocentric</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">theater</ENAMEX> as "the intellectual version of extreme fighting"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Rich</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ). But the debate was judged to be a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">flop</ENAMEX>--lots of combative bravado and little payoff. "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> humorless and often
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">petty</ENAMEX> egomaniacs intransigently reiterated their familiar positions"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rich</ENAMEX>).

            

               Updates
            

            
               New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Denby</ENAMEX> joins in the general celebration of the film Kolya
and its accompanying Czechophilia: "The movie speaks quietly, in the
chamber-music tones of ... [a] <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dvorak</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">quartet</ENAMEX>." ... The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Podhoretz</ENAMEX> blasts Everyone
Says I Love You: "Why would <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woody Allen</ENAMEX> willingly make a movie that
resembles nothing so much as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Springtime</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> , the deliberately bad
show at the center of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mel Brooks</ENAMEX>'s classic comedy The 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Producers</ENAMEX> ?"
... 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stevens</ENAMEX> turns up the volume on the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tiepolo hype: Tiepolo</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">paints</ENAMEX> as a stylish swordsman might kill,
with a flashing wrist; he gives us flourishes, a kind of
whistling-through-the-air bravura, as if to say, 'Of course! It is easy,
nothing. I was born a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX>.' " (See also <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Benfey</ENAMEX>'s review in
Slate of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tiepolo</ENAMEX>
exhibits.)

            
               Recent
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment</ENAMEX>" columns:
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">29:</TIMEX>

            
               Art --"Giambattista
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tiepolo</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1696-1770</TIMEX>";

            
               Event --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Halftime</ENAMEX> at
<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Super Bowl</ENAMEX> XXXI;

            

               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kolya</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Island of</ENAMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Colorblind</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oliver Sacks</ENAMEX>;

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> -- The
Steward of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Christendom</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- Fierce
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Creatures</ENAMEX> ;

            

               Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Le Divorce</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diane Johnson</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">22:</TIMEX>

            
               Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Behind the</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oval Office</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Winning the Presidency</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nineties</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dick Morris</ENAMEX>;

            
               Movie -- The Whole
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wide World</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Event --The
Inauguration of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Jefferson Clinton</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- One World</ENAMEX>,
Ready or Not: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Manic Logic of Global Capitalism</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William B.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Greider</ENAMEX>;

            
               CD -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Idomeneo</ENAMEX> ,
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart</ENAMEX>, performed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Placido Domingo</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metropolitan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Opera Orchestra</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chorus</ENAMEX>, conducted by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Levine</ENAMEX>;

            
               Movie -- Albino
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Alligator</ENAMEX> ;

            

               Television -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Naked Truth</ENAMEX> .

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">15:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cérémonie</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Book -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prospect</ENAMEX>
Before <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Her: A History of Women</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Western Europe</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1500-1800</TIMEX> , by Olwen
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hufton</ENAMEX>;

            
               Television -- King
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX> ;

            

               Architecture --<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Tokyo International Forum</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beavis</ENAMEX> and
Butt-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Head</ENAMEX> Do <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slouching</ENAMEX> to
Gomorrah: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Modern Liberalism</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Decline</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Bork</ENAMEX>;

            

               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Politically Incorrect With Bill Maher</ENAMEX> ;

            

               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mother</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- Some
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mother's Son</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dior: The Man Who Made the World Look New</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marie-France Pochna</ENAMEX>,
translated by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joanna Savill</ENAMEX>;

            

               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yves Saint Laurent</ENAMEX>: A <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Biography</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alice Rawsthorn</ENAMEX>.

            
               --Compiled by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Franklin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foer</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> .
            

         
      
   
