
   
   
      
         
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 25</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Oct. 25</TIMEX>)
            

            A cover
editorial praises <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> for softening his policy toward <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>. He once
threatened to withhold <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MFN</ENAMEX>; now he engages <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> through trade. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Engagement,</ENAMEX>
coupled with an active military presence in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Far East</ENAMEX>, will keep <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> from
endangering the world. A story recommends that baseball <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> share television
revenue. Currently, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> in small television markets can't afford to pay great
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> and thus can't compete. An essay lauds the creative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">charity</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Soros</ENAMEX>, who eschews boring gifts to wealthy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museums</ENAMEX>. Instead <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Soros</ENAMEX>
funds drug decriminalization, immigration reform, and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Eastern European</ENAMEX>
democracy--projects that may change society. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Utterly Predictable Department</ENAMEX>: A
review showers yet more praise on the universally acclaimed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guggenheim Museum</ENAMEX>
in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bilbao</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 10</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, Oct. 24</TIMEX>)
            

            An
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UNICEF</ENAMEX> doesn't deserve your <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Halloween</TIMEX> money. Donations feed its
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">wasteful</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bureaucracy</ENAMEX>, not starving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. A story mocks <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s burgeoning
dread of germs. New, incredibly popular "antibacterial" products rely on fear
to boost sales, yet are largely ineffective in fighting <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacteria</ENAMEX>. The piece
also notes that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacteria</ENAMEX> aren't so dangerous that we need to be constantly
paranoid about them. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TRB</ENAMEX>" urges <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> to embrace school vouchers. The poor
should be able to flee bad <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> just like the rich, and the competition will
strengthen public education.

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times Magazine</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 26</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, Oct. 23</TIMEX>)
            

            A cover
story ponders the medical and ethical issues raised by post-menopausal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pregnancies</ENAMEX>. Thanks to donated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eggs</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sperm</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in their <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">60s</NUMEX> now can give
birth. Older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> face high health risks and, as they become <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elderly</ENAMEX>, might
not be up to the job of parenting. It's just plain unnatural, some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> say.
A feature story says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Detroit Piston Grant Hill</ENAMEX> is ready to dominate <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX>.
The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fourth-year</TIMEX> forward hopes to shed his deferential reputation: "I think I
can be the best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBA</ENAMEX>, and I want to show it."

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 27</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Oct. 21</TIMEX>)
            

            School's in at both
magazines. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's cover package considers "what makes a good <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>."
Recommendations: good after-school programs, lots of computers, smaller
classes, and higher standards for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> also tracks the
growing popularity of school vouchers among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> in
inner <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> hope to attract black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> with the issue.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's cover story explores how <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> handle learning
disabilities. Early diagnosis, new teaching techniques (emphasis on the arts,
thematic programs), and new research into the brains of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LD</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are starting to
rectify a neglected problem. Shocking stat: "[A]s <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">many as 20 percent</NUMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">schoolchildren</ENAMEX> may have a neurological deficit, ranging from mild to severe,
that makes it hard for them to read and write."

            
               Time interviews <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang Zemin</ENAMEX>. When <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>
asks if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang</ENAMEX> should make a "gesture on human rights" to ease relations with
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang</ENAMEX> replies: "I would like to know what you refer to specifically as
a gesture. We have made it clear that we respect human rights." A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>
investigation finds that nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> neglect <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Seniors</ENAMEX> have died of thirst and starvation; some <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> are crawling with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">maggots</ENAMEX>.

            In
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Quayle</ENAMEX> derides <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>'s recent praise for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellen</ENAMEX> :
"By paying homage both to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> and to the gay <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lobby</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> has beaten
his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">rivals</ENAMEX> to the cash machine." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quayle</ENAMEX> does give <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> points for recognizing
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>'s power to shape culture. Also in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , drug-of-<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last-week</TIMEX>
ketamine, or "Special <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX>" (see <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>), gives way to drug-of-<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this-week</TIMEX> gamma
hydroxybutyrate, known as "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">GHB" or "Grievous Bodily Harm</ENAMEX>." The
inhibition-lowering <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemical</ENAMEX> is catching on at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>, and has been linked to
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least 20</NUMEX> deaths.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News & World Report</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 27</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Oct. 21</TIMEX>)
            

            "The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Career Guide</ENAMEX>" says hot
career paths include: animator, crisis <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">specialist</ENAMEX>, corrections <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX>,
grief therapist, and cosmetic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dentist</ENAMEX>. A companion piece notes that a growing number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> pay full
salaries for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four-day</TIMEX> workweeks. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Four-day</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> are actually more
productive in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>. A story argues that the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is dumbing down
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> culture. An "art for everyone" policy pitches opera to soccer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> and
adds prurient plot lines to once-staid radio shows. Also, an article predicts that smart cards, a microchip-laden credit/debit
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">card</ENAMEX>, already popular in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, will soon catch on in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>: "In theory, a
single smart card could replace a fistful of credit and debit cards, serve as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">driver</ENAMEX>'s license, store a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s medical history, feed a parking <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">meter</NUMEX>, and
function as a tamperproof personal ID encoded with an individual's
fingerprint."

            

               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 27</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Oct. 21</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
essay lambastes the talk show <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Politically Incorrect</ENAMEX> for its inane
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">discourse</ENAMEX>: "The pace is plodding, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX> struggle to figure out
what it is they're talking about." A story concludes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vincent Foster</ENAMEX>
committed suicide, and that the conspiracy theories hold no water. The real
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cover-up</ENAMEX> was the post-suicide removal of documents from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Foster</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>. Also,
an editorial condemns <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> for avoiding the accelerating fight against
racial preferences: "It won't do for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> to delay the prize of
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">colorblindness</ENAMEX>, even for a moment, by silently ignoring the battle while it's
waged."

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harper</ENAMEX>'s , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 1997</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, Oct. 16</TIMEX>)
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harper</ENAMEX>'s runs <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> newly discovered short stories by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anton Chekhov</ENAMEX>.
Written during a feverish tuberculosis fit when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chekhov</ENAMEX> was in his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early 20s</TIMEX>,
titles include: "On the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Train</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Sarah Bernhardt Comes to Town</ENAMEX>," "From the
Diary of an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Assistant Bookkeeper</ENAMEX>," and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Elements Most Often Found in Novels</ENAMEX>,
Short <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Stories</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Etc.</ENAMEX>" A story reports from a funeral <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">convention</ENAMEX>--they
see big business in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of aging <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby boomers</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hot</ENAMEX> cremation stat: "[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX>]he
average <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> takes <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an hour and a half</TIMEX> to burn.") A book review calls
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Underworld Don DeLillo</ENAMEX>'s best work. Among his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contemporaries</ENAMEX>, DeLillo
"is the shrewdest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">observer</ENAMEX> of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> and the purest and most native
prose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stylist</ENAMEX>." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter Kirn</ENAMEX>'s review of the book in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>.)

            

               --Compiled by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seth Stevenson</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> .
            

         
      
   
