
   
   
      
         
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 18</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, April 18</TIMEX>)
            

            The
cover editorial warns that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> stocks are severely
overvalued. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Reserve Board</ENAMEX> should raise interest rates now to
prevent a horrible crash <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later</TIMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ominously</ENAMEX>, merger mania is usually associated
with the final stages of a bull market." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to read a

                  Slate
                "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dialogue</ENAMEX>" between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Bork</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor M. Fox</ENAMEX> on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">megamergers</ENAMEX>.) ... A story claims the cellular phone boom is the bane of
radio astronomers. Cell phones interfere with radio frequencies and force
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> to develop complicated countermeasures, wasting precious research
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> and funds.

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 4</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, April 17</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
story says we can't stop global warming, so we should just adapt to it. One
problem: Environmental <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> are so obsessed with alternative <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fuels</ENAMEX> that they
"pressure against any research that would render fossil <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fuel</ENAMEX> use benign."
... A story uncovers a new real-estate scheme. First, buy
environmentally sensitive land and start raping it. Then, wait for eco-friendly
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> to pressure the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> into buying the land--at an inflated price.
It's worked for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">redwood groves</ENAMEX>, land in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> desert, and forests next to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yellowstone</ENAMEX>. ... An article discovers a new literary enfant
terrible : <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Muammar Qaddafi</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Libyan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>'s new Escape to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hell</ENAMEX> and
Other <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Stories</ENAMEX> rants at a fictional land called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Amelica</ENAMEX>" in prose that is
"turgid." Who wrote the introduction? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TWA</ENAMEX> 800 conspiracy-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">theorist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pierre</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salinger</ENAMEX>, who thinks economic sanctions against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Libya</ENAMEX> are unfair.

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times Magazine</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 19</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, April 16</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
story reports on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> war-crime trials in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">The Hague</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Netherlands</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Serb</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">defendants</ENAMEX>' excuses: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) they weren't aware of the concentration <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camps</ENAMEX> that
killed and tortured <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camps</ENAMEX> started out innocently and then got
out of hand; or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3</NUMEX>) they killed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX> because they anticipated a murderous
onslaught by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX>. Hazy international law makes the tribunals "the legal
equivalent of gathering <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from all over the world to put on a play in
Esperanto that no one has really learned." ... A story says the
fast-food industry no longer innovates--the only way to grab market share is to
steal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX>' specialties (e.g., the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big King</ENAMEX> replicates the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Mac</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald's</ENAMEX> forthcoming MBX <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">burger</ENAMEX> copies the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whopper</ENAMEX>). ... An essay
urges <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">New Yorkers</ENAMEX> to adopt pro-civility measures instituted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bogotá</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colombia</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bogotá</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX> flash cards with a thumbs-up or thumbs-down
logo at fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">motorists</ENAMEX>, and government-hired street mimes mock litterers and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">jaywalkers</ENAMEX>.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity Fair</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 1998</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, April 16</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
profile makes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Seinfeld</ENAMEX> seem quite charming, if a tad immature. Post-show,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seinfeld</ENAMEX> plans to take time off, swim with <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dolphins</ENAMEX>, and then start an ad
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">boutique</ENAMEX> (he wrote his own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Express</ENAMEX> ads). The article is supposedly an
"exclusive ... behind-the-scenes report on the final episodes": Someone should
tell <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> (see below). ... A piece describes the alarming
world of executive kidnappings. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gangs</ENAMEX> routinely kidnap rich
foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> and demand <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">multimillion-dollar</NUMEX> ransoms. A counterkidnapping
industry now exists--you pay insurance, they handle negotiations and the drop.
Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">execs</ENAMEX> pay a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$60,000</NUMEX> "vaccination" directly to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">gangs</ENAMEX> to avoid a future
kidnapping. ... An essay mourns <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">feminists</ENAMEX>' sellout to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Feminists</ENAMEX> ignore <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s heinous behavior because they belong to the
establishment and are friendly with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX> on male behavior
has been substantially lowered, and this is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">feminists</ENAMEX>' own fault.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 20</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, April 14</TIMEX>)
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Easter</ENAMEX>-pegged
cover: the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shroud of Turin</ENAMEX>. Yes, it's still fake. But many
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">believers</ENAMEX>, including some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX>, continue to deny the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">carbon</ENAMEX>-dating
procedures that identify the shroud as a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">14 th</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">century</TIMEX> product. A
counterclaim: <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Bacteria</ENAMEX> growing on the shroud throws off the dating process.
Shroud tidbit: The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> wrapped in the shroud was crucified through the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">wrists</ENAMEX> (consistent with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Roman</ENAMEX> practice), not through the hands. ...

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> puts <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seinfeld</ENAMEX> 's cast on the cover. An "exclusive" behind
the scenes look at the filming of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seinfeld</ENAMEX> 's final episode reveals
little, since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> signed nondisclosure agreements.

            Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> explain the new <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX>
drug <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Tamoxifen</ENAMEX>. It drastically reduces breast <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> rates but increases the
chance of blood clots and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">uterine cancer</ENAMEX>. The drug only makes sense for those
already at high risk. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> does a better job of explaining how the drug
works.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Excite</ENAMEX> is trying to challenge Yahoo! as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Netizens</ENAMEX>'
"portal" of choice. Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> want to provide news, shopping, chat <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX>,
and entertainment. Both also fear <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft Start</ENAMEX>, a portal site to be launched
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later this year</TIMEX>.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News & World Report</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 20</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, April 14</TIMEX>)
            

            The
cover story hypes the impending arrival of high-definition
television. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Digital</ENAMEX> HDTV really is a technological breakthrough, featuring
incredible images and audio, but the sets cost <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$7,000 to $12,000</NUMEX>. The
government requires a wholesale switch to digital broadcasting by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2006</TIMEX>,
rendering your current TV set useless (or, at least, more useless). ...
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Patrick Moynihan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.Y.</ENAMEX>, pens a piece explaining his new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> plan. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moynihan</ENAMEX> favors
letting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> move up to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2 percent</NUMEX> of their wages into private accounts but
wants to maintain the "basic structure" of the program. ... A story covers the emerging science of cargo drift studies.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Oceanographers</ENAMEX> predict where and when goods lost at sea will wash ashore.
Recent treasures: hockey gloves, shoes, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legos</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 20</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, April 14</TIMEX>)
            

            An
appreciation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman Mailer</ENAMEX>--pegged to the release of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Time of Our</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> , a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,300</NUMEX> page <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Mailer</ENAMEX> anthology--calls him the "most lavishly gifted of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> postwar <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>." He lost favor in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '70s</TIMEX> because he rejected "irony
and postmodernist play" and "remained a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Balzacian</ENAMEX> social chronicler." At <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">75</NUMEX>,
he's still tough and barrel-chested, but he drinks and brags less. ...
An essay about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">50 th</NUMEX> birthday warns that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> is
dividing against itself, fragmenting into <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Orthodox</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ethiopian</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX>,
Sephardic, and Ashkenazi interest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>. But it's still the only place where
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> can really belong. ... <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">In "Talk of the Town</ENAMEX>," more conspiracy
theorizing from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> of an assassinated '60s icon. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A week</TIMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Martin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luther King Jr.</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> petitioned the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX> to reopen the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Earl Ray</ENAMEX> file, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sean Lennon</ENAMEX> alleges that the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1981</TIMEX> murder of his father
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX> may not have been the work of lone <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gunman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark David Chapman</ENAMEX> but the
result of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> plot. "It was in the best interest of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> to have my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> killed."

            

               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 20</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, April 14</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
package slams the tobacco deal and the persecution of both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">smokers</ENAMEX> and the
tobacco industry. The deal essentially raises taxes on working-class <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>,
with the proceeds to fund unspecified social-spending programs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Smokers</ENAMEX> make an
individual choice that hurts no one else: The risk of secondhand smoke has been
exaggerated and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">smokers</ENAMEX> actually save <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> costs by dying younger.
An accompanying piece says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> waste huge amounts of time indoctrinating
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> about <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco</ENAMEX>'s evils. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Kids</ENAMEX> are now routinely assigned classwork on
the horrors of smoking. ... A story argues that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> has never been
"less imperialist, less militarized, less threatening to its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> and the
world, and more receptive to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Western</ENAMEX> ideals and practices than it is in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>."
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> must continue to fight the temptations of nationalism.

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nation</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 27</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, April 14</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
story identifies the latest drug to endanger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>: caffeine. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Youngsters</ENAMEX> drink
huge amounts of highly caffeinated sodas (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coke</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mountain Dew</ENAMEX>) and hang out at
local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Starbucks</ENAMEX> (which serve all ages), getting hooked on the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX>. Caffeine
makes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> hyperactive and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">moody</ENAMEX> and can weaken their bones. ... An
editorial blasts public-school uniforms. Uniforms discriminate against girls
(who must wear impractical skirts), cost money to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> (who still must buy
play clothes) and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> (who must provide uniforms for poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>), and
have not been shown to improve academic performance or behavior.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stevenson</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
