
   
   
      
         
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 20 and Dec. 27</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Dec. 20</TIMEX>)
            

            A <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> double issue.
The lead editorial stresses the severity of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX>'s financial problems and
asserts that they could well spread to the rest of the world. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">solution</ENAMEX>? As always, the free market: <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX>
shouldn't block capital flows or choke the money supply. An article says
current forecasts of ecological doom are greatly exaggerated. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Environmentalists</ENAMEX>
have long predicted the imminent exhaustion of fossil <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fuels</ENAMEX>, but there are more
oil reserves now than ever. (See 
                  Slate
               's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Motley Fool</ENAMEX>"
on how technology is aiding oil exploration.) A story says <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> are
getting fatter (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">54.4 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">overweight</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">22.5 percent</NUMEX> are obese).
The causes: <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> eat more, exercise less, and increasingly tolerate
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tubbiness</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Read</ENAMEX> 
                  Slate
               's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dialogue</ENAMEX>" on
fat.) Also, a story looks at what the world laughs at. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Blondes</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> are globally funny, but regional humor persists. A newly rich <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russian</ENAMEX>
crashes his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mercedes</ENAMEX> and starts wailing about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>: " 'How can you worry
about your <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>,' asks a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">passer-by</NUMEX>, 'when your arm is ripped off?' The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russian</ENAMEX>
looks at his stump and bawls: 'My Rolex!' "

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 5</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 19</TIMEX>)
            

            A story
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rages at William Bennett</ENAMEX>'s assertion that the average life expectancy for gay
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">43 years</TIMEX>. The figure is false, the source of the figure is a wacko, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX>'s conclusion that homosexuality should be discouraged is abhorrent.
(For 
                  Slate
               's take, see "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Bennett</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gays</ENAMEX>,
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Truth</ENAMEX>.") The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican Party</ENAMEX>'s opposition to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Lann Lee</ENAMEX> and
skepticism about immigration have alienated once-friendly <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>, says an
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX> won the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> vote by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">27</NUMEX> points in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX> won
it by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only five</NUMEX> points in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>. A story questions the heroism of the
much-honored "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hollywood Ten</ENAMEX>." These blacklist <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>, who refused to squeal on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX>, were untroubled by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stalin</ENAMEX>'s murderous reign and benefited from the
capitalist system they denounced.

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times Magazine</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 21</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 18</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
story questions the motives of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">conservatives</ENAMEX> fighting persecution of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christians</ENAMEX>
overseas. These <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">evangelists</ENAMEX> (e.g., the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Family Research Council</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Bauer</ENAMEX>) accuse secular human-rights <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> of class bias (the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">seculars</ENAMEX> back <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tibetan Buddhists</ENAMEX> but not <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christians</ENAMEX> oppressed by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>).
Human-rights <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> hate the implied assertion of Christianity's supremacy. An
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> profiles a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientist</ENAMEX> who fights <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> with the common <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cold</ENAMEX> virus.
Also, a story exposes the incredible power of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drug lords</ENAMEX>. Drug
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traffickers</ENAMEX> and narcopoliticians are buying police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> and murdering nosy
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX>.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 22</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 16</TIMEX>)
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Princess Di</ENAMEX> decorates the
covers of both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX>' <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year-end</TIMEX> photo issues. (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Question: Does this</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">disqualify Di</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Woman of the Year</ENAMEX> honor <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX>?)
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's photos are better and more numerous. The mags share several
identical images (starving <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">North Koreans</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hale-Bopp</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evander Holyfield</ENAMEX>'s
mangled ear).

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> publishes
obits for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> of this annus horribilis . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deng Xiaoping</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willem</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">de Kooning</ENAMEX> get a paragraph each; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Di</ENAMEX> gets a few pages. Also, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">trashes Disney</ENAMEX>'s forays into professional-sports ownership. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anaheim Angels</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Mighty Ducks</ENAMEX> offer entertaining sideshows (mascots, food <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dancers</ENAMEX>)
but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> stink, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> say that's all that matters.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> runs <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> anti-emotion articles. An essay accompanying the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year-end</TIMEX> photo roundup labels this
the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Show Us You Care</ENAMEX>" year, mocking the outpourings of feeling at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Di</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">funeral</ENAMEX>, at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Promise Keepers</ENAMEX> rally, and on countless talk shows. Another
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">essay</ENAMEX> argues that healing racism requires civility and
restraint, not the self-expression of a "national conversation."

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News & World Report</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 22</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 16</TIMEX>)
            

            The
cover story counters the popular wisdom that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">millionaires</ENAMEX> are the
leading <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">philanthropists</ENAMEX>. In fact, middle-class <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX> are increasingly active
and generous. Community <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cleveland Foundation</ENAMEX> are "the
fastest-growing element of philanthropy," and let small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX> make powerful
collective gifts. An article finds a new use for DNA technology: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientist</ENAMEX> wants
to determine if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Jefferson</ENAMEX> fathered black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> (a long-standing
controversy). Soon we'll know for sure. Also, more
praise for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>' new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Getty Center</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> tries to incorporate
all <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">L.A.</ENAMEX>'s subcultures, and features interactive exhibits to keep <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
interested.

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 22 & 29</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 16</TIMEX>)
            

            A special
fiction issue, The 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> 's <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>, includes
stories by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nick Hornby</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alice Munro</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Kesey</ENAMEX> writes a short sketch about
drinking on skid row. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> profiles the difficult, brilliant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">James</ENAMEX>
Thackara, who has written an <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,100</NUMEX>-page novel about <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX> and likens
himself to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tolstoy</ENAMEX>. He finished the book in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX> but hasn't yet published it.
Why? His manuscript needs editing--the parts that aren't <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX> are wooden--and
he refuses to be edited.

            

               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 22</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 16</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
story calls <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Family Research Council</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Bauer</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>'s most
formidable conservative." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralph Reed</ENAMEX>'s retirement from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian Coalition</ENAMEX>
has made the pugnacious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX> the leading social-conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activist</ENAMEX>. He has
won plaudits for his tough anti-China stance. He probably won't run for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> (a persistent rumor), but he will force <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> to heed
his demands. A piece about the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kyoto</ENAMEX> summit argues that we would do better to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">clean</ENAMEX> our "microenvironments" than to deal with greenhouse <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gases</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ensuring</ENAMEX>
supplies of clean <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> is a much more fundamental project than
hashing out unenforceable international pollution laws. An article says the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Library Association</ENAMEX> is encouraging Internet porn: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">association</ENAMEX>,
citing the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">First Amendment</ENAMEX>, refuses to endorse "content filters" for
Web-equipped library computers.

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nation</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 29</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 16</TIMEX>)
            

            The
cover story salutes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX> presses. Less profit-motivated
than major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publishers</ENAMEX>, university presses put out the regional titles and
modest books that the trade presses ignore. One criticism: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX> presses
aren't the mouthpieces for the academic left that they used to be. An editorial signals <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Nation</ENAMEX> 's early support for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gephardt</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> presidential run. While acknowledging <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gephardt</ENAMEX>'s weaknesses
(he's a "career <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX>" posing as a "populist tribune"), the piece claims
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gephardt</ENAMEX> has a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> agenda--something the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> lacks.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wired</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 1998</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 16</TIMEX>)
            

            The
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX>-anniversary issue includes rosy essays from various cyberpundits: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">One</ENAMEX>
predicts an Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1 billion</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>. Another argues
that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past five years</TIMEX> have been the greatest in human history (due to
advances in health and quality of life). Also, the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">State of the Planet 1998</ENAMEX>"
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">section</ENAMEX> features a series of bizarre images overlaid with haikus from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> or quotes from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laurie Anderson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Noam Chomsky</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grove</ENAMEX>. (For example, a picture of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> with tubes coming out of her head is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">captioned</ENAMEX>, "Technology is the campfire around which we tell our stories.")

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stevenson</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
