
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Television
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Jefferson</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 18 and 19</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 p.m. EST</TIMEX>). Unlike <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burns</ENAMEX>' other epic documentaries ( <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Civil War</ENAMEX> was <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nine hours</TIMEX> long and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">Baseball</ENAMEX> , <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX>), his biography of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> is a brief three
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX>. In every other respect, however, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> find it numbingly familiar.
"The usual skillful <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burns</ENAMEX> package of period music ... lush photography ...
almost prurient avidity for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grainy</ENAMEX> feel of sacred relics ... and
delighted-to-be-here voice-overs" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Leonard</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> ). "At times
you may feel you've tuned into a commercial for Colonial interiors or an online
flower show" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter Goodman</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burns</ENAMEX> earns muted
praise for his evenhanded if inconclusive portrait of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jefferson</ENAMEX>, particularly
for his treatment of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sally Hemings</ENAMEX> question and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jefferson</ENAMEX>'s
contradiction-riddled approach toward slavery. (For more on the scholarly
debate surrounding the current <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jefferson</ENAMEX> craze, see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Greenberg</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">High Concept</ENAMEX>." Also
see the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> page
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">touting Thomas Jefferson</ENAMEX> .)

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Emma</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A&E</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 21</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 p.m. EST</TIMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> exempt the latest
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane Austen</ENAMEX> adaptation from the general backlash against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane Austen</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">adaptations</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kate Beckinsale</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emma</ENAMEX> is judged superior to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gwyneth Paltrow's</ENAMEX> in
the movie released <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beckinsale</ENAMEX> version is darker and less
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">accessible</ENAMEX>," says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sarah Lyall</ENAMEX>.

            

               Movies
            

            

               
                  Absolute Power
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Castle Rock Entertainment</ENAMEX>). Despite a screenplay
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Goldman</ENAMEX> and performances from acting heavyweights <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gene Hackman</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judy Davis</ENAMEX>, reviews of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clint Eastwood</ENAMEX>'s latest directorial effort are mixed, at
best. A plot in which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastwood</ENAMEX>, as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat burglar</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spies</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hackman</ENAMEX>, as the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, murdering his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mistress</ENAMEX> is deemed cartoonish and incredible.
"Frankly, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mars Attacks</ENAMEX>! had a better handle on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>," says
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rita Kempley</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastwood</ENAMEX>'s character
"would have to be telepathic to keep popping up, as he does, whenever the plot
needs him," says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Morgenstern</ENAMEX>. On the other
hand, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastwood</ENAMEX>'s performance is said to have saved the movie from itself.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastwood</ENAMEX> makes "the most of his vibrant geezerhood," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morgenstern</ENAMEX>. "This
time he even pokes fun at it." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Castle Rock</ENAMEX> has stills and clips.)

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Blood</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wine</ENAMEX>
                (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th Century Fox Films</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rafelson</ENAMEX>'s follow-up to his <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">1970</ENAMEX> classic, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Five</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Easy Pieces</ENAMEX> , bombs.
"Doggedly sincere," says <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Denby</ENAMEX>. Bad-tempered and "bad
for you," says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yorker</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony Lane</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rafelson</ENAMEX>'s take on
a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miami</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>'s lust, rage, and greed--"the usual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">trio</ENAMEX> of forties- noir
emotions"--is "too straight, almost TV movieish" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Denby</ENAMEX>). "The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> keep
laying into each other, as if to slam home the message--for what it's
worth--that everybody hurts sometime" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lane</ENAMEX>).

            

               Books
            

            

               
                  Gladstone: A Biography
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roy Jenkins</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Random House</ENAMEX>). Across the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlantic</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lord</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roy Jenkins</ENAMEX>' biography of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Victorian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX> was
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">universally</ENAMEX> applauded. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> called it "quite simply, a
masterpiece of the biographer's art." <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> have been less fulsome.
"A very decent try at an immensely difficult subject," writes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman Stone</ENAMEX> in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Book Review</ENAMEX> . Common complaints: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jenkins</ENAMEX>, a retired
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX>, projects onto <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gladstone</ENAMEX> such pet concerns as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European</ENAMEX>
unity. He also writes confusing prose. "It is something of a lazy book. (As in
'if I had more time, I would write a shorter letter')," says the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Eder</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam Gopnik</ENAMEX> is the lone
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enthusiast</ENAMEX>: "Part of the fun, of course, lies in the hair-raising
displays of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Victorian</ENAMEX> energy. Gladstone, in the midst of his political career,
produced a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three-volume</TIMEX> study of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Homer</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> long books on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX>, and
a new translation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Horace</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Odes</ENAMEX> ."

            

               
                  Asylum
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patrick McGrath</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Random House</ENAMEX>). "We don't usually
associate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gothic</ENAMEX> novels with elegance and discretion, but these are the
defining features of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patrick McGrath</ENAMEX>'s work," writes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Wood</ENAMEX> in the New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times Book Review</ENAMEX> . Asylum is credited with achieving new levels
of restraint. The story of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychiatrist</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> who falls in love with a
murderous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX>, it culminates in "a departure into madness that is perfectly
pictured but beyond analysis," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wood</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McGrath</ENAMEX> earns extra plaudits for
suppressing his usual fondness for the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">fantastic: Asylum</ENAMEX> "is closer to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hardy than Poe</ENAMEX>," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phil Baker</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">London Times</ENAMEX> . (See the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Random</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> site for excerpts from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Asylum</ENAMEX> .)

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hungry Ghosts: Mao's Secret Famine</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jasper Becker</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Free</ENAMEX>
Press). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Becker</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bureau</ENAMEX> chief for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South China Morning Post</ENAMEX> ,
describes in gory detail how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mao Tse-tung</ENAMEX>'s industrialization program, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great Leap Forward</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1958</TIMEX>, created a devastating famine--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30 million</NUMEX> dead, more
than the combined tolls of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stalin</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Becker</ENAMEX> succeeds in establishing
the famine "as one of the worst atrocities of all time" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Bernstein</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ). He does this despite the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s continued
effort to cover up the incident, and by way of "interviews with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">survivors</ENAMEX>
[that] provide us with a chilling view of the famine as it was experienced by
ordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">villagers</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Pickowicz</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> ).

            

               Art
            

            
               "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Darger: The Unreality of Being"</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Museum of American Folk Art</ENAMEX>). These
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bizarre</ENAMEX> (some say grotesque) watercolors by the reclusive (some say mad)
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">janitor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Darger</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1892-1973</TIMEX>) receive unanimous acclaim. The appeal
lies partly in the weirdness of his obsessions (scantily clad little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">penises</ENAMEX>), "so pungently suggestive of an imagined world," says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Stevens</ENAMEX>. There is also "his power of formal arrangement and his
sense of color" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert Hughes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> disagree, however, on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Darger</ENAMEX> himself--was
he a psychopath or an undiscovered <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX>? "He is not better than a trained or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'insider</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>," writes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stevens</ENAMEX>, "but he taps sources of power now lost to
sophisticated art." (See <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s review by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Larissa MacFarquhar</ENAMEX>.)

            

               Updates
            

            In the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Book Review</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathryn Harrison</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> of a
forthcoming memoir about incest with her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>, accuses <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mia</ENAMEX>
Farrow of cashing in with a memoir "that will satisfy a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peeping Fan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readership</ENAMEX>."... <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Reviewing When We</ENAMEX>
Were <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Kings</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Denby</ENAMEX> says, "For younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX>, there will
be <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> revelations--not only the mercurial <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ali</ENAMEX> but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman Mailer</ENAMEX> at his most
sympathetic and brilliant."

            
               Recent
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment</ENAMEX>" columns:
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Feb.</ENAMEX>
12

            
               CD -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Boone</ENAMEX> in a
Metal Mood: No More Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nice Guy</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Boone</ENAMEX>;

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dante</ENAMEX>'s
Peak ;

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- When We Were</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kings</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prisoner</ENAMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mountains</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Book -- What <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Falls</ENAMEX>
Away: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Memoir , by Mia Farrow</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- Before the
Dawn: An <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Autobiography</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerry Adams</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- A Supposedly
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fun Thing</ENAMEX> I'll <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Never Do Again: Essays and Arguments</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Foster</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wallace</ENAMEX>;

            

               Television -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Chris Rock Show</ENAMEX> .

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Feb.</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5:</TIMEX>

            
               Book -- Personal
History , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katharine Graham</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- What It Means
to Be a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Libertarian: A Personal Interpretation</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Murray</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- Do the
Windows <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Open</ENAMEX>? , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julie Hecht</ENAMEX>;

            

               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Gridlock'd</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Waiting for</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guffman</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Art --"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willem de</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Kooning: The Late Paintings, the 1980s"</ENAMEX>;

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Theater -- Men Are</ENAMEX>
From <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mars, Women Are From Venus</ENAMEX> ;

            

               Event --"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">On Cultural Power: The Wilson-Brustein Discussion</ENAMEX>."

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">29:</TIMEX>

            
               Art --"Giambattista
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tiepolo</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1696-1770</TIMEX>";

            
               Event --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Halftime</ENAMEX> at
<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Super Bowl</ENAMEX> XXXI;

            

               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kolya</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Island of the</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Colorblind</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oliver Sacks</ENAMEX>;

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> -- The
Steward of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Christendom</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- Fierce
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Creatures</ENAMEX> ;

            

               Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Le Divorce</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diane Johnson</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">22:</TIMEX>

            
               Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Behind the</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oval Office</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Winning the Presidency</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nineties</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dick Morris</ENAMEX>;

            
               Movie -- The Whole
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wide World</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Event --The
Inauguration of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Jefferson Clinton</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- One World</ENAMEX>,
Ready or Not: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Manic Logic of Global Capitalism</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William B.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Greider</ENAMEX>;

            
               CD -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Idomeneo</ENAMEX> ,
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart</ENAMEX>, performed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Placido Domingo</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metropolitan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Opera Orchestra</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chorus</ENAMEX>, conducted by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Levine</ENAMEX>;

            
               Movie -- Albino
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Alligator</ENAMEX> ;

            

               Television -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Naked Truth</ENAMEX> .

            
               --Compiled by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Franklin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foer</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> .
            

         
      
   
