
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tangled Wires</ENAMEX>

            So <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Girl Scouts</ENAMEX> can sing
again. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ASCAP</ENAMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">association</ENAMEX> of music copyright <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX>, has stopped trying to
collect royalties on campfire renditions of "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Land Is Your Land</ENAMEX>." The girls
have a new place to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX>, too--a vast stretch of land in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> recently declared a "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">National Monument</ENAMEX>." Mining's forbidden now. Too
bad for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andalex</ENAMEX>, which owned the rights to dig for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coal</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woody Guthrie</ENAMEX>, who wrote
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Land Is Your Land</ENAMEX>," was a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist</ENAMEX>. It's your land, but it's my land
too. From <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York Island</ENAMEX>, and probably <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> as well. I'd
quote more, but I'd need permission. Guthrie copyrighted the song in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1956</TIMEX>. It
remains the private property of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heirs</ENAMEX> until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2031</TIMEX>. As I said, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guthrie</ENAMEX> was a
capitalist.

            Most of
us are equally <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-faced about property. My property is mine; yours is for
sharing. Put any <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> toddlers in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> with toys, and you get <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> political
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">theorists</ENAMEX>. End-of-Property stories appeal to some grown-ups too. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karl Marx</ENAMEX>
finished <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1894</TIMEX>: A tidal wave of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> was going to sweep aside the
obstructive nuisance of private ownership. The 1990s version merely announces
the end of all intellectual property--ownership rights in words, music,
and so on--obliterated this time by a tsunami of new technology. Copying and
transmitting data is becoming too easy for the law to protect anyone's private
ownership. The ribbon of digital highway is for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">roamin</ENAMEX>' and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ramblin</ENAMEX>'. Copyright
is dead. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Digital</ENAMEX> content just "wants to be free." See <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Perry Barlow</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Esther</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dyson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicholas Negroponte</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wired</ENAMEX> ....

            There's an obvious technological rejoinder. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Digital</ENAMEX> content
can be shuffled as easily as it can be transmitted. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Encryption</ENAMEX> puts viscosity
right back into the fluid digital pipeline. Curiously, most of the property
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">abolitionists</ENAMEX> seem to like this home-brew form of copyright. There's a strong
economic rejoinder too, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Wright</ENAMEX> pointed out on these screens not long ago. Most
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> won't steal digital content if buying actually remains cheaper and
easier, as it probably will. But the "free the bits" view of things isn't just
inconsistent or unfinished. It's an analysis that hasn't progressed beyond the
Pampers stage of political theory.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Twenty</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> announced that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawmakers</ENAMEX> couldn't ban abortions in
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> trimester of pregnancy, but could ban them in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>. A
constitutional line is crossed, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blackmun</ENAMEX> reasoned, when a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fetus</ENAMEX> becomes
"viable" outside the womb. By that logic, the constitutional right retreats
with every advance in neonatal medicine. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">medics</ENAMEX> learn how to incubate a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">test-tube</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> for the whole <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nine months</TIMEX>, the abortion right ought logically to
disappear. Except that it won't. Logical consistency has nothing to do with
it.

            
It's a safe political prediction that the legal
rights in intellectual property aren't going to be abolished, however badly
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bits</ENAMEX> may want to be free. Even <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>'s softie-lefties go all hard and
capitalist when it comes to intellectual property. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Valenti</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>'s
lead <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">flack</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early '80s</TIMEX> trying to kill the new video
cassette recorder, which he was sure would be used mostly to pirate his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>' movies. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Valenti</ENAMEX> didn't succeed, but only because the VCR ended up
delivering huge profits to the movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">moguls</ENAMEX>. Far more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> use VCRs to rent
movies than to steal them.

            But <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> could
steal movies if they felt like it. The end-of-property <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cybersages</ENAMEX> argue that
the law may say what it likes, but the law doesn't matter any more.
Technological might makes right. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> with the machines will copy if they
please, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> shouldn't try to stop them. (Unless, of course, those
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> work for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wired</ENAMEX> , which is very actively defending its own
trademark.)

            But this
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">premise</ENAMEX> is also wrong. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> point to recognize is that copyright is just a
commercial form of privacy law. Indeed for some, it's the only kind of privacy
they still own. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madonna</ENAMEX> can no longer stop you from gazing at her breasts.
Copyright at least makes you pay for the pleasure.

            So we've done breasts and we've done abortion; let's move
on to the rest of your private life. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lexis-Nexis</ENAMEX> recently caused an uproar when
it offered to help personal biographical stuff on its way to freedom, through a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">database</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">P-Trak</ENAMEX>) accessible at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$82</NUMEX> a pop. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> numbers in the
database were removed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11 days</TIMEX> after its introduction: technology trumped by
popular protest.

            
Information wanting to be free doesn't seem so appealing when it includes
details about all your own flesh and frailties--credit history, shopping
habits, records of where you've been, what you asked for, and what you took.
Your modem doesn't know the difference between information called "property"
and information called "privacy." And privacy--cloak of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, stocking mask,
and any digital equivalent--is all that separates the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thief</ENAMEX> from the law. The
harder it is to maintain privacy, the easier it is to catch <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thieves</ENAMEX>. It's no
use responding that the law itself protects privacy better than copyright
protects a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spielberg</ENAMEX> movie. If you're a technological determinist, there is no
privacy law, not in cyberspace.

            
Which means that the easier it gets to steal
from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spielberg</ENAMEX>, the easier it gets for his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> to come after you. True,
technology empowers <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of potential copyright violators. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spielberg</ENAMEX>
doesn't have to catch them all. Spot enforcement, well-publicized with blue
flashing lights, is what maintains speed limits on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">highway</ENAMEX>.

            If you're
enough of a pirate to be worth bothering about, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spielberg</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> will get
you. And the law will then seize your property, like your <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pentium Pro</ENAMEX>, your
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ISDN</ENAMEX> card, and your Jaz drive. That is what has got the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cyberlibertarians</ENAMEX> so agitated. Do you see the irony? They aren't really
property anarchists--quite the opposite, in fact. They reject the new property
because it threatens their absolute control of the old. My high-speed modem is
mine, so your intellectual property must be mine too. If I really own my modem,
then I must have an unqualified right to dial up anywhere, any time, and suck
in whatever is out there to be sucked. Copyright law in cyberspace offends
because it limits what I can do in physical space. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Encryption</ENAMEX> is OK because its
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">authority</ENAMEX> is created in my very own machine.

            From <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marx</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lennon</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Imagine no possessions"</ENAMEX>),
anti-property zealots all miss the most fundamental point. Property is
politically neutral. Sure, property is the capitalist's tool. But the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">feminist's</ENAMEX>, too. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">libertarian's</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who wants an abortion says
it's her uterus, not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Robertson</ENAMEX>'s. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rancher</ENAMEX> says it's his
land, not the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>-protected <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">wolf</ENAMEX>'s. Your supposed constitutional right
to get an abortion, or smoke dope, or ride a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harley</ENAMEX> without a helmet, all
emerged from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Fourth Amendment</ENAMEX>--written originally to protect "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX>,
you're talking about land, abortion, or environmental protection, you
inevitably drift into the rhetoric of property.

            Property is an endless
succession of bubbles in space, or cyberspace, with different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> claiming
an endless variety of interests in them. Property is a bottle of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">champagne</ENAMEX>, or
the name of the label, or the whole concept of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">effervescent wine</ENAMEX>, or perhaps
just <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX> in your bloodstream while you drive <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> in your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buick</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Control of</ENAMEX>
each little bit of turf, physical or virtual, can always be made a bit more--or
a bit less--personal and private. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Politicians</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">litigators decide</ENAMEX>, often one case at a time. The deciding <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">never ends</TIMEX>, because
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, and the things they value, change. Technology will never end the tug of
war.

            The only prognosis that's
certainly wrong is that all boundary-setting law will just somehow disappear,
because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Workers of the World</ENAMEX> have united, or because information wants to
be free.

         
      
   
