
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mother</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Little Tax Break</ENAMEX>

            Signing the
minimum-wage-hike bill <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> hailed its passage as a
big victory for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">working poor</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic Party</ENAMEX>. But buried in a tax
package attached to the wage law--and completely missing from most news
coverage--was a small triumph for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kay Bailey Hutchison</ENAMEX>.
Her sweetener, the so-called <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Homemaker</ENAMEX> IRA, would increase the sum that
homemakers are allowed to put away in tax-free Individual Retirement Accounts
from the current <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$250 to $2,000</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>, raising their IRA savings limit to
match that of their working <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouses</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hutchison</ENAMEX> originally
sponsored the bill in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>; by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over half</NUMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> had leapt onto the
bandwagon. Endorsements included every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian Coalition</ENAMEX> (it
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">promotes</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> values) to feminist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> would be the prime
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">beneficiaries</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX> is still endorsing its enactment--even though the plan
is now law. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> included <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hutchison</ENAMEX>'s proposal in the economic package he
introduced after the minimum-wage bill had sailed through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> on its way
to a sure presidential signature.)

            With so
broad a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">constituency</ENAMEX> behind it, why would anyone oppose the provision? Because
IRAs cost the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX> money--which must ultimately be made up either by
raising other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s taxes or cutting their benefits. According to an
estimate by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joint Committee on Taxation</ENAMEX>, the IRA expansion would cost <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$267</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX> in lost revenue over a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five-year</TIMEX> period, which makes the merits of the
case worth a closer look.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Supporters</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Homemaker</ENAMEX> IRA argue that the new benefit
is needed because the current tax code discriminates against single-earner
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Families</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> incomes can put away <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2,000</NUMEX> for each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouse</ENAMEX>,
while <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> can save <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">only $2,000</NUMEX> for working <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouses</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$250</NUMEX>
for homemakers. It's "another marriage penalty," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hutchison</ENAMEX> contends.

            By the
"marriage penalty," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hutchison</ENAMEX> means the quirk in the tax code that pushes
married <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> into higher tax brackets than their unmarried <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counterparts</ENAMEX>. That
penalty, however, is paid only when both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouses</ENAMEX> work. When <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouse</ENAMEX>
works, married <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are charged at a lower rate than the working <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouse</ENAMEX> would
be if he or she were single. The benefit of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Homemaker</ENAMEX> IRA will go to those
who already enjoy this marriage bonus ; those who bear the marriage
penalty won't be affected.

            
And that tax bonus is not the only perk of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Partridge Familydom</ENAMEX>. Almost every tax law pertaining to marriage gives
single-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> more bang for their buck than any other category of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayer</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> are prime examples. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Employees</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> are each required to pay <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">7.65 percent</NUMEX> of an employee's income in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> taxes and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1.45 percent</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> taxes. (The self-employed
must contribute <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">15.3 percent</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> taxes and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2.9 percent</NUMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> taxes.) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> benefits are based on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>' earnings
during their careers.

            Single
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and two-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> pay in when they are young and cash out when
they retire. However, nonworking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouses</ENAMEX> (who never paid <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> taxes
because they didn't have an income to be taxed) are entitled to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>
benefits and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> based on the contribution of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouses</ENAMEX>. Retired
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> collect <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> benefits, and their nonsalaried <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouses</ENAMEX> receive
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Working</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouses</ENAMEX> must choose between their own earned benefit or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of
their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouse</ENAMEX>'s.) After primary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">beneficiaries</ENAMEX>' deaths, their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouses</ENAMEX> collect 100
percent of the benefit earned by the deceased. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouse</ENAMEX> also continues to
collect the full <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> benefit. So single-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> collect <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1½</NUMEX> times
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> benefit and twice the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> entitlement a single person
with the same income receives.

            

               Health care is another part of the
homemaker bonus package. Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> and private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> that offer
health-care benefits to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> provide coverage to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouses</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dependents</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> without a commensurate increase in employee
contributions. As a result, single-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> (and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>)
typically get coverage for more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> than do single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partners</ENAMEX> in
dual-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Supporters</ENAMEX>
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Homemaker</ENAMEX> IRA also make a feminist/fairness argument. Homemakers
don't get the IRA, they argue, because their contributions to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and
the economy aren't counted as income. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hutchison</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara Mikulski</ENAMEX>,
D-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Md.</ENAMEX>, wrote in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> 
               Times op-ed, "Failure to address the
IRA fairness issue tells homemakers: If your hard work doesn't produce taxable
revenue, it doesn't count." Because the overwhelming majority of homemakers are
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gloria Steinem</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">feminists</ENAMEX> have long argued that their work
should be counted as part of national production.

            
But the basic premise of the IRA rules is that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with income are taxed on their earnings. IRA accounts allow
income-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">earners</ENAMEX> to duck some taxation on that income if they promise to save it
until they're old. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Interest</ENAMEX> on IRA savings is not taxed until an individual
withdraws it. Furthermore, money put in IRA accounts is tax deductible when
family income is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">less than $40,000</NUMEX>.)

            And while it may be unfair
that homemakers are not paid for the work they do, the upside to the deal is
that they are not taxed on it, either. Tax <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">purists</ENAMEX> would argue that the value
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homemakers</ENAMEX>' hard work--and the intrafamily benefits they presumably
receive in return for it--should, in fact, be treated as income and taxed, just
like the wages paid to outside service <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby sitters</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">housekeepers</ENAMEX>. But you won't find many in either the feminist or family-values
camps promoting that idea. As long as unpaid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouses</ENAMEX> do not pay taxes, the
whole notion of offering them tax reprieves is questionable.

            So is the
disparity between the value that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hutchison</ENAMEX> and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> apparently put on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">at-home</ENAMEX> work done by middle- and upper-class <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouses</ENAMEX> and the contributions of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> farther down the income scale. "Work is work, whether it is done inside
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> or outside the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hutchison</ENAMEX> argues. But you have to have money to
save it, and not many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couples</ENAMEX> with young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> have the luxury of tucking
away <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2,000</NUMEX> apiece annually for their <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Golden Years</TIMEX>. Moreover, tax breaks are
worth most to those whose high-bracket positions mean they need them least.

            By contrast, when it came time for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hutchison</ENAMEX> to weigh in on
the welfare debate , she supported a bill that would force single parents
on welfare to get a paid job after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> as long as their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are over
age <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>. Her mixed priorities when it comes to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> were also revealed by the
fact that she voted "nay" on the minimum-wage bill even though it included her
own IRA proposal--and despite the fact that, according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bureau of Labor</ENAMEX>
Statistics, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">60 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> working at minimum wage are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hutchison</ENAMEX> is careful to
explain she only intends to assist <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouses</ENAMEX> who "choose" to stay home--not to
discourage those who work. But here's the rationale: "We are seeing, every time
we talk about crime in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, that it does come back to poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and
the values that some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> learn at home," she says. "Anything we can do to
encourage the family <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> and encourage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouses</ENAMEX> who are able to stay at home
with their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, if that is their desire, we should do it." In other words,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hutchison</ENAMEX> is offering a reward for making the "right choice" to those who can
already afford to make it.

         
      
   
