
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Flytrap Blame Game</ENAMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the few truths
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">universally</ENAMEX> acknowledged about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flytrap</ENAMEX> is that presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betty</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Currie</ENAMEX> deserves our sympathy: an honest, loyal civil <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">servant</ENAMEX> dragooned into a
scandal she had nothing to do with.

            But does <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Currie</ENAMEX> deserve such
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sanctification</ENAMEX>? After all, she knew <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s history when she took her job
then enabled <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s sleaziness anyway. She stood by while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> cuckolded
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and perhaps even helped him commit obstruction of justice. And did she
protest? Not as far as we have heard. Did she quit on principle? No. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Currie</ENAMEX> may
not be <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX>'s chief <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">malefactor</ENAMEX>, but nor is she the saintly innocent that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> believes her to be.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Currie</ENAMEX> case suggests that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX> needs a moral recalibration.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>, for example, has fantastically low
approval ratings, much lower than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> poll I saw pegged her
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">favorability</ENAMEX> rating at <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5 percent</NUMEX> (even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX> manages <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least 25</NUMEX>
percent). Now, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX> certainly isn't the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroine</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX>. She did seduce a
married <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, damage the presidency for the sake of casual sex, lie frequently
and insouciantly, and blab her "secret" affair to anyone who'd listen. But she
was also sexually exploited by her older, sleazy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX>; had her reputation
smeared by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">lackeys</ENAMEX>; and was betrayed by her "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Tripp</ENAMEX>. She
hardly deserves such universal contempt.

            Others besides <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Currie</ENAMEX> have
benefited from the public's excessive generosity. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX> has
become a white knight of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX>, the former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX> who had the courage
to turn on his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX>. And bravo to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chastising</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>! But it smacks
of hypocrisy for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX> to "discover" in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is a lying,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">womanizing dog</ENAMEX>. He has, after all known this since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>. Back then
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX> himself helped quell bimbo eruptions and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parroted</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
lying denials. He has never shouldered blame for those deceptions. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mickey Kaus</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> noted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX>' unbearable sanctimony in this "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>" item in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX>.) And while loyalty isn't a universal
good, it was opportunistic for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX> to betray <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> just at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">moment Clinton</ENAMEX>'s stock was about to plunge.

            
(Sometimes, of course, the public's rating is dead on target. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Tripp</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">allies</ENAMEX>--a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> that includes her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goldberg</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>,
and absolutely no one else as far as I can tell--have tried repeatedly to
improve her sorry public image. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonah Goldberg</ENAMEX> tried right here in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>. No sale.)

            
Below is 
                  Slate
               's entire
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">scorecard</ENAMEX>, which ranks <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">31</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX>'s key <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX>: The scale runs from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">-10</NUMEX> to
+<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>. Anything less than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX> means the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">player</ENAMEX> is a net miscreant. Anything
above zero rates a sympathy card. (This is not, of course, an exact science.
How, for example, do we judge <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ann Lewis</ENAMEX> compared to other last ditch <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defenders</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> is said to be more outraged by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s misbehavior than The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Guys</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>. Yet <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> didn't quit in disgust. Is her outrage a
plus or a minus if she doesn't act on it? You decide.)

            The
Scorecard

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> (The public's rating: <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">-6</NUMEX> )

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Minuses:</ENAMEX>

            To recapitulate

            a) Had an adulterous affair
with a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intern</ENAMEX>.

            b) Lied about it to
everyone .

            c) Probably perjured
himself.

            d) Perhaps obstructed
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice</ENAMEX>.

            e) Entangled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">allies</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX>
in his web of deceit.

            f) Humiliated his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">g</ENAMEX>) Did not have the grace to
apologize to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">h</ENAMEX>)Tried to shift the blame
for his failures onto his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">accusers</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Pluses:</ENAMEX>

            a) Had his private life
exposed to the world in a way no one's should be.

            b) Has
been persecuted by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX> who won't be satisfied until he is destroyed.

            
               
                  Slate
               
rating-- He never asked for our sympathy, and he doesn't deserve it:
-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> (The public's rating: <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">-6</NUMEX> )

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Minuses:</ENAMEX>

            a) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Encouraged Clinton</ENAMEX>'s most
deplorable habits: lying and polling. (When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> revealed his adultery to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX>, the political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultant</ENAMEX> immediately took a poll to see how <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>
would respond to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> admission. When the results suggested <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>
would be angry if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> had perjured himself, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Morris</ENAMEX> encouraged <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to
deny the affair.)

            b) Further sullied the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintons</ENAMEX> with a revolting comment suggesting that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> cheats because
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> is a lesbian.

            c) Not even loyal enough to
keep his mouth shut.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pluses</ENAMEX>: I cannot think of
any.

            

               
                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">rating: -7</ENAMEX>
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX> (The public's rating: <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">-7</NUMEX> )

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Minuses:</ENAMEX>

            a) Betrayed her
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>."

            b) Obsessively nosed into
the private lives of others.

            c) Tried to score a book
deal off sex gossip and other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s distress.

            d) Tattletale.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Pluses:</ENAMEX>

            a) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Whistleblower</ENAMEX> (see d
under <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Minuses</ENAMEX>): risked humiliation to expose something she believed was
wrong.

            b)
Smeared mercilessly by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">allies</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  Slate
               
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">rating: -7</ENAMEX>
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">James</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carville</ENAMEX> (The public's rating: <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">-1</NUMEX> )

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Minuses:</ENAMEX>

            a) Has known about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
woman problem since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>.

            b) Happily parroted
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s denial despite knowing that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> was a deceitful womanizer.

            c) Has not expressed the
slightest chagrin or disappointment since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s apology.

            d) Has not retreated from
vicious attacks on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>, despite evidence of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s lies.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Pluses:</ENAMEX>

            a) Perfectly loyal.

            b)
Consistent in attacks against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  Slate
               
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">rating: -5</ENAMEX>
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lindsey</ENAMEX> (The public's rating : To be determined )

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Minuses:</ENAMEX>

            a) Not yet known what he did
to protect <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> affair. Early signs suggest he knew a lot
and helped clean it up.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Pluses:</ENAMEX>

            a) Unquestionably loyal to
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX>.

            b)
Silent.

            
               
                  Slate
               
rating-- Not enough information to make a clean guess: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Approx -5</ENAMEX>
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vernon</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX> (The public's rating: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">+3</ENAMEX> )

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Minuses:</ENAMEX>

            a) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX> have known and must
have suspected that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mistress</ENAMEX> (given that he and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> are
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">confidants</ENAMEX>, it's hard to believe that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX> was totally in the dark about
her).

            b) Protected too readily by
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">establishment</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Pluses:</ENAMEX>

            a) May
have helped <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> simply because he's bighearted and generous not because
she was the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lover</ENAMEX>.

            

               
                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">rating: -4</ENAMEX>
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sidney</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blumenthal</ENAMEX> (The public's rating: <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">-3</NUMEX> )

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Minuses:</ENAMEX>

            a) Spun the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s
denial for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> without bothering to check if it was true.

            b) Pushed for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to be
aggressive rather than contrite during his speech.

            c) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trumpeted Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
denial but has not expressed chagrin now that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has admitted his
lies.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Pluses:</ENAMEX>

            a) Consistent in belief that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> is an ideologue and that the sex charges are political.

            b)
Loyal.

            
               
                  Slate
               
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">rating: -3</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Lanny
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Davis</ENAMEX> (The public's rating: <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">-1</NUMEX> )

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Minuses:</ENAMEX>

            a) Spun the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s
denial for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> without bothering to check if it was true.

            b) Said for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven months</TIMEX>
that we'd have to "wait and see." Then, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> finally admitted his lies,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Davis</ENAMEX> was hardly embarrassed or critical of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Pluses:</ENAMEX>

            a)
Loyalty to old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  Slate
               
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">rating: -3</ENAMEX>
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX> (The public's rating: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">+4</ENAMEX> )

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Minuses:</ENAMEX>

            a) Hypocritical for him to
"discover" in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is a lying <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX>. After all, he knew that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
was a lech in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> and helped cover it up. Yet he has never shouldered
responsibility for the lies <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> told then.

            b) Disloyal to turn on old
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">boss</ENAMEX> as viciously as he has in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past few weeks</TIMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Pluses:</ENAMEX>

            a) Had courage to turn on old
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">boss</ENAMEX> and criticize his moral lapses.

            b) Urged
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to be fully contrite.

            
               
                  Slate
               
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">rating: -2</ENAMEX>
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betty</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Currie</ENAMEX> (The public's rating: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">+8</ENAMEX> )

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Minuses:</ENAMEX>

            a) Abetted adulterous
affair.

            b) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX> have abetted
obstruction of justice.

            c) Knew what she was getting
into when she took the job so can't be excused on grounds of naiveté.

            d) Did not quit on
principle.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Pluses:</ENAMEX>

            a) Reputation for
honesty.

            b)
Probably dragooned into cover-up against her will.

            

               
                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">rating: -2</ENAMEX>
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Begala</ENAMEX> (The public's rating: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">0</ENAMEX> )

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Minuses:</ENAMEX>

            a) Spun the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s
denial for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> without bothering to check if it was true.

            b) Did not quit on principle
after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> admitted lies.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Pluses:</ENAMEX>

            a) Urged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> to be
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">contrite</ENAMEX> and wrote excellent, sufficiently apologetic speech.

            b)
Loyal.

            
               
                  Slate
               
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">rating: -2</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Rahm
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emanuel</ENAMEX> (The public's rating: <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">-1</NUMEX> )

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Minuses</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Pluses:</ENAMEX>

            Same as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Begala</ENAMEX> (except <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emanuel</ENAMEX> didn't write the speech).

            
               
                  Slate
               
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">rating: -2</ENAMEX>
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ann</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> (The public's rating: <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">-1</NUMEX> )

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Minuses</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Pluses:</ENAMEX>

            Same as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emanuel</ENAMEX>, except <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> seems more morally outraged with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> than other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  Slate
               
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">rating: -2</ENAMEX>
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> (The public's rating: <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">-9</NUMEX> )

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Minuses:</ENAMEX>

            a) Seduced a married <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>.

            b) Damaged and endangered the
presidency for the sake of casual sex.

            c) Has lied frequently.

            d) Is a capable adult,
not--as her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> claim--a naive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>, defenseless against the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">wiles</ENAMEX>.

            e) Protected herself with
immunity when she needed to, even though her testimony would do enormous harm
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>.

            f) Blabbed her "secret"
affair to lots of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. (So, while she was dragged into the scandal against
her will, it was her own loquaciousness that made the dragging possible.)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Pluses:</ENAMEX>

            a) Sexually exploited by her
older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX>.

            b) Had her reputation smeared
by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clintonistas</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>.

            c) Betrayed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX>.

            d) Dragged
into the scandal against her will.

            
               
                  Slate
               
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">rating: -2</ENAMEX>
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCurry</ENAMEX> (The public's rating: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">+2</ENAMEX> )

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Minuses:</ENAMEX>

            a) Spun and spun and spun the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s denial for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> without bothering to check if it was true.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Pluses:</ENAMEX>

            a) Was clearly dismayed by
the entire scandal and his role in it.

            b) Is quitting the
administration (though not, apparently, on principle).

            c)
Loyal.

            

               
                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">rating: -1</ENAMEX>
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kendall</ENAMEX> (The public's rating: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">0</ENAMEX> )

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Minuses:</ENAMEX>

            a) Relied on iffy legalisms
to help <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> escape trouble.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Pluses:</ENAMEX>

            a) Relying on iffy legalisms
to help <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> escape trouble is his job. He's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>.

            b)
Admirably reticent, compared to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Bennett</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  Slate
               
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">rating: -1</ENAMEX>
            

            
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rev.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Jackson</ENAMEX> (The public's rating: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">+2</ENAMEX> )

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Minuses:</ENAMEX>

            a) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Revealed Clinton</ENAMEX> family
troubles immediately after his pastoral visit.

            b) Parlayed pastoral visit
into a week of self-promotion.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Pluses:</ENAMEX>

            a) Graciously counseled a
political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rival</ENAMEX> in time of need.

            b) Did
not demand any political compensation in exchange.

            
               
                  Slate
               
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">rating: -1</ENAMEX>
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barr</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">R-Ga.</ENAMEX> (The public's rating: <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">-5</NUMEX> )

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Minuses:</ENAMEX>

            a) Unapologetically vicious,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">partisan</ENAMEX>, and unforgiving in his impeachment quest.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Pluses:</ENAMEX>

            a)
Consistent throughout the scandal: He has been pushing impeachment since before
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX> materialized in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX>.

            
               
                  Slate
               
rating: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">0</ENAMEX>
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> (The public's rating: <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">-9</NUMEX> )

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Minuses:</ENAMEX>

            a) Seems merciless toward
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>.

            b) Has pursued investigation
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">into Clinton</ENAMEX>'s private life with more zeal than seems appropriate.

            c) Is too willing to provoke
constitutional standoffs for the sake of his investigation, seems indifferent
to the dignity of the presidency.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Pluses:</ENAMEX>

            a) Was right about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>.

            b) Is compelled by law to
investigate diligently and forcefully.

            c) Has
been <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> with the stonewalling, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">deceiving</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  Slate
               
rating: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">+1</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Paula
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> (The public's rating: <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">-5</NUMEX> )

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Minuses:</ENAMEX>

            a) Brought a legally dubious,
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX>-digging lawsuit.

            b) Resisted a settlement that
would have saved the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> much embarrassment.

            c) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Happily</ENAMEX> became a tool for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Pluses:</ENAMEX>

            a) Is vindicated because
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> probably did it.

            b) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forced Clinton</ENAMEX>'s lechery
out in the open.

            c)
Persisted in the face of ridicule and humiliation.

            

               
                  Slate
                rating: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">+1</ENAMEX>
            

            
               The
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> (The public's rating: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">+7</ENAMEX> )

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Minuses:</ENAMEX>

            a) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hypocritically</ENAMEX> claim to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">despise</ENAMEX> scandal, follow it breathlessly, then blame the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> for obsessing
over it.

            b) Are secretly fascinated
by the sleaziness of it.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Pluses:</ENAMEX>

            a)
Magnanimous toward the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  Slate
               
rating: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">+1</ENAMEX>
            

            
               The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Media</ENAMEX> (The public's rating: <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">-8</NUMEX> )

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Minuses:</ENAMEX>

            a) No sense of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">proportionality</ENAMEX>. Coverage is wretchedly excessive even when it shouldn't
be.

            b) Endlessly self-involved.
How many stories have you seen about the media and the scandal?

            c) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Unforgiving</ENAMEX>. The media
want the scandal to continue, hence won't ever be satisfied that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has
suffered enough.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Pluses:</ENAMEX>

            a) Worked hard to break a
very important story and investigated the hell out of it.

            b)
Unfairly savaged by hypocritical <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> (see above).

            
               
                  Slate
               
rating: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">+1</ENAMEX>
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leon</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Panetta</ENAMEX> (The public's rating: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">+1</ENAMEX> )

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Minuses:</ENAMEX>

            a) Slightly disloyal to old
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">boss</ENAMEX>.

            b) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX> have known about
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s extracurricular activities, yet turned a blind eye.

            c) On television too
much.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Pluses:</ENAMEX>

            a) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Urged Clinton</ENAMEX> early on to
come clean.

            b) Had
good sense to leave the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> before corrupting himself.

            
               
                  Slate
               
rating: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">+1</ENAMEX>
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> (The public's rating: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">+4</ENAMEX> )

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Minuses:</ENAMEX>

            a) Knew what a lech he was,
yet always protected him.

            b) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX> have always known
truth about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>, yet still lied to protect Bill.

            c) Chose aggressive,
political strategy over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">contrition</TIMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Pluses:</ENAMEX>

            a) Lied to, betrayed, and
cuckolded by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>.

            b) Personally humiliated.

            c) May
have disgraced her own good name by echoing his denials on the Today
show.

            
               
                  Slate
               
rating-- She made a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Faustian</ENAMEX> bargain, but you still feel sorry for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Faust</ENAMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">+2</ENAMEX>
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> (The public's rating: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">+3</ENAMEX> )

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Minuses:</ENAMEX>

            a) Did not (apparently) urge
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> to come clean with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Pluses:</ENAMEX>

            a) Stayed loyal.

            b) Did
not take advantage of scandal to burnish his own image.

            
               
                  Slate
               
rating: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">+2</ENAMEX>
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathleen</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX> (The public's rating: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">0</ENAMEX> )

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Minuses:</ENAMEX>

            a) Was in it for the money
(told her story partly in order to land a book contract).

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Pluses:</ENAMEX>

            a) Seems to have told story
honestly and forthrightly.

            b) Reluctantly dragged into
scandal.

            c) Was
victimized by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  Slate
               
rating: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">+2</ENAMEX>
            

            
               The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton Cabinet</ENAMEX> (The public's rating: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">+2</ENAMEX> )

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Minuses:</ENAMEX>

            a) Spun his denials without
digging for the truth.

            b) Did not quit on
principle.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Pluses:</ENAMEX>

            a) Were conscripted
unwillingly into scandal defense. (Unlike political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Begala</ENAMEX>, who
are expected to do political dirty work, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> are public
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">servants</ENAMEX> who should be kept away from such sleaze.)

            b) Were lied to by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>.

            c)
Loyal.

            
               
                  Slate
               
rating: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">+3</ENAMEX>
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Erskine</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bowles</ENAMEX> (The public's rating: Doesn't care )

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Minuses:</ENAMEX>

            a) Refused to involve himself
in the critical issue of the presidency.

            b) Stood aside while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> was shanghaied by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Pluses:</ENAMEX>

            a) Stayed utterly silent
about the scandal, clearly disgusted by it all.

            b) Kept the rest of the
administration focused on policy, thus preventing total executive
paralysis.

            c) Did not
lie or spin for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  Slate
               
rating: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">+4</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Rep.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Hyde</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ill.</ENAMEX> (The public's rating: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">+4</ENAMEX> )

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Minuses:</ENAMEX>

            There are none yet.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Pluses:</ENAMEX>

            a)
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mostly</ENAMEX>) kept his mouth shut and prevented the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Judiciary Committee</ENAMEX> from
jumping the gun on impeachment.

            

               
                  Slate
                rating: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">+4</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Secret
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Service</ENAMEX> (The public's rating: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">+8</ENAMEX> )

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Minuses:</ENAMEX>

            a) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fought Starr</ENAMEX> subpoena too
hard because it considers itself the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Praetorian Guard</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Pluses:</ENAMEX>

            a) Dragged unwillingly into
scandal by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> (unlike <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Currie</ENAMEX> or his political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> have no choice about being near the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>).

            b) Testified honestly but
unwillingly, as they should.

            c) Did
not leak.

            
               
                  Slate
               
rating: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">+5</ENAMEX>
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chelsea</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> (The public's rating: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">+10</ENAMEX> )

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Minuses:</ENAMEX>

            There are none.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Pluses:</ENAMEX>

            a) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Humiliated</ENAMEX> and
embarrassed by her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s misbehavior.

            b) Had family problems
paraded before the world in a way they should not be.

            c) Has been endlessly
psychologized by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>.

            d) Had
her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer vacation</TIMEX> ruined.

            
               
                  Slate
               
rating: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">+10</ENAMEX>
            

            More Flytrap
...

         
      
   
