
   
   
      
         
            Term Limit Traitors

            Before they got control of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> contended that the big problem in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> was an
infestation of vermin known as "career <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">newcomers</ENAMEX> came armed
with a powerful repellent. Setting maximum terms of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between six and 12 years</TIMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> would function as an antidote to <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Potomac fever</ENAMEX> and restore the place of
the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen legislator</ENAMEX>," whose loyalty would remain with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> who
elected him, not the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX> in which he served.

            This
movement caught fire in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of that year</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> had passed
term limitations on their own congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">delegations</ENAMEX>. But because it wasn't
yet clear whether these limits were constitutional--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> decided
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> that they weren't--the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Contract With America</ENAMEX> also endorsed a term
limits amendment to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX>. And since a constitutional amendment
might not pass, many congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> and since have term
limited themselves voluntarily. That is, they've promised to call it quits
after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six to 12 years</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12 years</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>. One gung-ho
freshman elected in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">'94</NUMEX> even gave the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clerk</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> a letter of
resignation dated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 2001</TIMEX> to demonstrate the sincerity of his promise.

            Forced retirement was a distant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prospect</ENAMEX> then. But now the
most enthusiastic term limiters in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> are facing the expectation that
they will follow through on their pledge. For those who vowed to return to
their plows after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six years</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next term</TIMEX> will be their last. Several of those
freshmen actually appear to take the idea that they made a promise seriously
and have reaffirmed their intentions of stepping down. But others are
discovering nuances to the issue they never noticed before. In other words,
they have turned into term limit traitors.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benedict Arnold</ENAMEX> of the
term limits movement is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Nethercutt</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. Nethercutt
defeated the last <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Foley</ENAMEX>, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> on a
platform that consisted of little more than term limits for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>. He rode to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> by allying himself with a state term limit
initiative that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Foley</ENAMEX> filed suit to overturn. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nethercutt</ENAMEX> recently changed his
mind. "Make no mistake, I remain committed to term limits, but experience has
taught me that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six years</TIMEX> may be too short," he said in a statement issued in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX>. In a follow-up interview, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nethercutt</ENAMEX> said that if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fifth District</ENAMEX> clamored for him to stay, he would consider it.

            Of course,
the chief objection to term limits has always been that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> should have
the right to elect whoever they want to represent them in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, including
someone they have elected repeatedly before. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nethercutt</ENAMEX> now sees the merit of
this argument, but he's far from admitting he was wrong. He says he's still for
term limits--he just had the details wrong. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Twelve</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> would be a more
appropriate limit for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>--with nothing precluding <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">another 12</TIMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>. And if <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> decide they still want <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nethercutt</ENAMEX> after <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>? We can cross that <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridge</ENAMEX> when we come to it.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nethercutt</ENAMEX>'s fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">turncoat</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Shadegg</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arizona</ENAMEX>, one of the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hotheads</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">freshman class</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">'94</NUMEX>. In his first
congressional campaign, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shadegg</ENAMEX> promised he would abide by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the six-year</TIMEX> limit
set by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>. That limit, however, was declared unconstitutional, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shadegg now</ENAMEX> feels the tug of his broader responsibilities. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are
honoring <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the six-year term</TIMEX> limit are the ones with the most revolutionary zeal,
and they're the ones that are leaving," he recently told the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> , explaining his defection. In other words, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shadegg</ENAMEX> thinks people
like himself who support term limits must go back on their word to prevent
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are really against term limits from getting elected.

            Another
slow learner is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott McInnis</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX>, who was elected in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McInnis</ENAMEX> has
announced he will not step aside in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> as he had originally promised. His
reason is that before he was elected to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>, he didn't understand how
important the seniority system was in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>. If <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX>'s representatives
were to heed term limits, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">delegation</ENAMEX> would be less
powerful than the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">delegations</ENAMEX> from states that don't recognize term limits. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">upshot</ENAMEX>, he says, would be unilateral disarmament for his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>.

            The problem with these arguments is not that they are bad
arguments. In fact, they're quite sensible. The seniority system means you get
power by serving long enough to gain seniority. And a state that voluntarily
limits the terms of its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> harms itself relative to others. But
there is no excuse for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McInnis</ENAMEX>' just coming to grips with these objections.
After <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 years</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Colorado House of Representatives</ENAMEX>, the last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> as
majority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>, he's no stranger to the concept of seniority. As to the
unilateral disarmament point: It's a very solid objection. But it was an even
better objection when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McInnis</ENAMEX> supported the passage of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX>'s term limits
law in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>. Had the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> upheld the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> law, a binding term
limit on all the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">legislators</ENAMEX> would have put it at a far greater
disadvantage than a disposable promise by a few of its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">legislators</ENAMEX>. In fact,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McInnis</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> knew perfectly well what they were committing to
when they swore they'd limit their own terms. But back when they made those
promises, before they'd ever been elected to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, the prospect of leaving
in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six or eight</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a dozen</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> didn't sound so bad.

            The hypocrisy here does not
belong just to the few who made specific pledges. Term limits was the official
position of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican Party</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>. The Contract With <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> called for
term limits for the entire <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>. (Of course, if you read the fine
print, it only promised to bring such a proposal up for a vote.) More senior
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> have been as disingenuous as the young <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bloods</ENAMEX>. They've just been
more adept at avoiding personal embarrassment. Take <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill McCollum</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX> who is one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> on the issue in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>. He's in his
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18 th year</TIMEX> of service and is running for re-election. No one back
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> is giving him a hard time on the issue, because he was not so foolish as
to make a personal promise to step down.

            The term limits craze makes a
nice case study in political demagoguery. All the problems the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">radicals</ENAMEX> are belatedly recognizing now were totally obvious at the outset.
Before long, we can expect to hear retirement-averse <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> making the
rest of the fine arguments against term limits. Experience, they will discover,
is actually valuable. The fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> can and do reject <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">incumbents</ENAMEX> will
strike them as an epiphany. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> term limit traitors don't need to
apologize for changing their minds, which they have every right to do. What
they owe us is an admission that their professed faith in term limits was phony
in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place.

         
      
   
