
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Real Secret</ENAMEX>

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX>, the federal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> accomplished something no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX>, government
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agency</ENAMEX>, or private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> has been able to: They said "no" to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret</ENAMEX>
Service.

            The fight
over the "protective function privilege" has raised complicated, delicate, and
important questions about presidential privacy and the obligations of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX>. Is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Praetorian Guard</ENAMEX> that can abet an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">imperial</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> in sleaze and coverup? How do we reconcile the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s
privacy with law enforcement's demands? While the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> have settled the legal
issue (for the moment), <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> continue to masticate these questions
dutifully.

            But something is being overlooked in the privilege
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">squabble</ENAMEX>: other complicated, delicate, and even more important questions about
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX>. Notably: Are there any limits on the amount of money we
will spend to protect the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>? Is it healthy for a democracy to surround
its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> with a bloated paramilitary security apparatus?

            The real
worry about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> is not, as the privilege spat suggests, that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> has too much control over it. The real worry is that no one
has control over it. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX>'s rise is one of the most remarkable
and unremarked stories of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last 40 years</TIMEX>. In an age of open
and (ostensibly) frugal public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> is an
anomaly, an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> that operates with nearly as much secrecy as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> and
spends almost as freely as its heart desires. How has this happened?

            
As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Greenberg</ENAMEX> chronicles in

                  Slate
               's "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Backstory</ENAMEX>," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> was established in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1865</TIMEX> to fight
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">counterfeiting</ENAMEX>. It began guarding the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> regularly in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1901</TIMEX>, after the
assassination of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William McKinley</ENAMEX>, but remained a modest enterprise
until <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John F. Kennedy</ENAMEX>'s murder.

            Since
then, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> has experienced the kind of growth that, well, only
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stockholders</ENAMEX> in software <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> have come to expect. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1957</TIMEX>, it spent <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3.5</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">million</ENAMEX> and employed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">450</NUMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> costs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX> about
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$590 million</NUMEX> and employs <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 4,600</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>--including <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,000</NUMEX> special agents
(whose responsibilities include presidential protection) and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,200</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Uniformed Division</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> for more details about its proliferation.)

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> is evidence of the Iron Law of
Bureaucratic Growth: An <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> unchecked by outside <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> expands. The service
asks, and it is given. For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal 1999</TIMEX>, it requested <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$594,657,000</NUMEX> in federal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">funding</ENAMEX> (an increase of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">more than 5 percent</NUMEX> over its <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$564 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">base</ENAMEX>--it
receives <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $30 million</NUMEX> more in other appropriations). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> just passed
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> appropriations bill, and how much did the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> get?
Exactly <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$594,657,000</NUMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>
stiffs other federal programs, but all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX>'s desires are
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fulfilled</ENAMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6 million</NUMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> armor-plated <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">limousines</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3 million</NUMEX> for Y2K
conversion, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> to pay for extra travel expenses, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$62 million</NUMEX> to beef up
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> security, including new bulletproof windows, air <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">defenses</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">27</NUMEX>
extra security <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffers</ENAMEX>. (Not that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> can find out much about how the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> spends its money: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Details</ENAMEX> about how the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> is protected
are classified. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> has even removed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> floor plans from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Library of Congress</ENAMEX>.)

            
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> is untouchable. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> is
terrified of scrimping on it. "No one ever wants to not fully fund it," says a
congressional appropriations <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffer</ENAMEX>. "No one ever wants to be the one who is
responsible for risk or danger to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>." Another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffer</ENAMEX> asks, "If
they say it's necessary for the safety of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, who is going to say
no?" The media, too, are reluctant to criticize: The last major story to
question the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> appeared in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1981</TIMEX>. (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Two months later</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> was shot.) When the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> does attract
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">notice</ENAMEX>, it tends to receive coverage best described as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Protection Porn</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX>
for an explanation.)

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> does not hesitate to exploit its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dead</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> advantage,
practicing an elegant variation of "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fireman First</ENAMEX>" (a classic bureaucratic
defense mechanism--when your budget is threatened, propose cutting the fire
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>). On the rare occasions the service is queried, it invokes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dead</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A month</TIMEX> after the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma City</ENAMEX> bombing, and without a hearing, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> shut <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Pennsylvania Avenue</ENAMEX> and surrounding <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> to traffic.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Washingtonians</ENAMEX> complained. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> declared it was necessary for the safety
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">avenue</ENAMEX> stays closed.

            The privilege squabble, in fact, marks the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time the
Dead <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> defense has failed. In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX> briefs and in private
meetings, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> insisted that the failure to recognize the
privilege: would result in "profound and predictable peril" to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>,
"could mean the difference between life or death," would endanger "the
integrity of our national security," etc. The appeals court rapped the agency
for its scare tactics, saying it must base its conclusions "on solid facts and
a realistic appraisal of the danger rather than on vague fears extrapolated
beyond any foreseeable threat."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret</ENAMEX>
Service is not incompetent or corrupt, or even especially greedy. In fact, it
is almost universally admired for its professionalism and efficiency. Even so,
its ascendancy is troublesome. It has made standard--even admired--measures
that ought to be intolerable in a democracy. A <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">half-century ago</TIMEX>, a president
could drive through city <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> in a normal <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> with a few bodyguards, and
anyone could stroll up to the front door of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>. Of course, ours is
a different and more dangerous age: There are undoubtedly more and more
sophisticated threats to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> than we can imagine.

            
But the expansion of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> has
normalized a paramilitary presidency. No one blinks at: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> motorcades that
shut down <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">interstates</ENAMEX> and gridlock traffic, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200-plus</NUMEX>-strong <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">delegation</ENAMEX> that accompanies the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> abroad, the transformation of the
open <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> into an impenetrable <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">fortress</ENAMEX>. During public events, it is
perfectly acceptable for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> to approach crowd <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> and
yank their hands out of their pockets to confirm they are not hiding <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX>.
It is unquestioned that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> should be chauffeured in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> that costs
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.5 million</NUMEX> . It has become a deep inconvenience for average <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> to
see their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, and a deep inconvenience for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> to see average
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>. There is something unseemly about this excessive security, and
something undemocratic.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Patrick Moynihan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.Y.</ENAMEX>, perhaps the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawmaker</ENAMEX> who ever criticized
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> before the privilege flap, said in a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> speech that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> has made the "insufferable" routine. "I don't know if the agency
itself is aware of how arrogant and presumptuous it has become." <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Two years ago</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moynihan</ENAMEX> remarked that soon, the service will "have a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billion-dollar</NUMEX> budget.
And still just one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX>."

            It isn't that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX>'s precautions are
definitively unnecessary. It's that no one knows whether they are necessary and
no one is willing to ask. Perfection is impossible in presidential security. No
matter how much we spend, the goal will always recede. A determined assassin
will be able to find a way to kill the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> will
be able to find a way to spend more money to prevent it. (In fact, the agency
seems to have found most of those ways already.)

            No one
wants the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> assassinated. But should it be forbidden to ask if we could
spend less and do less to protect him?

            
               If you
missed the link to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Backstory</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX>, here it is again.
Here's <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the</TIMEX> , and here's the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> on .
            

         
      
   
