
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Lite</ENAMEX>

            Try to remember, if you can
for a moment, the old <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX>. He was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who liked to talk very
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">grandly</ENAMEX>, often describing his political program as "renewing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
civilization" and replacing what he referred to as "the bureaucratic welfare
state" with a new kind of society. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> election that brought him to power
was a "revolution" that he cast in terms of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Braveheart</ENAMEX> , a gory movie
about freedom <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fighters</ENAMEX> in medieval <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scotland</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traitors</ENAMEX> knew what to
expect. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> blamed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> for sensational murders and called the
Clintons the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX> of "normal <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>." He drew cosmological charts with
himself at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> and got very fat.

            The new
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt</ENAMEX>, by contrast, is a humble <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fellow</ENAMEX>. In his book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lessons Learned the Hard</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Way</ENAMEX> , he presents himself as shorn of his old harshness and grandiosity, as
well as of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">30 or 40 pounds</NUMEX>. On the cover, he appears in faded jeans, hiking
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">boots</ENAMEX>, and a leather jacket, smiling as he leans against a post-and-rail <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">fence</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bathed</ENAMEX> in soft filtered sunlight. The few specific proposals he makes are
stunning in their modesty. For instance, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> diabetes screening
as a way to save <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> money and thinks it is especially important for
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Native Americans</ENAMEX>, who are highly susceptible to the disease, to monitor their
blood pressure. He admits to mistakes such as failing to keep his mouth shut at
several points, mismanaging the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>, and underestimating his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX>. He describes himself as tolerant of internal dissent, even
identifying with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebels</ENAMEX> who plotted a coup against him <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last summer</TIMEX>.

            Seeing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt</ENAMEX> so shrunken is somewhat disheartening. There's
a poignant moment in his mostly very dull book when, as his career is being
torn apart by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Ethics Committee</ENAMEX> investigation into his college course,
he describes visiting <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of his favorite places, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Museum of</ENAMEX>
Natural History in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>. Communing with <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dinosaurs</ENAMEX> revives his spirits. In
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the old days</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt</ENAMEX> didn't need fossils to spur him on. He had the courage of
his convictions and of his boorish aggression. Now he comes across like a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> of some <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dale Carnegie</ENAMEX> re-education <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX>--it's as if he's constantly
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">reminding</ENAMEX> himself of his image-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultant</ENAMEX>'s lessons in seeming nice. Where the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">old Newt</ENAMEX> was a compelling meanie, the new one offers anodyne platitudes and
empty uplift. He calls at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point in his book for "a serious conversation
about our national future." At another point he writes of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican</ENAMEX>
agenda, "What we have to offer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> ... is strength and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adventure</ENAMEX>, the
experience of a new level of life-enhancing energy, and love of a great
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>." This could be anyone talking--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Gephardt</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX>, or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marianne Williamson</ENAMEX>.

            What
happened to transform the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">raging bull</ENAMEX> into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Caspar Milquetoast</ENAMEX>? There are
various theories. Some think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> has modified his behavior because he is
still fighting for survival, trying to appease the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> who
plotted to overthrow him and might plot again. I've heard others suggest that
he is an undiagnosed manic-depressive coming off a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three-year</TIMEX> spree. Perhaps
the most common view is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt</ENAMEX> is merely positioning for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>, trying to
diminish his stratospheric "negatives" in preparation for a presidential
run.

            
None of these explanations quite cuts it.
Whatever his past gaps in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">judgment, Gingrich</ENAMEX> is too smart to think he has a
realistic chance of being elected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. His unpopularity is deep and
indelible. If he does run in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> primaries, it will be as a way of
gracefully exiting his job as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX>. (He has to step down in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX> anyway,
according to the rule he set.) In fact, I don't think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX>'s transformation
is all that calculated. To be sure, his book is disingenuous at points. He says
the coup plot was merely a cry for attention by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">freshman class</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>,
not a serious attempt at getting rid of him. That's ridiculous. And nowhere
does he mention one of his biggest mistakes--the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4.5 million</NUMEX> book deal.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> returned the advance, but he still wrote (or caused to be written) two
books, of which this is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> and more nearly readable. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">arrogance</ENAMEX> is genuinely diminished. He truly seems a different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>.

            I think
the new personality-modified <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt</ENAMEX> is mainly the product of his shattering
experiences in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995 and 1996</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> tried to lead a revolution and ended up
with his head in the guillotine. In a way, this catastrophe was the result of a
misunderstanding. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> was never of the same mind as the radical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">freshmen</ENAMEX>.
Before the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Contract With America</ENAMEX>, he was not notably anti-government. To the
contrary, he thought the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> had suffered as a result of its foolish opposition
to popular federal programs. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> had a swollen ego. He thought of
himself as a world historical figure, so when the election of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> gave birth
to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">movement</ENAMEX>, he stepped forward to lead it. In fact, it drove him. He was
thus the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> standing in the intersection when the would-be conservative
revolution smashed into the moderate reality of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> politics.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> is now picking himself up off the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">asphalt</ENAMEX>. His
plan for the future is to stay out of traffic. Beyond that, he proposes the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Party</ENAMEX> support something he calls "entrepreneurial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>." He
would let the private sector act wherever possible and get the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> to
act more like a business. This is probably what <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> would advocate if
they were smart. Entrepreneurial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is compatible with tax cuts and
does not demand an assault on purposes and programs that the voting majority
regards as essential. It is a politics with great potential appeal to an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">electorate</ENAMEX> increasingly dominated by an independent, stock-owning middle class.
This kind of politics does not alienate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>. If the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> could adopt it as a
general approach while distancing itself from aggressive social conservatism,
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> would have reason to fear at the presidential as well as the
congressional level.

            But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt</ENAMEX>'s entrepreneurial
idea, which stresses flexibility and innovation in how government discharges
its role, contradicts the libertarian urge to have <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> simply butt out.
And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> still wants to have it both ways--or at least to make the class of
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">'94</NUMEX> think he does. According to his numbers, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> at all levels currently
consumes <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 38 percent</NUMEX> of personal income. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gingrich</ENAMEX> proposes reducing it to
just <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">25 percent</NUMEX>. If you subtract the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">16 percent</NUMEX> that goes to state and local
spending, that means the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> would defend the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, pay for
electricity to light the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Capitol dome</ENAMEX>, and do not much else. But that's not all
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> intends to have it do. He wants to "protect" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>, dole out
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billions</NUMEX> in highway subsidies, and fund research into diseases that
affect <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>.

            Here <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Lite</ENAMEX> has something
in common with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Heavy</ENAMEX>. His interesting ideas don't quite add up.

         
      
   
