
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trashy Books</ENAMEX>

            Scandals customarily
generate lots of quick, trashy literature; the kind of unedited, misspelled
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">garbage</ENAMEX> designed to sell scads of copies before <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> realize just how junky
it is. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flytrap</ENAMEX>, until now, has been a publishing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">flop</ENAMEX>. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last few weeks</TIMEX>
have finally brought the first crop of scandal books: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William J. Bennett</ENAMEX>'s
The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Death of Outrage</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Assault on American Ideals</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ann Coulter</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">High Crimes and Misdemeanors: The Case Against Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerome D. Levin</ENAMEX>'s The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton Syndrome</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Self-Destructive Nature of Sexual Addiction</ENAMEX> .

            None of
these books is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flytrap</ENAMEX>'s All the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Men</ENAMEX> (or should that be
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Women</ENAMEX> ?). The books are, for the most part, shameless attempts to exploit
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s sorrow for money and fame. They are essentially clip jobs,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">repackaging</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> and TV reports with a gloss of new opinion. But there is
something interesting about them: the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> distinct strains of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
criticism they represent.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">1 Somber Moral Instruction:</ENAMEX>
            

            Unsurprisingly, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX>'s
project in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Death of Outrage</ENAMEX> is to stiffen <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s backbone, to
persuade us to care about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s misdeeds and to punish them. He writes,
"<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> know better--and they will demonstrate that indeed they do
know better. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> will realize they are being played for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fools</ENAMEX> by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defenders</ENAMEX>."

            
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Death of Outrage</ENAMEX>
suffers from the same surfeit of self-righteousness that plagues all <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ventures</ENAMEX>. It is jacketed with the sober brown <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> that covered <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Book of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Virtues</ENAMEX> , and it seems a calculating attempt by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX> to secure his
franchise as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s scold in chief. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX>'s pose of nonpartisan moral
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">authority</ENAMEX>, annoying enough when he writes for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>, seems particularly forced
in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Death of Outrage</ENAMEX> . Click for a spectacular example.

            After reading <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX>,
however, I began to think that the consciousness-raising he preaches might
actually be possible. He is a fine rhetorician, and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Death of Outrage</ENAMEX>
makes the best case yet for public condemnation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX>'s arguments
are nothing you haven't read before on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> editorial page
or in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly Standard</ENAMEX> , but they're powerful nonetheless. Basic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">premises</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s reckless, repeated adultery weakens essential moral codes;
his betrayal of vows and his lies undermine public trust; his use of legal
chicanery to duck ethical responsibility is cowardly and grotesque; the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">public</ENAMEX>'s silence in the face of this is a capitulation, "moral disarmament";
and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, which has always believed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>' moral behavior
matters, must start judging <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>.

            But the
inspiration of this book is its tone. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX> is obviously obsessed, partisan,
and furious about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flytrap</ENAMEX>, yet he has managed to write a book without vitriol.
He refrains from gloating. He chastises others for their glee in savaging
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. He takes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s immorality so seriously that he can't even joke
about it. Like television, the book is a cool medium; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX>'s anger is
convincing because he holds it in check.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">2 Rage:</ENAMEX>
            

            I realized the effectiveness
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX>'s restraint when I opened <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coulter's High Crimes</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Misdemeanors</ENAMEX> , which represents the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> strain of criticism. If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX>
is superego, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coulter</ENAMEX> is id. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX> says in measured tones what <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">conservatives</ENAMEX>
ought to believe. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MSNBC</ENAMEX> pundit Coulter screams what they really feel.

            
               High Crimes has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
principal aims: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) to explain what, historically and legally, constitutes an
impeachable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offense</ENAMEX> (summary: moral offenses, not just criminal ones) and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) to
build an impeachment case against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> by summarizing his malfeasance in
everything from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> case to campaign fund raising to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Webb Hubbell</ENAMEX>'s
job search to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House Travel Office</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coulter</ENAMEX>,
whose TV manner is that of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> going stark raving mad, is the wrong person
to write a sober legal tract. High Crimes is supposed to show that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX> have a strong legal case against him. Instead, it suggests
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX> are nutters.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coulter</ENAMEX> argues ad <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hominem</ENAMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> satellite policy was "treason." He is "The Manchurian
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Candidate</ENAMEX>" and a "horny <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hick</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> doesn't allow <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oval Office</ENAMEX>
because "it might interfere with his potency." She says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor Clift</ENAMEX> has gone "beyond the call of duty to earn [her] presidential
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">kneepads</ENAMEX>."

            
               High
Crimes is painfully shoddy, even for a book rushed to press. Misspellings
are commonplace. Quotes are muffed: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s most famous comment, "I did not
have sexual relations with that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>, Miss <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>," is rendered "I never had
sexual relations with that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>." Entire paragraphs are repeated, nearly word
for word, in different chapters of the book. Coulter claims to lay out the
facts against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, but it's hard to trust her: In I happen to know
something about, she grossly misrepresents evidence to make <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> look worse.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coulter</ENAMEX>'s legal scholarship is so repetitious and garbled that it's hard to
puzzle out her definition of "high crimes and misdemeanors." It's as though the
book was not edited at all.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Psychobabble</ENAMEX>:
            

            I did not think a book could
be any worse than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High Crimes</ENAMEX> . Then I encountered <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerome</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Levin</ENAMEX>'s--whoops, I mean, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerome Levin</ENAMEX>'s-- The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton Syndrome</ENAMEX> .
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Psychotherapist Levin</ENAMEX>'s ostensible purpose is to use <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s problems to
bring attention to sex addiction. His underlying purpose seems more cynical: to
get his shoddy little book stocked in both the political and self-help
sections.

            To these ends <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Levin</ENAMEX> has
written a psychological profile of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> as sex <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">addict</ENAMEX>. According to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Levin</ENAMEX>, the root of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s "hang up." As the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> of an "enabler"
and a "rageaholic," as well as an "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACOA</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Adult Child of Alcoholics</ENAMEX>)," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>
became a chronic "musterbator," a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> who overachieved in order to win the
"unconditional love" that was missing at home. He sought it in power, in the
love of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX>, and especially in casual sex. But all were poor substitutes
for true love and didn't vanquish his feelings of inadequacy and guilt. The
deaths of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Brown</ENAMEX> ("an older-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> figure" to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yitzak Rabin</ENAMEX> ("an
important <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> figure"), and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> (a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> figure?) made <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
vulnerable to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>.

            "The more I thought about
it," writes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Levin</ENAMEX>, "the more I realized that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> had about as much chance
of leaving her alone as a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">addict</ENAMEX> has of passing up a line." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
deserves sympathy and compassion, not vitriol, because he exercises no control
over his compulsive sexual behavior. Straight-faced conclusion: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> should
hold "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">SCA (Sexual Compulsives Anonymous</ENAMEX>)" chapter meetings at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>,
thus inspiring <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> to overcome their addictions.

            Never mind that the very
existence of sex addiction is questioned by most respectable shrinks. Never
mind that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Levin</ENAMEX>'s profile of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is constructed from <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a papier-mâché</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A.M.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosenthal</ENAMEX> columns and episodes of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlie Rose</ENAMEX> . Never mind that The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton Syndrome</ENAMEX> is filled with gobbledygook such as "Let us sum up <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s early childhood influences in terms of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">bio-psycho-</ENAMEX>social
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">determinants</ENAMEX>." (Let's not and say we did.) Never mind that it's even more badly
edited than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High Crimes</ENAMEX> . Never mind that this flimflam is padded to book
length with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> pages of irrelevant stories about other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">addicts</ENAMEX>. It doesn't
matter. This is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flytrap</ENAMEX>'s moment. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arianna Huffington</ENAMEX> is touting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Levin</ENAMEX> on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">air</ENAMEX>, and his book is stacked high by the register at my local Borders.

            
               The
sidebar on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bennett</ENAMEX>'s self-righteousness is . The sidebar on how <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ann</ENAMEX>
Coulter misrepresents a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> story is .
            

            More Flytrap
...

         
      
   
