
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patrick O'Brien</ENAMEX>'s <I>The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last</TIMEX> Campaign</I>

            ... hard upon forging
their unexpected <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alliance</ENAMEX> amid the quadrennial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panoply</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grand Old Party</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nominating</ENAMEX> convention, our protagonists, acting in unavoidable response to the
exigencies of a contest dominated by the incumbent's strategy and tactics, set
out for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">heartland</ENAMEX> in a manner similar to his, where, beneath storm-riven
skies suggestive of incunabular <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Turners</ENAMEX>, the desperate reality of their task
began to reveal itself, rising like a black basalt orogeny from the soft soils
of internecine enthusiasm.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Chapter 5</ENAMEX>

            ... the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">locomotive</ENAMEX>, a diesel-burning Class <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2900</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santa Fe</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">4-8-4</ENAMEX> that had been constructed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1943</TIMEX> but had survived <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the decades</TIMEX>
most admirably and now gleamed like a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX>'s lapel pin, was
gaining speed swiftly, its <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one hundred</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">five tons</NUMEX> departing another
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">whistle-stop</ENAMEX> in another anonymous <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inhabitants</ENAMEX> clustered where the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rails</ENAMEX> seemed to converge, their fluttering hands and smiling faces congealed
into a tuberous mirage that already was beginning to deliquesce, its bipedal
spores gamboling away from the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX> where, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">only moments</TIMEX> before, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> had stood to receive the traditional accolade from the traditional
close-packed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX>.

            The last <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>, with its
funereal <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">platform</ENAMEX> and tufts of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bunting</ENAMEX>, gave off a flapping chorus that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">enveloped Dole</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kemp</ENAMEX> as they looked backward down the rails. Around them
edged subalterns, each plucking away like a blue-suited migrant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX> the
decorations that went up before each stop. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX> had to work quickly, lest
momentum send the froufrou and gewgaws drifting onto the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roadbed</ENAMEX>. In a minute
the removal had been accomplished, and the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> on whose behalf this
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">excursion</ENAMEX> had been undertaken again had the expanded-steel protuberance to
themselves. Even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glassner</ENAMEX>, for <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">years Dole</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body man</ENAMEX> and coat <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carrier</ENAMEX>,
had retired to the common area, where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> would be attempting its usual
stab at gaiety. They believed in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX>; they had to believe in him, even as
his brooding presence infected the farthest corners of the campaign with an
acidity specific to him. His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would never admit what he was admitting:
that the prize he had chased almost all his adult life was bound to elude him
in the most humiliating manner.

            His capacity for gloom had ever equalled his capacity for
work, but he could never have foreseen his worst musings out-galloped by the
campaign of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, a broken-backed stumble in which no error was too small to
convert into an enormous problem. He had, in his wretched <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenties</TIMEX>, dangling by
a wrecked <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX> on a homemade exercise gibbet, accepted, no, hugged to himself
the knowledge that life was hard and then you died. It was damnably unnatural,
this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> to which he had most ironically ascended. When things were in their
proper order, a buoyant spirit led, not a mordant one, and what was he if not
the most mordant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>? It was a cruel fate to replay in parallax the
role he had taken <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX> back with the affable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kemp</ENAMEX>,
could be counted on to float above any malaise like an empty <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water cask</ENAMEX>. It was
as if he had been struck by a hail of red <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Kryptonite</ENAMEX> and instantly become the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bizarro</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>, immensely strong, yet unable to prevail against the
backward-beating current.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>, who at the rally had projected a steely
excitement, the contained enthusiasm of a veteran <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> grip of
his emotions but willing to share with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> what bits of them he
must, sank back into himself, simmering in a glumness he wished he could
contain but knew he could not. Terrible things had always happened to him, and
always would; this was only the latest of them, but it was a terrible thing of
a specifically galling nature. He was the most prestigious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passenger</ENAMEX> on a
hell-bound <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">train</ENAMEX>, a shining doomed conveyance hurtling down a narrow and fatal
track. Through all his trials, darkness had always been his strength, an
obsidian girder holding him to the path; now it stood to crush him and, perhaps
not coincidentally, the entire <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> ticket, which his opponent's
ever-clever <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">propagandists</ENAMEX> had labeled as "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole-Gingrich</ENAMEX>," as if he and the
pumpkin-headed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX> had conspired like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesuits</ENAMEX> to ruin the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kemp</ENAMEX> leaned closer,
speaking more loudly than was necessary, perhaps to compensate for the rush of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">air</ENAMEX> around them and the clatter of steel <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">wheels</ENAMEX> beneath and behind. "Something
preoccupies you, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kemp</ENAMEX> said. "I thought that was really neat back there,
didn't you?"

            It was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kemp</ENAMEX>'s habit to voice such banalities in an utterly
unironical manner, a gift of naiveté withheld from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> since birth and made
even more distant by life. Why could he not have been born a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kemp</ENAMEX>, blessed by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">luck</ENAMEX> and genes with the smiling disposition of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> who is shown a stable full
of ordure and instantly concludes that there must be a pony in there somewhere?
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> was sentenced to always know better than what he wanted to believe.

            "Yes, most assuredly," he replied, struggling not to
answer with a grunt. "I sense we might profit from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a few minutes</TIMEX> out of the
weather." Of course, there was no "weather" to speak of; but he had learned a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thousand years ago</TIMEX> that sometimes, he had to say something.

            "Certainly," his running mate said, stepping aside
so the older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> could enter the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">rail car</ENAMEX>. He did so with surety, using the
elbow of his bad <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX> to steady himself at the threshold, then raising both
fists in a stretch. At the far door, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">steward</ENAMEX> stood.

            "Your pleasure, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gentlemen</ENAMEX>."

            "A <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Diet Coke</ENAMEX>, if you will, please," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kemp</ENAMEX> chirped.
"Caffeine free."

            "None for me right the
moment, thanks."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> pulled off his suit jacket and assumed his usual
position in an overstuffed chair on the starboard side of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>. He loosened
his tie. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kemp</ENAMEX>, still wearing his jacket, did likewise.

            "What troubles you, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>?" he asked again. "Is
it the poll numbers? The back-bounce? We have as yet <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven weeks</TIMEX> to do the
things we must. Do not despair."

            "As you know, 'despair' is not in my vocabulary,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> said, leaning suddenly so that he was looking <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kemp</ENAMEX> in the eye. He wanted
to bark out the syllable that had become his hated signature, but did not. Damn
the myopic but all-seeing eyes of that news-ferret <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cramer</ENAMEX> for having the cruel
wit to reduce him to an onomatopoeia. No longer could he essay an "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Aaargh</ENAMEX>" in
public or private without apprehending in his <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">marrow</ENAMEX> that he had become what he
was described as being.

            "No, what is on my mind is the damnable situation
into which we have been thrust by this contest," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> continued, rising to his
feet. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and his railroad trick have forced us into a like strategy. I
would vastly prefer to travel by aeroplane--there is no substitute for the
swiftness, the ease, the comfort--but here we are, bumping along the ground
like a crippled millipede, waging a campaign that could have been waged in the
latter <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days of the last century</TIMEX>."

            "But surely, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob</ENAMEX>, you must acknowledge the romantic
appeal of the tactic," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kemp</ENAMEX> said. "At <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>'s grave, remember, it was you who
invoked the whistle in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night</TIMEX>, the long rumbling procession of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> carrying
someone else somewhere else."

            "Yes, yes, I recall my eloquence all too well,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> said, exasperated at having been caught in the web of his own rhetoric.
"But I was not running for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> then."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kemp grinned</ENAMEX> impishly. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob</ENAMEX>, you have been running
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1976</TIMEX>," he said. "What would you say to a little game,
something to take our minds away from the press of combat<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>"

            The suggestion relaxed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>. "Excellent," he said.
"Let us commence with a session. I will wait on the platform while you make
ready."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kemp</ENAMEX>, velellidous mop
shining like the crest of a blow-dried raptor, reached for their instruments.
Upon joining the ticket, he had instantly made it his habit to maintain the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">equipment</ENAMEX>.

            Amid the clotted air on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">platform</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> let his eyes
ease into <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night</TIMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob</ENAMEX>, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>!" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kemp</ENAMEX> called from the center of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">railway</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>. He was holding up a pair of grey rectangles, linked by a black
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">umbilicus</ENAMEX> and each winking a single garnet eye. "Excellent news! I have found
the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Game Boys</ENAMEX>. The batteries are as fresh as new flounder. Lose not a
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minute</TIMEX>."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> could never have predicted that in this, his
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">grimmest hour</TIMEX>, after all these years of morosely pursuing the presidency, he
would come to enjoy as his particular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> a chronically cheery former
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">footballer</ENAMEX> who could broadcast an enthusiasm for gimcrack economic theory in
such a way that one could not tell if he was embracing it or mocking it. Now,
as he squinted at the red lights in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kemp</ENAMEX>'s fists and felt his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">companion</ENAMEX>'s boon
personality radiating in his direction, he also faced the knowledge that life
was more durable than pain, more difficult than you could have imagined, and
yet still you lived, as he now lived, seeing that his last campaign, the battle
to the candidacy, would be his last success. He stepped inside and closed the
door on the wind.

         
      
   
