
   
   
      
         
            Requiem for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liberal</ENAMEX>

            This is my last "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Strange</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bedfellow</ENAMEX>." When I return from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">vacation</TIMEX>, I'm going to take a break from
politics and try my hand at a column about the arts. To ease the transition, I
thought it might be fitting to pay tribute to someone whose career spans these
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> worlds. He is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sidney R. Yates</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">congressman</ENAMEX> who represents my
birth-district on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North Side</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yates</ENAMEX> retires at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the end of</TIMEX>
this congressional term at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">89</NUMEX>, he will have served in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>, but for one
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two-year</TIMEX> interruption, since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1948</TIMEX>. Leaving with him, I fear, will be not only a
chunk of postwar history but much of the enlightenment that remains in the
lower <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chamber</ENAMEX>.

            I'm far
from objective on this topic. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yates</ENAMEX> gave me my first paid job as a
congressional page <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many summers ago</TIMEX>, and the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> writing I ever did about
politics was answering constituent mail in his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>. But my real gratitude is
for what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yates</ENAMEX>' example teaches: that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> aren't required to preen and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pander</ENAMEX> or to speak only for the parochial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">interests</ENAMEX> of their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">districts</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yates</ENAMEX>
has held the esteem and affection of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> he has represented for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">century</ENAMEX> by thinking about their good in a more elevated way. He is a liberal,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the nearly extinct <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roosevelt-Truman-Kennedy</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson</ENAMEX> variety. But in
another way, I think of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sidney Yates</ENAMEX> as one of the only true conservatives
around. He has found his mission in preserving what matters in our culture, and
in standing in the way of attempts to coarsen and reduce it.

            Up on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few weeks ago</TIMEX>, I stopped by his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Rayburn Building</ENAMEX> for lunch. As ever, I was greeted by his chief <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mary</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bain</ENAMEX>, who is an extraordinary story of liberal longevity in her own right. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX>
came to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> to work on the New Deal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Youth Administration</ENAMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1935</TIMEX> and has been with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yates</ENAMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1965</TIMEX>. She and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> were busy sorting <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>' worth of files and packing them up for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Truman Library</ENAMEX>. On the table
were things they had found: a note from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor Roosevelt</ENAMEX> expressing outrage
about some now obscure postal reorganization bill, and a yellowed copy of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Sun-Times</ENAMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 15, 1965</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adlai Stevenson</ENAMEX>
died.

            Sifting
through these relics left <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yates</ENAMEX> in a more wistful mood than usual. Though he
can usually be counted on for a bit of patter from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gilbert</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sullivan</ENAMEX>, most
of which he knows by heart, he told me he felt it had been too long since he
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">reread Edmond Rostand</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cyrano de Bergerac</ENAMEX> in the classic translation by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian Hooker</ENAMEX>. He began reciting it for me from memory:

            I carry my adornments on
my soul.I do not dress up like a popinjay; But inwardly, I keep my
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">daintiness</ENAMEX>.

            The lines
apply to no one so well as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">congressman</ENAMEX> from the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th District of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>, who must be the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX> left in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> who avoids publicity
and whose style is to follow the dictates of his conscience without making a
spectacle of himself doing so.

            
As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yates</ENAMEX> recounted over <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">soup</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sandwiches</ENAMEX>, he
didn't go into politics to save the world. He did it because he was bored
working for his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father-in-law</ENAMEX>'s law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1939</TIMEX>, he ran against the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> machine for a seat on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> and not surprisingly lost.
Recognizing that the only way in was with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blessing</ENAMEX> of the regular
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organization</ENAMEX>, he got it in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1948</TIMEX>, when he was allowed to run for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> as a
sacrificial <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">lamb</ENAMEX>. According to the elaborate ethnic spoils system of those
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North Side</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> seat belonged to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Germans</ENAMEX>. But the German
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> who'd been slated to run decided in the face of a looming <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican</ENAMEX>
sweep that he'd like to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">postmaster</ENAMEX>, so <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yates</ENAMEX>, who is <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX>, got his chance.
He ran on a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> ticket with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Truman</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stevenson</ENAMEX> for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Douglas</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX>. "I was the tail on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX>, and we all
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">won</ENAMEX>," he said.

            Almost as
soon as he was elected, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yates</ENAMEX> attempted self-immolation by voting against the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">McCarran Act</ENAMEX>, which placed <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">McCarthyite</ENAMEX> restrictions on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Colleagues</ENAMEX> told him that if he voted against it, he'd be a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> term
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">congressman</ENAMEX>, and they were nearly right. His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponent</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1950</TIMEX> passed out pink
leaflets asking if the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th District</ENAMEX> wanted a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">congressman</ENAMEX> who voted
with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communist Party</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yates</ENAMEX> wrote a thoughtful letter to his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">constituents</ENAMEX>--the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">several hundred</NUMEX> to come--explaining why he thought
the bill was unconstitutional and eked out a narrow re-election. After
surviving another close call in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1952</TIMEX>, he was regularly returned by lopsided
margins. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>, he continued to get excited about injustices that
bothered hardly anyone else. Around the same time, he saved the career of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hyman</ENAMEX>
Rickover, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> of the nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">fleet</ENAMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rickover</ENAMEX> was passed over for
promotion to admiral in part because of anti-Semitism in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy</ENAMEX>.

            Though he had the endorsement of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard J. Daley</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yates</ENAMEX> was never a machine <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1962</TIMEX> he had become the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">delegation</ENAMEX> by virtue of seniority, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daley</ENAMEX> decided it was time for him to run
for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>, in a kamikaze challenge to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">incumbent</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Everett</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dirksen</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yates</ENAMEX> lost, and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">freshman</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Rostenkowski</ENAMEX> assumed his place
as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">delegation</ENAMEX>. After a stint working for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stevenson</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mission</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yates</ENAMEX> returned. But with his seniority erased,
he began to narrow his focus to the issues that truly motivated him: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>,
the arts, and the environment.

            The year
he returned to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1965</TIMEX>, the national endowments for the arts and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">humanities</ENAMEX> were voted into existence. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yates</ENAMEX> became <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>
Appropriations <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">subcommittee</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Interior</ENAMEX>, the national endowment
budgets fell under his jurisdiction. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1970s</TIMEX>, he was known as a
tough-minded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporter</ENAMEX> who could be counted on for a meticulous review of how
the endowments were spending their money. But after attempts to eliminate them
began under <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>, and intensified with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mapplethorpe</ENAMEX> fiasco,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yates</ENAMEX>' career became preoccupied with keeping them alive.

            
He has managed to do so, at times through sheer
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> of will. Other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> invite <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrities</ENAMEX> to testify
before their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committees</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yates</ENAMEX> invited <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yo-Yo</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Ma</ENAMEX> to play a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bach</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">suite</ENAMEX> before
his, soothing the savage breast of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NEA</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX>. After <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> lost
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NEA</ENAMEX> budget was cut in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yates</ENAMEX> is battling to save
it once more. He now leaves that mission to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">New Yorkers</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louise Slaughter</ENAMEX>,
a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amo Houghton</ENAMEX>, a patrician <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>. Whether his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">successors</ENAMEX> in
this role succeed or not, I suspect that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yates</ENAMEX> will <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> be better
remembered for another accomplishment: the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Holocaust Memorial Museum</ENAMEX>,
which he and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Addie</ENAMEX>, worked for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> to bring into existence.

            As we finished lunch, I
asked whether I was right in assuming <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yates</ENAMEX> thought term limits were a bad
idea. "To the contrary, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob</ENAMEX>," he declared. "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Twenty-four</NUMEX> terms is enough for
anyone."

         
      
   
