
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Beasts</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bus</ENAMEX>

            Run for your life! Now the
press is actually hitting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. Even saintly <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">C-SPAN</ENAMEX> has turned
violent.

            
               By <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Simon</ENAMEX>
            

            
               (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1477</NUMEX> words)
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joan Egland</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 68</TIMEX>, came
to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX> rally in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ames</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX>, aware that politics is rough-and-tumble. But
she was unaware that it had become a contact sport, until a videocamera smacked
her in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>. "I'm sorry ," she said to the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cameraman</ENAMEX> who had
whacked her with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">40 pounds</NUMEX> of cold <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">steel</ENAMEX>, "but that was my head you
hit!" The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cameraman</ENAMEX> looked at her briefly, sneered, and then returned to his
shot. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joan Egland</ENAMEX> was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prop. Politicians</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffs</ENAMEX> assemble crowds to form the
background for TV pictures. The props are expected to applaud; they are not
expect to complain.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanley</ENAMEX>
Egland, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">72</TIMEX>, went up to the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> and tapped him on the shoulder.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cameramen</ENAMEX>--officially they are known as "videographers" though <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">some years ago</TIMEX>
they were nicknamed "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Visigoths</ENAMEX>"--hate to be touched: It jiggles the camera. The
young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> whirled around, and that's when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Egland</ENAMEX> gave him a shove. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX>,
when you smash somebody in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> with a large piece of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">metal</ENAMEX>, you are
expected to apologize.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX> was oblivious to
all this, of course. Surrounded by cameras, sound <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, still <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">photographers</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX>, he could barely see the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>, let alone take notice of the
casualties in it. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iowa State Memorial Union</ENAMEX> was a small
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>--campaigns try to get the smallest room possible to make the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowds</ENAMEX> look
bigger, and so the press <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horde</ENAMEX> must muscle its way through tight spaces. The
pencil <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX> can sometimes hang around the edges, writing sardonic little
comments in their notebooks, but the TV <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crews</ENAMEX> must get good pictures and good
sound. That is why they exist.

            So the
major danger of the press is not, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Fallows</ENAMEX> argues, that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX>
threaten democracy by their shallow and relentless cynicism. And the major
danger is not, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathleen Hall Jamieson</ENAMEX> argues, that political coverage is
"strategy saturated," "poll-driven," and "manipulated by artful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultants</ENAMEX>."
The main danger of the press corps in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> today is that they can knock your
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">block</ENAMEX> off. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bus</ENAMEX> have become the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">beasts</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bus</ENAMEX>.

            The number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crews</ENAMEX> chasing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> around grows
larger every election cycle. At an event in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>, there were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crews</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX> alone, including a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">60 Minutes</ENAMEX> , one for a special
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> was doing, one for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Morning</TIMEX> , another for the news that
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, and one for the "<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">pool</ENAMEX>"--the take-turns-and-share system sometimes
imposed on the press in a futile attempt to cut down on this sort of
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">insanity</ENAMEX>.

            Multiply that by the other
major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX> plus <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">C-SPAN</ENAMEX>, add the local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">affiliates</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">independents</ENAMEX>,
and you begin to get the idea. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Just a few</TIMEX> presidential cycles ago, you would
see a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX> from, say <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tallahassee</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fla.</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rockford</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ill.</ENAMEX>, only if a local man
was running.

            Today, TV <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crews</ENAMEX> from
smaller markets are in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Hampshire</ENAMEX>, and other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> as a matter of
routine. And it's not just because time on the "bird" (the communications
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">satellite</ENAMEX>) has gotten cheap. Such coverage is good marketing: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Your Live</ENAMEX> at
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">NewsTeam</ENAMEX> covers <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Election '96</TIMEX>!" It also looks good at license-renewal time:
Your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">station</ENAMEX> has helped fulfill its "public service" commitment.
License-renewal applications don't discuss, though, how many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> you have
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">conked</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>.

            Also,
as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Brokaw</ENAMEX> notes, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> "every local television station and tabloid
show and news <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> and whatever is all organized for what I call <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Big Event</ENAMEX>
television. ... It's cheaper than going out and doing hard work or breaking
original stories or investing time in doing investigative stories. They get a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">truck</ENAMEX> and picture up and they look like a national news <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>."

            At the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holiday Inn</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Des Moines</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX> showed up for a campaign brunch with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">43</NUMEX> camera <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crews</ENAMEX>. "Please move
away," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin McLaughlin</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forbes</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Polk County</ENAMEX>, pleaded with a
press corps that insisted on standing between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>. The
press did not move away. It couldn't: There was no "away." Cameramen, sound
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, still <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">photographers</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> clogged all available space, jostling
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> as they sat and ate. "I paid good money!" a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> yelled at a camera crew
planted directly between him and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>. The sound <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> turned around and
mouthed an apology but did not move.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Four days later</TIMEX>, at lunch
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nashua</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.H.</ENAMEX>, at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha</ENAMEX>'s Exchange, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">brew</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pub</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forbes</ENAMEX>
engaged in a staple of primary campaigning: a "meet and greet" (sometimes
called a "grip and grin") with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">diners</ENAMEX>. It is not easy under the best of
circumstances--few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">diners</ENAMEX> actually want to be interrupted by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> while
chewing--but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX> was still being followed by an enormous press contingent.
As soon as he exited his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bus</ENAMEX>, he was surrounded by camera <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crews</ENAMEX> and boom mikes
arching overhead like brontosauri looking for lunch.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX> entered the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">restaurant</ENAMEX> and walked over to the candy counter where he purchased some
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homemade</ENAMEX> fudge for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3.42</NUMEX>, handing over a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10</NUMEX> bill and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">two pennies</NUMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX> carries pennies? I wrote in my notebook.) He then put a piece of fudge
in his mouth, chewed, and turned toward the cameras. Which is when they surged
forward to catch whatever gems might usher forth from his lips and when a
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX>-ish <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> waiting for a table got hit in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> by a camera.

            "Could you please watch
out?" she asked the cameraman.

            "Shut up!" he screamed at
her.

            "What did you say?" she
said to the cameraman.

            "Shut up, shut up, shut
up!" he screamed at her. What the prop didn't understand was that she was
ruining his sound. Without thinking about it, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s TV <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> has come to
expect near-perfection when it comes to sound and video. The pictures must be
in focus and steady--no bounces, no jiggles. And the sound must be
interference-free. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> are listening in stereo now.

            "These
crushes do get big, but it's what we do ," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Zirinsky</ENAMEX>, executive
producer for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Campaign</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">'96</NUMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS News</ENAMEX> (and model for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holly Hunter</ENAMEX> character
in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Broadcast News</ENAMEX> ). "Very infrequently do you miss a major shot if
you're a network <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX>. It doesn't happen ." And they don't miss the sound
either. "Sound becomes so critical," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zirinsky</ENAMEX> says. "If a whole news
story is one comment, you don't want to miss it."

            And so you don't miss it. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX> swallowed the fudge.
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Good</ENAMEX>," he said.

            Then he strode through the
press crush, knowing it would part for him. But the aisles couldn't accommodate
all the cameramen and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">photographers</ENAMEX> who wanted a good angle on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX>. One
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cameraman</ENAMEX> leapt up on a table as astonished <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">diners</ENAMEX> looked up at him. Then
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX> plunged into the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen</ENAMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Guys</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX>, we have food here!" a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">waitress</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">wailed</ENAMEX> as one camera <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX> dragged its cable over a tray of cheeseburger.

            The camera and sound
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> blame <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producers</ENAMEX> who, when the competition comes up with a picture or
soundbite you missed, don't want to hear excuses about how you didn't want to
trample some old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX>.

            And not
just old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ladies</ENAMEX>. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next day</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forbes</ENAMEX> went to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sunapee</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.H.</ENAMEX>, where his campaign
searched out the quaintest general <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> they could find to demonstrate how
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX>, unlike <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamar Alexander</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day before</TIMEX>, knew the price of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk</ENAMEX>. Quaint
general <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> have quaint narrow aisles, and the few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> inside were
quickly run over by a metal-packing press corps. Which is where I got slammed
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> by a cameraman. As I struggled to stay on my feet, I looked at the
side of his camera and saw a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">C-SPAN</ENAMEX> decal. Getting whacked in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">C-SPAN</ENAMEX> is like getting kneed in the groin by Mother <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Teresa</ENAMEX>. "Does <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian Lamb</ENAMEX>
know you're behaving this way?" I asked my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assailant</ENAMEX>.

            Neither the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Communications Commission</ENAMEX> nor the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Elections Commission</ENAMEX> keeps track of injuries to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX> by the press.
All evidence is anecdotal. But any number of "anecdotes" showed up in the press
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff Greenfield</ENAMEX>, writing in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 4</TIMEX>, told of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamar</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander</ENAMEX> rally in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Des Moines</ENAMEX> where he saw a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cameraman</ENAMEX> accidentally slam a
tripod into the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>, "knocking her into semi-consciousness."
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Associated Press</ENAMEX> reported that in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center Barnstead</ENAMEX>, a tiny <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Hampshire</ENAMEX>
village, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX> was unable to talk to any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX> because of all the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">media</ENAMEX> around him, and that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffer</ENAMEX> had to rescue <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nephew</ENAMEX> from an
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">onrushing</ENAMEX> camera <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX> by yelling, "Stop it! You're squashing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>!" The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nashua Telegraph</ENAMEX> reported on jostling within the press <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horde</ENAMEX> that led to
a fight in which "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> cameraman was left lying in the snow."

            If the cameramen are
turning on each other, maybe there's some hope the rest of us will be
safe.

         
      
   
