
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor</ENAMEX>'s Cheap Thrill

            Until <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Sweeney</ENAMEX> took over
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFL-CIO</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> had barely mentioned the labor
movement. They didn't have to. The rich got richer. The median wage fell. In
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">third quarter of 1996</TIMEX>, after a brief reversal, it went back to falling
again. No one has the nerve to ask for a raise. For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, labor, or what was
left of it, did nothing at all. Then <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last winter</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFL-CIO</ENAMEX> voted to spend <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$35</NUMEX>
million for "voter education." Not contributions to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>: i.e., hard
money. But just telling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>' voting records: soft money.
And suddenly denunciation of "labor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bosses</ENAMEX>" is on every <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> lip.

            Now, it's a pittance, right?
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$35 million</NUMEX>? Business vastly outspends labor on political contributions--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX>
to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX>. So why does the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> worry? Why is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$35 million</NUMEX>, against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">hundreds of millions</NUMEX>, such a
crisis? Why is <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> control of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> now at stake, with such a
laughable amount? Because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> has big, big trouble if there's even a
whisper that:

            Your real wage has
fallen.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Inequality</ENAMEX> is spreading like
a plague.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> and student loans
are now "in play."

            With only
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$35 million</NUMEX>, hey, word could leak out. Maybe business can outspend labor by
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">90 to one</NUMEX>, but it can never spend enough to cancel the message
out.

            But isn't it unfair for union <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> to have to pay for
this, from "compulsory" dues, when many vote <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>? No, it is not unfair.
First, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> can opt out, or object. Typically, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> get cards:
"Remember, you can opt out of paying dues for extra political work."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Conservatives</ENAMEX> have sued <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX> over this for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Unions</ENAMEX> must have major
audits, segregate money. There is notice, hearing, rebate procedure. (The kind
of due process <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> dream of for the poor but never get.)

            Compare this machinery with
your rights as a company <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stockholder</ENAMEX>. Can you opt out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s
soft-money political spending? No. Do you even know what they're doing? No.
With <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of us in mutual funds, who has any idea what political messages
we're paying for?

            But back to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX>. Do
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> in fact opt out, with all their legal rights to do so? No. The highest
opt-out union right now is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communications Workers of America</ENAMEX>, which until
recently was an "open <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX>," meaning that many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> never paid dues at all.
Out of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">600,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CWA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>, there are currently <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 2,000</NUMEX> objectors. In other
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX>, the opt-out rate is much, much lower.

            So if union <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> do vote
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>, why don't more of them opt out of soft-money spending on ads that,
implicitly at least, criticize <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>? Maybe <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> want to
cast their own votes, but they still like to hear what their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX> says.
Because of abortion or gun control or the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX>, I may decide I want to vote
for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>. But don't I want to hear my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX>'s voice on issues where the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">union</ENAMEX> has some expertise? That's why labor is making fewer endorsements. Just
provide the consumer advice. On wages, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>. Let people
make up their own minds.

            The notion
that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of union <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> are being forced against their will to help
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">finance</ENAMEX> this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX> campaign is simply a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> fantasy.

            
When labor gets involved in politics, this is
not a detour from its "real" job of negotiating wages and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX>. Soft money for
voter education. That is labor's real job, the very core purpose of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">union</ENAMEX>. Ever since the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> decision that required the "opt out," the
court has drawn a wobbly line: Negotiating wages? OK. Discussing politics? Oh,
that's an "extracurricular," unrelated to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX>'s "real" work.

            But as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Felix Frankfurter</ENAMEX>
wrote in dissent, this distinction is silly. After all, what is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>
but a job benefit? Either the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX> gets the pension directly at the bargaining
table ... or indirectly in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>. Or what about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s poster <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>,
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> leave"? Crawl off in a corner and give birth, without pay? Still, it's
something. Either labor can get it directly from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX>, or labor can get it
from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> via <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>. What's the difference, except in the latter case
all of us benefit?

            At least <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Frankfurter</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dealer</ENAMEX>, understood--as we no longer can--what a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX> is supposed to do. In
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Europe</ENAMEX> the labor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">movement</ENAMEX> often began first as a "labor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">parliament</ENAMEX>
was the bargaining table.

            But when labor defends
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>, isn't it still being a special interest? No. What's unique about
labor is: It's not a special interest or a single issue. Special interest? It's
not like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">R.J. Reynolds</ENAMEX> looking for a tax break. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFL-CIO</ENAMEX> is never, or
rarely, looking for something that helps the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFL-CIO</ENAMEX> purely as an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX>.
"Look at the last session," an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFL-CIO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer friend</ENAMEX> said to me recently, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">What</ENAMEX>
was labor fighting for? Stop <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> cuts. Raise minimum wage." These
"soft-money" fights mostly help ... not union <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chiefs</ENAMEX>, or even <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>, but the
nonunion <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masses</ENAMEX>: the private-sector <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">90 percent</NUMEX> who have no <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX> at all.

            Who benefits, then? You. Me.
Aren't we nonunion types the freeloaders? Why do the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX> have
to pay for our battles? That is the real unfairness of soft money.

            Of late, business groups
have begun running "counter ads." Sure. But what can they "counter" <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">with?</ENAMEX> "You
don't need a minimum wage"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX> "Let's cut back <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX> "Isn't your
standard of living getting too high"? No, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Business</ENAMEX> can't counter the ads. It
has to change the subject. Thus: "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bosses</ENAMEX>!" (But what about business
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bosses</ENAMEX>?)

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union</ENAMEX> corruption!" (That's
been true, sometimes, but who pays the money to corrupt <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX>?)

            The frightening thing about
labor soft money is that on the merits of the issues, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> is defenseless.
What do you say to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who want the standard of living to rise? For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 years</TIMEX>
the median wage has dropped, while the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> have hauled in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> from business <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>.

            Isn't labor, with its soft
money, seeking to raise the standard of living for those of us with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">W-2s</ENAMEX>, the
closest thing we have now to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>?

         
      
   
