
   
   
      
         
            Maledict<I>oratory</I>

            The high costs of low
language.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday, Jan. 14, 1996</TIMEX>: A
day that will live in--well, not infamy, exactly. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blasphemy</ENAMEX> would be closer to
it.

            Early <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">that afternoon</TIMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh Steelers</ENAMEX> defeated the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Indianapolis Colts</ENAMEX> to win the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">Football</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conference</ENAMEX> championship. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Linebacker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg Lloyd</ENAMEX>, accepting the trophy
in front of a national television <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>, responded with enthusiasm. "Let's
see if we can bring this damn thing back here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>," he said, "along with
the [expletive] <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Super Bowl</ENAMEX>."

            A few
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> later, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Irvin</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dallas Cowboys</ENAMEX> offered this spirited defense
of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX> on TV after his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> won the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Football Conference</ENAMEX> title:
"Nobody deserves it more than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry Switzer</ENAMEX>. He took all of this [expletive]
."

            Iwatched those episodes, and, incongruous as it may sound,
I thought of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Tynan</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>'s great postwar drama <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> was no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> football, but he was a fan of swearing. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thirty years earlier</TIMEX>, almost
to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tynan</ENAMEX> was interviewed on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BBC</ENAMEX> television in his capacity as
literary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Theater</ENAMEX> and asked if he would allow the
theater to present a play in which sex took place on stage. "Certainly," he
replied. "I think there are very few rational <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in this world to whom the
word '[expletive]' is particularly diabolical or revolting or totally
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">forbidden</ENAMEX>."

            It turned out there were a
few more than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tynan</ENAMEX> thought. Within <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24 hours</TIMEX>, resolutions had been introduced
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House of Commons</ENAMEX> calling for his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">prosecution</ENAMEX> on charges of obscenity,
for his removal as a theater <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX>, and for censure of the network for
allowing an obscene word to go out on the airwaves. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tynan</ENAMEX> escaped punishment,
but he acquired a public reputation for tastelessness that he carried for the
rest his life. To much of ordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>, he became the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who had said
"[expletive]" on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BBC</ENAMEX>.

            Neither
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg Lloyd</ENAMEX> nor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Irvin</ENAMEX> was so stigmatized. "It's live television," <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed Markey</ENAMEX> said, rationalizing the outbursts. "It's an emotional
moment. These things happen." Irvin wasn't about to let that stand. "I knew
exactly what I was saying," he insisted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later</TIMEX>. "Those of you who can't believe
I said it--believe it."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Swearing</ENAMEX> isn't the only public act that Western
civilization condones <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> but didn't <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30 years ago</TIMEX>. But it is one of the most
interesting. It is everywhere, impossible to avoid or tune out.

             

            

               I am sitting in a meeting at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>, talking with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleague</ENAMEX> about a
business circumstance that may possibly go against us. "In that case, we're
[expletive] ," he says. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Five years ago</TIMEX>, he would have said "screwed." <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Twenty</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX>, he would have said, "We're in big trouble." Societal tolerance of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">profanity</ENAMEX> requires us to increase our dosage as time goes on.
 

               

               I am walking along a suburban <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX>, trailing a class of pre-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">schoolers</ENAMEX> who
are linked to each other by a rope. A pair of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-agers</ENAMEX> passes us in the other
direction. By the time they have reached the end of the line of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, they
have tossed off a whole catalog of obscenities I did not even hear until I was
well into adolescence, let alone use in casual conversation on a public <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX>.
 

               

               I am talking to a distinguished <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> of public policy about a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">foundation</ENAMEX> grant. I tell her something she wasn't aware of before. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1965</TIMEX>, the
appropriate response was "no kidding." In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, you do not say "no kidding." It
is limp and ineffectual. If you are surprised at all, you say what she says:
"No shit."

            

            What word is taboo in middle-class <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>? There
are a couple of credible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>: The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>-letter word for "vagina" remains
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">off-limits</ENAMEX> in polite conversation (although that has more to do with feminism
than with profanity), and the slang expression for those who engage in oral sex
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">males</ENAMEX> is not yet acceptable by the standards of office-meeting
etiquette.

            But aside from a few
exceptions, the supply of genuinely offensive language has dwindled almost to
nothing as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 20th century</TIMEX> comes to an end; the currency of swearing has been
inflated to the brink of worthlessness. When almost anything can be said in
public, profanity ceases to exist in any meaningful way at all.

            That
most of the forbidden words of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1950s</TIMEX> are no longer forbidden will come as
news to nobody: The steady debasement of the common language is only one of
many social strictures that have loosened from the previous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> to the
current. What is important is that profanity served a variety of
purposes for a long time in Western culture. It does not serve those purposes
any more.

            What purposes? There are a couple of plausible answers. One
of them is emotional release. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Graves</ENAMEX>, who wrote a book in the 1920s
called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Future of Swearing</ENAMEX> , thought that profanity was the adult
replacement for childhood tears. There comes a point in life, he wrote, when
"wailing is rightly discouraged, and groans are also considered a signal of
extreme weakness. Silence under suffering is usually impossible." So one
reaches back for a word one does not normally use, and utters it without undue
embarrassment or guilt. And <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> feels better--even stimulated.

            The anthropologist Ashley
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Montagu</ENAMEX>, whose <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anatomy of Swearing</ENAMEX> , published in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1967</TIMEX>, is the definitive
modern take on the subject, saw profanity as a safety valve rather than a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">stimulant</ENAMEX>, a verbal substitute for physical aggression. When someone swears,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Montagu</ENAMEX> wrote, "potentially noxious energy is converted into a form that
renders it comparatively innocuous."

            One
could point out, in arguing against the safety-valve theory, that as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>
has grown more profane in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past 30 years</TIMEX>, it has also grown more violent,
not less. But this is too simple. It isn't just the supply of dirty words that
matters, it's their emotive power. If they have lost that power through
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">overuse</ENAMEX>, it's perfectly plausible to say that their capacity to deter
aggressive behavior has weakened as well.

            But there is something else important to say about
swearing--that it represents the invocation of those ideas a society considers
powerful, awesome, and a little scary.

            I'm not sure there is an
easy way to convey to anybody <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">under 30</TIMEX>, for example, the sheer emotive force
that the word "[expletive]" possessed in the urban childhood culture of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX>. It was the verbal link to a secret act none of us understood but
that was known to carry enormous consequences in the adult world. It was the
embodiment of both pleasure and danger. It was not a word or an idea to mess
with. When it was used, it was used, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ashley Montagu</ENAMEX> said, "sotto
voce , like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">smuggler</ENAMEX> cautiously making his way across a forbidden
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">frontier</ENAMEX>."

            In that
culture, the word "[expletive]" was not only obscene, it was profane, in the
original sense: It took an important idea in vain. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Profanity</ENAMEX> can be an act of
religious defiance, but it doesn't have to be. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greeks</ENAMEX> tempted fate by
invoking the names of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">superiors</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mount Olympus</ENAMEX>; they also swore upon
everyday <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">objects</ENAMEX> whose properties they respected but did not fully understand.
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">By the Cabbage</ENAMEX>!" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Socrates</ENAMEX> is supposed to have said in moments of stress, and
that was for good reason. He believed that cabbage cured hangovers, and as
such, carried sufficient power and mystery to invest any moment with the
requisite emotional charge.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">These days</TIMEX>, none of us believes in cabbage in the way
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Socrates</ENAMEX> did, or in the gods in the way most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Athenians</ENAMEX> did. Most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> tell
poll-takers that they believe in God, but few of them in a way that would make
it impossible to take His name in vain: That requires an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Old Testament</ENAMEX> piety
that disappeared from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> middle-class life a long time ago.

            Nor do we believe in sex
any more the way most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> believed in it a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">generation ago</TIMEX>: as an act of profound mystery and importance that one did not
engage in, or discuss, or even invoke, without a certain amount of excitement
and risk. We have trivialized and routinized sex to the point where it just
doesn't carry the emotional freight it carried in the schoolyards and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedrooms</ENAMEX>
of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1950s</TIMEX>.

            Many
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enlightened people</ENAMEX> consider this to be a great improvement over a society in
which sex generated not only emotion and power, but fear. For the moment, I
wish to insist only on this <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point: When sexuality loses its power to awe,
it loses its power to create genuine swearing. When we convert it into a casual
form of recreation, we shouldn't be surprised to hear <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">linebackers</ENAMEX> using the
word "[expletive]" on national television.

            To profane something, in other words, one must believe in
it. The cheapening of profanity in modern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> represents, more than
anything else, the crumbling of belief. There are very few ideas left at this
point that are awesome or frightening enough for us to enforce a taboo against
them.

            The instinctive response
of most educated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to the disappearance of any taboo is to applaud it, but
this is wrong. Healthy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">societies</ENAMEX> need a decent supply of verbal taboos and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">prohibitions</ENAMEX>, if only as yardsticks by which ordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> can measure and
define themselves. By violating these taboos over and over, some succeed in
defining themselves as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebels</ENAMEX>. Others violate them on special occasions to
derive an emotional release. Forbidden language is one of the ways we remind
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> that there are rules to everyday life, and consequences for breaking
them. When we forget this principle, or cease to accept it, it is not just our
language that begins to fray at the edges.

            What do we do about it?
Well, we could pass a law against swearing. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mussolini</ENAMEX> actually did that. He
decreed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trains</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">buses</ENAMEX>, in addition to running on time, had to carry
signs that read "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Non</ENAMEX> bestemmiare per l'onore <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">d'Italia</ENAMEX>." ("Do not swear for the
honor of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>.") The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commuters</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX> reacted to those signs exactly as you
would expect: They cursed them.

            What <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mussolini</ENAMEX> could not
do, I am reasonably sure that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">1990s</NUMEX> cannot do, nor
would I wish it. I merely predict that sometime in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the coming generation</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">profanity</ENAMEX> will return in a meaningful way. It served too many purposes for too
many years of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> life to disappear on a permanent basis. We need it.

            And so I am reasonably
sure that when my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, there will once again be words so
awesome that they cannot be uttered without important consequences. This will
not only represent a new stage of linguistic evolution, it will be a token of
moral revival. What the dirty words will be, God only knows.

         
      
   
