
   
   
      
         
            Sorry Excuse

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> has been
roundly denounced for his "apology tour" of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Majority Whip</ENAMEX> Rep.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom DeLay</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>, implied the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s expressions of regret about slavery
were almost treasonous. "Here's a flower <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> with gray hairs doing exactly
what he did back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '60s</TIMEX>: He's apologizing for the actions of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>. ... It just offends me that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> is,
directly or indirectly, attacking his own <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> in a foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">land</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> wrote that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> had "groveled" in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Novak</ENAMEX> called the
apology for slavery "ridiculous." Others have charged that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">contrition</ENAMEX> regarding the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> failure to prevent genocide in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rwanda</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> was
cheap and hypocritical, since it was a considered decision, not (as he implied)
some kind of oversight, and there is no reason to suppose the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
will decide differently if it happens again.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fair</ENAMEX>
points? Not really. Once again, loathing for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is making it hard for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to see straight. These objections conflate complaints about this
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s personal shortcomings with the question of how any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> should
represent the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> abroad. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ought Clinton</ENAMEX> have gone to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX> and
simply not mentioned slavery? Should he have noted it but offered no view? Can
any world <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> travel to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rwanda</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> and not discuss genocide? To do so
would be heartless and insulting. It's hard to believe that even a primitive
such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeLay</ENAMEX> thinks the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> should play <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">emperor</ENAMEX>, never explaining or
apologizing for his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s actions. Then again, that was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX>'s
position. "I will never apologize for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States of America</ENAMEX>, I don't
care what the facts are," he said during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1988</TIMEX> campaign, after a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cruiser</ENAMEX> had mistakenly shot down an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iranian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX>, killing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">290</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX>.

            It's not just <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s sympathetic promiscuity that
accounts for the recent boom in the atonement. Apologies for national failings,
both domestic and foreign, are in fashion not just in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> but
also in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>, and elsewhere. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> reason is that honesty has become
less costly since the end of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> no longer has an
enormous propaganda apparatus trained against us. Now the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> of the West
can admit wrongdoing without the fear that they are giving ammunition to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX> of freedom.

            But when
are national apologies sensible? Offered casually or indiscriminately, they can
look like sops to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">constituencies</ENAMEX> rather than expressions of genuine regret. No
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nation</ENAMEX> should want to turn into <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Brock</ENAMEX>. I don't think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has reached
the point where saying he's sorry is an empty gesture, but he may be flirting
with it. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> of his apologies in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX> meet the test. A <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> one doesn't.

            
The best case for apology is a great and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">indisputable</ENAMEX> national misdeed. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX>'s apology to <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II-</ENAMEX>era
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">internees</ENAMEX> falls into this category, as does the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vatican</ENAMEX>'s apology to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX>. So also do <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s comments in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Uganda</ENAMEX> about
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">slavery</ENAMEX>. The objections--that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Africans</ENAMEX>, too, dealt in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">slaves</TIMEX>; that slaves came
from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Africa</ENAMEX>, not <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Uganda</ENAMEX>; that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX>, not <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Africans</ENAMEX> deserve the
apology--are nit-picking. Here's what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> actually said: "Going back to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> before we were even a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European Americans</ENAMEX> received the fruits of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slave</ENAMEX> trade. And we were wrong in that." To say that white <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>
wrongly benefited from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slave</ENAMEX> trade doesn't imply that white <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> were
exclusively responsible.

            On the
other hand, an apology can be justified without being required or even
desirable. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has decided, for a variety of reasons, that a domestic
apology for slavery isn't a good idea. This does not require him to observe a
taboo on the topic abroad.

            Somewhat more troubling was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s apology for not
intervening to prevent the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Rwandan</ENAMEX> genocide. Here's what he said:

            The international
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">community</ENAMEX>, together with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX>, must bear its share of
responsibility for this tragedy, as well. We did not act quickly enough after
the killing began. We should not have allowed the refugee <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camps</ENAMEX> to become safe
havens for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">killers</ENAMEX>. We did not immediately call these crimes by their
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rightful</ENAMEX> name: genocide. We cannot change the past. But we can and must do
everything in our power to help you build a future without fear, and full of
hope. ... We owe to all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the world our best efforts to organize
ourselves so that we can maximize the chances of preventing these events. And
where they cannot be prevented, we can move more quickly to minimize the
horror.

            This
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">apology</ENAMEX> seems insincere, because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> did not offer any realistic sense of
the obstacles to humanitarian military action involving the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. At
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">first Clinton</ENAMEX> may have wished, at some level, to intervene in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rwanda</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Haiti</ENAMEX>. But for practical and political reasons, he determined intervention
was possible only in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Haiti</ENAMEX>, then later in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX>. This was after the debacle in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Somalia</ENAMEX>, remember, and at a time when his popularity was at low ebb. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
judgment that he was in no position to send <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rwanda</ENAMEX> may not have been
courageous. It may not even have been correct. But like a decision not to risk
saving someone from a burning <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>, it is not morally culpable.

            
So why apologize? I would defend <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
apology as a statement of aspiration. He delineates specific actions that he
might plausibly have taken short of sending in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marines</ENAMEX>. And there is reason
to think that with more political capital, no re-election looming, and a
heightened sense of horror, he would behave differently.

            What a
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> should not apologize for is a basically sound foreign policy. And
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> unfortunately did that as well--though it drew less attention than his
other comments. In his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Uganda</ENAMEX> speech, before the part about slavery, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
said:

            In our
own time, during the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX>, when we were so concerned about being in
competition with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX>, very often we dealt with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX>
and in other parts of the world based more on how they stood in the struggle
struggle for their own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s aspirations to live up to the fullest of their
God-given abilities.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> speaks here as if the battle against
communism were an overheated <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World Cup</ENAMEX> match, rather than itself a struggle for
democracy and human rights. Even when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Realpolitik</ENAMEX> led the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
to side with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dictators</ENAMEX> and oppressors, it was in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> of maximizing
democracy and human rights in the world at large--a goal we in fact achieved.
Every <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX> decision to put <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> interests ahead of "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s aspirations"
in individual <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> may not be defensible, but the general policy is one we
needn't apologize for. And by the way, the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX> did not always define
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> policy in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX>. Well before the fall of communism, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> passed
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">comprehensive</ENAMEX> sanctions against the apartheid <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Africa</ENAMEX>. We did
this even though the white <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">South African</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> was a staunch <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">ally</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> ties.

            As it happens, that subject
came up during <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s stop in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Africa</ENAMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mandela</ENAMEX> publicly refused to
apologize for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ANC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Realpolitik</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alliances</ENAMEX>. It is debatable whether
friendships with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Libya</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX> actually serve <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Africa</ENAMEX>'s interests <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.
But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mandela</ENAMEX> is right not to apologize for having accepted help from various
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">malefactors</ENAMEX>, including the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX>, during the liberation struggle--when
actual support from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> came very late. Like the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold</ENAMEX>
War, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ANC</ENAMEX> made reasonable choices under circumstances in which moral purity
wasn't an option.

         
      
   
