
   
   
      
         
            Get Spun

            When the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX> scandal
broke in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX>, I joined the media <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">herd</ENAMEX> in calling it fatal. The chance that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> would serve out his term, I estimated early on, was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 25</NUMEX>
percent. This laughably inaccurate prognostication reflected the hysteria of
the moment and has illustrated for me the foolishness of making predictions,
especially ones that can be proved wrong and used to shame you in social
settings. I also learned something else: why the press is so eager for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s downfall. If a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> tells a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> he has <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six weeks</TIMEX> to live and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> survives for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many years</TIMEX>, it's humiliating for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX>.

            There are
other reasons--conscious, unconscious, and semiconscious--why <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> would
like to see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> kaput. On the high-status but low-interest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>
beat, there is no story as exciting as that of the fall of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. You
can't get around the fact that bad news for him is good news for us. An even
more powerful reason flows from the groupthink that afflicts the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>
press <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">corps</ENAMEX>. The general consensus is that, since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has got away
with murder--on draft dodging, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gennifer Flowers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitewater, Travelgate</ENAMEX>, Paula
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>, etc., etc. From <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> scandal broke, many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX>
determined this could not and should not happen again. The feeling that the
Slick <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> must not be allowed to elude capture once more is palpable in the
daily <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> briefings, in the hostile questioning by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Bloom</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>
or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deborah Orin</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Post</ENAMEX> , and in the massive play the
scandal continues to receive everywhere.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s unanticipated resilience leaves <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> in an
awkward position. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Journalists</ENAMEX> are most comfortable following public opinion,
not leading it. Now they must explain to themselves and to their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audiences</ENAMEX> how
it is that the public has not come to share their low opinion of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> obvious explanation is the strength of the economy. Another is that moral
strictures have loosened, at least when it comes to political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>. But
faced with the reality that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> has actually become more popular
since the scandal broke, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> have ventured a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> explanation of late:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has survived thanks to diabolically effective "spin."

            This
theory is now treated as acknowledged fact. "Given the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>'s
state-of-the-art public relations machine, it is not a surprise that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> has appeared to enjoy the upper hand," wrote <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don Van Natta Jr.</ENAMEX> in one
recent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> story. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Tribune</ENAMEX> refers casually
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s "obsessive and adroit image machine." That the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>
is wickedly good at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PR</ENAMEX> is the premise of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spin Cycle</ENAMEX>: Inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
Propaganda <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Machine</ENAMEX> , a new book by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard Kurtz</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> 's media <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kurtz</ENAMEX> points to the skill of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> Press
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael McCurry</ENAMEX>. Writing of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">60 percent</NUMEX> approval rating
before the scandal, he notes, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCurry</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> had mastered the art
of manipulating the press and were reaping the dividends." <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Elsewhere Kurtz</ENAMEX>
comments, "It was a carefully honed media strategy--alternately seducing,
misleading, and sometimes intimidating the press--that maintained [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s]
aura of success."

            
Is it not possible that the aura of success is
generated by real success? Might <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> have become a popular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> not by
brainwashing the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> but by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">legitimately</ENAMEX> winning the public's support? In
fact, there's no real way to judge the effectiveness of media relations except
results--and the results depend far more on the underlying reality than on the
spin. But "spin control" remains a useful explanation for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> who can't
understand how the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> can like this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>. In fact, it's not the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time
they've trotted it out. The current round of barbed paeans to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PR</ENAMEX> machine echoes press grousing during the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> sought
to explain why the public supported a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> they believed was ineffective
and incompetent. Since <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> knew they weren't wrong, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>'s
popularity had to be a tribute to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> image <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">makers</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deaver</ENAMEX> did it with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">smoke</ENAMEX> and mirrors.

            That
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> now think of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clintonites</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX> spinmeisters is especially
ironic in light of what they said about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> spin machine a few
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX>. Back then, the common wisdom was that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> was
breathtakingly inept at communications. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Officials</ENAMEX> assigned to deal with the
press were arrogant and hostile. The result was an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> that was
regularly embarrassed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PR</ENAMEX> "fiascoes." <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Officials</ENAMEX> naively thought they could
bypass the press and speak directly to the public. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kurtz</ENAMEX> himself
wrote, "By initially trying to circumvent the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> press corps, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX> clearly underestimated the degree to which negative
news reports could cause them political trouble."

            Administration <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> sort of liked this line, because
it exonerated them at a substantive level. They had failed only at
communicating their agenda. The inverse of the proposition--that they have
great form but lousy content--pleases the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> far less. In reality,
very little has changed. It is true, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kurtz</ENAMEX> writes, that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCurry</ENAMEX> is an
especially smooth and capable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX>. But the reason he is so well liked is
that he is generally straightforward and truthful; he does not go in for heavy
spin. Judged as a whole, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> media-wrangling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> is not obviously more
skillful than others past. Few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ann Lewis</ENAMEX> is a more competent
communications <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> than her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">predecessor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don Baer</ENAMEX>. I would venture that
none thinks <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sidney Blumenthal</ENAMEX> is more effective as a press tactician than his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">first-term</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counterpart</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Gergen</ENAMEX>.

            When <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> explain
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s popularity as the result of brilliant spin, what are they saying?
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spin</ENAMEX>" means the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> using the media to mislead the public. So they
are, in effect, praising the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> for lying to them--and getting away
with it. What does that say about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> themselves?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Reporters</ENAMEX>, whose job is
depicting reality, profess to despise spin. In fact, they like getting spun. It
makes them part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">great Washington</ENAMEX> game, and it gives them something to
act cynical and world-weary about. If <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> took to telling the truth,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> would lose their role as interpreters. But to say that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> spin is working amounts to saying that you, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX>, are failing
in your job of blocking it. It's a startling admission--all the more shocking
because it isn't true.

         
      
   
