
   
   
      
         
            Party of <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">One</ENAMEX>

            I wish we
could sit around my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen</ENAMEX> table--just Bill, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Liddy</ENAMEX>, and me.
Actually, I might be pressed for time, so it would work better if we could
stand around my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen</ENAMEX> table while I chug <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half a pint</NUMEX> of takeout
Szechwan shrimp, no MSG, before I run out to meet a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> who has also come
home late from work to gulp something before we connect for a concert and
dinner.

            But in my
spare <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 minutes</TIMEX>, while I have all the major presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> and their
significant but loving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouses</ENAMEX> gathered, I'd tackle what the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">first lady</ENAMEX> told
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Convention</ENAMEX> "matters most in our lives and in our
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nation</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>." Because the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> were mostly
"triangulating" their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> message to duel with the similar
message that came out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Republican National Convention</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few weeks</TIMEX> before,
I'd tackle <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> next. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> imagines himself a bridge "to a time of
tranquillity, faith, and confidence," so I'd ask him to what <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">village</ENAMEX> or America
his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridge</ENAMEX> will carry <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> like me--seeing as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> like me don't have
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> or traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Soccer Moms</ENAMEX>" are desirable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> this
election year, but single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> are off the charts--just a rung below
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homosexual men</ENAMEX> who are contemplating, but denied, marriage.

            At our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen confab</ENAMEX> (which would probably, I'm sorry to
say, take place not around the table--since many single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> live in
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartments</ENAMEX> where the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen</ENAMEX> is the size of a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">linen</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">closet</ENAMEX>--but around the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">counter</ENAMEX>), I might suggest that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">first lady</ENAMEX> ask <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Reno</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donna Shalala</ENAMEX>
if they ever feel stressed out or over-committed, even though they aren't
"packing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">lunches</ENAMEX>, dropping the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> off at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>, and going to work." The
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX>, who detailed so eloquently the pressures faced by working <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX>,
might be surprised to know that the current <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney general</ENAMEX> and the secretary
dinner, pay the bills, and feel a little tired when, on top of all their other
responsibilities, they have to take the dog to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vet</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
politics were a little more inclusive when campaign rhetoric revolved around
"it's the economy, stupid." Yes, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> must feed their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, but
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>--married and single--must feed themselves, too. But once the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> decided that the goal of all <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> must be family
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> rearing, an unpremeditated exclusionary process began.

            
At the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Republican Convention</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> urged us to
practice "right conduct" <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX>. Well, it's pretty hard to practice "right
conduct" when the very fabric of your personal life is judged to be
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">second-rate</ENAMEX>. But it's not too late to redeem single nonparents. We could change
the tax code to deter their behavior (and balance the budget) by slapping a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX>
percent tax hike on every <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> who has not procreated and married.
(Are you listening, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>? You could even punish the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX> for
their sinful ways with a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">15 percent</NUMEX> tax hike of their own. Single nonparent
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX> could be slapped with a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">30 percent</NUMEX> tax hike.)

            Why are
single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are so vilified? Many of them have more time than the
married-with-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children crowd</ENAMEX> to contribute to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX>: I wonder how many
from each group volunteer for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> campaigns, and how
the figures compare. Does <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Morris</ENAMEX> know? Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morris</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX> of
triangulation as well as of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX>'s and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">first lady</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>-values
speeches, might have consulted his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">companion</ENAMEX>, Miss <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rowlands</ENAMEX>, during his "off"
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jefferson Hotel</ENAMEX> about whether she felt included in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>'
agenda.

            It is precisely our current <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s generation, the
"me-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boomers</ENAMEX>" who, in unprecedented numbers, opened the doors for gay and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s rights and, therefore, postponed or rejected traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> values.
It seems disloyal, even a sign of self-loathing, for this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s campaign
strategy to work overtime to gain the admiration and respect of the center
while ignoring his own backyard. If Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> insists on playing footsie with
the religious right, shouldn't Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> acknowledge his lifestyle left?

            Perhaps it's time for both
parties to consider "rectangularization"--to include in their focus groups
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> who care about health care and education but not necessarily about
getting married or having <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. At the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Republican Convention</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX>
commended as right conduct "any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">screenwriter</ENAMEX> who refuses to contribute to the
mountains of trash." Well, I'm <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> who would promise Bill, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Liddy</ENAMEX> personally, at my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen</ENAMEX> table (well, kitchen counter), not to
contribute further to the trash <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>. But on one condition: Both parties
must return to a genuine debate and stop bickering over who can present a
better image of wistful middle-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> life. It's irritating to be
ignored. But it's painful to be living a life which both political spectrums
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">deem</ENAMEX> as virtually un-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX>.

            It takes a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen</ENAMEX> to make a
village. Not just a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
