
   
   
      
         
            Brill, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mote</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beam</ENAMEX>

            If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Brill</ENAMEX>'s object is
to make the media look absurd, he got off to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a roaring start</TIMEX>. On the front page
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Sunday</TIMEX> was a story that said the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> issue
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brill's Content</ENAMEX> would report that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Independent Counsel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>
had leaked information about his investigation to the press--including the
Times . Now if the question of whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> leaks to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> is
important enough for the front page, you might wonder why the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">needed Brill</ENAMEX> to raise the subject. And who knows better than the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX>
whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> leaked to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> ? Yet the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> cites <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brill</ENAMEX> and
then cites its own <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Oreskes</ENAMEX>, saying the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX>
does not discuss its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>. And all this contortion was induced by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brill</ENAMEX>'s
having leaked his own forthcoming article to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> .

            But if
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brill</ENAMEX>'s goal is to offer a socially useful critique of media misbehavior, he is
doing less well. There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> problems with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brill's Content</ENAMEX> . The first
is that though the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> seems to envision a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> that will hold the press
accountable to a wider <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>, he has created one that is unlikely to interest
anyone outside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> problem is that though <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brill</ENAMEX> deserves a
Pulitzer for self-righteousness, he simply isn't a careful enough <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX>
himself to be criticizing others.

            Let's start with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>. After hearing it disputed
for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">so many days</TIMEX>, potential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> will be fooled into thinking something
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">scintillating</ENAMEX> is going on. In fact, what will strike most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> when they
finally get their hands on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brill's Content</ENAMEX> is how boring it is. Dullness
is a problem for media <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> in general, the prototype being the ever
worthy, always soporific <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia Journalism Review</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CJR</ENAMEX> is
filled with articles you'd say only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> could possibly want
to read, except that they're too mundane even for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the business. "New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guild</ENAMEX> contract at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milwaukee</ENAMEX> Sentinel " is the sort of thing
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CJR</ENAMEX> does. You will find praise for that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>-part series on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX>'s neglected infrastructure, and a spank for local TV news
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX> who can't seem to put anything but crime on the air.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brill</ENAMEX> is hoping for an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> beyond the industry, but most of his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>--the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> issue,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">anyhow</ENAMEX>--amounts to little more than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CJR</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">steroids</ENAMEX>. There's a long
feature lauding the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> for its fine reporting on
mismanagement at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia/HCA</ENAMEX> health care <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">conglomerate</ENAMEX>, and another rapping
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">60 Minutes</ENAMEX> for a flawed story--aired <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 years ago</TIMEX>--on alleged
spontaneous acceleration in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Audis</ENAMEX>. There's a "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Heroes"</ENAMEX> column about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>
at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> who exposed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beardstown Ladies</ENAMEX> for inflating the
returns of their investment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX>. Seems he had to go in for sinus surgery the
day the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> picked up his scoop. Crazy ... If I were a
better <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>, perhaps I would read stories like this through to the end.

            What is pernicious is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brill</ENAMEX>'s
attitude that he's the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> in the world with the guts to point out other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s mistakes. His maximum opus on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first three weeks</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>
scandal coverage is intended to be a devastating case study of media
malpractice. This <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24,000</NUMEX> word story charges <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> with just about every sin
in the book, and commits most of them itself. Here are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> journalistic no-nos
that stand out in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brill</ENAMEX>'s piece:

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Overhyping</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Point</ENAMEX> of Dishonesty
            

            Brill
contends the press has allowed itself to be used by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> to make <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> look
guilty. But to prove that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> has leaked grand jury information to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">media</ENAMEX>--which, by the way, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brill</ENAMEX> doesn't do--is not to demonstrate that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> have been irresponsible. By my reading, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brill</ENAMEX> does not document a
single error of fact made in the national <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX> he analyzes--the New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> , and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> --and he presents only a few cases in which any of them even
misplayed a story in a significant way. He ignores the tough coverage <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> has
received. To conclude, as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brill</ENAMEX> does, that the press is now "an institution
being corrupted to its core" wildly overreaches the evidence he presents.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>)
Misquotation
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schmidt</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>, claims she did not tell <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brill</ENAMEX> that
she "heard from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s office something about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vernon Jordan</ENAMEX> and coaching a
witness." The quote is damaging because it implies <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schmidt</ENAMEX> revealed the
identity of an anonymous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX>. For another example from a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nonjournalist</ENAMEX> who
claims plausibly to have been misquoted by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brill</ENAMEX>, see "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>." We cannot know for sure who is right, because Brill
did not tape-record his interviews.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Self-Contradiction</ENAMEX>
            

            Later in
the piece, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brill</ENAMEX> writes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schmidt</ENAMEX> and another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> "declined all comment
on their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>." Well, did she or didn't she?

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>)
Distortion
            

            Brill
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">accuses Newsweek</ENAMEX> of suppressing critical exculpatory information about
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> in its initial story published online. He cites a passage in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tripp</ENAMEX> tapes in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tripp</ENAMEX> asks <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> knows she is going to
lie in her upcoming deposition in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> case. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> answers "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">No.</ENAMEX>"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Isikoff</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> whom <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brill</ENAMEX> criticizes, notes,
first, that the full <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchange</ENAMEX> is equivocal--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> also tells Tripp the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> doesn't think she is going to tell the truth. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> online story stated that the tapes offer "no clear evidence" to
support or undermine <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX>'s allegations. And <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>, in the issue it published
the following <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> included the full excerpt--which is where
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brill</ENAMEX> found the out-of-context quote he claims <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> ignored.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neglecting Contradictory Evidence</ENAMEX>
            

            In
building his case that much of the information could have come only from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>,
Brill ignores a highly plausible alternative explanation: Most if not all could
have come from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> of various <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> sympathetic to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lawyers</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintons</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betty Currie</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">steward</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bayani Nelvis</ENAMEX>, and
others are operating under what is called a "joint defense agreement." They
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">pool</ENAMEX> data about what their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> have told <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">grand jury</ENAMEX>. This means
there are lots of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> with access to information about what various
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> said and a variety of motivations to leak that information. Noting
this possibility isn't just a matter of fairness--it's an issue of basic
intellectual honesty.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>) Giving
Only <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">One Side of an Argument</ENAMEX>
            

            Brill
asserts that leaks from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> were obviously illegal. "There are court
decisions," he writes, "that have ruled explicitly that leaking information
about prospective <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> who might testify at a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">grand jury</ENAMEX>, or about
expected testimony, or about negotiations regarding immunity for testimony, or
[about] the strategy of a grand jury proceeding all fall within the criminal
prohibition." Nowhere does he note court decisions that have ruled the
opposite, or acknowledge that the question is far from settled.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Faking Scoops</ENAMEX>
            

            Almost
all the criticism of the press in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brill</ENAMEX>'s piece is familiar, much of it to the
point of cliché. Items about "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX>" retracted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dallas Morning</ENAMEX>
News and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> Web edition have been endlessly
hashed over. So have various nuances that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brill</ENAMEX> presents as revelatory. Both
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> and 
                  Slate
               , for instance, have reported
that the source for the erroneous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dallas Morning News</ENAMEX> item about a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph DiGenova</ENAMEX>. Brill reinvents the wheel in this
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> numerous times. And while we're at it, is it really a revelation that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>
talks to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX>? At televised press conferences he has held in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Little Rock</ENAMEX>,
he can be seen calling on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> by their <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> names, suggesting that he
knows some of them pretty well and that he doesn't regard this as a secret.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sabotage Through Blind Quotes</ENAMEX>
            

            Defending
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> story on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Currie</ENAMEX>, "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>" is
quoted by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brill</ENAMEX> as saying that "this was not some <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sue Schmidt</ENAMEX> jam job." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schmidt</ENAMEX>
is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> covering the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Whitewater</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> beat for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> . To allow her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX> to snipe at her under cover of anonymity
seems exactly the sort of thing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brill</ENAMEX> started his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> to nail other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> for doing. And what's a "jam job," anyway?

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>)
Conflict of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Interest</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard Kurtz</ENAMEX> reports in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brill</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> donated <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2,000</NUMEX> to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton-Gore</ENAMEX> campaign in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>. Most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX> forbid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> from making
campaign contributions, certainly to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> they're writing about. But whether
or not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brill</ENAMEX> thinks such a prohibition makes sense--I look forward to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20,000</NUMEX>
words on the topic in a future issue of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brill's Content</ENAMEX> --he should have
disclosed this fact, as he acknowledged when busted.

            Don't get
me wrong. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Reporters</ENAMEX>, especially TV <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX>, have been far from blameless in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX>. In the heat of competition, stories have run that shouldn't have. But
the best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> covering the scandal have done an extremely good job in a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">vexing</ENAMEX> and unfamiliar situation. At times, they have behaved almost heroically.
When first offered a chance to listen to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tripp</ENAMEX> tapes, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isikoff</ENAMEX> refused,
passing up what might have been the scoop of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the decade</TIMEX> out of concern that
doing so would put him in an ethically compromised situation. Brill disparages
these compunctions, noting that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isikoff</ENAMEX> had to run off to "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNBC</ENAMEX>, where he was a
paid <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> sex scandal pundit." Actually, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isikoff</ENAMEX> notes, it was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MSNBC</ENAMEX>, where
he was under contract to discuss the campaign finance scandal. That makes
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>) Errors of Fact . But more to the point, is there anybody who thinks
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Brill</ENAMEX>, back before he was a press scold, would have passed up the
chance to hear those tapes?

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Brill</ENAMEX> .
            

            
               If you
missed the link to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>, where a nonjournalist claims he
was misquoted by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brill</ENAMEX> in the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pressgate</ENAMEX>" piece, click here.
            

         
      
   
