
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABCs</ENAMEX> of Communitarianism

            Sometime over <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the last two</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, someone somewhere must have decreed that the intellectual buzzword of
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">'90s</NUMEX> was to be "communitarianism." <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Only five years ago</TIMEX>, communitarianism
was an obscure <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> of philosophy discussed in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faculty</ENAMEX> seminars; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, its
ideas are splashed across <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">People</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> and on network TV. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community</ENAMEX>"
and "civil society," the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> mantras of the movement, are part of everyday
political discourse.

            
Curiously, in a climate of polarized political discourse, everyone is a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">communitarian</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">movement</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cheerleaders</ENAMEX> can be found across the political
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">spectrum</ENAMEX>, from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbra Streisand</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX>. On the
left, large liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundations</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carnegie</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bellwethers</ENAMEX> of
political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correctness</ENAMEX>, throw <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">millions of dollars</NUMEX> into projects relating to
these ideas. (The result, predictably, is that the magic words "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX>" and
"civil society" are sprinkled liberally now in all proposals for research
grants, as in "The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">East Asian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Balance of Power</ENAMEX>--The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Neglected Role of Civil</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Society</ENAMEX>.") On the right, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Policy Review</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journal</ENAMEX> of the resolutely
conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heritage Foundation</ENAMEX>, announced <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> that it was reorienting
itself to focus on civil society.

            What is communitarianism? Where did it come from? How come
everyone seems to agree it is good? It's actually all quite simple. You just
need to remember your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABCs</ENAMEX>.

            *************

            
               A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Is for Aristotle</ENAMEX>.
He is probably started it all. In his treatise on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, The
Politics , he famously wrote that "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> is by nature a political animal,"
meaning that human beings can best fulfill themselves as part of social and
political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>, not as isolated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> sitting at home watching TV
(well, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the fourth century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">B.C.</ENAMEX> equivalent). Usually regarded as the original
conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">philosopher</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aristotle</ENAMEX> is popular now with "troubled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX>" who
worry that modern <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">societies</ENAMEX>, organized around an individualistic, rights-based
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">creed</ENAMEX>, leave human beings feeling "hollow at the core."

            Of
these troubled <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">types</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard University</ENAMEX> political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">philosopher</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Sandel</ENAMEX>
is perhaps mostly closely identified with communitarianism. Along with serious
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Walzer</ENAMEX> and unserious publicists like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amitai Etzioni</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sandel</ENAMEX> criticizes "minimalist liberalism"--the tradition made most famous by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Stuart Mill</ENAMEX>--for too easily celebrating individualism and materialism at
the expense of social and moral issues. In his new book, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democracy</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Discontent: America in Search of a Public Philosophy</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sandel</ENAMEX> tries to
revive an alternative <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">path</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> tradition, which, he says,
focused on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>-building and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizenship</ENAMEX>. While their critique of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">liberalism</ENAMEX>'s reluctance to introduce morality into politics is trenchant,
left-wing communitarians like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sandel</ENAMEX> themselves are reluctant to advocate
strong remedies--say prayer in public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> or laws against divorce--and rely
instead on vague statements about the value of community life and
neighborhoods.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Conservatives</ENAMEX> have few such inhibitions. Former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reagan</ENAMEX>
official and intellectual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">firebrand</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Bennett</ENAMEX> agrees with everything that
troubled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> say is wrong with modern society. His answer, however, is not
to talk about nice neighborhoods, but instead, to talk about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Virtue</ENAMEX>. Actually,
he writes about it, and since his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Books of Virtues</ENAMEX> , collections of
morally instructive tales from all over the world, are relentless best sellers,
one has to assume someone is reading them.

            The advantage that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX>
and others, like neo-conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben Wattenberg</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian Coalition</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">spokesman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralph Reed</ENAMEX>, have is that while <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> spend a great deal of time
analyzing the problem--liberalism's value-free politics--they are wary of
actually filling the vacuum with any kind of absolutist morality. They are,
after all, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX>. By contrast, conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communitarians</ENAMEX> have solutions.
Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> talk up abstract virtues like honor, commitment, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">thrift</ENAMEX>, but
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> then propose specific policies that put into law their moral and
religious preferences in order to deal with all sorts of issues: unwed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX>,
absent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fathers</ENAMEX>, unruly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">schoolchildren</ENAMEX>, gay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lovers</ENAMEX>, and so on. It's a game
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> can't win.

            
*************

            
               B Is for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bowling</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the most important debates
among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">academics</ENAMEX> and policy wonks over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last two years</TIMEX> has been, is it better
is bowl together or alone? In "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bowling Alone: America's Declining Social</ENAMEX>
Capital," a now-legendary article written in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert Putnam</ENAMEX>
pointed out that league <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">bowling</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> has been declining for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX>,
while individual bowling is on the rise. This, he contends, is a symbol of the
decline of community <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spirit</ENAMEX> and the rise of atomistic individualism.

            Part of the reason that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Putnam</ENAMEX>'s article resonated so strongly outside <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elite</ENAMEX> circles-- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">People</ENAMEX>
magazine profiled him in a bowling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alley</ENAMEX>--is that in using the example of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">bowling</ENAMEX>, that staple of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1950s</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Putnam</ENAMEX> touched on a powerful chord of nostalgia
for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> of that golden <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decade</TIMEX>. A new book by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Ehrenhalt</ENAMEX>, The
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lost City</ENAMEX> , is subtitled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Discovering the Forgotten Virtues</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community</ENAMEX>
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1950s</TIMEX> .

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ehrenhalt</ENAMEX>'s book may be
the best of the new literature on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX>, because rather than waxing poetic
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> in the abstract, he describes actual communities. The result is
a vivid picture showing that the strong bonds that developed in those fabled
neighborhoods of yore were kindled by conditions that we might find
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">discomforting</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>--fear of authority, lack of choice, and poverty. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">People</ENAMEX>
stayed in neighborhoods, for example, because they could not afford to move,
and because other neighborhoods would not accept them easily. They attended
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">church</ENAMEX> services and neighborhood social events because small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>,
and other community <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX> were run by a local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elite</ENAMEX> that enforced a
certain kind of conformity. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Porches</ENAMEX> and stoops, those symbols of a vibrant
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">social</ENAMEX> life, stopped being used as gathering places for a rather practical
reason--air conditioning. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ehrenhalt</ENAMEX> himself <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> a return to the
choice-free, obedient life of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1950s</TIMEX>, but while seductive in the abstract,
it sounds more and more confining on close examination. Imagine having to go to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> with your local bank <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> so that you could get a mortgage.

            Hard-core <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">left-wingers</ENAMEX> are
horrified by this rise in nostalgia about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1950s</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a decade</TIMEX> that was seen,
not so long ago, as a grim period of pre-enlightenment, racist, sexist,
capitalist boredom. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nation</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katha Pollitt</ENAMEX> takes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Putnam</ENAMEX>'s very
example, the shift from league <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">bowling</ENAMEX> to ad hoc bowling, and suggests that
"[that] story could be told as one of happy progress from a drink-sodden night
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouse</ENAMEX>-avoidance with the same old faces from work to temperate and
spontaneous fun with one's intimate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hmm</ENAMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Temperate</ENAMEX> and
spontaneous fun" sounds like something one might have to do in a work <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX>. And
the occasional "drink<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">-sodden night</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouse</ENAMEX>-avoidance"--for both sexes--is
probably key to enduring marriages.

            B, by the way, could also
be for "<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX>," but it turns out that <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">leagues</ENAMEX> have been growing
steadily over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last decades</TIMEX>. And the number of soccer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clubs</ENAMEX> has been rising
meteorically as well. The simplest explanation for this rise might be the
desire for a little exercise.

            
***************

            
               C Is for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Civil Society</ENAMEX>. Civil <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Society</ENAMEX> has nothing to do
with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Emily Post</ENAMEX>. It's a term used to describe that part of society that exists
between the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>--voluntary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>, choral <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>,
Rotary <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">clubs</ENAMEX>, etc.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexis de Tocqueville</ENAMEX>
noticed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1830s</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> was brimming with them, and argued that they
were good for democracy. This celebrated hypothesis has by now become a
theological certitude in the minds of most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX>. It recently
received powerful empirical support from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Putnam</ENAMEX>, whose <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX> book,
Making <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democracy Work</ENAMEX> , documented that northern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> is civil-society
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rich</ENAMEX> and southern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>, civil-society poor. Certainly the north has been
better governed than the south for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">centuries</TIMEX>, but that is not to say that is
has been a better democracy. After all, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> has not been a democracy for that
long. There was that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fellow</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mussolini</ENAMEX>, and before him, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">emperor</ENAMEX>. Perhaps
civil society is good for efficient <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> rather than democratic
government. Memo to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee Kuan Yew</ENAMEX> ...

            Of
course, civil society could also be the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mafia</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michigan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">militia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hamas</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nation of Islam</ENAMEX> and other such <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> involved in communal projects. But when
most civil-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">society boosters</ENAMEX> talk about the concept, they use it to
mean--arbitrarily--those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> that they like. So the left points inevitably
to nonprofit do-good <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>, and the right talks about church
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>.

            Consider the difference between the conservative writer
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis Fukuyama</ENAMEX> and left <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">winger Benjamin Barber</ENAMEX>, who, in their recent books,
praise civil society extravagantly. In <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fukuyama</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trust</ENAMEX> , he argues that
private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> are an important part of civil society and that nonfamily
business activity is a key indicator of a politically and economically healthy
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">society</ENAMEX>. But for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barber</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jihad</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">McWorld: How the Planet</ENAMEX> is
Both <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Falling Apart and Coming Together--and What This Means for</ENAMEX>
Democracy-- a book <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has read and praised--business, far
from being part of civil society, leads the assault on civil society. "Who will
get business off the backs of civil society?" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barber</ENAMEX> asks. Now it isn't clear
why <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> don't fulfill most of the functions of civil society. Indeed the term
"civil society" originated with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam Smith</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam Ferguson</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Hume</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scotland</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 18th century</TIMEX> as a way to describe
private business activity. On the other hand, you don't hear many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">conservatives</ENAMEX>
proclaiming the virtues of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Greenpeace</ENAMEX>.

            Communitarianism was
supposed to be a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> way, neither <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberal</ENAMEX> nor conservative, that charted a
new course for philosophy and politics. But as this primer suggests, it has
become a collection of meaningless terms, used as new bottles into which the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">old</ENAMEX> wine of liberalism and conservatism is poured. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community</ENAMEX> means <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> thing if
you are a conservative and another if you are a liberal--the same with civil
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">society</ENAMEX>, and even <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">bowling</ENAMEX>. Call it politics as usual.

            
               Illustrations by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert</ENAMEX>
Neubecker
            

         
      
   
