
   
   
      
         
            Speech and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spillover</ENAMEX>

            
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>
probably will overturn the notorious Communications <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Decency Act</ENAMEX>. But the issues
are not as cut-and-dried as some might suggest.
            

            
               By <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eugene</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Volokh</ENAMEX>
            

            
               (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,777</NUMEX> words; posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, July 18</TIMEX>; to be composted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, July 25</TIMEX>)
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the great recurring
problems in free-speech law is spillover. Free speech, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> has
held, has limits: Some speech is so harmful and so lacking in redeeming value
that it may be restricted. Threats, blackmail, and false advertising are
obvious examples. There's no right to say, "Your money or your life" to a
stranger in a dark <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alley</ENAMEX>; there's no right to spread intentional falsehoods
about your product or your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enemy</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> likewise
has held, rightly or wrongly, that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minors</ENAMEX> have no right to see very sexually
explicit material, and that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> (except, perhaps, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minors</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>) have
no right to distribute such material to them. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Psychologists</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">philosophers</ENAMEX>
can debate this, but as a constitutional matter, the question is settled.

            But
it's often impossible to keep such <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">materials</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> without also denying
them to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bookstores</ENAMEX> can check <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>' ages, but TV <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">broadcasters</ENAMEX>,
muralists, or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who post things on the Internet can't. The law can allow
public display of this <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">material</ENAMEX>, protecting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX>' access but also making it
available to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>; or the law can prohibit <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> display, insulating
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> but also restricting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX>. Either way there's spillover. Either the
restriction spills over onto speech that should be free, or the freedom spills
over onto speech that, in the judgment of most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">legislators</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX>,
should be restricted.

            This spillover problem is a recurring question in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Amendment</ENAMEX> law. The law cannot restrict all harmful, valueless speech and at the
same time protect all valuable speech. A classic illustration of the spillover
problem is the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Communications Decency Act</ENAMEX>, passed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this year</TIMEX> in an
attempt to stop "indecency" on the Internet. A <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>-judge <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">federal court</ENAMEX> was
probably correct in striking down the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDA</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 11</TIMEX>. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX>' opinions
don't squarely face the spillover problem. Perhaps--contrary to the suggestions
of some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> cases--spillover questions should always be resolved in
favor of free speech. Perhaps <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s increased vulnerability is a price
worth paying for extra freedom for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX>. But it's important to confront
honestly both what's being lost and gained in the process.

            The most controversial
part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDA</ENAMEX> prohibits anyone from

            "us[ing]
an interactive computer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX>"

            "to
display in a manner available to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">under 18 years of age</TIMEX>"

            "any
comment, request, suggestion, proposal, image, or other communication"

            "that, in
context, depicts or describes,"

            "in terms
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">patently</ENAMEX> offensive as measured by contemporary community standards,"

            "sexual or excretory
activities or organs."

            Virtually any sort of speech in the public areas of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cyberspace</ENAMEX> is available to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minors</ENAMEX>, so the law really applies to all such areas,
including Web sites, Internet newsgroups, e-mail discussion lists, chat <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX>,
and bulletin boards.

            And
"patently offensive" can cover a lot of territory. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">profanities</ENAMEX> might be
considered "patently offensive" descriptions of "sexual or excretory activities
or organs," especially under the standards of some conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX>.
Putting a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Mamet</ENAMEX> play on your Web site, thus, might be a crime. The term
"patently offensive" is vague enough that no one knows for sure, but the wise
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user</ENAMEX> will take a conservative approach. Given some recent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>
decisions, it seems unlikely that the vagueness alone would make the act
unconstitutional. But there's no doubt that the law's vagueness does indeed
make it more likely to stifle someone's freedom of expression.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDA</ENAMEX>, though ostensibly intended to protect <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>,
clearly has a spillover effect on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Adults</ENAMEX> generally have the right to
see material that's "patently offensive." There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> exceptions to this:
child pornography (sexually explicit pictures made using <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child models</ENAMEX>) and
"obscenity"--but both are much smaller categories than the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDA</ENAMEX>'s "indecency."
May the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, in its quest to shield <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, restrict the online
choices of grownups? Or to look at it the other way: Must the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX>, in order
to protect the freedom of grownups, restrict the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s ability to shield
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>?

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> precedents are unclear. In a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1957</TIMEX> case called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Butler</ENAMEX> vs.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michigan</ENAMEX> , a state law barred distribution of material that might be
unsuitable for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minors</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> concluded that such a ban was
unconstitutional. The law, it said, "reduce[<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">d</ENAMEX>] the adult <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michigan</ENAMEX>
to reading only what is fit for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. ... <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Surely</ENAMEX>, this is to burn the house
to roast the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pig</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> agreed that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> could bar distribution of
such stuff directly to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. But clearly, such limited restrictions don't
work as well as a total ban. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> apparently was willing to tolerate some
perceived harm to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in order to protect the freedom of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX>.

            But in some recent cases, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> has taken a different
approach. One such case is the oft-criticized <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pacifica</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foundation</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1978</TIMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pacifica</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> upheld a ban on
"indecency"--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Carlin</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Seven Dirty Words</ENAMEX>" monologue--on radio and
television broadcasts "when there is a reasonable risk that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> may be in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>." The spillover was clear: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Adults</ENAMEX> were deprived of access to
certain materials on certain media (radio and television) during <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">most hours</TIMEX>.
But the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justices</ENAMEX> were willing to allow such a restriction of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX>' access to
speech in order to shield <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pacifica</ENAMEX> is a narrow decision, and there's language in it suggesting
that it only applies to over-the-air broadcasting. But in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s cable
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">indecency</ENAMEX> case, known as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Denver Consortium</ENAMEX> , <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justices</ENAMEX>
were willing to use <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pacifica</ENAMEX> as a guide for cable television as well as
over-the-air broadcasting. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>'s decision was written before
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Denver Consortium</ENAMEX> was handed down.) And during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last 10 years</TIMEX>, some
lower <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> have upheld bans on public display of sexually explicit material
that's not technically "obscene" on the grounds that the law may shield
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> even if this keeps, say, a would-be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">muralist</ENAMEX> from communicating to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> hasn't spoken on these specific statutes.

            Another important, though somewhat ambiguous, precedent is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sable Communications</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>), in which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> struck down a
ban on dial<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">-a-porn</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> argued the ban was needed to protect
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> pointed out that there might be "less restrictive
alternatives" that would insulate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> without entirely banning the medium.
For example, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> said, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> could require services to take
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">credit-card</ENAMEX> numbers, or require phone <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> to let <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> block
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">area-code-900</ENAMEX> phone calls.

            Still, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> was
willing to tolerate some spillover; after all, even the alternatives it
suggested would deny access to some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX>. And it also hinted that it might
even allow a total ban if such alternatives could be shown to be inadequate.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Denver Consortium</ENAMEX> followed the same pattern: It struck down a
restriction on indecent speech because there were other effective alternatives
available; but it suggested that such a restriction might be constitutional if
it were, in fact, the only effective way to shield <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Sable</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Denver Consortium</ENAMEX> make clear that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> won't
tolerate unnecessary spillover onto <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX>. But on the tough
question--what happens if it's impossible to shield <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minors</ENAMEX> without burdening
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX>?--there's an unresolved tension. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Butler</ENAMEX> says that the speech must
be allowed. Pacifica , <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Sable</ENAMEX> , and now <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Denver Consortium</ENAMEX>
suggest that the speech may be restricted.

            On the Internet, is it possible to shield <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> without
restricting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Parents</ENAMEX> can get software--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">SurfWatch</ENAMEX> is one popular
brand--that keeps their computers from accessing any place that's on a list of
"dirty" locations, a list selected and frequently updated by the software
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designers</ENAMEX>. If the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> wanted to, it could buy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SurfWatch</ENAMEX> (for a fraction
of what it would cost to enforce the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDA</ENAMEX>) and give it away to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>. Could
this be the "less restrictive alternative" that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> could use
instead of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDA</ENAMEX>'s total ban? Well, it depends on how much shielding of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
you're willing to sacrifice. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">SurfWatch</ENAMEX> solution is limited by the software
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designers</ENAMEX>' ability to keep up with the latest "dirty" places. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Dozens</NUMEX> of Web
sites are being added <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX>, and you never know what will get posted tomorrow
even on existing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> or newsgroups. Some things will inevitably be
missed.

            The purely technological
fix, then, is less restrictive than the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDA</ENAMEX>, but it's also less effective. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDA</ENAMEX>, of course, won't be perfect, either--many will flout it, and Web sites in
other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> won't be bound by it--but the ban plus the technological
fix probably will shield <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> better than the technological fix alone. Does
this extra protection justify the considerable spillover? The precedents don't
answer this.

            There's
a hybrid technological and legal approach that might be more effective, and
thus more likely to be the sort of "less restrictive alternative" that would
make the total ban invalid. The law might demand that online material be
rated--that any sufficiently sexually explicit text or image be marked "dirty"
in a way that computers can easily recognize. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Parents</ENAMEX> could then set up their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s computers to block access to these pages. Alternatively, the
software could assume that any page is dirty unless it's labeled "clean," with
the law making it illegal to falsely mark "clean" a page that's actually
dirty.

            Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, of course, might misrate their
material--intentionally or accidentally. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDA</ENAMEX> will be intentionally or
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">accidentally</ENAMEX> violated, too. In fact, a rating requirement might be more
effective than a total ban. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> may be more willing to comply with the
rating law, since it would let them continue selling their wares or expressing
their views. Still, ratings won't shield <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> using computers that don't
have the rating <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">software</ENAMEX> turned on. And no one knows how often this will
happen.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDA</ENAMEX> is now in the
hands of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>. Some say the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justices</ENAMEX> should simply rule that
sexually explicit material isn't as dangerous for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> as it's cracked up
to be, and therefore, free speech should prevail. But many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, probably
including the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justices</ENAMEX>, are willing to accept that sexually explicit material
is indeed harmful to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. Other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> assert that the technological
alternatives will shield <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> every bit as well as a total ban would, and
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDA</ENAMEX> therefore is entirely unnecessary. But that too will be
hard to prove.

            Ultimately, then, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justices</ENAMEX> will have to make a hard choice: sacrifice some shielding of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
in order to protect the freedom of grownups, or sacrifice some access by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">grownups</ENAMEX> in order to shield <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. My guess is that the marginal benefit of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDA</ENAMEX> over the technological alternatives is small enough, and the burden
that the law creates is large enough, that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDA</ENAMEX> will be overturned. But it's
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">closer</ENAMEX> question than many might think.

         
      
   
