
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leak Soup</ENAMEX>

            Since leaks became a big
issue in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> sex scandal, the whole affair has taken on a surreal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alice</ENAMEX> in Wonderland quality. For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past several days</TIMEX>, the press has
been trying simultaneously to report stories derived from anonymous leaks,
report on the phenomenon of these leaks, and--in the editorial pages--express
an opinion about the propriety of the leaks. If the definition of media
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">unfairness</ENAMEX> is the press behaving as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX>, then the
definition of media absurdity is the way the press is now acting as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defendant</ENAMEX>.

            We
slipped down the rabbit hole <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 6</TIMEX>, when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> reported
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betty Currie</ENAMEX>, had, while testifying to a grand
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX>, contradicted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s sworn testimony about his relationship with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>. According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> story, which was attributed to "lawyers
familiar with her account," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> summoned <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Currie</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 18, the day</TIMEX> after he was deposed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paula Jones</ENAMEX>. These sources
told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> rhetorically asked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Currie</ENAMEX>, "We [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>] were never alone, right?" According to the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Currie</ENAMEX> has
handed over to the independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> gifts from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> had given <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Currie</ENAMEX>.

            If, as various <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesmen</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s
private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Kendall</ENAMEX> have charged, the source of this leak was the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> of the independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX>, it is a serious offense. Disclosing
information from a grand-jury proceeding violates the federal rules of criminal
procedure and would subject <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> to contempt charges and
possibly jail time. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> himself could be fired by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney general</ENAMEX>--who,
if she isn't worried about setting in motion an infinite regression, could name
an independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> to investigate the independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX>.

            There is
no telling for certain where the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Currie</ENAMEX> leak came from. It might have sprung
from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>; from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Currie</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> (in which case it would not be
illegal); or from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX>, which could have found out about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Currie</ENAMEX>'s
testimony from her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>. A preponderance of evidence, however, points in the
direction of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>. Here are the reasons.

            
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> account was spun for
maximum harm to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. (The catch-up story in late editions of that same
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">morning</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> 
               Post presented roughly the same facts in a
less damning way.) By casting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s question to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Currie</ENAMEX> as rhetorical, the
Times ' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">source</ENAMEX> implied that he was asking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Currie</ENAMEX> to lie to back up his
version of events. If not rhetorical, the same question would have no such
conspiratorial connotation. It might indicate only that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> was trying to
refresh his recollection. In fact, this has been the defense offered by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesmen</ENAMEX> since the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Currie</ENAMEX> story broke. There's no
reason anyone sympathetic to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> would have included that "right?"--even if
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> had said it.

            The
disclosure was timed for maximum damage to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. At the moment it broke,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> was facing an imminent deadline for striking an immunity deal with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>. Like several previous leaks (some of them subsequently cast
into doubt), the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Currie</ENAMEX> story contained what looked a lot like a message from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> to his reluctant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX>: I have other evidence against you and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>,
so you'd better cut a deal quick. Even if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> side wanted to get this
damaging revelation out in order to spare itself pain later, it would have had
every reason to hold back until <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> concluded their
negotiations.

            
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">story</ENAMEX> quoted a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> spokesman
saying point-blank that the leak was "false." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Currie</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lawrence</ENAMEX>
Weschler, also said it was false that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> had tried to influence <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Currie</ENAMEX>. If
the leak did come from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Currie</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> or from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> legal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX>, the
Times was a willful party to a gross deception. It's almost impossible
to believe the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> would mislead its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> by allowing a
source to plant a story and deny planting it in the same news article.

            The same
day the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> story came out, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kendall</ENAMEX> rattled off a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX>-page letter to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> denouncing it and other leaks. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> fired back a defensive response.
Everyone spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX> debating who was right. This left the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX>
and, to a lesser extent, other news <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> in the screwy position in
which they remain. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> had to report on the debate about where its leak
had come from. But its goal was not the usual <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of news reporting, which is
to find the truth. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , after all, knows the truth here: It knows
who its own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> are. But in this case, it has granted its own version of
immunity to an act of potential lawbreaking for the sake of gathering
information about other potential misdeeds, much as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>
might do.

            
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A few days later</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX>
editorialized: "The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Kendall</ENAMEX>, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>'s
designated spinner, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Begala</ENAMEX>, cannot prove their sweeping televised
assertions that Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> has illegally leaked grand jury testimony. If he did,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> that supervises him and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney General</ENAMEX>, who has the
power to fire him, have the resources to deal with prosecutorial misconduct."
Hold it right there. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> knows whether <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kendall</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Begala</ENAMEX> are
correct or not. But it doesn't want to say, so it hides behind the legalistic
formula that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kendall</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Begala</ENAMEX> "cannot prove" their allegations. And if the
Times thinks that such leaks are "prosecutorial misconduct," why does it
participate in them?

            Is there any way out of this
morass? It's tempting to say that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> shouldn't accept leaks unless the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bias</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX> can be indicated. But that's probably not realistic. The
price of getting the story is often a promise of full anonymity. So long as
there's competitive pressure in the press, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> will use the outlet that
affords them the greatest protection.

            What the press can do is
cover leaking more aggressively. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> can't very well send
reporters snooping around after <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> in the same <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">newsroom</ENAMEX>. But there's no
ethical stricture against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> who aren't getting spoon-fed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>
pursuing the story of how and why and to whom the independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX>'s office
is leaking. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard Kurtz</ENAMEX>, the media <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> ,
does this a bit from time to time. For a story on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Currie</ENAMEX> leaks, he
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">interviewed Michael Oreskes</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Times Washington</ENAMEX> bureau <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX>. Oreskes
declined to tell him, of course, who the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> were. Instead of
leaving it there, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> should dig a little deeper. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> has an
obligation to protect his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>. He doesn't have to protect anybody else's.
So why hasn't 
                  Slate
                outed the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leakers</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> and
elsewhere? Because I haven't been able to establish who they are. Anyone who
knows, please feel free to leak it to me.

         
      
   
