
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albright</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet Dr. No</ENAMEX>

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last month</TIMEX>, as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tomahawking Osama Bin Laden</ENAMEX>, another little-noticed <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> foreign
policy drama was playing out in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Caribbean</ENAMEX>. On the tiny <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island nation</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St.</ENAMEX>
Kitts, a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine smuggler</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Charles "Little Nut</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miller</ENAMEX> threatened to
murder <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veterinary students</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX> unless the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> dropped its efforts to extradite him. A former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drug informant</ENAMEX> and
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dropout</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX> protection program, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miller</ENAMEX> has found a safe
haven on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Kitts</ENAMEX>, where his bullying and his cash have won him enormous
political influence with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX>'s shaky <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. At the news of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miller</ENAMEX>'s
threat, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Department</ENAMEX> flew diplomatic security <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisers</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Kitts</ENAMEX> to
reassure <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>; some of the young <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> fled home, and there were even
rumors of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grenada</ENAMEX>-like military strike to capture <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miller</ENAMEX>.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miller</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">imbroglio</ENAMEX> and the assault on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Bin Laden</ENAMEX> would appear to have nothing in
common, but they both illustrate a peculiar development in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> foreign
policy: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Bondification</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, born and raised during the age of the
nation-state, is accustomed to thinking of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> as the natural <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> of
foreign policy. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> negotiates with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX>, trades with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX>,
issues sanctions against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX>, and makes war on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX>. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> has begun to realize that it lives in a very different kind of world,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> filling up with what policy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">types</ENAMEX> call "nonstate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX>" and what
moviegoers recognize as "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Bond</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">villains</ENAMEX>." The nonstate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> range from
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 cent</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thugs</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miller</ENAMEX>, who has merely shanghaied a small island, to
world-class dastards such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Laden</ENAMEX>, who runs a supranational <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>,
has loyalty to no <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, owns a vast fortune and an armory of high-tech
weapons, and is engaged in an elaborate conspiracy so secretive that we were
not aware of it till it smacked us in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Habituated</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidents</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime ministers</ENAMEX>, we are now dealing with autonomous, mysterious characters
driven by motives that baffle us and who are unchecked by any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. Bin
Laden may not be quite as masterful as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blofeld</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miller</ENAMEX> may not be quite as
sinister as Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Big</ENAMEX>, but they're closer to them than we might think.

            Nonstate
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> are not, of course, an invention of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '90s</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> fought
its <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> war against the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Barbary Pirates</ENAMEX>, who terrorized <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> shipping in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mediterranean</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the turn of the 19 th century</TIMEX>. More recently, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yasser</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arafat</ENAMEX>'s stateless <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palestine Liberation Organization</ENAMEX> and terrorist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> such
as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hamas</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Islamic Jihad</ENAMEX> built <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> that have shaken governments
around the world. But there is no doubt that the variety and power of nonstate
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> is greater now than it has been for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">centuries</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Laden</ENAMEX>'s worldwide
terror <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> is currently dominating headlines, but other terrorist groups
are thriving as well. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Colombian</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Caribbean</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southeast Asian</ENAMEX> drug
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">lords</ENAMEX> have neutralized (or purchased) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> and recruited private armies.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">triads</ENAMEX> have established themselves as autonomous <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">powers</ENAMEX> in much of
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX>. What was <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central Asia</ENAMEX> is now a free-fire <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">zone</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drug</ENAMEX>, mineral, and
arms <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">barons</ENAMEX> compete for power, while legitimate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> of the region are
patsies by comparison. Even <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> are getting into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bond</ENAMEX> business.
Executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Outcomes</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">South African</ENAMEX> mercenary business, recently invaded,
stabilized, and controlled <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sierra Leone</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>--interrupting a long-waged
civil war--in order to protect that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s diamond <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mines</ENAMEX>.

            
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> reason why this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bondification</ENAMEX> seems to be
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">proliferating</ENAMEX> is the decline of the nation-state. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Kaplan</ENAMEX> chronicled
in The Ends of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX> , environmental collapse, tribal conflicts,
overpopulation, and urbanization have undermined Third World <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX>. For
most of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this century</TIMEX>, colonial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rulers</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nationalist dictators</ENAMEX> dominated
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>, monopolizing power with mighty central <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX>. But central
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">authority</ENAMEX> has vanished in much of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX>, and nonstate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> have
filled the vacuum. Where anarchy reigns, dollars can buy a private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire</ENAMEX>. It's
no surprise that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Laden</ENAMEX> chose <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sudan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bases</ENAMEX>: Neither
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> has had a functioning <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 years</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Laden</ENAMEX> paid the
Taliban <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a few million dollars</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> and guaranteed himself cover. Drug
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealers</ENAMEX>, similarly, have purchased fiefs throughout <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Latin America</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caribbean</ENAMEX>. (The difference between <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> is the difference
between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grenada</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Kitts</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Fifteen</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> invaded a
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Caribbean</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX> to get rid of a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> we didn't like.
Today, we could invade a <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Caribbean</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX> to get rid of a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealer</ENAMEX> we
don't like. This is government privatization, twisted beyond recognition.)

            This
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">anarchy</ENAMEX> has so far limited itself to marginal <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sudan</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sierra Leone</ENAMEX>, etc.--but soon, warns <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kaplan</ENAMEX>, a major <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> will
collapse. And when that happens, who knows what nutters will emerge? "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>
has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. So if it goes, there will be a lot of crazy lunatics
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">loose</ENAMEX>," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kaplan</ENAMEX>.

            There is another, more artificial, reason why <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> is
increasingly challenged by Bond <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">villains</ENAMEX>: We create them. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> public
generally yawns at the rest of the world. The tried and true method for ginning
up excitement about a foreign entanglement is to demonize, to focus on a single
foreign scoundrel. We battle <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX>, not <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Muammar Qaddafi</ENAMEX>, not
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Libya</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Manuel Noriega</ENAMEX>, not <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Panama</ENAMEX>. Similarly, it's easier to pin <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s drug
problem on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pablo Escobar</ENAMEX> or to blame global terrorism on a single nefarious
puppeteer such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Bin Laden</ENAMEX>. (It was astonishing how rapidly <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bin Laden</ENAMEX> emerged
as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s most hated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">One day</TIMEX>, a few <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Department</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operatives</ENAMEX> knew
his name. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next day</TIMEX>, we all did, and we were mad as hell at him.)

            Demonization creates a
dilemma for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> foreign policy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">makers</ENAMEX>. The best way to generate popular
support is to personalize the fight. And yet <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> policy forbids <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> from
actually trying to assassinate the chosen villain. Here is the heart of the
dilemma of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bondification</ENAMEX>. We know how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Bond</ENAMEX> neutralizes Bond <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">villains</ENAMEX>, but
how does a great power do it? The cruise <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missile</ENAMEX> strike against <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bin Laden</ENAMEX>
eerily mirrored the latest Bond movie, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tomorrow Never Dies</ENAMEX> , which opens
with a cruise <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missile</ENAMEX> strike against a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorist</ENAMEX> gathering in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central Asia</ENAMEX>. But
you can't rely on Bond tactics forever. We bombed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Laden</ENAMEX> once. Can we keep
doing it? Is it acceptable to pluck "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Little Nut</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miller</ENAMEX> off <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Kitts</ENAMEX>? Or does
that violate the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX>'s sovereignty? These are questions to which we don't
know the answer.

            More worrisome is that the
rise of Bond <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">villains</ENAMEX> encourages <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> to mistake the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enemy</ENAMEX> for the issue.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Colombian</ENAMEX> drug <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">warriors</ENAMEX> concentrated obsessively on destroying the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">wicked Escobar</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medell√</ENAMEX>≠n <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cartel</ENAMEX>. But while they pursued <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Escobar</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX> market opened for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cali</ENAMEX> cartel. Enemy eliminated, but problem
intact. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Laden</ENAMEX> is a fearsome enemy of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, and the sooner he's
killed the better. But even if he dropped dead <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, there would still be
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of underemployed, undereducated, alienated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Middle East</ENAMEX>
ready to follow a charismatic, militant, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>. In a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bond</ENAMEX> movie,
when <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">007</NUMEX> kills the archenemy, the crisis disappears. In the real world, it may
not.

         
      
   
