
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nut Watch</ENAMEX>

            
Everything you need to know about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Klayman</ENAMEX> can be gleaned from a press
release he blast-faxed to the world <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks ago</TIMEX>. The heading read:

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CLINTON</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ALLIES BEGIN SMEAR</ENAMEX> CAMPAIGN AGAINST JUDICIAL WATCH

            Use "Friendly" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Reporter</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Harm Memory of Grandmother of Larry</ENAMEX> Klayman

            Likely
Complicity of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton Private Investigators</ENAMEX>

            The
unhinged prose that followed responded to an item filed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">reporter Daniel Klaidman</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Klayman</ENAMEX> did not dispute the fact that he is suing his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mother</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shirley Feinberg</ENAMEX>. He claims his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> won't pay him back <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50,000</NUMEX> he spent
on private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurses</ENAMEX> for her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>, his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yetta Goldberg</ENAMEX>, who died
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last August</TIMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">89</NUMEX>. He did not want this suit to become public, but the
Clintonites, he asserted, learned about it and leaked word to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> .
The final paragraph of his statement bears quoting in full:

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Klaidman</ENAMEX> used this
information, obviously dug up by private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintons</ENAMEX> to
suggest that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Judicial Watch</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> will sue anyone, and so hurt Klayman
by trampling on the memory of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX>. This is untrue, unfair, and
outrageous! What is true is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Klayman</ENAMEX> will do what is right, no matter who
is involved. Whether it means caring for his sick and dying <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> who
raised him, guaranteeing payment to her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurses</ENAMEX>, or taking action to make sure
they are paid. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Klayman</ENAMEX> will not shrink from his standards of ethics and
morality. Unlike <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Klaidman</ENAMEX>, who wants to curry favor with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> administration
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> such as [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX>] <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Klayman</ENAMEX> looks to no one, other than
God, for guidance and direction.

            In fact,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> did not hear of this lawsuit, which was concealed under the
name of a collection <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> that belongs to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Klayman</ENAMEX>, from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>. It
found out from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Klayman</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>, who volunteered the information. But the
point is not just that this Klayman conspiracy is imaginary and far-fetched
( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , which broke the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> scandal, is hardly "friendly" toward
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>). It is that, as evidenced by this and other paranoiac
effusions, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Klayman</ENAMEX> is off his rocker.

            This became abundantly evident when I went to interview him
at his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>. After attempting to ascertain whether I was
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> spy or worked for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Salon</ENAMEX> magazine ("in our view, a front for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>"), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Klayman</ENAMEX> told me that "private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigator types</ENAMEX>"
working for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> have been spotted "casing" his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>. With darting eyes
and barely repressed rage, he alleged that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> secret <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> keep
files on him. He went on to tell me that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Brown</ENAMEX> was probably murdered
because of what he knew about various <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> scandals. Alleging the
existence of forensic evidence of murder, he explained, "Everybody in that lab
believed there was a round hole the size of a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.45</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">caliber bullet</ENAMEX>." (In <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> TV
interview, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Klayman</ENAMEX> suggested the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">killer</ENAMEX> was "perhaps the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> himself.")
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX> cover-up is the subject of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX> lawsuits <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Klayman</ENAMEX> has filed
against the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>. Another concerns the investigation into the death
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vince Foster</ENAMEX>, who <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Klayman</ENAMEX> thinks may also have been murdered.

            In other
words, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Klayman</ENAMEX> is one of the fringe <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> who has sprouted in the moist
ground of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> scandals as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mushrooms</ENAMEX> do after a spring <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rain</ENAMEX>. But Klayman
is not treated like a fringe figure. He has, by and large, achieved the
mainstream credibility he craves. He is a frequent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guest</ENAMEX> on such TV programs as
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Crossfire , Rivera Live</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MSNBC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Internight</ENAMEX> , and The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Grodin Show</ENAMEX> (with whose twitchy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX> he seems to have a special
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">affinity</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Klayman</ENAMEX> is financially supported, praised, and frequently cited by
the wider conservative movement. But he isn't just a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nutter</ENAMEX> who gets right-wing
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">foundation</ENAMEX> money and gets on television. He's a nutter with a law degree who
takes advantage of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> to harass his political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX>. How does he
get away with it?

            
The press elevates <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Klayman</ENAMEX> for a couple of
reasons. On television, there are more and more shows that take off from the
Crossfire format, expecting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX> to represent strongly contrary
positions. If one thinks <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Starr</ENAMEX> is out of control, the other, ideally,
should argue that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> knifes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and buries their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> basement. If these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX> scream and yell, so much the better.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barking</ENAMEX>, however, undermines the pretense of a rational debate. Klayman, who
presents a coherent façade while making wild and unsubstantiated charges, is
perfect. With print <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX>, there's a different problem. Fine profiles of
Klayman have recently appeared in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> . But the conventions of newspaper journalism are such that an
"objective" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> cannot render his own opinion that the subject has a screw
loose. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Klayman</ENAMEX> is described in such terms as "controversial legal gadfly."

            You might
think mainstream <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> would be wary of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Klayman</ENAMEX>'s tactics. Tort reform
was part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Contract With America</ENAMEX>, and he is a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-man litigation
explosion. But so far, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> have been silent, perhaps because Klayman
has proved remarkably effective at abusing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">right-wingers</ENAMEX>
dislike. His primary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">vehicle</ENAMEX> is a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$90 million</NUMEX> invasion of privacy suit filed
against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX> and others on behalf of the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>" of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Filegate</ENAMEX>.
Never mind that congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Starr</ENAMEX> have decided that the
gathering of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> files on previous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> with names starting
with letters A through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX> was not part of a grand plot to harass political
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Klayman</ENAMEX> has found an opening to harass his political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX>,
inflicting costly all-day depositions on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harold Ickes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">James</ENAMEX>
Carville, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Begala</ENAMEX>, and many others.

            In these torture session, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Klayman</ENAMEX> rants and raves and
demands to "certify" for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> answers that he deems evasive. ("What does
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'certified</ENAMEX>' mean," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ickes</ENAMEX> responded to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Klayman</ENAMEX>, "other than 'crazy'<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>") Klayman
asks <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> about whom they date, where they go after work,
whether they were expelled from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> for disciplinary problems. One
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assistant</ENAMEX> was interrogated about a triple murder that
took place at a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Starbucks</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgetown</ENAMEX>. Klayman videotapes these depositions,
excerpts of which air on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Geraldo</ENAMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Klayman</ENAMEX> appears on the program,
and publishes the transcripts on the Internet. This is in pursuit of a case
about the invasion of privacy, remember. But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resistance</ENAMEX> is largely futile. Last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>, the presiding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> in the case sanctioned <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX> for not looking
hard enough for documents covered by a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Judicial Watch</ENAMEX> subpoena. As punishment,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX> has to go through the ordeal of another deposition and pay some
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Klayman</ENAMEX>'s legal costs. The ultimate goal of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Filegate</ENAMEX> suit appears to be
to inflict this treatment on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX>.

            Why don't
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> put a stop to this? Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> have tried. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Klayman</ENAMEX> lost a patent case on behalf of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">distributor</ENAMEX> of bathroom accessories.
His obnoxious behavior got him barred from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Keller</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courtroom</ENAMEX> for
life. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Klayman</ENAMEX> has hounded <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keller</ENAMEX> ever since. He appealed the ruling, accusing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keller</ENAMEX> of being <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-Semitic</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-Asian</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Klayman</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX>; his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX> was
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Taiwanese</ENAMEX>). After losing his appeal and being scolded by the appeals court
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX>, he tried to appeal to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>. He has not given up yet. It is
this matter, he has said, which led him to found <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Judicial Watch</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organization</ENAMEX> supports requiring <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> to undergo psychological testing and
holding them personally liable for "reckless" rulings. It also advocates
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">removing Keller</ENAMEX> from the bench.

            
More recently, in a trade case in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Klayman</ENAMEX> found himself on the other end of charges of ethnic bias. When <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Judge</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Denny Chin</ENAMEX> ruled against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Klayman's</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">client</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Klayman</ENAMEX> wrote <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chin</ENAMEX> a rude letter
asking about his contacts with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Huang</ENAMEX> and suggesting that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chin</ENAMEX>'s being an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asian-American Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">appointee</ENAMEX> may have biased him. The connection was
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">imaginary</ENAMEX>. In our interview, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Klayman</ENAMEX> claimed press accounts of this incident
have made it sound as if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huang-Chin</ENAMEX> connection was baseless. He said it was
supported by a document discovered in one of his lawsuits. But the document,
which he faxed to me, turns out to be merely a list of Asian-Americans
appointed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>. Chin fined <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Klayman $25,000</NUMEX> and barred
him from his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courtroom</ENAMEX> for life. A <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>-judge <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Court of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Appeals</ENAMEX> threw out the fine but upheld the expulsion. "I've got ethics
complaints pending against all <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> of them," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Klayman</ENAMEX> says.

            Despite <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Klayman</ENAMEX>'s record of
abusing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Royce C. Lamberth</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">appointee</ENAMEX>, has been
extremely indulgent of his antics in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Filegate</ENAMEX> case, giving him wide
latitude to issue subpoenas. Whether <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lamberth</ENAMEX> has succumbed to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Klayman</ENAMEX> out of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ideology</ENAMEX>, permissiveness, or fear of reprisal it is impossible to say. Last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamberth</ENAMEX> did finally throw out a fishing-expedition type subpoena Klayman
sent to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">New Yorker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane Mayer</ENAMEX>. After <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mayer</ENAMEX> reported <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Tripp</ENAMEX>
had lied about a youthful arrest for robbery, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Klayman</ENAMEX> asserted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mayer</ENAMEX> had been
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fed</ENAMEX> the information by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> secret <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> and that it was thus relevant
to his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Filegate</ENAMEX> case. It turns out, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mayer</ENAMEX> wrote in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>, that her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX> on the robbery incident was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tripp</ENAMEX>'s former
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">stepmother</ENAMEX>--who has since agreed to go on the record. But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Klayman</ENAMEX> still
believes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> fed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX> arrest story to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mayer</ENAMEX>. "She's not
telling the truth about that," he says. "Were there <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> private
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> working with her?" Maybe he'll ask his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> in her next
deposition.

         
      
   
