
   
   
      
         
            Out of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Left Field</ENAMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> does not ordinarily
expect a slim volume written by an academic philosopher and published by a
university <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX> to cause widespread consternation on the right. But for some
reason, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Rorty</ENAMEX>'s new book, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Achieving Our Country</ENAMEX> , which is based
on a series of lectures delivered <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX>, seems to be having that
effect. Writing in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Will</ENAMEX> commented <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> that the
book "radiates contempt for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>." (Perhaps more to the point, it
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">radiates</ENAMEX> .) And in the most recent issue of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly Standard</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brooks</ENAMEX> contends that the book's criticism of the left is merely the latest in a
succession of moves designed to advance the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>'s academic career. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brooks</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">accuses Rorty</ENAMEX> of being a "pseudo-deviant" who poses as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> of academic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">radicals</ENAMEX> while really congratulating them.

            You'd
think high-minded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> would approve of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Rorty</ENAMEX> at some level,
even if they disagree with him. He is, after all, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">philosopher</ENAMEX> who writes good
English prose in defense of the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">100 percent</NUMEX> American philosophy of pragmatism.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rorty</ENAMEX> has no truck with campus PC and is by all reports a humane, thoughtful,
and decent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, not the kind of self-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoter</ENAMEX> or manipulative careerist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brooks</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">posits</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Achieving Our Country</ENAMEX> tells <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rorty</ENAMEX> calls the
"cultural left" to come down from their postmodernist ivory <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tower</ENAMEX> and think
about how to make the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> they live in a better place. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rorty</ENAMEX> says radical
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">academicians</ENAMEX> should wipe that sophistical smirk off their faces, lose their
mocking disdain for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, and view it more as their progressive ancestors
did: as a great, problem-filled <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> that must be brought into closer
alignment with its ideals.

            Isn't this the kind of loyal opposition <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">right-wingers</ENAMEX> are
supposed to want? The harsh response to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rorty</ENAMEX> may have something to do with his
penchant for gratuitous, con-baiting asides, such as the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> in which he
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">absurdly</ENAMEX> states that "we caused the death of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Vietnamese</ENAMEX> out of sheer
macho arrogance." In the course of the book, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rorty</ENAMEX> sets even liberal teeth on
edge with such outlandish statements, though they are usually contradicted in
more sober moments. (He thinks the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX> was necessary and that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> was
correct to call the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> an "evil <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire</ENAMEX>.") But I think that what
really alarms the right about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rorty</ENAMEX> is not his moments of rhetorical excess but
rather the buried fear that the left might <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> wake up and take his advice.
If the alienated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">theorists</ENAMEX> of academe transformed themselves into a Rortyan
left--a unified, engaged, and patriotic left--conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnists</ENAMEX> could run
dry of material in a matter of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX>.

            It
wouldn't be good news for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>, either, if the left listened
to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rorty</ENAMEX> and joined a common crusade for social betterment. His book argues not
only that academic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leftists</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heirs</ENAMEX> to the '60s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Left</ENAMEX>, need to become
pro-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> but also that they need to quit knocking heads with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heirs</ENAMEX> to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Old Left</ENAMEX>--the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX>--and vice versa. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rorty</ENAMEX> wants to draw a
curtain over the distinction between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leftists</ENAMEX>. We should all
forget about our past conflicts, he says, and realize that we were always on
the same side, more or less. "It would be a good idea to stop asking when it
was unforgivably late, or unforgivably early, to have left the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communist</ENAMEX>
Party," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rorty</ENAMEX> writes. "A <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">hundred years from now</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howe</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Galbraith</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harrington</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schlesinger</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilson</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Debs</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane Addams</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angela Davis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Felix</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Frankfurther</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John L. Lewis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">W.E.B. Du Bois</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor Roosevelt</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Jackson</ENAMEX>, will all be remembered for having advanced the cause
of social justice."

            
Some on the right may fear the emergence of a
new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">left-liberal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Popular Front</ENAMEX> that looks up to all these ancestors.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Conservatives</ENAMEX> achieved a general unity despite their wide differences during
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, and they might think the left is capable of doing the same
thing. But what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rorty</ENAMEX> proposes is still <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several decades</TIMEX> away, at least.
Disagreements on the left are far more ingrained--and more meaningful--than he
seems to fathom. But even if they were to magically vanish <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">overnight</TIMEX>, they
aren't about to dissolve in favor of anything resembling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rorty</ENAMEX>'s agenda. His
political platform, a kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Swedish</ENAMEX> model democratic socialism couched in
extracts from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Whitman</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dewey</ENAMEX>, is about as likely to sweep the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> at
this point as freemasonry or theosophy.

            In trying
to persuade <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lefties</ENAMEX> of various stripes to quit fighting, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rorty</ENAMEX> borrows a
strategy from pragmatist philosophy. He takes questions that he doesn't find
useful to his cause--such as who was correct about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> or about the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold</ENAMEX>
War--and rules them out of order. They aren't helpful to us in moving forward,
so there is no point in discussing them. But the issues that have split the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> left in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this century</TIMEX> were not the expression of narcissistic small
differences. They represented fundamental splits--between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> of
constitutional democracy and its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX>, between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX> of
human rights, between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who believe in limited <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and those who
want an overweening <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arthur Schlesinger</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angela Davis</ENAMEX> were not on the
same side, even in the most general way. For <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rorty</ENAMEX> to brush aside even these
conflicts as the nuances of ancient history is both <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">crude</ENAMEX> and an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offense</ENAMEX> to
those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> who were on the right side. In constructing an inclusive
tradition of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> left, he would undermine the sound tradition of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> left. Rorty, who comes from a distinguished <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> of progressives and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">anti-communist</ENAMEX> left <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX>, ought to know better.

            But even if these old battles somehow were to cease to seem
relevant, which they might to a generation raised in a world without communism,
it is hard to imagine a revival of interest in the kind of democratic-socialist
program <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rorty</ENAMEX> sees as the essence of national betterment. Though he is at his
most vague on the subject of actual policy, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> gathers that what he wants is a
kind of economic <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> way: A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> that redistributes wealth through the
tax system while providing uniform social benefits, such as health care and
pensions. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Unions</ENAMEX> should be more powerful, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> less so. It's the
dull-but-worthy program of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dissent</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>, circa <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1967</TIMEX>. Think of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bulworth</ENAMEX> without the rhymes. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rorty</ENAMEX> believes that it is merely the greed
of the wealthy that prevents the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> from solving all its problems. They
want to keep their money for themselves! And navel-gazing literary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> let
them get away with it!

            Personally, I don't think
that what stands in the way of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rorty</ENAMEX>'s utopia is the failure of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frederic</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jameson</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Terry Eagleton</ENAMEX> to endorse it. It's that there's not enough caffeine
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>--and that the whole world is in retreat from all forms of socialism
and semi-socialism. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rorty</ENAMEX> writes about politics as if he'd been holding out in
a small cave without <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past several decades</TIMEX>. He has not
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">gleaned</ENAMEX> anything from the experience that the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Atlantic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">democracies</ENAMEX> have had in
governing themselves over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past 30 years</TIMEX>, or from their rather mixed record
in dealing with social ills. Nor does he consider the possibility that markets
might be effective in dealing with some social problems. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Conservatives</ENAMEX> can quit
fretting. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Liberals</ENAMEX> might be out of it, but we're not about to start taking cues
from a peacenik philosophy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prof.</ENAMEX> who's still chasing after the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Swedish</ENAMEX>
model.

            
               If you
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">missed Rorty</ENAMEX>'s slap at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Will</ENAMEX>, click .
            

         
      
   
