
   
   
      
         
            No Left Turn

            A regular feature of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> has been the unfulfilled prophecy that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> is--any
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> now--about to make a sharp turn to the left. Through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">most of 1993</TIMEX> and
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">'94</NUMEX>, the refrain of disenchanted <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">New Democrats</ENAMEX> was that although <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> had
been elected on a centrist platform of welfare reform and deficit reduction,
his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> was being captured by old-school libs. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '96</TIMEX> campaign,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX> warned <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> that a re-elected <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> would drop his guise of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">moderation</ENAMEX>, "his liberalism unrestrained by the need to face the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> election," as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> put it.

            These
predictions' failure appears to be no deterrent to their regular renewal. Only
the rationale for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s rebirth as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LBJ</ENAMEX> changes. The latest version is that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is finally showing his true color (pale pink) because of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>. "The politics of scandal is doing what mere policy hasn't done since
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> took <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>--forcing the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Great Triangulator</ENAMEX> back into the
protective custody of his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Gigot</ENAMEX> wrote <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> in the
Wall Street <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> .

            There are actually several versions of this theory.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Conservatives</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gigot</ENAMEX> believe <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberal</ENAMEX> at heart. They see him
lying in wait for an opportunity to expand <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and raise taxes. A
variation on this casts the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">first lady</ENAMEX> as the closet <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberal</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Conservatives</ENAMEX>
point to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dick Morris</ENAMEX>' recent assertion that the scandal has given <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whip hand</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>. There are also nonconservatives who think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>
may turn left for practical if not ideological reasons. "He's going to have to
keep an eye on his base--the very <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who elected him," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Cohen</ENAMEX> wrote
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few days ago</TIMEX>. "Significantly, that means <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>,
especially <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">feminists</ENAMEX>, and organized labor." The theory here is that if
threatened with impeachment, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> will need his <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">die-hards</ENAMEX> for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">protection</ENAMEX>.

            The
problem with these forecasts is that they are, once again, wrong. It is very
probable the sex scandal will have some effect on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s politics. Though
it's hard to make out the precise effect at this point, the fear of a meltdown
in his popularity and the distant threat of impeachment are likely to make the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> more risk-averse. He's less liable to do anything dicey or bold. At a
moment in his presidency when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> might otherwise be thinking about how to
spend some of his accumulated political capital, that's a damned shame. Instead
of leading the way on entitlement reform, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> may return to the sort of
middle-class populism he expressed during his last campaign--with perhaps an
extra dollop of pandering. An embattled <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is prone not just to play the
demagogue on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> but also to promote dubious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> reforms and climb aboard
a new <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Communications Decency Act</ENAMEX>.

            
Much of the new suspicion about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">lurching</ENAMEX> left stems from the surprising entente between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and
congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> who are more liberal than he is. After quarreling for
the better part of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX>, they now seem to be getting along. But there's
an explanation for this, which has nothing to do with the scandal. After the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> voted not to renew the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s fast-track trade negotiating
authority <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last fall</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> became preoccupied with fostering a more
productive relationship with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Staff Erskine Bowles</ENAMEX> authorized <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> senior
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Podesta</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rahm Emanuel</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doug Sosnik</ENAMEX>--to try to draw up a
common agenda with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Gephardt</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daschle</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> revealed the fruits of these negotiations in remarks at a "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic</ENAMEX>
Unity" rally <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 14</TIMEX>. The main items he focused on in that speech were making
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> as young as <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">55</NUMEX> eligible to buy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> coverage and regulating managed
care with a "Patients <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Bill of Rights</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> revealed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> other proposals
jointly supported by the congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dems</ENAMEX> in his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State of the Union</ENAMEX> address,
which was delivered after the scandal broke: reserving future budget surpluses
until some fix has been found for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>, and raising the minimum
wage. These are hardly radical proposals--old-style <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> would prefer to
spend a budget surplus on social programs, and they want to increase the
minimum wage by <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than the $1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has offered. But in any case, the
common <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">platform</ENAMEX> was negotiated long before anyone had heard of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>.

            In embracing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s agenda, congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> have
moved toward the center more than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has moved left. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Liberals</ENAMEX> who used to
spend most of their time being annoyed at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> have rallied around him in
the face of a common enemy, realizing that a crumbling presidency would leave
them in the worst possible shape to face the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> election. Is it possible that
the threat of impeachment will force <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> deeper into the embrace of liberal
interest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>? This is largely uncharted terrain, but there's little reason
to think so. Looking to the only comparisons available, <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iran-Contra</ENAMEX> didn't make <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> more ideological. They just took the
wind out of their sails and undermined the possibility of any <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> term
agenda.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Conservatives</ENAMEX> continue to
fall prey to the fallacy of an impending left turn because they misunderstand
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. They think that because his political consciousness was formed during
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">'60s</NUMEX>, he must be a secret <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberal</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is above all a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pragmatist</ENAMEX>.
One lesson he has learned is that being too far to the left is a political
hazard. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> lost his job as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX> as a result of
liberal crusading during his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> term. He regained it in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1982</TIMEX> by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">repositioning</ENAMEX> himself as a moderate. The same thing happened again after he
became <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> thought he was safe supporting universal health care
if he rejected the single-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">payer</ENAMEX> system supported by old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX>. But even his
hybrid scheme was too much for a public mistrustful of expanding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> regained his footing and won re-election in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> through a calculated
centrism that is likely to remain his approach to politics for what remains of
his elective career.

            Of course, it doesn't take
much to make someone a lefty <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Liberals</ENAMEX> used to call for cutbacks in
defense spending, higher welfare benefits, and a federal full employment
program. Now they want a tiny bit more social spending within the context of a
balanced budget. To <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX>, a liberal <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> is someone who doesn't
support cutting taxes. They should give <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> a few more <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX>. If things
get hot enough, he may come out for a tax cut too.

         
      
   
