
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Norplant</ENAMEX> Option

            Now that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> have opted to use the threat of utter destitution to dissuade
poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-agers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> from having <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> on the public dole, it's time to
revive a more humane, and perhaps more effective, proposal with the same
objective.

            This idea surfaced briefly
and spectacularly in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>, when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Philadelphia Inquirer</ENAMEX> suggested in
an editorial that perhaps some welfare <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> should be "offered an increased
benefit" if they would agree to practice effective birth control--specifically,
to use the then-new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Norplant</ENAMEX> contraceptive, which prevents pregnancy for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> after being implanted under the skin of the upper <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX>.

            An uproar
followed. The editorial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>--who had insensitively suggested a desire to
reduce births of poor black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX> in particular--were savaged by many
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inquirer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffers</ENAMEX> and others as racist <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> of eugenics, even of
"genocide." They also caught it from some abortion-rights <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">zealots</ENAMEX>, who are
suspicious of any government efforts to influence reproductive choices, and
from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX>, who think the only proper way to discourage teen pregnancy
is to preach abstinence. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> abjectly apologized for a "misguided and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">wrongheaded</ENAMEX> editorial opinion." And ever since, the whole subject has been
taboo.

            
But it's still a good idea, for poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> themselves, and for the rest of us. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Millions</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX> are being born to
poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-agers</ENAMEX> so lacking in elementary skills, work habits, and
self-discipline that they are unlikely to be either responsible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> or
self-supporting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX>. Many of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX> grow up in squalor and
themselves become dependent denizens of the welfare culture.

            The only
realistic hope for breaking the bleak cycle of teen pregnancy and welfare
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dependency</ENAMEX> is to find ways to persuade <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poor teen-agers</ENAMEX> not to have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX>--at
least, not until they are old enough, and capable enough, and self-supporting
enough to provide a decent home life. But nobody--nobody--has any great ideas
for realizing this hope, short of reverting to the cruelest, let-'em-starve
brand of social <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Darwinism</ENAMEX>.

            
Thoughtful progressives like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patrick Moynihan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.Y.</ENAMEX>, have properly stressed the need to push welfare
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> into jobs and job-training programs. This makes sense because some of
these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> will rise to the occasion, learn the work ethic, and become
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">self-supporting</ENAMEX>. And others may be dissuaded from having <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">prospect</ENAMEX> of being required to work. But (as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moynihan</ENAMEX> acknowledges) many welfare
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> are so crippled by their own early childhood environments as to be
essentially unemployable, no matter how well-financed and well-run the jobs
programs and related counseling, training, and child-care programs.

            And under the harsh new
welfare reform, the jobs programs will not be well financed. It appears that
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of welfare <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> will simply be cut off--unable to get
or hold jobs, and left to beg from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strangers</ENAMEX>, to steal what they
can, even to sleep on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX>, depending on how much <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calcutta</ENAMEX>-style misery
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX> are willing to tolerate.

            Given the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">stark</ENAMEX> ugliness of trying to end the welfare culture by spreading homelessness
and hunger, it's especially striking that one pretty good, pretty humane idea
has been virtually ignored in the welfare debate of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past year</TIMEX>.

            
In a small effort to reopen discussion of this
option, here's a specific proposal: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">States</ENAMEX> should experiment with programs in
which all qualifying <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-agers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> would be offered lump-sum <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX> cash
payments--on top of any other benefits they receive--to have <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norplant</ENAMEX> (or
another long-term contraceptive) implanted at government expense. They would be
free to have it removed whenever they chose, but would be rewarded with
additional payments (of, say, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$30</NUMEX>) for each month in which they kept it.

            The
category of qualifying <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-agers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> could include all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> of
welfare or other public assistance (including <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX>) who are
competent to give informed consent to the implant procedure. Or the program
could be restricted in various ways in order to blunt possible objections. For
example, you could require parental consent. Or, eligibility could be
restricted to those who have already been pregnant, or at least sexually
active; to those over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 13</TIMEX>, or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">under age 21</TIMEX>; or some combination thereof.

            
Why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norplant</ENAMEX>? Because it requires no ongoing
effort or supervision to be effective, and it can be discontinued only after
some (rather small) effort. As such, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Norplant</ENAMEX> is the only contraceptive the
government could pay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to use with any hope of affecting those who aren't
strongly motivated to either become pregnant or avoid pregnancy.

            How much
good the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Norplant</ENAMEX> option would do is debatable. But the arguments that it would
do harm seem unpersuasive. Here's a quick review of possible objections, left
and right:

            
B ribing poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> to implant
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Norplant</ENAMEX> would coerce them into not having <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, thus violating their
rights to reproductive choice, like the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-child-per-family policy and coerced
abortions in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>.
            

            To the contrary, a government
offer of money is not coercion--and not even remotely comparable to what goes
on in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>. Existing benefits would not be reduced for anyone declining
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Norplant</ENAMEX>. This means that nobody who really wanted a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> would be prevented
from having <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. To be sure, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> would be trying to influence
reproductive choices. But the same is true of existing policies promoting free
contraception, and of laws like the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Hyde Amendment</ENAMEX>, which denies Medicaid
funding for abortions--not to mention the still extant statutes making it a
crime to commit statutory rape (sex with a consenting minor), fornication
(premarital sex), and adultery.

            In its groveling <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>
editorial apology, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inquirer</ENAMEX> said: "Our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> countered that to
dangle cash or some other benefit in front of a desperately poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> is
tantamount to coercion. They're right." No, they were wrong, and the
Inquirer was right in its initial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Norplant</ENAMEX> editorial, when it noted that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> would be free to "change their minds at any point and become fertile
again."

            "Many
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Boldt</ENAMEX>, then-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inquirer</ENAMEX>'s editorial page, noted in a
subsequent commentary, "saw the editorial as part of an ongoing white
conspiracy to carry out genocide of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>."

            This is
pernicious nonsense, no matter how many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> say it. The original
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inquirer</ENAMEX> editorial unwittingly invited such smears by linking its
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Norplant</ENAMEX> proposal to race--specifically, to a report that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly half</NUMEX> the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nation</ENAMEX>'s black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are living in poverty. But nobody is proposing that
race be a factor in any program promoting <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Norplant</ENAMEX> to welfare <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX>, most
of whom are white. Nobody is proposing to sterilize <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> or forbid them from
having <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. And while a disproportionate percentage of welfare <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are black, black <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, like white <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, can only benefit from
any program that rewards <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> for avoiding pregnancy unless and until they
are old enough and self-supporting enough to provide decently for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>.

            
G irls and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Norplant</ENAMEX> may be at
greater risk of contracting and spreading <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX>, because they will be less
likely to demand that their sex <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partners</ENAMEX> use condoms.
            

            A <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>
study reported in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New England Journal of Medicine</ENAMEX> found that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Norplant</ENAMEX> had no effect on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX>' decisions whether to use condoms or visit
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX>--and was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19</NUMEX> times as effective as the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pill</ENAMEX> in preventing pregnancy. Any
Norplant incentive program should include vigorous counseling about the need to
use condoms against <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX>. But even now, how many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> are so much
more afraid of pregnancy than of death that they use condoms solely to avoid
the former, and would stop once on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Norplant</ENAMEX>? Not many, I suspect.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX> orplant itself may be unhealthy.
            

            The
possibility of serious long-term health damage from any relatively new
contraceptive like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norplant</ENAMEX> must be taken seriously, and the risks should, of
course, be fully disclosed to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> considering using it. But no contraceptive
is risk-free. And the available evidence indicates that the risks inherent in
pregnancy and childbirth--and in abortion--are at least as great as the risks
inherent in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Norplant</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Plaintiffs</ENAMEX>' tort lawyers
have nearly killed off <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norplant</ENAMEX>, scaring away many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX>, by a
torrent of personal-injury suits against its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> include
many of the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> who created a tidal wave of litigation based on the
apparently bogus claim about the dangers of silicone breast <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">implants</ENAMEX>. But the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Food and Drug Administration</ENAMEX> has repeatedly found <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norplant</ENAMEX> to be safe and
effective. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">More than a million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> have used it with only minor side effects,
such as changing menstrual bleeding patterns, reported.

            There
have been complaints by a small percentage of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Norplant</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> of severe pain or
scarring from having it removed. But the apparent reason was inadequate
training of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX> in the (usually quick and painless) removal
procedure--an easily remedied problem--and not any inherent defect in the
product.

            
I t is sexist to seek to thrust contraception
only upon <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>.
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sexism</ENAMEX> has nothing to do with
it. First, almost all welfare checks are written to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>--not to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, who
don't get pregnant. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, the only forms of contraception now available for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> are condoms and vasectomies. It would hardly make sense to hand out <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX>
payments to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> for taking home a bunch of condoms, or to try to police their
use. And a vasectomy--unlike a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Norplant</ENAMEX> implant-- cannot always be
reversed.

            
               Giving teen-agers
contraceptives encourages promiscuity, and bribing them to use <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Norplant</ENAMEX> will
encourage it even more.
            

            The weight
of the evidence suggests that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-agers</ENAMEX>' decisions whether or not to engage in
sexual activity don't have much to do with whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> gives them
contraceptives. Many have unprotected sex, and almost all can get
contraceptives if they want them. As I have suggested, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> possible restriction
(although not one I would favor) on any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Norplant</ENAMEX> incentive program would be to
limit eligibility to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-agers</ENAMEX> who have already been pregnant or, at least,
sexually active. Norplant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counselors</ENAMEX> could also stress the benefits of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">abstinence</ENAMEX>, while presenting the contraceptive as a backup safeguard.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">een-agers</ENAMEX> should learn about sex and
contraception from their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>, not the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>.
            

            A parental-consent
requirement would answer this objection. I would not advocate such a
requirement, however, because of the overwhelming evidence that many parents
have little or no constructive communication with their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> about such
matters. I hope that my own <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX> (now <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12 and nine years old</TIMEX>) would
consult with me and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> before getting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norplant</ENAMEX> or becoming sexually
active. But if they end up deciding to go their own ways, I'd rather that they
have unrestricted access to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Norplant</ENAMEX> than that they risk pregnancy.

            Would a
Norplant program be thwarted by the fact that many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poor teen-agers</ENAMEX> actually
want to get pregnant and have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>? I don't think so. First, there are about
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3 million</NUMEX> unwanted pregnancies in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of which
end in abortion. Many of these involve <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-agers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who are (or will
be) on welfare. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Norplant</ENAMEX> could stop almost all these. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, the allure of
pregnancy for many other poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-agers</ENAMEX> may be so slight, or so fleeting, or
so fraught with ambivalence, that a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX> Norplant incentive would have plenty
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">takers</ENAMEX>.

            
And even if such a program only delayed
pregnancies <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years</TIMEX>, that would be a very good thing. Most <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15-year-olds</TIMEX>
would be better <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX>, and have a better chance of making something of their
own lives, if they waited <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five or seven years</TIMEX> before having <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Norplant</ENAMEX> is no panacea for
poverty; nothing is. The question is whether a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Norplant</ENAMEX> incentive program might
do some good. There's only one way to find out: Give it a try. If it fails, the
cost--in terms of numbers of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-agers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> taking the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX> offer--will
be tiny. And it just might help.

         
      
   
