
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dobson's Choice</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Conquest</ENAMEX> has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> laws of politics, which are recorded in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kingsley Amis</ENAMEX>'
Memoirs . The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> is that, "generally speaking, everybody is
reactionary on the subjects he knows about." The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> is "every organization
appears to be headed by secret <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> of its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX>."

            Conquest
Rule No. 2 applies nicely to the recent activities of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Focus on the Family</ENAMEX>, an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organization</ENAMEX> of the religious right run by the radio <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">evangelist</ENAMEX> and family
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">counselor James Dobson</ENAMEX>. Those on the irreligious left describe <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dobson</ENAMEX> as the
most powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian conservatives</ENAMEX> active <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. But lately, his
behavior seems as if it were scripted by his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">antagonists</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> for the

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">About two months ago</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dobson</ENAMEX> began saying in private that
the failure of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> to take his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>-values agenda seriously
might impel him to lead a mass walkout from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>. He delivered that
démarche to a meeting of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">basement</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Capitol</ENAMEX> on
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 18</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dobson</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> that they must act on a range of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">social</ENAMEX>-conservative issues, such as abortion, gay rights, and school prayer--or
else. Unsatisfied with their response, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dobson</ENAMEX> went public with a series of
unusual interviews in the secular media. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dobson</ENAMEX>'s face appeared on the cover of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News & World Report</ENAMEX> , below a headline that read, in part, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Now</ENAMEX>,
he has decided the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican Party</ENAMEX> must convert or be brought down." On
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> , he said that evangelical <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christians</ENAMEX> who put the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> in control of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> had been "insulted" and
"disrespected" ever since. Asked about the consequences of a walkout, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dobson</ENAMEX>
told <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Russert</ENAMEX>, "It would be the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, so that would be unfortunate. But you never take a hill unless you're
willing to die on it. And we will die on this hill if necessary."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> are furious with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dobson</ENAMEX> over these comments, and for good reason. By
blackmailing them so openly, he is telling them, in effect, to choose their
poison. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> can either show <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dobson</ENAMEX> the door, or it can try to move his
radical agenda, which calls for, among other things, abolition of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Department</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Education</ENAMEX> and a constitutional amendment to ban abortion. If
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> stiff him, they may lose a crucial component of their narrow
majority. If, on the other hand, they "convert," they get to watch moderates
and economic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> flee in horror. In sending a message that the party
can't take its conservative base for granted, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dobson</ENAMEX> also sends a signal to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">electorate</ENAMEX> as a whole: <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> are being ordered around by a frightening
religious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">zealot</ENAMEX>.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dobson</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">62</TIMEX>, is less well known than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Falwell or Pat Robertson</ENAMEX> and far more powerful than either of them. Born in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shreveport</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">La.</ENAMEX>, he is descended from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generations</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nazarene</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ministers</ENAMEX>.
But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dobson</ENAMEX> did not become ordained as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX> himself. Instead, he took a
psychology. His book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dare to Discipline</ENAMEX> , published in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1970</TIMEX>, turned him
into a kind of conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spock</ENAMEX>, as he has often been described,
eventually selling <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 2 million</NUMEX> copies. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1977</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dobson</ENAMEX> used the book as
a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">platform</ENAMEX> to found <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Focus on the Family</ENAMEX>, a nonprofit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> based in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Colorado</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Springs</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colo.</ENAMEX> Focus on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Family</ENAMEX> dispenses family counseling over an
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">800</ENAMEX> number and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sponsors</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dobson</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> radio broadcast, in which he serves up
advice on marriage and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>-rearing along with condemnations of "humanism," a
philosophy he equates with all forms of social permissiveness. The program,
which is heard on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX>, has helped <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dobson</ENAMEX> develop a mailing list of
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 2 million</NUMEX> names.

            Over the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past decade</TIMEX>, he has become more and more explicitly political. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dobson</ENAMEX>
set up the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>-based <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Family Research Council</ENAMEX>, headed by his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ally</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bauer</ENAMEX>, a former <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bauer is to Dobson</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ralph</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reed</ENAMEX> until recently was to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Robertson</ENAMEX>. Focus on the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Family and the Family</ENAMEX>
Research <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> are now technically separate, but they work hand in glove.
Both raised a ruckus in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> when party <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Haley Barbour</ENAMEX> ventured the
notion that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> could be a "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Big Tent</ENAMEX>" party on abortion. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
threatened to walk out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Republican National Convention</ENAMEX> if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>
modified its uncompromising anti-abortion <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">plank</ENAMEX> or if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX> picked a
pro-choice running mate such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Colin Powell</ENAMEX>.

            This absolutism contrasted with the stance of the rival
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coalition</ENAMEX>. Under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reed</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian Coalition</ENAMEX> was more
politically savvy, more open to compromise with the nonreligious right, and
more accepting of the reality that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> victory was a prerequisite for
any kind of conservative change. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reed</ENAMEX> recognized that his power depended on not
demanding constant satisfaction from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>. Thus, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">in 1996 Reed</ENAMEX> threw his
weight behind <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> early in the primary <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX> and flirted with the idea of
accepting modified language on abortion in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> platform. For this, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dobson</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX> denounced him as a power-hungry sellout.

            With <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reed</ENAMEX>
gone into private political consulting, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian Coalition</ENAMEX> has been
eclipsed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dobson</ENAMEX>. Of late, they have been involving themselves in
congressional races, to the chagrin of the national <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bauer</ENAMEX> spent <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$250,000</NUMEX>
in support of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Bordonaro</ENAMEX>, a conservative who defeated the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Committee</ENAMEX>-approved moderate in a special election primary in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bordonaro</ENAMEX> then lost to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lois Capps</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dobson</ENAMEX>, who has
seldom made political endorsements in the past, recently backed ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dornan</ENAMEX>, the well-known ultracon wacko, against a moderate <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> in an
upcoming congressional primary. Party <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">regulars</ENAMEX> worry that the same thing may
happen again--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dornan</ENAMEX> will win the nomination and lose to the incumbent
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Loretta Sanchez</ENAMEX>, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX>.

            
Is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dobson</ENAMEX> a menace to freedom? <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Liberals</ENAMEX> try to
play it both ways. They love to argue that the religious right controls the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Party</ENAMEX>. But they also maintain that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian conservatives</ENAMEX> are
extreme and marginal. In fact, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dobson</ENAMEX> does have power, but it's of a kind that
depends on subtlety and patience, qualities he tends to lack. To the extent he
can align himself with something resembling majority opinion--on an issue like
partial-birth abortion or opposition to the marriage penalty--he may get
somewhere. But to push his further agenda, he threatens to do to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> what
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> interest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> did to their party in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1970s and 1980s</TIMEX>--that is,
drag it down to principled defeat.

            Indeed, in what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dobson</ENAMEX> is
now doing there is an echo of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Jackson</ENAMEX>'s past threats to bolt the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Party</ENAMEX> if he and his views weren't accorded more "respect." Appeasing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX>--the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mondale/Dukakis</ENAMEX> strategy--was far less effective than confronting
him--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> strategy. The risk of alienating a voting <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">base</ENAMEX> is real, but
the risk of looking like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoner</ENAMEX> to the ultras is greater. Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't
want to vote for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> that constantly succumbs to extortion from an extreme
faction. You might expect <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Dobson</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child psychologist</ENAMEX>, to understand how
this works.

         
      
   
