
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betty</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff Danziger</ENAMEX>'s cartoon,
originally in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> and reprinted in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times</ENAMEX> , shows <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betty Currie</ENAMEX> sitting at a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">booth</ENAMEX> in a
fern <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>, slathered in makeup and dressed in what presumably is
intended to represent a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">designer outfit</ENAMEX>, clutches a frilly <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocktail</ENAMEX> and gabs
away in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX> speak: "So, I'm like, yuh, and he's like, duh, and I'm like
thinking about a new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>." Currie wears a raincoat and stares uncomprehendingly
at her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">companion</ENAMEX> over a cup of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX>. "That's nice," she says. The caption is:
"Now we are asked to believe that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betty Currie</ENAMEX> tried to get <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> a
job because they were actually great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>."

            Danziger
was probably borrowing his joke from a column by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maureen Dowd</ENAMEX>, who also finds
the idea of a friendship between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Currie</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> laughable. "Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>
said it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betty</ENAMEX> who became <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dowd</ENAMEX> wrote in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 8</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> . "It makes sense that the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">58-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX>, known
for her dignity and discretion, would have enjoyed the dithering visits of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shopaholic</ENAMEX> who thought she was having a high school romance with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>,
like, of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>." The general belief seems to be that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> or his
minions have essentially concocted the notion of a bond between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Currie</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> in order to explain <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s many visits to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> and the
high-level help she received in searching for a job in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>.

            We may be at the stage in the scandal where any assertion
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> or his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partisans</ENAMEX> has everyone not only doubting it but also
immediately assuming the opposite. And often for good reason. In this case,
however, it turns out that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Currie</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>. The
original link was apparently <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter Kaye</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> advertising <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mogul</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donor</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s who sponsored <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX> for an
internship at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kayes</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Curries</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> who have
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">socialized</ENAMEX> together in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>. It is not surprising or intrinsically
suspicious then, that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Currie</ENAMEX>, who has a reputation for looking out for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> interns with whom she has no personal connection, would have been helpful
and friendly to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX>.

            Because
none of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">principals</ENAMEX> is talking, it's hard to discover much about how close a
relationship <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Currie</ENAMEX> developed. But the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> do seem to have been
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>. Interesting detail: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mourners</ENAMEX> who attended the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">funeral</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betty</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Currie</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Theodore Williams Jr.</ENAMEX>, who died in a car accident last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX>--recall seeing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> there. Lest anyone assume that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX> showed
up at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metropolitan Baptist Church</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that day</TIMEX> to ogle the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, a source
who asked not to be named says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> was spotted in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen</ENAMEX> back at the
Currie <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arlington</ENAMEX>. She helped clean up and serve <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> to the
out-of-towners. In fact, she brought a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dish</ENAMEX>.

            
This background casts a rather different light
on the plausibility of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s claim in his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> deposition that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Currie</ENAMEX> helped <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> find a job in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>. Another fact that has been
largely ignored, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Currie's</ENAMEX>, is that she and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vernon</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX> have been <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30 years</TIMEX>. She also has a long-standing friendship
with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> Deputy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief of Staff</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Podesta</ENAMEX>. Like most everyone in
politics, she uses her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">connections</ENAMEX> on behalf of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>. Thus when <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jordan</ENAMEX>
says that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Currie</ENAMEX> called him to ask him for help in finding <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> a job in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, there is every reason to think he is telling the truth--and it's at
least plausible that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Currie</ENAMEX> was calling at her own behest, not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s.

            None of
this is to say that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> wasn't sexually involved with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>, or that he
wasn't also interested in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jordan</ENAMEX>'s efforts to find her a job. But the automatic
presumption that a personal relationship between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Currie</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> couldn't
have existed says less about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s lack of credibility than about the
assumptions of certain white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. An older black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> and a rich white
airhead, many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> have glibly conjectured, couldn't have
enough in common to be close. This testifies to a failure of imagination. It
also embodies a mentality that is not quite racist but smacks of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">condescension</ENAMEX>.

            The attitude is not limited to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cartoonists</ENAMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the first <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> stories about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Currie</ENAMEX> quoted an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">anonymous White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX>. "She dresses nicely and she speaks well, and
she's neat," the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> said of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Currie</ENAMEX>. "Her sweaters are probably stacked up
nicely in her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">closet</ENAMEX>." This was someone who worked with her, sounding as if
Currie was applying to be a domestic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">servant</ENAMEX>. Who would ever assume that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assistant</ENAMEX> wouldn't be neat or use proper grammar?
You can't imagine anyone describing a white presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assistant</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evelyn</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rose Mary Woods</ENAMEX>--this way.

            Another grating manifestation
of this mindset is the way <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Currie</ENAMEX> is constantly referred to as "dignified."
This compliment threatens to become for black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> what "articulate" is for
black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vernon Jordan</ENAMEX>. Though meant as praise, it is in fact highly
patronizing. A middle-age white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> would seldom be characterized as
"dignified" or "deeply religious" (unless he is some kind of religious
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fanatic</ENAMEX>). The clichés that have been employed to describe <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Currie</ENAMEX> embody an
assumption that most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> are not dignified.

            Lots of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> writing about
this sex scandal want to make <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betty Currie</ENAMEX> out to be the ultimate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX>, taken
cruel advantage of by a truth-evading <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> who happened to be her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX>.
What <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Currie</ENAMEX> has been put through is certainly unpleasant. But let's remember
that a lot of innocent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bystanders</ENAMEX> have been subjected to swarming <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> and
unexpected legal bills--and perhaps faced with hard choices between loyalty and
integrity. Currie, who has had a long career in politics, is no naif. As one
old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pal</ENAMEX> of hers told me, "There is a kind of worldly-wise <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> in there--this
has been lost in all the saintly religious stuff. She is very good to her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>. And those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> include <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>."

         
      
   
