
   
   
      
         
            Obnoxious for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Holbrooke</ENAMEX> is a
person many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> can't stand. Though he may be no more ambitious or
egotistical than a lot of career-minded <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Washingtonians</ENAMEX>, he is exceedingly
transparent about it. Physically large, he can be seen in photographs towering
over his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">rivals</ENAMEX>--and sometimes elbowing them out of the picture frame. A
courtier worthy of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holbrooke</ENAMEX> is legendary for his flattery and
back stabbing, and even for buttering someone up and sticking the knife in at
the same time.

            Those who
tend to roll their eyes at the mention of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holbrooke</ENAMEX>'s name will find much
eye-rolling material in his book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">To End a War: From Sarajevo</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dayton</ENAMEX> and
Beyond , which is about his role in negotiating a peace settlement in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX>. In places, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holbrooke</ENAMEX>'s account reads like a self-nominating speech for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary of state</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nobel Peace Prize</ENAMEX>, distinctions for which his stomach
audibly growls. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holbrooke</ENAMEX> seldom declines the chance to fluff up someone who
might be useful to him in the future, especially if that someone is a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Cohen</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> is "astute." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen</ENAMEX>
Engelberg, also of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , is "impressive." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Pfaff</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Herald Tribune</ENAMEX> is "insightful." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holbrooke</ENAMEX> suffers from a
strain of narcissism that impels him to quote himself, frequently and at
length, including from diaries, articles, TV interviews, faxes, and private
letters to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. His name-dropping is out of control. At <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point, he
offers the odd boast that it was his idea to send <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Brown</ENAMEX> on a trade mission
to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX>--the mission that led to the death of the commerce <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">34</NUMEX>
others.

            But those who fixate on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holbrooke</ENAMEX>'s insufferability do him
a serious injustice. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holbrooke</ENAMEX> lacks subtlety, modesty, and discretion. He can
be vain, pompous, and ridiculous. We know this. But he also managed to carry
off, almost by sheer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personality</ENAMEX>, an accomplishment that eluded
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX>, world <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>, and multilateral <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX>: He
ended the war in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX>. The story he tells is really about performing a kind
of jujitsu with his own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personality</ENAMEX>, channeling his dubious personal
qualities--his bullying, his egomania, and his impatient ambition--toward the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">noble</ENAMEX> (and perhaps <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nobel</ENAMEX>) end of peace in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Balkans</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the lessons his
book teaches is that in politics, self-interest isn't the opposite of public
interest. To the contrary, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ego</ENAMEX> can be the engine that makes political and
diplomatic accomplishments possible. By the end of the book, I couldn't help
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">liking</ENAMEX> and admiring <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holbrooke</ENAMEX>--not despite his evident flaws but in a curious
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> because of them.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holbrooke</ENAMEX>'s intervention in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Balkans</ENAMEX> is a rejoinder to the social
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historians</ENAMEX>' conceit that individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> don't really matter. In the summer
of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holbrooke</ENAMEX> went to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX> as a private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen</ENAMEX>, with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugee</ENAMEX> aid
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organization</ENAMEX>, and saw horrors such as <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX> being driven out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Banja Luka</ENAMEX>, where their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> had lived for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four centuries</TIMEX>. He resolved to
try to do something about it. As part of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s foreign policy
brain <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">trust</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holbrooke</ENAMEX> prodded him to take an interventionist stand, which
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> did. After the election, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holbrooke</ENAMEX> wrote a memo to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren Christopher</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony Lake</ENAMEX> advocating the strategy known as "lift and strike"--lifting
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX> embargo that prevented the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX> from defending themselves, and
bombing the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Bosnian Serbs</ENAMEX>. He also asked for the job of special <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">negotiator</ENAMEX> on
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holbrooke</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rival</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lake</ENAMEX> made sure none of this happened. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX> job
went to someone else. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holbrooke</ENAMEX> was kept away from the issue and on the
periphery of foreign policy-making in general. Eventually he was named
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ambassador</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s tough talk stopped.

            
But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holbrooke</ENAMEX> still cherished hopes of
involving the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. Offered the post of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assistant secretary</ENAMEX> of state
for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> affairs, a job he considered beneath his dignity, he took it for
the sake of directing <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> diplomatic efforts in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Balkans</ENAMEX>. As he pushed
and prodded, wheedled and connived, the crusade became more personal. Early in
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">shuttle</ENAMEX> diplomacy, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX>, including his top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">deputy</ENAMEX>, were killed
in a gruesome road accident for which the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Bosnian Serb</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">warlords</ENAMEX> were indirectly
to blame. This tragedy spurred him in his hazardous ricocheting between
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgrade</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Zagreb</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sarajevo</ENAMEX> and helped bring about better-late-than-never
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">airstrikes</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>. When he was dissatisfied with official policy,
Holbrooke undermined it. For instance, he was supposed to take advantage of the
bombing to demand a cease-fire by all sides. In fact, he encouraged the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Croatian-Muslim Federation</ENAMEX> to keep fighting, since it was making territorial
gains that he thought would make a territorial settlement easier.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Holbrooke</ENAMEX>
does not waste a lot of time on the question of whether intervening in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX>
was in our national "interest." In answer to former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary of State</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Baker</ENAMEX>'s view that we didn't have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> in that fight, he asserts the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> had a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Samaritan</ENAMEX>'s obligation to stop ethnic cleansing. The Europeans
having failed, we were the only ones who could do anything about it. Inside the
administration, he fought off objections from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX>. Spooked by anything
that smacked of "mission creep" or "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> building," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> resisted
sending <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX> and has refused to allow them to become
involved with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX>, elections, or human rights. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holbrooke</ENAMEX> continues to
argue for what he calls a "maximalist" interpretation of our military role. He
views it as a scandal that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Bosnian Serb</ENAMEX> war <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ratko Mladic</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Radovan Karadzic</ENAMEX> have yet to be captured and brought to justice.

            The narrative climaxes in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dayton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX>, where the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">combatants</ENAMEX> sat around an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">base</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three weeks</TIMEX> and reached a peace
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">accord</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holbrooke</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">proponent</ENAMEX> of the intuitive, improvisational <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> of
negotiation. He played tennis with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Franjo Tudjman</ENAMEX>, drank shots of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">plum brandy</ENAMEX>
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan Milosevic</ENAMEX> before lunch, enacted hysterical scenes of feigned and
real anger, and essentially sat on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heads</ENAMEX> of the various <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> until
they cried <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncle</ENAMEX>. Here the story becomes especially gripping and takes an
unexpected turn. It is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Bosnian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alia Izetbegovic</ENAMEX>,
who turns out to be the biggest obstacle to peace, unwilling to make even
meaningless concessions. On the other hand, the brutal but undeniably charming
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> most responsible for starting the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yugoslav</ENAMEX> civil war, saves
the accord with territorial concessions at the last moment.

            Surely <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holbrooke</ENAMEX> pursued
peace in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Balkans</ENAMEX> in part for the glory involved. And as one not afflicted
with false modesty--or any other kind--he clearly enjoys his plaudits
immensely. But by the end of the book, the issue of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holbrooke</ENAMEX>'s motivation no
longer looms very large. From an early stage, he found himself drawn into
something larger than himself, something more compelling than his own career.
As the object elevates him, his pettiness melts away.

         
      
   
