
   
   
      
         
            Insufficient Funds

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> see <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX>'s election as a replay of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1984</TIMEX>
electoral triumph. But they may be overlooking a more obvious parallel: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>'s landslide in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1972</TIMEX>.

            Until his campaign moved
into gear, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>'s popularity, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s until recently, was low--stuck at
the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nemesis figure</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">43 percent</NUMEX>," as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Theodore White</ENAMEX> recounted in The
Making of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1972</TIMEX> . But, again like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> was fortunate
in the choice of his opponent. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fall of 1972</TIMEX>, in full contest with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hapless George McGovern</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> was enjoying <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">60 percent</NUMEX>-plus popularity.

            Though
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> had no <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gennifer Flowers</ENAMEX> growing in his home garden, he had been plagued
by allegations of unethical--or at least unattractive--behavior dating back to
his earliest political days in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>. Still, while the public might think
twice about buying a used <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> from either "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tricky Dick"</ENAMEX> or "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slick Willie</ENAMEX>," most
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> seemed willing, then as now, to make an independent judgment about the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">incumbent</ENAMEX>'s ability to govern--especially when weighing it against the capacity
of his challenger.

            Both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidents</ENAMEX> came into their <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>-term election
campaigns having governed against type: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>, proposed to
establish a federally guaranteed income for all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. He
extended the food-stamp program nationwide and established a federal benefit
floor for the elderly and disabled. Urged on by a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, he
signed a pile of big-government initiatives. These included a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20 percent</NUMEX>
increase in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> benefits, plus automatic cost-of-living
adjustments; the "black lung" disability benefit program for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">miners</ENAMEX>; and
creation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Environmental Protection Agency</ENAMEX> as well as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Occupational</ENAMEX>
Safety and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health Administration</ENAMEX>.

            Grants for
low-income housing programs, needy college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>, the arts and humanities,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">urban</ENAMEX> renewal, mass transit, community health, and worker training gushed from
the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX>. When inflation jumped in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer of 1971</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> didn't
fool around with balanced budgets, tight money, or other conservative nostrums;
he slapped on wage and price controls. ("," he had remarked <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few months</TIMEX>
earlier.)

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, on the other hand, having set
off leftward at the start of his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> term, soon reversed course. Under strong
pressure from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> in his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> year in office, he submitted a plan
that purportedly would balance the budget in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven years</TIMEX>--at the price of deep
domestic spending cuts. Later, on the campaign trail, he declared his devotion
to school uniforms, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX> curfews, tough crime control, and kiddie-safe TV
programs. Where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> would have doubled family welfare rolls, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> signed a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bill</ENAMEX> that promised to deny benefits to most welfare <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. "The era of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Government</ENAMEX> is over," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> proclaimed in his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>
State of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union</ENAMEX> address.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">challengers</ENAMEX> to both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidents</ENAMEX> were undermined by the rise of noisy extremists
in their respective <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> who alarmed many mainstream <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>. For <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McGovern</ENAMEX>,
it was the hard left, abetted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hippie</ENAMEX> fringe--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bella Abzug</ENAMEX>, along with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abbie Hoffman</ENAMEX>. For <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>, it is the religious right and noisy populists--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralph</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reed</ENAMEX>, with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX> looking over his shoulder. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1972</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> platform
was a wish list compiled by every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberal</ENAMEX>--even radical--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>,
who carried their banners across the floor of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that year</TIMEX>'s party <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">convention</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX> and blue-collar <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> deserted the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>, and its
fund-raising capacity was debilitated for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> to come among big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX> and
small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">givers</ENAMEX> alike.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> had its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> convention under far better control,
but the fractures, made evident during the contentious primaries, were no less
deep. Debarred by his own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> from running on his record of fiscal and social
moderation--and with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> pre-empting much of the conservative agenda--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>
sought, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McGovern</ENAMEX> had in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1972</TIMEX>, an eye-catching proposal to set him apart from
his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitor</ENAMEX>.

            And, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McGovern</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> was
enticed into an untenable choice, not by his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>'s fringes, but by ostensibly
responsible establishmentarian elements. For <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McGovern</ENAMEX>, it was the liberal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professors</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX> who persuaded him to embrace his misbegotten
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000-</NUMEX>a-person "demogrant"--a cash-welfare plan that would have put half the
country on the take. For <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>, the damage was done by a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">coalition</ENAMEX> of pinstriped
supply-side <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enthusiasts</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nobel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">laureates</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stanford</ENAMEX>. These <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">worthies</ENAMEX> lured the red-ink-wary <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> into espousing an
across-the-board <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">15 percent</NUMEX> tax-rate cut that even the average <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voter</ENAMEX> (not to
mention most of Wall Street) could spot right off as a budget <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buster</ENAMEX>.

            With the
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">economy</ENAMEX> rebounding smartly from the brief <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1971</TIMEX> recession and inflation
temporarily in check, even the unpopularity of the raging <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Vietnam War</ENAMEX> couldn't
shake the power of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>'s incumbency. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McGovern</ENAMEX>'s big blip in the polls came
earlier than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>'s post-convention gain. His gap with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>, according to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">White</ENAMEX>, narrowed briefly to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> percentage points after a string of primary
victories. The disastrous <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Convention</ENAMEX>, however, left <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McGovern</ENAMEX> a then
record-setting <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">23</NUMEX> points in the hole. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> got a bounce out of the
well-orchestrated <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Republican Convention</ENAMEX>, but soon fell back into a double-digit
deficit. With the gap still of landslide proportions in most polls, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> has
been written off, correctly or otherwise, by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX>. (See <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>'s
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Horse</ENAMEX>
Race.")

            
Finally, lest their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX>' weakness not
suffice to produce a landslide, both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">incumbents</ENAMEX> got further help from a
third-party <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Wallace</ENAMEX>, who drained white <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southern</ENAMEX>
support from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ross Perot</ENAMEX>, who likely will drain
white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suburbanites</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>.

            Beyond the election, the
parallels may break down. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX> sins (dismissed by the public on
the eve of the election as, at most, the work of overzealous campaign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX>)
caught up with him in his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> term. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitewater</ENAMEX> and assorted other
troubles, having been more thoroughly aired in his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> term, may have run
their course. In any case, it's hard to imagine <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>, accepting bundles of cash in his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spiro Agnew</ENAMEX>
did.

            It's not so hard, however,
to imagine the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> following the pattern set by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1972</TIMEX>:
pulling themselves together momentarily to field a winning centrist candidate
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years later</TIMEX>--and then thwarting his ability to govern (as the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> did <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy Carter</ENAMEX>'s)--thereby producing an era of domination by the
opposition for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next two decades</TIMEX>.

         
      
   
