
   
   
      
         
            No Respect

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent weeks</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s stock has been trading higher. His approval-disapproval rating in the
latest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> poll is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">59-31</NUMEX>. This may account for the grudging credit the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> has begun to receive on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX> talk shows (see

                  Slate
               's "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pundit Central</ENAMEX>") and in the opinion columns. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Commentators</ENAMEX>
are commending the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s strategic acumen in proposing to expand
child-care benefits and let <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">55-year-olds</TIMEX> buy into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>. More generally,
they have lately accorded <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> a measure of respect for presiding over peace
and prosperity, and simply for staying afloat for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX>.

            Yet,
beneath these acknowledgments there runs an undercurrent of distaste, disdain,
even contempt. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last month</TIMEX>, the unapologetically <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">establishment journalist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">R.W.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Apple Jr.</ENAMEX> wrote a piece in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GQ</ENAMEX> about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s place in history. Though
he hasn't screwed up in any profound way, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple</ENAMEX> contended, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> will be
remembered as a middling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, at best. He is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> with a "compulsion to
cut ethical corners" and "total contempt for ethical niceties." Such hostility
continues to peek through at regular intervals. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">election</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agribusiness</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> and former TV <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Brinkley</ENAMEX> announced that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> was "a bore" and would always be one. Among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
establishment, especially the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> media <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">establishment</ENAMEX>, there is a scorn
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> that is not always articulated in public but never fades.

            I'm not talking here about conservative anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> animus
as represented by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Spectator</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX>
editorial page, or the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Ruddy-Ambrose Evans</ENAMEX>-Pritchard-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Mellon</ENAMEX>
Scaife-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Falwell</ENAMEX> school of conspiracy wackiness. Though this form of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">detestation</ENAMEX> does have a clinical element, it is easy to understand.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Right-wingers</ENAMEX> hate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> in much the same way that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">left-wingers</ENAMEX> hated <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>
(although <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is, of course, hardly an ideological threat as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> was,
and in fact, many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">left-wingers</ENAMEX> also hate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, precisely for being a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">centrist</ENAMEX>). The left had the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX> Surprise; the right has <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vince Foster</ENAMEX>. What
is much harder to understand is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clintonophobia</ENAMEX> exhibited by a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
elite that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">roughly</NUMEX> shares the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s center-liberal orientation. This
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX> includes the editorial page <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> , as well as leading <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnists</ENAMEX> for both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>. It is the
oft-expressed view of what remains of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgetown</ENAMEX> society. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goodness</ENAMEX> knows there
are plenty of reasons to dislike anyone, maybe more than the average number in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s case. What is mystifying is the intensity of the contempt for
him.

            
Let's begin with the conscious reasons. If you
ask <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">detractors</ENAMEX> what she objects to, she is likely to
mention that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> is duplicitous, disloyal, and unethical. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kelly</ENAMEX> has called the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> "a shocking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liar</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple</ENAMEX> has compared the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintons</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">F. Scott Fitzgerald</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daisy Buchanan</ENAMEX>, who left
a trail of broken <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> in their single-minded social ascent. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maureen Dowd</ENAMEX>
recently wrote that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arlington</ENAMEX> graves-for-cash scenario sounded like
something <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> would have done, even though he did not, in fact, do it.
Interestingly, if these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> are much bothered by conventional immoral
behavior, such as the extramarital affairs, they don't make a public point of
it.

            Each of
these criticisms contains a kernel of truth. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> almost certainly has not
told the truth about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX>, just as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">first lady</ENAMEX> did not tell the truth
about the travel-office firings. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> treated his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> Lani Guinier
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harold Ickes</ENAMEX> badly. Investing with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James McDougal</ENAMEX> does not reflect the
highest ethical standards. But those who continue to dwell on these well-aired
matters seldom exhibit much perspective. What <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> or successful
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">politician</ENAMEX> has never acted expediently by dissembling, dropping old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>,
and compromising his ethics at various points? The real question is whether the
extent of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s bad behavior is extraordinary. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JFK</ENAMEX> was a favorite of many
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgetown</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> when they were younger. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX>, of course, cut
his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">corners</ENAMEX> with a touch of class, something else <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is said to lack.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> haters hate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> for not having the dignity and sense of restraint
that should attach to his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>. Even his jogging shorts, they think, are
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">unpresidential</ENAMEX>.

            The next level is less literal, more psychological, and
involves <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">several</NUMEX> disparate strands. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> were seduced by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>, and subsequently felt personally betrayed. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Klein</ENAMEX> is the chief
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">specimen</ENAMEX> here. During <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1992</TIMEX> campaign, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Klein</ENAMEX> gushed about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>. After <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> became <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Klein</ENAMEX> tongue-lashed him in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> for not measuring up. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Klein</ENAMEX> distilled his own emotional
roller-coaster ride into an excellent novel, Primary Colors . Related to
this sense of betrayal, which is shared in varying degrees by many others who
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">covered Clinton</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>, is the feeling that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has "got away with it," in
the sense of never paying the bill for his sexual misdeeds. Related to this is
an attitude not far from envy. Disappointed in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, many of the shrewder
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s peer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> seem to think that they could do better
themselves. Since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is no smarter and certainly no better behaved than
they are, why aren't their positions reversed?

            The
generational factor is significant. Everybody distrusts the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby boomers</ENAMEX>. The
older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> sees them as spoiled and self-indulgent. Those younger see
them as greedy and narcissistic. Often, those who came of age during the 1960s
seem to resent themselves. Just as he gets it from all sides as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the
'60s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> gets it coming and going on the issue of class. To
Georgetown sophisticates, there is something hopelessly garish and cheap about
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintons</ENAMEX>. At the same time, others sneer at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> for being part
of a snooty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">meritocratic elite</ENAMEX> (viz., <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Renaissance Weekend</ENAMEX>) with no feel for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">grimy</ENAMEX> working-class <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soul</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic Party</ENAMEX>.

            
But the most important explanation of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">establishment</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> hating is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> threatens its waning
power. At the height of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgetown</ENAMEX> society was the center of the
political world. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">These days</TIMEX>, it is a vestige, whose only real wellspring of
importance is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> who elevates it with his blandishments and listens to
its advice. When a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> fails to heed the
wise <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> of the permanent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, they can dismiss him. When a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX>
like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carter</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> ignores them, they must launch their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX>. For
whatever reason, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintons</ENAMEX> have been notably uninterested in cultivating the
surviving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgetown</ENAMEX> set. During the presidential transition in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintons</ENAMEX> attended a dinner at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katharine Graham</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and drew
glowing comments from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attendees</ENAMEX>. They launched a round of intimate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> dinners. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnny Apple</ENAMEX> cooed.

            After that, however, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> more or less stiffed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Georgetowners</ENAMEX>. This outraged them--you could
tell because they all said their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> were outraged. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 1993</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sally</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quinn</ENAMEX> observed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> : "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> who have been here and
who have attained a certain social or political position do not want to be
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'dissed</ENAMEX>.' They want the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> to respect them. Because these tribal rituals
were not fulfilled, many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were virtually gleeful when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> went into
free fall in the polls. You reap what you sow, was the attitude." As he begins
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">sixth</NUMEX> year of his presidency, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is reaping it still.

         
      
   
