
   
   
      
         
            In <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Search of Cronygate</ENAMEX> 

            You probably haven't heard
about the latest scandal to rock <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> have ignored it.
And that is part of the story.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> press has named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">it Cronygate</ENAMEX>. The gist of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cronygate</ENAMEX> is this: A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>
for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Observer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX>, posing as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX>, approached <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyists</ENAMEX> with close ties to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blair</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> to
see what they were peddling. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyists</ENAMEX> was a callow and garrulous
young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Derek Draper</ENAMEX> who had been a close <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair</ENAMEX> and his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">deputies</ENAMEX>. Draper boasted that, in exchange for an extortionate fee, he could:
arrange lunches at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Downing St.</ENAMEX> and meetings with top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ministers</ENAMEX>, help the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX> get appointed to a government advisory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX>, and obtain early drafts of
parliamentary reports related to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">client</ENAMEX>'s industry.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX> was apoplectic. For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX>, the major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dailies</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bannered Cronygate</ENAMEX>: It marked the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s "fall from grace"; it
marked "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair</ENAMEX>'s worst week." <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tory</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Hague flayed Blair</ENAMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House of Commons</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blair</ENAMEX> declared that "we must be pure," and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>
floated a proposal to ban contact between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyists</ENAMEX> and top government
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>. Cronygate overshadowed not only the violence in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern Ireland</ENAMEX> but
also the long-awaited meeting between <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prince William</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Camilla Parker</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bowles</ENAMEX>.

            As a
scandal, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cronygate</ENAMEX> is inadequate in several ways. First, if you start from the
premise that there are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyists</ENAMEX>, it is unsurprising to discover that what they
do is lobby. (A famous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX> caught working as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prostitute</ENAMEX> is news. A
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prostitute</ENAMEX> caught working as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prostitute</ENAMEX> is a tautology.) <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, unless young
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Draper</ENAMEX> is unlike any other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyist</ENAMEX> in history, he was exaggerating his ability
to infiltrate the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Third</NUMEX>, what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Derek Draper</ENAMEX> promised is nothing that
former <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Haley Barbour</ENAMEX> doesn't do <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a dozen</NUMEX> times before lunch
(for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>, among other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>). And it is nothing that would tax <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pal Vernon Jordan</ENAMEX>'s youngest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">associate</ENAMEX>.

            
The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> press has ignored <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cronygate</ENAMEX>, in
other words, because to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> the behavior is not scandalous. It's not that
many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> would actually approve of what amounts to trading money for
influence (or access or whatever you call it) with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. It's that
we've decided to live with it. We don't get shocked by it, and we don't have
laws against it.

            In part,
the overwrought reaction of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> reflects their irritation with
the holier-than-thou <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair</ENAMEX> and their impatience, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than a year</TIMEX> into his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">premiership</ENAMEX>, to catch him out at something . They have longed to show
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Laborites</ENAMEX> are as scheming and money-grubbing as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Old Tories</ENAMEX>
were. But much of the fuss reflects genuine surprise and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offense</ENAMEX>. Lobbying is a
smaller and less familiar industry in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> than it is in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>.
The capacity for outrage hasn't (yet) withered.

            But wait. The lesson is not that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> are more cynical
and apathetic than the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brits</ENAMEX> about influence peddling (how marvelous it is that
they still rage at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rent-</ENAMEX>seeking and small-bore sleaziness we take for
granted ...). It's not that simple. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> reason the lobbying culture is bigger
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> than in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> separation of powers. A company
wishing to influence the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> must work the executive branch and butter
up both the majority and minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>.
In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>'s elected <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dictatorship</ENAMEX>, lobbying is limited because virtually all
power resides in a very few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> at the top of the majority <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>.

            And the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> are not so
pure. For example, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX> can manage to generate a fair amount of
resentment over <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> accepting campaign contributions from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX>--though not enough resentment, apparently, to reform the system.
But in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>, it is actually legal and accepted for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Members</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parliament</ENAMEX>
themselves to be paid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyists</ENAMEX>. There are explanations: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MPs</ENAMEX> are poorly paid,
and those without additional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> posts have almost no power anyway. But
the fact remains: The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s elected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> can be paid
specifically to influence legislation--and no one cares.

            Another
example: In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> there are no limits on the size of political contributions
and no requirements that contributions be made public. And <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX> may make political contributions directly out of their treasuries (as
opposed to raising the money from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>). In the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">post-Watergate</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX>, it is unthinkable that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would shrug off large secret
contributions by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> to the ruling party. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> probably don't
care for it either, to the extent they think about it. But they don't make a
scandal of it.

            
So which society is more cynical and decadent
and which more idealistic and pure? No, that's not the point. The point is that
what becomes a scandal--and what a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">society</ENAMEX> chooses to outlaw--is a bit random.
It may depend more on morally neutral cultural factors, or historical
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">accidents</ENAMEX>, than on any moral or practical calculus about different types of
behavior.

            This column, as my <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Strange Bed</ENAMEX>, is free of history. It is also, needless to say, free of any
taint of bias or corruption. Young and pure, it can still aspire to moral
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">clarity</ENAMEX>. Also modest, it will not attempt to solve all the problems relating to
campaign finance, lobbying, and other activities that allow money to buy
influence in politics. What it can do is suggest some general principles.

            Principle No. 1 is the
easy-to-forget point that money shouldn't be able to buy influence with
a democratic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. It's wrong. The world would be a better place if
government decisions were made without reference to who has written a check or
who has hired a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX>'s former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who profit from these
arrangements should find another way to make a living.

            But you don't outlaw every
activity of which you morally disapprove. Trying to prevent all exchanges of
money for political influence would be costly (in terms of liberty as well as
of more mundane considerations) and futile. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Half</NUMEX> measures are inevitable. You
can, though, aspire to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> measures that do <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> things. First, they should
deliver maximum moral benefit at minimum practical cost. And <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>, you want
your <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> measures to be reasonably consistent on an absolute scale of
morality. This notion of consistency is what's violated by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>'s outrage
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about</TIMEX> lobbying and indifference about campaign contributions and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s
opposite treatment of both.

         
      
   
