
   
   
      
         
            Is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Impotent</ENAMEX>?

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pragmatist</ENAMEX>'s case
against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>--as opposed to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">moralist</ENAMEX>'s--is premised on the
notion that he's powerless, so disgraced and mistrusted that his presidency is
finished politically if not chronologically. But a peculiar little side drama
on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol Hill</ENAMEX> suggests that this conclusion is not as certain as it seems. It
offers evidence that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s Flytrap weakness can be, in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> small
case, a perverse source of strength.

            The drama
concerns one of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>'s dreariest <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> rituals, the appropriations
process. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Every September</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> squabbles over the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> spending bills
needed to keep the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> operating. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Every year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> strip
funding from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">favorite</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> programs and lard the bills with anti-abortion
and anti-environmental <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">riders</ENAMEX>. As <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of each fiscal year</TIMEX> looms with no
agreement between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, conflict escalates, and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> threatens vetoes. And <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX>, a last minute continuing resolution
prevents shutdown (or not, as in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995-96</TIMEX>), both sides make cosmetic
concessions, the bills move, and everyone goes home.

            Same story <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this September</TIMEX>. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year</TIMEX> ends in two
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Only one</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX> bills has passed, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is threatening to veto
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> of the unfinished ones. He objects that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> would defund
and that they have attached unacceptable language about abortion, the census,
and the environment. Does this mean we are headed for another shutdown?

            No, and
the reasons reveal much about <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Flytrap</ENAMEX> game theory. At the mere mention of the
word "shutdown," the average <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX> curls up in a ball on the
floor and blubbers. (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> fretful <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffer</ENAMEX> I spoke to would refer only to
"the s-word.") The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995-96</TIMEX> budget showdown and shutdown were, of course, a
nightmare for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> demonized them, revived his own flagging
career, and guaranteed himself the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> presidential election. The memory still
traumatizes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>. (But <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> may laugh last about that shutdown. It
was then, after all, that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> began their affair.)

            
It is now an article of faith among
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> wants another shutdown, that he will gin up a
spending fight to provoke <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> fear that if he picks his issues
carefully--education or the environment, not the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX> (too foreign)--vetoes some
of the spending bills, and blocks a continuing resolution, he could galvanize
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">disaffected</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> and distract <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Flytrap</ENAMEX>. A
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Times</ENAMEX> op-ed piece <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> called this <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s "domestic
... <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wag the Dog</ENAMEX> strategy." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Majority Leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Lott</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Speaker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX> have repeatedly hinted that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> should not be
suckered by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>-induced shutdown.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> worries are not far-fetched. Though a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> appropriations
dismiss the idea that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> want a shutdown, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> are clearly spoiling for a good fight. "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> want to talk about
anything besides <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>. They are looking forward to talking about
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">education</ENAMEX>," says <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pollster</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Mellman</ENAMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> are urging
us to be tough," says a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffer</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>, who don't have much
else to campaign on, would welcome an appropriations riot. Tarring <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>
as <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-</ENAMEX>education, anti-abortion <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">polluters</ENAMEX> is a time-honored <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic</ENAMEX>
election strategy.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>' dilemma is that they are, as always,
fiercely divided. Red-meat <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX>, who willfully refuse to learn from
their <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> mistakes, yearn to boot <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> when he's down. They loathe him. The
weaker he gets, the less they are willing to concede in appropriations. Leading
conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David McIntosh</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ind.</ENAMEX>, told <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Roll</ENAMEX> Call <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX> that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> would "win" a shutdown if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> forced <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, because <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> would
realize he was trying to distract them from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>. (They thought they would
"win" the last shutdown, too.)

            Talk of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">challenging Clinton</ENAMEX> alarms <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">moderates</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is gushing
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> are sinking. "Congressional
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> are judged in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX>. ... They are on a roll, and they don't need
to do anything that will jeopardize that roll," says congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analyst</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norm</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ornstein</ENAMEX>. And <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX> makes other political jockeying especially foolhardy.
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> don't want to seem partisan or malicious now so they can
be partisan and malicious during the post-election <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX> hearings.

            
So the result, weirdly, is a no-lose for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. If conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> are reckless enough to provoke an
appropriations showdown, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> will probably win the public relations war,
revive <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>, and ward off <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flytrap</ENAMEX>, exactly what <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> fear most. If
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> doesn't provoke him, he'll be able to extract concessions in the
appropriations bills. The latter scenario is far more likely. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Die-hard</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> are not numerous enough or suicidal enough to force a showdown.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Moderates</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> will prevail and give <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> much of what he
wants. They will let the enfeebled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> win now, the better to kill him
later. "They don't want to give us any chance to recover and distract from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> report and unify us. So they'll cave," says a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffer</ENAMEX>. This,
I suppose, is politics: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> will happily concede the substance (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">money</NUMEX>) to
win the symbolism.

            A backdoor appropriations
victory is not exactly the strong-arming triumph a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief executive</ENAMEX> is supposed
to win over <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>. But for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrapped</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, it's better than
nothing.

         
      
   
