
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian or American</ENAMEX>?

            Asian-Americans, who so
rarely appear in print or on television, can tell you that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> are no
mirror of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s complexion. But they understand that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> do
reflect the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s psyche--and that is why the events of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent weeks</TIMEX> have
been so distressing. First, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analyst</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Kim</ENAMEX> was accused of
spying for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Korea</ENAMEX>. Then, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John Huang/Lippo</ENAMEX> scandal broke, raising
suspicions about <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> money in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> politics. Suddenly, there was no
shortage of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> names in the news. Just as suddenly, a question was in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">air</ENAMEX>: Do Asian-Americans have dual loyalties?

            No one,
to my knowledge, has framed the issue quite so explicitly. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Safire</ENAMEX>, for
instance, has hyped the so-called "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> connection" with dark mutterings about
"favor-hungry <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foreigners</ENAMEX>," "insidious networking," and "penetration by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asian</ENAMEX>
interests." The pull quote in his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 10</TIMEX> column--"Selling influence to rich
aliens"--veers into <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">The Protocols of the Elders of Zion</ENAMEX> territory. But
even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Safire</ENAMEX> felt compelled recently to throw in a "some-of-my-best-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>"
paragraph of praise for hard-working <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asian-Americans</ENAMEX>. The old <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hand</ENAMEX> knows
well that innuendo is effective only if well calibrated.

            Still, the unmistakable subtext of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Safire</ENAMEX>'s columns and the
press coverage of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lippo</ENAMEX> affair is that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asians</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> are just
that--<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asians</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, sojourners and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foreigners</ENAMEX>. Thus, when we learned that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huang</ENAMEX> had raised <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">over $5 million</NUMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>, little distinction was
made--reportorially or morally--between contributions from abroad and
contributions from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> descent. Moreover, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huang</ENAMEX>'s activities,
however unlawful, have now given rise to a presumption that "Asian-American
political participation" is merely a cover for some sinister foreign
agenda.

            Of course,
the notion that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asian-Americans</ENAMEX> are torn between an outward allegiance to this
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and a hard-wired fealty to some <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oriental</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">motherland</ENAMEX> has a long and
undistinguished pedigree. The indelible <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chineseness</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> was
the rationale for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Exclusion Act of 1882</ENAMEX>. The indelible Japaneseness
of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese-American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> justified their internment after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pearl Harbor</ENAMEX>.
Small wonder that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asian-Americans</ENAMEX> have protested the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tenor</ENAMEX> of the Lippo
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reportage</ENAMEX> and the portrayal of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asian-Americans</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with divided
loyalties.

            
But the source of these stereotypes is not
solely white racism, or even the more subtle prejudices of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Safire</ENAMEX> and his ilk.
It is also, to a lesser but still substantial degree, the racialist language of
modern-day identity politics.

            "One ever feels this
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">twoness</ENAMEX>--an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Negro</ENAMEX>; <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">souls</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> thoughts, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> unreconciled
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">strivings</ENAMEX>; <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> warring ideas in one dark <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX>, whose dogged strength alone
keeps it from being torn asunder." So wrote <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">W.E.B. Du Bois</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1903</TIMEX>, describing,
in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Souls of Black Folk</ENAMEX> , a "double consciousness" that afflicted, yet
graced, the coloreds of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">his day</TIMEX>.

            Nearly a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">century later</TIMEX>, the metaphor of dual identity endures in our racial narratives.
The notion that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minorities</ENAMEX> are instrinsically alienated from themselves--and
that the struggle is somehow ennobling--is a central <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tenet</ENAMEX> of multiculturalist
ideology. We see it in ethnic-studies <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courses</ENAMEX> and academic talk of "racial
destiny." We see it in the deconstructions of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.J. Simpson</ENAMEX>'s blackness. We see
it in the ghosts and doppelgängers who populate the melodramas of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amy Tan</ENAMEX> and
her imitators.

            This bifurcation is intuitively appealing because it makes
concrete the ambivalence of assimilation, the gnawing sense among many people
of color that membership in the mainstream comes at a high personal cost. The
symbolism of split <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personalities</ENAMEX> and divided <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">souls</ENAMEX> also has visceral power. And
there is a certain romance to the imagery, adorning the ordinary lives of
nonwhite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folk</ENAMEX> with the dignity of redemptive suffering.

            But there
is too much that is flawed about this pose. For, what do we presume when we
speak of the minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s "dual identity"? We presume that "racial
identity" is foreordained and monolithic, and ever at odds with "national
identity." We presume also, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanley Crouch</ENAMEX> has dryly observed, that identity
is never more complex than double.

            
Black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nationalists</ENAMEX>, like their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counterparts</ENAMEX> in
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asian America</ENAMEX>" or "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Latino Nation</ENAMEX>," believe that race is primordial, as organic
as gender. But consider the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asian-American</ENAMEX>: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thirty years ago</TIMEX>, there was no such
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">creature</ENAMEX>. There were only <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> descent, or <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX>.
But over the course of a generation, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bureaucrats</ENAMEX> have
manufactured a single race out of a diverse mass of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">several million</NUMEX> people
whose origins can be traced to dozens of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>.

            What has
bound this Asian-American "race" together is not its biological badge--eyelid
folds, hair color, pigmentation--but its cultural content. Through magazines
and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campus clubs</ENAMEX> and advocacy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>, self-appointed race <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> have
sought to create an "authentic" Asian-American consciousness by inventing
something called "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian-American</ENAMEX> culture." The fact that they are succeeding
tells us something about the magnetic appeal of racial fundamentalism. More
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">importantly</ENAMEX>, it reminds us that "racial identity" is utterly malleable--and
that "racial essence" is utterly artificial.

            Yet, even if we did believe in the fixity of races, "double
identity" is meaningless unless we also presume that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> identity is
immutably white. As the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albert Murray</ENAMEX> has long argued, that wasn't even
true in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Du Bois</ENAMEX>' time. It is even less true now--and not because <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, in
the classic pluralist formulation, is a "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX>," a neutral holding
pen for various diasporas; nor because <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> is some dehumanizing,
single-mold "melting pot."

            What gives
lie to anyone's whitewashed vision of national identity--and what makes <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>
exceptional--is the fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> culture is more hybridized and
mongrelized than anything humanity has ever before seen. When <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>
Caucasians are practicing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Feng Shui</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zen</ENAMEX> meditation, when suburban <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teens</ENAMEX> are reciting gangsta rap lyrics, when salsa sales are surging past
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ketchup</ENAMEX> sales, how can we speak with a straight face about the ineffaceable
whiteness of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> life? And how then can we sustain the race-nation
opposition central to "double consciousness"?

            
Ultimately, the weakness of the dual-identity
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">myth</ENAMEX> is that it reduces <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX> into bits of binary code. It treats the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
experience as a simple equation plotted along <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> axes, as if class or gender
or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">birthplace</ENAMEX> or birth order or family <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX> mattered not--as if
contingency never sculpted one's sense of self. And, in the name of
anti-racialism, it recommits the worst errors of racialism: Denying the
minority individual his full, complex humanity; interpreting his voice as the
mere expression of a greater <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Volksgeist</ENAMEX> .

            In the milieu of
contemporary multiculturalism, that sort of illogic can be affirming. So long
as color is a proxy for entitlement, there will be many who find it useful to
ostentatiously posit a conflict between their racial core and their assimilated
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">shell</ENAMEX>. But the fallout from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Huang</ENAMEX> debacle should remind
Asian-Americans that claims of racial loyalty can cut both ways. And it should
remind us all that flimsy notions of the minority's eternally dual identity,
whether tinged with xenophobia or candied with race pride, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX> amount to
just so much double talk.

         
      
   
