
   
   
      
         
            Waiting for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 5</TIMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L></ENAMEX>ast week in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate , Jodie T. Allen</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barnes</ENAMEX> proposed using advanced <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> software to condense the
transcripts of the presidential debates. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Compression</ENAMEX> is the right approach, but
more of a human touch is needed. Rather than reduce political dialogue to
straightforward facts and proposals, perhaps we should try to bring out the
singular aesthetic vision that <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wells</ENAMEX> up in even our most robotically
pre-programmed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>. Too many facts, too much information: We need to
make politics more beautiful, melancholy, strange. The vast <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> that
attends the plays of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Samuel Beckett</ENAMEX> or reads the poetry of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Ashbery</ENAMEX> is
sadly neglected in our political process. Here is a compressed transcript of
the debates. All the words were actually spoken. They are presented completely
out of context, but in perfect accord with what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">transcriber</ENAMEX> believes to be
the inward poetic essence of each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>.
            

            [Note:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX>'s remarks required less editing than the others'.]

            

               Act I
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hartford</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Conn.</ENAMEX>
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> ( from a high rocky outcrop ): I want. I will try. I ran. I
wanted, you took me. Let's keep it going. We cut, let's balance. We cut, let's
pass. We passed, let's expand. We passed, let's keep going. We passed, let's
make. We can build. I look forward. We're going. I believe, I have worked. I
supported, I felt. I've worked, I supported. I supported, I differed, I
believe.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> ( standing in a
trash can ): <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thirty-five</ENAMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bureaucracies</ENAMEX>. I carry a little card
around in my pocket. He noted a few, but there are others.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
( descending ): I do think. I do believe.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> : That's not true
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Connecticut</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> : Best shape,
biggest drop, all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> ( gesturing
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">darkly</ENAMEX> ): <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Scaring</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">seniors</ENAMEX> and tearing me apart. He twisted <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX>. I
don't--you know.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
( <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">sorrowfully</NUMEX> ): It wasn't me.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> : We ought to
agree that somebody else should do it.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> : I will
continue. Because we need it badly.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> : If they started
they ought to stop.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> : We need to do
this together and we can.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> : Look at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Haiti</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bosnia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern Ireland</ENAMEX>. I failed to mention <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Korea</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> : Every single
country but <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> : <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Food</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moderator</ENAMEX> : <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Food</ENAMEX>.

            ( A long silence. )

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> : And so it seems
that we can talk about what we call <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenny</ENAMEX> the great exaggerator because he just
liked to exag--

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> : I think my
ideas are better.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> : I have my own
little <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundation</ENAMEX>. Just did. I haven't before.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> : I support
school choice. I support school choice.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> : I like young
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. I like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> : The results
are highly ambiguous.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> : <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George McGovern</ENAMEX>
is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of mine.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> : Our plan is
better.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> : I've never
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">discussed Whitewater</ENAMEX>. I'm discussing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Whitewater</ENAMEX> now. We've had that discussion.
I know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D'Amato</ENAMEX>, I think. He's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of mine. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> is a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of yours.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> : No
comment.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> : What's the
subject matter?

            ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Music</ENAMEX> and
dancing. )

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act II</ENAMEX>
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Petersburg</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fla.</ENAMEX>
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Kemp</ENAMEX>
( on an enormous bicycle ): This is the greatest democracy in the world.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX> is one of those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> who's served in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States Senate</ENAMEX>. Clearly,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abraham Lincoln</ENAMEX> put it best.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> ( on a
hovering <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">cube</NUMEX> ): We have a plan. I'm excited.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kemp : Ambivalent</ENAMEX>,
confusing.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> : We have a
positive plan. Here's how we plan. We have a balanced-budget plan. Our
plan.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kemp</ENAMEX> : Clearly.
Frankly. Ask <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Van Woods</ENAMEX>, a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entrepreneur</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> : <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Risky $550</ENAMEX>
billion tax scheme.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kemp</ENAMEX> : All wealth is
created. <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">25 to 26 percent</NUMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.5 million</NUMEX> words.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> : Risky tax
scheme. We have a plan.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kemp</ENAMEX> : And clearly.
And frankly. And that's what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abraham Lincoln</ENAMEX> believed.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> : Let me tell you
a story about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joann Crowder</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Detroit</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kemp</ENAMEX> : We will
greenline every <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dana Crist</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lancaster</ENAMEX>.

            ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Van Woods</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joann</ENAMEX>
Crowder, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dana Crist</ENAMEX> slowly and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">silently</ENAMEX> walk across the stage, accompanied
by amplified radiator noises. )

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> : It is a risky
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$550 billion</NUMEX> tax scheme.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kemp</ENAMEX> : <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50 trillion</NUMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$550 billion</NUMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50 trillion</NUMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> : <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Risky $550</ENAMEX>
billion tax scheme.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kemp</ENAMEX> : <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$8 billion</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">$23</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">billion</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX> suggested a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">commission</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> : Our plan.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kemp</ENAMEX> : <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6-</NUMEX> or
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$7-trillion</NUMEX> economy. <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6 trillion</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15 years</TIMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> : A
balanced-budget plan.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kemp</ENAMEX> : I will answer
the question. There is no consensus. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Haiti</ENAMEX> is very ambiguous at best.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> : It was a tense
moment. And this is helping.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kemp</ENAMEX> : We need more
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">chairs</ENAMEX>. We need a bigger table.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> : These are parts
of the plan. Our plan.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kemp</ENAMEX> : Strong
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">community</ENAMEX>, strong <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>. Strong economy, strong <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX>, strong <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>.
The word "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>." As strong as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, a strong job. Strong <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX>,
strong <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> : I don't agree
with their plan. We have a plan. We also have a plan. We also have a plan. Our
plan. This plan. Risky scheme. Our plan.

            ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dance</ENAMEX> impressions of
the Plan and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Scheme</ENAMEX> in terrible combat. )

            

               Act III
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">San</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diego</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX>
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> ( as
before ): I got lots of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> ( as
before ): What really matters is what happens. We stand on the brink. What
really matters is what we can do. We have to go on. If we can do those things,
we can build that <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridge</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> : I have a little
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">foundation</ENAMEX>. We don't talk about it.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Voter</ENAMEX> : I have an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amway</ENAMEX>
business.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> : Good for
you.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Voter</ENAMEX> : My name's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jack</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flack</ENAMEX>. I'm a retired <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilot</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> : <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> different
things. Let's talk about them separately.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> : This is
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> : I still
remember a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> I met <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 years ago</TIMEX>. I met that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> again. I want to make
more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> : This is about
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> : My whole
administration is about your future.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Voter</ENAMEX> : I'm a martial
arts <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">instructor</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> : I never go
anywhere, it seems like, where I don't meet somebody. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Longview</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>, the
other day, I met a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who was almost in tears.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> : I see my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mitchell</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> : I met a lady
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado Springs</ENAMEX> about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven weeks ago</TIMEX> now. I visited a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dealership</ENAMEX>
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> : I don't think
so.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Voter</ENAMEX> : I'm a travel
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> : I'm for
it.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> : After <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">midnight</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one morning</TIMEX>, in the dark of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>--he proposed it.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Voter</ENAMEX> : I am Verda
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Strategus</ENAMEX>. I think it's a real problem.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> : How many of
you like it?

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> : The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">L.A.</ENAMEX>
Times discovers it.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> : It's going to
help everybody.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> : I'm not
suggesting it be done, but at least we ought to look at it.

            ( It does not
appear. )

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
( <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">wearily</NUMEX> ): I visited a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dealership</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tokyo</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> ( darkly ):
No doubt about it.

            ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> turn
together and look ahead. Suddenly--it appears. )

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> : That's the
kind of thing we need to do!

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> : That's the way
it's always been! And that's the way it will always be!

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> : That's the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> the system works!

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> : This is
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>!

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> : That's all we
need to know!

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> : This is what
it's all about!

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> : If you don't
leave this <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> with anything else--

            ( Curtain. )

         
      
   
