
   
   
      
         
            Unplug the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOE</ENAMEX>!

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Washington</ENAMEX> had only
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">departments</ENAMEX>. Since his time, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX> new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">departments</ENAMEX> have been created
and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only two</NUMEX> eliminated (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy Department</ENAMEX> was absorbed into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1949</TIMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post Office</ENAMEX> was spun off as a federal corporation
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1971</TIMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX> promised to close down <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Energy and Education</ENAMEX>).
Instead, he added <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Veterans Affairs</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX> proposed adding another
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Environment</ENAMEX>), but didn't get to do so. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">revolutionaries</ENAMEX>" who
took over <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> pledged to abolish <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">departments</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Energy</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Education</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commerce</ENAMEX>), but quickly retreated.

            If
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is looking for an easy symbolic way to cement his reputation
as a "small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX>--and, if we know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, he surely is--the
answer is clear: Be <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-up on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>, and actually abolish a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>.

            But which one? The corporate-welfare-dispensing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commerce</ENAMEX> is an obvious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>, since it mostly serves a big-business
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">constituency</ENAMEX> with an array of subsidies and favors. By punting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commerce</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> could portray himself as a more principled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defender</ENAMEX> of the free market
than <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>, who tolerate the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> that are chronically dependent
on the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>.

            What's the
downside? Taking on corporate welfare might backfire, casting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> in the
discredited role of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scourge</ENAMEX> of business. Also, using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commerce</ENAMEX> to
promote <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> business abroad has shielded <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> on the left
who say he's helplessly infatuated with free trade.

            
Another option is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Education</ENAMEX>, created by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carter</ENAMEX>--mostly as a favor to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Education Association</ENAMEX>, which gave him
its <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> presidential endorsement. Federal spending on elementary and
secondary education remains small in aggregate, amounting to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">just 7 percent</NUMEX> of
total public spending on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>. Most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>'s popular programs,
like college student aid and <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Title I</ENAMEX>, which provides money for educating poor
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, existed before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> was born. Another sacrosanct federal
education effort, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Head</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Start</ENAMEX>, is not even under the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ed Department</ENAMEX>'s
jurisdiction. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Education</ENAMEX> does finance science and math instruction, but so do
other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>.

            Junking
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Education</ENAMEX> probably isn't politically feasible, though. For <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> thing, it would
anger the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX>, a powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">constituency</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic Party</ENAMEX>: A
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">full 525</TIMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4,293</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">delegates</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> convention belonged to
vilified the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX> of learning for their proposed cuts in
federal education outlays, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> would appear hypocritical
if they abolished the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Education</ENAMEX>. Can't have that.

            That leaves <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Energy</ENAMEX>, which is perfectly suited to abolition
on practical as well as political grounds. Aside from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">environmentalists</ENAMEX>,
who are fixated on renewable <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fuels</ENAMEX>, few <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> care much about the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Department</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Energy</ENAMEX> anymore. The chief motive for creating the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1977</TIMEX> was to regulate oil prices, which only exacerbated the "energy crisis."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>'s decontrol of energy has resulted in the steady decline of gasoline
prices (in absolute terms), and has removed the issue from the table. Even
during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last spring</TIMEX>'s spike in prices, no <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> advocated price controls or
punitive taxes on Big Oil.

            For the
most part, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOE</ENAMEX> is an anachronism whose main function under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has been
to generate embarrassing news stories about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hazel O'Leary</ENAMEX>'s expensive
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">globe</ENAMEX>-trotting. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two-thirds</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOE</ENAMEX>'s budget pays for programs unrelated to
energy: nuclear-weapons production, maintenance, and cleanup. Those tasks can't
be eliminated; but they can, logically, be transferred to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX>. Many of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOE</ENAMEX>'s functions, like owning <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Strategic Petroleum Reserve</ENAMEX>) and oil
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fields</ENAMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Naval Petroleum Reserve</ENAMEX>), can be privatized. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has already
proposed selling off the petroleum reserve.) Subsidies for solar power and
energy conservation likewise deserve the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ax</ENAMEX> (energy taxes would do the job far
more efficiently, if the job needs doing); or, they could migrate to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Interior</ENAMEX>.
Funding for science research at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">28</NUMEX> national <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">laboratories</ENAMEX> may be more
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">defensible</ENAMEX>, but even a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOE</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">task force</ENAMEX> recommended an end to government
ownership of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">labs</ENAMEX>. Much of their research is in commercial applications,
which belongs in the private sector.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Skeptics</ENAMEX> will carp that it is not critical
whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> survives, but whether its programs do. It's true that if
the programs aren't winnowed down, not much changes apart from the stationery.
But, even if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> were to parcel the existing programs out to other
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">departments</ENAMEX> without appreciably reducing their cost, it would still make
political sense to dump <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOE</ENAMEX>. Nobody will bother to compare the before-and-after
budgetary authority, but few will fail to notice that a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> has
vanished.

            After shuttering the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOE</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> could depict himself as a crusader against waste and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bureaucracy</ENAMEX> who
succeeded where even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> failed. Like his agreement <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> to a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven-year</TIMEX> plan to balance the budget, this step would change the terms of the
debate with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>. Before the balanced-budget accord, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> framed all
opposition to its budget cuts as fiscally irresponsible conduct by people
committed to everlasting deficits. Afterward, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> were obliged to
defend the proposed cuts on their individual merits, an argument which the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> generally carried.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> have done
themselves a lot of harm by refusing to discriminate between those programs
that are vital and those that are not. For <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to abolish the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOE</ENAMEX> would be
a bracing lesson in how to do just that. The question is whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has
the nerve. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> have long demanded smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. They should pray
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> doesn't give it to them.

         
      
   
