
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Paxon</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mysterious Epiphany</ENAMEX>

            Briefly displacing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> as Topic A <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> was a news flash from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol Hill</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Paxon</ENAMEX>, a
well-scrubbed, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">43-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Buffalo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.Y.</ENAMEX>, was
retiring. This came as a shock, because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paxon</ENAMEX> was viewed as an ambitious fellow
with a long career ahead of him. Though he had been displaced from his position
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> as punishment for his role in the failed
coup against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Speaker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last July</TIMEX>, he remained popular with his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">As recently as a few days</TIMEX> before his withdrawal, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paxon</ENAMEX> had been
busy canvassing support for a challenge to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Armey</ENAMEX> for the post of majority
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>. But instead of announcing his candidacy for a job that would put him in
line to become <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paxon</ENAMEX> pledged never to run for
anything--not even dogcatcher--again. Like his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Molinari</ENAMEX>, who quit
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> to become a news anchor on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX>, he said his move was prompted by a
desire to spend more time with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>.

            Despite
the eagerness of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX><TIMEX TYPE="TIME">-morning</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> to embrace it, the official story
does not begin to add up. A purely political creature, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paxon</ENAMEX> has spent his
entire adult life in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> jobs: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assemblyman</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>. Here he was giving up his life's work, with no idea of what he would
do instead, because of an epiphany that seemed totally out of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>. His
transformation from someone desperate to spend more time with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX>
and less with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> to someone desperate to spend none with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX>
and all with his family happened <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">within days</TIMEX>. And even if you take his
explanation at face value, why would Paxon rule out seeking elective office
ever again, even after his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> was in college?

            The predictable result has been a plague of rumors, all
nasty and none very plausible. The only remotely convincing interpretation is
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paxon</ENAMEX> knew but was not willing to admit publicly that he could not defeat
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Armey</ENAMEX> and that, without a path forward, he lost heart. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Beltway outsiders</ENAMEX> might
wonder why any of this even matters. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paxon</ENAMEX> is the world's most replaceable
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>--a lightweight <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operator</ENAMEX> of fungible principles, not especially
conservative, not especially moderate, and with no great or special political
talent. He will be forgotten in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX>, if not <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX>. What is significant
about the episode, and about the haze of innuendo surrounding it, is the way it
epitomizes what the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> has become. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past year</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>
side of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol</ENAMEX> has become not only an extraordinarily vicious environment
but also an entirely unproductive and unsatisfying one. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paxon</ENAMEX>'s hasty departure
and whatever invisible machinations lie behind it show that the devil makes
work for idle hands. They also show the total intellectual and political
exhaustion of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Republican revolution of 1994</ENAMEX>.

            For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">over a year</TIMEX>, the only
real news coming out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">caucus</ENAMEX> has been gossip about internecine
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">warfare</ENAMEX>, tales about coups and countercoups, ambition, rebellion, and
retribution. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX> has been consumed with especially intense jockeying
and speculation about the leadership hierarchy. Would <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Paxon</ENAMEX> challenge <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Armey</ENAMEX> for
the majority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>'s job (in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">an election</TIMEX> that is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nearly a year</TIMEX> off)? What
would that mean for the eventual succession to the speakership should <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX>
quit to run for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>? Shortly before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paxon</ENAMEX> announced his retirement, Rep.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Livingston</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">R-La.</ENAMEX>, decided that instead of stepping down to become a
fat-<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyist</ENAMEX>, he would hang around in the hope of winning the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX>'s job
after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> leaves. That fueled more kibitzing. Could <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Armey</ENAMEX> conciliate the
angry and disappointed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">'94</NUMEX>? What would <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom DeLay</ENAMEX> do? Would there be
another attempt to overthrow <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX>?

            In short,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> has deteriorated into a sub-Shakespearean Elizabethan
revenge drama. This is hardly surprising. Where there is no strong <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>, no
unifying sense of purpose, and no rule of law, political chaos tends to ensue,
as surely in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Longworth Building</ENAMEX> as in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rwanda</ENAMEX> or the former <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX>. But
the fratricidal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> is an amazing change from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the heady days of early 1995</TIMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s policy vacuum makes the gimmicky Contract With <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> look like
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lenin</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">What Is to Be Done</ENAMEX>? Where there was unity and esprit de corps,
there is now factionalism and demoralization. How did the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> revolution
turn so quickly into a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brooks Bros.</ENAMEX> version of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lord</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Flies</ENAMEX> ?

            
I think there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> important causes. The
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> is structural. When he became <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> tossed out the age-old
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> rules. He placed a term limit of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight years</TIMEX> on himself as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX> and a
limit of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six years</TIMEX> on committee chairs. In choosing chairs, he suspended
seniority. For example, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> bypassed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> more senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> to make
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Livingston</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Appropriations</ENAMEX>. This transformed the political
culture of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>. Advancement no longer had to be slow and steady.
Shake-ups were to be expected. Careers could take off and fizzle suddenly. The
result was a lot of scheming by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paxon</ENAMEX> who suddenly had an
opportunity to get ahead quickly.

            The
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> explanation has to do with the political trajectory of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the last few</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gingrich Congress</ENAMEX> has paid a high price for overinterpreting its
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> mandate. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> almost lost his job, and though the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> kept control of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> have abandoned both the rhetoric and substance of
anti-government radicalism. Lately, they've been hanging back and venturing
little. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 89</NUMEX> scheduled workdays; the annual average
since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">140</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> now fears controversy the way a convalescent fears
a draft. This means that all the issues that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> care most
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about</TIMEX>--banning affirmative action, cutting taxes, pushing school choice--remain
on indefinite hold. The demagogic gimmicks get ever more desperate and empty.
Their latest is to fix a date for abolition of the tax code--the idea being
that it would force sweeping reform (details to follow).

            Gone, perhaps for good, is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX>'s "visionary" rhetoric.
Replacing it is a litany of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boy Scout</ENAMEX>-scale good deeds reminiscent of nothing
so much as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pointillist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> agenda <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> mocked so sneeringly
around <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>. In his most recent speech, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> boasted about building <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F-</ENAMEX>22s
in his district and improving the water quality of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Chattahoochee River</ENAMEX>. He
also proposed new ideas: giving cell phones to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> and--I <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> you
not--screening <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Native Americans</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diabetes</ENAMEX>. The main business in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> was dividing up <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$173 billion</NUMEX> in transportation goodies.

            In a way, the collapse of
conservative principles in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> only heightens the mystery of why <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paxon</ENAMEX> quit. The post-revolutionary <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> is an environment in
which he might well have flourished, and where he ought to have felt very much
at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
