
   
   
      
         
            The Case for Community Service

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has spent
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last six years</TIMEX> lecturing <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> about the glories of community service.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AmeriCorps</ENAMEX> is his pet project, and his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> has encouraged service as
an alternative to jail time. Well, now is the chance for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> to put
his ideas to work for himself. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">allies</ENAMEX> are desperately seeking a
dignified way out of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX>: How about community service? We should let the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> serve out his term, but let's make him really serve.

            The basic
conundrum for those who want <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flytrap</ENAMEX> to end is this: Any remedy lenient enough
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> diehards will enrage the right <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, and any remedy
punitive enough for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> will enrage the left <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">solution</ENAMEX> must
simultaneously <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) minimize carnage to the presidency and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) be
vindictive enough to sate the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) be soft enough to pass the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>; and
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) allow us to put the scandal aside (or mostly aside) for the remainder of his
term.

            None of the proposed remedies suffices. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>,
especially those on the judiciary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX>, are set on eviscerating <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
and won't settle for anything as gentle as censure (even if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> does agree
to take his licks standing in the well of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>). A censure plus a fine
also dissatisfies <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX>, because it suggests <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> can buy pardon. On
the other hand, impeachment would be bloody, endless, and intolerable to most
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>. And resignation would set the horrific precedent that the media and the
opposition can drum a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> out of office if they shout enough.

            But
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">community</ENAMEX> service, plus censure, might succeed. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Every week</TIMEX> until the end of his
term, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> would spend <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a few hours</TIMEX> on some direct, necessary community
service. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> would decide--after negotiation with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>--the total
number of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> and the kind of work (more on the specifics of this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later</TIMEX>). The
service would be an everyday obligation for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, with no presidential photo
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ops</ENAMEX> and no special treatment.

            
What would be the benefits of this regimen? For
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">starters</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> would make tangible reparations for the damage he has
inflicted to society. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> are infuriated by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s notion that
apology is action. His prolific, ever savvier apologies are selfish: They are
designed to make him look better. He has announced that he has accepted
responsibility, but what exactly has he done about it? Redemption, in most
religious and ethical traditions, requires deeds. In service, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> could not
allow words to substitute for actions. He would have to act.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Service</ENAMEX>
would meet another requirement of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX> punishment: It would humble him.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has suggested that he can best make amends by being an excellent
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. But we require more visible evidence of his regret. Being president
is no suffering for him. In fact, being <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> reinforces his worst
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">instincts</ENAMEX>. His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flytrap</ENAMEX> sin is believing that normal rules and moral codes
don't apply to him, that everyone else exists to do his bidding. His punishment
must remind him that he is merely a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, and so he must be chopped down to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">man</ENAMEX>-size. In service, he could not use his power to bully others. In service,
he would, for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 years</TIMEX>, take orders instead of give them,
cater to others instead of being catered to. That might begin to cure, or at
least temper, his wicked and dangerous sense of entitlement.

            The humbling of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> would also serve a political
function: It would placate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX>, especially if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> were combined
with a haymaker congressional censure. The image of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> scraping graffiti
off some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">high school</ENAMEX> might persuade enough <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> to sign on.

            Service, too, might be
cathartic enough to liberate us from our Flytrap obsession. We would no longer
need to debate dada legal technicalities and gasp over sordid details.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> won't be able to gripe that he escaped scot-free: He will be
paying the price, quietly, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every week</TIMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Service</ENAMEX>
might even benefit the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> in the way he cares most about. It must
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">devastate Clinton</ENAMEX>--a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> obsessed with his legacy--that his place in
history is now secure: He's the reckless lech who ruined his presidency for a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intern</ENAMEX>. Whether he resigns, is impeached, or is censured, that will
be his epitaph. If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> does community service, he will still be remembered
as the reckless lech, but he may also be remembered as the reckless lech who
had the grace to make amends for his sins.

            
There are obstacles to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s community
service, but they are surmountable. Would he have time? We can't expect him to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">skip G-7</ENAMEX> summits so that he can collect roadside trash. But he managed to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">squeeze Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> (or rather, she squeezed him) into his schedule--not to
mention <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">dawn-to-dusk</TIMEX> fund raising--so surely he can squeeze in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a few hours</TIMEX> of
good works on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturdays</TIMEX>.

            Some will
object that service, like censure, is not in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> cannot
impose community service on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> without his permission--that would be
an unconstitutional "bill of attainder." (
                  Slate
               's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Explainer</ENAMEX>"
examines the "bill of attainder" at greater length here.) But if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> consents, censure and community service can
proceed. And he would certainly consent if the alternative was impeachment.

            The thorniest question, of course, is: What kind of
service? It must be dignified: It cannot tarnish the presidency, and it must be
acceptable to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. (So bedpans and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain gangs</ENAMEX> are out. Sorry, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barr</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-Ga.) Yet it must be punitive enough that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> will be satisfied.
(It can't be, for example, any activity that lets <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> talk, even though
that's what he does best. Just as <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">drunken</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX> convicted of manslaughter are
forced to recount their sins to high schoolers, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> could probably give a
superb heart-to-heart speech on the perils of infidelity. But he would enjoy it
too much for it to be a suitable punishment.)

            Fortunately, a perfect model
for such honorable yet humble service already exists, and it even has a
presidential imprimatur: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Habitat for Humanity</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> should build <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poor</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy Carter</ENAMEX>. Or, better yet, he should build <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> for the poor
under the supervision of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy Carter</ENAMEX>. Now that's a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX> remedy even
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s worst <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX> can love.

         
      
   
