
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Diamonds</ENAMEX> in the Rough

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Fourscore and seven years</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ago</TIMEX>, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">steel</ENAMEX> and concrete baseball <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palace</ENAMEX> opened for business.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Shibe Park</ENAMEX>, home to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Athletics</ENAMEX> and later the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Phillies</ENAMEX>, was
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX> urban <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ballparks</ENAMEX> built in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven-year period</TIMEX> now regarded as the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">golden</ENAMEX> age of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ballpark</ENAMEX> architecture. All but <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Wrigley Field</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fenway Park</ENAMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tiger Stadium</ENAMEX>) have since been razed.

            
Replacing parks built of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wood</ENAMEX>, these ballyards set new standards for size, fire
safety, intimacy, and convenience. As places to watch ballgames, they were
vastly superior to the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">post-World War II</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX>, especially the facilities
designed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late '60s and '70s</TIMEX> that doubled as football <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stadiums</ENAMEX>. But these
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">concrete monsters</ENAMEX>, plopped into vast parking <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lots</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cincinnati</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX>, and elsewhere, lack the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> of the classic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">parks</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">New Comiskey Park</ENAMEX>, which opened in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>,
attempted to address the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> question with a superficial postmodern
facade that in some ways resembled the exterior of the golden-era <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> it
replaced. New <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Comiskey</ENAMEX> was marketed as an old-fashioned <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> with all the
modern conveniences. But inside, it was still a symmetrical concrete monster,
and it sat in the middle of a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7,000</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> parking lot rather than in an urban
neighborhood.

            A year
later, a new--yet more genuinely old--ballpark arrived to dispel the gloom.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Oriole Park</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Camden Yards</ENAMEX> revived the idea of a quirkily
asymmetrical, relatively intimate, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">steel</ENAMEX>-structured, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">city</ENAMEX>-friendly <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ballpark</ENAMEX>.
"Once this opens," predicted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Commissioner</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Baseball Bart Giamatti</ENAMEX>, "everyone
will want <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> like it." And so it came to be: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Camden Yards</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">successors</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cleveland</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arlington</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>), and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Denver</ENAMEX>, and those designed for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milwaukee</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seattle</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX>, take their cues from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore</ENAMEX>'s conceptual
breakthrough. Even totally nontraditional <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX>, like those in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Phoenix</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miami</ENAMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tampa Bay</ENAMEX>, emulate the asymmetry of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Camden Yards</ENAMEX> outfield. It's almost
as though a disembodied voice intoned, "If you build it, they will copy."

            While <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Camden Yards</ENAMEX> and its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offspring</ENAMEX> are almost universally
praised, some of them don't deserve the hype. The most annoying hype is that
all the new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX> are intimate, and that every seat is better at the new place
than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the old</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Intimacy</ENAMEX> has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> aspects--actual size and the subjective
perception of size and scale. A good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX> can ace the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> part of the
test through convincing forms, good proportions, and attractive materials. The
exposed steelwork, brick, stone, tile, and well-placed wall openings of the new
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">parks</ENAMEX> beat the cold and sterile <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stadiums</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a generation ago</TIMEX>.

            For the new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX>' charms,
we should be thankful. But in actual size, the new ballyards are not intimate.
All their amenities--<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">elevators</ENAMEX>, wider concourses, abundant <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">toilets</ENAMEX> (especially
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bathrooms</ENAMEX>, escalators, plentiful food <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stands</ENAMEX>, and luxury
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">suites</ENAMEX>--make them far larger than the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX> they claim to emulate. These parks
are larger than even the multipurpose hulks we all love to hate. Compare, for
instance, the spanking new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Ballpark</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arlington</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">49,100</NUMEX> seats), which rests on
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">13.6 acres</NUMEX>, to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kingdome</ENAMEX>, a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">58,000</NUMEX>-seat <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">multipurpose stadium</ENAMEX> that
opened in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1976</TIMEX> and covers <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">9.3 acres</NUMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ebbets Field</ENAMEX>, home to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brooklyn</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dodgers</ENAMEX>, occupied <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a mere 5.7 acres</NUMEX> and seated <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">32,000</NUMEX>.)

            Or
compare heights: <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">New Comiskey Park</ENAMEX>'s roof is <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">146 feet</NUMEX> above field level; old
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Comiskey Park</ENAMEX> was <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about 75 feet</NUMEX> high. This is not ballpark trivia, but an
indicator of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> experience: <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Upper-deck</ENAMEX> seats in the new, taller <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stadiums</ENAMEX> are
farther away from the action. At <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arlington</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> sitting in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the middle-row</TIMEX>,
upper-deck seat closest to home plate is <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">224 feet</NUMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">batter</ENAMEX>, compared to
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">125 feet</NUMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tiger Stadium</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4,300</NUMEX> more seats.

            Why are upper-deck seats in the new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX> so far from the
game? <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> reasons: column placement and luxury seating.

            In the old <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX>, the
structural columns stood within the seating areas, placing the upper-deck seats
closer to the game. The trade-off was that these columns obstructed the view of
some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architects</ENAMEX> "remedy" the problem by placing the columns
behind the seating areas, thus moving the upper decks back from the field. (It
should be noted that the new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX>' claim that they have no
impaired-view seats is an overstatement.)

            Added
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tiers</ENAMEX> devoted to luxury seating at the new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX> also push the upper deck away
from the field. The retreat of that deck is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a century</TIMEX>-long process, but it can
be stemmed. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Orioles</ENAMEX> pressed for several design changes that lowered <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Camden</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yards</ENAMEX>' top deck and produced a middle-row viewing distance of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">199 feet</NUMEX>, about
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> rows closer than <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arlington</ENAMEX>'s.

            Design references to golden-age <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ballparks</ENAMEX> are only one
parallel between <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that period</TIMEX> and ours. We are also matching that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">era</TIMEX>'s frenzied
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pace</ENAMEX> of construction: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Twenty-six</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Major League Baseball</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">32</NUMEX> franchises
occupy a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> that is less than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 years old</TIMEX>; has been, or will be, extensively
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">remodeled</ENAMEX>; or hope to move into a new one soon.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the classic <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX>'
merits was that they were unsubsidized. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Team</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> bought land and paid for
stadium construction--some even built trolley <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">lines</ENAMEX> to transport <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> to the
games. In all but <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> cases during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last 65 years</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX> have covered
most or all of the costs of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stadium building</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">San</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Francisco Giants</ENAMEX> are planning a similar arrangement for their bayfront <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stadium</ENAMEX>,
assembling <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $240 million</NUMEX> in private funds and persuading the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> to pay
for some of the infrastructure. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Giants</ENAMEX> say that other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> are
rooting against their scheme, because it calls into question the profligate
public subsidies. Some of the subsidies exceed capital and maintenance costs:
If the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White Sox</ENAMEX> fail to draw <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.5 million</NUMEX> annual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">New Comiskey Park</ENAMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 11th through 20th years</TIMEX> of their lease, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX> is
contractually obliged to cover the shortfall at the gate by buying upto 300,000
tickets.

            You'd expect that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> would get something, perhaps
affordable seats, in return for subsidizing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stadiums</ENAMEX>. Instead, the cheap seats
in the new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX> are scarcer. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seattle Mariners</ENAMEX>' proposed <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX>, for
instance, will contain <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about one-fourth as many</NUMEX> general-admission seats as the
present location. This erosion of low-cost seats is a long-running trend.

            So too is the dramatic
increase in luxury seating, which is the primary real reason for the
ballpark-building boom. The real gold <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mines</ENAMEX> are the posh luxury <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">suites</ENAMEX> that
lease for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">between $30,000 and $200,000</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> (payable in advance). A
comparable moneymaker is the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">club deck</ENAMEX>, just above the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>-tier seating.
These pricey sections are occupied usually on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a season</TIMEX>-ticket basis, and offer
the best sightlines, roomier seats, and wait <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> who peddle gourmet fare.

            The gilding doesn't end
there: New <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX> also include <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>-only <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stadium clubs</ENAMEX> and on-premises bars
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX>.

            
Naturally, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> don't advertise their new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX> as a means of making life
better for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elite</ENAMEX> ticketholders. They say that only a new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stadium</ENAMEX> will allow
them to make enough money to stay in town or to field a competitive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> and to
allow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> to savor that old-time <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> flavor in greater comfort and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">convenience</ENAMEX>. Local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX> tend to lay off this pitch--they have voted these
measures down in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wisconsin</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michigan</ENAMEX>. Politically savvy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> usually bypass the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> and tap state
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> directly for the money.

            Larger and more lavish <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stadiums</ENAMEX> translate into greater land
and construction costs. Operable roofs, such as those in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Toronto</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">SkyDome</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Phoenix</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">BankOne Ballpark</ENAMEX>, and those proposed for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milwaukee</ENAMEX>, are
budget-busters. Since most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> put up little (if any) of their own money,
they have scant incentive to economize on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mariner</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> has demanded an operable roof even though the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> has the driest
weather in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MLB</ENAMEX> outside <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>. The real problem with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX> climate is
cold weather in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">spring</TIMEX> and fall, but the unsealed roof won't make the park
warmer or totally free of wind.

            Lately, the cost of
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stadiums</ENAMEX> has ranged from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $300 million to $500 million</NUMEX>. The multipurpose
stadium that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yankees</ENAMEX> want built on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX>'s lower west side tentatively
carries a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 billion</NUMEX> price tag. Add the financing and maintenance costs,
and even a midpriced project goes through the retractable roof. At <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point,
the cost of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brewers</ENAMEX>' proposed <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stadium</ENAMEX> grew from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$250 million to $845</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">million</ENAMEX>, and that's not counting the value of the land.

            The
good news is that not every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> is demanding a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">castle</ENAMEX> for his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX>. All
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Pirates owner</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin McClatchy</ENAMEX> wants is a "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35,000</NUMEX>-to-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">37,000</NUMEX>-seat <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX>
with natural grass and no roof, bells, or whistles." Though his attitude is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">commendable</ENAMEX>, the proposed <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> will still cost <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $200 million</NUMEX>, and perhaps
an equal amount in interest.

            Why should the public chip in? Taxpayer subsidies don't
produce cheaper tickets--they produce more expensive tickets. The average
admission price (not counting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX> seats and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">suites</ENAMEX>) rises <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 35 percent</NUMEX>
when a team moves into new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">digs</ENAMEX>. And independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> (i.e., those not
hired by stadium <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">proponents</ENAMEX>) discount the claim that new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stadiums</ENAMEX> spur regional
economic growth.

            But <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> compelling
argument for subsidies is that new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stadiums</ENAMEX> can pull their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> together when
properly designed and sited. This requires a downtown or neighborhood location
where lots of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> can take the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bus</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">train</ENAMEX> to the game; where they can
walk to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stadium</ENAMEX> from work, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bars</ENAMEX>; and where getting
to the game is a communal event that is part of a broader urban experience.
This is the case with older <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Wrigley Field</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fenway Park</ENAMEX>, and
the new ones in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Toronto</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cleveland</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Denver</ENAMEX>.

            "If you
put them in the wrong place, it's a colossal waste of money," says the planning
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cleveland</ENAMEX>. "But if you put them in the right place, the
benefits are phenomenal,"

            Recent attendance patterns show that urban parks generate
much better patronage than suburban ones or those in neither/nor locations.
There are also strong indicators that suggest new urban <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX> have "legs,"
retaining more of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patrons</ENAMEX> after the novelty wears off. But some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX>
deliberately seek isolated locations, where they can better monopolize parking
revenues and game-related <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>, drink, and souvenir business. This is why the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White Sox</ENAMEX> moated their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">100 acres</NUMEX> of parking, why the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milwaukee</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brewers</ENAMEX> refuse to build downtown, and why the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mariners</ENAMEX> insisted on the most
remote of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ballpark</ENAMEX>-siting options.

            Modern conveniences aside,
the new baseball <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shrines</ENAMEX> are a mixed bag. Most are visually impressive, boast
interestingly shaped playing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">fields</ENAMEX>, and start off as box-office hits. But too
many of them are large and expensive, tend to live on the dole, and are
hampered by seat layouts that create a caste system among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX>. At their best,
they strengthen their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>; at their worst, they exploit them.

            The decision-making
process behind the financing and building of new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ballparks</ENAMEX> has become
predictable, as have the designs. But the good news is that our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stadium</ENAMEX> boom is
far from over. If <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> and public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> can be persuaded to take a longer
view of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stadium</ENAMEX> economics and community <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX>, we may yet see <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX> that
better unite traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> with modern convenience.

         
      
   
