
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Football Caucus</ENAMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">73</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Republican</ENAMEX>
freshmen elected to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> arrived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> with the status of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrities</ENAMEX>. One was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sonny Bono</ENAMEX>, lately replaced by his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">widow</ENAMEX>, Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bono</ENAMEX>. The
other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> were both former professional <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX>, both from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX>
and both aggressively religious. The white one is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Largent</ENAMEX>, who represents
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tulsa</ENAMEX>. The black one is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J.C. Watts</ENAMEX>, who grew up poor in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">hamlet</ENAMEX> of Eufaula
and represents southwestern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX>.

            From the
moment they arrived, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> have had an aura about them. Both won desirable
committee assignments. They are frequent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX> on talk shows and favored
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speakers</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fund-raisers</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Largent</ENAMEX> has been touted in conservative
publications such as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly Standard</ENAMEX> as having what it takes to be a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Watts</ENAMEX>, who is also frequently mentioned as veep
timber, gave a big speech at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> convention in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX> and was
selected by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX> to deliver the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> response to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State of the Union</ENAMEX> address. (His signature line, used in both speeches:
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> is simply doing what's right when nobody is looking.") Even
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">nonconservatives</ENAMEX> praise <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Watts</ENAMEX> in somewhat patronizing tones. "The cynical,
secular world of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> might snicker a bit at his home-made, hand-me-down
wisdom," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cokie Roberts</ENAMEX> write in their syndicated column. "But in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eufaulas of America</ENAMEX> they know he's right."

            You're not supposed to say that <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Watts</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Largent</ENAMEX> are dumb
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jocks</ENAMEX>. This taboo is a form of political correctness that even <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>
endorse. But in truth, the stereotype is not too far off the mark. Both are
embarked on undistinguished, if not utterly futile, careers in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>. While
they're both very nice <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, in an unworldly sort of way, they're in way over
their heads. Treated as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX>, they're really just mascots.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Largent</ENAMEX>
was the more successful <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> and is a more extreme <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservative</ENAMEX>. A
pass receiver for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14 years</TIMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seattle Seahawks</ENAMEX>, he was inducted into the
Pro <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Football Hall of Fame</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>. His <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX> are principally the taxes that
afflict upper-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">earners</ENAMEX> like himself (he's worth <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">several million dollars</NUMEX>)
and issues that flow from his evangelical Christianity, such as opposition to
gay rights. "My faith is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundation</ENAMEX> of my life," he says. "I won't deny
that, because the way I relate to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> is a reflection of my faith." On his
Web site is a profile touting his anti-tax zeal. It is reprinted from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spotlight</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">anti-Semitic Liberty Lobby</ENAMEX>. (A spokesman
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Largent</ENAMEX> said he thought the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Liberty Lobby</ENAMEX> was merely a "conservative,
pro-family <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>" and didn't know it was <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-Semitic</ENAMEX>.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Largent</ENAMEX>'s two
signature proposals are abolishing the tax code on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 1, 2002</TIMEX>--an idiotic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gimmick Largent</ENAMEX> is either stupid enough to believe in sincerely or cynical
enough to push despite its idiocy (I have my hunch) and something called the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Parental Rights and Responsibilities Act</ENAMEX>.

            
What makes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Largent</ENAMEX> ineffectual is not his
extremism but rather his disinclination to compromise or operate as part of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">team</ENAMEX>. As part of the small, ongoing insurrection of conservative true believers
against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Speaker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX>, he has essentially given up his chance to get bills
introduced or to have an influence on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> agenda. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Largent</ENAMEX> appears to
have decided early on that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> was spineless. When the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX> decided to
surrender to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> during the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> shutdown, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Largent</ENAMEX> voted to
keep it closed. He subsequently opposed the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> budget agreement and called on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> to step aside during his ethics trouble. During one heated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">caucus</ENAMEX>,
he made a scene by telling the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX> that he wouldn't succeed in intimidating
him, because burly <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NFL</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">linebackers</ENAMEX> had tried and failed.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Largent</ENAMEX>
does have a kind of blinkered integrity. Along with another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleague</ENAMEX> from
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Coburn</ENAMEX>, he blew the whistle on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Transportation</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Infrastructure Committee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bud Shuster</ENAMEX>'s offer of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$15 million</NUMEX> in road
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pork</ENAMEX> in exchange for votes for the highway bill. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Largent</ENAMEX>'s own passes have
all been intercepted. He had to withdraw his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>' rights bill when even
religious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> opposed it as too extreme. His end-the-tax-code initiative
had merely given fodder to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> in its efforts to paint
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> as irresponsible. On a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> basis, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Largent</ENAMEX> spends <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">his time</TIMEX> trying
to attach anti-abortion, anti-gay rights, and anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NEA</ENAMEX> amendments to anything
with an H.R. number. (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">On Meet the Press</ENAMEX> , he recently advanced the novel
argument that without <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Roe vs. Wade</ENAMEX> we would have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">26 million</NUMEX> more workers
helping to keep <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> solvent.) He sees <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> as a
city filled with "temptations" and pines openly for his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tulsa</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">J.C.</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Julius Caesar</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Watts was not Largent</ENAMEX>'s equal as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">quarterback</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Oklahoma</ENAMEX>, he led his team
to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Orange Bowl</ENAMEX> championships but never made it from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Canadian Football</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">League</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NFL</ENAMEX>. He has been marginally more effective as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">congressman</ENAMEX>,
because he has cooperated with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Watts</ENAMEX> has succeeded in helping
his district and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>--saving an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">base</ENAMEX> from closure and winning <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$90</NUMEX>
million for a new cross-town <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridge</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma City</ENAMEX> in exchange for his vote
for the transportation bill. His pet community renewal bill, an enterprise-zone
type proposal, was defeated--but at least it got to the floor.

            But
despite his go-along, get-along affability, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Watts</ENAMEX> is unlikely to accomplish
much in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>. The problem is that <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Watts</ENAMEX> would never be given a leading
role in his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> if he weren't black. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> affirmative action is the
basis for his career, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> political correctness is the basis for his
reputation. Though <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Watts</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX>, when he speaks without a script, he can
do little more than utter what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cokie</ENAMEX> gently describe as "home-made,
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">hand-me-down</ENAMEX> wisdom." Here's a sample from our phone conversation: "We can
agree without being disagreeable. I'm not trying to be like anybody or
different from anybody. I'm here to be who I am. I'm comfortable with that. I
am not an anti-conservative kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>--whoever else is who they are, and
whoever else isn't, is something different. I didn't come to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> to be
like somebody or be different from somebody. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">At end of the day</TIMEX>, I'll let the
talking heads and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> do their thing." A world-class waffle. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Watts</ENAMEX> can go
on like this forever. On affirmative action, he has urged "caution." When I
asked if he would have voted for <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Proposition 209</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, he said, "I
understand the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who have voted for it, and I understand the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who
voted against it." Asked which he would have been, he answered, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Good</ENAMEX>
question."

            
If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Watts</ENAMEX> sticks to his pledge to step down
after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six years</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next term</TIMEX> will be his last. But like other term limit
traitors, he is now hedging. "I think I'll do what the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX>
wants," he told me on the phone <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>. "I'll just weigh it." But then <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Watts</ENAMEX>
added that he had seen too many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> fail to leave the stage while the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> was still applauding. "Whenever I leave, whether <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six or eight or 20</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, I'm comfortable to allow history to speak," he said.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jocks</ENAMEX> may be no
denser than many of its other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>. This is the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, after
all, that gets credit for sending <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don Nickles</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ernest Istook</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>.
Indeed, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Largent</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Watts</ENAMEX> could match lack of wits with plenty of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> members
from both parties and all <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>. But it's uncontroversial that many
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> are dim. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Only about</NUMEX> former <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> are you not
allowed to say so.

         
      
   
