
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Second</TIMEX> Place

            Remember the scene in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Philip Roth</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Portnoy</ENAMEX>'s Complaint where the newly teen-aged <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alex Portnoy</ENAMEX>
goes to a frozen pond in his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">hometown</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Newark</ENAMEX> to gaze upon gentile girls
ice-skating?

             

            
               So: <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">dusk</TIMEX> on the frozen lake of a city <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX>, skating behind the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">puffy</ENAMEX> red earmuffs and the fluttering yellow ringlets of a strange
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">shikse</ENAMEX> teaches me the meaning of the word longing . It is almost
more than an angry thirteen-year-old little <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> Momma's <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Boy</ENAMEX> can bear.
Forgive the luxuriating, but these are probably the most poignant <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> of my
life I'm talking about--I learn the meaning of the word longing , I learn
the meaning of the word pang .
            

            This scene often involuntarily flitted across my mind
during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past winter</TIMEX>, when I spent a lot of time watching <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> glide across
expanses of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX> on skates. The reason is that my <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>, also an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alex</ENAMEX>,
was playing in a hockey <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">league</ENAMEX>. Having grown up in the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Deep South</ENAMEX>, I was
entirely innocent of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX> matters when I <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> got into this. At my inaugural
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hockey</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>' meeting, I realized that I had wandered into a vast and
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all</NUMEX>-encompassing subculture. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> times a week, we had to drive our
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30, 60</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">80 miles</NUMEX> to some unheated <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX> for a practice or a game.
Often these were held at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6 o'clock in the morning</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Kent</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Conn.</ENAMEX> West
Point, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.Y. Morristown</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.J.</ENAMEX> We <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> would stand at the edge of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rink</ENAMEX> in
a daze drinking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dunkin Donuts</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX> and griping that they weren't hustling
enough out there.

            For
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alex Portnoy</ENAMEX>, athleticism was something alien. It was part of a total package
that included not only the golden shiksas but their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> ("engaging,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">good-natured</ENAMEX>, confident, clean, swift, and powerful halfbacks"), their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fathers</ENAMEX>
("<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> with white hair and deep voices"), their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> who never whined or
hectored, their curtained, fireplaced <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX>, their small noses, their lack of
constant nagging worry--in short, the normalcy and confidence that go along
with belonging, with being on the inside.

            In the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Portnoy</ENAMEX> household nobody played sports--bodies
existed only to generate suffering--and there was only one thing that really
went well. That, needless to say, was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alex</ENAMEX>'s performance in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albert</ENAMEX>
Einstein the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Second</ENAMEX>," his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> called him, and thought it may have been
embarrassing, he didn't really disagree. By the time <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Portnoy</ENAMEX>'s Complaint
came out, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1969</TIMEX>, it was clear--and this was part of the joke of the
ice-skating scene--that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like awkward <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alex</ENAMEX> were going to wind up ahead of
the gliding shiksas and their halfback <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX>, because they were more
book-smart. The goyim were wasting their time with all those sports.
What the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> had was the real ticket. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alex</ENAMEX>'s overwhelming insecurity wouldn't
have been so funny if it hadn't been unjustified.

            In my
many <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> standing next to hockey rinks <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last winter</TIMEX>, I sometimes engaged in
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>' secret vices: <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jew</ENAMEX>-counting. All over the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX> were little
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cohens</ENAMEX>, little <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Levys</ENAMEX>, their names sewed in block letters on the backs of their
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">jerseys</ENAMEX>. It was amazing how many there were. Occasionally, an entire front line
would be <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX>, or even the front line and the defensemen. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Green</ENAMEX>--is
he one? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marks</ENAMEX>?) The chosen <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were tough <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX>, too.

            In fact, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Portnoy</ENAMEX> of the present, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> with his nose
pressed up against the window (to borrow the self-description of another
ghetto-bred <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Theodore H. White</ENAMEX>) would surely regard these
stick-wielding, puck-handling lads as representing full, totally secure
membership in the comfortable classes of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> society. Some Lysenkoist
suburban biological deviation, or else intermarriage, has even given many of
the hockey-playing <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> blond hair and even blue eyes.

            More to the point, these
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> have decided to devote <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">endless hours</TIMEX> of childhood
to an activity with no career payoff. Do you think they're going to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6 a.m.</TIMEX>
practices for a shot at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Hockey League</ENAMEX>? Of course not. They're
doing it--mastering hockey, and every conceivable other sport--to promote
"growth," "teamwork," "physical fitness," "well-roundedness," "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>," and
other qualities that may be desirable in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> but don't, as a practical
matter, help you get into medical school.

            What
all the hockey-playing <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> are not doing, during their
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> hustling to, on, and from the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rink</ENAMEX>, is studying. It's not
that they don't study at all, because they do. It's that they don't study with
the ferociousness and all-out commitment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who realize (or who have
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> who realize) that outstanding school performance is their <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> shot at
big-time opportunity in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>.

            Meanwhile, there is another ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> whose
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> devote their free time not to hockey but to extra study. In this
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX>, it's common for moms to march into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the beginning of the year</TIMEX>
and obtain <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several months</TIMEX>' worth of assignments in advance so their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
can get a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> start. These <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> pressure <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school systems</ENAMEX> to be more rigorous
and give more homework. This <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Asian-Americans</ENAMEX>.

            At the
front end of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> meritocratic machine, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asians</ENAMEX> are replacing <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> as
the No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX>. They are winning the science prizes and scholarships. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>,
meanwhile, at our moment of maximum triumph at the back end of the meritocracy,
the midlife, top-job end, are discovering sports and the virtues of being
well-rounded. Which is cause and which is effect here is an open question. But
as <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asians</ENAMEX> become <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s new <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> are becoming ... <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Episcopalians</ENAMEX>.

            The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> extracurricular venue where I run into a lot of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asian-Americans</ENAMEX> is a Very Serious music <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scarsdale</ENAMEX>, the suburban town
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> area that (because of its famous school system) has the most
name-brand appeal for transferred <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX>. Music is a form of
extracurricular activity that Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Portnoys</ENAMEX> approve of, and the atmosphere at
this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> would be familiar to earlier <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generations</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American Jews</ENAMEX>. In the
lobby, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> waiting for music lessons bend over their homework, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> perched
at their shoulder. Musical exercises drift through the air, along with snatches
of conversation about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX> courses, recommendations, test prep, tracking, and
nursery-school admissions.

            The
hockey ethos is to be elaborately casual and gruff about competitive
achievement: Outstanding performance gets you a little slap on the helmet, a
good-natured insult. At the music <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> they take the straightforward
approach. At my younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>'s first piano lesson, his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX>, Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sun</ENAMEX>,
explained the rules. "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Every week</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Theo</ENAMEX>, at the end of the lesson, I give you
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">stamps</ENAMEX>," she said. "If you're a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>, I give you one stamp. If you're a
very good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>, I give you two stamps. And if you're a very, very good
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">boy</ENAMEX>, I give you three stamps! Then, every time you get <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX> stamps, I give you a
statue of a great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">composer</ENAMEX>." Watching <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Theo</ENAMEX> take this in, I could see
that he was hooked. Ancient imperatives had kicked in. When he hit <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX> stamps
for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time, Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sun</ENAMEX> gave him a plastic statuette of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mozart</ENAMEX>. "Do you
know how old he was when he composed his first piece of music, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Theo?</ENAMEX>" A look of
rapt anticipation from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Theo</ENAMEX>. "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Four years old</TIMEX>! <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Three years</TIMEX> younger than you."
Theo, get to work .

            My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> grew up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX>, not too far from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Philip</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roth</ENAMEX>. I was raised on the story of her crushing disappointment over being only
the salutatorian of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Perth Amboy High School</ENAMEX>, when she had been
valedictorian of her junior high school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX>. Her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>, a small-town
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pediatrician</ENAMEX>, had somehow gone to medical school without having gone to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">college</ENAMEX>, or possibly even (here we begin to slip into the realm of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marquez</ENAMEX>-like
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fable</ENAMEX>) finishing high school. Every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relative</ENAMEX> in my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX>' generation
seems to have graduated from high school at some improbable age like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14 or 12</TIMEX>.
Then, for the most part, at least as the story was received by the young me,
life turned disappointing. Why? Because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> is the only part of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">society</ENAMEX> that's fair. Afterward, a vast, subtle conspiracy arranges to hold you
back in favor of those more advantaged by birth.

            Even by my <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">school days</TIMEX>,
the academic hunger had begun to wane. By now, it is barely producing a pulse,
except among <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> who are within <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> of the immigration cycle. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Jews</ENAMEX>
have not become notable as academic underachievers. But something is gone: That
old intense and generalized academic commitment, linked to sociological
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ambition</ENAMEX>, is no longer a defining cultural characteristic of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>.

            What
has replaced it is a cultural <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">insider</ENAMEX>'s sort of academic preoccupation: a
task-specific, in-the-know <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> with successfully negotiating the key
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">junctures</ENAMEX>--mainly, college admission. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> are now successful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who want
to move the levers of the system (levers whose location we're quite familiar
with) so as to ensure that our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> will be as successful as we are. This
is quite different from being yearning, not-successful-enough <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who hope,
rather than know for sure, that study will generate dramatic upward mobility
for our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>' new second-place status in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strivers</ENAMEX>' hierarchy is
most noticeable in places with good public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school systems</ENAMEX> like Westchester
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">County</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.Y.</ENAMEX>, (where I live) and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">San Gabriel Valley</ENAMEX>, outside of Los
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Angeles</ENAMEX>. The same is true of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">super-meritocratic</ENAMEX> public educational institutions
like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lowell</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">High School</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of California at</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Berkeley</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bronx</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School of Science and Stuyvesant High School</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York</ENAMEX>, which are all now <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX>-plurality.

            By contrast, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asian</ENAMEX>
presence is noticeably less, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> presence noticeably more, in
private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>. In these, no matter how great the meritocratic pretenses, the
contest is always less completely open than it is in public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX>. Just
at the moment when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Princeton</ENAMEX> have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidents</ENAMEX> named
Rudenstine, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Levin</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shapiro</ENAMEX>, those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX> are widely suspected of
having informal ceilings on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> admissions, of the kind that were imposed on
Jews <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two generations ago</TIMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">achievement</ENAMEX> is highest in areas like science and classical music, where there
is no advantage from familiarity with the culture. This also once was true of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> (why do you think my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX> become a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX>?) but isn't any more.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Several years ago</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asian-American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> successfully lobbied to
keep an essay section out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Scholastic Aptitude Test</ENAMEX>. It's impossible to
imagine organized Jewry caring.

            In his famous <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1958</TIMEX> book, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Rise of the</ENAMEX>
Meritocracy , <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sociologist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Young</ENAMEX> proposed the following
formula: IQ plus effort equals merit. Young, like many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">theorists</ENAMEX> of
meritocracy, assumed that ethnicity would become a nonissue (should be
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nonissue</ENAMEX>) under such a system. Instead, it's an overwhelming issue. Accounting
for ethnicity, you might amend <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Young</ENAMEX> this way (to the extent that "merit" and
academic performance are the same thing): an ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX>'s long-term cultural
orientation to education, plus its level of sociological ambition in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">society</ENAMEX> at the moment, will equal its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>' merit. The cultural connection
seems so obvious that it amazes me how often ethnic differences in the
meritocracy are explained in terms of genes.

            By these standards,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asian-Americans</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> advantages over <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>. They have a lower average
income, and so are more motivated. And most back-home <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> cultures rival or
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">surpass Jewish</ENAMEX> culture in their reverence for study. Therefore <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> are going
to have to get used to being No. 2.

            In the past, when this
fate has befallen the reigning ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> society, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>'s
standard response has been to redefine merit. It's not academic performance (or
whatever the prevailing measure of the moment was) after all! It's something
else, which we happen to possess in greater measure than the upstart <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> know all too well what the alternate form of merit that we didn't have
used to be: a certain ease, refinement, and grace. This may be what has led
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s generation of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> to athleticize our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. We want them
to have what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alex Portnoy</ENAMEX> longed for: a deeper sort of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> comfort
and success than <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SAT</ENAMEX> scores and music lessons can provide.

            But <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> are not alone in
having this thought. Recently, I've been interviewing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asian-Americans</ENAMEX> for a
book on meritocracy in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>. A sentiment that emerges consistently is that
meritocracy ends on graduation day, and that afterward, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asians</ENAMEX> start to fall
behind because they don't have quite the right cultural style for getting
ahead: too passive, not hail-fellow-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">well</NUMEX>-met enough. So, in many of the
Asian-American <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> I met, a certain <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> ritual has developed. After
breakfast, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> takes the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> off to the juku for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> goes to
his golf lesson.

            The final irony is that
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">golf and tennis</ENAMEX> are perceived by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asian-Americans</ENAMEX> not as aspects of an ethos
adapted from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">landowning</ENAMEX> classes (which is the way <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> used to
perceive them), but as stuff that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> know how to do. The sense of power and
ease and comfort that the playing field symbolizes is now, to non-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> trait. The wheel of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assimilation</ENAMEX> turns inexorably: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scratching</ENAMEX> out an
existence is phase <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, maniacal studying is phase <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>, sports is phase <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>.
Watch out for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asian-American</ENAMEX> hockey <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about 20 years</TIMEX>.

         
      
   
