
   
   
      
         
            What Is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Deal</ENAMEX>?

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX>, I was included in
a group of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> invited by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX> for an off-camera but
on-the-record "dialogue" about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s plans for celebrating the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">millennium</ENAMEX>. This session attracted an unusual amount of interest, because it
was the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">first lady</ENAMEX> was going to have to face questions from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> about the sex scandal. As we filed into the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Map Room</ENAMEX>, familiar from
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX> videos, we were told that she would entertain questions
that didn't have to do with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the millennium</TIMEX> toward <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the end of the hour</TIMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">first lady</ENAMEX> arrived,
dressed in a pale but intense yellow suit, and proceeded to circumnavigate the
room and greet everyone. She then sat down at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of the table and for
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">45 minutes</TIMEX> explained, with help from a few others, what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Millennium Council</ENAMEX> has planned. It intends to perform a number of good works,
mostly historical in nature, such as restoring the flag that inspired <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott Key</ENAMEX> to compose "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Star Spangled Banner</ENAMEX>" and conserving the original
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Declaration of Independence</ENAMEX> and other documents. At last <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helen Thomas</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UPI</ENAMEX>,
who had been looking rather agitated, piped up.

            "How do you think the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s bearing up?"

            "I think he's doing very
well, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helen</ENAMEX>," the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">first lady</ENAMEX> responded, a bit awkwardly.

            "Is it hard?"

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Well</ENAMEX>,
we're working on a lot of very important things," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> said. "He's been
spending a lot of time speaking to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> around the world and consulting with
his political and diplomatic and military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisers</ENAMEX> about the situation in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>.
And that's the primary thing on his mind right now."

            The interview was going nowhere. Although <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> was
prepared to answer tough questions, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> didn't seem to have the stomach
to ask them--or at least, I didn't. To interrogate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> about the news of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>--a report in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> that a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> had
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">seen Bill</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX> alone together in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oval Office</ENAMEX>--would have seemed to
add insult to the injury she presumably had suffered at the hands of her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> already. But then someone pitched her a softball that elicited what I
think is the most inadvertently revealing thing she has said on the subject to
date. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> was asked whether she was surprised, and perhaps gratified, by
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>'s response to "the situation." For her complete answer, click .

            This
answer was most of all revealing for what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>, in a lengthy discourse, did
not say. In explaining why the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were supporting her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>
despite plausible allegations of a sexual relationship with an intern, and
perhaps of a cover-up, she did not claim that it was because her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> had
done nothing wrong or that it was because the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> believed his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">denials</ENAMEX>. Indeed, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">first lady</ENAMEX> did not even assert that she believed
his denials. Rather, she made a version of the point that many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> have
made in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent weeks</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> has thrived under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX>, and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are "savvy" enough to weigh--and here the argument remained
implicit--his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> flaws against his record as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>.

            
This answer points to something many people
have long suspected: that there is a psychological bargain, if not a literal
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, involved in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>'s continuing to stand by her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>. Reading a bit more
into her answer, one might understand that she is furious at her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> but
stays with him out of respect for what he is capable of, and out of calculated
self-interest. In other words, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>'s "deal" with her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> may resemble
what has emerged as the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>'s deal with him, writ small.

            But what
struck me during the interview is that for all the speculation, nobody really
has any idea what she thinks. Does <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX> believe her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">denials</ENAMEX>? Does she love him, despise him, or both? Do they have an open marriage
in which his extracurricular activity is accepted, or is each new revelation a
painful surprise to her? We all project our own views and experiences onto the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First Marriage</ENAMEX>. But there is no indication that anyone, including even close
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>, has any idea what's inside <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>. What she knows, and
what she thinks, determines whether she is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> or an accomplice, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">long-suffering spouse</ENAMEX> or a kind of co-conspirator. Remaining an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enigma</ENAMEX> lets her
retain the benefit of the doubt. So long as we don't know, we can't really
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>.

            The key question may be not what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> knew but when she
knew it. She surely is aware that her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> was unfaithful to her before he
became <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>--he admitted as much on national television. She may have
thought, however, that she was giving him another chance and that he was
promising, in exchange, to do better. It may have come as an awful surprise to
her to discover--assuming it is true--that her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> was still screwing
around after he was elected. There are degrees of knowledge, of course. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>
could have known in detail, known in general, not wanted to know, or truly had
no idea. And she might not care, be hurt but not surprised, or be deeply hurt
and surprised. Here is a grid that expresses the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> basic possibilities.

             

            
Let's consider each of these, beginning in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">northeast</ENAMEX> corner and moving clockwise. If she didn't know that her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> was
still fooling around after his election in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>, but does care, it seems to me
she is in the most sympathetic of the available positions. She would be in the
same spot as many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the press and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>, who thought that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> had
made a tacit agreement to quit fooling around for the duration of his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">presidency</ENAMEX>, for the sake of common sense if not common decency. On learning
that her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> had not lived up to his <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of the bargain, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> would be
very upset. But she would also realize that she couldn't leave him while he was
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>, in part because her tenure is co-terminal with his. If she
made a mistaken bet that her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> could reform, she is now in the position
of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Siamese</ENAMEX> twin. If his presidency dies, her quasi-co-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidency</ENAMEX> dies with
it.

            If, on
the other hand, she didn't know, but also didn't much care, that would suggest
an immoral <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alliance</ENAMEX> à <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">la JFK</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackie</ENAMEX>. In fact, such a bargain might be
deemed much more ruthless in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintons</ENAMEX>' case, as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s reason for
tolerating her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s misbehavior would probably be less a desire to keep up
decent appearances than a desire to gain and retain power herself. If this is
the way it is, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> has used her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> for the sake of her own career as
much as he has used her to advance his. This wouldn't leave much ground for
sympathy.

            If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> knew what her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> was up to and didn't care,
her position is even worse. If she knew her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> was going to continue to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">philander</ENAMEX> and agreed to help him pretend that he had reformed and become a good
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>, she has been a party to a hoax. If accepting a faithless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> was
her price of power, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret Talbot</ENAMEX> recently argued in the New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> , she would be his accomplice, not only in a fraud on the public
but also, perhaps, in what most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would recognize as sexual
harassment.

            But what
if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> knew (or at least strongly suspected) that her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> hadn't
changed, and did care? She would be both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> and accomplice--furious at him,
yet for reasons of the heart or reasons of power, or both, unwilling to bring
him to book. She would be in the morally ambivalent position of the abused
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouse</ENAMEX>, both deserving of sympathy and responsible for her own failure to act.
If I had to guess, I'd guess that this is the contradictory position she is
actually in. But I repeat: When it comes to what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX> thinks, no one
really has a clue.

            Was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> surprised by the public's response to "the situation"? Click for her
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">full</TIMEX> answer.

         
      
   
