
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Salvation Through Quotation</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Rostenkowski</ENAMEX> has been
making public appearances in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>, dining at his old haunts with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>
like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Durbin</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX>, and meeting with potential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> of
his "consulting" business. Though he has yet to visit <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> since his
release from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX>, he aspires to return to respectability in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s eyes.
The strongest sign that he will accomplish this task was buried on Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">A12</NUMEX> of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> . In a story about who deserves credit for
balancing the budget, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rostenkowski</ENAMEX> was quoted as saying, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX> had as
much to do with reaching out to balance the budget as anybody I know. He
finally recognized that there would have to be revenue increases."

            The
significance lies not in the substance of this quote but in the fact of it. For
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rostenkowski</ENAMEX>, who is referred to only as "the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> who headed the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ways and Means Committee</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>," being treated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> as an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">authority</ENAMEX> on politics, rather than as a news story himself, marks a giant step.
Obligingly, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> of the article, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Pear</ENAMEX>, did not find it necessary
to remind <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> that the former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> is on parole after a stretch in
prison. Nor did he dwell on the irony that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosty</ENAMEX> did his own modest part to
unbalance the budget by stealing <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$600,000</NUMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, a crime for
which he has yet to voice any apology or regret. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> simply
treated him as a thoughtful elder statesman.

            Well-versed in the ways of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rostenkowski</ENAMEX> knows
that for someone in his position, quotation is more important than contrition.
It is a lesson he might have learned from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Deaver</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lyn Nofziger</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tony</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coelho</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elliott Abrams</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Packwood</ENAMEX>. All these figures, brought down in
political scandals, have nonetheless managed to re-establish themselves as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>. The drill is fairly simple. First you resign, get thrown
out of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>, and go to jail, community service, detox, or whatever. Then you
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">visit Quote Rehab</ENAMEX>, and come out as a <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Beltway</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen</ENAMEX> in good standing.

            The fallen
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> are engaged in a reciprocal <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stroke</ENAMEX>. For the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX>, being quoted means respect and acceptance. What ties you to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX>--inside knowledge, social connections, the common
enterprise of governing--turns out to be stronger than what drove you away from
it--getting caught with your fingers in the till, committing perjury, or what
have you. For the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>, a humbled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX> is always great copy. Someone
who has been brought low by scandal will tend to be more daring in his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">utterances</ENAMEX>, because he is trying to recover status rather than preserve it. He
has nowhere to go but up. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> is happy to help elevate him in exchange
for a good quip or even a few bland words.

            
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betty Ford</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quote Rehab</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Morris</ENAMEX>.
In record time, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morris</ENAMEX> managed to change the story from what he did--whispering
secrets to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prostitute</ENAMEX>, etc., during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the1996</TIMEX> campaign--to what he knows and
what he thinks. He has thrown himself at <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">the feet</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> as promiscuously
as he once threw himself at <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">the feet</NUMEX> of ... well, never mind. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> has been
quite open about what he is trying to do. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX>, he told Roll
Call : "I guess a lot of it is that I want <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to see that I don't have
horns--even if I was horny." He has been remarkably successful. In most of the
stories that quote him as an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX>, he is referred to simply as a former
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">adviser</ENAMEX> or a political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultant</ENAMEX> (with no mention of the fact that his
only known <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX> is in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Honduras</ENAMEX>). In a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> story about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>
politics, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> is described only as "the former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> political
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultant</ENAMEX> who has worked regularly over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last 25 years</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
politics." In a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> story about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madeleine Albright</ENAMEX>'s good
relations with both parties, he is called "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Morris</ENAMEX>, a political consultant
to both <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>."

            In these
stories, as in countless others, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Morris</ENAMEX> serves <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> by playing what they
call a "trained seal"--a glib <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX> who can be counted on to deliver an
apposite quote to substantiate the thesis of any story. In a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> story about how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Hilley</ENAMEX>, an administration <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX>, was crucial
to the budget deal, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> offers: "Without him, there never would have been a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">budget</ENAMEX> deal. Literally." In an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX> story about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>'s weaknesses as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">successor</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>: "He does the steps, but he doesn't hear the music."
Part of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX>' appeal for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> is that he is willing to teach it round
or teach it flat to suit the needs of their stories. He will defend <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> as
a political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> of integrity. But if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> wants him to say
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> signaled <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Reno</ENAMEX> not to appoint an independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX>, as the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Review</ENAMEX> clearly did <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last April</TIMEX>, he's happy to oblige.
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Definitely</ENAMEX>, I think that happened," he told them. In a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
story about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s disloyalty to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subordinates</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> offers: "There is a
certain empirical truth to what [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James</ENAMEX>] <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McDougal</ENAMEX> is saying. Just look at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">carcasses</ENAMEX>." Never mind that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> was unaccountably loyal to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morris</ENAMEX> himself
after his self-induced downfall.

            The point is not that disgraced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> must be treated
as unquotable pariahs forever. But they should be used sparingly, and much more
skeptically, as a last recourse rather than a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rostenkowski</ENAMEX> is a proven
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thief</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liar</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX>' views are almost always totally worthless, because he
obviously will say anything, to anybody. Though he used to pride himself on
never being quoted in the press, he now scurries to return calls from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Louis Post Dispatch</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Investor</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Business Daily</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX>
gets much more out of the transaction, in terms of selling copies of his book
and putting ignominy behind him, than the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> that quote him
do. I called him to ask about the phenomenon, but for once he didn't want to
play. It violated his policy, he said, of "not talking about the scandal or its
effects." He would be happy, however, to discuss politics or policy.

            At the very least, a decent
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">interval</ENAMEX> and a reminder of what these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> did wrong would be appropriate. But
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> might ask whether they need to quote them at all. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the irksome
conventions of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> journalism is the pretense of superneutrality: A
knowledgeable and reliable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> is not allowed to make even obvious or
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">uncontroversial</NUMEX> points directly. If you're going to say the sky is blue, you'd
better find a meteorologist to say it for you. Most of the time, this is merely
inefficient, a waste of time and newsprint. In the case of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quote Rehab</ENAMEX>,
however, the trustworthy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> puts his own observations in the mouth of
someone far less credible. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Rostenkowski</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Morris</ENAMEX> end up speaking for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> .

         
      
   
