
   
   
      
         
            The logistics of presidential adultery.

             

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Times</ENAMEX>
could hardly contain its excitement: "A former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> assigned to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> describes in a new book how <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> slips past his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret</ENAMEX>
Service detail in the dead of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, hides under a blanket in the back of a
dark-colored <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">sedan</ENAMEX>, and trysts with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>, possibly a celebrity, at the JW
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marriott Hotel</ENAMEX> in downtown <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>." For <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>-haters, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Aldrich</ENAMEX>'s tale
sounded too good to be true.

            And it was. The
not-so-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret-Service</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX>" turned out to be a thirdhand rumor
passed on by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> scandalmonger <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Brock</ENAMEX>. Those who know about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> security--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffers</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX>, former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Presidents Reagan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>--demolished <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aldrich</ENAMEX>'s claims. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> couldn't give
his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> the slip (they shadow him when he walks around the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>), couldn't arrange a private visit without tipping off hotel <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>,
and couldn't re-enter the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> without getting nabbed. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guards</ENAMEX> check all
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> at the gate--especially those that arrive at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4 a.m.</TIMEX>)

            Even so,
the image resonates. For some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>, it is an article of faith: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> cheated on his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> when he was governor, and he cheats on her as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. But can he? Is it possible for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> to
commit adultery and get away with it? Maybe, but it's tougher than you
think.

            Historically, presidential adultery is common. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren</ENAMEX>
Harding cavorted with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nan Britton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carrie Phillips</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franklin Roosevelt</ENAMEX>
"entertained" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucy Rutherford</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor</ENAMEX> was away. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>
was none the wiser, even if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> were.

            Those who
know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is cheating often point to the model of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John F. Kennedy</ENAMEX>,
who turned presidential hanky-panky into a science. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> invited mistresses
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX> (and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX>, and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">overnight</TIMEX>) liaisons. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX>
seduced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> (including, it seems, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackie</ENAMEX>'s own press
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> made assignations outside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>, then escaped his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> detail by scaling walls and ducking out back doors. If <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kennedy</ENAMEX>
did it, so can <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>.

            
Well, no. Though <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> slavishly emulates JFK
in every other way, he'd be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fool</ENAMEX> to steal <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">MO d'amour</ENAMEX> . Here's
why:

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) Too many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would
know. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> hardly bothered to hide his conquests. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kennedy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mistress</ENAMEX> (and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mob moll</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judith Campbell</ENAMEX>'s autobiography, those who knew about
their affair included: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX>'s personal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> (who pandered for
him), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> gate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guards</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House Secret Service</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> domestic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>, most of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Campbell</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>, a lot of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>, and several <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>. Such broad circulation
would be disastrous <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> because:

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) The press would report
it. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> conducted his affairs brazenly because he trusted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> not
to write about them. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> knew about, or at least strongly
suspected, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX>'s infidelity, but never published a story about it. Ask <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hart</ENAMEX> if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> would exercise the same restraint <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> must worry
about this more than most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidents</ENAMEX>. Not only are <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> and magazines
willing to publish an adultery story about him, but many are pursuing
it.

            For the same reason, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
would find it difficult to hire a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mistress</ENAMEX>. A lovely young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> would set
off alarm bells in any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> investigating presidential misbehavior. Says a
former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX>, "There has been a real tendency to have no good-looking
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> in order to protect him."

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> cannot avoid <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> protection. During the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> era, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> employed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fewer than 500</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and had an <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> budget of about
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4 million</NUMEX>. Then came <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee Harvey Oswald</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Squeaky Fromme</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Hinckley</ENAMEX>. Now
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> payroll tops <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4,500</NUMEX> (most of them <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX>), and the annual
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">budget</ENAMEX> exceeds <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$500 million</NUMEX> (up <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">300 percent just</NUMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX>). At any given
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 100</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents guard</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>. Top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX>
from recent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administrations</ENAMEX> are adamant: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> never lets
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> escape its protection.

            So what's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">randy president</ENAMEX> to do? Any modern presidential
affair would need to meet stringent demands. Only a tiny number of trusted
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> could know of it. They would need to maintain
complete silence about it. And no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> could catch wind of it. Such an
affair is improbable, but--take heart, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>-haters--it's not impossible.
Based on scuttlebutt and speculation from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">insiders</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford White Houses</ENAMEX>, here are the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> likeliest scenarios for
presidential adultery.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sneak</ENAMEX>. This is a discreet variation of the old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kennedy/Campbell</ENAMEX> liaison.
It's <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">late at night</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s personal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX> have gone home. The family
is away. He is alone in the private <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">quarters</ENAMEX>. The private <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">quarters</ENAMEX>, a k a "the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">residence</ENAMEX>," occupy the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">floors</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>. Secret
Service <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents guard</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">residence</ENAMEX>'s entrances on the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">floor</ENAMEX> and ground
floors, but the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> family has privacy in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the quarters</TIMEX> themselves. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maids</ENAMEX> and
butlers serve the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> there, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">first lady</ENAMEX> ask them to
leave when they want to be alone.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> dials a
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>" on his private line. (Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidents</ENAMEX> placed all their calls
through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operators</ENAMEX>, who kept a record of each <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>; the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintons</ENAMEX>
installed a direct-dial line in the private <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">quarters</ENAMEX>.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> invites
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> over for a cozy <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>. After he hangs up with
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>, he phones the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guard</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">East Executive Avenue gate</ENAMEX> and tells him
to admit a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitor</ENAMEX>. He also notifies the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> and the usher on
duty downstairs that they should send her up to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">residence</ENAMEX>.

            A taxi
drops the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> near the East gate. She identifies herself to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guard</ENAMEX>, who
examines her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ID</ENAMEX>, runs her name through a computer (to check for outstanding
warrants), and logs her in a database. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">usher</ENAMEX> escorts her into the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Wing</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>. They walk through the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Wing</ENAMEX> and pass the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> guard post by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> movie <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theater</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> on duty
waves them on. The usher takes her to the private elevator, where another
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> is posted. She takes the elevator to the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">floor</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> opens the door and welcomes her. Under no circumstances could
she enter the living <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">quarters</ENAMEX> without first encountering <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX>.

            
Let us pause for a moment to demolish <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of
the splashier rumors about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> fornication. First, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">residence</ENAMEX> is the
only place in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> can have safe (i.e.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">uninterrupted</ENAMEX>) sex. He can be intruded upon or observed everywhere
else--except, perhaps, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oval</ENAMEX> Office <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bathroom</ENAMEX>. Unless the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> is an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">exhibitionist</ENAMEX> or a lunatic, liaisons in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oval Office</ENAMEX>, bowling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alley</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">East</ENAMEX>
Wing are unimaginable. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, the much-touted tunnel between the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury Department</ENAMEX> is all-but-useless to the presidential adulterer.
It is too well-guarded. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> could smuggle a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mistress</ENAMEX> through it, but
it would attract far more attention from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> than a
straightforward gate entry would.

            
Meanwhile, back in the private <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">quarters</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> get
comfortable in one of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedrooms</ENAMEX> (or, perhaps, the billiard <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>). After a
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">pleasant 15 minutes</TIMEX> (or <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two hours</TIMEX>?), she says goodbye. Depending on how long
she stays, she may pass a different shift of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> as she
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">departs</ENAMEX>. She exits the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> grounds, unescorted and unbothered, at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">East</ENAMEX> gate. The Risks : A gate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guard</ENAMEX>, an usher, and a handful of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret</ENAMEX>
Service <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> see her. All of them have a very good idea of why she was there.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">maid</ENAMEX> who changes the sheets sees other suspicious evidence. And
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>'s--real--name is entered in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> computer. None of this
endangers the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> too much. The computer record of her visit is private,
at least for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several decades</TIMEX> after he leaves <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>. No personal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX> know
about the visit. Unless they were staking out the East gate, no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> do
either. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guard</ENAMEX>, the steward, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">maid</ENAMEX> owe
their jobs to their discretion. Leaks get them fired.

            That said, the current <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> has every reason
not to trust his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> detail. No one seriously compares <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret</ENAMEX>
Service <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> (who are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pros</ENAMEX>) to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX> state troopers (who aren't). But
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> might not trust any security <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guards</ENAMEX> after the beating he took from his
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">posse</ENAMEX>. Also, if other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> are anything like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aldrich,</ENAMEX>
they may dislike this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> leak--the lamp-throwing
story--already damaged <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Agents</ENAMEX> could tattle again.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The "Off-the-Record</ENAMEX>"
Visit. Late at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, after his personal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX> and the press have gone
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> tells his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> detail that he needs to take an
"off-the-record" trip. He wants to leave the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> without his motorcade
and without informing the press. He requests <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> and an unobtrusive
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">sedan</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> shift <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> grumbles, but accepts the conditions.
Theoretically, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> could refuse all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> protection, but it
would be far more trouble than it's worth. He would have to inform the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> and the secretary of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and the two
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> drive the unmarked <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman friend</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>. Ideally, she has a
covered <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">garage</ENAMEX>. (An apartment <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> or a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX> would raise considerably the
risk of getting caught.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents guard</ENAMEX> the outside of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> while the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> do their thing. Then the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents chauffeur</ENAMEX> the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>, re-entering through the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Southwest</ENAMEX> or
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southeast</ENAMEX> gate, away from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">press station</ENAMEX>. The Risks : <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Only two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret</ENAMEX>
Service <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> and their immediate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supervisor</ENAMEX> know about the visit. It is
recorded in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> log, which is not made public during the
administration's tenure. Gate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guards</ENAMEX> may suspect something fishy when they see
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> or passer-by could spy the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>--even through tinted
windows--as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> enters and exits the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX>
might spot him, or they might notice the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> lurking outside her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>. A
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">neighbor</ENAMEX> might call the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> to report the suspicious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX>. All in all, a
risky, though not unthinkable, venture.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Camp David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Assignation</ENAMEX>. A bucolic, safer version of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House Sneak</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> invites a group of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffers</ENAMEX>--including his paramour but
not his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>--to spend <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Camp David</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX> is assigned
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cabin</ENAMEX> next to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s lodge. Late at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, after the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Hearts</ENAMEX> game
has ended and everyone has retired to their cabins, she strolls next door.
There is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> command post outside the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cabin</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> on duty
(probably <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> of them) let her enter. <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">A few hours later</TIMEX>, she slips back to
her own <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cabin</ENAMEX>. The Risks : Only a few <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> know about
the liaison. Even though the guest list is not public, all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marine</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Camp David</ENAMEX>, as well as the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX>, would know that the
presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entourage</ENAMEX> included an attractive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>, but not the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">first lady</ENAMEX>.
That would raise eyebrows if it got back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> press <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hotel Shuffle</ENAMEX>.
The cleverest strategy, and the only one that cuts out the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> is traveling without his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> secures an entire
hotel <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">floor</ENAMEX>, reserving <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">elevators</ENAMEX> and guarding the entrance to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">suite</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s personal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX> (a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> in his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late 20s</TIMEX>) takes the room
adjoining the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s. An internal door connects the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX>, so the aide
can enter the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> without alerting the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hall</ENAMEX>. This is
standard practice.

            Late in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the evening</TIMEX>, the aide
escorts a comely young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> checks her,
then waves her into the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>. She emerges <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three hours later</TIMEX>, slightly
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">disheveled</ENAMEX>. She kisses the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hall</ENAMEX> as she leaves. Someone got
lucky--but who? The Risks : The posted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> might see
through the charade. More awkwardly, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX> would be forced to play the seamy
role of procurer. (He would probably do it. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assistants</ENAMEX> performed this
task dutifully.)

            In short, presidential
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">adultery</ENAMEX> is just barely possible in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>. But it would be extremely
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">inconvenient</ENAMEX>, extremely risky, and potentially disastrous. It seems, in fact, a
lot more trouble than it's worth. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> might be wiser to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">imitate Jimmy Carter</ENAMEX>, not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Kennedy</ENAMEX>, and only lust in his heart.

         
      
   
