
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		all right <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert</ENAMEX>
 		uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> just went on the floor anyway um what do you do about recycling in your area
 	
 	
 		well as a matter of fact uh it's it's funny that i chose this subject because uh uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Raleigh</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about six weeks ago</TIMEX> has just uh put in a city wide recycling
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX> in which uh bottles and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> are recycled and a truck comes around uh once every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">couple of weeks</TIMEX> and they separate your bottles for you and your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> and uh and they
 		give you little uh or actually fairly large green plastic uh containers to put out curbside and all that so i think this is a real sign of progress here in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Raleigh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they separate everything for you
 	
 	
 		they do all you have to do is you put all your glass in the bottom of this thing followed by your plastic followed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> and when they come around to pick it up they do all the separation so you only have one
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		place to put stuff
 	
 	
 		wow
 	
 	
 		so they've made it uh they've made it convenient it used to be if you wanted to recycle you had to drive to a uh
 		a central location in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> and then do all the separation yourself and a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> didn't do it just because the recycling location was so unpleasant
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		because you know when you have all that amount of stuff pretty soon you have various kinds of vermin running around and
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> seem to have something against having <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> running across their feet when they're trying to recycle
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 		yeah
 		that sounds like it's uh a really a
 		what you have to do basically you have to make it as easy and convenient for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> as possible and
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		unfortunately while the responsibility should be on the consumer it will be placed on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> now
 		because you know of the convenience factor i try to get as i try to save aluminum cans and uh <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">plastic</ENAMEX> and all that and whether i get much for it or not doesn't really bother me but uh
 		you know i live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sherman Texas</ENAMEX> which is probably a small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> of about i don't know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty twenty five thousand</TIMEX> and they have sites around in the community the the grocery <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> are really helping out a lot
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they allow you they've got fenced in areas on their properties and
 		and you go and uh drop off all your goods there but like you said you have to separate  them
 		and uh
 		i don't know if it's really i don't think it's that bad cleanliness wise
 		because it's there on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX>'s property and it's on a it's on concrete it's on you know <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">asphalt</ENAMEX> and there's huge trash bins but there may be some unsightly  <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">creatures</ENAMEX> running around
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i wonder what happens if somebody just misses with a bottle and it hits the asphalt i would think you'd just end up with a lot of broken glass unless you swept up everyday
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah i
 		i don't drop mine off there i take <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX> in to a uh
 		a uh a big metal recycling <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">place</ENAMEX> that takes about everything and they pay you for it  so i've never taken mine to the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">to</TIMEX> grocery <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> and dropped off  but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah but uh it it it sounds let's see you you may you said one thing that uh uh you know just for the the sake of argument here um
 		that that i'd like to bring up and that is whether it's the function of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> to do the recycling rather than the individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumer</ENAMEX> and i guess my opinion would be that that's maybe one of the few
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		functions that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> ought to do i can think of a lot of things that they shouldn't do that they do do
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh it seems like recycling is something that uh that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> ought to do and that everybody ought to pay for because i think in the long run
 		it's one of those things that's that's of universal benefit to every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen</ENAMEX> in the country
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well all i was saying was that to get it done it would have to take
 		the the convenience and and the burden would have to be placed
 		on someone other than the consumer because the consumer just won't do it so if if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> should do it you know somebody's got to do it and if if anybody it should be the government
 	
 	
 		right
 		right right
 	
 	
 		but you know ultimately it should be the responsibility of the consumer but that just won't happen it's unrealistic so uh
 		you know in the ideal society everyone would uh buy all unrecyclable all recyclable stuff and everything would get recycled and we wouldn't have any problem but uh uh that's
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		not feasible so uh yeah the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> should probably step in and uh take a little more charge and what's really good is um
 		uh that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> there in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Raleigh</ENAMEX> i mean they've you know they provide the bags didn't you say that
 	
 	
 		they provide well they provide these big plastic uh boxes actually they're a good size box maybe uh eighteen uh <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">inches by uh thirty inches</NUMEX> in size and uh you know maybe <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">fifteen inches</NUMEX> deep
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		a good sturdy plastic box and it's got uh some uh uh bungy cord uh kind of arrangement so when you put your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> on the top they don't blow away in the wind if it's windy and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then they they apparently built these rather uh
 		uh fancy <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trucks</ENAMEX> that come around and have and have the various bins for the recyclable various colored glasses and a bin for the plastic and a place for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> and they're kind of these high
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		sort of uh high tech uh uh uh trash collector <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trucks</ENAMEX> they're big things too they must be as long as at least as long as a school bus
 	
 	
 		wow
 	
 	
 		and uh i'm sure it's costing the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Raleigh</ENAMEX> money but of course
 		i mean that comes out of the taxes and
 		so the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are ultimately paying for it and i think that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> ought to ultimately pay for the convenience of having <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> and bottles and and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">plastics</ENAMEX> and all that
 	
 	
 		uh-huh i wonder if uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> there makes any money off the recycling
 	
 	
 		well i think that they that they do attempt to uh
 		that that that they they sell the the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glass</ENAMEX> and the newspaper my understanding is that they don't meet expenses with it but that they offset a lot of expenses
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the problems with newsprint especially is that virgin newsprint costs about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty five or thirty</TIMEX> percent of what recycled newsprint costs so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		a newspaper <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> is not is not going to buy recycled newsprint when virgin newsprint is available at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a third</NUMEX> of the cost and i think one of the problems there is that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		is is the cost of virgin newsprint is not being accurately accurately reflected because that cost ought to reflect the cost of recycling
 		and
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		and what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> needs to do really in a good capitalist society i mean capitalism thrives on there being a fair price for a product and
 		and that price ought to has to include uh the cost of its disposal and it also has to include the cost of of any damage it inflicts on the environment
 		and that's really where we as a capitalist society have gone have gone awry we have not
 		really assigned costs appropriately for example the real cost of a barrel of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX> if you take into account pollution and all of the other side effects is probably a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">hundred dollars</NUMEX> a barrel
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		now i'm just guessing but i bet you that that's an accurate guess
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		hum
 	
 	
 		and
 		but we're we're paying <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty</TIMEX> so the the cost is wrong on that thing and somewhere along the line you have to pay the piper that's what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam Smith</ENAMEX> was saying <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> as far as capitalism is concerned if you don't charge the right
 		prices you're going to eventually that price is going to make itself felt but the way to make the system work is to is to put the price on the commodity and have the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who use the commodity pay that price
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and the role of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> in a capitalist society is to see that that happens and the way government uh does that is through taxation
 		so with newsprint for example the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> should tax virgin newsprint to the point where
 		its uh its price is pretty much the same as recycled news print and earmark that money for the recycling of newsprint you see what i mean
 		so that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who use the newsprint are ultimately paying for the entire product not only for its production but for its disposal
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		hum
 	
 	
 		hey i bet you didn't think you were going to get a lecture on it
 	
 	
 		no i didn't figure i'd get a lecture but yeah i never thought of that that's you know i didn't know there was such a price difference there what about oil recycling oil
 	
 	
 		well the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the um</TIMEX> of course most you know you can't recycle <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX> in the form of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gasoline</ENAMEX> because it's destroyed
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so there's not a question of recycling there but there is a question of of uh environmental damage
 	
 	
 		well i was talking about like motor <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX> because i had read an article about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years ago</TIMEX> that said
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		it costs so much less to just clean up the motor <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX> that's that's used in the engine and run it through a few different processes than
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know it's it's more economical to actually do that and i was just wondering if it's just slow because it's messy or because there aren't the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> available to recycle the oil i was wondering if you knew anything about that
 	
 	
 		yeah i don't know when
 		
 		
 	