
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay what kind of things do you like to do in your spare time
 	
 	
 		well uh i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> so i don't have a whole lot of spare time right now one of the things that i've made time for is uh playing softball
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i really enjoy i enjoy softball but i enjoy all kind of sports i enjoy watching and participating i really like <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> sports like swimming and skiing but i don't get to do that too often
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and then i i really enjoy sewing but i don't get much of a chance to just really sit down and do much sewing how about you
 	
 	
 		oh i uh like sports type things too we like to get out and walk and we like the water sports too but like you it's unless you have a pool in your backyard it's kind of hard to get to do that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		i know it it is do you work full time
 	
 	
 		very often
 		yeah well part-time we're going to have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX> so part of my big hobby has been  trying to put together a nursery and all that kind of stuff lately but
 	
 	
 		part-time
 		oh
 		right yeah that definitely takes over your time
 	
 	
 		yeah it does i've been
 	
 	
 		is this going to be your first
 	
 	
 		yes uh-huh i've been doing some cross-stitch for something i wanted to put in the nursery so i haven't done that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> but i've kind of enjoyed that but it's just hard to find the time to sit there and do it and
 	
 	
 		oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		right well that's
 		it sure is fun to do that kind of thing because then you've got something to show for it
 	
 	
 		right yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah that's neat
 	
 	
 		and i guess i kind of consider shopping a hobby
 	
 	
 		yeah i do too
 	
 	
 		i just go out just to just to enjoy it and not really spend money sometimes just look
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		well since i've had <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> it's kind of funny i i never really was much of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">garage</ENAMEX> sale shopper until i had <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> but you'll probably find after your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> get bigger
 		uh like when they want things like tricycles toys things that cost quite a lot in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> you can find that kind of stuff at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">garage</ENAMEX> sales for just a few dollars  and
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah we bought some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> clothes yeah <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last weekend</TIMEX> at a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">garage</ENAMEX> sale
 	
 	
 		yeah oh you can just get all kinds of things and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> especially clothes and toys they just don't use them and wear them you know for that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many years</TIMEX> or anything
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so i'm i've become a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">garage</ENAMEX> sale shopper and it is fun on the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekends</TIMEX> i drive around look to see you know who's selling what and i found my little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> some tap shoes for her tap class and
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh
 	
 	
 		just you know all kinds of things like that that you'd probably pay <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> dollars for and i got them for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> dollars  yeah so
 	
 	
 		wow yeah
 		yeah it kind of a hobby it that's time consuming too really to find the things you want sometimes you have to stop a lot of places
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah it is it it does take more time but i don't work so uh that's something i've decided i'm going to make sure my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> have a have a happy growing up <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and
 	
 	
 		right yeah i think that's important too i'm not going to work after the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> comes
 	
 	
 		yeah well
 		that's good i'm glad
 	
 	
 		so i guess hopefully i'll have time for more hobbies i do not know
 	
 	
 		yeah well at first when you first have a baby you uh seems to take every moment of your time partly because you're not used to you know juggling your time around like that but
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		eventually the you'll you'll be doing lots of stuff so
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		but i think my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> is real into sports too he plays on a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> softball <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> softball <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> and by the time he plays <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> games a week and i play a a game <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> we go to lots of softball
 	
 	
 		wow yeah
 	
 	
 		but the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> enjoy going because there's usually a lot of other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> for them to play with and we that's getting outside and you know doing things they like to do too so
 	
 	
 		yeah so that's good a whole family your whole <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> can enjoy those hobbies
 	
 	
 		yeah and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> other thing we're doing this year is uh we bought <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Wet and Wild</ENAMEX> passes
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		we've never done that before but the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are always wanting to play in the water and uh like you said unless you have a pool in your backyard or access to a good place to play it's kind of hard
 		and uh they have real good kiddie areas uh at both of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Wet</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wilds</ENAMEX> around here so we're planning on going <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two or three</NUMEX> times a week
 	
 	
 		oh wow that'll make <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> go by in a hurry keep the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> busy
 	
 	
 		yeah i think it will yeah because my oldest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>'s in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and she gets bored real fast when she's <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> with nothing to do
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		so i think that'll be a lot of fun
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so we're looking forward to that
 	
 	
 		yeah um
 		do you consider yard work a hobby at all or is that just a chore
 	
 	
 		well when i got married i thought it was going to be fun  but my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and i both i think consider it a chore it's our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">yard</ENAMEX> has had so many problems it's completely died out <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> times
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		oh no
 	
 	
 		and uh we've had to start all over trying to plant <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">grass</ENAMEX> and so it's become a chore  do you and your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> like to work in the yard
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh well we like it once in a while but not as often as we have to do it  i like to put <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers</ENAMEX> out and you know a few little things like that but as far as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mowing</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every week</TIMEX> and finding time to get all that stuff done it gets to be a chore
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		yeah that's true
 	
 	
 		seems like sometimes hobbies do that they kind of take over and turn into work instead of
 	
 	
 		yeah well that's how sewing i love to sew and uh i wish i had more time to do it but sometimes i'll get started on a project and then finishing it is more of a chore than
 	
 	
 		fun
 		yeah if it doesn't go crite quite right
 	
 	
 		yeah another thing i enjoy doing is cooking i i like especially it's real strange but i like to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cook</ENAMEX> for other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> that's uh pregnant but she can't get up and walk around right now
 	
 	
 		oh no
 	
 	
 		so i enjoy you know cooking things to take over to her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> or
 	
 	
 		oh that's nice
 	
 	
 		yeah it and it's fun for me to do that it's it's something i enjoy doing it's funny though it's like i don't really want to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cook</ENAMEX> for us  it's kind of like when you're a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> and and someone else's <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> was fun to clean but you didn't want to do your own
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah your how funny  i think i'll enjoy cooking more when i'm not working when i don't get <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five thirty or six</TIMEX> and i have to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cook</ENAMEX> and clean up it's not it's not fun but i think i'll like it better
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh yeah
 		yeah when you're home it's it makes a difference it sure does
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		well do you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> go camping or anything like that
 	
 	
 		uh yeah we've done a little bit of camping we like that it's there again it's just so hard to find time to get away for a whole weekend
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		well that's something we're plan on doing not <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this weekend</TIMEX> but the next my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> go camping a lot
 		and they invited the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and me to go with them and
 	
 	
 		oh that sounds fun
 	
 	
 		yeah we're really looking forward to it the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> love it they've been a couple of times and uh just getting to be outside you know all the time and sleep in a tent and that's really fun to them so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		we're looking fo rward to that
 	
 	
 		well that sounds nice i i think that'll be a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> thing
 	
 	
 		yeah i think so
 	
 	
 		to start doing more often if
 	
 	
 		yeah my uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> loves to fish i'm not much into fishing but uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> thinks she wants to learn how to fish so i think it'll be real good for them  they can go fishing
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		yeah we've camped with some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> who have young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and uh if you can find some place where those little sunfish are right around the shore where they can just pull in a lot
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh they have so much fun doing that and they think they're really great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fishermen</ENAMEX> because they're catching so many
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah yeah
 		oh i know yeah um she's really looking forward i'm hoping that's another thing though when sometimes your uh
 		hobbies can interfere with each other because my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s afraid he's going to have a softball tournament that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekend</TIMEX> and i'm saying no no yeah if you're doing a lot of things sometimes you have conflicts and you have to decide what you enjoy the most so
 	
 	
 		oh yeah skip this tournament
 		right yeah do you do any other crafts or anything besides just sewing
 	
 	
 		well  not really right now i keep thinking when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> get bigger and i have a little more time uh i might take up there's i'd love to cross-stitch i think cross-stitching's so pretty but i have never done any
 	
 	
 		it's not too hard it's i don't think it's as hard as like knitting or crochet or something like that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		yeah i i crocheted when i was younger it's funny when i was in high school i made a blanket and
 		but you know i can't even remember how i did it now it's been so long since i did it but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah i started to sweater knit to knit a sweater and i got off on my rows somehow and so what should have been the back all of a sudden was on the front and then i tore it out and threw it down and i i never have
 	
 	
 		but
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh yeah
 		
 
 	
 	
 		picked it back up again and now i can't remember anything about it
 	
 	
 		yeah well i did the same thing uh when i was pregnant with my <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> i was really bored and i bought one of those latch hook rug kits
 	
 	
 		oh uh-huh
 	
 	
 		oh it was a real pretty rug and i thought well i could use this as a gift or something you know and oh it was so it's beautiful but i did not realize how long it took and i got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about three two thirds</NUMEX> of it done
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and then i just i had the baby  and then it was just like i forgot all about it and every once in a while i'll be digging through the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">closet</ENAMEX> and i'll find that thing and i'll think oh maybe i ought to get the rest of that out you know and finish it
 	
 	
 		yeah forget it
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but uh for a while there latch hook rugs were a real big uh hobby it seemed like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> did them a lot uh uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't do that much anymore so it was something easy i could do
 	
 	
 		yeah i remember that yeah
 		yeah yeah they are pretty easy
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		well it's been real good talking to you and i hope you enjoy your camping trip
 	
 	
 		yeah you too
 		oh thank you and thanks for calling bye-bye
 	
 	
 		um-hum bye
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	