
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		are you a computer professional
 	
 	
 		uh well i would like to call myself that yes but i'm sure there's always something new to learn because we have a growing  growing uh computer world out out there
 	
 	
 		but are you working at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Instruments</ENAMEX> or are you at home
 	
 	
 		no i'm at uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Instruments</ENAMEX> um-hum
 	
 	
 		okay
 		uh what's what's your application for PC's
 	
 	
 		oh golly numerous uh application presentations uh memos uh uh spreadsheets um
 		just all kinds of things
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		i don't do any plotting though i don't do any you know i don't do any uh device creations or anything like that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		like in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">AutoCAD</ENAMEX> i don't do those but we have that capability here
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 		well i got involved in uh computers because i have an interest in speech recognition
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		which is probably why i got involved in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> switchboard project
 	
 	
 		um-hum that's been ongoing for quite a while now is the speech recognition it's uh i don't know how old it is but i know they've been pursuing it for a long time
 	
 	
 		and will probably be pursuing it for a long time to come
 	
 	
 		that's right yes a lot of uh glitches to get out of it to work out of it uh-huh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well i bought a uh PC oh well i bought a series of personal computers of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> kind or another but the latest one i bought for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 		to use uh for their educational games and and for entertainment games
 		and i soon discovered that it was running faster than the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX> PCAT that i had purchased to do my uh uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">postgraduate</ENAMEX> studies
 	
 	
 		oh that's interesting isn't it
 	
 	
 		so i've uh i've taken over the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s computer
 	
 	
 		oh my word
 	
 	
 		and uh enhanced with uh uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">uh Texas Instruments DSP</ENAMEX> board
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i'm using it for uh speech recognition research at this point
 	
 	
 		well that's wonderful how are you advancing on your uh endeavors
 	
 	
 		well i've gotten to the point where the program will phonetically label a sentence that i speak into the microphone
 	
 	
 		well great that sounds good
 	
 	
 		and uh it's it's just now up and running in that mode and i've got to make a lot of improvements and uh improve my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">models</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		adjust coefficients and try to improve the performance a little bit but the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> results look promising
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well that's wonderful that's wonderful now if we can get everybody together that has got all these uh uh new inputs that they're doing for speech
 		and if if they could get them together and compare notes they probably would do well to jump <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a couple hundred</NUMEX> feet in that area
 	
 	
 		i think we're getting to the point now where
 		uh there's a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who've done research in a lot of individual areas and we're sort of entering the phase now where i think we're starting to pull some of these results together and getting them to work together
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well that's good do you have
 		do you have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> that uh you can interface with each other like uh
 		who's interested in speech
 	
 	
 		well not really uh but
 	
 	
 		that wouldn't be a bad idea though do you think that
 	
 	
 		well my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> has has expressed an interest and they've asked me to do a lot of research so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i've been traveling around the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> country talking to uh different <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> i spent uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three or four days</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this year</TIMEX> talking to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MIT</ENAMEX> and uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bobrank</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and a place named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sonotek</ENAMEX> uh just to find out what their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of the art is and i see what's out there that can all be brought to bear on the problem
 		and i think the focus of my dissertation is to uh to look at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> different uh technologies that have already been researched and
 		see if i can't make them work together in synergy to to get a step ahead
 	
 	
 		right
 		um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh so i think that's probably the way things will go in the future they'll they'll they'll start pulling together the different aspects of speech recognition i would say that there will be
 		well there'll certainly be a lot of commercial products on the market in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next five years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and there'll probably some be some very good systems available by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the turn of the century</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		so it's that that soon
 	
 	
 		yeah uh there'll probably be some
 		you know reasonable breakthroughs in terms of uh bringing products to market
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		it's going to be interesting to uh
 		uh look at
 		i'm not involved in it myself you know but uh just hearing what is going on at <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> is very uh fascinating
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i don't know that much about it i know that um in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> that i was working in there was
 		an area that was really focused on speech recognition however i'm not in that uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> any more within <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> i'm in uh a different area of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> now working on something totally different
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so uh my interest was spurred and then it was uh taken away because i i um was moved out of that area
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah i think it's an interesting field and
 	
 	
 		oh it's definitely very fascinating
 	
 	
 		my primary interest is in speech understanding
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh so once we get the the basic word recognition or something resembling word recognition
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh my interest is in extracting the understanding and in developing uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> machine dialogue type operations like intelligent tutoring systems that uh
 		the tutoring system can sort of gain some insight into what the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> knows or doesn't know and modify it's tutoring program accordingly
 	
 	
 		oh that's wonderful
 	
 	
 		and uh getting the interactive speech is a key part of that
 	
 	
 		that's like almost giving them a um evaluation
 	
 	
 		but
 		right
 	
 	
 		and going into the direction where they're gifted in
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's wonderful
 	
 	
 		well it's it's all of parallels techniques that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> ordinarily use during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> they they're teaching a grade stool grade school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> to
 		add and subtract they they pose problems for them and they see where they make their mistakes in in carrying or uh in borrowing or something like that and they then pose problems which will
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know point out the proper procedure and then test them again to see that they've learned that fact
 		and so that's that's where the artificial intelligence comes in is is in developing that kind of an art in a machine
 	
 	
 		well you're you sound like you're very current with all that information
 		uh i know it because you have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> too and you're also interested in the uh
 		uh voice recognition it's been so long since my  my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandchildren</ENAMEX> are in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> now but i don't have to worry about them any more just worry about your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		and uh let let the let the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> worry about the about their babies
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but you just know that their doing well so but i don't have any idea what's going on in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> today
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		i'm not active in any school other than paying my school taxes
 		
 		
 	