
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		um what do you think  the major cause of air pollution or at least in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> areas
 	
 	
 		well the the the major major major cause it seems up here is simply i live right on the ocean so
 		it's kind of hard for me to tell what would happen if i lived in some of the valleys inland but the major cause here and we always seem to and it seems to be validated by the press is the car pollution we don't have too much industrial pollution
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> pollution seems to be the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and only thing that that i can really put my finger on here
 	
 	
 		um that isn't the same in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> area because we don't have any major um industry except for uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and services
 		and the the transportation situation is such that uh all the car pollution is is absolutely awful
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX>  also the worth of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">hub</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airports</ENAMEX> in this general area there is uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Dulles</ENAMEX> and then uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore Washington</ENAMEX>
 		and it interestingly some of the information i've been reading indicates that the amount of air pollution from uh uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">airplanes</ENAMEX> is extraordinary
 	
 	
 		is that so i didn't know that
 	
 	
 		yeah and that's always something that you know you just don't real you don't think about
 	
 	
 		well most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> talk about the noise pollution from <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">airplanes</ENAMEX> rather than the air pollution
 	
 	
 		uh but the uh apparently the air pollution and the fact that it's delivered right up in high altitudes is a very significant factor
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i would think so you know uh i i guess it talked about all types of pollution i happen to read just read something the other day
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		at least in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> there were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> things that that come to note one is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">carbon fluorides</ENAMEX> that are
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> being released into the atmosphere are causing even a larger hole in the southern hemisphere in the ozone layer and again and now they've located another one or  rather an expanding one in the northern hemisphere so car
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		so i'm quite concerned i don't think it's involved any longer with
 		with uh <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hair sprays</ENAMEX> or those those no i think it's now is what uh from what i understand it's air conditioning <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> and and we certainly turned into an air conditioned society
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">society</ENAMEX> has especially recently
 	
 	
 		yeah i know in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> there's no place you go that isn't air conditioned and i do quite a bit of business in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>  and
 	
 	
 		i mean you know what it's like here
 	
 	
 		oh yeah it's quite is is the  it's really out of the norm not to find something that isn't air conditioned
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah yeah we just had the
 	
 	
 		and and i guess refrigerators are the same way they release that
 	
 	
 		that's right so solutions to this would be i i you know improved
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well
 	
 	
 		well i guess the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first the</NUMEX> to me the first thing is i wish society would get as upset about this as you do get getting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> upset about animal rights
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i mean this is so so basic it's human rights in the sense
 		but uh in terms of demanding it's just not caused but demanding that um
 		uh we can spend so much money on certain things but
 		that research really be directed toward um improvement of polluting <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicles</ENAMEX> and not just <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> but also <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">buses um  planes</ENAMEX>
 		that something can be done i mean i can't imagine that well if we can't send <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to the moon that we can't improve these things
 	
 	
 		well i i think yeah
 		no i think that it can be done simply because uh uh we've we've every <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> now in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> that's been produced for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past fifteen years</TIMEX> has what they call a catalytic converter
 	
 	
 		converter yeah um-hum
 	
 	
 		and no <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">lead gas</ENAMEX> was came to the pumps and and that's been done there's the lead pollution has that problem essentially i guess because it was at crisis proportions was was licked
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i think that there are there there are solutions certainly we don't even need a need a research anymore it's just a matter of passing the law and passing the law depends on how heavy the car industry the automobile <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lobby</ENAMEX> is
 	
 	
 		and that uh for buses
 		that's right well and also to make it economically feasible
 	
 	
 		that's right that's right
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and particular also in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">buses</ENAMEX> i don't know if you ever got caught in a traffic jam behind a bus
 	
 	
 		oh yeah well  that that the the smell is awful and but you know i was reading <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX> not to go on with this but that diesel fumes actually have less pollutants in them than gasoline fumes
 	
 	
 		that you know
 		um-hum yeah
 		um-hum uh-hum
 	
 	
 		so i guess you're better off sitting behind a bus than a car although i can never i could never uh really a a rationalize that while i was sitting there
 	
 	
 		yeah but even of course in the longer term just to get away from fossil <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fuels</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i mean i'm i'm thinking of research in that direction rather than we we've taken the intermediate step but i don't think fossil <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fuels</ENAMEX> are the answer
 	
 	
 		well we you know up here in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">New England</ENAMEX> uh where i've right close to where i live is the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Seabrook Nucleus</ENAMEX> site which is practically a you know guerrilla war up here went on for years
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yes i mean
 	
 	
 		uh my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX> marched in the uh uh against the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Seabrook</ENAMEX> and i kind of uh my feelings were that we needed this <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridge</ENAMEX> to to uh to
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		jump from whatever it was going to be from fossil <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fuel</ENAMEX> to whatever it was going to be
 	
 	
 		yeah you don't throw the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> out with the bath <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> and condemning nuclear use
 	
 	
 		yeah unfortunately unfortunately unfortunately though i think the oil <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> have lied to us for years
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		so we really don't know whether there's enough fossil <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fuel</ENAMEX> left or there isn't and uh and uh i
 	
 	
 		but with the pollution issue uh fossil <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fuel</ENAMEX> is not the way to go anyway
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		uh so you've to look you've got to look elsewhere so uh but it is something that's a little frightening and in fact well i within our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> we have said said my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX> uh well one one is already in college in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New England</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and the other will be going in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX> and we just feel that when we leave uh this area we're we're going north not south
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		uh i like the mentality north and i also like the fresher air up there
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		so i mean that's the way we will be going
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but um so i i i'd be interested in having spoken with somebody also from the far west on this issue to see how they their attitudes are
 	
 	
 		well since since <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisiana</ENAMEX> and uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> that in that ranking order the worst pollutants in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i mean i read that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX> i mean <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisiana Louisiana</ENAMEX> for a small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> was it was amazing but it's the industrial pollution i should imagine and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> seems to be taking steps i mean
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you you read about the the fairly fairly stiff laws they put in on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> now they're they're enforcing but uh again uh that didn't occur without a crisis nothing will occur i guess without a crisis
 	
 	
 		the smog and yeah
 		um-hum yeah
 		i mean even <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> was notorious for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">its smog years ago</TIMEX> before it even was an issu e out here
 	
 	
 		yeah exactly exactly
 		well the greatest thing that happened to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pollution</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last couple of years</TIMEX> as far as i'm concerned is the no smoking rules on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">airplanes</ENAMEX> and in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> and it it really is a pleasure for me although i guess <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">smokers</ENAMEX> don't think that
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well that that's that's personal that's personal air pollution
 	
 	
 		but that to me was pollution
 		that was its most personal personal uh pollution that i can think of
 	
 	
 		yes yes
 		yeah well i i definetely definitely advance that well listen i enjoyed speaking with you and let's hope some there are other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that feel the same way
 	
 	
 		surely
 		something happen right on thank y ou bye-bye
 	
 	
 		you're welcome bye-bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	