
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		all right uh well that's an interesting topic
 	
 	
 		yes it is do you have young people
 	
 	
 		yeah i've got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> small ones okay would you feel like those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youngsters</ENAMEX> could be raised with a balanced life understanding all of the aspects of their lives if they did not perform some kind of public service
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well i basic feeling is that everybody performs some sort of public service no matter what career path they take unless they are just absolute dropouts
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh part of my reaction is that uh some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> particularly those that are gifted and talented
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and highly motivated uh ought to get on with their lives and uh and do the thing that they do best
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know if somebody wants to become a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> or a uh dedicated professional and they're serious about it
 		uh i hate to see their their lives put on hold for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year or two</TIMEX> while they uh uh they do something that's uh not down their alley
 	
 	
 		well you're looking at it from a perspective of something equivalent to the draft where you take <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> out of your life and
 		and serve as as a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a</NUMEX> a military in the military however they didn't say that it would be required required to be <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two consecutive years</TIMEX> what about the option
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		of requiring these young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to have <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> of public service in association perhaps with their education and that they get you know how we have uh life credits in college
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		experience credits why could those not apply in exactly that way you actually are using that as a part of your college education and it's a quote public service course
 	
 	
 		um-hum well i think uh i hate to see things mandated for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> because i like to see <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have their choice freedom of choice let's not get into that subject uh
 	
 	
 		uh-hum
 		well it would be like an elective
 	
 	
 		
  
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it would be the equivalent of an elective do you want to serve in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace Corps</ENAMEX> or do you want serve uh maybe
 		you know on a on a some sort of a social <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> where you do volunteer work or perhaps you'd like to do reading for the blind for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of years</TIMEX> in your spare time
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it might be uh <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three hours</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> that's what a class is
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">four hours</TIMEX> a week then they have a balanced view i think of
 		what is out there i know that a lot of young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are raised in a very protected environment mom and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> don't want them exposed to the kinds of things that
 		they had to endure or they had to go through they want a better life for their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and they do put them in this wonderful little cocoon and then when they get out in the real world and life does give them a good smack they go to their knees
 	
 	
 		um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because they haven't had the experience in helping <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> therefore they don't have experience in seeking help or in
 		being helped gracefully uh i i myself have done a lot of volunteer work but i am very apprehensive about accepting help
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i'm very independent and i don't care much for that and i raised my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> to be very independent
 		and yet they did their share of volunteer work we went to the nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> and carried <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> gifts and we visited sick <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> those are all good community service behaviors and activities and they don't require a big bite of your life
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah i think one of the reactions i had was when i graduated from college i was all set to uh go into military <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> and and do my part
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh when it at the end of my <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX> and i got my degree and i started talking to uh some of the recruiters for different companies
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh one of them sat me down and he said hey you know what are you going to do in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> in the military uh where are you going to go and and what's going to happen to you
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they persuaded me that uh i could serve my <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> better by going to work for one of the uh military industrial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> in direct support of uh military operations
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		defense
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so that's where i've been ever since and so i don't regret uh not going into military service
 	
 	
 		right
 		right but you did serve
 	
 	
 		yeah but
 	
 	
 		in in a different respect and that's what i'm saying you don't have to go into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace Corps</ENAMEX> in order to be of of service to the community
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		and uh everybody has there uh soapbox i have a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> come around to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> uh uh trying to solicit funds for some environmental action or preserve some form of wildlife
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i turn them down uh because i i choose to contribute directly in terms of energy and i've been involved in research diving on several occasions to uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh gain information about the environment and it contributes to the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> of knowledge so i'd rather put my money in that form directly and i think a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> do things like that that uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they have their own applications that get them involved in the public
 	
 	
 		oh yeah i do a great deal of you know i would rather expend the personal energy than just shell out a few bucks and let my conscience rest i feel like that you
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you i don't know the the benefit to you is much of greater value if you are physically or emotionally involved in what you're doing it's it's no big deal to be emotionally involved in writing a check
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i mean you know you don't really get involved and you don't really comprehend what you're accomplishing
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i think that's important and that's the reason that i think that there should be some provision even if it's not mandatory
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		at least provide the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">avenue</ENAMEX> through which young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> can do volunteer work even if it is not a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two year</TIMEX> stint in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace Corps</ENAMEX> uh
 	
 	
 		yeah well i think an awful lot is available at the present time i have a niece who's with me for the summer
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh she had done volunteer work for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sierra Club</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		in uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> past
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and she currently has a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> job with them so she's
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		she's getting paid for what she used to do as a volunteer but she's getting more more actively involved with the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sierra Club</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um-hum yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		but that's that's the thing that she wants to do
 	
 	
 		you got to remember though the nature of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> we're  when we're involved with here you you can expect someone like that perhaps to be willing to volunteer to get expend the energy to go out and find
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the area where they match very well
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but it might be of interest to put in some sort of a formal system like they do the screening <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">system</ENAMEX> in the military service okay you know what are your interests and what are your aptitudes let's see if we can match you to a job that you prefer
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		particularly with you have the education to deal with it
 		i don't know that may or may not be uh a useful choice but i do know that there are a great deal of young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> out there who would say why do i want to go
 		you know out and get mosquito bit and sleep sleep on a hard ground when i can sit here in this cushy bed and not go out and and uh i can have my music and drive my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> and have fun through the summer
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and there are a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">em</ENAMEX> who just do not have that sense of consciousness and i think maybe something in place might build that sense
 		
 		
 	