
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		what type of news media do you prefer for keeping up with current events
 	
 	
 		okay normally i watch uh TV
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		uh usually twice a day
 	
 	
 		the news shows themselves or uh like network news or national or uh
 	
 	
 		oh basically network news
 	
 	
 		okay how about shows like uh <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sixty Minutes</ENAMEX> or or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Twenty Twenty</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		was it
 		once in a while depending what i think's going to come on when they put on the previews
 	
 	
 		yeah i kind of watch for uh what what they're going to cover on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sixty Minutes</ENAMEX> if it's not if it doesn't look interesting uh pass on that
 	
 	
 		yeah that's about what i do
 		but uh usually i hit the headlines when i walk by book <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> or anything else on papers but i normally don't buy newspapers
 	
 	
 		yeah i'll only get the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of days a week</TIMEX> but uh i get a lot of calls from uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morning News</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times Herald</ENAMEX> where they want to sell me the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> at a special rate  but uh no i'll only read it on on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Fridays</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sundays</TIMEX> typically
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fridays</ENAMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sundays</TIMEX> why <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> because they have a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and garden section in the paper
 	
 	
 		oh
 		okay <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>'s usually my big one
 	
 	
 		yeah i get the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> because of the TV schedule
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but i'll flip through and see what read the headlines see what's new
 	
 	
 		yeah i enjoy just point blank reading basically the headlines and i go especially if i've seen something one way or the other and i hit the
 		TV to find out actually what's going on around here
 	
 	
 		yeah i i don't listen to the radio for news that's strictly for entertainment while i'm driving to and from work
 	
 	
 		oh it's same way here
 	
 	
 		and for waking up in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX> have to set the alarm
 		whatever news they cover they usually read out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> that day
 	
 	
 		what about when um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Desert Storm</ENAMEX> was on
 	
 	
 		oh i thought <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> was great
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but uh
 		i was glued to the TV all during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that time</TIMEX> watching <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> but after after it was over i haven't even tuned in to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> since
 	
 	
 		yeah well see i had the radio going on that almost all the time especially between jobs on that and that's when i hit the radio but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		when they stopped i stopped
 	
 	
 		yeah there has to be absolutely nothing else on TV before i turn on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> usually
 	
 	
 		but uh now i like
 		see i usually i hit the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">six o'clock</TIMEX> and usually <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the ten</TIMEX>
 		but uh sometimes i have to search on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten</TIMEX> because they get
 		boring they pick up the same thing on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> so i usually have to search to see if anything is come up or not
 	
 	
 		yeah uh i'll catch uh some of these news briefs that they have say at the top of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the hour in the evening</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and they'll mention the subject and say they have details at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> i hate it when they do that because i usually don't catch the news at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ten o'clock</TIMEX> and they don't fill you in at that time on uh what's going on
 		even though it's something interesting that you may want to watch
 	
 	
 		do you ever discuss at work
 	
 	
 		um yeah usually with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i work with uh
 		uh we don't talk too much about the news but if something comes up uh yeah it's a topic for discussion at the lunch table
 	
 	
 		now see usually when i was working at <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> we hit <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about eight o'clock in the morning</TIMEX> we all just  what was news and coming up and all so we just
 		hack it out between all of us one way or the other
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		no we don't discuss too much uh too much news except for at lunch unless there are rumors  for pertaining to layoffs or company business things of that nature
 	
 	
 		but uh
 		well ours was kind of strange because we'd hit um
 		since we were all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">females</ENAMEX> and uh
 		we'd hit either the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> because <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of us were black
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one one two three four</NUMEX> of us are white
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so it would be a cross between all of it going in together
 		and uh i really enjoyed that i really enjoyed that because we got
 		a cross section of viewpoints
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and it was fascinating in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX> so we ended up getting there well
 		we were all there usually by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven thirty</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		you get a lot of different perspectives that way
 	
 	
 		it was it was fascinating it really was i really enjoyed it and i think everyone else did otherwise we wouldn't keep doing it every <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh-huh do you get any news magazines
 	
 	
 		but
 		no
 	
 	
 		okay i don't get any news <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> but i do get a uh a photography <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> that does have a lot of photo journalism in it
 		which is interesting
 	
 	
 		oh that would be interesting
 	
 	
 		instead of reading about the news you get to look at the pictures
 	
 	
 		i'm not uh
 		i don't seem to find time to read
 		too much except of the stuff i'm studying right now
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh news wise that way no
 		but i have realized most of mine uh from the TV i think has increased watching the news
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		since the since the war
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah i think the coverage has gotten better are are you real satisfied with the TV news coverage
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		are there other things that you'd like them to to spend more time on
 		they're they're very limited they have <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">half hour</TIMEX> to provide provide all the news weather sports and what not and uh most of the major stories are the same across all the network major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX> but uh
 		they do have uh
 		uh scoops and specific stories that um i'll say one <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> that another one won't cover
 	
 	
 		well see i'm like as i said i pick up on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sixty Minutes</ENAMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Twenty Twenty</NUMEX> usually my favorite is <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sixty Minutes</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i'll pick up on them and find out what they're going to see and then i'll pick up the rest of the stories stories like that and get into like that but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		not uh
 		most of the time if a really interesting one thing or another i'll go a little bit further but usually it's i just don't have the time
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah i think it's good that we do get a lot of variety in news coverage although uh TV <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX> and uh there are radio <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX> that uh specifically cater to the news
 	
 	
 		but i can understand now why some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX>'s circulation has gone down
 		because it's so much easier to watch the TV and keep <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">at least ninety percent</NUMEX> abreast and watching you know reading the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> and forget it
 	
 	
 		yeah well it's like i read a lot at work and i really have to make an effort to read anything when i get home
 		i think that's why uh uh reading newspaper suffers to watching TV and TV is more entertaining uh it uh  usually have it on all the time when i'm at home whether i'm watching it or not
 	
 	
 		well i got tired with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> because i seem to stack them up without reading them
 	
 	
 		yeah um
 	
 	
 		that's why i stopped
 	
 	
 		that's uh that's a weekly chore
 		get rid of the old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> that haven't been read
 	
 	
 		i found out when i got the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> that it i'd read the headlines front page and maybe through a couple other sections and
 		then i start packing them up and i'm going i never read this what am i you know why even subscribe to it when i'm not reading it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well i get the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> paper <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX> and i'll pull out the TV <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">section</ENAMEX> and put that aside and i get out the sports section and read that and then i start clipping coupons
 		and if i have any time uh later in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX> to read the rest of it i may pick it up and uh glance at it but u h i usually don't scan it cover to cover
 	
 	
 		well see like when they have that recycle program on was it <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Save the Earth Save America</ENAMEX> i think what it was
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i watched that twice i recorded that because there were some things in there i wanted
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		that i hadn't written down so i had recorded that but you can't find that in the newspaper
 	
 	
 		that's interesting
 		no
 	
 	
 		but see i take that as far as my concern that's news to me
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because i enjoy something like that
 		but uh
 		i wonder about the rest of the world in itself how much they get or how much i talk to
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that i work with at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> now and the younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> they don't watch too much
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		they don't even see it but i think they're being raised watching TV more than newspapers
 	
 	
 		yeah i believe that's true
 	
 	
 		so i wish they'd put a little bit more depth in some of their stories
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah well think that's that gets back to what i was saying before about uh the say the network news coverage they only have so much time to provide so much uh coverage of the news
 		and they can't get very in depth in the with the within the limitations of the time that they have to present it
 	
 	
 		i think they could
 		use a little more of it a little bit wiser and put a little more positive in some of their stories than complete negative all the time
 	
 	
 		well
 		sure but uh you're talking about uh sensationalism here that you have to report the news and typically news is is uh or types the types of events that uh shock <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> or uh
 		uh major crimes uh
 		court cases things of that nature and most uh it's just a fact that most things that make news are are bad types of occurrences
 		they aren't uh positive in nature
 	
 	
 		well that's too true to a degree if they can put a complete <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">half hour</TIMEX> TV program on of what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> have done to
 		um
 		or fireman you know off handed when they go in and find <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> or going down all all sorts of things you know what i'm talking about
 	
 	
 		yeah there is a show on
 	
 	
 		sorry about that
 	
 	
 		there is a show on in fact it was on <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">eight o'clock</TIMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Cops</ENAMEX> have you ever seen that
 	
 	
 		right
 		i've seen parts of it that's one of them
 	
 	
 		that's very very interesting gives you a whole new perspective of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> department
 	
 	
 		
  
 		um
 		there there is lots of stories out there about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> what they've done
 		out of you know stop on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">highway</ENAMEX> and stop someone uh just because there was an accident one way or the other
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		to me that's positive
 	
 	
 		yeah well i think they actually came up with that to show not just to to fill in on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> but to promote the image of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> department
 		because it does show uh what positive impact the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> have in the society
 		not just that they're always there when bad things happen
 	
 	
 		see so you wouldn't see like that's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cop</ENAMEX> show fine but there's positive in
 		many different areas
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		that they could push a little bit more on TV
 	
 	
 		well like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">environmentalist</ENAMEX> and uh
 		
 		
 	