
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 		well i'm talking to you from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> what part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> are you in
 	
 	
 		oh boy this is gonna be tough i'm in Plano
 	
 	
 		well we can uh complain together or we'll swear we can complain together about the humidity
 	
 	
 		
 
 		exactly
 		i guess the weather hasn't been too different between us
 	
 	
 		no i don't think so i wouldn't think yeah i north far north <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>  yeah <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about a half a mile</NUMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plano</ENAMEX>  so we're in the
 	
 	
 		what what part of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> are you from
 		oh north <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 		well jeez
 		well then you've been getting quite a bit of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rain</ENAMEX> also
 	
 	
 		yeah it's very very rainy i know oh
 	
 	
 		how about that how does it compare to the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> past
 	
 	
 		um i don't know i haven't lived here let's see we moved lived out of state
 		in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wisconsin</ENAMEX> and we just we lived here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years ago</TIMEX> and when we first lived here we lived we were in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Garland East Richardson</ENAMEX> and um doesn't seem like it was quite as humid
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and i don't know then we went we lived in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Madison Wisconsin</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX> um for my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s schooling and graduate schooling and it just it's a lot cleaner up there but um
 		it's a lot colder too so
 	
 	
 		huh well what brought you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> down to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> then
 	
 	
 		uh his job he came back to start work again for a different <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> so
 		said here here's a here here we are again it just seems a little more humid than it i don't ever remember
 	
 	
 		how about that
 		that's great
 	
 	
 		course you know you only remember the good stuff but um
 		i just don't remember the humidity
 	
 	
 		right well
 	
 	
 		this much <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rain</ENAMEX> and this humidity
 	
 	
 		definitely i'm sure the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winters</TIMEX> are more mild here
 	
 	
 		uh yeah they are actually though it was a lot rainier here in the winter uh we came back up <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX> it's just a lot rainier than i remember it all the through the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seasons</TIMEX> you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		sure
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		it seems that progressively i've been down here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years just over five years</TIMEX> now that every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">spring</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> seems to get more and more rainy
 	
 	
 		yeah and i think it's because it's just getting more crowded and more polluted i really do think that's part of it
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		um  in in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wisconsin</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota</ENAMEX> when they get <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winters</TIMEX> it's um the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the winters</TIMEX> are bad but not what you hear about it's just like down here when you hear when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> here think it's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred and six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> up north think it's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred and sixty</NUMEX> down here
 	
 	
 		a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundred and sixty</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		hundred i'm making that up you know when it's only <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">like ninety five</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh-huh right
 		sure
 	
 	
 		um it's just like up there when you hear it's <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">forty</NUMEX> below it's probably really only <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> below
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> and it's so dry that it's
 		it's like going to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">well</ENAMEX> probably what you <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX> used to be like you know it's just dry and cool so it's not it's not what you think it is
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		true
 	
 	
 		um no there've been times though when it gets so frigid that you  you can't stand it where did you move here from
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Colorado</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well there you could talk about that that's that's a strange state for
 	
 	
 		oh sure i i'm uh i'm very familiar my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX> and all my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> are from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wisconsin</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh there you go okay
 	
 	
 		so i'm uh quite familiar with how it is up there and if you kind of interesting
 		uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> down here typically don't think it gets above you know fifty degrees
 	
 	
 		this is very true
 	
 	
 		and it's always snow you know but uh
 	
 	
 		yeah right well actually the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summers</TIMEX> up there we thought were the most beautiful time of the year
 	
 	
 		oh yes
 	
 	
 		um in terms of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> i know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> likes to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> and backpack and all the stuff i don't like um but i'd used to go on i worked for a mortgage <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wisconsin</ENAMEX> and i did a lot of business in uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">um Colorado</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">well</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Denver</ENAMEX> and that's that's probably one of the stranger things when you see the air inversions
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then you go into the mountains and it's snowy and cold uh it just was a very mixed bag in terms of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh sure
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> just live uh <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">thirty miles</NUMEX> south of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Denver</ENAMEX> and it can be sunny and
 		and no problem in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Denver</ENAMEX> and they'll be having snow
 	
 	
 		is that strange
 	
 	
 		
 
 		so it's pretty amazing it can be that drastic in just a short distance
 	
 	
 		yeah and then things like tornadoes are there tornadoes in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> yes or no i don't
 	
 	
 		
 
 		uh it's getting to be more and more of a possibility
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it used to be no problem just because it was such a a rugged terrain and with <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> everywhere but now as they start to clear more things out
 	
 	
 		the mountains yeah
 		even i mean i'm originally from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh Pennsylvania</ENAMEX> and i can tell you that um
 		they've even had in eastern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX> and then western <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX> they've even had i'm going to say <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mini tornadoes</ENAMEX> for lack of a better word and and that's just a part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> that it's rolling hillside
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that was unheard of you know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years ago</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		um so i don't know what's happening if it's you know we are
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">greenhouse</ENAMEX> is i don't really know
 	
 	
 		yeah me neither
 	
 	
 		it just  you know
 	
 	
 		but
 	
 	
 		it's definitely not as um
 		i know i associate the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pollution</ENAMEX> with weather in general so i guess one thing we do miss is that's a smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> and it was it was just it just seemed a little bit more pleasant in terms of the atmosphere you know
 	
 	
 		sure sure well it's been good talking to you good bye
 	
 	
 		you too okay bye-bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
  
 		
 		
 	