
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		do you use your credit cards very often
 	
 	
 		um no not really we use <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas</ENAMEX> cards more than anything
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">okay</ENAMEX> is that just out of habit or convenience
 	
 	
 		uh
 		basically convenience
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh which led to habit i guess
 	
 	
 		okay i don't use <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gasoline</ENAMEX> credit cards i used to have one
 		but i didn't use it uh i used it so seldom that i'd get letters from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mobil</ENAMEX> uh reminding me that i had a credit card to use
 	
 	
 		oh really
 		yeah we don't we don't ever we don't carry a whole lot of cash with us so we use the the gas cards because our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> are both out of
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">town</ENAMEX> and like when we travel and stuff we
 		use the gas cards
 	
 	
 		right so you basically use them as an alternative to carrying cash
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		and then we have a
 		an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Express</ENAMEX> that's through <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> that
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX> uses just for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> stuff
 	
 	
 		are you uh solicited a lot uh for other uh credit cards
 	
 	
 		yes
 		yes a lot
 	
 	
 		what
 		what uh criteria do you consider on whether or not you'll accept a particular card
 	
 	
 		uh probably the uh
 		uh if there's a premium <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each year</TIMEX> and the uh
 		the APR
 	
 	
 		yeah i won't get a card if there's an annual fee
 	
 	
 		and there's it's it's kind of hard to beat <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and so uh you know usually we just trash it just tear it up and trash it and
 		most most of the time it goes unopened
 	
 	
 		yeah i
 		i i think that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Texan</ENAMEX>'s is charging thirteen point <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">nine percent</NUMEX> uh interest
 	
 	
 		yeah if if that much
 		they're thirteen something but i'm not sure if it's i think it's a flat thirteen right now
 	
 	
 		it could be could be i don't uh use them often enough to even keep tabs on it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but most of them charge between eighteen and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty one</TIMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">percent</NUMEX> per year
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i think that's
 	
 	
 		and then you're then you're if you're that lucky you get to pay them another <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty five bucks a year</TIMEX> just to be that privileged to get <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">twenty one</NUMEX> percent a year
 	
 	
 		right right
 		and i look for a grace period too so that they don't charge interest on from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">from the day</TIMEX> of purchase
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and of course no <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> fee
 	
 	
 		yeah that would that would help a lot i i'm not even sure why i mean the purpose of an annual fee i'm not really
 	
 	
 		well i i think it just generates revenue for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> that uh for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sponsor</ENAMEX> the credit cards
 	
 	
 		well i guess so because it's not any more prestigious to have to pay it
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> as far as getting another card where you don't i mean you know
 	
 	
 		no
 		uh i get uh applications for cards from oh different places for various reasons uh i got an application from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Home Depot</ENAMEX> for their card
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		and uh the incentive there was that they'd give you ten percent off on your first purchase with that credit card
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so i got that card just so i could uh make a major purchase
 	
 	
 		have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> percent off but you got to use that credit card
 	
 	
 		right and get a discount on it
 	
 	
 		right yeah that
 	
 	
 		i did did the same thing with uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Foley</ENAMEX>'s they uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh</ENAMEX> had a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">fifteen percent</NUMEX> discount on a purchase if you just apply for a card
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right i did that with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> uh he was off working at <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> and so i went out to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mall</ENAMEX> to kind of look around and hit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mervyn</ENAMEX>'s
 		and found some stuff stuff after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> on sale and ended up getting fifteen percent off already off of it already whatever it was lower and i think that's the only card i have that's
 	
 	
 		yeah uh-huh
 	
 	
 		you know recently is gotten a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mervyn's</ENAMEX> card and i used it for i think for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time when i was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this weekend</TIMEX> and i have i've had it for months
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah i always maintain a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX> balance uh i don't like owing anybody anything
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah i don't i don't like it a whole lot either
 	
 	
 		if you want to borrow money there're better ways to do it uh i think you can get a loan through the credit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX> for about uh oh i don't know <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> percent now i guess
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh keeping a credit cards uh charged up is just uh
 		not a very good way to uh to make to make use of borrowing money
 	
 	
 		yeah i never understood how <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> could i mean there are some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who say well i can't charge it it's at it's limit and i thought God how can you charge a credit card to its limit
 		it just it just i guess it's that that you know lack of discipline when you have a piece of plastic that says pay later you know
 	
 	
 		yeah it's the buy now pay later plan and uh live for today
 	
 	
 		yeah and i just it's that
 		yeah it just borrow worry about it tomorrow
 	
 	
 		nobody bothers saving any money
 	
 	
 		yeah and it just i don't i don't really go for them and i in fact i had my own before we got married and ended up cutting them up just for the fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> had lower rates
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		sure
 	
 	
 		you know and decided and i mean when i tried to close with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chase Manhattan</ENAMEX> it was just like pulling teeth
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		i mean i couldn't close they'd send me a statement every little this is your new
 		you know balance with bonus points or whatever you know and it's like look i closed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this months ago</TIMEX> and i don't want any more of your letters i don't want anything and well you have a credit balance well send me a check  you know
 	
 	
 		
 
 		right
 		yeah well there's a
 		a basic problem too with not using credit cards that they are good credit references
 		when i closed on my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> mortgage uh the mortgage <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> was looking for uh references credit references and i didn't have any credit cards charged up at all i keep the balance paid off so they make lousy credit reference then
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		yeah they do but we we were in in that same boat <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of years ago</TIMEX> and they had said well
 		just list your major ones and and the balance still owed on it you know or give it a balance still owed on it and
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		that's all we did
 	
 	
 		when the balance is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX> it doesn't help much
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		i get a lot of uh pre approved applications from various <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> and i throw all those out
 	
 	
 		yeah and it's like well who are you to approve  something for me without my permission anyway
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but i think um i think what you can do as far as
 		i don't think as many companies
 		when you are a good customer i don't think they report that as much as they should their delinquent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right uh-huh
 	
 	
 		because a lot of times you have to write a nd ask them to report it to the credit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bureau</ENAMEX> so that you look like you have good credit
 		as far as you know paying off you know your cards early or on time or whatever
 	
 	
 		yeah uh-huh
 	
 	
 		that usually doesn't happen unless i've heard <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> say well you have to write to ask that and i say well you know if someone's so quick to turn you over because you're <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty days</TIMEX> late
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i think they should they should do do that more often
 	
 	
 		yeah i think you're right
 		uh
 	
 	
 		what do you think about that uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Discover</ENAMEX> card
 	
 	
 		i
 		well uh  funny thing about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Discover</ENAMEX> card is i just pulled a uh <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">one dollar</NUMEX> check from them out of my briefcase <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> that expired uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX> i didn't cash it
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh they they sent me a dollar uh refund from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>'s purchase i i used it one time
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		and uh i got a dollar credit a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">dollar</NUMEX> check but i didn't uh cash the check and the check expired but on my last statement i noticed that they credited my account with a dollar credit
 	
 	
 		the dollar you didn't cash
 	
 	
 		could very well be
 	
 	
 		oh oh well i was wondering how that that worked because it's like you know we'll pay you for and i'm going wait a minute
 		you know
 	
 	
 		i've got so many uh well i don't have a lot of cards but i've got a lot that i never used
 		uh i stick basically with uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Texan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MasterCard</ENAMEX>
 		and uh very seldom use the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Express</ENAMEX> card
 	
 	
 		yeah we don't we wouldn't even have one if it wasn't for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX> traveling we just
 	
 	
 		sure corporate card
 	
 	
 		you know
 	
 	
 		i would never pay <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty five</TIMEX> dollars or more a year for uh use of a card
 	
 	
 		no
 		and uh
 		we basically just have the we you know we cut up a lot of cards when we you know like it's just as easy just to use <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> you know instead of paying so much
 		
 		
 	