
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well i guess um i'll start out and that is um i don't know what section of the public school system they're talking about whether it's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first eight</TIMEX> grades the high school or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX> i have mixed views on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all three</NUMEX> of them
 	
 	
 		um-hum what do you think about what do you think about the the lower grades you know <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> through <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		well i i i should imagine the lower grades what would what what's what's certainly drawn everyone's attention to that
 		is the fact that uh many of the inner city and uh i guess what we'd call uh ghetto or poorer <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">districts</ENAMEX> including rural districts
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		don't seem to be able to produce the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> that indeed indeed many uh manufacturing and other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enterprises</ENAMEX> want they can't seem to they can't seem to read properly do math properly and conform to what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> want
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yep i uh
 	
 	
 		so that's got everybody excited high <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> i'm not too sure it seems that high <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> at least produce <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> uh although although i have great misgivings about the SATs
 		that go on to a variety of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX> it seems a great deal of our public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX>
 		have foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> in them uh from um a myriad of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> and uh and also um uh i think that
 		uh a certain percentage of uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX> produce a fairly decent uh public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX> produce a fairly decent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> or fairly decent graduate
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah i i i just read some things recently where um
 		uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX> now uh graduate programs in general now train basically they're fifty <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">percent</NUMEX> foreign
 	
 	
 		oh i didn't realize it was that high
 	
 	
 		uh all just about fifty when you consider um when you consider uh
 	
 	
 		wow
 		
 
 	
 	
 		especially in technical areas science engineering and computers yeah especially in those areas it's um  i know it's it's almost fifty <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">per cent</NUMEX> foreign like forty <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">eight percent</NUMEX> and that involves both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Canadian</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah well that's what i was going to point out i think it mostly is that technical
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh uh <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European Middle Eastern</ENAMEX> and and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Far Eastern</ENAMEX> yeah i i think um  i i think i have similar views that's you know where our elementary grades um
 	
 	
 		wow
 	
 	
 		it it's amazing i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> who's an elementary who's an elementary school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> and she said that they recently
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know they have to go through they have to they have to pat the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> down because they bring <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> to school she teaches in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore</ENAMEX> and that
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah that yeah that must be an inner school i just read a an amazing article i guess in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this month</TIMEX>'s New <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh which uh went on to talk about i don't know i thought it was rather slanted in favor of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> or or or the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> in the in there i do i do i do know a few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and have been have done some business up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but it seemed to me that the inner school system there was the one thing that didn't system the inner city school system was the one thing that didn't flower too well they talked about individual cases of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> trying hard but it was very difficult
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i i i i think if i was going to fault it now if i'm i'm looking to carry on a conversation
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		that way i think there's a couple of things that really bother me i think when i learned <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX> uh uh that uh the average <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> the average <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> watches <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> point <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two hours</TIMEX> of television a day
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and that school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> uh are are not far off that mark with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> point <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> now i don't know what school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> what year that is i mean that's a hell of a lot time to be sitting in front of the tube
 	
 	
 		
 
 		right
 		yeah and and it's uh uh it's really you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> can't read um
 		it's really sad they you know by the time they my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> teaches uh middle school yeah and and they can't yeah by the time they get there they can't read they they they can't read anything
 	
 	
 		well i
 		yeah
 		really oh so you're close to the subject
 		and yet you know i have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandchildren</ENAMEX> i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandchildren</ENAMEX> uh in various parts of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and of course you know i can't speak to the
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rural</ENAMEX> or poorer inner city <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> go to a fairly they live in a fairly nice upper scale neighborhood and they seem to be doing extraordinarily well i i i mean i quiz them and i talk to them and they
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they read well they do everything well but i i i mean i think that's a
 		that's part of the environment
 	
 	
 		yeah i think it's it's probably the work that your your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are doing uh um
 	
 	
 		yeah that that that that could be very well true
 	
 	
 		she she's yeah she can tell
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		she can tell you know when they have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> come in for they meet with all of the parents and she can tell before a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> comes in normally you know give or take <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty ninety</NUMEX> percent
 	
 	
 		right
 		yes
 		really
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know what the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> are going to be like when they come in and the responses the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> will give back oh yeah
 	
 	
 		no kidding oh i i i yeah i guess i could i can understand that oh i'm a product of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> public school system from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fifty years ago</TIMEX> uh maybe not that long ago but and um and so i i
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		always felt i didn't get a real good education in the public in the grammar <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and part of high school
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so i lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">New England</ENAMEX> at the time i sent all my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> to prep school i was i well i didn't have that much money but we struggled and we did it and i thought it
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		i thought a great deal of it was a great deal of the success that they had in their education was due to the low student <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> ratio
 	
 	
 		i think i think it's probably very true
 	
 	
 		and i i i think that could that's a formula that could be applied everywhere except it must cost a heck of a lot of money if you do it in public school
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		but you know surprisingly i i because you put such a commitment on education um your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> probably could have gone to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> with uh uh a higher
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		student <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> ratio and still done well because when they would come home you and your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> would say you know what did you do today if we let's sit down and read together yeah um-hum
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		well that that that's that that must be then then if that's uh i think we both agree on that then then then then a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> parental involvement has to be there and i guess you got to take them away from the tube also another thing that i have another
 	
 	
 		yeah oh it's parental
 		yep um-hum yeah
 	
 	
 		problem i have is uh i don't really know how to resolve this but is the
 		incredible at least in the high school and college level emphasis on sports where enormous amounts of money are spent and it seems to me that money money could be more well well spent somewhere else
 	
 	
 		but you know you know what's really funny is that they there's been some research because i'm a i'm a college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX>  and um uh and and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		well a lot of the research shows that like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgetown</ENAMEX> while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ewing</ENAMEX> was playing at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgetown</ENAMEX> basketball <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgetown</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right
 		right right right
 	
 	
 		and they were winning
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">endowment</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX> in other words money that could to everything
 		everything and normally gets directed away from sports realistically a lot of the was uh was probably <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two thirds</NUMEX> i guess it's now <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two thirds</NUMEX> of what it was
 		when they were national <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">champions</ENAMEX> in other words while they're national <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">champions people</ENAMEX> donate more money
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah yeah
 		right
 	
 	
 		average human beings like you and i average <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Joes</ENAMEX> that make a decent salary that are a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduate</ENAMEX> of the school send big bucks like couple <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">hundreds of dollars</NUMEX> but <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of people
 	
 	
 		right but i mean it
 		right
 		to to what uh to sports you say other things than sports though
 	
 	
 		because no because normally it's because of the sports
 	
 	
 		yeah i know but i mean they don't just send it to the new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stadium</ENAMEX> or
 	
 	
 		right right but see the sports brings in the money
 	
 	
 		really i well i guess they're
 	
 	
 		because when <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgetown</ENAMEX> was number one their their their money money that was donated to them from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> from from local from business <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduates</ENAMEX> whatever was up into you know like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">twenty million</NUMEX> dollars and now it's down to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">like fourteen million</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		right right right
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		during that time period in other other words
 	
 	
 		well i never thought of that benefit
 	
 	
 		their income has slowly their their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alumni alumni</ENAMEX> giving and other funds have slowly dropped since then
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well i i never thought of that benefit but the consequence then i my i guess what i'd have to say about that is there can only be one champion
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		that's yeah it's it's amazing the way but now that's big time yeah but but uh smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> aren't like that uh only only the big time schools show that but you're right i i think the emphasis on sports and as a see i'm a i'm a i'm a former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">athlete</ENAMEX> in a sense i swam
 	
 	
 		isn't that something though i didn't realize that
 		no
 		yeah
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		but swimming never gets much glory so it really doesn't matter but
 	
 	
 		well <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Spitz</ENAMEX> made a lot of money out of it and he didn't and he came back <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> didn't he but he didn't make it ah
 	
 	
 		that's true that's true but you know they still
 		he didn't make it no i i would have liked it if he if he would have though but i think uh realistically you know you read the the research studies and uh i don't think he would have made it simply because
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		the well the event he was trying to swim they even the research shows that distance running
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so i would assume distance swimming might be similar that and he was good at distance splits as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">swimmer</ENAMEX> you know at i can remember that but the distance um
 	
 	
 		well
 	
 	
 		the the distance strength and endurance or whatever sort of starts to peak at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about twenty eight twenty nine</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> that's why some of your long distance <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">runners</ENAMEX> were in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">their late early thirties</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		right right
 	
 	
 		and but he's was trying to make it in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sprinter</ENAMEX>'s event and most of them are under <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty five</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		right well
 		i read i i also read i we're getting off the subject here a bit but i i do want to add this to that because i i was quite interested in that myself but i read where the reason that he had to do this in the sprint events is that national television wouldn't pay
 	
 	
 		um-hum yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		for the long distance events and they didn't think they could capture the excitement to get <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sponsors</ENAMEX> if you brought just the finish here he comes down the finish line right
 	
 	
 		oh you're kidding
 	
 	
 		so it had to be it had to be where they could put it in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">segment</ENAMEX> and get and and i guess capture the whole thing for some sponsor
 	
 	
 		jeez
 		and that's
 	
 	
 		let me ask you another question
 	
 	
 		as as an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">athlete</ENAMEX> i just hate that go head yeah what were saying what were you saying
 	
 	
 		yeah well if if you teach college uh college and and i know when i went to college i i went to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> school and i thought that uh in fact that uh my my idea of it was uh rather than
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		rather than finish early i just enjoyed some of the subjects that i was taking and i had the ability to to go in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> school and i
 		i didn't take those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX> so what that leads me my next thought is i understand there's a lot of talk now about extending <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the school year</TIMEX> which seems inordinately short anyway compared to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Germans</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 		yeah i think i think
 	
 	
 		well how do you think that would work in grammar <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		i think uh in in some sense um what i would do before i would extend a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">school year</TIMEX> is i would make it better before i would continue the agony
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah that's right  yeah
 	
 	
 		and something you have to consider too um because i know as as a as a as a former high school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> i know that from right now
 		
 		
 	