
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay um do you have any advice for college i'm i'm i'm full of advice i'm still a graduate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		uh-huh well having been there not too long ago and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> having only recently completed a doctorate i'm fairly full of it of it myself uh
 	
 	
 		oh
 		hum
 		
 
 	
 	
 		the main point that i have about
 		choosing where you want to go to school
 		is that
 		definitely you have to early on define what it is you want to do
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		or at least what area you want to be in
 		uh i had the unpleasant experience of going through several
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> that were very specialized
 		i went through a number of them uh undergraduate schools
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		before i found a a good <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> that was more general uh to give me time to make up my mind
 	
 	
 		oh that's interesting
 		i went to a a liberal arts <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> actually at <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> and you weren't really even um
 		they didn't expect you to choose any sort of major or anything at all until you were
 		in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">your second year</TIMEX> and then you you know you had i think you had to pick it by the by the by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the end of second</TIMEX> you had to pick some sort of major but until then they didn't sort of force you they they sort of forced you to run around taking classes in everything until then
 		certain requirements so that so that you had to sort of get a general feel for everything
 		so it wasn't that specialized so that
 	
 	
 		that's wonderful i'm a great  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">proponent</ENAMEX> of liberal arts education for anybody
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yes
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> being an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineer</ENAMEX> now i believe in it even more strongly than i did before
 	
 	
 		um-hum i was just on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> recently actually sponsored by uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Association for the Advancement of Science</ENAMEX> trying to sort of you know where where they were just trying to figure out how to fit science and liberal arts together you know
 		because there are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are getting just wonderful science educations and not getting enough liberal arts and then the other way around as well <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are getting just pure technical science educations and not getting very good liberal arts sorts of issues so
 	
 	
 		well thus far it's working to my advantage uh
 		the great gap historically has with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineers</ENAMEX> has been while they may have all this technical information they have no way of imparting it to except to another engineer
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i have the ability to listen to them and then translate that into something that non <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineers</ENAMEX> can understand
 	
 	
 		well that must be helpful
 	
 	
 		well it's a lot of fun at the moment
 	
 	
 		that could be very helpful
 		yeah well i figure that that that that's probably the thing that i would most tell any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> you know to tell to tell their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> i think probably make sure the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> goes to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> where they can get sort of a general education and
 		save specialization i guess for graduate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> unless they're sure they want early on they want to do something like engineering or something or they can
 	
 	
 		even at that i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> that who is only <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> at the moment but i see him very rapidly becoming
 		the engineering personality and uh if he decides to pursue that
 		i'm going to insist that he spend <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> at a liberal arts <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> before i'll even let him go to an engineering <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> and yes that'll add <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one year</TIMEX> to his education experience
 	
 	
 		hum
 		yeah but that's that's a good idea well where i am right now actually i'm at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Rochester</ENAMEX>
 		and that's a pretty good engineering <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> i think i think we do some they have a pretty good engineering here they also have a program a fairly large liberal arts <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> as well a sort of a separate a separate you know college uh arts arts and sciences college um
 	
 	
 		yes it is
 	
 	
 		and i believe the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineers</ENAMEX> are sort of required to take <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classes</ENAMEX> in in in everything and i know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i do uh i do work in language processing and and and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who's in my field started off as an engineer
 		started off as an electrical electrical an electrical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineer student</ENAMEX> and then switched over at some point into language processing because he found that he enjoyed it more so they do force them <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are forced to sort of take all different kinds of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classes</ENAMEX> here which i think is wonderful
 	
 	
 		oh i agree uh
 		i have the experience uh the last <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> that i went to was Mississippi <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State University</ENAMEX> which is
 		historically an engineering and agricultural school
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh the typical land grant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX> every
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">state</ENAMEX>'s got one
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		anyway it
 		while it has both engineering and liberal arts the
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">engineering</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> tend to cluster together you know they're in classes together even when they're outside of the engineering department
 	
 	
 		yes
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they don't learn the communications they don't learn the thought processes of other fields of of endeavor it's you know it's kind of like
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		if i were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a day</TIMEX> and got to and got to make one rule
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 	
 	
 		my rule would be no one could get out of high school without an <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">entire year</TIMEX> of philosophy
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		that would be very good actually
 	
 	
 		and it's
 		that's not even true in our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right you you don't need any philosophy at all in school
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		or some yeah or or or or some other thought provoking area you know very true we had uh when i went to undergraduate we had uh um
 		went to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brandeis</ENAMEX> don't know if you know of it or not um we had uh uh a requirement <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">freshman year</TIMEX> of just humanities then you were given a choice of
 		um you know there were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> or twelve or whatever fifteen or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fifteen</NUMEX> different <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courses</ENAMEX> that that you could take but they all centered they all came out of <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Philosophy English</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Literature</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">departments</ENAMEX> and they were
 		they were they were a set of assigned readings everybody had to read you know for so <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first year</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Humanities</ENAMEX> courses everyone had to read the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Iliad and and</ENAMEX> and so forth and what they did though was they all approached it from
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		from very different you know so so they had you could have one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> in the philosophy of something that that the philosophy of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> mythology or something that actually approached this or um
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> literature you know or a literature a literature course or just all sorts of different perspectives on it and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> got to
 		choose pick and choose but but by the end everyone had a good sample of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">of</NUMEX> of sort of how to think about these things non scientifically you know and
 		and uh and that sort of forced them but i believe that that that that that that you one of the one of the best things to do at least for me in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> was was i was sort of forced to take lots of different kinds of courses
 		um i was forced to take i think you know some sort of art history course
 		and you we all grumbled about it at first but then afterward we all wound up taking extra art history <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classes</ENAMEX> because it just seemed like something we we didn't totally know nothing about but just enjoyed very much doing and something i never would have done if i if if i wasn't forced to take it
 	
 	
 		yes i really
 		i remember that experience
 	
 	
 		hum hum
 	
 	
 		that and uh extra music classes
 	
 	
 		yes um-hum and that and that really is something that that i notice like uh i talk to a lot of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> that are more specialized and they don't have that
 		they just you know they went in and took their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courses</ENAMEX> that they were expected to take and that was all they never had some of the more fun classes i guess
 		i feel a little more worldly now
 	
 	
 		well that will continue to grow
 		even as you
 		go beyond graduate school
 	
 	
 		yes i'm i'm i'm hoping i'm hoping
 	
 	
 		have have you gone straight through
 	
 	
 		yes i i graduated um <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty seven</NUMEX> and i just went straight through
 		um i'm finishing up <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX> so yeah i didn't i didn't take any break or anything yet  i've been trying actually in graduate school i've been trying to do the same thing take <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courses</ENAMEX> outside it's completely outside my area and i'm finding that in graduate school it's a lot harder
 		because uh i just don't have the time anymore to sort of sit in a course
 		that i'm not getting graded for whereas before i would just sign up for credit for it now i can't sign up for an art history course for credit necessarily
 		so i have to try and go myself and i went for like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two or three weeks</TIMEX> and realized not enough time for the work unfortunately
 	
 	
 		that's true are you pursuing a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Master</ENAMEX>'s or a Doctorate
 	
 	
 		i'm pursuing a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Doctorate</ENAMEX> in Psychology so i'm just
 		wind up spending a lot of time doing that instead
 		uh
 		what else i i think i  oh
 	
 	
 		well let me let me encourage you to stop stop and experience life along the way
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		i i <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> enrolled in college in nineteen <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixty six</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six years</TIMEX> and a
 		and a war later uh i got a degree an undergraduate degree
 		and then
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fifteen</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> after that
 		i got the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of a set of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX>'s degrees and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX> after that i got another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX>'s degree
 	
 	
 		hum so you had real world experience in the middle there
 	
 	
 		oh yes
 	
 	
 		
  
 		and that helped you think
 		or that was
 	
 	
 		it certainly it certainly makes acceptance of different ideas a lot easier
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		hum yeah i'm getting some of that um i have i have sort of some work experience yet my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> is not an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">academic</ENAMEX> at all
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> is sort of in the real world and i so i sort of hinge halfway out in the real world getting you know real world  especially she works in uh um
 		she works in something i she she works for a temporary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> and and i and i never would have had she's the office <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supervisor</ENAMEX> i never would have had any i've i've learned much just sort of by watching her and her and her business as well so yeah so i i can see where that might be a
 	
 	
 		well vicarious learning is a wonderful thing uh you know it certainly means that we don't have to experience everything but experience is a wonderful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> also
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		that's my oh yeah
 		yes agreed agreed well i'll i'll take that i'll take that  and think that through a little bit um
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> as as as i may have mentioned just finished a doctorate <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of years ago</TIMEX> and and she pursued her education along the lines that i did
 	
 	
 		yes
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		with lots of break in between and she feels reasonably comfortable teaching now she has an awful lot of experience to draw on no longer is
 		
 		
 	