
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">great</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um are you what what type of music do you like
 	
 	
 		uh i like uh
 		probably  cutting edge rock would be the best way to describe it
 	
 	
 		oh well then i'm sure we're going to have a lot in common  i'm just joking what exactly is cutting edge rock
 	
 	
 		good deal
 		
 
 		cutting edge rock oh i don't know you got your top forty rock which i just can't stand top forty music the stuff you'd see on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MTV</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VH One</ENAMEX> and what have you and then there's new music come from we've got a radio station down here that uh
 	
 	
 		oh really  um-hum
 	
 	
 		started broadcasting <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a year ago</TIMEX> and they've uh they play music that you just wouldn't hear on any other radio station more like a college it's more like a college <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX> would play
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		which we don't have down here but uh
 		it's just music by different <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> it's you know things you wouldn't you wouldn't uh
 	
 	
 		i see
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you wouldn't would never be exposed to
 	
 	
 		is it music that um like you can understand the words to
 	
 	
 		yeah most of it
 	
 	
 		oh okay well the the thing that i hate really is music that um
 		it just seems like instruments playing all at once to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> different scores of music do you know what i mean like didn't seem like it was meant what
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		kind of noise
 		it's noise
 	
 	
 		yeah it's noise it just doesn't seem like it was supposed to be played at the same time together or that someone isn't tuned or whatever
 		but um i have to admit i do love top forty
 		and um
 		although i don't watch <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MTV</ENAMEX> i do love that type of music but
 		i feel like it's the best music that you can sing along to and dance and
 	
 	
 		well
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		and um i'm an aerobics freak so i just uh i love that type of music to do aerobics to and exercise and that sort of thing
 		do you go out to listen to music a lot
 	
 	
 		do i go out to listen to music well i go to school and work so i don't get too too many opportunities to uh go out and see a a live band although occasionally
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		don't get much time
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i'll go downtown they have what they call <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Deep Ellum</ENAMEX> down here where a lot of local bands play and i've gone down there a few times
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		do you play any sort of instrument oh
 	
 	
 		no i'm musically destitute
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		have no talents
 	
 	
 		oh don't be silly i used to play the piano and i used to play the guitar but
 		then when i moved out you don't get to take the piano with you and uh there's no guitar around so i decided just to turn on the radio and that'll be my musical entertainment from now on
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but we don't get to go i love concerts if i could i would save my money and just go to concerts but
 		obviously not only is they don't come around <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rochester</ENAMEX> too often but um standing in line for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> on end doesn't really appeal to me either
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah i used to go i when i <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several years ago</TIMEX> i've gone to a few concerts but it just
 		it just gets to be more of a hassle than it's worth yeah you get a lot of thirteen and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fourteen year olds</TIMEX> and it's just a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> of little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah exactly
 		i know and then by the time you leave you end up like sitting in your <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an hour</TIMEX> just to get out of the parking lot
 	
 	
 		yeah we usually go down and there's a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tower</ENAMEX> that they have downtown you go down have a couple of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drinks</ENAMEX> and wait for traffic to go away
 	
 	
 		do you have a good <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">um stadium</ENAMEX> there or or
 	
 	
 		it's
 		it's an indoor arena
 	
 	
 		oh right what's it called
 	
 	
 		Reunion
 	
 	
 		oh Reunion no that's not what i'm thinking of wasn't
 	
 	
 		there's one there's the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Bronco Bowl</ENAMEX> that's out in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort Worth</ENAMEX> though
 	
 	
 		i don't know what i'm thinking of
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arlington Stadium</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		there's several big things down in down here most of the most of the concerts are out at uh <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Reunion Arena</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it's it's okay the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the acoustics</TIMEX> could be better but like i say i haven't been down there to a concert since
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		jeez i don't remember who i went to see last
 	
 	
 		well now you have to like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Beatles</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Billy Joel</ENAMEX> you know uh
 	
 	
 		i like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Beatles</ENAMEX> some <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Billy Joel</ENAMEX> you know back in high school i guess i was a big <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Billy Joel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i've been
 	
 	
 		sort of grown out of that
 	
 	
 		well you know i listen to it but i won't go buy it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i've i've like i've been exposed to so many new and different bands lately just through this new radio station that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i realize there's just a lot of a lot of things i've i never would have heard or even thought of looking at or listening to
 	
 	
 		like who are some of those bands what are they called
 	
 	
 		and
 		oh i'm trying to think of a good example one that won't get me into too much trouble
 	
 	
 		who won't get you in too much trouble
 	
 	
 		um
 		yeah
 		be a bad example but like for example the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Violent Violent Femmes</ENAMEX> they've been around for a while and they've just started playing some new music of theirs and it made me go out and buy some and listen to it i won't say i like the whole album really but uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well you know i was just reading the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> and um there's this big thing on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madonna</ENAMEX>'s new movie <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Truth of Dare</ENAMEX> have you heard about that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah i was reading an article about that yesterday
 	
 	
 		and um well i haven't seen the movie but obviously it looks extremely risque and um
 		they were just mentioning some figures that she's made like in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past year</TIMEX> she made <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">nine million dollars</NUMEX> and over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past couple of years</TIMEX> it's totaled <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">almost two hundred million dollars</NUMEX>
 		and i mean as much as i like top forty i don't like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madonna</ENAMEX> i don't like her and i don't like her music and um i just don't like anything about her actually
 	
 	
 		the only thing i like about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madonna</ENAMEX> is i think if if i was given a ticket to see her perform i think she'd be entertaining to see perform
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		probably yeah
 	
 	
 		but i don't i don't really care for her music there's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one or two</NUMEX> songs that i like you know for a while until they overplayed them to death but uh i've never been a big <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madonna</ENAMEX> fan
 	
 	
 		um-hum right exactly
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i do think if someone gave me a ticket it'd be a really entertaining show
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true
 	
 	
 		i wouldn't go stand in line or sleep <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">overnight</TIMEX> at the
 	
 	
 		but i know oh God no but to think that she's able to make that much money
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		just think of i mean that is what our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are growing up with right now you know that they that they were talking about how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madonna</ENAMEX> is becoming a role model for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's crazy
 	
 	
 		and uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> it's really scary
 		i don't know but i guess i i still go back to the old faithfuls like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Taylor</ENAMEX> and if i could if i had my choice to sit and listen to um
 		oh i don't know some new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> or just uh
 		put on a tape of i don't know
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carly Simon</ENAMEX> or whatever that's probably what i would stick to
 		although i do have uh an unending love for fifties music which you probably detest
 	
 	
 		some no there's some my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> you know i used to listen to the stuff they listen to you know the Guess Who and what have you i've got some of that uh i don't i don't
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i won't say i make tapes to listen to in my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> but occasionally i put on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LCD</ENAMEX> and crank it up because i you know stuff i grew up with
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		um-hum yeah
 	
 	
 		listening to so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i'm i've got pretty broad musical tastes i don't really care for gospel and i'm not a big <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> fan but
 	
 	
 		me either
 	
 	
 		other than that i'll listen to just about anything
 	
 	
 		yeah do you have uh any sort of collection are you like uh you know do you go out and buy a bunch of CD's or tapes or
 	
 	
 		yeah i've got some i've got i don't know about <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred hundred and fifteen</NUMEX> CD's i suppose
 	
 	
 		do you really
 	
 	
 		i just i've got a bunch of the albums but i never play them because
 		CD's have taken over
 	
 	
 		yeah exactly they really have
 		we were talking about um how the only way to really destroy a CD is to drill a hole through it that you can microwave them and uh i don't know do whatever really it amazes yeah amazing
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		you can scratch them up pretty good they'll still play
 	
 	
 		but well it was nice talking to you
 	
 	
 		yes so go out and play in that sun
 	
 	
 		yeah right and i'll go turn on my <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Taylor</ENAMEX> tape or something  all righty take care bye-bye
 	
 	
 		all right
 		
 
 		okay bye
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	