
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 		okay
 	
 	
 		so what kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> do you want
 	
 	
 		well i think we're we have pretty much narrowed it down to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mazda</ENAMEX> minivan
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		the new uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh M P V</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the uh the one that's the all wheel drive
 	
 	
 		do you have a family
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		uh that helps
 	
 	
 		well we're we do it mainly because we travel we do a lot of traveling and i want to do it in comfort
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right now we have we have we have a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> door you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">sedan</ENAMEX> but it's just uh it just doesn't have quite as much room and it's not very comfortable to drive long distance in
 	
 	
 		you you sound like you've been looking recently or you're buying soon
 	
 	
 		well we've we've been looking for about you know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> to decide but you know with the style changes you know they're they're a lot of them are changing right now and we're trying to wait until we see what what it's going to you know the style going to stay for a while
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh supposedly the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mazda</ENAMEX> is going to change this coming year
 		and we'll just we'll wait till the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ninety twos</ENAMEX> come out
 	
 	
 		that won't be much longer
 	
 	
 		no so that's that's pretty much uh you know where we stand now how about how about you
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well actually i haven't it's funny i haven't been looking at all i mean because um i'm a grad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> and
 		and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s got an <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty seven</NUMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Olds Ferenza</ENAMEX> and i have an <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty two</NUMEX> Bonneville
 		which basically our our our our plan is to wait <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">another year</TIMEX> until i'm done with graduate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and then sell the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bonneville</ENAMEX> for whatever we can get for it and go out and buy another a a new car some place else and i think
 		we probably i'm sort of stuck i want <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of me wants some sort of little sporty thing just for the hell of it because it may be the last time i can drive one for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time</TIMEX> and the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of me says be pragmatic and get some sort of
 		um probably small economical <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of years</TIMEX> and then get something bigger like a minivan when when when we have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and stuff or or or when we travel a lot
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah you pretty much have to take advantage of the uh the wild and crazy while you can and then you got to turn into the practical
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right
 	
 	
 		that's kind of the way i've had to transition i was into you know the sportier <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> and then uh when when when it comes to putting car <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">seats</ENAMEX> and all that kind of stuff in it you know you just don't uh
 		can't get away with it any longer
 	
 	
 		yeah they don't work
 	
 	
 		or then and then you got to wait until you're you know after your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are grown and you can scale back down again
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but uh you know right now i have a pickup <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX>
 		and it's one of the supercabs and you can get you can get uh you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids kids</ENAMEX> and everything in there the only thing is it's it's not very comfortable
 	
 	
 		right well it's a it's a it's note like the i've seen that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mazda</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">van</ENAMEX> and and it seems like it would be the right thing then
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well they've made some changes over the you know the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last couple of years</TIMEX> since they've come out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> they're coming out with a new transmission a little bit heavier duty transmission
 		which the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> are not well known for but uh
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but they're supposedly getting a new uh transmission in fact i think <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board Warner</ENAMEX>'s the one that going to going to design it for them
 	
 	
 		oh okay that'll be nice
 	
 	
 		and that'll that'll help some and uh they're going to change the interior to where the backseat itself can either be removed or laid laying down into a bed
 		whereas now it can't
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		you can lean it back a little bit but not all the way
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		so we're looking at those type things also
 	
 	
 		that's just yeah it's thinking ahead
 	
 	
 		yeah plus you know the the uh the wheel base uh
 	
 	
 		it's real good
 	
 	
 		the way it is right now the all wheel drive
 		it's a little bit higher up off the ground but they're going to raise it <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">three more inches</NUMEX> up
 		and a little bit more clearance
 	
 	
 		that'll give you a little extra
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh you know not that i really need it for any but i like sitting up high so you can see
 	
 	
 		yeah it's actually a real nice feeling
 		i uh grew up driving the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Suburban</ENAMEX> and then recently i test drove
 		for some strange reason i test drove a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Range Rover</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		not because i was going to buy a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">forty thousand dollar</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jeep</ENAMEX> mind you
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		but just but but because um my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> works for a temporary agency
 		and they and and they had a job and they called me basically i basically i was shopping the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> to make sure you know he was doing good things by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Range Rover</ENAMEX> you know
 		they sent me out as a to sort of act like i wanted to buy one
 		basically and then report back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> as to how the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">salesman</ENAMEX> is doing
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		so i had to act like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buyer</ENAMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		that's kind of interesting
 	
 	
 		yeah it's a neat little um it's it's it's it's
 		it's sort of like being a scab i guess in a sense but uh but i used you know i mean he did a wonderful job so i just went back and said wonderful things about him you know but we went and part of it was test driving a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Range Rover</ENAMEX> and i realized afterward you know it's a real nice ride because it's nice you're nice and high
 		lots of clearance and stuff like that like you said but
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">forty seven thousand dollars</NUMEX> is
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">forty thousand dollars</NUMEX> yeah that's just way too much for for a jeep in my opinion
 	
 	
 		it's a little stiff
 		yeah i agree i don't think even if i had the money to spend on it i don't think i'd buy one
 	
 	
 		no i wouldn't i mean i would get if i wanted to pick out a car like that i'd go for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Bronco</ENAMEX> or or or you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Blazer</ENAMEX> or something i figure it's
 	
 	
 		plus nowadays you know you it <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> are high anyway you know can't hardly get anything decent for less than you know nineteen or <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and that's that's a pretty big investment even nowadays and i want something that's going to last me for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at least seven eight years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		i just can't see you know these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> spending <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these thirty five</TIMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">forty five thousand dollars</NUMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMWs</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mercedes</ENAMEX> and then trading them <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> or two
 	
 	
 		oh yeah this this is nothing i mean he um he was showing me they had this i was you know they had they had a beamer there that was <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">seventy eight thousand</NUMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mercedes</ENAMEX> that was ninety
 	
 	
 		God that's so that's silly
 	
 	
 		you know and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> claimed that he sold <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fourteen</NUMEX> of these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mercedes</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the previous year</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		i uh i like i say i don't i think even if i had the money i wouldn't want something like that it's just not within my it's just it's impractical
 	
 	
 		it was amazing
 		yeah
 		it totally impractical and i i can't imagine what's that much better about them that
 	
 	
 		too many other good things you can do with the money besides <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">waste</ENAMEX> it uh i just uh you know there's too many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that need things and
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know places that you can put it
 	
 	
 		yeah i agree
 	
 	
 		not not to waste money like that
 	
 	
 		it'd be nice to think that i could afford it mind you but
 	
 	
 		yeah i mean it'd be nice to be able to afford it but i i'm just not i even if i had the money i i'm i know for a fact i just wouldn't i wouldn't buy one i just can't bring myself to do that kind of stuff
 	
 	
 		yeah no i wouldn't
 	
 	
 		but uh
 		we try to keep our <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> on an average of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years</TIMEX> if we can if we can get by with it we have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Volvo</ENAMEX> right now that's
 		i t's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven years old</TIMEX> and it's got uh <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about eighty five thousand miles</NUMEX> on it and it still drives like it's brand new
 	
 	
 		i was going to say a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Volvo</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">eighty five thousand miles</NUMEX> is still being broken in isn't it
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about</TIMEX> that's about right and we we anticipate on keeping that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> for hopefully <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">another five six seven years</TIMEX> if we can if we can make it go that long
 	
 	
 		i mean
 		yeah those aren't aren't those the ones that that have is it <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Volvo</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saab</ENAMEX> that has like the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three hundred thousand</NUMEX> mile <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		well <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Volvos</ENAMEX> uh there's a lot of them that we in fact we have a mutual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> uh my
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and i that uh
 		they uh they just passed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three hundred thousand</NUMEX> miles on theirs
 	
 	
 		and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>'s probably still fine right
 	
 	
 		it's still mechanically fine now you you know there's there's money to invest in it during during that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three hundred thousand</NUMEX> miles you know uh timing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chains</ENAMEX> and and various other things but
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		all in all if you if you take it mileage uh based on what you spent over that life of the car
 	
 	
 		it's wonderful
 	
 	
 		relatively cheap
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so uh
 		you know i i so far i can't complain it's been a good car and and we're going we're like i say we'll try to keep it for a long time it's been paid off for several years
 	
 	
 		the that's that's nice to have no payments yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah and uh
 		the the only other thing is you know the the pickup <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX>'s nice but it's impractical for for traveling and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> so we'll get something that we can haul stuff in if we have to and then have it for you know trips and and everything
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		that's great you've really thought this out it sounds like i mean i'm sort of you know i sort of look around and go yeah that's a nice <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> that's a nice <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> but i haven't really
 	
 	
 		well nowadays it pays to shop because you're going to have to live with it for a while you know if you if you're paying for it for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three or four years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 		uh
 	
 	
 		uh that's a long time right there in itself and then you don't want to turn around and and you know the next time you buy a car it's going to be more expensive and uh you don't want to start another payment that's going to be up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">around four</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five hundred dollars</NUMEX> a month
 	
 	
 		to be paying for a car
 		that's true
 	
 	
 		so uh it it's it's crazy so
 	
 	
 		that's that that that's real true actually
 	
 	
 		but the little that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bonneville</ENAMEX> that you have that that uh that's probably a pretty good car
 	
 	
 		that's that's actually it's got um it's actually it's low on mileage given that it's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty two</NUMEX> it's only got seventy <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five thousand</NUMEX> on it and uh
 		or seventy <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> or whatever you know and it's it's in uh it's a funny coincidence that my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX> sold me the car
 		and she's up for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX> now  so she's out babysitting in the next room  sort of perfect coincidence it's a perfect time to be talking about that car um but yeah it's just it's just you know i have little problems here and there you know um stupid things start to go like the uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i can't open it it has electronic windows unfortunately electric windows and doors and the uh
 		and the passenger window is gone you know it doesn't open any more but i'm not going to fix it because i'm going to sell it in a year
 	
 	
 		yeah well you know uh things like that that go out you know if you replace them it's just so costly anyway
 	
 	
 		yeah it's it's it's seventy <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five dollars</NUMEX> for the motor alone
 		and then another seventy <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> to install it you know so that can that that's crazy or like the air conditioning went the air conditioning sort of blowing warm air so i went down to the you know my local mechanic and for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">forty dollars</NUMEX> they did an air conditioning check and they
 	
 	
 		it's crazy
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		went through everything i told them to put in a shot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Freon</ENAMEX> and they said yeah it needs a shot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Freon</ENAMEX> but then he came back and he said well the reason you're losing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Freon</ENAMEX> is because you have a leak in this condenser line and when i and that's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred</NUMEX> and fifty dollars to fix that and then while we're in there we have to change this this and this and you know and
 		so it would would would would have wound up costing me close to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">four hundred dollars</NUMEX> but he said look if you're selling the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> don't bother doing it all he said i'll give you a shot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Freon</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every now and then</TIMEX> and and you're you're fine you know so
 	
 	
 		well and your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> has what kind of car
 	
 	
 		she has an <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty seven</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">um Ferenza</ENAMEX> i it's an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oldsmobile</ENAMEX> yeah it's an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oldsmobile</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh Ferenza
 		yeah okay that's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pontiac</ENAMEX> okay or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Olds Firenza</ENAMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah no it's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Olds</ENAMEX> actually olds yeah that's actually a real good car i'm finding it's uh mechanically is very sound um
 		unfortunately the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> was rust proofed by a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rusty Jones</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		which i'm not sure if you've ever heard of or not but uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rusty Jones</ENAMEX> went out of business because their <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rust proofing</ENAMEX> wasn't very good
 	
 	
 		so now you've got some rust
 	
 	
 		and now i've got some i mean the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty two</NUMEX> has
 		no rust at all and the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty seven</NUMEX> has some pretty big rust spots on it so it's
 	
 	
 		that's terrible that's one that's one bad thing about living in an area where you have to put <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salt</ENAMEX> on the roads
 	
 	
 		so and
 		yeah actually we're we're looking forward to getting out of here
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		we're yeah in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> i'm done and then we're moving south or west
 		or southwest
 		
 		
 	