
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wayne</ENAMEX> i've uh feel very strongly about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> doing things with their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and making time available even sometimes when time isn't available how do you feel about it
 	
 	
 		well yeah i feel much the same way i've uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> right now one is <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two and a half</TIMEX> and one's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nine months</TIMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		that age of course everything you do they're trying to learn to do and so uh it's important for you to spend time doing the things that you want them to learn you know that that they need to learn at the age you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		reading and uh reading and playing nice with others and that sort of thing
 	
 	
 		yeah we went through this with our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and now with our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandchildren</ENAMEX> and i've always tried to do things with them uh
 		like when you're at the little league helping out even though i'm not a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">athlete</ENAMEX> myself i was able to help the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX> in in just controlling the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> if nothing else
 		and we've always uh oh tried to take our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and now now at this age our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandchildren</ENAMEX>
 		to see and do things that otherwise they might not be able to i think that's just part of their overall educational process is to get out and see and do things
 	
 	
 		right uh-huh
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah so it's uh we have uh lived several places around the the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> and we have where we've lived we've taken them to see and do things of interest and of historical significance in the area
 		like when we lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tennessee</ENAMEX> we we took them to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX> to see all the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">capitol and</ENAMEX> and things like that when they were small
 		and that just uh it helps i think the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> to when they're learning in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> to say well i've been there and i've seen that
 	
 	
 		right uh-huh
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah so uh that's the type
 	
 	
 		yeah it certainly does because uh you know the things in the books seem so dead to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and you know unless they've actually been there or whatever because i remember our family
 		well we went we went everywhere and uh
 		uh seeing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New England</ENAMEX> and uh being on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plymouth Rock</ENAMEX> and stuff like that was uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		really made the whole thing more uh visual and you could uh read the things in the history books and understand what they said when it was like we need food we need to raise food quickly because this this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">place</ENAMEX> gets very cold very soon
 	
 	
 		yes
 		yeah
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yeah we've uh
 		gone through that uh i remember my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> didn't do all those type things and so i made a special effort with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> to do things like that and even now with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandchildren</ENAMEX> i feel it's a very important thing to be done
 	
 	
 		right because if uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> don't look up to you or or can't can't feel they can spend time with you they're going to find someone else and uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know nowadays there's a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> out there that you don't want your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> to emulating or whatever
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah well i can remember <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the things i'm most proud of is uh when my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> was i think it was in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">sixth</NUMEX> grade
 		they had to write uh a little brief autobiography of themselves and about what they had done and what they wanted to do and
 		i was very proud when my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> wrote that he wanted to uh have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and be able to help coach little <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">league</ENAMEX> and do things like his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> had done with him
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		a real a real point of pride with me
 	
 	
 		yeah that is nice
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		excuse me we sound like we both have colds
 	
 	
 		yeah well it's um
 		well it's uh
 		<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">uh ten o'clock</TIMEX> here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Falls Church Virginia</ENAMEX> so that the only reason i'm home is because i'm home with a cold  and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> says well you need something to do talk to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> on the phone
 	
 	
 		oh oh
 		oh well you're kind
 		yeah well i'm sitting here on the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">ninth</NUMEX> floor of an office building on the north side of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas Texas</ENAMEX> so we're we're kind of far apart here
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		we've uh this is a very interesting program i i've heard about here on this and when i signed up for it it uh looked like it could be uh make a real contribution in in participating and uh
 	
 	
 		right yeah i'm uh electrical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineer</ENAMEX> by trade
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>  likewise we uh
 		we do some projects every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> and then we like to get support from uh other other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> as well so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah i'm an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">accountant</ENAMEX> presently working as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contractor</ENAMEX> liquidating a
 		failed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">savings and loan</ENAMEX>  so you know trying to work myself out of a job  but it's it's been an interesting uh roughly oh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nine months</TIMEX> here and uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 		oh
 	
 	
 		again this is our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">home</ENAMEX> area we've lived here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about seventeen years</TIMEX> and it's uh
 		we enjoy living here it's where we originally started out and we've lived up north for a while in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> and over in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tennessee</ENAMEX> so wound up back <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about two hundred miles</NUMEX> aware away from where we started out
 	
 	
 		yep
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well uh that's about all i can think to talk about right now it's been a pleasure talking with you
 	
 	
 		okay right bye-bye
 	
 	
 		thank you bye
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	