
 
     		
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well
 	
 	
 		well what kind of music did you all listen to
 	
 	
 		oh my goodness now see we think of classic rock that they you know have on all the easy listening <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX> now as our heart and soul i mean it was
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's a really good question because that was everything from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rolling Stones</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Beatles</ENAMEX> i mean we were there
 	
 	
 		no now well then you was in the uh
 		or i am sorry i am going to make you sound like you're eighty something
 	
 	
 		yeah i was
 		well i was i was in <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">seventh</NUMEX> grade when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Beatles</ENAMEX> came out i <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fourteen years old</TIMEX> Woodstock
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">okay Woodstock</ENAMEX>
 		what was yeah what was you doing during Woodstock
 	
 	
 		well i wanted to go i was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> and i guess i was close to eighteen or something i i it was like i think <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> between my uh
 		high <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and college somewhere around in there i can't quite remember <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> and um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		you would have had a ball
 	
 	
 		uh yeah
 	
 	
 		i i kind of liked would have liked to have been there
 	
 	
 		we couldn't we couldn't get it together to drive i mean you know we'd never driven outside of you know <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> miles out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> at that time and here we were all hep to go to Woodstock you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		don't you wish you'd been able to though
 	
 	
 		i really do you
 	
 	
 		oh that would have been such a great memory
 	
 	
 		it would have been incredible i i think of um you know all the social changes that were going on around that time
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and and the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixties</TIMEX> as being so <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">revolutionary</ENAMEX> in a lot of ways in terms of raising <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s consciousness everything from well i mean i remember we had the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Earth Day</ENAMEX> back then you know we got out of school at at uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX> and we celebrated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Earth Day</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		you went and planted a <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX> or something
 	
 	
 		yeah planted <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> and stuff and we didn't realize you know the implications of all that then and a lot of the stuff that goes on today
 	
 	
 		well
 		well growing up with
 		when i grew up it just wasn't
 		we did not have any causes
 	
 	
 		well
 	
 	
 		to me it didn't doesn't seem like we've got
 		much you know what i mean
 	
 	
 		well you do you'll you i mean there was there was no name to it it was everything that was started in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the sixties</TIMEX> you had you had to fight for racial equality
 	
 	
 		well i do remember demonstrations over busting
 	
 	
 		and busting themselves it was like just a continuum you know everything sort of had a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">seed</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the sixties</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s rights i mean things for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> were totally different for you by that time
 	
 	
 		yeah well right by the time i was born even now
 		you know women's rights uh we just
 	
 	
 		just assume
 	
 	
 		we are totally equal now there is not really a lot to fight for now i saw something on TV last night
 		on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Twenty Twenty</NUMEX> you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fathers</ENAMEX> or daddies now wait a minute daddies are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> too it is about a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> you know all right
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		going through divorces the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> will usually
 		uh give custody to the mother <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ninety seven</NUMEX> percent of the time because they go through the female and
 	
 	
 		yeah well we learned that from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Kramer versus Kramer</ENAMEX> didn't we
 	
 	
 		yeah  something like that but it does seem
 		you know
 	
 	
 		it seems unfair
 	
 	
 		yeah it really does
 	
 	
 		but it see <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> are coming into their own now too
 	
 	
 		yeah they are well i thought about that i thought well now <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> you know have to fight to be equal
 		and i think that's only right though really he one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> said the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> looked at him and said well now mister so and so he says i've
 		have never seen uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">calves</ENAMEX> follow a bull they always follow the heifer that is why i always he said that is why i always give custody to the mama
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and he said well he said does that mean you are going to shoot them if they break a leg and you know butcher them if they get fat he said my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are not cattle
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know but that that is the way most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> feel that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> should get custody
 	
 	
 		well are you married and do you have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah i am married and i've got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and and how does your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> respond to all the new social um changes
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> is not a conformist at all he is still back there in the seventies
 	
 	
 		well see bless his heart you know  um
 	
 	
 		well i mean he is still wearing bell bottoms jeans not bell bottoms but flared pants and
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and he well i do not like them but you know to him
 	
 	
 		they're going to be back in style <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">any day</TIMEX> now
 	
 	
 		yeah <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">any day</TIMEX> now  well he just you know he is he is his own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> he you know he does stay with it as far as music and stuff goes but he wears what clothes he wants to which we are both that way
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		if something is out of style i don't really care if i like it i'm gonna wear it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> is not a conformist at all
 	
 	
 		oh well see that that's the spirit of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixties</TIMEX> and whether we are talking about the rain forests i tell you you know the situation you have <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">right now and</TIMEX> and all of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generations</ENAMEX> is what to do with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> because both
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> have to work now
 	
 	
 		well uh we are trying to keep away from that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> works for the railroad we have got it real tight but i've got a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four month</TIMEX> old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> and i do not want to work i want to tend to her i want to raise my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 		that's
 		that's see that is your commitment you do not know what you are changing when you do something like that you don't understand the total commitment it takes to be a parent
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well
 		right well when he grew up he grew up with his we both grew up with single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		ah
 	
 	
 		and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so she had to work and you know i was raised by my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> and stuff and i can i can't see the difference but i know that it would have been better had mom been able to stay home with us
 	
 	
 		that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> that you could always count on being there
 	
 	
 		right
 		right and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> was the same way and we just
 		i want to raise my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> i do not want a day care or an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aunt</ENAMEX> or anybody else raising them
 	
 	
 		well
 	
 	
 		i want to be there to make sure that
 		well they need guidance and they do need parental guidance
 	
 	
 		they definitely do
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">four hours a day</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		they definitely do i
 	
 	
 		do you stay home with yours
 	
 	
 		uh well see i if i had some i would i i haven't i had an unfortunate thing happen and i'm you know and it is not going to happen that way but my my uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> are having <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX> right and left so i get to see the different ways that they
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		they raise them
 	
 	
 		um all raise them and and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> gal she started a business in her home and she she hired an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">au pair</ENAMEX> which is a college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> to come in and take care of her <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> while she works in the other end of the house
 	
 	
 		well but see now
 	
 	
 		and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> lives in with her you know i mean you know it is a family sort of unit sort of thing and the
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		okay sweetie let mommy talk
 	
 	
 		and so
 	
 	
 		well i think that's neat
 	
 	
 		so that is a different way and then my other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX> just you know tears her hair out and goes at it you know <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty four hours</TIMEX> a day watching both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> all the time and i think there is a point where you just have to get away
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and it's good for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> and it is good for you to develop you know your interest so you do not stop growing at the same time
 	
 	
 		um-hum well i know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> is really going through changes but now we're trying to go back to about the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixties</TIMEX> when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> you know when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> was staying at home
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		or that what do they call it the nuclear family yeah but uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		do you have any um do you have your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> or anybody around you that helps you
 	
 	
 		um well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kentucky</ENAMEX> now my my one of my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> is down here her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> happened to get a job at <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> they moved out here but well his family lives here and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> was in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> when i met him
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so we we've been all over  okay <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kyle</ENAMEX>   he sunburn in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen</ENAMEX> so i keep having to scratch his back
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh
 	
 	
 		the uh
 		i would love to get a business going out of my home
 		outside of i mean going
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		yeah i'd would work at home if i could
 	
 	
 		well that's
 		well see and and that is uh the sort of the thing of the nineties is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> working out of their own home
 	
 	
 		yeah that's the trend
 		yeah they are bringing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> i mean just i mean big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> into their homes bringing their computers home and working from there
 	
 	
 		right
 		and i think you know the more we try to you know shape that the more input we have into
 		what that whole system is going to look like because that's that's our choice now too that's that's our cause
 	
 	
 		well i think for i think one that would be uh
 		it's uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> could see their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> you know how hard they work
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		they would understand more when uh we first moved down here i was working i was working <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a twelve hour</TIMEX> shift
 		it was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four days</TIMEX> a week
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh oh my little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> just
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		he went wild you know i mean because
 		because he had been used to me
 	
 	
 		being there all the time yeah
 	
 	
 		being there all the time yeah
 		and he's just now well when i got pregnant i went ahead and quit work
 		and decided just to stay at home and it was costing too much at home than more at home than i was bringing in so
 	
 	
 		yeah see the the the economic situation on the whole thing and then uh well it's see we do have things that we're  concerned about here this generation i don't know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">social</ENAMEX> change is always going to go on but i think we have taken a big leap in the last you know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty thirty years</TIMEX> and um nothing is the same
 	
 	
 		no it seems like it's totally different of course
 		i do not have much to compare it to to me our causes don't seem as important as you all's were do you know what i mean
 	
 	
 		well
 		yeah but we we grew we passed them on to you you know i mean i said we passed them on to you i mean you know because it takes a lot of hard work it takes writing letters to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">congressmen</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		you you what
 		we passed them on to us
 	
 	
 		and you know just being very very politically astute about how to shape and mold the future and and u you know um did we make the right choices we do not know we will never know
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		i mean you know i i think we made a wrong choice when i look at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> yeah i think we made some big wrong choices and i think business got in the way i think the greed of the eighties got
 	
 	
 		okay yeah
 		
 		
 	