
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		okay well uh what's your opinion about capital punishment
 	
 	
 		well <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cathy i</ENAMEX> think that uh capital punishment certainly
 		has has a place in our society
 		um
 		maybe from the sense that
 		there are some things that
 		we just can't afford to have repeated uh even even in the remote chance of repetition
 	
 	
 		right i think i would agree with you on that too i i can't see any point in keeping someone who's obviously beyond any kind of rehabilitation uh keeping them you know paying for them to live in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and years
 		when you could probably just eliminate the problem
 		maybe spend the money on someone who could possibly be helped
 	
 	
 		that might be true um
 		um what i don't know is where do we draw the line
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh do we say that
 		everyone who commits murder in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> degree is liable for capital punishment if that's what the
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> decides is an appropriate punishment for their crime
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> or do we extend it
 		uh beyond that
 	
 	
 		uh-huh beyond murder or just beyond like first degree murder
 	
 	
 		well either you know
 		uh i have a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a nine year old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> and there are some crimes that could be committed against her that are not even considered capital crimes that
 		that i would consider basis for murder
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah well that really gets into into a sticky issue uh i could see that too i think there's probably things i could think of short of murder that someone i think someone would probably deserve to be killed for
 		but gosh and and who's going to decide which is how bad you know something that to you is really bad might not be quite so bad to me and
 		yeah it's gets into a pretty sticky issues
 	
 	
 		yes it does uh a lot of that has to do with
 		the cultures that we grew up in and what's termed acceptable and and uh
 		to what's allowable and and where are we
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh
 		you know if we were lived in a different <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> then murder is not so bad
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but over here where we're
 		promised the
 		civil liberties of pursuit life liberty and pursuit of happiness then taking that away
 		is a a heinous act
 	
 	
 		yeah in some eyes i think some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> give up that  i think some of what we consider rights are really more privileges than
 		think what most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> think of them as
 		i don't know what um <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>'s criteria for capital murder is do capital punishment is do you know are there some set guidelines like only under these circumstances
 	
 	
 		i don't know i believe it's uh at the discretion of the
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> or or jury
 	
 	
 		uh-huh i used to live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> and i know when they first reinstated capital punishment it was only um
 		if someone killed a police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> or someone committed rape and then murder those were the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only two</NUMEX> circumstances where you could
 		give someone the death penalty which i think is a little too limited
 	
 	
 		i tend to agree with you there
 		um
 		my belief is that
 		is that uh any crime that's
 		freely committed you know freedom of choice these these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> had a choice of committing this crime
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that involves the taking of another's life or the altering of someone's life
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		such as rape
 		deserves punishment by death
 		but then i'm also told that i'm a pretty harsh person
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah in general terms i'm not so harsh but then whenever i hear of a specific case you know where someone did something then it's it's like yeah put it to them  so i i think i probably tend to be a little bit harsh too as far as that goes
 		because yeah i think you're right that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> voluntarily gives up when they decide to commit that crime they voluntarily give up their right
 		to continue on with their happy life just because you know they they ruin someone else's life
 	
 	
 		oh i
 		i can see a difference between
 		a
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who goes out to rob a store
 		for food
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		than a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who
 		commits a crime to
 		uh either for the thrill of committing the crime or the thrill the feeling of power that they get from it or to
 		acquire <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> for some other i mean acquire funds for some other illegal activity
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know that <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> group of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> falls into the the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> that i say give up their rights the the first guy
 		i you know i just assumed that it was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> that that went out to rob a store for food
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		that to me is is a different set of circumstances where he
 		he deserves help instead of
 		uh the loss of life
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah he didn't go out with the intent of hurting someone else
 	
 	
 		
 
 		that's right or with the
 	
 	
 		or with no regard for someone else's
 		well being
 		what about uh like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teenagers</ENAMEX> that get involved in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gang</ENAMEX> and do a drive by shooting or something like that say fifteen <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixteen year old</TIMEX> would you
 		consider uh capital punishment for them
 	
 	
 		i think i would probably lower the age to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about fourteen</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		there's some and and i
 		certainly don't know myself but somebody needs to do a study
 		that says at what age
 		true and complete logical thought to include the the
 		consideration of of long term consequences
 	
 	
 		right yeah what age that they're accountable for their actions
 	
 	
 		begins
 		you know i i have an <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eighteen year old</TIMEX> and uh it well he's nineteen now
 		and i don't think that i saw it in him until maybe <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and i have an <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year old</TIMEX> and a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nine year old</TIMEX> and i don't don't see it in them yet but i'm i'm not sure where it begins
 	
 	
 		yeah i know that they are lowering the age of uh
 		whatever is considered a minor i think the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> certain <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are have been tried as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> who were a lot younger than they used to be like
 		i think i read about a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> that was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> that got mad at some playmates and went in and got a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> and just opened fire on them and they were trying to charge him as as a
 		
 		
 	