
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		do you y'all do you get together with family reunions or
 	
 	
 		yes we try to uh we have not in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">some years</TIMEX> now and i think we are going to try to have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this summer</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh that will be fun if you haven't done it in a while
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aunt</ENAMEX> is planning it
 	
 	
 		oh where is your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> from
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">uh Missouri</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">southwest</ENAMEX> part of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Missouri</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so you are going to have to go there
 	
 	
 		that will will be where it is uh if if she gets it planned i have been out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> so i do not know what she has been doing but uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		they are all getting very very old all my aunts and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncles</ENAMEX> so we need to see them soon
 	
 	
 		oh
 		yeah
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> is from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kentucky</ENAMEX> most of them is down there
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i have got an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncle</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisiana</ENAMEX> and another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right do you all get together often or
 	
 	
 		we did when i was growing up it was every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> we got together now my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> just passed away <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this last year</TIMEX> so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know she was the
 	
 	
 		i think as we get older it is difficult more difficult to uh
 		when all my aunts and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncles</ENAMEX> are in their eighties now so it is uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i have to uh i will probably have to take charge and do it one of these uh one of these
 		days
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but uh
 	
 	
 		well it
 	
 	
 		i still have elderly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> alive so uh it takes a lot of effort to either get everybody called or written and settle on a date you know that
 	
 	
 		it sure does
 	
 	
 		and if they are
 	
 	
 		well we in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kentucky</ENAMEX> it wasn't hard because everybody lives so close together we just did it word by mouth you know by word of mouth
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncle</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisiana</ENAMEX> he is the only one that
 		you know had to travel
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and now i have got a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		oh my gosh
 	
 	
 		we are just scattered all over the place so it is going to be hard this time but we have got a huge family
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		so the
 		yeah and we need to have more and more of them i hope i think i hope that is not a lost art that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> getting together as they do spread out all over the world
 	
 	
 		yeah because it is so fun i mean
 	
 	
 		yeah it is
 	
 	
 		
 
 		we my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> has got like thirteen <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> and sisters
 	
 	
 		oh i see
 	
 	
 		yeah she has got a huge family and every one of them have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and most of them you know have got kids
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		sure that makes a big crowd
 	
 	
 		yeah it we just we had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> baseball <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bleachers</ENAMEX> full of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and there are still <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about eight or six eight or ten</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> taking pictures
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		is that
 		is that right
 	
 	
 		yes and it was just the last time we had one it was so fun
 	
 	
 		that is wonderful i hope
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		well we need to have another one i hope my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aunt</ENAMEX> is successful as uh later well it is probably not going to be done because i have not heard from them i it was supposed to be this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX> so i don't imagine there is anything coming this is hardly almost <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah well i
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		we have always had ours in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> or something but it has away been the same <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> and there is nothing really special there only thing is it is big and it is open
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah that's
 		we have it usually at this uh at this one <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> because there is a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pavilion</ENAMEX> there in case it <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rains</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh you have to have it uh fairly <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early in the summer</TIMEX> or it is too hot up there
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Missouri</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Missouri</ENAMEX> yeah it is too muggy it is not it is just uh very humid and the old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> cannot take it anymore
 	
 	
 		well that was part of the problem with
 		well that was part of the problem with the ones we have now the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> would sneak off and we were just being <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and we found what we thought was just an old <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> hole so we was going swimming
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and like i said we was just <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stupid kids</ENAMEX> we was like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years old</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> came and caught us we had been  playing in the  sump it was
 		part of the sewage cleaning system
 	
 	
 		
 
 		isn't that great
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kyle</ENAMEX> don't  i have got a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four year</TIMEX> old
 	
 	
 		yeah well that keeps you busy yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah but if we could have gotten it by a lake or something i thought that would have been much better
 	
 	
 		yeah it would have been something for the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to to do but
 	
 	
 		yeah well they there was uh i am sorry there was uh i remember now there was like uh a baby pool just  about a foot deep
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yes i remember my little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> riding a bicycle through it we were all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> anyway
 		
  
 	
 	
 		every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> has all that going on i am sure
 		so
 	
 	
 		oh but i love it all the different <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">foods</ENAMEX> because that yeah
 	
 	
 		oh i do too that is the best part of it
 	
 	
 		that's the yeah
 	
 	
 		everybody bringing something for a potluck picnic and
 		oh grand yeah
 	
 	
 		so how long did you say it has been since you all had one
 	
 	
 		i do not know i think it has been uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four three or four years</TIMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> even uh since they have had it tried to get everybody together they are just spread out so much and
 		and we really need to uh no matter how what kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> they get
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i hope
 	
 	
 		well i have been married <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">almost five</NUMEX>
 		so i guess it has been <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven years</TIMEX> since we have had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and since then we've lost
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh well just our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> that is surprising
 	
 	
 		yeah well time flies so fast it may have been that that long since we have one it is hard to remember but i think it has been <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about four or five years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so uh
 		anyway i i hope both our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> get to have one soon
 	
 	
 		oh if i can ever get down to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kentucky</ENAMEX> it has been like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX> since i have been home
 	
 	
 		yeah it is difficult with little ones i know when we had had our
 	
 	
 		yeah that is the reason that is the reason i don't i would get on a bus <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">any day</TIMEX> by myself but i won't do it with the babies
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because uh i have got uh a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four month old</TIMEX> and a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four year</TIMEX> old
 	
 	
 		sure
 		oh Lord
 	
 	
 		so i am just starting
 		and i just quit too
 	
 	
 		oh i am telling you
 		that's uh
 	
 	
 		uh i won't be adding any more to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> reunion
 	
 	
 		no i hope
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		it i know it takes a lot of effort right with with that with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> little ones like that
 	
 	
 		yeah they are good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> though
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so uh i am not too upset
 		anyways i've enjoyed talking to you
 	
 	
 		enjoyed talking to you good luck in everything
 	
 	
 		all right all right you too bye-bye
 	
 	
 		bye-bye
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	