
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		okay so my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty and twenty four</TIMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> just moved
 		uh to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX> so he's married so course uh uh when when they're here when they lived here and i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> whose <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty</TIMEX> and we spend a lot of time together
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		not so much as you know  we're we both have everybody's busy but when my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> were younger
 		i was a single <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> and i spent most of my life with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> i did a did a lot things with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but uh yeah it's uh a i don't i i
 		i one thing that happened is when when my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> uh graduated from high school and he went off to college
 		then it it drastically changed uh before prior to that we had sit down dinners and we talked and we did a whole lot of things and then when he left
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> and i just kind of said well let's just kind of do what do our own thing and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know i i think that might i don't know i don't know you know it's been so long since i had little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> at home i'll i'll leave it up to you as to what's really going on these days
 	
 	
 		yeah well i <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of all i'd i admire you for i have a few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> who are single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> and i just don't know how <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> do it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		that's is a tremendous burden to be working and have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> to take care of
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		and i don't know how you did it but um i have a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six year old</TIMEX> that's well she's in <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> grade and then i have a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three and a half year old</TIMEX> and um
 		i have always been a big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocate</ENAMEX> of spending tons of time with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 		and um when i my <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> when she was born i had to work part-time for a while because we had to have the extra money
 		but when the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> one came along i was fortunate enough that i i quit and i've been able to stay home and um
 	
 	
 		oh so you're not working now great
 	
 	
 		no no i don't work yeah and so i'm one of those few old-fashioned moms  and we
 		uh i spend <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the whole day</TIMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tara</ENAMEX> and we go and do things and we read books and we play and you know it's just it's great and i did the same thing with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taylor</ENAMEX>
 		uh who's my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">first grader</ENAMEX> she's also a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> and uh i think i think i can tell a real difference um <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Taylor</ENAMEX> has excelled in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> like i just
 		i never imagined she would she's at the top of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> in everything even though she's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">almost two year</TIMEX> younger than almost all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> in her class
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		and i really feel like that um time i spent with her i mean she probably already had a lot uh
 		of it in her but you know we spent a whole lot of time together reading books and doing a lot of things i think it helped her to feel real good about herself and
 		feel like she could she could do it you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so it's it's been real rewarding for me anyway
 	
 	
 		right but you know if uh uh i know now that i can look back and and i think about how much
 		how much time i devoted to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and and
 		not necessarily but sacrificed a social life because i really did devote myself to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> basically i mean
 	
 	
 		oh i'm sure
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i mean i was i mean i did some things but i mean i really did but i have no regrets about that and i you know um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i can look back and it was so much fun being a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> with them and getting to do all the fun things that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know you get to do it that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> get to do and and that you wouldn't do by do you know with other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		so it's great fun i really envy you
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		this is a wonderful time of your life
 	
 	
 		well it is you know as a matter of fact i think i'm real bad about looking ahead and thinking oh i don't ever want them to  grow up and you know go away to college and all that kind of thing
 		but at least i'm really making the most of the time while they're little and um everything <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Taylor</ENAMEX> even attempts to do you know we go and watch her and
 		and support her and that was something my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> weren't able to do and i resented that because i would be in i was always in plays in high school and in all kinds of drama and they could never come and watch me and that just
 		it was so hard for me so i made a vow that when i had <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> no matter what they did i was going to be there you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and see them do it so it and like you said it's fun i really enjoy it
 	
 	
 		well i can remember my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> started working
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>  well course both of them worked but my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> started working when i i was third
 		the last the youngest and she started working when i went to <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> grade and i can remember
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		just a couple of few times that she would stay home and i i don't know if she was sick or just wanted to take <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> off or what but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		come home from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and you know every like you'd tell that she'd just mopped and she had you know <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> was cooking and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> smelled so good
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh i tell you what i'd take i don't know if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> who maybe <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> who have that everyday don't don't don't appreciate it as much as you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh it really was really was a special and i wished that she could have been home more it would have been greater because she was
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		because she worked she was always kind of high strung and you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		didn't have the time to spend with us individually so
 	
 	
 		right yeah
 	
 	
 		i think it's great if if uh if if you enjoy staying <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> with your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> while they're young and and can do it
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		that's great i wish i could stay home now
 	
 	
 		yeah i know well i feel i feel really thankful that i can i mean we have had to really lower our standard of living you know we have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> who have beautiful <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> and we have a very small old house
 		but i just to me that's not important because i feel like we'll have plenty of time to get us a nice <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">some day</TIMEX>  and i won't have these you know these little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> all my life so
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		um i just i have been willing to make the sacrifices and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> has too and so it's not been a problem for us
 	
 	
 		well and and uh so you probably have a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> who have small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> do you do you find the the trend is uh
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		away from what you're doing or that they're not spending that much time with them put them off with
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sitters</ENAMEX> and how about
 	
 	
 		well it's interesting we're real involved with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church group</ENAMEX> and so most of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> are uh church <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and they're the majority of them do stay home uh almost all of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> i can call any time of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX> and they're home
 		but um the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> that i've kept in contact with from you know when i did work and they're still working moms you know uh that
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		i feel like i real big uh difference in opinion with some of them because some of them work just because they enjoy working you know they they don't really have to work they just want to they like to get out and
 		they don't want to be with their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all day</TIMEX>  and and that's hard for me because to me they're giving up something so precious you know and um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so any time we talk get on that topic i have to be real careful because i'm afraid i'll say something to offend them
 		but um most of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> do stay home so that it's kind of nice we we have a big support <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> around here
 	
 	
 		well that's great
 	
 	
 		yeah it is i don't know how long everybody will be able to afford to keep doing it  but if
 	
 	
 		well
 	
 	
 		i guess you just get used to you know living however you have to live to
 	
 	
 		well i meant you know i meant
 		if you don't ever have to go to work and you and you're you're happy you know even if your
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> all the way through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">high school</ENAMEX> and then it doesn't mean you have to go back to work
 	
 	
 		right yeah
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		yeah well i intend to uh i think when they're both in school i may i have a degree to teach and um i've never used it because i was pregnant when i graduated from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> and i've always had you know been home with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> or worked part-time
 		but um i might go into like substitute teaching or something because
 	
 	
 		okay the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> are at least to be home you know
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah and i can choose they say as a substitute you can tell them <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the days</TIMEX> that you're interested and you know the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> you're not you don't have to so
 	
 	
 		that way uh maybe then then you can find out if you're really happy doing that if you want to do it full time later on
 	
 	
 		right yeah because i have a feeling i'm not going to like it  when i did my uh student teaching i oh i hated it
 	
 	
 		so that's good
 	
 	
 		i said i don't know why i majored in uh elementary education and here i'm about to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduate</ENAMEX> and i don't even like this
 	
 	
 		well maybe now that you've had your own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> you'll like to be around little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> or have a little little better tolerance
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		yeah it'll probably make a whole difference and plus i didn't feel well at the time i was pregnant and i was real sick and
 	
 	
 		that'd be tough yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah i and you just don't feel like being around all these little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> when you are just sick to your stomach
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but anyway it's been nice talking to you
 	
 	
 		
 
 		nice talking to you and maybe i'll talk to you again okay bye-bye
 	
 	
 		and uh thanks for calling bye bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	