
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		um i guess my feelings are that uh we almost have a universal health care system uh to a great degree except that now i read where we've left out about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four million</NUMEX> people
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and um i don't know exactly how we're gonna cover many of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> because i'm sure that some of them uh don't uh don't have the wherewithal to do it themselves so uh i i have a feeling since i have
 		just about as good a health care coverage that anybody can get that this uh then becomes an obligation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> because it's gonna become an obligation of either <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> local or federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> anyway
 	
 	
 		yeah because when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> can't pay they end up going to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clinics</ENAMEX> or you know to public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> and that kind of thing and you know
 	
 	
 		well it seems to me that that i'm paying anyway because when i go or my insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carrier</ENAMEX> anyway when i pay something the bills seem inordinately high
 	
 	
 		oh definitely
 	
 	
 		and the reason that they're inordinately high is because that has to cover the costs for the indigent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who apparently don't have the money or the wherewithal to do that
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		would seem to spread it out a little better if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> who
 		uh employ these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and pay them uh you know subminimum wages or whatever were asked to share to share their fair burden of this too just as my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employer</ENAMEX> is and myself i guess
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah yeah yeah that sounds like a good idea my only <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> is what happens when you turn things over to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> i don't know do we wind up with more red tape and more problems so yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		well
 		well who who else is gonna do this then
 		i mean it's worked successfully in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> i've heard all these stories about i travel extensively
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and spend uh maybe <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> and i find that the health care programs there
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> are administered with uh at least people i talk to
 		with uh a great deal of integrity and uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't seem to be reluctant to use them to any degree as a matter of fact if i'm injured or
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		have an emergency when i'm say in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> uh that i'm automatically taken care of i mean i don't even have to pay
 	
 	
 		wow yeah well i think part of the the
 		tremendous benefit of that is that there's so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who wait now because they don't have the money until you know they have no preventative measures because
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> um you know just go on and on and on i mean so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't even get prenatal care or and it just extends with if if it what what would be a minor problem to deal with if they had a help available early on becomes just this horrendous
 		you know burden on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX> they're saying now that one out of every <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> born in in public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> is addicted to crack well you know
 	
 	
 		well i uh uh i i i know it i have a solution you see uh my my solution even though i'm rapidly approaching the uh
 		the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age</TIMEX> when i'll qualify for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX> i i my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> both uh uh well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s not living but my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> is
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they are um of of an advanced <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and when i see the money that's poured down the down the drain on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX> i mean the absolute uncontrollable situation that we find ourselves in and the extraordinary amounts
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i know that because those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> vote i mean they're the ones who get out and vote that's what's robbing a poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> of the prenatal prenatal care the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> aren't getting the proper care that they need and nutrition i think
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		and we're spending on these useless many times useless and inordinately complex unnecessary tests in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> for older people
 	
 	
 		oh it's just unbelievable how much you go through when i just had a problem with my neck and they ended up doing a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">seven hundred dollar</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CAT</ENAMEX> scan and i mean a chiropractor got it in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time it was just strange
 	
 	
 		that's right i mean it does seem like we're the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the the now</TIMEX> i noticed just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> that that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> will be based payments will be based not uh just on cost but on cost effectiveness so i guess
 	
 	
 		oh well that should help
 	
 	
 		well i don't know uh we'll see how that goes i think that was just a regulation that was up for comment but we'll see what happens
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh i see oh gosh
 	
 	
 		well listen uh i think i've i've exhausted my uh self on at least i've blown off steam of the way i feel about it
 	
 	
 		okay well  okay thank you bye-bye
 	
 	
 		okay see you next time bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	