
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">okay Ray</ENAMEX> what do you think about taxes
 	
 	
 		okay
 		um
 		too high obviously
 	
 	
 		um-hum yeah i agree
 	
 	
 		but my
 		property taxes have been going up repeatedly
 		uh over the last uh
 		well this is going to be the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">seventh</NUMEX> year in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a row</TIMEX> that they've increased
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		so
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> and they're always saying if you know if they don't raise taxes then they're going to have to lay off on uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> they're going to have to lay of uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">firemen</ENAMEX> they're going to have to lay off the police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">hum-um</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but yet they don't talk anything about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> about cutting back on that end of it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they just they've they're in the middle of an expose now on
 		the state and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">City of Providence</ENAMEX>
 		uh public works departments
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh yeah</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they've had TV cameras going around uh they wait at
 		some of the yards
 		and they follow the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trucks</ENAMEX> as they come out uh at random
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		just to see what they do during the course of the day
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and there's not much that's going on i'll tell you i mean they're going to gin mills and and spending <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">half</NUMEX> a day in there drinking or they're going to other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> and doing work
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh so you've got you have you have a little graft and corruption huh
 	
 	
 		uh i think that's
 		in any
 		city or town i don't think there's any that are free from graft and corruption
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh if they could eliminate something like that
 	
 	
 		um
 		yeah you know the waste you know that's i think uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i i think that's a big problem uh uh i don't do you think you get some good services for your taxes do you have a good school district do you have
 	
 	
 		um
 		i thought we always did i grew up in a town it was it's a small town
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it's in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rhode Island</ENAMEX> actually i live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rhode Island</ENAMEX> i work in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 		but
 		about uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six seven months ago</TIMEX> they had a breakdown of all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school systems</ENAMEX> and
 		how many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> actually
 		once they once they get into the school system how many actually graduate
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i was kind of shocked at the amount of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dropout</ENAMEX> in our town
 	
 	
 		yeah around fifty percent
 	
 	
 		uh not quite
 		but
 		it was up there it was the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">forty percentile</NUMEX> range
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah that's that's pretty much i think nationwide it's
 		you know the average is about seventy <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> percent uh complete school you know <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty five</TIMEX> percent dropout rate throughout the country
 	
 	
 		yeah that's
 	
 	
 		for school districts i'm not sure how they figure that out if they do per pupil or if they look at just averages per school district and things like that
 		but some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> i i don't know see i i live in a small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX>  and um
 		we don't pay much in taxes i don't uh this sets
 		this is a farming <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX> control your property taxes basically and and in a sense you services
 		we have uh probably what's considered the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> worst
 		maybe the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> worst school district in uh
 		in the in the state
 		other than the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore</ENAMEX> itself probably you know which is always i guess a low is a low streak so actually i think for the return on my taxes for my for my
 		my uh state taxes that go to my school district and my services or whatever i think i get a pretty good return
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but my employment tax you know the federal i don't think i get a good federal
 		return at all i think locally i think property taxes on my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> were twelve <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">hundred dollars</NUMEX>
 		and that was that included state and local taxes so that was school district and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">snow plowing</ENAMEX> which isn't probably anything like that you have and that included my <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> and sewer
 		um but i didn't think that was too bad
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah  <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX> are right now they're <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">two thousand dollars</NUMEX> just a little over <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two thousand</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh-huh do you own a lot of property just a or a small lot
 	
 	
 		no uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a third</NUMEX> of an acre
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh it's a colonial <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> that we have it's a saltbox it's uh twelve years old
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		the uh
 		plus the plus the personal property tax we get taxed on our automobiles
 	
 	
 		oh do you
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		see we don't do that
 	
 	
 		and then the the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> also has a fire tax
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so we get a fire tax added to
 	
 	
 		the uh everything on top of that
 	
 	
 		yep
 		and it's the bulk of it's going for the school system
 	
 	
 		yeah see i i
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but we had uh
 		when i when i got out of school i i went up and i worked in a
 		in a missile <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> up in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Buffalo</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		and up there
 		they had like all our fire <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">departments</ENAMEX> were volunteers
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		they had uh the best of equipment and and the best of training a
 		and it didn't really
 	
 	
 		you mean you have a full-time fire department
 	
 	
 		no full-time
 	
 	
 		is that what you have now though in your town
 	
 	
 		yes yes we've got all full-time fire departments
 	
 	
 		oh
 		how many about how my goodness see that's see that's down here um  being a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of we have we have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a couple</NUMEX> full-time <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">firemen</ENAMEX> but basically
 		you know they well train the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> and they run the show and they live in the firehouse and you know and then most everybody else is volunteer
 	
 	
 		oh okay and then you have call
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so there's like a core of like each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">station</ENAMEX> has like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two or four</NUMEX> full-time then everybody else is a volunteer
 	
 	
 		yeah we got volunteer i mean uh we used to have volunteer up here
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and now they're all paid
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		which is you know i don't know we can
 		there's a lot of things that can be done because federal taxes are out of sight because of
 	
 	
 		yeah oh that just federal taxes just
 		more and more and more and less and less services you know
 	
 	
 		that's it they just keep
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they don't cut anything
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and it just feeds on itself and i don't think there's anything that anyone ca n do anymore
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's just grown to such proportions
 	
 	
 		yeah such it's just out of hand i agree you know the the whole idea like around here um
 		you know after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Desert Storm</ENAMEX> or whatever we have a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> here that feeds one of the military contracts that should be cut you know that they advised on cutting
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		but because of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Desert Storm</ENAMEX> now they said well we can't cut it so they put it back in action now granted everybody around here was happy because it keeps <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two or three hundred</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> employed
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but you know if we don't cut some of these nationwide you know some of these expenses just have to be cut if we don't need such a large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> and we don't need if the military comes out and says we don't need all these planes
 		then why does <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> say tough take them anyway
 		you know
 	
 	
 		well it's like the
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">tanks</ENAMEX> now everyone's after the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">tanks</ENAMEX> they're the you know like the the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mach One</ENAMEX> is it the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Mach One Abrams</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um i don't know how much it costs let's let's round figure just say <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a million dollars</NUMEX>
 		now for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a million dollars</NUMEX>
 		you can produce probably
 		a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">thousand handheld</NUMEX> antitank weapons
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">rockets</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and you give them to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a thousand</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peasants</ENAMEX>
 		you don't even have to train them
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and out of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of those <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands one</NUMEX> of them is going to hit now you take out <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a million dollar</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tank</ENAMEX> with a with a
 		you know
 	
 	
 		with a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one thousand</NUMEX> dollar antitank weapon
 	
 	
 		right but they're but they're still going with the with the mechanized  it's like the it's like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the old days</TIMEX> when they had the cavalry they didn't want to give up their <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horses</ENAMEX> to go for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Jeeps</ENAMEX> or whatever they were doing then
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 		and you know <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a million dollars</NUMEX> do you know how many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that would feed and clothe and get off the welfare rolls and get and keep in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and you know if we  uh i just
 	
 	
 		
 
 		right
 		yep
 		and
 	
 	
 		in some ways i just don't
 	
 	
 		you talk to them and you talk to like the big aircraft <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> and all they say well if they didn't spend the money and they didn't then they're overruns and if didn't cost <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a hundred dollars</NUMEX> for a hammer uh you would put a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> out of work
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you put out of work you could you could
 		rechannel their energies into making a rapid transit system in this country
 	
 	
 		that's right oh i agree with you a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundred</NUMEX> percent you know our direction has really
 		you know solar energy
 		uh you know there's been some recent great discoveries in solar energy surprisingly because there's there's no money invested in it
 	
 	
 		that's right
 		no um in fact in fact <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> just announced some breakthroughs in solar energy
 	
 	
 		yeah a big thing
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know some flex
 	
 	
 		a flexible solar material that it can be woven over top of something it could be it could be put on the top of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">airplanes</ENAMEX> to help power the plane
 	
 	
 		yep
 		yep
 		yep
 	
 	
 		you know it uh it just it could be put on the top of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">automobiles</ENAMEX> to
 	
 	
 		it's being channeled into special action <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> by special action <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> and they just keep the taxes keep going
 	
 	
 		right
 		uh they just keep yeah it that just
 	
 	
 		just for those just for those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> and we've got like the the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Groton Connecticut</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		where they make the subs
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and we've got a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">division</ENAMEX> in uh in uh Quansett
 		that does it that does the same thing
 		so when they announced the contract up here for that latest
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">hum-um</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">uh</ENAMEX> sub i guess uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Newport News</ENAMEX>
 		said they were going to sue the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> because of you know blah blah this and blah blah that whatever it was but it's generating jobs up here for us but it's really it's really not if you look at the whole you know it's generating jobs for a few people
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		if they channeled their energies if they go back to like when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roosevelt</ENAMEX> put put in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C C C</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camps</ENAMEX> and they built border ways for the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">reservoirs</ENAMEX> and you know <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">highways</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridges</ENAMEX> and yeah um
 	
 	
 		right
 		
 
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">highways</ENAMEX>
 		see that's a big problem we have um i'm originally from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX> and the biggest problem we have in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX> is that almost every bridge
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		that in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX> was built during the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eisenhower</ENAMEX> administration
 		uh within was in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City of Pittsburgh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		is that right
 	
 	
 		and there are yeah because see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">they Eisenhower</ENAMEX> put through money for uh though it probably didn't affect <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> it went the uh a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">highway</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX> west
 	
 	
 		was it
 		was it funded by by special bonds or
 	
 	
 		i'm not sure what it was but it was uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eisenhower</ENAMEX> i guess thought that you should be able to move tanks across the country
 		
 		
 	