
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		do you know something about how to take care of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah i was just wondering how did this get on my list  how how did this subject get on my list oh well i'm not sure um
 	
 	
 		it's what
 		i i don't know i've got mine
 	
 	
 		well uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are grown now but i used care child care services uh for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a number of years</TIMEX> and i
 		i don't know if i had it to do it over again maybe i would be a little more selective and really you know find out more about them i think the main thing was that i needed someone to take care of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and i and i generally used some place that was either
 		you know uh close to where i lived or close to where i worked and i really never had any had any real problems and i always felt like that they did a good job and um but i don't have small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> now so
 		uh i don't know if it would be different now you know i hear i hear i know a lot of uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> or uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that i work with and they are you know putting their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in different places
 	
 	
 		well yeah i i don't have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> yet um i won't for a couple uh for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at least two or three years</TIMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> is planning on probably taking care of them at that point um
 	
 	
 		um
 		
 
 		so you
 		yeah uh i suppose uh depends it depends on what kind of program they have especially for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer summer</TIMEX> programs
 		um
 		whether or not you know a lot of it is uh when they're in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and you know their after school thing you'd hope that they would have time for studying but most of the time they don't they just play
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but uh i think Summer time i'll i i know i was talking to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> she's just changing her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> to a different uh
 		child care <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Summer</ENAMEX> because they have so much more structured time and they offer different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classes</ENAMEX> like her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>'s going to be taking gymnastics and she said if she had left her where that she was
 		uh previously that a lot of time would you know just be free time for them to do whatever they wanted do and a lot of times they get bored so
 	
 	
 		that's actually yeah what i've been i'm thinking of the child care <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> because they have like licensing procedures and
 		and stuff like that that seems to me you know good and i mean it is a state license to seemingly more often than not that means that they're good and they have lots of activities and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who know how to take care of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and some
 	
 	
 		and i guess the ratio of of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> you know would be something to consider uh especially if they're little bitty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> that would be a i would i i would hate to leave an uh a real small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh before say before
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three or four years old</TIMEX> anything anyone younger younger than that i'd just kind of feel kind of uncomfortable about leaving the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> but
 	
 	
 		with somebody else yeah oh i agree
 	
 	
 		yeah but i did it so i mean but but i look back on some of the things that i did with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and i shudder
 	
 	
 		and
 		i wonder actually i wonder about costs because most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i know who who have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> you know uh
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> doesn't work a part of the time you know only works part time and takes care of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> part time and then it turns out that that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s salary just winds up going to paying
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who who who take care of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's true that's true
 	
 	
 		you know that which which amazes me um i i you know it never occurred to me how expensive that sort of thing can be
 	
 	
 		so basically i think that that when they do that that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> really feels a need to get out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and you know even if their the money is going mostly to child care they're not really having much to take home
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it's something a filling fulfilling another another need i suppose than staying <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> with with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> all the time but that's a tough deal to do too too you know but uh it'd be nice to
 		to work you know
 		i don't know i don't know a good solution to that but but it's it's tough to be i started i started to say stuck at home with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> all the time and never getting out that that's just probably not a real good way to put it
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 		yeah that
 	
 	
 		but some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you know they their their life and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> can be a full time job and you don't have time for anything else so you
 		so i would say maybe you know a day or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> to get out to go do something else not necessarily go back to work or something but
 		i don't know
 	
 	
 		yeah i don't i don't you know i just yeah it it just strange because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> do i mean in that sense it probably is pretty good to go out and just who cares if it if if all your salary goes to pay somebody
 		you sort of get away for a while too we have i don't i don't um it's strange it's funny that i should get this particular we should be on this topic now because uh because we have even though we have no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> we have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> staying with us
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">um for the for the for the</ENAMEX> for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX> and they have a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a six year old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> and a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three month</TIMEX> old son
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		so i'm just sort of seeing what all the hassles are you know of you know like <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX> we we we the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six year old</TIMEX> decided he wanted to go camping in the back yard
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so we pitched a tent in the dark yard actually and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> and
 		and the little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> and i all went out and had you know a a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>'s a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX>' night out
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		in the back yard and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about quarter</NUMEX> of one he woke up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> crying and he couldn't sleep and this and that i mean we we wanted to bring him inside
 		so when about a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one o'clock in the morning</TIMEX> we all got up and sort of wandered inside so i'm think all the benefits of taking care of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> or all the fun part of taking care of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> i guess
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah i tell you it's uh
 		yeah maybe it's something before you start having <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> you know maybe there's a lot of stuff but but if if
 		you'll never have them if you start  doing all that get too logical about it
 		but it's great it's great having <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and then
 		uh yeah i think everybody ought to ought to try it
 	
 	
 		yeah we plan on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of years</TIMEX> and i just like it's just like child care will become very important to my life then
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah she'll probably she'll probably spend a lot more time finding the right place uh
 	
 	
 		you know
 	
 	
 		i don't know i i tend to think if they're licensed then they're you know
 		i don't know i you know you you can feel you can get a feel from it too if your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> is too small you can't but if you if they're old enough to to know you know they'll they'll let you know if they're unhappy or if or if someone isn't treating them well or
 	
 	
 		yeah that that that that's probably true although i i don't like you say i don't know if i'd put a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> there who's less than you know uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years old</TIMEX> or something
 	
 	
 		i'll tell you one thing is that my of course i'm i'm a single <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> and so i guess and um
 		my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> was two
 		and i had uh they had to go in child care
 		but uh but i think they were more uh well i uh
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> who had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> and she did not work and she
 		and she had a real difficult time when the when time for them to go to school they did not uh want to leave her and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> who were so used to being out and
 		uh learning how to get along with other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and taking directions and stuff like that they just went very smoothly off into school you know without a problem so
 		i think even if you don't leave them full time but have them you know preschool or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s day out or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">couple</NUMEX> things <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of days a week</TIMEX> or something like that i think it's always good
 	
 	
 		yeah probably just to make <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and and stuff like that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah i if it's just like i say this is a very foreign topic for me so
 	
 	
 		so
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of those things i have to learn about i do i work with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> a lot
 	
 	
 		you do
 	
 	
 		i i i do work with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> a lot i uh i
 		i do uh um i teach a karate class <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twice a week</TIMEX> with with with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh what age
 	
 	
 		um they're <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> actually there's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> at i work mostly with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> and then <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> to twelve i i'm i'm the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX>  so i i help out in this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> and uh
 		and it's really um weird because i'm not you know the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> when i <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> started doing it i i can
 		put it this way it it it's helped me gain lots of respect for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who can work with lots large numbers of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because when i <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> started like i had no idea how to how to handle a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five five year</TIMEX> old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>
 		with especially when there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> of the m floating around and you're supposed to be running around teaching them things and
 	
 	
 		um do they pay have uh their attention span is it do do you have a hard time holding their attention
 	
 	
 		of course
 		uh i i do but i'm finding there's there's uh another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> there who has good he has got absolutely no training from what i know but he's just wonderful with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and he seems to know how to hold their attention you know he keeps them
 		he does lots of you know he's he's he's fast moving with them they'll do this exercise they'll do that they'll do this they'll do that he keeps them moving quick enough that you know when they stop losing attention they start you know they're the all of a sudden they're switched
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and you know there're a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> in there who actually have um
 		who i think have attention deficit disorders or they have very very low attention and those are harder to work with but i you know but i i i i uh the regular ones you know the normal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> you can just let them go a little bit and
 		and and he sort of he's real good at keeping them in line i'm learning from him how to do these sort of things just just by watching him
 	
 	
 		did you say uh your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">karate class</ENAMEX> is all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> or mixed
 	
 	
 		no it's it's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> and girls
 		it it it it's mixed there are uh there are um more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> but there are a number of number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> in there who actually uh do some good stuff and beat up a lot of the little girls i mean i mean a lot of the little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> too
 	
 	
 		is that right
 		
 
 		why why would a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> want their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> to take karate or is it the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> wants to take it uh
 	
 	
 		um in some case actually a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> send their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> or just bring their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> because
 		because of the sort of discipline you know and it it's not we don't you know say get down and do <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred</NUMEX> push ups for me now you little guy but um it teaches we we we focus very highly on you know on on on issues of respect and self-discipline
 		and self-confidence we have a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students kids</ENAMEX> who come in very shy you know and unsure of themselves and and you can see them come you know week by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX> that they come more and more out of their <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">shells</ENAMEX> and start to become you know more sociable and more sure of themselves instead of more sure footed
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		you know um and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> love it actually they find you know we we we there are rules like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> aren't allowed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> have to bring their report card in every after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every quarter</TIMEX> or whenever or whenever they get their report cards they have to bring them in to make sure that they're keeping up with their grades
 		
 		
 	