
 
     		
 	
 		yes what what major changes have affected your life
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well i think that uh women <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> working is the one that really affects me most strongly right now
 		um
 	
 	
 		you mean yourself or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in general
 	
 	
 		well <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in general and and also myself but um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it used to not really really make a difference to me
 		um or at least i didn't think so but my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> worked and i kind of now wish that that she hadn't that uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that she had um stayed home and right now i'm kind of stuck because i'd like to have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> but i'm not ready to do that because when i do have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> i want to stay home
 		so i'm having to uh try to figure out a way
 		to be able to do that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and in in our society right now that's really something that's that's um
 		not respected and it's not
 		it's not um
 		it's it's not easy to do at all i mean there's a great deal of sacrifice that has to be made on the part of a family if the if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> is going to actually be a mother
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		that's interesting because that relates to the thing that that strikes me the most and i'm sure you've you've labeled the cause because what strikes me the most in the changes in society is the way <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> behave
 	
 	
 		um-hum i think that that they're  well they have to be related
 	
 	
 		and
 		that's right that's right and you know i mean i was thinking it just you know my complaint would would be um that i think that
 		you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> in the neighborhood run wild and they they destroy property and they you know steal each other's toys and stuff and there's just no respect for for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> or property
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i guess you know when you stop to think of it these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> have probably been deprived of a lot of attention that they've needed all their lives
 	
 	
 		um-hum  i think that that's probably true
 	
 	
 		oh scary
 	
 	
 		i just wish there was a way i know that in in you know in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sweden</ENAMEX>
 		what they have there it's really their medical plan but it also deals with this subject because if a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> um
 		is working and i think even if she's not and has a child the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> subsidizes her to stay home and raise the child
 	
 	
 		uh
 		but for how many years
 	
 	
 		i don't i don't know until it and um i'm sure until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at least school age</TIMEX> and maybe longer and what this does is
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh that's great
 	
 	
 		it allows the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> to subsidize her to be the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> rather than to subsidize child care
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		to raise the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> for her
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and i think that that's a real a much much more viable solution really
 	
 	
 		um-hum no i agree <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred</NUMEX> percent
 		a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundred</NUMEX> percent i guess i was lucky because i was teaching and so i was able to just go to a class and teach when my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> was little and so i'd be gone you know <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an hour and fifteen minutes</TIMEX> or something at a stretch
 	
 	
 		oh yeah that's great
 	
 	
 		and then yeah very soon he was old enough to just go and sort of stay in my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> and you know nobody seemed to have a big problem with that so that's an interesting issue though
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um yeah
 	
 	
 		um
 		goodness what else
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		oh there's been so many how do you just you know
 	
 	
 		
 
 		right i've actually another one that i a question i would have is i guess i'm
 		being you know beyond the age of thinking of this this problem
 		i had an argument recently with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> i think it was about the need for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> to work but i think you put your finger on it when you said that they're not respected if they don't work because it seems to me that
 		a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> i know are doing very uh menial jobs in a certain sense certainly financially
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i mean when i see the amount of clothes that they buy and and how much it costs them to buy fast food on the way home
 	
 	
 		yeah um-hum
 	
 	
 		i'm sure that they're not making quote making money for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> on this
 	
 	
 		yeah really
 	
 	
 		and and probably you're right
 	
 	
 		i don't see how they could be especially not if they have to pay for child care
 	
 	
 		well no even <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> that don't have child care i mean you know when i think of this one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> who makes probably twenty <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">thousand dollars</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> and i'm sure she spends at least that in clothes plus you know fast food <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> and out to lunch <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		um-hum you're probably right if she sat down and looked at it she'd be like God what am i doing this for you know
 	
 	
 		and
 		exactly and i mean you know even though they don't have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> they they have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> and you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> would certainly like a lot more attention and and she wouldn't have to hire somebody to clean the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		do the gardening and so i i guess you're right it's it's our society demands <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> to work if they're going to be respected
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		really sad
 	
 	
 		yeah religion has changed too
 	
 	
 		oh that's true
 	
 	
 		
  
 		um
 		uh uh some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> now it seems like are turning back toward actually trying to find out what they're in it for instead of just um
 		it it's it some places still it seems like it's a social club
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know it's just a place to go to visit uh to wear your nice clothes and and to sit around and talk but um
 		i think a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are really you know searching now to find find out you know who they are and who God is and what all that really means now
 	
 	
 		um-hum so that might be of a positive change in society
 	
 	
 		yeah well it's it's um
 		it's beginning i think
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		i guess i haven't seen that as much in this area although every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> and then you hear about it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 		but among you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i know i don't see a great you know there are those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who have have had serious questions all along and you know are sort of pursuing it but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX> here are growing leaps and bounds and i thought it was more because of the
 		the very transient nature of the area and that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were going basically just as you said as a social to meet <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but um it's hard to judge
 		there are a lot of things changing i suppose
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		just you know the whole the whole environment i find
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 		sort of you know i wonder with with all our <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemicals</ENAMEX> and and that and and the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">foods</ENAMEX> we eat and you know young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that i know are getting very serious diseases and
 	
 	
 		oh yes well i guess that's always happened  maybe not as much as now but
 	
 	
 		you
 		probably
 		well it's just it's maybe it's more unusual now when you know somebody quite young gets certain kinds of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> and in the past maybe the same percentage got them but we didn't know it or
 		i don't know
 		well i guess we've sort of run dry a little bit  it was nice talking to you okay bye-bye
 	
 	
 		okay
 		nice to talk to you
 		bye-bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	