
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		uh do you work
 	
 	
 		yes i do
 	
 	
 		what do you do
 	
 	
 		uh i'm a data <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> at a manufacturing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that makes landing gear
 	
 	
 		oh well do they have good job benefits
 	
 	
 		yes they do very good uh comparable i used to work for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> and i used to work for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Martin Marietta</ENAMEX> and they are comparable to them um as good or better
 	
 	
 		huh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		what do do you work
 	
 	
 		no i don't
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		uh i said my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> works on the railroad they've got
 		a lot of benefits but it's expensive
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		this uh the insurance is a kick in the tail every month
 		
 
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well i uh my insurance is is very reasonable where i work and course the
 	
 	
 		it would
 		well the insurance is good we only have to pay like a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">hundred dollar</NUMEX> deductible per year it's just it's uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's like a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">hundred dollars</NUMEX> a month
 	
 	
 		oh is it really
 	
 	
 		yeah well i mean well that's just
 	
 	
 		well i i chose an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMO</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX> only runs <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five dollars</NUMEX> a uh <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five dollars</NUMEX> a month
 	
 	
 		well this is uh like retirement benefits and it's a bunch of different benefits in one it's not just
 	
 	
 		oh i see
 	
 	
 		it's not just medical insurance
 	
 	
 		okay well i pay <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five dollars</NUMEX> a month for my medical and then we have a retirement uh
 		benefits package a profit sharing type of thing they match our uh we can put in up to fifteen percent and they'll match uh sixteen <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">six percent</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one hundred</TIMEX> percent you know so that is that's better than most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> do
 	
 	
 		that's great
 		yeah that's good
 	
 	
 		plus plus they you know we have bonds we have a credit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX> it's a fairly it's not a real large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> well it is it's part of a large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> it's a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">subsidiary</ENAMEX> of a large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		whoops i'm sorry
 	
 	
 		we have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> different that's my call's waiting they'll just have to call back uh we have uh
 		uh we're part of a
 	
 	
 		i'm sorry
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> in  we have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX> and this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> here and uh so we have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about five hundred</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> at each place
 	
 	
 		they do
 	
 	
 		uh so it's that's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about fifteen hundred</NUMEX> all together then we but we're a a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">subsidiary</ENAMEX> of a of a larger <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> so we have all the benefits that all the big large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> have
 		i don't know any that we don't have
 	
 	
 		i don't know a lot about benefits most of the jobs that i've had you know were
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i don't have a degree i quit college when i <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> got pregnant with my little boy
 	
 	
 		oh uh-huh
 	
 	
 		i plan on going back  just i want to wait for my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> to grow up now
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		uh i'm sorry  so all i've had was mainly fast food jobs and i worked at a toy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> and i worked at <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> for a while but it was for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Manpower</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		that's all right
 		oh uh-huh
 	
 	
 		i liked working at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TI</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i worked for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seventeen years</TIMEX> and then i moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> and worked at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Martin Marietta</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Orlando</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX> and then i got
 	
 	
 		oh you're in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i was no i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> uh i left <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Martin Marietta</ENAMEX> for this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort Worth</ENAMEX> it's i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grapevine</ENAMEX> right now but
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		i work in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort Worth</ENAMEX> and they just offered me such a fantastic deal i i just couldn't turn it down there wasn't any way i could turn it down they
 		they moved me and they paid for every i mean they paid for everything my license my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX>'s license my all my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">utilities</ENAMEX> at my home plus you know paying to move my furniture and
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		my license tags everything i just you know and plus a huge salary increase and i thought God i'd be stupid if i don't take this and i wanted to come back to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> anyway so
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well that's great
 	
 	
 		and like i say they have all those same benefits that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Martin Marietta</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> had so um
 		i've
 	
 	
 		what did you say you did again a computer a data
 	
 	
 		i'm a data manager
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		and it
 	
 	
 		well i took data processing in college
 	
 	
 		oh did no this is a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> think that it has something to do with computers and it really doesn't i mean i do have a computer but it it really doesn't have anything to do with computers it's
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX> that uh is generated like reports test reports financial reports all kinds of reports that
 		that uh a project would generate uh now it's my job to see that
 		contractually contractually these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you know deliver them on time and i have to make sure that they they do get delivered and that's that's what my job is and it's that's that kind of data instead of
 	
 	
 		instead of computer data well that sounds great though what did you do at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TI</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah uh-huh
 		i was a a configuration <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> at at <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> which was
 		similar well it was uh similar but wasn't i mean i it was uh
 		doing uh it was a little bit more technical configuration management <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> it's a little bit more technical than what i'm doing now
 		and i liked it but it was a
 		it was a job that i always felt like i didn't have control of you know what i mean i never felt like i'd mastered that job and when i moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> i moved down there as a configuration manager
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and stayed there from uh stayed at that job for quite a while until i
 		got an opportunity to go into data management which i and i've been in that ever since and love it i mean that's just my cup of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tea</ENAMEX> the configuration <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> was
 	
 	
 		right
 		oh i hate to feel out of control of anything
 	
 	
 		oh i do too and i really did i'd sit there and you know when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> asked me what i did i never could really tell them what i did because i didn't know because i you know  i was doing the job
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		you played it by ear
 	
 	
 		and i was getting good raises and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> even goes you even got non periodic raises but i really just felt so control out of control
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		so but anyway i'm
 		and i like i say i've always been with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that's had a lot of benefits so uh and and when you get older now i know when you're younger my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> just doesn't realize it but
 		i wish i had when i was younger thought about retirement but you know you think oh that's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years</TIMEX> away from now who's going to worry about it well i
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well me and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> are we've talked about it we're having <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">six dollars</NUMEX> a day taken out of his check for retirement
 	
 	
 		that's good that's smart i wish i could talk my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> into realizing that she works at <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> also
 	
 	
 		well that's
 	
 	
 		and she needs yeah
 	
 	
 		at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sherman</ENAMEX> or
 	
 	
 		no she works at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Expressway</ENAMEX> site uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SC Building</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay well uh
 	
 	
 		and
 		uh
 	
 	
 		um that's about the only thing we're doing for retirement <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> when i worked i wanted to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI i</ENAMEX> was wanting to become a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TIer</ENAMEX> that way i could get some benefits because most the jobs around here you can't get benefits
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		i know isn't that a shame
 	
 	
 		especially if you well if you don't have a
 		degree or something
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but i'll go back to school one of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> and i will get me a
 	
 	
 		see well i was uh
 		<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">forty five</NUMEX> before i got my degree i uh started back when i was it took me <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nine years</TIMEX> i was about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> something before i even went back to school or even started college
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i was <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">forty five</NUMEX> when i finally graduated
 	
 	
 		well i was eighteen and i went and got my GED i quit the high school i just couldn't stand it and then course i hated it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> after i quit i wish i'd never done it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but then i i went and got my GED and i went to school and then i i loved college i was making a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> point oh average i wasn't having hardly any problems except for with my computer class i did have problems there but uh
 	
 	
 		really
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		now i was then i was old enough to know you know well i'm paying for it i've got to
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know do something with it but then i wanted to stay home with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		yeah i stayed home with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> i think i guess the longest i ever stayed home was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight years</TIMEX> i stayed home with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> went ahead and graduated from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> has quite a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">few hours</TIMEX> but she
 		bless her she and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> are you know kind of struggling he's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policeman</ENAMEX>
 		they're both having and she works a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> job too so she really doesn't have time i guess if she wanted to make time she could but and eventually i think she'll go back when it really means something to her but right now that's not foremost and her she likes being with her little girl
 	
 	
 		well we're having a hard time right now too but it's just who if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> don't have direction if their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> ain't home directing them through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are growing up wild nowadays
 	
 	
 		oh i know it i know it
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> had to work and i i can feel the difference um a lot of
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> had somebody to push him his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> was able to stay home with him more and you know he got his life straight at an early age which i'm not a i never i never went wild or anything but
 	
 	
 		yes
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i still don't know what i want to be when i grow up and i'm <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty seven years old</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		i know it that's me i here am i in my fifties and i still don't know what i want to do but my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> didn't work she was always home so and it  didn't i guess really looking back
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		knowing that she was always there when we got home from school my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> was there and now what i did when my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> were growing up since i had to work i worked <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nights</TIMEX> i was home i was sleepy but i was home when they got home from school
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah that's what's important isn't it you have to while i'm when they start going to school now my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX>'s just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three months old</TIMEX> and i'm not having any more so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i'm going to be there for them at least until they're in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">well</ENAMEX> until the baby starts
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		school
 	
 	
 		preschool uh kindergarten not preschool
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		which it don't take long it seems like just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> that my little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> was born and he's fixing to go to school next year
 	
 	
 		oh is he
 	
 	
 		yeah they're all growing up
 	
 	
 		your your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> works for the railroad you say
 	
 	
 		yeah he sure does

 	
 	
 		oh now do do they have pretty good benefits there besides uh
 	
 	
 		yeah their medical and dental is real good and uh like i said they do make it easy for you to that's where a lot of our money is going is toward his retirement but i want we'll like that once you know we get older
 	
 	
 		is it
 		sure oh yeah absolutely
 	
 	
 		and we'll need it and like i said that's <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">six dollars</NUMEX> a day and oh i haven't really sat down and figured it out but i guess it'd be pretty easy <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> is what eighteen
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah so it's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred and eighty</NUMEX> a month
 	
 	
 		oh once i did
 		well yeah that'll add up fast fast fast absolutely yeah you're smart in doing that i would never quit that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		no well it's it's like this we don't see it so we don't really miss it
 	
 	
 		well i've started uh
 		that's right that i went <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX> and had them start taking some money out of my uh
 		savings my checking at work to in to put into savings account plus i buy a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">two hundred dollar</NUMEX> a month a bond a month so they'll and they'll stack up faster than you realize
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah now i wish they had that bond here i know that they had that at <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	