
 
     		
 	
 		some of the the more recent uh changes that i've noticed in society is i guess over the last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years</TIMEX> or maybe the
 		technological advances you know <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years ago</TIMEX> there wasn't a VCR in every <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> and there wasn't uh
 	
 	
 		oh i know the remote control was a great big <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">box</ENAMEX> that was connected to the back of the TV
 	
 	
 		some some of the
 		
 
 		uh that's true yeah and the old remote controls that were all by sound and you could drop a coin or clang some dishes and turn off the TV or change <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX> and all the things that have changed over the years
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but along with that i unfortunately i guess there's been a down side to a lot of that stuff i mean another <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three or four years</TIMEX> you're going to have a land fill full of VCR's that and the parts and things that don't work and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		a lot of those things just don't go away and uh i guess the  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">environmentalists</ENAMEX> have done their jobs that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years ago</TIMEX> i didn't think of it that much i knew about all the the uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organizations</ENAMEX> that tried to do that for a living you know let you know what what environmental impact was but just kind of recently uh the world's waking up to that so that's a change that's come along
 	
 	
 		yeah you got to well let's see you i guess you grew up in the you were a teenager in the seventies right okay did you go to like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woodstock</ENAMEX> and all that
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		no no never got around as it were but i uh i paid attention to it all being there so that that has changed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are uh i think the
 		the outspoken <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people people</ENAMEX> who make a difference and make a change that age has come down it seems like uh you can make a difference at a younger <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age these days</TIMEX> you don't have to be a an older part of the establishment to make waves
 	
 	
 		no like that one little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> that wrote who did she write
 		oh i think she was in some kind of a airplane crash
 		seem like it was an <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> wrote <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gorbachev Gorbachev</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Noriega</ENAMEX> or someone
 	
 	
 		oh yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		i thought that was a lot
 	
 	
 		it's true they can uh they can make quite a difference at no matter what the age nowadays
 		plus there seems to be uh uh there's a few negative changes that have come along i was just thinking last night how different uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>' childhood is from uh
 		when i grew up i i was allowed pretty much a free rein around my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> to ride my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bike</ENAMEX> uh you know all several blocks away even at the age of of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years old</TIMEX> i could ride
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">couple of miles</NUMEX> away i'd ride to school you know and it was it was right at <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">two miles</NUMEX> away from the house
 	
 	
 		uh-huh but it's just not safe anymore
 	
 	
 		whereas here uh yeah i won't let them go you know more than a block out of my sight there i'm just a little too paranoid <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> with what's going on and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">hum-um</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah we get you know reports from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> will give us warnings about this neighborhood and some activity that's occurring there and then you know occasionally it works its way around to our neighborhood and we have to keep a real close rein on them won't even let them go out of our sight for a while and then
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		how
 	
 	
 		after they catch that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> you know you can let him go out for a while but it's uh it's kind of sad
 	
 	
 		well how old are your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i've got a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nine year old</TIMEX> and a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven year old</TIMEX> and uh they both like to ride their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bikes</ENAMEX> off into never never land and you know be
 	
 	
 		okay
 		right well we used to ride around
 		well i guess it would be a city block
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> didn't mind i wouldn't dream of letting my little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> take off
 	
 	
 		yeah i used to uh i grew up in kind of a good combination of between the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and the city
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Texas</ENAMEX> and i had while we were in town we'd ride <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">several miles</NUMEX> away like to school and the like but when we were in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> we would ride
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">twelve miles</NUMEX> away we'd spend a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">whole day</TIMEX> just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two or three</NUMEX> of us get together and take a lunch and go ride somewhere and eat lunch and come back and you know as long as we told the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> what <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX> we were going to be on and if there any
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		trouble was they could come find us but uh can't do that now  just no safe place to let your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> go that long and of course it probably wasn't that good of an idea back then either it just uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">hum-um</ENAMEX>
 		well no but back even when i was growing up it wasn't
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> wasn't as now <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> was pretty bad but they weren't near as bad as they are now
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and  this
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> abuse wasn't as bad as it is now either
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and there's uh so many missing kids
 	
 	
 		you know they they're saying that the uh uh the education is going to be enough or at least a major part of the drug deterrment
 		and though i remember when i was in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> they had a a drug awareness week type deal that we studied in the science classes and we got little posters and we did all sorts of stuff but
 		that was nothing compared to the you know campaigns that are going on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> but i guess it's just the the class of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> or the area that we're in but
 		i i'm not in contact with any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 		that think it's it's it's it's a positive thing to do i mean it is it is really looked down upon even to the point of smoking i mean that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are so ingrained
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that they look down on them we have to tell them you know don't say anything in public to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stranger</ENAMEX> about his smoking you know not not quite that's not quite accepted yet now if he's in a nonsmoking area you might want to say something but
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well
 	
 	
 		they uh they're so outspoken on the topic that uh
 		
 
 		it's an interesting change in attitudes
 	
 	
 		yeah that is because
 	
 	
 		there's coming coming along with the education
 	
 	
 		even in my time smoking was just cool
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		all the cool <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> did it
 	
 	
 		yep
 	
 	
 		went outside but
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stepdaughter</ENAMEX>'s getting like that
 		and that's pretty hard because her granny smokes and
 		we smoke so it
 	
 	
 		yeah it won't take but a like uh maybe generation or so before it uh it it no longer the cool thing to do i don't know
 	
 	
 		oh yeah have a smoke free
 	
 	
 		hopefully hopefully we can get away from it yeah
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		it's quite an expense too now they keep deciding that's the thing to tax
 	
 	
 		yeah they do it's what <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about two dollars</NUMEX> a pack now
 	
 	
 		yeah it keeps going up and up well i guess there's uh
 		it's i don't know of any other major changes other than the political environment course that things are no longer the cold war scares and the things that are going on that realm and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s no longer the major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enemy</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		well who is the major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enemy</ENAMEX> now
 	
 	
 		i i don't know if there is one one easy <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to uh to pick that's part of the problem
 	
 	
 		i don't when i was growing up i was scared of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Red China</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		now everybody told me that they had the biggest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> in the world which i guess they still do because
 	
 	
 		they probably still do as far as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX> go
 	
 	
 		yeah because <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s real densely populated unless they
 	
 	
 		of course there you wouldn't be able to go over and attack them but i don't know that they'd be able to go anywhere and attack us  they can't get all those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> across the sea they don't have the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ships</ENAMEX> to get them anywhere so they may have a huge <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> but it's going to stay put
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		hm
 	
 	
 		uh it's kind of an interesting uh interesting problem not having any one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemy</ENAMEX> to focus on as a society
 		tends to uh let that go out of the mind you're no longer concerned with the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapon systems</ENAMEX> and the the defense area so now that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s gone as a major focused on enemy uh
 		that whole defense issue is just not quite as important to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s lives
 		so that's an an interesting social change i guess
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		course it'll surprise them some day when when all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hostilities</ENAMEX> start back up and some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> aren't prepared for it  so
 	
 	
 		oh i don't think anybody was prepared for this last war
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	