
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 		i guess we're ready
 	
 	
 		okay so what's wrong with our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school systems</ENAMEX>
 		besides it's really screwed up some of them
 	
 	
 		well i
 	
 	
 		i don't think i don't think all of them i think maybe mainly <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school systems</ENAMEX> because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richardson</ENAMEX> is fine and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Garland</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Plano</ENAMEX> he was in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all three</NUMEX> them <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richardson Plano</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Garland</ENAMEX> and i don't have any problems with with with them
 		as far as you know
 	
 	
 		well um
 		well it's been a long time since i been in uh involved with public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school systems</ENAMEX> uh
 	
 	
 		i think
 	
 	
 		my youngest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> has graduated and she graduated in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty nine</NUMEX> so
 	
 	
 		oh my goodness i think the biggest problem for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now days</TIMEX> with the school system is
 		some of the parents i don't wanna say all of them because i'm not one of them but some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> thinks just uh they're <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby sitters</ENAMEX> and they're not
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know they're putting a lot of responsibilities off on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> and i don't think they should i think they should also get involved
 	
 	
 		well i don't know if uh  you mean they keep the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> they want the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> to keep the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> longer
 	
 	
 		under a shelf it's in there under there
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">hello</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		uh what do you mean by that statement do you mean they want the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> to keep the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> longer than they're supposed to or are they  to train them
 	
 	
 		no more or less train train them yeah
 	
 	
 		in all phases of life
 	
 	
 		uh sometimes more discipline discipline uh because
 	
 	
 		really you mean just  in
 	
 	
 		they wouldn't be too much of a discipline problems i think if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> would um
 	
 	
 		well the discipline starts in the home
 	
 	
 		well that's that's what i'm saying
 	
 	
 		and carries over into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> when they are school age and and
 	
 	
 		that's right
 		but i mean you have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> you have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> going to school with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> knives that's that's from the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> but you know it's i don't know i guess <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> aren't
 	
 	
 		and i think the school i think
 		oh that's
 		well
 	
 	
 		like when i was growing up you know you didn't have all this problems i mean we had problems in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> but not like this
 		nothing like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">and the</ENAMEX> and the violence there is in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well it's just gotten uh completely out of hand as far as the violence in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and i don't know what the solution to that is at all i mean its just uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">hum-um</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		to me it's utter chaos i don't know how some of those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> function because uh
 		they are being violated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> and
 		i know that there are some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> that are patrolled by um
 		private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> and even public police and and and they're not getting any satisfaction from that effort
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		and they're not getting any paid neither i mean there's not you know it's like a hazardous job now to in some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> i should say not all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> you know it's
 	
 	
 		i think uh i don't know what the solution is if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> doesn't know how are the um there's somebody that needs to rise up
 		and have a plan that is going to resolve the many issues that are facing the public school system and i wouldn't know where to start since i haven't been involved in
 		the public school system that much
 	
 	
 		well i've been involved and you know what
 		i still don't know the problem i mean i wouldn't know where to begin to solve it i mean
 	
 	
 		when my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> were in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> they were in a in a private school system so i mean we just
 		i mean they just knew that they had to toe the line otherwise they would
 		uh suffer the consequences and and that was enough for them i mean they just were very responsible
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and i didn't have any problems with them
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and i believe that uh that starts in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> and then if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are influenced i guess they're influenced by their peers
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">uh monkey see monkey</ENAMEX> do a lot of times
 	
 	
 		and then but see that also begins at home because he
 	
 	
 		and it kind of
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> has well i i've seen a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> you know and it's like i tell my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> that's not my child
 		what that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> does don't you do i say well see i'm not his mother
 		and i you know you will get in trouble for something somebody else <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> may or may not let they child do but you know right from wrong
 		so
 	
 	
 		well i guess that's the bottom line if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> do know right from wrong
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh with uh with so many of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> being disorganized themselves it's no wonder that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are so you have to look at that uh factor also
 		where those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are coming from and what kind of home life they have
 	
 	
 		yeah but what and then you got what about this other
 		
 		
 	