
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">okay Catharine</ENAMEX> can you uh give me your views on uh  what you think about the uh care of elderly
 	
 	
 		well
 		i would i hate to see them being put into a hair care or a health facility care environment because they then feel like you know the family has abandoned them
 		is uh what i get the comments from elderly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that i know that it's happened to
 		and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elderly people</ENAMEX> that i  that are still hanging onto their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> that is their greatest fear is to be put into a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a</NUMEX> a care <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> rather than their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> taking them in
 		because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> then seem to neglect visiting them
 		but if that is the case that they have to go to a care <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> like that i think that care <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> has to be thoroughly investigated as far as the uh medical um
 		evaluation what kind of credentials do the medical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> hold uh if they're qualified uh what type of recreation do they have for them uh their food uh situation
 		um
 		the environment that they are exposed to the the majority of the time that they're there is it bright and cheery um
 		and to put them in with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that
 		have the same type of uh lifestyle uh that they would feel more more welcome in uh
 		in making new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> because they can relate to certain <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> because of their personalities
 	
 	
 		um yeah
 	
 	
 		um
 		so i guess i would like to hear how you feel about it now <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh we uh just went through an experience um
 		both my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> passed away fairly young and uh
 	
 	
 		oh my
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> died when she was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only nine years old</TIMEX> so the only one that we really had was her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>  and uh
 	
 	
 		i i see
 	
 	
 		he's no longer with us he passed away when he was uh he was going on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eighty nine years old</TIMEX> so he had a good long life
 	
 	
 		yes he did uh-huh
 	
 	
 		but he always maintained his own <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> he lived in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> he lived in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rhode Island</ENAMEX> in fact we live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rhode Island</ENAMEX> i work in in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> but i live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rhode Island</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		he's always lived in the in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> and he's always been kind of independent he's uh
 	
 	
 		that's wonderful that's good
 	
 	
 		he's never had a a never owned an automobile never had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX>'s license you know he's always you know yeah
 	
 	
 		so he was very independent wasn't he
 	
 	
 		he got around yeah yeah because he lived right down down <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> in the
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">port</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> right there so he used to take the steamer down to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> and you know i mean he went
 	
 	
 		wow that's wonderful
 	
 	
 		yeah he went everywhere he wanted to go
 	
 	
 		sure he it didn't have any hindrances for him
 	
 	
 		no and then <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a year and a half ago</TIMEX> he uh he started having mini strokes
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and we got kind of concerned about him and then uh he had fallen in the street a couple of times but
 	
 	
 		oh bless his heart
 	
 	
 		he uh
 		he still didn't want to give up his apartment
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		and uh finally <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year ago last Thanksgiving</TIMEX> um my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> tried to call him and he wouldn't answer the phone so we kind of expected the worse so i went down
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and he had had another <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stroke</ENAMEX> and uh i found him he was just he was just standing in the middle of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> all covered with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">shaving cream</ENAMEX> he always trying to shave and he didn't know who i was so we brought him up to to uh stay with us
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh he snapped he snapped out of it
 		he uh
 		he was probably uh
 		say <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ninety five</NUMEX> percent himself
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and in in the course of the next during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next year</TIMEX> towards again it was getting on towards <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thanksgiving</TIMEX> time he started having you know more strokes and then uh
 	
 	
 		that's wonderful
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one morning</TIMEX> he felt real dizzy so we took him to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and while he was in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> he had a a massive stroke
 		and it crippled him
 		on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> side his right side
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so he didn't have the use of of his arm or his leg or and then uh he lost the ability to speak
 		and we're not sure but we think that he was
 		very hard of hearing to begin with his almost his whole entire life
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i see
 	
 	
 		so we figured that uh his hearing deteriorated even further and his eyesight
 		um we did as much as we could for him and then it got to the point where we couldn't handle him anymore
 	
 	
 		sure i understand that
 	
 	
 		um i was working during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> and and uh
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> couldn't she she couldn't get him up
 	
 	
 		um-hum sure
 	
 	
 		so um
 		the alternative was to put him back in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> which we did and they took care of him you know and he slowly deteriorated and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		to the point where he uh became fairly stable i mean he he knew who we were when we went in to visit him  even though he couldn't communicate with us
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then they said that um there was nothing more that they could do for him and he had to go into a nursing home the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> said that he couldn't come back with us
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because we couldn't take care of him
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and we started looking around and they said no the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> nursing home that's closest to you that has an available bed is where he's going to go
 		so we didn't have much of a choice
 	
 	
 		wow i didn't know that they were that uh
 	
 	
 		well at least up here um so he went in there anyhow and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> went in there <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> to see him and you know she
 	
 	
 		
 
 		were you satisfied with uh the facility
 	
 	
 		uh at first well at first no
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's uh it's very cold uh or at least we thought it was they're very clinical they're it's like a  well it's a business
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		you get them in uh you do what you have to do for them and that's it
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		um so I would go on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekends</TIMEX> and she would go during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> to to visit him and they had a laundry you know they had the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> was there but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		closed up most of the time so she'd go in and do his laundry for him and she'd go in and feed him and
 		and it got to the point where um they we knew them just as much as they knew us and and they really cared for him at you know he was in there for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">almost six months</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		so you established a relationship with the uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX> there um-hum um-hum
 	
 	
 		with the nursing home right um and it was run the nursing home was run by uh
 		regular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> but it was owned by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seventh Day Adventists</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		which was a surprise to us you know we didn't realize that they had i guess
 	
 	
 		well then you did see some compassion from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> there
 	
 	
 		uh but most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were
 	
 	
 		or were they just very businesslike and perhaps not of that faith
 	
 	
 		well they didn't have anything to do with it they owned it
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		but they
 		i suppose they cared how it was run but they had an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">administrator</ENAMEX> that ran it and and most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were um
 		uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX> you know uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamaicans</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Africans</ENAMEX> or
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">okay um-hum um</ENAMEX>
 		okay yes
 	
 	
 		and they uh they took real good care of him he had lost a pair of slippers <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> and one of them out of her own money bought a pair of slippers for him and you know that type of thing
 	
 	
 		i see uh-huh
 	
 	
 		but i think only because my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> spent so much time there she was there i mean <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every single day</TIMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX> and then on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekends</TIMEX> we would go in the both of us
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and she would do things and she would donate little things and she'd help clean up the tables and you know that type of thing so um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		but you're right when most when most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> end up in there and i hear it from a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elderly people</ENAMEX> their greatest fear is that they're going to end up there and nobody's going to see them
 	
 	
 		sure
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		they'll be abused but you hear horror stories all the time
 	
 	
 		oh yes sure
 	
 	
 		but if you care
 		then it makes a difference those people
 	
 	
 		oh absolutely absolutely
 	
 	
 		that have uh a a lot of visitors
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and we had a gentleman that uh that uh
 		let's see maybe <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a week</TIMEX> after my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father-in-law</ENAMEX> was in there he shared his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> he came in he could get around fairly well he again had a had a stroke and he was partially paralyzed
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but he was young enough where they gave him therapy and he was beginning to move up but he could talk  and would tell us things oh you want to see what they're doing here and do you want to see this but don't tell anybody you know
 	
 	
 		so he kind
 		yeah yeah so he kind of adopted you and your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah in fact uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we go down to see him she goes down occasionally maybe maybe uh once or twice <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> just just to see him
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh i'll stop in maybe once or once or twice <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX> i'll go down to see him
 	
 	
 		well i'm sure he looks forward to that
 	
 	
 		uh yes but he gets out he can get out you know he can he's got a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and they take him here and they take him there so he's not as as bad off as some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> because some of them are in there and in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the six months</TIMEX> that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father-in-law</ENAMEX> was in there
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um i've i've seen a lot of them that didn't have any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> whatsoever at least while i was there
 	
 	
 		right yeah
 		they're abandoned by their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> yeah or if they or they might not have any at all
 	
 	
 		yeah they just uh
 		yeah and uh we had an old <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> an old shepherd they were inseparable my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father-in-law</ENAMEX> and the dog we brought the dog down there and it was nice and all the old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> oh look at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh yes
 	
 	
 		well most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't do that you know they don't they don't they figure figure once you're in there you forget everything and that's that's really not the case and it's it's sad um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		um
 	
 	
 		i hope that i never get into that situation where you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> will say well okay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> you know here you go
 	
 	
 		of course yes
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i think i'll walk off into the mountains somewhere or out into the
 	
 	
 		like the old <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> used to do
 	
 	
 		
 
 		but yeah yeah and you know and there's something to say for that i think
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well yes they died with dignity didn't they
 	
 	
 		right they do and and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> that don't
 		
 		
 	