
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		well i do not know how big a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX> i mean you have heard about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> and the the crime here is pretty bad
 	
 	
 		well <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX> pretty small but uh we hear a lot about uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> there is a lot of crime down there and i am i am afraid to go down there because
 	
 	
 		yeah i was going to say
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know i mean you hear about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> getting mugged You leave your <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ten minutes</TIMEX> and it is stripped when you come back so
 	
 	
 		yeah have you ever been there
 	
 	
 		no i have not only to the airport
 	
 	
 		that is uh probably enough to see  um are you in college right now
 	
 	
 		
 
 		no i am i work at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">for the Air Force</ENAMEX> so there is a base up here and
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 		are base that's interesting interesting concept are bases safe you know
 	
 	
 		bases are pretty safe because they check your <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">ID</ENAMEX> on your way in and
 	
 	
 		yeah the they uh minimize the access
 	
 	
 		right but even so we had a um um at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">New Years</TIMEX> we had some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> come in and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		like attack one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX> because they were protesting uh the presence over in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Persian Gulf</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh no
 		sure oh great that's wonderful yeah well <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> uh we lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minneapolis</ENAMEX> uh we moved here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about ten months ago</TIMEX> and
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> is pretty uh well we live in north <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> north <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> which is like a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">suburb</ENAMEX> near a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">suburb</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Plano</ENAMEX> so we are out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> but it is uh
 		it is bad everywhere in terms of uh you know the handgun situation um the number of rapes the number of muggings just it's it's
 		i would not say it is not as bad as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> but it is pretty scary you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> put bars on their windows in certain neighborhoods and you know they call them ornamental grates but they are still bars
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yep
 		that makes it bad for getting out during a fire
 	
 	
 		yeah it really does and if you're a little bit claustrophobic but uh i don't know i mean the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">jails</ENAMEX> are crowded i i i'm not a criminal justice <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">specialist</ENAMEX> so i don't know what you know what can be done i'm
 	
 	
 		i don't i don't know it seems to i think it is getting worse because i keep hearing things like i when i was home i went home my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> but i went home and we were watching TV and
 	
 	
 		you know
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		this thing came on where these a group of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">like five</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> went and filmed themselves beating up <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> and and robbing them and it was really disgusting and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> was like they should just be all shot <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">right now</TIMEX> and
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		i mean you hear
 	
 	
 		were they <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teenagers</ENAMEX> or like that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> that got beat up by you know when she was jogging in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central Park</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of years ago</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 		yeah yeah um they weren't i think they were early <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenties</TIMEX> they were young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		huh yeah but they so they weren't you know and were they uh were they were they obviously poor or deprived you know that is really strange sick
 	
 	
 		i know and how  deprived could they be if they had a camcorder those are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a thousand</NUMEX> bucks
 	
 	
 		yeah unless they stole it and i mean that is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> big thing down here i mean they have like uh and they are not all young i mean they are eighteen to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">twenty four</NUMEX> some of the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> but
 		i mean you can you can see the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crime Stoppers</ENAMEX> ads on television or sometimes it's the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that have been that have been observed and they still can't catch them
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and you are wondering how you know um we lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minneapolis</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wisconsin</ENAMEX> i mean there was all kind of i i know i i i know it is getting worse i do not know what the world is or is not um
 		the  in a small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wisconsin</ENAMEX> near <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Madison</ENAMEX> um a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> somehow got a hold of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">shotgun</ENAMEX> and killed his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> and his <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> and sisters
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> had and he they said that he was twelve <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years old</TIMEX> and he had uh he had not uh displayed any tendencies deviant or disturbed or whatever you know and you are thinking to yourself um i know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i wonder where
 		i do not know i wonder where he gets it you know you must i think TV is bad because they uh show all sorts of violence on
 	
 	
 		that and i don't think a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> i mean i don't i don't know how it is in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">base</ENAMEX> but uh i just don't think a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> because of the economy both need to work you know i just don't think a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> are that involved any more
 	
 	
 		yeah they don't they don't talk to their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and take them out and and aren't there all the time so the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are off to their own devices a lot
 	
 	
 		
 
 		right and discipline i do not know how your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> were but i mean i sure knew as heck when i was growing up that uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> were
 	
 	
 		oh definitely
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">superior</ENAMEX> and i was the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subordinate</ENAMEX> and you know
 		it was sort of like there were boundaries and i do not think i do not know i think <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">parents um</ENAMEX> are ruled by their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> i i
 	
 	
 		i think so definitely when you go to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are running all over the place they
 	
 	
 		yeah right i mean they're  not learning such as well like boundaries i mean i don't i see it in work place too sometimes i  do not know how old you are but you sound a little bit younger than me but i am in my <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirties</TIMEX> and i
 		i i see um even <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that work with me that are <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years</TIMEX> younger that you know they kind of have an attitude that i hate i i hate to say it but it's that's just what it is it is an attitude like the world owes them something
 	
 	
 		yep but
 		right i i see that too in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX> especially oh yeah a lot of uh especially since a lot of us are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineers</ENAMEX> where i work
 	
 	
 		do you
 		are you in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX> okay
 	
 	
 		i'm in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX> and so
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> outside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX> doing engineering get paid a lot more than we do and so all the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineers</ENAMEX> are like well i am just going you know get it for all it is worth and that you know and i am like you are the one who signed up if you did not want to do it and
 	
 	
 		sure
 		
 
 		right
 		right right and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX> is one of the bitter better military supposedly military <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX> experiences i mean
 	
 	
 		yep it is i like it but uh
 	
 	
 		pardon me
 	
 	
 		i like it so far
 	
 	
 		i mean that is are you going to be a career <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> i'm digressing but  i don't talk to many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the military so i am
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh probably not but um they pay for my college so
 	
 	
 		
  
 		that's the way to do it i mean and that's you know at least the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX> is i don't know i just um
 		i am nervous in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> i mean i you know i mean i go to like an aerobics <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> or something you know i um seventy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in your average size exercise class in a public <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">um parks</ENAMEX> and rec <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> and you are supposed to feel safe but then there are all these
 		it doesn't matter race but you know it's an inter-racial mix and you see these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> standing there watching you jump around in your leotards leotards
 	
 	
 		yep
 	
 	
 		and i do not even think that way but i mean you just think to yourself
 		you you just i mean nobody can think that that it can't happen to them no matter who they are or where they are at you know
 	
 	
 		it
 		yeah and you never know who is watching either
 	
 	
 		i mean did you i do not know i was in the grocery <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> this morning we um
 		went to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Orleans</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four days</TIMEX> and came back <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">late last night</TIMEX> driving it's <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about seven hours um</TIMEX> and that's a very we had never been there that's a very very neat <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> to visit uh in terms of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">French Quarter</ENAMEX> and all of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th</ENAMEX> e things you hear about but the crime is so bad there
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		i mean in all the tourist brochures you read about what you should or should not do how to carry your wallet um
 	
 	
 		uh-huh this is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Orleans</ENAMEX>
 		oh i'd hate to be there during <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mardi Gras</ENAMEX> let
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Orleans</ENAMEX> yeah
 		i would never yeah you just don't don't even bother it's not worth it uh the when we came back i don't know if you have seen i was in the super market <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX> and on the cover of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time magazine</ENAMEX> there is a girl
 		she is in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> she is on the east coast somewhere real attractive young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> college freshman i college coed i think she is a freshman
 		she'd been dating a fellow for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several weeks</TIMEX> and they went back to her dorm <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> and date rape i mean and it just
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		she she looked anguished i mean it was really just sad i mean didn't pick it up and read it but i should have but i just looked at the picture and thought what a world
 	
 	
 		i know
 	
 	
 		i mean i do not yeah i do not have any uh cure
 	
 	
 		you can't trust anybody it's it's really scary
 	
 	
 		no you really can't i mean i they we lease out a really nice <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> story town <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Dallas</ENAMEX> and
 		they have a real big thing here <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i mean even dry <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cleaners</ENAMEX> knock on the door and are soliciting you know they everybody wants your business kind of thing and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> is the kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> he's
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		he's sometime he was raised on a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farm</ENAMEX> in southern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX> near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dayton</ENAMEX> and think sometimes it is just he and i are very different in terms of that i i mean i basically have started not to trust anybody in general street smarts
 	
 	
 		right
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and uh he opened the door i came downstairs and i was real upset and i probably got more nasty  than i should have but i just said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard</ENAMEX> you know oh my God i would not i mean
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well you you hear about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> opening the door and getting blown away or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you know
 	
 	
 		oh yeah And it does i mean it is it is not a reason i mean i have been to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> You shouldn't deny yourself going to visit and all that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh but it is not any worse i used to work for a mortgage <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that was owned by uh are you from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Home Owners Savings and Loan</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> and i know i never felt
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i mean i've been to downtown <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> and i've been to downtown <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> and i never felt any safer on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Milk Street</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> staying at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Meridian</ENAMEX> i didn't  pay for but i mean i never felt any safer there than i did in any other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> in any other city i have been in you know
 	
 	
 		
 
 		right
 	
 	
 		so i would say one thing do not deny yourself the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> experience but experience but go with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that you know
 	
 	
 		yeah i wouldn't want to go by myself
 	
 	
 		no uh but i mean it yeah i don't know i mean i i guess i could go on and on about what to do about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> uh i think the handgun i'm not real big on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> myself so i mean
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		i think our justice system needs to be stricter i mean because everyone they do it and then they get out in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of years</TIMEX> it seems like
 	
 	
 		are the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> uh are the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> i do not know how the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> state <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison system</ENAMEX> is but
 	
 	
 		they are booked up yeah
 	
 	
 		are they booked up  that is a way to put it they are booked up Are they paroling uh like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">murderers</ENAMEX> and i mean here it is just a real big deal they parole <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that have killed police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> and then they are out doing it again
 	
 	
 		
 
 		right um i do not i do not know because i am not real up on a lot of news things but you know you just hear about that that you know it is a lot of repeat crime
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and you are like why are they repeating they should have been in there longer or
 	
 	
 		i know and then you think i mean i have i mean i can remember i haven't been out of school that long but it has been at least <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years</TIMEX> and you think to yourself was it that bad back then
 		or is it just i think that like you said television is it just that more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> think there is like excitement in it you know i mean <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that may have been close to the edge just go over because they see something or read something
 	
 	
 		it seems like a lot of it that it is more like in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> there was a case of uh a couple of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> fifteen <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year olds</TIMEX> they wanted to see what it was like to kill someone so they they picked on this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> who was like new in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> and they were like well no one was going to miss him anyway
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know and it like ugh that is horrible how can you even think like that
 	
 	
 		oh God
 		it it is yeah isn't it something i mean i i have a i am originally from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh Pennsylvania</ENAMEX> and i have a niece and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nephew</ENAMEX> and i just um
 		i mean my <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten year</TIMEX> old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nephew</ENAMEX>  says things that he is aware of that i am just going <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael</ENAMEX> how did you hear about that
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		you know it is just i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> get too much too fast and all those sort of things in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX> where my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inlaws</ENAMEX> live um they had that thing you know the high top sneakers the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Jordans et</ENAMEX> cetera
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right
 	
 	
 		kids killing each other and beating their brains out you know right or the or the jackets the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Raiders</ENAMEX> and the caps you know stealing the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundred</NUMEX> dollar jackets um
 	
 	
 		oh for the sneakers yeah
 		yep
 	
 	
 		i mean it is i guess it goes from the most petty like that to like what you were saying that they in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> that is crime where they videoed that is probably one of the most bizarre i have heard of where they videotape themselves
 	
 	
 		yep
 		yeah it seems like a crime is turning into a pastime instead of like you know be
 		
 		
 	