
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well i guess it depends on what age i'm in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> something so i know i mean i lived through it uh are you old enough to know about the war
 	
 	
 		um just barely yeah i'm uh <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty nine</TIMEX> so uh
 	
 	
 		oh
 		okay well yeah you're old enough but it was on the fringe
 	
 	
 		yes but just uh yeah exactly had some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> over that were that were in it
 	
 	
 		it ended when i was in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> in uh
 		when i turned nineteen in nineteen seventy i can't even remember at this point um when i turned nineteen it was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> that uh the draft was still going on if i had been a male or in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> i'd have been number <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		yeah  so i learned a lesson in gender  um in terms of the war i don't know um
 	
 	
 		wowie
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		see actually i don't really know that much about it i just know socially the impact it had here and what you hear in the media you know um i guess i think it was  not that great that we were in there
 		um in terms of for how long it lasted
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know what do you think
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well i think it's uh basically the same way it's certainly has affected uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> policy though there's no question it had an overwhelming effect of how we approached the the thing in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because uh the whole thing that was bad about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> was no different from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> i mean it was uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> country picking on a smaller weaker one
 	
 	
 		right the devastation yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah the only difference was that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> said okay if we're going to support this smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> then we're going to support it <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred</NUMEX> percent and we're going to consider ourselves against in war against these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> as well
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah and in full faction yeah
 	
 	
 		which uh right which really wasn't the attitude with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> it was sort of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s war rather than a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s war
 	
 	
 		yeah it just kind of dragged on um i don't know how you were historically but i was was a little bit older before i realized just how long it had been going on since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LBJ</ENAMEX> and i mean i had yeah
 	
 	
 		right yeah it seemed to me like it was it seemed like it was going on forever yeah
 	
 	
 		it really well yeah in fact because in terms of when your
 		there's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at least ten years</TIMEX> between us so in terms of when you were in school i'm sure that it was you know the majority of your high school and junior high <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the things i didn't like was the weapon the weapons i can't even say it the weaponry that systems that they used um it just didn't seem that um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i don't know technically we knew what we were doing either then you heard about the things like <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">agent orange et cetera</ENAMEX> and you'd think
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know just uh how could the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> uh whomever <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">whomever</ENAMEX>'s in charge there been so careless
 	
 	
 		yeah right
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		of course now  uh now everyone's more uh you know environmentally uh intelligent than they were back then i mean back then it wasn't commonly known that saccharin was bad for you and all these other  things that people
 	
 	
 		conscious yeah
 		Nutrisweet yeah and all these other things that's true uh
 	
 	
 		that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> know about themselves now
 	
 	
 		um monetarily too i just don't think we've done enough for the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Vietnamese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> as a whole um in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Vietnam</ENAMEX> in general in helping them restore themselves
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know and i don't know if it's because there aren't any <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">fields</ENAMEX> there
 	
 	
 		yeah i don't know if they uh i don't know if they have that resource or not
 	
 	
 		yeah i mean i don't think they do but i just think it's kind of a shame that uh you still hear things about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> that are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">orphans</ENAMEX> there and um so on a whole i don't know war isn't good and that one i probably um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		my main opinion would be  we shouldn't have done it
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		well that's what i know about the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Vietnam War</ENAMEX> unless you have
 	
 	
 		yeah  yeah well you know a little uh a little bit more than i do explain it said i didn't uh get to live through it that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that i know that it did
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh</ENAMEX> felt very strongly most of i work for a government contractor so most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> i work with are uh well at least some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> i work with rather are veterans
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		um-hum oh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> and i haven't talked to any of them that that weren't you know glad that they went or or rather thought that the reason they went was a good one
 	
 	
 		jeez yeah
 		um-hum and that that
 	
 	
 		you know most of them are very very strongly that that the reason for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> to be there was a good one they just felt that the way <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> backed them up wasn't wasn't at all right
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		in terms of the personal yeah the bitterness is more on a personal level than on a
 	
 	
 		yeah in term of
 		yeah personal level and and the finances how they started you know like air attacks and stuff like that dropped off like crazy because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> wouldn't approve you know yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		the money's after yeah i mean i think it started actually like like in the late fifties i mean like in fifty <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> fifty <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		um i i
 	
 	
 		so it really i mean because i know in nineteen <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixty three</TIMEX> i mean i was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nine years old</TIMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> was shot
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so i mean i remember um right around then that that's when i <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> started hearing about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> but then as i got older and studied in school i realized it was even going on before that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know and you think to yourself oh my goodness <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eisenhower</ENAMEX>  that sounds ancient yeah and i know i know you know a lot of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> vets that are my age in their <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later thirties</TIMEX> um <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> that i know that
 	
 	
 		yeah right
 	
 	
 		they're just kind of bitter you know they they you know i hate to quote that movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Born on the Fourth</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX> but it's that kind of idea
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know they just don't feel that socially they were given like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of mine called it the yellow ribbon syndrome yeah they weren't given the yeah so
 	
 	
 		right right the ticker tape parade and all that
 	
 	
 		well i won't keep you anymore that's probably about as much as we both but thanks for talking to me ah yes is that where you're at
 	
 	
 		okay
 		yes uh were you calling from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 		no i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Falls Church Virginia</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh i know where that is that's beautiful where you're at
 	
 	
 		yeah right right near <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC yeah</ENAMEX> are you a native of there
 	
 	
 		ah pretty much yep been
 	
 	
 		yeah uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> it is uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ninety two</NUMEX> degrees here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> but at least the humidity is uh below forty percent which makes it kind of like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Phoenix</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah it's about the same weather here little bit little bit cooler like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty nine</NUMEX> but basically the same thing
 	
 	
 		really
 		well you yeah well you're not missing too much then
 	
 	
 		yeah right
 	
 	
 		really well take it easy okay bye-bye
 	
 	
 		okay bye-bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	