
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		where are you from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um i'm from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> and um i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> who's
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months almost sixteen months old</TIMEX> are are you married or
 	
 	
 		yeah uh-huh i have i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> i have a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven year old</TIMEX> and a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three year</TIMEX> old
 	
 	
 		you are
 		oh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		and uh so i try to spend as much time as possible with them
 	
 	
 		that's good uh what kind of things do you do
 	
 	
 		well um
 		we
 		we do a lot of things with them you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Taylor Taylor</ENAMEX> my youngest is or my oldest is in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and so she has a lot of school programs and things like that
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		how was it a big change in your life to uh  have a child
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		um yeah it's really nice uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> uh um is is working most you know most of the time he's working <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">long hours</TIMEX> but uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i'm staying home
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh i'm just working <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple days a month</TIMEX> and um
 	
 	
 		oh uh-huh what do you do during those those days
 	
 	
 		um we we spend a lot of time at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">playground</ENAMEX> and we go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">zoo</ENAMEX> and we go and we watch
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah well you said you said you worked <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a couple</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> a month though what do what do you do
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurse</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh are you
 	
 	
 		so yeah so it's it's it's real easy to work out my schedule you know to uh get in to to still
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		stay in with that an and to have enough time to spend with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew</ENAMEX> he
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		he's uh just now really starting to to get interested in a lot of things  so um
 	
 	
 		yeah i understand that yeah
 		they really grow up quick especially at that early age
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> was uh she worked part time when my oldest was was little and now she's staying home all the time but uh that worked out really well because it's a big transition i think to have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		you know to go from you know nothing you know if you want to do something <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">every night</TIMEX> that's fine but when you have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> it doesn't work that way anymore so
 	
 	
 		that's right and i think a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are um are turning to
 		well i think i think a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are realizing that but still there are so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are you know have their careers <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> and it's uh i think it's really hurting the
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		yeah i agree with you i
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> you know but
 	
 	
 		i i think that
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> leaned that way and i'm really glad she did and you know i'm glad she's staying <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> but you know i know there are <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">some days</TIMEX> when she wishes she wishes she was back at work
 	
 	
 		i know
 		that's why i like to  to work to work <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple days</TIMEX> i think it's uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it gives me a break
 	
 	
 		yeah well see that's that's why i'm glad my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> did too because she worked either <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two to three three days a week</TIMEX> and that got her out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and yet she'd get to spend you know
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three or four days</TIMEX> with yeah yeah and so
 	
 	
 		most of the time at home yeah
 		uh we had started out like that and um i think that was
 		really ideal uh
 	
 	
 		yeah i do to i agree but then when you start having <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of them it's you know a little bit tougher
 	
 	
 		it's
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		because you've got to make a little more money to make that payoff and stuff
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		it's difficult but
 	
 	
 		are are you from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> area
 	
 	
 		uh-huh i'm i've i've lived here forever so
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		yeah i'm in i live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germantown</ENAMEX> and uh are you where are you from
 	
 	
 		um uh i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> oh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		so uh i'm i've lived here like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight years</TIMEX> or so my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort Worth</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh uh
 	
 	
 		but
 		yeah i work for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Instruments</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay oh  so that explains  well um i don't know i uh
 	
 	
 		yeah that explains it doesn't it
 	
 	
 		we we do a lot of things on the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekends</TIMEX> together the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> but uh
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		but as far as during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX> it's it's usually uh you know just my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> and i and we're
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		what's your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> do
 	
 	
 		uh he he works for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coca-Cola</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so he uh
 		he manages a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> out here <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an</TIMEX> and it takes a lot of time
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh yeah i'm sure it does
 	
 	
 		but um
 		it you know we take walks and  go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> and try to fill our day with things like that but um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		yeah what uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> did some teaching at like uh
 		like a private tutoring place
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sylvan Learning Center</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> and so that that got me to spend to be able to spend more time with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> and stuff
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		because normally if if they need something they just go to mom
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		no matter what it is i mean i could i'm perfectly capable of doing it for them but
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		it's so much easier to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> i guess they get used to it
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so but you know we'd go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> and do things like that yeah but
 	
 	
 		that's good
 		that's good i know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> was real uh in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the beginning</TIMEX> when he uh he was transferred to a a larger <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> and he um
 	
 	
 		but
 	
 	
 		he works <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about an hour and a half</TIMEX> away from here from our home and uh so it takes him a little bit of time and
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		i'm not able to work during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX> uh because of that he was i was working in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the evening</TIMEX> and he was coming home and i i could go to work but uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		their relationship uh when i was able to work in the evenings uh really grew he you know just the time that they were spending together
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i think it it really it really helped to have that time together
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> it really does because i think you you know you grow closer was your uh was your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> i mean naturally a child i mean had had he been around <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh oh yeah he has uh he has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> and they have
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		we have thirteen grand well his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> have thirteen <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandchildren</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so it's uh
 		you know there's a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and and he really enjoys it but uh right now it's kind of a difficult time but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and and the cost of living here is just so tremendously you know outrageous  um
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		it's difficult uh to do it any other way
 	
 	
 		yeah i understand
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um you know it's it's hard because then
 		you're not getting to spend as much time with at home i mean your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> is not getting to spend as much time at home as he'd want to
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		so yeah that that's a tough situation but then then again you know some you got to do what you got to do
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know to get along too so
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah at least i i just consider myself blessed that i can stay home  it uh
 	
 	
 		uh-huh well well like i said my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> normally feels that way there are <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> when uh i come home and she says here take these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> i'm getting out
 	
 	
 		i know
 	
 	
 		so she's she's had about enough during those days
 	
 	
 		i know
 	
 	
 		but but for the most part i you know i've really feel like that's led the way that you know what just like what you said with the cost of living and everything i think a lot of people can't afford to get by on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">just one</NUMEX> salary an
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and won't
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and so i think that's led tended to lead to a decline in in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> and family values especially
 	
 	
 		oh yeah it has
 	
 	
 		and i really think that that's one of the problems the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s facing that you know we need to do something about but i don't know what
 	
 	
 		i believe that too and i think uh
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are where they need to you know they need to really focus on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in the world in this
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		country
 	
 	
 		yeah would would you have said that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of years ago</TIMEX>
 		do you think
 	
 	
 		no i didn't i didn't even really think about it that much i mean you know i knew i was aware vaguely aware of it but um i didn't it wasn't really that important to me and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		it's amazing how your whole focus on life changes after you've had a child
 	
 	
 		oh it it really does i  just the whole uh
 		you know seeing how you really are creating are are forming this you know the mind
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		well you know in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next year or so</TIMEX> you'll see so many instances where you know he'll mimic something that you've done and you see you know everything i'm doing he's learning from
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		and and you think if i wasn't here he'd be learning that from a babysitter or from a day care
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know they that's how they're developing their patterns and i think a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> either don't care or don't realize it you know that's
 	
 	
 		or or they just put it in the back of their mind and let it slide i
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i've seen a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> just say well you know he'll learn everything when he gets into
 	
 	
 		yeah eventually
 	
 	
 		uh you know
 	
 	
 		yeah it's true
 	
 	
 		but it um
 		i i know even just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this first year</TIMEX> that i've been with uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> here here um he's i can just see how much
 		of of a difference it makes staying <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> with him instead of uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah plus plus i think it becomes part of you part of you too i mean you get to stay home i mean it's not just for him but it's also for you because you're both kind of bonding together there too i think so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		that's true
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		well it's been nice talking to you
 	
 	
 		well it's nice talking to you too
 	
 	
 		okay good luck okay good bye
 	
 	
 		okay bye bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	