
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well i know that uh i have only like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two or three</NUMEX> favorite television shows
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i think one of my favorite then is from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen is it Brochco</ENAMEX> who does like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LA Law</ENAMEX> uh-huh and uh he also did <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hillstreet Blues</ENAMEX> i like those type of shows
 	
 	
 		oh yeah uh-huh
 		yes
 		yeah we we really enjoy that too
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh i don't get a lot to watch a whole lot of TV we have a couple of young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we're usually outside and so it's usually <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the nine o'clock</TIMEX> shows shows that if we get them in bed we usually watch that and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L A Law</ENAMEX> is one of my favorites
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh yeah me too i know they uh i think they're different than a lot of other shows of which they have like the reruns in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the middle of the season</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and then towards <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX> when everybody else is showing reruns they start showing some of their newer stuff
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so i thought that was really interesting the way that they did that
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		oh and so you must watch a lot of uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> or cartoons then
 	
 	
 		well we have on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sesame Street</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mister Rogers</ENAMEX> that kind of stuff and i think those programs are really good for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> i know that both of mine have probably learned quite a bit from there
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's kind of nice to know that they're just going to be seeing you know not a lot of violence and that kind of stuff and they usually
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh show a lot of things that really teach them different things about the world so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> he's going to be <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> and he's more into watching the cartoons and that kind of stuff now so
 	
 	
 		oh that's true that's true well i noticed that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are uh older now they're uh getting close to the teenage <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> but they did we watched all of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mister Rogers</ENAMEX> and everything but even some of your uh cartoons can be very violent
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh you know they they talk about death and we were watching uh  oh gosh that <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Bugs Bunny</ENAMEX> just last night
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		and um uh i think it was on uh i have to remember which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX> but anyway uh we were watching that and it was talking about opera and they showed like what they thought an opera would be and one of the things was to kill the rabbit kill the rabbit
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and i thought oh how violent you know to kill the rabbit  so he ended up killing the rabbit in the end  uh but then of course the the rabbit comes back to life and says well see this is how an opera is supposed to be
 		and i thought gee <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whiz</ENAMEX> if a little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> was watching this you know that would be pretty violent even uh for a small child
 	
 	
 		well yeah and you know they especially <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> i mean they're always talking about shooting and killing and all that kind of stuff and i don't think that they really realize that death is forever you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		and showing them something like that really doesn't teach them that it is
 	
 	
 		that's right
 		that's right well i don't think cartoons portray that but like
 	
 	
 		no and to get them to feel like that that's just pretend i think is the hardest part you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> lives
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but they don't  they just have one like we do
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh so that's really funny  but uh we've gotten uh-huh go ahead
 	
 	
 		i  i was just going to say i know that
 		at least before our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> were born we used to always enjoy watching the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cosby Show</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nights</TIMEX> usually had pretty good with that and as far as um very good comedy
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i like to watch <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Designing Women</ENAMEX> if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are in bed by then
 	
 	
 		yes
 		yes yeah that's true that's a good show i used to watch uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> i don't i don't know where you're at
 	
 	
 		we're we're in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> uh-huh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> yeah yeah i used to watch <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years years ago</TIMEX>  and somewhere in the middle i got uh bored and uh so i in fact i didn't even watch the finale
 		uh you know that's about how disinterested i had become
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well i did watch it just to see what it was and wasn't it wasn't really that great so i think after a while they just kind of you know there's no new stuff they can do they've done everything dirty in the book you know so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well actually uh-huh
 		yep
 		yep i know i know was was it actually based on a book
 	
 	
 		well no i imagine
 	
 	
 		oh but you were just talking about okay
 	
 	
 		everything you could think of you know had a hard time and i think maybe with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> as far as they lost a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> that had been around at the first
 	
 	
 		okay
 		yeah right
 		that's true that's true
 	
 	
 		where i don't know i never watched <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Knots Landing</ENAMEX> but i think they've had a lot of their characters stay around
 	
 	
 		stay um-hum um-hum yeah in if you notice and if you notice on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> they lost all the women
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yes so the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> mainly stayed but the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> were the ones who left and i thought that was very interesting and wondered kind of wondered about that uh
 		well anyway that's a whole new issue  oh goodness so anyway i don't know if our  <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five minutes</TIMEX> are over yet
 	
 	
 		yeah  oh
 	
 	
 		but we uh we also have the paid uh television <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX> uh the only thing i don't like about it especially with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teenagers</ENAMEX> is that all the violence the sex the nudity and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">curse</ENAMEX> words
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know and so i know they didn't pick up these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">curse</ENAMEX> words from me so uh they had to have picked them up from uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">T V</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		one nice thing though about the cable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> we use they have uh
 		they have that little parental uh uh key yeah yeah um-hum  so i i have that at home and i keep the keys with me
 	
 	
 		where you can lock up the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX> or whatever
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and that's about the only way that i can that i can do it because their natural curiosity you know to go towards that way and want yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		and i don't know the way the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generations</ENAMEX> are up growing up now i mean i just think they watch so much more <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">T V</ENAMEX> i try to limit what they watch they aren't sitting in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> watching <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">T V</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all day</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because i think it's good for them to have physical activity and that kind of stuff too so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and especially in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> time we aren't in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> very much in the evenings it's the only cool time to be outside
 	
 	
 		that's true well and here lately it hasn't been that cool anyway with the humidity being so high
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well true
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well it was nice talking to you
 	
 	
 		well it was nice talking to you too
 	
 	
 		okay talk with you later good-bye
 	
 	
 		okay bye-bye
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	