
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well where what what's good in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX> to eat
 	
 	
 		well i think we're very fortunate because um in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past twenty years</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> has really developed a a good number of quality <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> um
 		mostly although you have your normal continental we've gotten the excellent excellent ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> um we have <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Ethiopian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> we have <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX>
 		um you know besides the normal range of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> and things like that so uh we try to experience
 		because i am Italian background and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> we really try to uh experience quite a bit of difference in cooking styles
 	
 	
 		well you have a lot to thank your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">noodles</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh God yeah  but
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i live in a great place i live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Berkeley California</ENAMEX> in what they call the gourmet ghetto it's uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's it's it's got every well it's it's a very uh polyglot community you know got every every kind of ethnic background you can think of but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		just up the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> is one of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only two five</NUMEX> star <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> on the east coast less than a block i mean on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Coast</ENAMEX> i think there's only like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> but
 	
 	
 		oh my
 		well what
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> is it continental
 	
 	
 		uh well no it's <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> actually
 	
 	
 		it it is <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> uh-huh
 	
 	
 		it she uh yeah yeah the the name of it is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chez Penny</ENAMEX> you may have heard of it but they uh they they  they specialize in flower salads actually
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		and i'm sure it's quite i'm sure it's quite pricey
 	
 	
 		and they got you know
 		well actually it's like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty five</TIMEX> dollars for the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meal</ENAMEX> and that's you know and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">each night</TIMEX> is a different that that there's never the same meal twice
 	
 	
 		oh
 		so it's a price fixed and you go in for the menu that they have
 	
 	
 		they
 		yeah and you go in you know and of course it's booked for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> on end
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		but they also have a um a uh i understand a buffet or something that you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> can just walk in
 	
 	
 		oh that's interesting uh-huh
 	
 	
 		you know combination this is like during <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the day</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		what kind of food do you like
 	
 	
 		oh good
 	
 	
 		
 
 		any specific any specific time
 	
 	
 		oh no no no i'm one of those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that as long as it's good it really doesn't matter
 	
 	
 		and and you're adventuresome
 	
 	
 		oh extremely yeah i was one of those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> that would go into a menu go into a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> when i was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> and and and would not order unless i had never had it before
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well we're very fortunate we have we have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX> and ever since they were even even very little they we very adventuresome i mean they tried frogs legs an and they tried rabbit and all sorts of things so uh
 		we've never had to have the problem of picky <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">eaters</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well it's oh i was a i was a picky eater when i was real young but then i got to the point where i discovered that you know
 	
 	
 		and
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		there was something other than than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Twinkies</ENAMEX> in the world
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh well they they've been they've been adventuresome since they were i mean even preschoolers they'll they tried anything
 	
 	
 		oh that's great
 	
 	
 		yeah so um  it's been fun it's been great and uh of course in the area of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> where we are of course crabs are one of our big delicacies
 	
 	
 		oh i know i know i i used to live back in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX> and i remember going to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">up to</NUMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Richmond James River</ENAMEX> and we'd get  and and flounder you don't we don't get flounder out here on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Coast</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh i know but you get some other kinds of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> that are just wonderful i know that you have abalone out there
 	
 	
 		yeah that's that's true that's true
 	
 	
 		and fresh i there's nothing to rely i mean fresh <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">abalone</ENAMEX> is wonderful
 	
 	
 		yeah it really is a lot of work but it's it's good really is
 	
 	
 		yes yes but uh you know <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore</ENAMEX> also is a wonderful eating city
 	
 	
 		uh yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore Baltimore</ENAMEX> i saw a movie about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore</ENAMEX> recently Abalon that's right
 	
 	
 		i'm
 		okay okay and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore</ENAMEX>'s got some great dining areas it's got little  ethnic communities
 		little pockets of ethnicity in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> and it's absolutely marvelous the  it's sort of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of these underrated <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> and they're some great <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> there
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		um it there are mostly um besides the little ethnic things you've got your great seafood places and there's one great <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> there called Hausners
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> of which um traveled all over the world and this place is <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> of art so that you feel you're in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> except it's completely over done
 		and it's it's a real place to bring <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> for something to talk about and it's a very <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> they've got the whole gamut of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> dishes
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		so uh when we go out i guess we look as you said you like to try when you were young something different we try to go out for either <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> things something to make it a festive occasion
 		and to try something very unusual  or else we go back to a few of our uh for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> we usually follow the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chef</ENAMEX>
 		if we know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chef</ENAMEX>'s in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> and what their specialties are so there are certain <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> this is something i learned from my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> where you only eat certain things
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		and uh other things that they don't produce in you know in quality but other aspect other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> you would eat other things so uh
 		we we do tend to eat out at least once a week sometimes more although with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX> in college now that may be it may be a little less
 	
 	
 		yes well  uh uh of of course without <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX> it's it's it's also easier to go out isn't it i mean
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		really you know i mean
 	
 	
 		it certainly is
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so uh what's what's your major consideration when you go out to dinner
 	
 	
 		well uh basically it it's it's it's it's good <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> and and uh price comes into it some you know not not
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah which would so it's fun to find good <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> for a reasonable price too
 	
 	
 		yeah well that's what's really great about where i live here it's in in an area that's within you know <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four or five</NUMEX> blocks there must be forty <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> i'm not kidding it's just uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh that's
 		oh well how tempting
 	
 	
 		it's in you know it's just just down from the from um <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of California Berkeley</ENAMEX> and uh and it's
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and that that's what's good about it is that the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the the</TIMEX> the prices are extremely reasonable and the competition is so keen that the food really is good so you know you
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		we have to we have to drive  any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> where we're not in walking area of any even a store so we do have to drive but within you know within a um
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fifteen</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty minute</TIMEX> drive we have a whole span of of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> that we can chose from and unless you go into downtown <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> and the elegant areas
 		uh even the some of the areas in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> you can get very reasonable and very tasty meals and uh
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one one</NUMEX> more time what was the name of that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore</ENAMEX> the German
 	
 	
 		Hausners
 	
 	
 		Hausners i'll
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hausners H A U S N E R S um</ENAMEX>-hum
 	
 	
 		have to remember that well <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda</ENAMEX> it's been a pleasure talking to you
 	
 	
 		yeah if you ever get out there
 		well i enjoyed talking with you too all right bye-bye
 	
 	
 		all right you have a good one bye-bye
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	