
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		all right do you have a bunch of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factories</ENAMEX> and stuff out there
 	
 	
 		um we've got
 		quite a few actually what we're more concerned with is the inner pollution in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> uh we've actually had some warnings in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Raleigh</ENAMEX> uh on air pollution
 	
 	
 		the uh
 		oh you mean
 		for like smog and stuff
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> because of there're so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> and we have a belt line along around <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Raleigh</ENAMEX> where we're trying to divert traffic
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		and um you know it's it's still it's just surrounding the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> and you can actually see it there's <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a couple of uh</NUMEX> tall <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Raleigh</ENAMEX> and and you can actually you know they're blurred they're even dark and what it is is the pollution
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		huh
 		what do you think of that uh the
 		greenhouse effect that's going on
 	
 	
 		well i guess that's fluorocarbons the fluorocarbons and uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		that's causing the hole in the ozone
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah that's very serious i mean we can we're even feeling the effects of the weather from uh uh the shift in the jet stream
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> it it is scary though isn't it
 	
 	
 		oh yeah i mean uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last two uh years our winters</TIMEX> have been absolutely nothing i mean maybe one snow
 	
 	
 		
 
 		right
 		well all right <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX> that's up there by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kentucky</ENAMEX> isn't it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kentucky</ENAMEX> uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX> is all the way on the east coast it's further west than <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgia</ENAMEX> it's uh right below <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		okay
 		okay well <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kentucky</ENAMEX>'s next to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> i'm pretty sure well i'm from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kentucky</ENAMEX> i should know but i don't i'm sorry but <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kentucky</ENAMEX> we use to have severe i mean just real cold cold <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winters</TIMEX> and we'd have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">four feet</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">snow</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">course</ENAMEX> here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they don't have snow they don't know what snow is they freak out when there's snow on the ground  oh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Amarillo</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">well</ENAMEX> that's close to here how long have you been in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Raleigh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX>  originally i'm from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> so i mean <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Amarillo</ENAMEX> so uh uh-huh
 		yeah real close
 		um i've been out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		well how old are you
 	
 	
 		oh twenty uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX>  i almost forgot my age oh really
 	
 	
 		okay well we're the same age  yeah i forget my age all the time so that's okay it's i think it's just something that goes with the territory  but to me <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> see and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kentucky</ENAMEX> we had to have <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX> on the ground for them to close school okay
 	
 	
 		hum
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> i'm serious if it gets <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cold</ENAMEX> and it looks like it's going to rain i i swear they close everything down i just laugh i mean i do they get i mean and traffic slows down to nothing
 	
 	
 		
 
 		actually they've been doing the same thing here it's you know it's kind of funny they um i guess northerners are different but even uh <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">North Carolinians</ENAMEX> they don't know how to handle cold weather
 	
 	
 		oh well no northern i'm from the north that's why i said we in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kentucky</ENAMEX> we i don't know you just get used to weather and of course the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> down in south they don't they're not used to cold weather and stuff and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it just i don't know i just laugh everytime they have a
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		everytime they have snow on the ground everything's closed up and you know you can have snow on the ground and not be slick on the road
 	
 	
 		that's true
 	
 	
 		but uh
 	
 	
 		do you all have much pollution there
 	
 	
 		no not really i mean not to see it now of course there's you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> is here <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oscar Mayer</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and there is a few <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factories</ENAMEX> but i don't see much pollution going on
 	
 	
 		well you know what irks me is these <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> that are driving down the road and you have that black smoke coming from their tail pipe
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well see they have that um uh what is it a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vet</ENAMEX> test or something like that they call it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh that's supposed to cut down on it
 	
 	
 		well supposedly that's supposed to catch it but i'll tell you what and even these <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">buses</ENAMEX> oh lord it's real bad these <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">buses</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Raleigh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah school <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">buses</ENAMEX> and the commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">buses</ENAMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		i mean school <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">buses</ENAMEX> are notorious
 	
 	
 		well they're burning that diesel <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fuel</ENAMEX> is what it is
 	
 	
 		oh yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		it it gets bad
 	
 	
 		well you know what they've started doing is is instead of the tail pipes being at the bottom of those <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">buses</ENAMEX> they've started putting them up at the top
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and that way it gets above um other <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> on the road
 	
 	
 		well that's a good idea
 	
 	
 		and uh it really does make a difference although it it settles you know even if it's at the top and it's a lot of black smoke coming out it still settles and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and you know if you're going to be jogging on the side of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> that's that's even more miserable i would i'd have to go out to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> to jog
 	
 	
 		well uh the you know pregnant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> aren't supposed to walk along a highway
 	
 	
 		no i didn't know that
 	
 	
 		because of that smoke fumes when i was pregnant with my first little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> i had read it because back then i was walking back and forth to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kentucky</ENAMEX> from well not back and forth i was walking home from uh
 		the college i was going to in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kentucky</ENAMEX> and i was having to walk along the highway it was just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day a week</TIMEX> but it was in
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i i have no sense of smell so i couldn't smell this but
 		it would make me sick and i'd be real tired anyway just from walking along the highway
 	
 	
 		hum
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		golly that's
 	
 	
 		but yeah it's yeah it's all the exhaust uh well that was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years ago</TIMEX> too it's probably a lot worse now yeah
 	
 	
 		that's bad
 		oh i'm sure well they um you can really feel it you know in your breathing even normal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and if you're older um i mean you can really
 		deplete your <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oxygen</ENAMEX> and it'll you know pass out and it's you know it's killed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">several</NUMEX> people
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		do you uh
 		smoke
 	
 	
 		um actually i'm a very i just smoke one in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the evening</TIMEX> if that so i'm a very very light smoker
 	
 	
 		well yeah it's kind of like
 	
 	
 		it was kind of funny  they were doing some uh ozone testing and uh the the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> and they were just screening some candidates
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i don't think i'd ever you know do that but they uh asked me if i was a smoker and i didn't fit into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">smoker</ENAMEX>'s category and i didn't fit into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">nonsmoker</ENAMEX>'s category um it was you know i was just one of those
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah because you do smoke <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> a day
 	
 	
 		yeah in between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> so that kind of threw them off
 	
 	
 		hum uh
 	
 	
 		but they're doing a lot of research here uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		for the air pollution
 	
 	
 		for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ozone</ENAMEX> and oh yeah all that they're they're real big into it they've got <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Research Triangle Park</ENAMEX> here
 		and they're you know they're just doing a lot of uh lot of stuff
 	
 	
 		huh
 		but they i don't hear much about it down here course <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> we don't have a bunch of  pollution but too we've got that air coming in off the coast and you know it'd blow it up north
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">hum-um</ENAMEX>
 		oh uh-huh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so maybe that's part of the reason it's not so bad down here
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but no it'd seem like it would be the same way in on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> coastline wouldn't it
 	
 	
 		oh gosh i think i would hate to live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> the smog there i mean i can't believe they have warnings here which it it's mainly just when it gets real real hot
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		but they usually have that everywhere because of the humidity especially
 	
 	
 		really well well that's kind of good to know because i thought Lord i thought i lived in a halfway decent area
 	
 	
 		i think they do that for most everybody it's especially it's usually for the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and the older
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		the old people
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		older old people
 	
 	
 		well you ought to come to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX> it's a big change  yeah
 	
 	
 		it is
 	
 	
 		there's no trees where i was from in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Amarillo</ENAMEX> and here they've got the mountains the beach the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> you know it's they've got streams rivers ponds it's really pretty here
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh
 		oh well this is pretty wooded area down here so in in a lot of parts yeah i know <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> is supposed to be flat but they've got you know down by the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Denison Dam</ENAMEX> there's a lot of uh
 	
 	
 		is it
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sherman</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Denison</ENAMEX> do you know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX> live in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Durant</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they do  they live close then in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Durant Oklahoma</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah real close i go there yeah
 	
 	
 		you go where
 		uh you go to visit them
 	
 	
 		oh uh-huh
 		yeah we used to go fishing in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lake</ENAMEX> Texoma
 	
 	
 		oh
 		yeah well down by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lake Texoma</ENAMEX> there's a bunch of wooded area this but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kentucky</ENAMEX>'s beautiful they've got <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> are supposed to you know purify you know what the best indoor purifying <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> is for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">smoke</ENAMEX> and stuff it's a philodendron
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">huh huh-uh</ENAMEX>
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		it's supposed to filter the air for you in your home i had one my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> bought it for me when my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> was born <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three months ago four months ago</TIMEX> yeah i do  yeah i do
 	
 	
 		well i'm going to have to get some
 		um-hum do you smoke
 		do you
 		did you smoke when you when you were pregnant
 	
 	
 		yeah i did i couldn't make myself quit i did cut down a lot  i got i've i've got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">smoke</ENAMEX> is smoking is it i don't i don't drink and i try not to cuss and i don't i do
 	
 	
 		well i mean i can understand that actually
 		well
 		
 
 	
 	
 		very little and smoking i just i got in the habit of it when i was about thirteen
 	
 	
 		yeah well one thing i miss is uh is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> are are you know i miss their morals their values and everything it's uh
 	
 	
 		yeah we're down here at the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX> belt aren't we uh i wasn't saved until i got down here and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> down here are just there's so many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christians</ENAMEX> and it's so
 		different from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kentucky</ENAMEX> but
 	
 	
 		um-hum how'd you get involved in this research
 	
 	
 		um i worked at <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> for a while but then my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">brother-in-law works</ENAMEX> there and he got me into it
 	
 	
 		oh i see huh
 	
 	
 		how'd you get into it
 	
 	
 		um i i was taking a voice IO class
 		and um and actually doing some research and so they told me about this project
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well it's fun i like talking to new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and i
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		half the time well a couple of times i've been interrupted by my little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> i've had to hang up and stuff but i enjoy it i talked <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from well <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carolina well Carolina</ENAMEX> now
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		up in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> well <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> isn't it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		uh no <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>'s above uh-huh
 	
 	
 		no <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston Massachusetts</ENAMEX>  but i've talked to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> but i've talked to a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 		because i guess it's because of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX>'s down here
 	
 	
 		yeah i've talked to a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> i had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> call from actually from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte North Carolina</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> and um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i can't remember where all
 		um up north like you said i think one was from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well
 		with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> i love their accent  i do i love a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> accent accent i met a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> one time my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> was in the service so we went from
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kentucky</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisiana</ENAMEX> down here to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>'s down here we're out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> now but yeah he got out of it his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> right after <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Panama</ENAMEX> we went to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Panama</ENAMEX> he went to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Panama</ENAMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Noriega</ENAMEX> was doing all that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh i bet you're glad
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh gosh
 	
 	
 		and uh he
 		
 		
 	