
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i know they have a waiting list and a quota on immigration now
 	
 	
 		i've lost track i don't really know i i do have some opinions but go ahead
 	
 	
 		yeah um well i know that they're they're real cautious about letting <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Middle Eastern</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> into the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> now because of all the terrorism
 		what do
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		what what
 	
 	
 		okay i hadn't thought about that uh
 	
 	
 		what all do you know about it
 	
 	
 		uh well i just have an opinion now i didn't think i i thought the terrorism thing was overstated i mean there was nothing over here in fact even
 		this is not our subject i guess but uh
 		or maybe it is or isn't i suppose
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> when she talked about the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> and everyone's afraid you know of how the war was going to go and everything i said i said i told her i said no it's just not going to happen there's not going to be any terrorism over here and there wasn't you know
 		they they just didn't have an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> but uh
 		i i concerned i'm concerned that we're letting too many that we don't have enough controls i think that uh
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gangsters</ENAMEX> that we've let in here and if and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> from uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX> you know there there's a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> down in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> that we've let in from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fidel</ENAMEX> pushed off on us and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and and the last you know out of all the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asians</ENAMEX> we brought in there there's a tremendous criminal element that we let in from from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX> and i think that there's got to be some sort of controls over that i mean this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asia mafia</ENAMEX> thing is getting out of hand
 	
 	
 		that's right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i i don't i don't i didn't know what i don't even know what our controls are i don't even know what uh
 		uh we if we have any guidelines at all uh on on immigration um
 		i always thought that we did but i don't i don't i don't i don't know what they are right now
 	
 	
 		there i don't think there's much of much of one because i'm sure all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX> have been released from that <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> that they were in
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh most of them it's just like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX> most of them were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX> and i think that was just an attempt that that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fidel Castro</ENAMEX> to undermine you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> to some extent so he just released and got rid of all his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> and sent them to us
 	
 	
 		yeah the
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and it's almost the same thing in in uh from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX> because
 		a lot of a lot of them was put out of business in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> after the war and
 	
 	
 		because we
 		i i do have some sympathy with uh you know of course we have this big <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> problem not a problem but i think that we need to do something with uh the immigration of back and across forth across
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i
 		uh i'm sympathetic i don't know what the answer is i guess i'm sympathetic certainly with that that that they they want to come over here and they i guess <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds of thousands</NUMEX> come over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> to work
 		and if if they have if they have jobs you know i i hear the story about they're taking away <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> jobs but i don't know
 		uh i don't know how many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> jobs they are really taking away i'm so i i'm sympathetic but i don't have an answer i don't uh
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i think that we should have good relations with with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> but that's not really exactly immigration it is and it isn't uh i i don't know to what degree we owe
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who come across before they're <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> owe owe the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> education and all that uh
 		although the idea their education is an answer to a lot of problems in the world so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i guess it's what they their the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> get a
 		good education along the way maybe that's a benefit to everybody you know
 	
 	
 		yeah and uh a lot of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> just cross the border during <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the daytime</TIMEX> to come over here and work
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they have green cards and uh then like you said a lot of i run into <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> that can't speak <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		and and most of them you know are working in janitorial positions so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		and that
 	
 	
 		so i i don't know you like you said i don't know how much how much they're taking from the work force you know
 	
 	
 		yeah i never thought that they were much i do cringe when i hear some of the problems we've had
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh um uh
 		of course you mentioned the language i i feel so bad that we here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> or certainly the southern part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California Texas</ENAMEX> and all that just why our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> don't speak fluid <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> uh
 		by junior high you know um as well as us you know
 	
 	
 		hm
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so that we could wouldn't have a language barrier certainly now that is a shame that we
 		uh have this tremendous border of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> and then in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> you know they they speak their <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> and all and they try they go out of their way to try to speak their their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX>'s language so they can understand we we certainly we don't really even make an effort
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		to speak <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Spanish</ENAMEX> and i feel bad about that
 		uh go ahead
 	
 	
 		well that's i yeah i took <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and that's you know one reason that i did it is because
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		because whenever you travel anywhere near the border you know there more and more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> speak <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Spanish</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i guess it's never too late i i do have some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> books and i've always uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> i say i'm going to try to speak uh some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">newcomers</ENAMEX> language you know
 		i don't know if it's costing us any money or how much money they're putting into it uh that's always a factor i mean how much my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> says they how much the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is putting into
 	
 	
 		well yeah well it's basically on the well i think it's mostly concentrated toward the borders and uh it's more um the immigration is tied in with uh drug trafficking so
 	
 	
 		immigration
 	
 	
 		they have to watch out who comes in and and they're always finding <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> on you know on the most um innocent looking kind of
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i forgot what they found but a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> found it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX> you know on on the border
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		oh yeah i i think that certainly is a problem uh
 		i guess our immigration history that's a great subject uh they didn't say to talk about that but that is
 		i mean uh on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellis Island</ENAMEX> they you know they're redoing that and going to make it a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> a national <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		now that certainly was interesting since all of us had
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> ancestors that came over that way or not all but i guess uh i guess if you go back far enough you came over on a
 		uh
 		a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> originally you know but uh
 		a lot of us have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents grandparents</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX> came over in
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about eighteen ninety</NUMEX> or something like that and i'm sure they came over
 		you know through <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellis Island</ENAMEX> you know
 	
 	
 		that's right yeah
 	
 	
 		so uh we all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> in one way or or another well we certainly are coming from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> you know or not
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah and one of the one of the things that really gets to me uh about the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexicans</ENAMEX> is that um once they have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> over here their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> then
 	
 	
 		oh yeah that those were laws are unusual you know
 	
 	
 		yeah and then they'll ship the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> back and that leaves the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> without any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		yeah that i don't understand i mean uh whose rule is that you know
 	
 	
 		and they you know and they and and they just follow the rule no matter you you know
 		so that doesn't seem fair to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah sometimes common sense should take over rather than yeah that's a law doesn't sound like it makes any sense at all
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		that you would do it that way
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you would think they could at least get a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a</NUMEX> a visa or something until they uh got citizenship i'm sure they want to
 	
 	
 		yeah and then they granted them amnesty if they could prove when was that and it was in the eighties sometime if they if they could prove they'd been here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		i heard something about that yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh a lot of them had been you know some of them some of them moved back and forth but uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		most of them don't ever want to go back to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> especially the way it was then
 	
 	
 		oh no
 		oh no i i could see uh
 		you can see why
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i don't know how much immigration we have from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> and everything what the controls are
 	
 	
 		i think most you know like especially the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrities</ENAMEX> and everything they just have a
 		uh well they have to get a green card if they're going to do any kind of work you know in the movies and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and such but most of them have temporary visas
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i guess you can get work visas pretty easily uh
 	
 	
 		as long it's like well it's it's a kind of a
 		a bad a bad example but when <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rafael</ENAMEX> Septien
 		took the job with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cowboys</ENAMEX> they had to offer his job to any other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">applicant</ENAMEX> that could do it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		so that you know and that's the thing with the jobs
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and of course no one beat him out so you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		he just ruined his own career so
 	
 	
 		oh well yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah well it's it's still interesting after all this time that we're probably one of the
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the few <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are still you know desperately trying to immigrate to
 		uh although i guess <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> now that the Communism is falling apart that maybe there'll be
 		won't be that much of a rush to get out of all the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist Communist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> uh
 		i guess <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Poland</ENAMEX> now is now a non <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		maybe not maybe immigration from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> to here will slowly you know slowly
 		uh change maybe it'll be even out like trade you know so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> will
 		immigrate here in in the twentieth at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at the year</TIMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two thousand</NUMEX>
 		so many of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who will go back overseas you know maybe it'll average out i don't know
 	
 	
 		yeah i think so
 	
 	
 		it doesn't has doesn't seem so far but
 	
 	
 		because there are other uh job uh uh job opportunities in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> that there aren't here and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know even um like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">orchestra orchestra players</ENAMEX> can find a job sometimes in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> when they can't find one here and um i'm a trumpet player
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		are you a teacher
 	
 	
 		uh no i uh i don't anymore i just went to school and i was a music major for a while
 	
 	
 		oh really yeah
 	
 	
 		but i had a trumpet <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> that played in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico City</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Symphony</ENAMEX> so so he had to have a work visa there
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and of course they had a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">musicians</ENAMEX> from from other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> and uh in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico City</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Symphony</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i think um like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> out of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>
 		other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the trumpet section are from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> now
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		but i think the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conductor</ENAMEX> i don't know or one of the conductors is is from another country
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's like any other symphony
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know and then and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eduardo Mana's</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> so
 		so he had to you know
 		
 		
 	