
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well what do you think about gun control
 	
 	
 		well i tell you i'm i'm for some really strong gun control measures but i mean that opens a lot of questions that i don't have any answers for
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it's like i'd i'd like to see a lot of controls um on it and because i would like uh i think
 		the purpose you know with a purpose goal and a purpose in mind of seeing violence decrease in our society but uh how to get from here to there i'm not sure
 	
 	
 		i wouldn't be for against control if it
 		made it virtually impossible for even <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> to get them
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		that's the problem is when you when you you know you take it away from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who don't intend to ever use them for for a violent crime other than hunting and things like that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> can always continue to get the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> regardless they can get them through the black market or whatever so i'm not sure if gun control in it's true sense that they're trying to implement it will ever work
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		but i i think what would happen though is that yes you would have a certain type of criminal a certain criminal element that would um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		be be able to find a way to get the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> but i think in a lot of domestic  uh disputes and a lot of family disputes um i'm not sure that those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would be able to get a hold of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX>
 		you know in other words a a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> that has a history say of physical abuse or physical violence but isn't the kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> that's involved in criminal activities if if there were gun controls and that there just were not <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> accessible to that type of family
 	
 	
 		yeah i think you know if it when it came down to these uh what i what i would consider militant type <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> assault <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">rifles</ENAMEX> and you know hand <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> because i'm i'm not i'm not a real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocate</ENAMEX> of hand <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> i i mean i do i do own one
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		do you
 	
 	
 		but i own it for protection i know how to use it i know when not to use it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i think for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> that's inexperienced has no business with one
 		uh
 	
 	
 		uh-huh i know well that's the thing i'm not really sure if i want to um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		learn how to use one i'm not sure i could use one i i've thought a lot about this there was something that came up that made me think a lot about it and i i'm not sure uh somebody was saying that you'd have to
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		you know be able to pull the trigger in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX> and i guess i always thought if it was threatening my personal safety or especially like my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well the reason i say we were uh we personally have experienced a major crime in our family
 	
 	
 		you have uh-huh
 	
 	
 		and uh you know with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh my goodness
 	
 	
 		they were kidnapped
 	
 	
 		you're kidding
 	
 	
 		and
 		you know and and it's really made me look differently
 	
 	
 		i can imagine
 	
 	
 		at the way it is you know and uh i'm not saying that i if i'd had a gun i could have done you know anything because i i really wasn't even there it happened while i was away but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but i think there are certain cases where it could get you in trouble you have to be able to know when it when it can and when it can't if it came in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the middle of the night</TIMEX> where if i could get my hands on it and do something with it that's one thing uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		um-hum yeah
 		but yeah that's the that is the thing see as in the past say <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX> i've evolved from thinking no i'm really i'm so much of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pacifist</ENAMEX> that
 		i would have to find another way to deal with the situation or deal with being victimized you know i couldn't use a gun hold on just a minute
 		sorry we have kind of an open house and the sound really travels um
 	
 	
 		that's all right
 		well i've kind of got pros and cons about both there there there there's good things and bad things and there's there's a lot of details that you you know it's hard to work out all the details
 	
 	
 		uh-huh no
 		yeah but i but i what i started to say is i've come to the point now where i'm thinking no i really want to take a self defense course and i want to take control over
 		um you know my own defense and my own safety i i i think i'm just i need to take responsibility more responsibility for that than i do right now i think i just
 		i allow myself to think well it will never happen to me or it won't happen to me you know i'm not going to have to deal with that and i just i don't think that's it will i'm sure yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah i assure you it it can it can and and the chances you know because we've been through a lot of the the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> battles and all this other stuff over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> because they're behind bars now but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but they won't be there long and and we we've had to deal you know we've had to deal with a lot of that and
 	
 	
 		oh boy
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the the frightening thing is and and i can i can tell you from you know just statistics and and from even other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i've talked with your chances is one is actually one in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> right now
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		wow
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> out of every <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> is has and i'm talking about a major crime committed against them now it's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> out of every <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four or five</NUMEX> for just a a crime
 	
 	
 		wow
 		right
 		right
 	
 	
 		whether it be just normal robbery or whatever
 	
 	
 		holy <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">smoke</ENAMEX> that's wild i was talking again i was talking with somebody just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> and about about crime in general i guess it's been on the news a lot lately and i guess must be in the back of everybody's mind but i was saying
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> around here think if they just get a better security <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">system</ENAMEX> and a higher <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">fence</ENAMEX> that you know they're going to take care of themselves and i said there's it's going to come to a point it
 		where that you can't get a fence that's high enough and a security system that's good enough
 	
 	
 		well actually the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a</NUMEX> a higher <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">fence</ENAMEX> is less is more of a security risk
 	
 	
 		yeah because
 	
 	
 		than a normal average <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> foot fence did you know that
 	
 	
 		no kidding no i
 	
 	
 		yeah we thought because we had an <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> foot fence
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the problem is they can get behind it and they can do a lot behind an <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> foot fence
 	
 	
 		oh that they can't do behind a
 	
 	
 		that they can't do behind a normal fence
 	
 	
 		that's something wow
 	
 	
 		um in fact they say it's actually it's you're actually more secure if you have no <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">fence</ENAMEX> at all
 	
 	
 		yeah well i can see how that might be now i mean you don't have to answer this or not if you don't want to because i know it's a personal thing but with the crime that your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> was involved in was was there were there <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> involved in that
 	
 	
 		but uh
 		yes
 	
 	
 		there were gosh
 	
 	
 		yes
 		yeah they well they didn't use them but they put they put the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> to their heads
 	
 	
 		that is really
 		well they don't have to use them in that case i mean they just have to have them
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		and you know they they physically were not harmed in any way they were very lucky
 	
 	
 		they weren't yeah um-hum
 	
 	
 		and and knowing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> and his record his normal motif is to kill them he just he just happened not to he put them in the trunk of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and drove them out and left them
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		really
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">wow</ENAMEX> is he just crazy
 	
 	
 		yeah he's just basically crazy he's he's been he's been in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prisons</ENAMEX> you know a couple times
 	
 	
 		wow
 	
 	
 		and yet he's out in a very little time
 	
 	
 		he has killed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and he's and he's out <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		one he's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> but he's he's used them not maybe necessarily killed them but that's his normal style i mean that that's what he would do in a in a confronted situation
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah yeah
 		yeah if he could
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh you know he's he's been it's been proven that he that he's not uh
 	
 	
 		gosh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">society</ENAMEX> material
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but yet you know like i say he'll be back out on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> just because of this this new you know uh
 	
 	
 		there's no <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> space
 	
 	
 		yeah there's no prison <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">space</ENAMEX> but you know you you come to the point where you have to  you have to say either they're rehabilitatable or not
 	
 	
 		right you got to do <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> or the other
 	
 	
 		uh you know and those that they that they that that clinically are nuts and out of their minds
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		or those who have committed a murder who are who will do it again because they've they've said you know when a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s murdered somebody out of cold <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> the chances are they would do it again because they feel no remorse
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		gosh
 	
 	
 		they need and i and i and i hate to say this because i know it sounds awfully bad but they need to eliminate them
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they need to get them out of society
 	
 	
 		yeah i because we can't
 	
 	
 		
  
 		we can't tolerate it anymore we don't we we we flat don't have the space we don't have the money
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		spend it on the ones who who do have a chance
 	
 	
 		have a chance
 		did you did you hear about that um prison reform that's going up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> state or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oregon</ENAMEX> or someplace up there where they're taking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> who are repeat <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offenders</ENAMEX> and i mean really repeat offenders
 		that uh have raped several times or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> molesters that have molested several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> over and over again
 		and they have put them in i don't even think they call it a police a a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> but that's some kind of special it's a separate building
 		in a separate location and they are just in there indefinitely they don't have any time when they are going to be released
 	
 	
 		i i mean i've i've heard of you know similar programs but to me i mean if
 	
 	
 		um-hum that
 	
 	
 		and i i you know again i hate to say this but had they had they really hurt my family
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		or whatever
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i would have stopped at nothing to ensure they were dead
 	
 	
 		yeah i i understand that
 	
 	
 		i and i i hate to say that but i i mean it's it's just you they they violate your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> of course at that point you don't have much to lose and i hate i really hate to say that but i think that i would be that uh taken buy it
 	
 	
 		no
 		that's right
 		that's right
 		no i can understand i i can understand and respect that i have my own <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and i
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i've i saw a story on TV <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time about a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> who did take revenge on um someone who had hurt his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and shot the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> and um i
 		you know i remembered that that was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> and i remember seeing that and and i really could understand where that was coming from
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 		but the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> are the ones that are the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> are made the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> i mean they're the ones that that end up hurting the worst
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yep i i've heard that
 	
 	
 		and that that's really a shame but as far you know but as far as gun control goes i think that there needs there definitely needs to be some measures taken because not everybody's capable of owning of owning and and taking care of a weapon
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		and using it yeah and terrible accidents do happen when there's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> around
 	
 	
 		and
 		yeah
 		you know it's hard to say that
 	
 	
 		but on the other hand you can't rely i mean  the whole time i was growing up up until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last five years</TIMEX> i always thought well the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> will handle it
 		you know they'll get it under control and i just don't feel that way
 	
 	
 		well there's not enough policemen
 	
 	
 		well i don't feel that's true anymore they're not going to be able to handle it
 	
 	
 		no well there's not enough policeman
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">detectives</ENAMEX> or whatever you know and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have to learn to
 		to help themselves some they have by being extra careful
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh by you know by knowing the signs of a crime of a crime beginning to happen or whatever
 		and and frankly frankly just reporting them a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't they they choose not to get involved when in fact they really should
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		wow that would that would be hard to understand
 	
 	
 		yeah well i mean lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> say well i don't want to get involved because then you know because then if you know if they get off then they are going to come after me uh you know there's a lot there's a lot of that well see to me i i will never stand by
 	
 	
 		oh yeah but still
 		yeah you can't yeah
 	
 	
 		i i won't
 		
 		
 	