
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		there you go
 		
 
 	
 	
 		what do you think invades your privacy
 	
 	
 		oh well <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that call on the phone all the time to try to sell you something
 		you know that that try to sell you the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> and uh what carpet cleaning and uh
 		what else roof repair
 		uh
 		and enough well i think it's a waste of paper the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that always leave uh
 		junk mail and
 		because um you just end up throwing it away most of the time
 		probably eighty percent of the the junk mail that you get is is um
 		something that you don't need
 		and the same way with those calls
 		what is it oh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MCI MCI</ENAMEX> really does even when you tell them no they keep calling back
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MCI</ENAMEX> what's that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MCI</ENAMEX> it's the long distance telephone company
 	
 	
 		oh now see i i really don't have much trouble with
 		i just say no thank you and hang up
 	
 	
 		um-hum well they won't they won't take a no for an answer here for some reason
 		they just keep calling back
 	
 	
 		i had a carpet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> call up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		all within in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an hour</TIMEX> but
 		i uh i do telemarketing
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so uh i'm very polite and i just say no thank you and say no thank you very politely and i hang up and
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		don't bother me after that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so i think the only thing that really bothers me
 		is if
 		when somebody contacts me and
 		they try to get information out of me like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Census Bureau United States Census Bureau</ENAMEX> that bothered me
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh yeah um-hum
 	
 	
 		i didn't feel they had a right to know how many <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedrooms</ENAMEX> were in my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> even
 	
 	
 		
  
 		right
 	
 	
 		that i think is my invasion privacy because it's the government
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		and i don't understand what their need to know is
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i think that is my biggest objection to anything as far as
 		invading my privacy if somebody wants personal information out of me
 		but telephone calls
 		i figure they don't bother me one way or the other
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh i know when i do telemarketing um
 		i'm a soft <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>  if if someone says i am not interested i'll just say fine and back out
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i make very good sales but i'm not uh as i said
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		i'm not <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> as pushy as these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> because i don't really care i mean
 		if if they're not interested fine you know that's it
 	
 	
 		
 
 		you can't force them to be
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		and i'm not pushing something down their throat that uh i don't think is a good item anyway that i don't think i could do anyway
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
 
 		but i feel like oh movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> or sure it's part of their
 		i guess they're
 		
 
 		portray being a movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> they get themselves in these rag sheets but uh
 		i think they go too far i think that's invasion of privacy
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		because they follow them around <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty four hours a day</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah  oh yeah
 	
 	
 		and you know they do <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Kennedy</ENAMEX>
 		of course he's breaking the law all the time so it's a different story then
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		you know but but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed McMahon</ENAMEX> i mean you know who cares about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed McMahon</ENAMEX>
 		he's probably hasn't done anything interesting in the last <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty years</TIMEX> that they've been on the air
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		you know and he has a chauffeur maybe he drinks but he never drives a car either you know it's not the same with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnny Carson</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no i think my seriously my classification of of
 		invasion of privacy is trying to get personal information
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and putting it falsely out or just bombarding me for the answers
 	
 	
 		
  
 		without your and without your permission um-hum
 	
 	
 		right
 		this to me is is my invasion of privacy
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		anytime i can honestly say no or
 		throw the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> away or but you can always write to uh
 		oh i forgot the name of it and stop the junk mail that i've done
 		because i don't want junk mail anyway so i wrote to them when it came on the air so i don't get any of that bull that it works by the way
 	
 	
 		oh good
 	
 	
 		but uh the telephone doesn't bother me because i leave it half the time on uh
 		you know answering <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> anyway unless i'm home
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so i figure i can turn it off <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> way or the other but
 		i think that's the only bottom line thing that i dislike
 		because it does other than the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U S Census</ENAMEX> um what was it
 		oh the the carpet place that called me <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that i felt was invasion because it was the same carpet place and called me <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times
 		i mean one should be sufficient
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		but if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't use the telephone it's like i don't know when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">police</ENAMEX> has their
 		project going and i don't know when the other ones have their project going and when they want to pick up down my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> for things that's the only way i know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh that's it
 	
 	
 		well you have to have the telephone but
 		you can't you know and and it's sometimes it's hard to screen out all the calls that you don't want
 	
 	
 		well see there's no way of knowing that's you know that's the problem like the product i sell
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh i sell mostly to older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> which can't get it in a normal public situation
 		the only way we'd get to them is by telephone
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		and uh most of them like it because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> i work for is nationwide
 		and uh reputable and they know that hey we're backing it <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one hundred</NUMEX> percent
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but if we were denied the right to call <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> up these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would never be able to get it
 		because your normal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> that offer it do not offer it in the amounts that we do and they'd never have it then at that point
 	
 	
 		hm uh-hum
 	
 	
 		because we offer it in a very low you know quantity
 		so i mean i i don't know what to do as far as that's concerned but it is nerve racking
 		i mean it is nerve racking to have the telephone but at least as i said
 		you can always say no thank you
 	
 	
 		right um-hum
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i gather you get a lot of telephone calls
 	
 	
 		sometimes yeah <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">some days</TIMEX> it just rings off the wall
 	
 	
 		yes yes yes in other words you own your own home
 	
 	
 		
  
 		no no uh-huh
 	
 	
 		i think that's where they hit most of us like i own my own home
 		and you just know about what time like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">some days</TIMEX> i hate staying home because the phone rings all the time
 		but uh i don't know i haven't been able to figure that out something else to do about it
 		when they call up and want to say well tell me this this this this and i'll give you a free something or another
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		my answer is no thank you i don't need it and they say well don't you want to know what's free and i say no
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		if i have to give them so much to answer the questions to get fifty rolls of film or something like that
 		they're taking something away from me and i don't like that
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah
 		
 
 		even if i guess it's for coupons they they have a survey they run
 		and it i guess it one of them is supposed to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">smokers</ENAMEX> survey but the questions go a lot farther than having to do anything with smoking
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they ask that you know they start out and they ask you even even to your income level i think that's you know
 		whether you buy a TV dinner or not i don't think it has anything to do with what
 		
 		
 	