
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay now you can tell me what you do
 	
 	
 		uh well i work with computers just like your son
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i actually do research in speech recognition
 	
 	
 		oh great
 	
 	
 		and so as part of the reason i'm participating in the project is to see how the stuff goes but um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i was working <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">well</ENAMEX> actually i haven't worked for any large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> per se
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh</ENAMEX> recently but hopefully the job that i will have will have lots of benefits namely lots of vacations not real good salary but lots of vacations but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		well the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX> works for seems to have a lot you know
 		good benefits and the pay is decent
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah the uh
 		well actually where
 		i was working with the company
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> i was working for actually had very good health care benefits which <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> i think are really important because health care is so ridiculously expensive because we're we're paying our own insurance right now
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		for it um and i'm we actually had a little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> so i'm taking a little bit of a  time off from work ah congratulations
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">great i</ENAMEX> had i had a granddaughter
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and um so one thing that i'm very concerned with now is
 		<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of all health benefits because it's more important with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and you know our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX>'s visits routine <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX>'s visits covered my health insurance only covers um
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		your emergency care and so
 	
 	
 		um-hum do you have major medical benefits
 	
 	
 		right yeah but i don't
 	
 	
 		that that helps some if it depends on what your deductible is how high it is
 	
 	
 		right well my our deductible is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five hundred</NUMEX> but it's for each
 	
 	
 		each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> yeah that's pretty hard that's pretty high
 	
 	
 		event yeah
 		right but you know so it covers the emergency things but it doesn't cover if you get sick it doesn't cover
 	
 	
 		
 
 		right that's that's right that's
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX>'s visits things like that
 	
 	
 		and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five hundred dollars</NUMEX> is a lot to come up with for each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> to be able to start using your major medical too
 	
 	
 		oh yeah it certainly is
 	
 	
 		yeah i know where my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> works now she she course we live in a a rural sort of setting and where she works she has no benefits at all and her her wage is not
 	
 	
 		um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		wow
 	
 	
 		not very good
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but it's a it's a type of area we live in of course living expenses aren't as bad either though which makes a difference
 	
 	
 		and probably the medical care care is less expensive too
 	
 	
 		well she has to pay for it herself you know they have to pay for their own insurance but uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		so i think that in general the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX>'s fees are probably lower there and so the insurance would cost lower
 	
 	
 		uh well
 		from what i've seen from my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aunt</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncle</ENAMEX> really from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> up to here they're not that much different
 	
 	
 		well i know that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> of mine had a baby up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> and their costs were about fifty percent of what it cost to have it in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		is that right
 	
 	
 		and they were at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the better <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> and you know good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh that's a big difference
 	
 	
 		and i was at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> but that's a huge difference just between
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know and it's two big <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> that i think of as somewhat comparable
 	
 	
 		oh yeah should be
 	
 	
 		so i was pretty shocked at that but the other thing that i'm really concerned about and most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> don't have some are starting to have is day care because it would be really nice to be able to have
 	
 	
 		yes uh-huh
 	
 	
 		you know someone that could watch my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> at work and i'd go to work and if she were sick i could go down and see her if she needs to be fed whatever it is
 	
 	
 		and it'd be much more convenient yeah it would be more convenient too um-hum oh yeah yeah my my other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> works and has they have to take their <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> to day care you know
 	
 	
 		and i
 		it would be more convenient more productive
 		i think
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh it it's it's i don't know how they do it i really don't you know getting them there and then and going to work and then picking them up and  all the preparations
 	
 	
 		and your and your and your <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">hours</TIMEX> are much more constrained and things like that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and that to me well that you know those <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> things the health care vacation and day care are probably the most important benefits i should suppose i should be concerned with
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		life insurance and uh retirement plans but
 	
 	
 		oh
 		i don't know i think those benefits you mentioned mentioned sometimes they're even more important than you the wage itself
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		if you can get those benefits even uh they they come out to much a much better benefit than than an increase in your wage a lot of times
 	
 	
 		right because you're you know certainly something like day care at the work place would like make life so much simpler that it's worth paying you know having a lower salary i would certainly accept a lower salary for that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh yeah oh yeah it make it a lot better
 	
 	
 		you know everything else being equal because your life would be so much easier and there's a question of quality of life also
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		uh well and if it was there you would really have a little more uh knowledge on what's going on probably you know with your child
 	
 	
 		yep
 		right and you you you don't feel like you're <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a half hour</TIMEX> away if she something happened
 	
 	
 		right yeah
 	
 	
 		and you're less preoccupied with it i think
 	
 	
 		right yeah
 	
 	
 		so but unfortunately there aren't i think <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX> has started having that in certain locations
 	
 	
 		i don't know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> works for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MCI</ENAMEX> and they don't they where she works they don't have anything like that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> is that locally
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">uh Pittsburgh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh Pennsylvania</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah because <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX>'s a big enough city too but you know i wouldn't be surprised if thing's like that didn't happen more in smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> before they happen in bigger ones
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum  um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		just because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> might be more flexible in smaller locations and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		things like that because many times small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> offer
 		better benefits
 		in terms of quality of life than larger companies
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		like uh one <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> had proposed to me that i could come back to work after having the baby um any where <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">between ten</NUMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">forty hours</TIMEX> a week
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and um you know call call my own days call my own <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> and
 	
 	
 		oh so they were very flexible and that that would be great yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah and and
 		you know which many times at a large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> it's almost impossible
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		to do things like that
 	
 	
 		they say you're going to do it this way and that's the way it's going to be yeah
 	
 	
 		right and if you get <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks</TIMEX> off you get <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks</TIMEX> off and you're not allowed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks</TIMEX> and one day
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		and so it all depends on what your position is there too
 	
 	
 		true well that's true in any any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> i think
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh i've i've never well i can't say i've never i've maybe worked <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX> out of our married life out of the home you know out of the home
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh the rest of the time i've been an <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Avon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> and a  lady
 	
 	
 		was that when you were um well those have its pluses and minuses too i've been a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultant</ENAMEX> recently and so i don't have any benefits at all and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		um-hum and you have to take care of any benefits you want yourself yeah
 	
 	
 		right and the same thing my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> is unfortunately being paid as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultant</ENAMEX> and we tried to argue that he should get more salary for that than what he is and um they they they
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		usually <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultants</ENAMEX> make very good income
 	
 	
 		right and they they refuse to give him more salary
 	
 	
 		is that right
 	
 	
 		because they say they can't pay more than this and that and they're not allowed to pay him more than what his previous salary was and things like that and you know times are rough now so it's new it's harder to get
 	
 	
 		uh oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the uh
 		your increases and things but um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultant consultant consultant</ENAMEX> really is should be more knowledgeable than everybody else  you know so it stands to reason they should really have have more benefits
 	
 	
 		yeah well the
 		right well he's been doing a long term he's being called a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultant</ENAMEX> and he's really sort of a temporary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX> at a place
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they they pay him as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultant</ENAMEX> but he doesn't get any health benefits he doesn't get well we don't care about retirement benefits he doesn't get um vacation benefits and he does a lot of things that
 	
 	
 		um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		get factored into somebody else's salary so really his salary should be you know <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">twenty percent</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">thirty percent</NUMEX> higher just based on that not including the fact that you know it's a less long term commitment for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> and all that sort of stuff
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah and they'll do it
 		
 		
 	