
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so what movies have you seen
 	
 	
 		uh well i have uh seen <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dances With Wolves</ENAMEX> which is probably the the best movie that i have seen lately uh i do not go out to films very often
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so as far as out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> so we do get a lot of videos that we bring in uh and i see some that way but uh i am not real current on films how about you
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah i saw <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dances With Wolves and uh Home Alone and</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i hear that's really good but i haven't seen it yet
 	
 	
 		yeah it is  about a little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> that that his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> go off to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they they forget all about him
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		the oldest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> they take a head count and the oldest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> counts <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbor kids</ENAMEX> instead of
 	
 	
 		oh cute
 	
 	
 		and he is up in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">attic asleep</ENAMEX> because he got in trouble
 	
 	
 		oh dear
 	
 	
 		so she made him go sleep upstairs
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh oh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and there is there is a couple of burglars uh breaking into the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> in the neighborhood
 	
 	
 		oh and he hears them or something and
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		yeah and he sets up traps for them all over the house
 	
 	
 		who wins
 	
 	
 		uh he does
 	
 	
 		oh great great yeah i had heard <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> talk about it and they say it was really cute but i hadn't seen it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh we usually wait and eventually eventually it comes out on video and then we get it and see it that way
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and that is it movies are very expensive uh movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">theatres</ENAMEX> here they are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> dollars uh for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX> performances and that is kind of steep
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i think i don't know how much is it in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well it is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">six dollars</NUMEX> and then but you get um matinee prices but
 	
 	
 		yeah you can do that but it is difficult if you if you work or you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh that is taking <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the middle of the afternoon</TIMEX> and if i am looking for entertainment usually i i have more uh time in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the evening</TIMEX> than i do in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the middle of the day</TIMEX>
 		to uh see things what do you think of movies in general as far as the as the trends
 	
 	
 		well i think they are a lot better than they used than they were well like um
 		in the early eighties or the during the like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Smokey</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Bandit</ENAMEX> era
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		when it was they i don't think they were very good during that time at least there weren't as many good ones
 	
 	
 		yeah did
 		yeah the quality i think maybe has improved in that respect uh the only thing that disturbs me is that now they think they have to add just a little bit of sex and violence in order to get a
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		a tougher rating which suggests that that you know it will be more enticing to the to the public and a lot of times it is added for no real uh valid reason
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh which does not make and i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smokey</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bandit</ENAMEX> was a little bit like that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh but <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Dances With Wolves</ENAMEX> did not seem to have anything added it was just all legitimate kind of uh film and that is where reason why i suppose it won so many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Oscars</ENAMEX> uh
 		because it really was good even though it is such a long movie you know they said oh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> won't won't be interested in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a three hour</TIMEX> movie but it certainly gotten good acclaim everywhere it has gone
 	
 	
 		and it was shocking at the end too so yeah
 	
 	
 		oh oh yeah absolutely uh but much more true to life and i think that is that is the point
 	
 	
 		yeah that is right
 	
 	
 		uh they do not have to keep making up stuff if they want to make something good i hate sequels too i hate these uh you know number one <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two three four</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		usually if a movie is good once is enough
 	
 	
 		yeah especially Jaws
 	
 	
 		right
 		that was on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prime Time Television</ENAMEX> here uh recently at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven thirty</TIMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the evening</TIMEX> and uh it was kind of shocking because that is a scary movie and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> could see could have seen that movie
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">that hour</TIMEX> and i thought that you know that would not have been the sort of thing i would have wanted my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> to see at that age uh i mean when they were young and here it was quite easily seen by anybody that turned on the TV
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh which was a it was a good movie i mean it was well done but uh that is one reason why it was scary
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so but i do not know that i have seen any of the uh sequels to that
 		i think one is enough
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		just more of the same
 	
 	
 		yes uh-huh that is what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> say
 	
 	
 		in one of them they have a mother <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">shark</ENAMEX> uh destroy a whole uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">marina</ENAMEX> and aquarium
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		which is kind of far fetched
 	
 	
 		yeah it just a touch
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well the whole movie is kind of far fetched
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i mean the whole idea behind it is far fetched
 	
 	
 		they hardly ever play music when a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">shark</ENAMEX> attacks somebody
 	
 	
 		not not too often
 		that has gotten to be a whole camp idea idea now though you know if you hear that music you know everybody knows what you are talking about
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it's funny
 		well it sounds like neither one of us are real movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buffs</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well uh every once in a while i go  but it it has to be like somebody that i like or
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know i did not i did not go see <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Field of Dreams</ENAMEX> when it was in the theatre because i did not know it was any good
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then when it was i i found out it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Costner</ENAMEX> when it was on um i guess <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> the other week then i
 	
 	
 		right yeah i saw it then too
 	
 	
 		yeah and then i really liked it
 	
 	
 		yeah it was good it was very good but uh um uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		see i have uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teenagers</ENAMEX> in my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and of course sometimes they rent movies and you know have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> over or something and sometimes movies are here that i did not i am not even aware that i could have seen you know because my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> tells me that that that it had been actually in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> before
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		but i'd missed it but i did see it on TV and i thought it was good
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		it was really and then and then uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shoeless Joe Jackson</ENAMEX> really was a player i thought they made him up and then i found out you know after i saw the movie that they they started talking about that scandal and
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		yeah when the when the anniversary came up that was around the time of anniversary and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
  
 		no kidding oh i did not realize that
 	
 	
 		then it was on the news
 	
 	
 		yeah uh you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> that uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Earle Jones</ENAMEX> played
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh uh i teach in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and we are doing a book called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Invisible Man</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralph Ellison</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i wondered if maybe he was patterned after him
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh i do not know i had not heard anybody talk about it but uh he certainly could have been
 		uh which was kind of interesting
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know someone who uh who was a real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activist</ENAMEX> but then took up the cause uh kind of gave up you know because he didn't think anything was happening and
 		so uh it was kind of fun
 	
 	
 		yeah and i wondered who it was too
 	
 	
 		i do not know for sure but there are certain uh qualities that suggest it could be he because they were uh
 		they were suggesting that this <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben</ENAMEX> was something of a recluse that he had stopped writing and had stopped you know and that is true for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ellison</ENAMEX> he he wrote that one book and a few essays and that is about it
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		and uh has pretty much dropped out of public life
 		but he is still alive and that you know that's what makes it so interesting
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and that book have you ever read that book
 	
 	
 		
  
 		uh i don't
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Invisible Man</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		what is that <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Invisible Man</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Invisible Man</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralph Ellison</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		uh no huh-uh
 	
 	
 		it is an incredible book
 		it uh really is very very interesting i highly recommend it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh</ENAMEX> did they make the movies after that or
 	
 	
 		uh the yeah the movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">the in Field Field of Dreams</ENAMEX> came out after uh that novel
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so it it could easily have been patterned after him but the the movie did not have anything to do with with the story that i am talking about but i just thought the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> could have been patterned after that uh
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		i mean that that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> could have been patterned after him or someone like him certainly
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		sort of interesting so
 		well i guess we have talked probably our limit time limit haven't we
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		okay very good it was nice talking to you
 	
 	
 		
 
 		okay it was nice
 		nice talking to you bye-bye
 	
 	
 		okay bye-bye
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	