
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		all right so uh what about automobiles
 	
 	
 		well i drive a pick up truck
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh
 	
 	
 		you should live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's probably true it it's a small pickup <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> though it's one of those <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Isuzu uh</ENAMEX> space <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cab</ENAMEX> types with a sunroof so it's actually not a real pickup <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> you know it's uh it's got nice bucket seats so it's very comfortable and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		it has uh with the space <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cab</ENAMEX> in the back i can carry some storage but i have to admit <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred</ENAMEX> i i've never had a gun rack back there so i probably wouldn't fit in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh oh you're in trouble
 		
 
 		you don't have a
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yosemite Sam</ENAMEX> mud flap back off or anything like that
 	
 	
 		no no  no no nothing like that it my it's pretty pretty i think uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		my truck sort of puts me as a uh as as a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore Baltimore</ENAMEX> suburbanite i think is more uh you know i uh when i bought the truck i was going to buy a boat
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i needed something that would be able to haul a small <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> but then i i um i because i wanted to try water skiing and enjoying some water sports and things and that's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> reason why i bought it but then right after i bought the truck i broke my foot
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and i and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> said because of the type of physical therapy i got no sideward movement you know for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of months</TIMEX> and that meant the whole
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		season uh water skiing you know uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX> was over so i thought well okay and then by the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next year</TIMEX> i was thinking about doing it again but i invested the money in a house
 	
 	
 		oh well probably that's probably a little more sound investment
 	
 	
 		you know so
 		little more sound investment yes so so then i still have this pickup <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> and then i think well now maybe i'll you know go by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> again and of course then i broke my foot again uh so the thought
 	
 	
 		
 
 		perhaps you should just uh dispel that thought
 	
 	
 		yeah that so that's so i'm not ever going going to own a boat
 	
 	
 		but you still like your <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> though
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh yeah i love my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> in fact uh well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and i contemplate selling both of us owned pickup <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trucks</ENAMEX> actually when we got married so we now we're a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pickup truck</ENAMEX> family
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh hers in in some ways is is a little more convenient and then mine's convenient other ways so it's hard to decide she has a a cap on the back and and uh she has um
 		uh roof racks so we were able to carry things on the roof and able to put things in the back of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> without them ever worrying about them them getting wet or whatever
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		but with mine see i have a space <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cab</ENAMEX> so you can put like luggage immediately behind the seats and i also have bucket seats
 		and air conditioning  so each one has its good points and each one has its bad points in a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> yeah uh what
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah do you feel that
 		uh you're the always the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> that gets called when someone moves or something
 	
 	
 		i think family um i do a little bit but surprisingly i have uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> since i bought my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Isuzu</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pickup</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> have bought uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Isuzu</ENAMEX> Troopers
 		which actually you know can open the back and just take out your backseat and you can haul washers and dryers and almost anything in them so i think um i used to be
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
  
 		
 
 	
 	
 		the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> that was called but now everybody owns <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> themselves you know i do have some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> every once in a while that'll ask me and i'll i'll of course do that you know that doesn't matter
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah it's for for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> you'd do it anyway so it doesn't really matter
 	
 	
 		yeah that's uh it just seems that uh i don't know if i'd ever want to own one because
 		i know i've used <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> with pickup <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trucks</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two or three</NUMEX> times and and they you know what are you doing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this weekend</TIMEX> well i'm helping a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> move you know and it just seems like they're always getting the call
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		yeah that's true what type of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> do you drive <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well i have a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mercury</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Cougar</ENAMEX> and i've had it since <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">well eighty six</NUMEX> actually so it was still fairly
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know it was a new style when it came out and uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> drives and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty seven</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Topaz</ENAMEX> or an wait an <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">eighty eighty seven Topaz yeah</ENAMEX> that's right and so we're a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mercury</ENAMEX> family i guess
 	
 	
 		yeah uh-huh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um not so much on her part but i don't know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> always bought <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mercury</ENAMEX> products so and i like the looks of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Cougar</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
  
 		yeah they're nice looking i like them
 	
 	
 		yeah thanks and uh except for i got a some <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> hail storm damage it's a little golf ball action so i've got
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		driving driving around a with a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> checker <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> basically
 	
 	
 		oh gee
 	
 	
 		i got that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a year and a half ago</TIMEX> actually <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years ago this May</TIMEX> and i just totaled out the car
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		so it paid for itself and i'm basically driving uh almost a free <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		yeah well that's see that's what i'm hoping to stop paying truck payments soon you know that's i think that's payments are important what you so but your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> drives a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mercury Topaz</ENAMEX> they're nice too
 	
 	
 		yeah we haven't had a trouble with either of them yet uh her Topaz uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh my Cougar</ENAMEX>'s got like eighty <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">some thousand miles</NUMEX> on it it's made trips because we're both from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX> and she moved down here first she she pardon
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah so you've gone
 		yeah back to visit family
 		have you driven back to visit family
 		in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah i've made the trip probably <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> times because i was still going to school and she was down here and so it's
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's just racks up you know about <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">sixteen hundred miles</NUMEX> each time
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and and we just started going in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carla</ENAMEX>'s car the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Topaz</ENAMEX> and it seems to make the trip pretty well it's getting around thirty <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">five forty miles per gallon</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh that's really good yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah it is especially we we were weighting it down a little bit it get it you know on the
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it averaged out around <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty five</TIMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">forty forty</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah is uh gas mileage an important reason why you buy the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> you do
 	
 	
 		probably uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Cougar</ENAMEX> i got it just for its looks
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh the the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mercury</ENAMEX> brand and uh  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carla</ENAMEX> wanted a
 		a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> that got  good gas mileage a little something to get around <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> and uh dependable and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh it it it's kind of a sportier model than most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Topazes</ENAMEX> it's got the the stripping on the side and it came with uh i think <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eagle</ENAMEX> tires
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> had some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">salesman</ENAMEX> had decked it out and uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so it it looked pretty sharp
 	
 	
 		well i i take it you don't have you don't have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> then
 	
 	
 		no no we we just got a new <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">puppy</ENAMEX> but uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		it's close enough
 	
 	
 		because if you had if you had <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> you wouldn't say anything about sportier looking you'd be saying things like it has a good backseat
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh the car seat fits in very easily and we can seat belt it in securely it's that's that's a big difference in conversations there  yeah
 	
 	
 		oh so you don't you don't have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> or
 	
 	
 		no we well we're uh just recently married in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		uh but that's we we laugh now my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> says we should sell my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> and i say we should sell hers
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and i said well the reason why we should sell yours <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laura</ENAMEX> is because see <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX> has the space <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cab</ENAMEX> and it actually has little drop seats in the space area with seat belts i said and we can seat buckle in a car seat there
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so we should get rid of yours because the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> of us won't be able to go on trips i said but we can go on trips in mine you know we can travel anywhere with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> so that's uh you know we laugh i laugh about that um-hum
 	
 	
 		
 
 		that's funny uh see that's true i never thought of that and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know oh it's a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> and you know loading up the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> you know we haven't crossed that yet so
 	
 	
 		i know  we haven't either but
 	
 	
 		have you seen these new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">station wagons</ENAMEX> they look pretty sharp
 	
 	
 		well what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX> ones
 	
 	
 		uh i don't know what it was i just saw it going down and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> were in there and it looked like a pretty sleek looking car
 	
 	
 		yeah i think uh i think <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX> was one of the first ones to step into that new um that new almost shuttle <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">space shuttle</ENAMEX> like appearance and i think they've done they've really come on strong with some of that um
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		uh wind resistance and energy saving and uh uh developments i think that that's their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">station wagon</ENAMEX> i think those are <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fords</ENAMEX> but i do i like those
 	
 	
 		okay
 		no more of the the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel station</ENAMEX> wagons anymore
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah now now the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">station wagon</ENAMEX> looks sleek it looks yeah
 	
 	
 		i know they do look pretty sharp
 	
 	
 		and uh and hopefully i think uh you know it's supposed to get better gas mileage and um i think that's that's becoming an important thing too my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and i've been discussing is you know looking for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> when we do get rid of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trucks</ENAMEX> we'll probably look for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> that gets good gas mileage
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		just because um
 		it it just has become such an important thing i think for the environment and for the economy and everything you know to start to pay attention to that more and more
 	
 	
 		so you you bought an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Isuzu</ENAMEX> so you're not a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a</TIMEX> the buy <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> or
 	
 	
 		no i think i think the reason why i i bought the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Isuzu</ENAMEX> is because you know i looked almost all the small <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trucks</ENAMEX> are made by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> anyway
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		there's only a couple of them like i looked the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place i went were the were <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dodge Chrysler</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Plymouth</ENAMEX> and you know i went to a number of them and i priced them all out and i was just the the i was almost going to buy a um a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler</ENAMEX> which was actually a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mitsubishi</ENAMEX> truck
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">salesman</ENAMEX> insulted me um the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">salesman</ENAMEX> you know they always do that deal with you where they say well i got to go talk to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> well here the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX>'s actually the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> that owns the place and in this small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> we live on he's always on TV
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and he comes out of his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> and i asked him for i i i said well you know it was like maybe eighty <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">three hundred dollars</NUMEX> for this truck
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and i said well i i'd like it for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">eight thousand dollars</NUMEX> i said for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">eight thousand dollars</NUMEX> i'll sell you know i'll write out the down payment now and you know because i can get financing i can get financing through my credit
 		because i'd checked about financing and everything you know i said i'll for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">eight thousand dollars</NUMEX> i'll take it you know because it was oh sort of marked down you know and the and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> came out of the back and insulted me he said
 		he said you want a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> for under <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">eight thousand dollars</NUMEX> go back to the used lot it's behind the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> and he walked away
 	
 	
 		oh man
 	
 	
 		i guess it was a sales technique he thought he was going to pressure me into giving up that <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">three hundred dollars</NUMEX> that i asked for i don't know and i said i said i looked at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">salesman</ENAMEX> i said i'm i'm sorry your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> just insulted me i can't it's against my pride to buy a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> here now
 	
 	
 		that
 		no kidding
 	
 	
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> and i felt really bad i walked out and the guy
 		called me at home <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next couple of days</TIMEX> it was terrible but you know i walked out i got into my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> was actually with me shopping for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and we drove down the street
 		and he said why don't you just look in here and we went into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Isuzu</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealer</ENAMEX> because my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> always had this love for an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Isuzu Trooper</ENAMEX> he wanted one you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and we walked in and here there was a demonstrator <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX> on sale like ninety <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">six hundred dollars</NUMEX> with everything standard
 		
 		
 	