
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well crime's not very bad out there
 	
 	
 		no as a matter of fact i understand we have one of the lowest crime rates in the area but then we aren't we're only a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">five thousand</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		how's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richardson</ENAMEX> doing
 	
 	
 		
 
 		it's been a lot worse this year
 		um
 		they have a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealers</ENAMEX> over on you know where <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spring Valley</ENAMEX> is and Coit
 	
 	
 		yes uh-huh
 	
 	
 		it's real bad there has been for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years</TIMEX> especially on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> side
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> is just across the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> and
 		and uh they've closed down a bunch of apartment <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complexes</ENAMEX> and uh
 		you know
 		like that and they're having to crime sweep
 	
 	
 		uh-huh well i wonder why it effects certain areas
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		because i i i've lived in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> area perhaps for about uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirteen years</TIMEX> now and i used to live in that not in that particular area but on that side of of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and that was always a a fairly good area in there if i remember correctly
 	
 	
 		yeah it used to be
 	
 	
 		but um i guess it moves in different uh areas at different times um
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		the only problem that we have here are are you know just very minute sort of crime we have neighborhood crime watch programs and then the uh city <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> patrol the areas at least <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> a day
 		and when you're not at home you're to notify your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> of course that you know you're going out of time <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">et cetera et cetera</TIMEX> and not do the things that are so obvious to uh potential
 	
 	
 		right get someone to pick up your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> and your mail
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		set your lights on timers and
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but um
 		other than that that's about the only thing we're doing in Sachse
 	
 	
 		uh-huh the murder rate really seems to be up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort Worth</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> well especially <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort Worth</ENAMEX> this year
 	
 	
 		i think i saw on TV just <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this evening</TIMEX> that there was a pregnant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> and and some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> killed was that over in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort Worth</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah this morning uh-huh
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		and apparently they already they already caught him or they're talking about somebody else they're talking about <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">two million dollar</NUMEX> bond for somebody
 	
 	
 		is that right
 	
 	
 		yeah i never i never heard all of the story about that i just heard it from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> at work and on the radio uh a little bit
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh
 	
 	
 		it's really been
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort Worth</ENAMEX> has really been bad because of the kidnappings and all the armed robberies
 	
 	
 		i wonder why over there i mean i'm glad it's not over here if you have to have it but um i don't understand why certain
 	
 	
 		i i think i think that um they're just getting well they had that crazy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> that  kidnapped the
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> and took her all they way to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saint Louis</ENAMEX> before they were caught you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and she called the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		was it over in that area <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> that they had the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> um that was in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mall</ENAMEX> and this other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> shot his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>
 		in in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mall area</ENAMEX> she and she was screaming and heading towards the entrance to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mall</ENAMEX> and they shot her
 		and then there was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> in the um parking lot and he pulled out a gun that he had in his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and he shot the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> was that over in
 	
 	
 		oh i i think that was Redbird
 	
 	
 		oh oh that was Redbird
 	
 	
 		yeah it's real bad too
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		everywhere there's a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mall</ENAMEX> there's bad crime though
 	
 	
 		as a matter of fact <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this summer early early  actually earlier this spring</TIMEX> i had gone to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Collin Creek</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mall</ENAMEX> and my hubcaps were stolen
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and the police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> told me that um
 		the the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">malls</ENAMEX> are a very good area where these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like to go and steal the hubcaps they just steal <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> side
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah exactly uh-huh
 	
 	
 		and and take off
 	
 	
 		they stole the emblem off of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of mine
 	
 	
 		did they
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		well i don't know whether that's a faddish thing or what
 	
 	
 		apparently
 	
 	
 		and then it costs us so much to uh replace those things uh-huh yeah surely
 	
 	
 		from the insurance and yeah
 		they also they tear off the hood ornaments too and one of them costs <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> dollars so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		and your deductible of course doesn't mean that it's it's under that it's it's normally
 	
 	
 		right
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		yeah  i don't know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um i really don't know what else to say
 		does that about cover it
 	
 	
 		yeah i think so
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		i mean and they said take what steps and we already discussed that you know you know
 	
 	
 		uh-huh about the only thing you do is is to provide the um protection in your own home and then be careful when you do go out at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> if you go out at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>
 		and um certainly that's about the best thing we can do and uh
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		they have any laws against that sort of thing
 	
 	
 		yeah i work at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Valley View</ENAMEX> and they have horse <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patrols</ENAMEX> and um and they have the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mall</ENAMEX> security that that drives around
 		probably around the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mall</ENAMEX> at least once every <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ten minutes at night</TIMEX> especially because they have so many stolen <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> and they've had um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three three</NUMEX> armed robberies of uh jewelry <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		and uh and they've all been in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the middle of the day</TIMEX>
 		you know
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		and uh one of them was <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">three hundred thousand dollars</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's quite a lot of money isn't it
 	
 	
 		yeah really is
 	
 	
 		and it gives other i imagine other uh potential crime <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> uh ideas too
 	
 	
 		but i've seen they've stepped up security quite a bit
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> are around a lot more now so
 	
 	
 		i imagine they're going to need more police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> too
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		if they do that
 	
 	
 		then they use they use undercover too
 	
 	
 		yeah i guess that's true
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well even here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sachse</ENAMEX> we have one undercover <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> car
 	
 	
 		right uh-huh
 	
 	
 		and actually if we
 		had to call him a few times and they're usually on the spot in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about five minutes</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		course as i say we're a small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> but still you know
 	
 	
 		yeah at least they're there
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		so well i've enjoyed talking to you
 	
 	
 		yeah it's nice talking to you
 	
 	
 		okay have a good <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX> bye-bye
 	
 	
 		you too bye-bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	