
 
     		
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well do you watch much TV
 	
 	
 		well i watch in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the evening</TIMEX> with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> how many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> do you have
 	
 	
 		i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh goodness i have got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		that's about all i want
 	
 	
 		well
 		yeah it keeps you busy doesn't it
 	
 	
 		yeah they do they're still babies
 	
 	
 		uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> like to watch <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sesame Street</ENAMEX> i watch with them every once in a while but that is not my favorite programs
 	
 	
 		oh well we have only get <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> channels we do not have cable but i am not crazy about TV much it just
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well it kind of is an idiot box now <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sesame Street</ENAMEX> is a good program because uh i do have that on videotape and i will let him watch that every once in a while and he has learned to count to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty</TIMEX> from that so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah it can be very educational there are shows that that i like uh i like good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> shows uh though uh i let my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> watch things like <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Little House On The Prairie</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		okay
 	
 	
 		and the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cosby Show</ENAMEX> is uh is uh kind of unrealistic as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> unless you live in upper class and have money
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		i think that sometimes the things they show on there though uh the problems that their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> get into are are good to uh show that they do have problems anyway
 	
 	
 		right but they also have a lot easier time disciplining their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> than real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> do
 	
 	
 		uh
 		yeah i mean like i said real life is not that easy
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		i watch a show that i like it for entertainment uh it is called the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quantum Leap</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh i love <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quantum Leap</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i watch that show every time and uh
 	
 	
 		yes that is a good show
 	
 	
 		i i like uh
 		how the how he has to help with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that he that he becomes
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 		because it is not a show that he just becomes these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and then he lives there for a while and then he is gone he has to do something positive to help them
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right he always got to change history is what it is
 	
 	
 		so i
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		usually yeah that it is so good i was glad when they put that back on this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX> because like i said we only get <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> channels because we do not get cable
 	
 	
 		it
 		me too me too
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and still my little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> he watches videotapes he won't hum this is terrible i do not like him sitting in front of the TV all day
 	
 	
 		no that's not terrible i do not think that's terrible at all
 	
 	
 		well
 		it but it is a not really a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby sitter</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well
 	
 	
 		it's really not he needs to get outside and play and he's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years old</TIMEX> and he just does not like to go out there by his self
 		and i'll let him watch the TV when i am wanting to get my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> work done
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but other than that i do not like him glued to the TV all the time
 	
 	
 		well i do not think it's it's healthy all the time either
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> like to to go play with their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and so i guess i do not mind too much when they do watch a little bit now i there are shows i do not have cable either
 		and there are shows that i really put my foot down on
 		if there starts to be a lot of violence i do not go for that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i will not let them watch that if there is a lot of language or
 	
 	
 		well we made the mistake right we made the mistake of getting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robocop</ENAMEX> and that is one of the worst oh i do not let him watch it anymore because just the pieces l
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		like especially where they kill somebody it is just not good i mean it is just real violent i mean
 	
 	
 		well it  you know today i watched and it is like they show bloody you know things and they show it in slow motion and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and everything like that and before in a western or something in the in the olden days
 	
 	
 		you would see somebody get shot they would just fall down
 	
 	
 		yeah and they were gone  and and it wasn't uh not like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		so graphic
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> it's it's really graphic they try to make it too realistic
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah too much realism i think sometimes
 	
 	
 		and
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i don't
 	
 	
 		now he is watching <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Honey I Shrunk The Kids</ENAMEX> right now
 	
 	
 		oh that is a fun show oh i really like that one
 	
 	
 		it is cute and that little <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Rabbit</ENAMEX> on before that that is cute and they have got the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">He Man</ENAMEX> uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		the cartoon or the
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Masters Of The Universe</ENAMEX> the movie
 	
 	
 		oh uh-huh
 	
 	
 		that is a real cute show
 	
 	
 		that has good moral values too
 	
 	
 		He Man
 	
 	
 		uh-huh well uh i think uh
 	
 	
 		yeah good versus evil huh
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		oh well it sounds like we have the same tapes for our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> anyway
 	
 	
 		yeah at least we have the same ideas
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yeah language too and language and violence and sexual you you know things i i get kind of uh saying i am sorry <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> this is and i i think it is important that i see
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		what they're watching
 	
 	
 		yeah they do have like those parental control things on the uh remote controls you know where you can block out what channels you do not want them to watch
 	
 	
 		if
 		you mean in cable oh i do not know because i do not have that but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well my my uh stepfather and them have my stepfather my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father-in-law</ENAMEX> and them have that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		they do not have any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> but they was told how to use that but still when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> get older they learn how to break through that parental control
 	
 	
 		oh do they
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		they're too smart
 	
 	
 		i think all you have to do is push a couple buttons
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so it's it's  i'm hoping that he will grow up not really caring much for those movies because
 		now we have got a lot of western tapes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Josey Wells</ENAMEX> now he loves to watch <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Josey Wells</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		i think that is a good show too yeah uh-huh
 	
 	
 		yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clint Eastwood</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">like The Man From Showy River</ENAMEX> we've oh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> likes westerns and he also likes <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Star Trek now Star Trek</ENAMEX> are good movies good shows
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the uh series we have got a lot of those
 	
 	
 		uh i think not even the old one but the new one too i like both of those
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">uh-huh  The Next Generation</ENAMEX> yeah  my little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> is  crazy  about  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Captain Kirk</ENAMEX> and my little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> has <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mister Spock</ENAMEX>'s ears
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and i told my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> he cursed my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>  they were both born with pointy ears
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh well
 	
 	
 		not real pointy my little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> grew out of it
 	
 	
 		oh that is not a problem anyway but it is fun to you know seeing the show anyway uh now i like uh everything <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael</ENAMEX> oh no not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Douglas</ENAMEX> um
 	
 	
 		no
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh i can't think of his name
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kirk Douglas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> right now who is having uh who has done
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">uh Bonanza</ENAMEX> and then he did <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Little House On The Prairie Michael Landon</ENAMEX> there you go <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Landon</ENAMEX> i have always liked and thought he did good shows
 	
 	
 		oh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Landon</ENAMEX>
 		oh now there yeah
 		like <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Highway</ENAMEX> to Heaven
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		here are some <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cookies</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kyle</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		yeah i liked <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Highway To Heaven</ENAMEX> and i
 		and i thought that was kind of neat though but i loved <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Little House On The Prairie</ENAMEX> especially when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa Gilbert</ENAMEX> grew up she was kind of like my
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">idol</ENAMEX>  when i was growing up because i am <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty seven</TIMEX> so it is you know she is about the same age as i am i wanted to be just like her because she is so cute
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah i and i liked that show because it it portrayed i thought really well uh pioneer kind of days
 	
 	
 		yeah and well i liked it but there that is about the only uh
 	
 	
 		you know but
 	
 	
 		show i have seen where every time they sit down at the table they pray before they eat and i thought that was real neat
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		because there is not a lot of shows that do that
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		they have this little cartoon that's on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">mornings</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		now what is that
 	
 	
 		with Jot
 		i remember him in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> but i do not it is just this little dot with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX> and feet and little eyes and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> are there they have it like before one of the church things uh you know <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> that comes on
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it is a just this little dot and he will go out and get himself into trouble and come home and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> will tell him that there is a verse in the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX> that will help him with that and it is just
 	
 	
 		oh i have not seen that
 	
 	
 		well it's usually we go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sundays</TIMEX> but we will miss every once in a while and i will let <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kyle</ENAMEX> watch that and he just well i even like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jot</ENAMEX> i mean i it is funny
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX> is it on
 	
 	
 		it is on channel well let us see you're in Plano
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh it's twelve or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> down here
 	
 	
 		well i will look and and see yeah we go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about one o'clock</TIMEX> is when our meetings start and uh
 	
 	
 		oh well this is of the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">mornings</TIMEX> uh around <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> i think it is before one of the i think it is before the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">First</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Baptist</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sherman</ENAMEX> airs i think that is the one that
 	
 	
 		it is in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX>
 		okay
 	
 	
 		it uh comes on before but it's real cute well he's bouncing around and his name is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jot</ENAMEX> and then he has got a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cat</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well we'll look
 	
 	
 		and i think the dog is the only one that's not a
 		a dot  but it is real cute and like i say they they
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		teach him stuff from the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX> and i think it is just a real cute show i'm trying to get my little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> into reading uh like church books and things we have got like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Noah</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ark</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lord</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">My Shepherd</ENAMEX> we have got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about eight</NUMEX> or twelve books for him just little <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible stories</ENAMEX> and they're he is he is getting to where he likes them
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		we got him a little <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> doll
 		uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a year ago</TIMEX> and he has always kept that
 		he likes it
 	
 	
 		well i really like now we get channel fifty <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>
 		although we do not have cable we do get channel fifty <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> and that is a uh like a
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		a song they sing songs on there but they're uh worship through music kind of things but they are up to date uh and some of them are like
 		uh videos like music videos that go along with the songs about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> and and i
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		so it's a uh <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> songs
 	
 	
 		yeah the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> it's called the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> music <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">station</ENAMEX> or something like that
 	
 	
 		oh that sounds fun
 		that's sound good well
 	
 	
 		and uh i really like that uh i turn that on on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">mornings</TIMEX> and i do not you know and so my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> don't uh i have an
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 		
 	