
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay can you uh give me your thoughts on what
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s roles are or how they've changed
 	
 	
 		well um
 		i'm in my i i i've seen the changes i think in my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> most of all because i'm a early <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> boomer
 		and uh i was brought up
 		uh to sort of get married and raise <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and uh be very domestic
 		and uh when i went to college or went to high school i did very well i was urged to become a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> or a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> because those are typical roles
 		and uh things have changed and
 		i i've ventured off in all sorts of areas and so have most of the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in my generation
 		and we're all in business or
 		the professions and uh and uh heavens we're  we're uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">astronauts</ENAMEX> and things like that who know who would wouldn't have been imagined in nineteen <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixty eight</TIMEX> or something
 		how about you
 	
 	
 		yeah well i was kind of same thing it's you know i was i was brought up in a small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> and and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> tended to just get married and take care of the house
 		um but as as times changed
 		um the price of things i guess started rising and it took <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than one</NUMEX> income
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		so more um more and more
 		of young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> were staying in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> they were getting a better education and they were going out into the work force
 	
 	
 		yes
 		another thing that happened that i found is that you know when i got married i didn't know anybody who had ever been divorced or or when i was younger i didn't know anybody who had ever been divorced
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this day</TIMEX> and age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are as likely to get divorced as to stay married
 		and very often the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> has to be able to earn a decent living
 		and uh so there's an additional reason for her to be capable of holding down a good job
 	
 	
 		yeah i think perhaps uh um <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> it was a stigma
 		on a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> to have a divorce in it
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		and whether it was warranted or not <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> just stayed together because of what the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> thought uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> little bit smarter <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> than that they uh uh yes there's a family <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> and it's and it's very difficult if there uh are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> especially young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 		but in a lot of cases it's probably it would probably more difficult if they stayed together
 		but uh i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> are taking a uh a more active role in politics i i think that uh
 		within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next ten or fifteen years</TIMEX> you'll probably see a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman vice president</ENAMEX> or a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> president
 		and you'll also see a lot more uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">congressmen</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> uh women
 	
 	
 		i i agree with that and i also think that they're taking a lead in in the arts and in business too
 		and uh
 		as as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> go by they run surveys to see how many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEOs</ENAMEX> or on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX> of major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> and the number is creeping up very
 		slowly but it's definitely increasing so that probably <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years from now</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		is that right you think they you think that's the case
 	
 	
 		yes it is i mean <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten fifteen ten fifteen</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> there were no women
 		on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX> or or or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX>'s of major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> unless they inherited the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> from their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> you know that sort of thing
 	
 	
 		oh yeah if it was if it was a family owned business you mean
 	
 	
 		but right if it was a family owned <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> but now they're they're in the board room and they're trying to get ahead
 		and make it in the business world of course to some extent the laws are helping them
 		but uh uh you know there's no no no holding back their ambition on the other hand what it does to the fabric of society and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> remains to be seen
 	
 	
 		yeah i still i still think it's it's uh it's a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> tiered system i uh
 		i know of of uh women <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineers</ENAMEX> and and
 		uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supervisors</ENAMEX> that are
 		uh they have to work twice as hard it seems like to achieve the same levels that a male does
 		uh i don't know if that's just my imagination or not but it seems to be that's uh
 		the ones that are up there
 		seem to have a little bit more intelligence than their counterparts
 	
 	
 		i i i
 	
 	
 		
 
 		if there was if it was up to me i think i would have uh more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">females</ENAMEX> because it seems like they try harder
 	
 	
 		well i think that in a way they're they're being tested right now we're going through a testing period
 		where capability is is everything and if
 		they succeed then the the the generation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> that are growing up now will have it much easier
 		because there will be a precedent they'll have had role models whereas you know the generation that grew up in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the sixties</TIMEX> and seventies
 	
 	
 		right they'll have role models they'll have protectors
 	
 	
 		sorry
 	
 	
 		they'll have protectors
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		uh there'll be more and more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> that are up higher and higher
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		um
 		and also they say that the bulk of the wealth
 		is controlled by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> now
 		uh just through i guess uh uh
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> dying off and just leaving their uh fortunes to women
 		so that's going to have a big impact uh
 		if you've got money and brains you can you can wield a lot of power
 	
 	
 		um i guess just by virtue of living longer in a way you're right because they do it does does come to them but they've got to be young enough to enjoy it i mean if they're just
 		old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ladies</ENAMEX> sitting around waiting for the end to come it doesn't do them much good
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		it must be the culture's different uh down there than up here also
 		um they're kind of uh
 		the old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yankees</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		you know it it takes uh uh it takes a stick of dynamite to get them moving off <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> in a lot of cases
 		where uh
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Midwest</ENAMEX> i think is a little bit more aggressive because they're closer to the west coast
 		where they're uh highly aggressive
 		you know uh ideas and or it seems like new ideas start out there and then kind of work their way east i don't know if you've found that to be true
 	
 	
 		well i'm in the middle of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and and it seems to me they could they start their from start from both coasts and work their ways inward
 		uh one of the one of the things that that i'm finding is that i've lived
 		in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> i've lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> and uh i
 		have i've done a lot of visiting out in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> and i know that we're lagging behind here and yet i really do see
 		uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s roles have increased and they're gaining new respect in fact
 		i believe that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> of the top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> major <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> cities
 		are all women
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		and that goes back to your original point about politics
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so uh uh you know it's going to get to a point i some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> are going to wonder if they're falling behind
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		the uh
 		i think the only problem there is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> that themselves that feel threatened by by a woman
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		uh by her intelligence probably
 		uh those are the ones that you're going to have problems with i think uh
 		a lot of the at least my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> they seem to have a a more open mind
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> than uh like when i was growing up
 	
 	
 		i think the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> today do have an open mind it's just not as much
 		uh
 		typecasting by sex by gender
 		uh
 		you know uh a little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> can say i want to be an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">astronaut</ENAMEX> or i want to be a fireman or a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policeman</ENAMEX> or
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		or a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rhodes</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholar</ENAMEX> which was impossible when i was going to college uh Rhodes
 		
 		
 	