
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 		are you a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veteran</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dudley</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh no
 	
 	
 		no do you have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> who were in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Vietnam War</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh no my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> was uh came in right after <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">world war</ENAMEX> two
 	
 	
 		okay so he was too old and you're too young right yeah all right do you know some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> who have been there
 	
 	
 		i am too young yeah
 		um yes a couple
 	
 	
 		okay
 		okay how did it influence them
 	
 	
 		uh the the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> i worked with down in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX> hated it uh he was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lineman</ENAMEX> down there and while he was there he caught some kind of a strange disease
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh all his hair fell out and he had like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred and five</NUMEX> fever for a while and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		uh what about long lasting effects on him has he still suffering from those problems
 	
 	
 		i do not think he was in combat so
 	
 	
 		um-hum well i've talked with a number of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veterans</ENAMEX> and i really i had no one directly related to me involved
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> and it it really made a completely different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> out of him he went to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> and came back another not better
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		then uh another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of mine went and he was in combat but he came back and he said okay that's it that is behind me i am going on with my life much like what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Staubach</ENAMEX> did
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		he was uh he was a <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Vietnam war</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veteran</ENAMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		but he was in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy</ENAMEX> though he was it makes a lot of difference
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true
 		right and but uh most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> that i have met that were actually on the land or in combat are still still carry a lot of anger
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they really do and uh i i i i really do not think that we did those young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> right i think that uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Desert Storm</ENAMEX> shows a lot of learning since that time
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		
  
 		uh
 	
 	
 		well the armed forces did so much to you know <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Agent Orange</ENAMEX> they did so much to their own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> all during that time you know and they take they take a even now uh they take a free hand as far as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true yeah
 	
 	
 		uh you know how they treat the war casualties you know if you come back and your leg's blown off you know or or it is hanging by a thread they still can't put it back together now but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but what they do afterwards and how they rehabilitate rehabilitate you
 	
 	
 		well you know one of the most troublesome things that i have
 		encountered as a result is the incredible influx of southeast <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asians</ENAMEX> into this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> since that conflict uh not so much that i say i do not want you here but there is just such a surge
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		of southeast <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asians</ENAMEX> it has affected the culture of this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> uh very much
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		it's about it's <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about nine</TIMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> percent now
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah yeah well uh the culture's changing look how much more oriental food we have <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> now for example
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 		even <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years ago</TIMEX>
 		there weren't that many a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> are are operated by uh southeast <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asians</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have complained in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> there is a culture change there the southeast <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asians</ENAMEX> seem to be very hungry there seem to be very studious
 		and uh tends to cause our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> to really have to buckle down to keep up with them which is not bad not really uh but it might in the long run you can see where
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		scholarships for example uh even jobs
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh jobs that would normally go to an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> with a lesser education
 		might be going to to some of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> here and that is all a result of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">of of Vietnam and</ENAMEX> and you see a lot of a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> that were over there brought <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> back
 	
 	
 		yeah that's
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and it concerns me that there is probably a lot of mixed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">breed youngsters</ENAMEX> still there and i'd be concerned or interested to find out how they are doing now
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well they are probably not doing very well at all because i know there's there's still <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> even in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> area there are there are still <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> trying to get some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> back from uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i know that they're
 		you are talking about POW's or missing in actions
 	
 	
 		um uh native <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">native Vietnamese</ENAMEX> people
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">native Vietnamese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> okay
 	
 	
 		yeah they were lost you know when they were little and and they could never did get back
 	
 	
 		oh i hadn't that that hadn't occurred to me
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		that'd be an interesting concept
 	
 	
 		and uh and uh that's is really a big <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">waste</ENAMEX> because they didn't they didn't win they didn't regain any of the land that they had it spilled over into uh now i can't even think of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Cambodia</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambodia</ENAMEX>  and to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Laos</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and all they did is run and hide and they weren't really fighting you know it it would've been the same as <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Desert Storm</ENAMEX> if all they had been fighting was <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Vietnam</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but and i am not even sure who was involved more whether it was <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> you know they were pouring they were pouring <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> in there and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and advising well digging <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tunnels</ENAMEX> for them you know and there is no way that they could ever catch them
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well i think the terrain had a lot to do with the the success of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Desert Storm</ENAMEX> as opposed to that in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah that is right
 	
 	
 		you know there is incredible cover in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> and you can't find much cover on  in a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sand</ENAMEX> dune
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah yeah and all they can do is dig in and they you know and then they try to camouflage the top
 	
 	
 		that's right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well now even i think even now in in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> they could probably have done a better job
 		because they could  they could kill all those <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> you know which would devastate the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> as far as farming from then on but and the and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corps of Engineers</ENAMEX> i think do a better job now like they did in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Desert Storm</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well
 	
 	
 		because they had he he dug a bunch of moats and filled them with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX> and he set a lot of booby traps all along the way as they went and they had to you know they had to blow them up or
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		or disarm them and then they had to fill in little <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridges</ENAMEX> all the way where he where he'd made those moats
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		what war do you think they found the experience for that
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		don't you think they learned from the mistakes in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well yeah partially uh-huh yeah part of it is technology yeah because all go ahead
 	
 	
 		part of it's that part of it's technology but
 		but when when
 		when you get into trouble like that in a place like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> you do tend to analyze the problems that you get into and you sa y never more and and you overcome those problems and you are prepared next time
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i think that's one of the reasons that they've they've pretty much avoided getting involved in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South America</ENAMEX> because
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		look what happened when they were looking for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Noriega</ENAMEX> and they lost him for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">four hours</TIMEX> when they were right on top of him you know he probably just went down into a tunnel
 	
 	
 		right um-hum
 		sure sure sure
 		well i know that  from a personal standpoint people
 		was one of the finest assets that we lost we didn't actually physically lose them they did not lose their lives but they lost a whole lot of the life they might have had
 	
 	
 		yeah that is right
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> being entirely different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i had dinner <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> with a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veteran</ENAMEX> who is just now beginning to recover from the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> and alcohol struggle that he had
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's a long time to suffer
 	
 	
 		yeah and they they really need everybody that's that's stood there it's when in in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> i think it was much closer contact you stand there with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">rifle</ENAMEX> and blow a a piece of somebody apart
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		or blow their head off and that has to affect you if you are human you know so they had to work all that that anger out and the and the nightmares that come along with it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh yeah yeah i can't uh
 		oh yeah you bet you bet
 	
 	
 		i don't i do not really think that anybody can ever forget forget that but they can they can reason and and try to adjust to to why they were there
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah well you see that's what the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veterans</ENAMEX> are so angry about now they say well we're going to listen to this and we're going to look at this find out what our mistakes were and we're not gonna make them again but that doesn't undo the ones that were done and that's what makes the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veterans</ENAMEX> angry
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and i can't blame them i don't know a solution
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i sure can't blame them for being angry on the other hand you know you can be angry about something for a very long time or you can say well that is the way it is and go on with your life
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh
 		for the most part i wish that it hadn't happened but it did so
 	
 	
 		yeah and that and that was that was in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the in the era</TIMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> that they were afraid of everything you know and and and they fought initially got into it because of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eisenhower</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		and he just he didn't want to be in it any more than than what we started out in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Desert Storm</ENAMEX> and then it just blew up into the war
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		well it has been that way for a very very long time though i can remember when i was in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">sixth</NUMEX> grade and that was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many years ago</TIMEX> we were reading about the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> struggling with that in southeast <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> yeah um-hum
 		
  
 	
 	
 		so and and and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asians</ENAMEX> historically have always had these kinds of wars going on there there has not been a lot of peace in that part of the world
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i really i don't know it we should not have maybe gotten involved but if we did we certainly should have supported our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who were there more so supported them when they got home
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right
 	
 	
 		and uh i am afraid that they were treated as castaways for the most part
 	
 	
 		exactly
 	
 	
 		and i i saw the movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Born On The Fourth Of</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX> and i think it did a good job depicting the temperament of the times
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah more than was apocalypse now
 	
 	
 		um-hum well <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dudley</ENAMEX> have we pretty well discussed the subject well i think so i enjoyed talking to you uh-huh bye-bye
 	
 	
 		yeah i think so yes it was nice talking to you okay bye-bye
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	