
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well i i been uh i've probably had more time than you have to think about this subject so i'll tell you is is it a serious problem yes i do believe it's a serious problem however there are solutions to it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and foremost uh where we compare we that we are now doing fifty percent of our uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are voting uh
 		we're probably making a comparison against uh some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> and uh and uh uh say newer <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">republics</ENAMEX> that uh that have very high percentages
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh so uh one of the reasons that that uh
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one one</NUMEX> of the reasons that we could get uh one of the reasons that it is lower in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> is that mostly we hold it on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesdays</TIMEX> God knows why we hold it on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesdays</TIMEX> and then we further complicate it by saying you know we'll keep the polls open until <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">eight o'clock</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		what
 		right
 	
 	
 		most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> uh a great number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> now work at various at different jobs that if a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are shift <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> they won't be able to get to the to the polls in any case if they uh have to work late into <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the evening</TIMEX> and not get up
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		my solution to that is that we hold it on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sundays</TIMEX> as do probably <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixty</TIMEX> to seventy percent of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> now
 	
 	
 		oh really they hold it on the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekends</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		they hold it on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX> no they hold it on a either a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> or a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> or at least a day when when uh a great number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> aren't working in in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> that's not true because a a great number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> work on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sundays</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		huh
 		well uh
 	
 	
 		but but that's one of my solutions so
 	
 	
 		i i know here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> that they've just instituted in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last couple of years</TIMEX> a um a real long period of time that you can absentee vote before the elections and
 		they i don't think they've seen a really high improvement
 	
 	
 		have you absentee voted in in in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> well i have absentee voted in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Hampshire</ENAMEX> and it's a fairly fairly complicated process where you have to go pick up the ballot
 	
 	
 		no no i always vote
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		i don't say it's that complicated but part of the process also is that you must register preregister at some particular point <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Hampshire</ENAMEX> is fairly easy but other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> you have to register <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every couple of years</TIMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		hum
 		to absentee vote specifically
 	
 	
 		well to vote to vote to just vote so registrations are perhaps a a problem also and we're the mobile mobile society uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are always mobile you know one out of every <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> moves every year
 	
 	
 		oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh that's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">almost a fourteen</NUMEX> percent turnover every you know if you compound that that uh if it is difficult to register to vote that would remove your eligibility to vote
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		but  i don't think it's difficult enough to prevent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are motivated in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place who or who are not just motivated who really believe that their they
 	
 	
 		well
 	
 	
 		their voice is heard i mean and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that i've talked to
 	
 	
 		well maybe that's another factor the motivational factor the motivational factor is probably i
 	
 	
 		right i think that is the biggest one that's the biggest problem i
 	
 	
 		well that's diminished by we we've noticed this in particular i i'm just read <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> books <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of them is <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Whose Stars and Stripes</ENAMEX> Now
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the uh trivial pursuit of the presidency in nineteen <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty eight</NUMEX> it's a fairly decent book i mean it's uh
 	
 	
 		oh really
 		hum
 	
 	
 		it's preceded by uh several other books by these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> uh <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wake Me Up When It's Over</ENAMEX> was about the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty four</NUMEX> elections and i forget what the other books were but any case uh it it it's uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh the  uh uh there was the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blue Smoke</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mirrors</ENAMEX> was the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty two</NUMEX> uh they these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> uh have taken the place of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Theodore White</ENAMEX> on reporting elections
 		in any case they say that uh there's a definite trend uh well you know toward <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> using negative voting it's the only way that you can use television effectively
 	
 	
 		i don't understand that why do uh is that just because they have such a low opinion of the public and the public's um gullibility
 	
 	
 		no the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> would rather hear something negative about the other guy
 		than uh than than a positive factor and you and you know to if you if you go on the attack and and put some sensational thing before the public as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Dukakis</ENAMEX> learned in the last campaign
 		and it's not refuted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> will you know uh believe it if you don't refute it as he didn't that that there must be some truth to the matter see
 	
 	
 		well he did refute it
 		he he refuted it just wasn't effective enough to
 	
 	
 		well he didn't refute it until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last two weeks</TIMEX> of the campaign he didn't believe anybody would believe that and indeed his trend started upward
 	
 	
 		well that see i i didn't believe anybody would believe that either i i i guess i have i have a hard time coming to terms with the the fact that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> really
 	
 	
 		well they do
 	
 	
 		was you know so
 	
 	
 		well don't give too much credit to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> for their motivational ability and and and it
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well then how can a democracy work then how how can it work
 	
 	
 		well it uh well i don't know is it working i mean that's that's the question i guess the question also is that we discovered is that they don't throw rascals out everybody seems disappointed but they don't throw the rascal out their own rascal
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh my my solution to
 		to part of this is is to
 		to make it an economic economic incentive for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to vote that sounds rather crass i think because then then you're saying well uh
 	
 	
 		what
 		
 
 	
 	
 		you know you  it could be convoluted convoluted in many ways where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would actually uh by paying them i mean you know you take a certain amount off their income tax or property tax or whatever
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		but that it would be very difficult to administer because i'm sure that any time money and votes are involved it just the whole thing just stinks
 	
 	
 		well
 		how about how about the reverse of that when i've heard about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>'s elections they are allowed to run for what a total of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six or eight weeks</TIMEX>
 		even for the higher <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> in the in the land what if we
 		totally took money out of the campaign made just severely limited the campaigns so money wasn't so much of an issue i feel like if if we did that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would have a lot higher confidence
 		that their vote was counting rather than their contributions would count
 	
 	
 		yeah but the idea is to get the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> to the polls and and and we have to make it as easy as possible for him to get to the polls
 	
 	
 		i don't think i don't care how easy it is for them i don't think they're going to because they don't think that their that anybody listens to their vote they think whoever has the bucks they really think that the packs
 		you know no matter what you're promised during a campaign and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> we're promised hardly anything of substance right
 	
 	
 		oh you mean the special interest groups
 	
 	
 		and uh and uh yeah no matter what a uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> promises during the campaign which isn't very much specific any that they don't promise anything specific <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> but whatever you're promised they just
 		they just reverse themselves depending on who pays them what once they get into office i mean i think that's the
 	
 	
 		well read my lips and and and no new taxes and yet <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> did that but i mean but but he's excused from that generally <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i've read polls now where they've excused him because there was a a definite necessity to balance the budget
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		
 
 		well then why did he say that during his campaign then he should it was totally
 	
 	
 		oh he he he gave it that he he did he did he promised the best he could and he's the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and he should
 		he should address those problems and if there needs to be a change in a period of time why what was so funny about it is that i guess that it happened so rapidly you know he knew it he actually knew it and being associated with government he should be held up to the light for that and maybe he will
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah yeah
 		yeah yeah well
 	
 	
 		but i think it's uh i mean i think you
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		you still have a view that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voter</ENAMEX> is different from other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> and he's motivated because we happ en to be the cradle of liberty and all that i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> are motivated uh
 	
 	
 		what about what about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> in the other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> that you're talking about like in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> where they have higher turnouts
 		and well the newer <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">democracies</ENAMEX> because it's going to be totally different but
 	
 	
 		well i don't know if they have higher turnouts overall i don't think <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> has i think <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> has about a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">seventy percent sixty five percent</NUMEX> turn out
 	
 	
 		you don't think so
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i think that we just discovered in this in in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> elections is one of the greatest and massive things in the in the world
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		uh just it was got violent more violent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> they went down to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">almost fifty percent</NUMEX> in this election before they blew up <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gandhi</ENAMEX> but
 	
 	
 		right
 		oh really
 		
 
 	
 	
 		simply because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were so concerned about
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		their inability that to that their vote doesn't count anyway
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		and the corruption of politics in in in that situation
 		but then but you know everything is relative to when uh  you know we had higher turnouts because at that time we  talk about the turnout relative to the eligible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voter</ENAMEX> right
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i mean is but but before these enormous before this <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Voting Rights Act</ENAMEX>
 		what we had was a a great deal of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> uh mainly the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Blacks</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanics</ENAMEX> were precluded by
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh
 	
 	
 		by uh voting laws uh from registering from their eligibility to register now everybody's available
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		so if you really computed it they probably when we said we had a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">seventy percent</NUMEX> turnout in nineteen fifty we really only had <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">a fifty percent</NUMEX> turnout because all the eligible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh i see because right
 		weren't qualified disqualified were disqualified
 	
 	
 		you know the it was skewed by the eligible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> being less than the total <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> of
 	
 	
 		but isn't that isn't that kind of a blanket racist kind of thing to say the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Blacks</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanics</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minorities</ENAMEX> just don't vote or is that just the the truth
 	
 	
 		no i think the high there's a higher percentage in in certain <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Black</ENAMEX> areas of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> i don't know about <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanics</ENAMEX> you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i just
 		i i mean i haven't studied the statistics well enough to i mean i think in this sort of a
 	
 	
 		well
 	
 	
 		conversation we can only do our own reactions
 	
 	
 		right right but you know that just made me think of something that happened down here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> they have this huge fight going over redistricting here and at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point they did they took another vote on it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minorities</ENAMEX> could not get enough of a vote out to to pass their plan and this is something that had been going on for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> it was on the news <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">every night</TIMEX>
 		they and they have had lawsuits over it i mean it was it was a major issue and there still wasn't enough minority vote to get to pass the plan that they were backing
 		so that's you you know i think that you have really hit on something there
 		to say that uh
 		those
 	
 	
 		what do you mean
 	
 	
 		well with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minorities</ENAMEX>
 		and we're saying we have low voter turnout maybe it is is uh
 		now that we have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minorities</ENAMEX> included in the
 	
 	
 		you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karen</ENAMEX> i wonder if we are recording
 	
 	
 		why did you not press one
 	
 	
 		i did press <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> but usually by this time they tell me that the time is up
 		
 		
 	