
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		you want to go first
 	
 	
 		well i believe that the um the voice that uh initialized this call asked about uh if we thought that it should be something that
 		should be put into action
 	
 	
 		yeah like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> if should the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> make it universal or something like that
 	
 	
 		yes i i i i would be committed to that
 	
 	
 		uh-huh you you would be in favor of it
 	
 	
 		because
 		oh definitely yes
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i know that there are many <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> that um
 		are very successful with the operation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> uh providing that plan
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		do they have options on who they
 		uh you know like choices of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> and that type of thing
 		do you
 	
 	
 		um i'm not sure what how their program is run but i know it has been successful
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i would really have to uh read the history of
 		probably i uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> that has faired very well with it i'd like to see the uh
 		the data on that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> that's the way with me i don't know a whole lot about it i would that's the only concern i would have because i think personalities
 		plus the type of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> it is has a lot to do with the care
 		and if you didn't have any choice
 		on you know on who you go to
 	
 	
 		well i
 		yes i think that's primary is if you have a good relationship
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		with your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> that you can feel free to discuss
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		anything with him
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh
 	
 	
 		or to change even like if you didn't approve or didn't think you were getting good service
 	
 	
 		oh absolutely that the choice would be yours
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um given the proper guidelines for your health
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that you should be able to make um a choice there
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> that that's one of my main <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX> i i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> that has
 		their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> has been sick for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several months</TIMEX> and they just have found out what's the trouble and they have gone through
 		uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one two three four five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> and then a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX>
 		and they finally determined what the problem was it took that long
 	
 	
 		yes and the expense of that yes
 	
 	
 		and that that something like that you know i thought if you couldn't change or
 		look elsewhere
 		you know for help
 		if you want i don't know how that program works you know if you can do that
 	
 	
 		well i would i would think that they would have that as part part of the benefit
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		to the health care program that you would indeed have a choice
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that you could select that individual yourself
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i'm sure that they would have a history of each doctor
 		and hopefully that they would have their um
 		accreditations there too
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		i guess that's that's primarily was one of my thoughts you know because you know how government is
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yes um
 		but those guidelines have to be set up and i think they should be voted on by the public
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh
 	
 	
 		for them to have a choice on
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		if they're in favor of it or not
 	
 	
 		right yes
 		and of course they would give a full plan of what their intentions would be and
 	
 	
 		it it would
 	
 	
 		um
 		i think that's
 		primary uh for the health if they were going to have a universal health care plan
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that uh they would have all the facts and the figures and uh
 		what it would mean to each individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and uh and individual
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		perhaps being single
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		huh
 	
 	
 		um i'm not sure what else that uh
 		we could address uh on health care
 		um
 		other than the fact i think um
 		the eyes and the ears and the uh whole self should be uh
 		uh included in all of that uh dental eye care and uh  our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> as a whole should be included in that because
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		there are so many <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">avenues</ENAMEX> that needs to be um
 		undertaken in a program like that
 		um
 		i wouldn't want to have to go for a private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> for
 		anything and not be covered by the program
 	
 	
 		uh-huh i know where my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> works they have uh an option
 		right now where they can have their own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physician</ENAMEX> or they can choose one that their company
 		has elected
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and that costs them less
 		if they take the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> that the
 		that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> has selected
 	
 	
 		and does he have an option uh if he doesn't care for the personality
 	
 	
 		he get
 		well only to the point that he could go to somebody at his own expense
 	
 	
 		oh i see
 	
 	
 		otherwise he would you know he has to take the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physician</ENAMEX> that uh and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> has chosen as their
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		you know the one they have taken
 		and their again i mean he's gotten good service he took the less expensive one of course
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well if he's pleased with it i guess that's uh the bottom line
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so but i i would be afraid of what would happen if you had a personality conflict or something
 	
 	
 		uh
 		right right yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah cause there's always that opposite story there
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> because that's the first i've really
 		known anybody that you know works for somebody that they had that option
 		you know to make the choice of what kind of insurance policy they what kind of hospitalization they wanted to take
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		it's quite different from when i was uh
 		under <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX>'s care that's for sure
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i'm i'm very thankful that i'm not under any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX>'s care
 	
 	
 		oh  if you have your health you're wealthy you really are yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 		that's right
 		yes
 	
 	
 		uh we live in a rural <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">area</ENAMEX> up here
 	
 	
 		uh-huh what part of uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX> do you live in
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> are you familiar with any of the area at all
 	
 	
 		well i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> that lives there
 	
 	
 		where
 	
 	
 		uh near uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh well that's that's a ways away but we live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Clarion County</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		uh we have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX> that lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX>
 		and uh
 	
 	
 		are you a native Pennsylvanian
 	
 	
 		yes uh-huh
 	
 	
 		okay so
 		i'm a former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michiganian</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		oh uh-huh that's a nice state
 	
 	
 		yes it is it's very lovely it's a very lovely state
 	
 	
 		so i suppose really our situation here is even different that it is in you know like more populated areas
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh uh</ENAMEX>-huh i'm sure it is uh-huh
 	
 	
 		as far as uh
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> that are available
 		of course we have good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX> here too we've been pretty fortunate
 		we've had some of the most outstanding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> in our area
 		for some of the different fields
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so uh we've been pretty fortunate um-hum
 	
 	
 		that has broadened so much also
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		that is the fields that you know are opening up are
 		um just phenomenal they
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i mean look at the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> uh case you know i mean they
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's a whole new
 		field in itself it's just
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		in itself it's just it's an auto <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">immune deficiency</ENAMEX> but it sure is a dilly one
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		it sure is i still wish they could do more with the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> situation though
 	
 	
 		yes i do too
 	
 	
 		they uh they just don't seem to be i know they're making progress but not like
 		that i would like to see yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		to eradicate it entirely yeah
 		well there's guidelines that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have to follow and if they're determined to uh have their cigarettes and the other uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		carcinogenic causing items then
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		how do you teach them i guess you would
 	
 	
 		but a majority a lot of them don't do these things even and it doesn't seem to matter
 	
 	
 		that's true too it's i i i really believe our environment have a lot to do with it
 	
 	
 		so uh it real
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well they say second hand smoke and that is worse than smoking  so so what do you do you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well you just have to ban the smoking to their to their little room that they want to
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah take their rights away from them they say  i never had the desire so i haven't ever had that problem
 		as far as that goes
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i can't take any credit for not smoking either
 		so
 	
 	
 		well it's a bad habit that's
 	
 	
 		it's hard to break it's a hard one to quit
 	
 	
 		that
 		yes it's they say that it is
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		well it was nice talking with you
 	
 	
 		yes very nice talking to you too and you have a good day
 	
 	
 		and
 		well you do the same and uh we'll be talking i guess talking around the country
 	
 	
 		right  okay
 	
 	
 		okay you bye-bye
 	
 	
 		um bye bye
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	