
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		um i guess my music taste musical tastes uh run pretty much the gambit i listen to a little bit of everything
 	
 	
 		oh well that's good
 	
 	
 		uh yeah uh i i grew up in east <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> listening to mostly mostly mostly <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> type music <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and western type stuff
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and of course uh grew up also with rock and roll so i'm that's pretty much ingrained
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh right now most of my musical uh experiences experiences are with radio
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we listen to one of the local uh you what's usually the number one local rock type station uh adult contemporary soft rock <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Chapman</ENAMEX>  right
 	
 	
 		hum
 		yeah
 		oh yeah yeah is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KVIL</ENAMEX> or yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh so we we listen to that uh pretty much all the time
 	
 	
 		huh well i grew up around here i grew up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort Worth</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um-hum hum
 	
 	
 		and uh it's funny because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KVIL</ENAMEX> back when i was a teenager was an AM station i think yeah and uh it used to have like the top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">twenty</NUMEX> top forty all the time you know
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 	
 	
 		and i of course i was listening to rock music what what i called rock music when i was a teenager  now the music is so different than what i used to listen to that i don't know if i could could consider it the same but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well it's i i was just thinking uh you know we we say or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KVIL</ENAMEX> says i think i think they call theirs uh adult contemporary
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		uh which means soft <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rock</ENAMEX> or early early type rock music and and that's really what i what i consider rock and roll
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 		yeah
 		yeah well
 	
 	
 		it's uh not rock
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and i are both that way we we both really like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Beatles</ENAMEX> a lot and um
 	
 	
 		right
 		um-hum well it's that's funny because i even when i first heard the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Beatles</ENAMEX> i couldn't stand them you know it took it took a a while before i really liked the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Beatles</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh really
 		that's funny well i'm probably older than you then  but but i uh i always thought the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Beatles</ENAMEX> were great and
 	
 	
 		well i doubt that
 		yeah i i might have been too old for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Beatles</ENAMEX> that might have been what it was  i was past that point when they came along uh but uh i i grew up uh listening to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elvis</ENAMEX> you know before even before the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Beatles</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh that's funny
 		oh
 		yeah
 		yeah see i liked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elvis</ENAMEX> a lot and he was like my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> and now my little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> thinks it's real funny because uh she'll see him she'll go ooh you mean you really thought he was neat
 	
 	
 		right yeah but uh
 		but uh
 		yeah but uh my uh like i said my my tastes run run the range we listen to uh you know even listen to a little bit of classical type stuff my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> uh plays the piano
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		and she plays a little bit of that and so we you know we listen to that she plays you know whatever what she can what she wants to
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		well that's good
 	
 	
 		um yeah but uh i guess <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">musicians</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singers</ENAMEX> in particular uh uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willie Nelson</ENAMEX>'s one of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">favorites</ENAMEX> you know so uh it uh
 	
 	
 		yeah i like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willie Nelson</ENAMEX> too
 	
 	
 		in the in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and western rein uh vein i really i'm enjoying quite a bit of the country music now
 	
 	
 		yeah well see i the the reason i said my taste is probably different is i have always liked country music and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> has always been just total rock
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and so uh we never could agree on what we were going to listen to after we got married because i'd want to listen hear <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and he'd want to hear rock and we couldn't get along because his rock was too rock for me i like soft rock but i don't like some of the heavy metal stuff he was listening to
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and um
 		so both of us were real strong <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> and uh we decided we start listening to contemporary <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> music so we started listening to one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX> around here that we both really like it plays just <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> music all the time
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and we've gotten now where that's pretty much all we listen to and uh there're some really really talented <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> that's you know song <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singers</ENAMEX> that uh do just <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> music
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yes i uh
 		right
 	
 	
 		so of course you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amy Grant</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like that are pretty well known there's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> named  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Carroll</ENAMEX> and he's my favorite because he has a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> sound but it's <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> lyrics
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and he's a wonderful song <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> he won a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an an</TIMEX> is it <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Emmy</ENAMEX> or what does it Grammy it's the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grammy</ENAMEX> awards they give for music yeah he won a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grammy</ENAMEX> for inspirational song of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year last year</TIMEX> so
 	
 	
 		right let's see the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">the Grammy</ENAMEX> yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well our our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> uh listens to uh to quite a bit to one of those uh i don't know which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">station</ENAMEX> it is she listens to
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		our son our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> is into heavy metal and our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>'s into the the the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> type music
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah well that's neat
 	
 	
 		uh matter of face she went to a went to the concert down at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">uh Reunion</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> uh
 	
 	
 		oh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sandy Patty</ENAMEX> and yeah well that's pretty neat well see i'm excited that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> these days are liking decent music and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sandy Patty</ENAMEX> right
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i mean all the songs of of course on on this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">station</ENAMEX> have real good good lyrics and good ideas and that kind of thing so i really encourage my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> to listen to that and she right now she loves it i don't know
 	
 	
 		right yeah
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		if it'll stick with her she's still young in elementary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		oh yeah well that's our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>'s an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adult</ENAMEX> so but uh so she's
 	
 	
 		yeah well that's that's good that she still chooses that but you know i like the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> sound there are several i like i like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willie Nelson</ENAMEX> i always like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don Williams</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> thought i was crazy but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah oh yeah i love i love his uh
 	
 	
 		he's always been one of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">favorites</ENAMEX> and um then my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> on the other hand he i guess when he was like in his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early twenties</TIMEX> really got into the heavy metal kind of stuff before we got married and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so then he'd want to play that stuff and i was like oh that's giving me a headache
 	
 	
 		uh that's uh our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> goes you know goes off into his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> and and turns his on he he's not around much either either very very much but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		he'd go into his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> and turn it up you know and we'd do our best to to live with it or get him to turn it down so and uh
 	
 	
 		that's right
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but uh you know it's i'm not uh i don't uh don't find too much of the heavy metal stuff that i want to listen to
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah yeah well i still whenever they um have these advertisements on TV for um records that have like all the songs from the seventies i was i was in high school like from the early seventies and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so all that music brings back a lot of memories you know and i'm always thinking oh i'd like to have one of those albums but since we made this agreement that we're going to listen to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> music i think oh well i'll probably set it on the shelf and  would never you know play it
 	
 	
 		let's see
 		yeah that's yeah so instead so instead y ou buy <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sandy Patty</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amy Grant</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		yeah  that's right we buy things that we know the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> can listen to
 	
 	
 		right that yeah that
 		uh i was trying to think there's some  uh we go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First Baptist Church</ENAMEX> over here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Richardson</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh there some some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">musicians</ENAMEX> some of the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from there that have become
 	
 	
 		oh that's neat
 	
 	
 		semi pro i guess musicians our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>'s gone uh gone on a couple of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">choir</ENAMEX> tour things with the with the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peoples</ENAMEX>' choir
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh that's good yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh you know she she really gets into into that singing with that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> you know and
 	
 	
 		yeah well see i'm an interesting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> because i go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Church of Christ</ENAMEX> and there's a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christ</ENAMEX> that think uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		now that's
 		you don't have music in the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Church of Christ</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's right and and i think my personal opinion is they're missing out on a lot and i love um this you know that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KLTY</ENAMEX> that's what i listen to all the time and i
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		i love all the music that they play on there but i have a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> with me that kind of criticize that and think that uh it's wrong and all this so uh it
 	
 	
 		yeah well i guess uh you know there there there are are ways to express your feelings and your beliefs and uh music is one of the ways of expression and you know it's not uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah yeah
 		well i told my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> the one thing i like about it is uh you know you kind of think about whatever you listen to i mean you just you may not realize you're doing it but you do and uh when i listen to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> music then i'm listening i'm thinking about something good you know and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		i'll be washing dishes or something and i'll think about a song and it'll bring back you know some ideas and so to me it's just a good influence but there's still a whole lot of other music i you know really enjoy listening to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and i both kind of really got into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REO</ENAMEX> Speedwagon
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right
 		
 		
 	