
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		what do you think about gun control
 	
 	
 		well uh
 		i am probably uh closer to being a what is it the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> is on the end of uh no gun control
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i guess i am probably closer to a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten than a one</NUMEX> i believe i am uh i am not opposed at all to having a waiting period for you know for the purchase of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh i think that is appropriate uh a background check on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that uh  excuse me especially especially <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that buy handguns
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh but  i believe that uh you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> gives uh the individual the right to own
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">firearms</ENAMEX> for you know for their whatever their own purposes are as long as they are legal purposes
 		and uh i am opposed to anything that would limit what the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> allows
 	
 	
 		yeah and i i think i think that is right uh
 		the only thing i object to is like <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">machine guns</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah i i i uh i agree with that uh although i can i can see where there might be even be a a potential uh sometime you know a need sometime in the future for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> to have
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh even <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">machine guns</ENAMEX> available uh you know if if we were ever invaded of course now that is pretty far fetched but if the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> were ever invaded i think that the
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> is going have to be the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to defend the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> at some point or or might have to at some point
 		and uh i think that there should be uh sufficient sufficient uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> and you know and ammunition and things available for that
 	
 	
 		do you think um
 		like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> of course before that you know he was in westerns all that all that time and and uh he was real gung <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ho</ENAMEX> And then  then just now
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">just this last year</TIMEX> it seems like he's he was uh and he was not that bill does not restrict anything outside of just having to wait <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven days</TIMEX> but
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		it is interesting that he turned around for some reason
 	
 	
 		yeah well i i always wondered you know why he was so adamant about you know about being opposed to that waiting period
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh you know even before i mean you know i i did not see that the waiting period was a you know it was a major restriction
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i think and i think a lot of times you know that uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> do not go out and buy a
 	
 	
 		excuse me
 	
 	
 		what uh uh a good gun costs like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two hundred</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five hundred dollars</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know a handgun they go out and buy the cheapest thing they can
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and and then they go rob a liquor store or something
 	
 	
 		yeah and uh plus you know  i guess my opinion is that if uh if a uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminal</ENAMEX> or somebody with criminal intent real criminal intent wants a gun they are going to get one
 	
 	
 		yeah that is true
 	
 	
 		uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealer</ENAMEX> is not going to you know he's not going to wait <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the seven days</TIMEX> for a gun anyway
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		so it is it is only the actually it is only the  the uh
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are trying to be
 		uh law abiding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are the ones that are going to wind up
 		being able to get the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> legally
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh you know after even with the waiting period and i you know i cannot see that uh that there is anybody that that does not have criminal intent that would have uh any reason to object to that waiting period that is
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		that is right
 		and a lot of times like um
 		what is his name i can't remember his name right the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tower</ENAMEX> uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitman</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitman</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know he was sane and and i guess they could have said like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee Harvey Oswald Oswald</ENAMEX> was sane when he bought his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> you know but he bought his by mail anyway
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but later on you know something can happen they can they can have a brain tumor or they can break down <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> way or another
 	
 	
 		right well uh you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hinckley</ENAMEX> was the one that took the shot at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> and uh he bought his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> at a pawn <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX> here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> i think or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">somewhere</NUMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> area
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and you know if if he'd had to have a waiting period he didn't stay in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> long enough
 		uh at that time to have waited <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the seven days</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		so if if there'd been a waiting period he wouldn't have had the gun
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> or a least he wouldn't have had that gun he might've had another one
 	
 	
 		yeah he might have
 	
 	
 		but uh
 		you know so i you know i can see that there are
 		are reasons for having a waiting period that uh i think that anybody that
 		you know anybody that does not have a a criminal background or you know any any real reason to not allow them to have one i think that anybody that wants one should be able to buy one
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's interesting because i don't own one  though i don't own a gun but that's you know that's my personal opinion anyway
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
  
 		yeah i do not either
 		yeah that is true because you know once once they start clamping down on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> thing or being against one <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> then the
 		
 
 		it gives them a foothold to to be against somebody else
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and uh and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hunters</ENAMEX> you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hunters</ENAMEX> uh
 		with what game species there are left well especially i mean using a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">rifle</ENAMEX> white tail deers mostly
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know that is what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> hunt for the most with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">rifle</ENAMEX>
 		uh you know they have every right to have a
 		a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">rifle</ENAMEX> and be able to to hunt
 	
 	
 		right you know they rifles and shotguns for you know for like you say for <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">deer</ENAMEX> hunting and for <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bird</ENAMEX> hunting are you know that is
 		kind of the the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> way so to speak
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		and that um i think it was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">rifle</ENAMEX> that that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> shot that burglar with in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arlington</ENAMEX> or wherever it was
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		yes i think it's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years ago</TIMEX> or so now
 	
 	
 		yeah i believe it was yeah
 		uh there was a a uh deal on television just uh i saw it uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day before</TIMEX> where there was an an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Oriental</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shopkeeper</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> i think it was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Bernardino California</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		That there were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> they were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gang members</ENAMEX> that came in to rob his store
 		and they all had <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> and he had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> somewhere under the counter that he got and he shot <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all five</NUMEX> of those killed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of them
 		but you know he he was really blazing away
 	
 	
 		yeah i wondered how he managed that
 	
 	
 		and uh i think he got shot twice himself and uh but he was okay you know it was just he was injured but not seriously apparently
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh you know it was really surprising but it was good you know  from my point of view it was good to see him being able to defend him you know his his property and his store
 	
 	
 		exactly
 	
 	
 		and uh you know i i think that is you know that is the intent of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> is to of that part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> is to allow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to defend themselves and their property
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		and and more and more of that kind of thing happens i mean can you imagine i mean it used to be like with the dapper bandit is one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> and a a lot of the stuff that he did they did not publicize
 		because that it would breach the security of the rest of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> the banks
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the things that he did is is um any counter top that was there up to maybe like <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">four feet</NUMEX> high he could vertical jump on top of the counter top and and jump down and and be
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		with those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> behind the counter before they knew it
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know and they they showed us a piece of tape of that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time but it looked like they had cut it up some and that was one of the things that was so scary about him
 	
 	
 		
 
 		right
 	
 	
 		and not only did he he um rob <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> but he uh
 		at the time when he first started he robbed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Safeway</ENAMEX> that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> was working at at the time  and that is how he that is how he surprised the cashier
 		he jumped he jumped back there with her and and you know there was nothing  she could do by that time
 	
 	
 		um-hum i had i had not heard about him robbing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Safeway</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but then there is also there is the uh what is his name <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bernie Getz</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">subway</ENAMEX> i guess uh well i would have  even mixed emotions about him uh somebody carrying a gun you know out into the public on public transportation
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh you know of course he was his the purpose of him having the gun was to defend himself because he apparently he had felt threatened you know on the on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">subway</ENAMEX> before
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh i am not sure that uh
 		the private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen</ENAMEX> carrying a gun
 		is
 		you know just the routine private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen</ENAMEX> carrying a gun
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		is uh necessary to
 	
 	
 		yeah i would
 	
 	
 		i mean if you are not if you are not uh in a position where you have to defend yourself you know
 		uh in a routine basis then uh
 		perhaps carrying a gun on your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> is not uh
 		is not all that advisable
 	
 	
 		yeah and then
 	
 	
 		uh i know that they are talking about here you know here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> about having a new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> law that would allow certain certain <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> to be licensed to carry a gun
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		i think they ought take a long a good long hard look at at who is allowed to carry a gun in those you know in those situations
 	
 	
 		yeah right
 		like the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> what was it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two or three months ago</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort Worth</ENAMEX> i think
 		maybe it was <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 		but he  he just convicted uh a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> for murder and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> jumped up and and apparently knew where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> kept his gun
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and held it on him for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a couple of hours</TIMEX> you know and
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		he should he should either have kept it fairly well concealed or kept it a secret
 	
 	
 		right
 		you know i guess that
 		i do not really know uh i i guess there is not really a you know a lot to say from my point of view except that
 		you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">the Constitution</ENAMEX> says what kind of rights we have and i do not i really do not see the the point
 		
 		
 	