
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 		okay
 	
 	
 		have you ever uh organized a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> reunion
 	
 	
 		uh no i never organized one but we're we have one uh we're going to have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Memorial Day</ENAMEX> i guess they've had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last two years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we go out to the my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farm</ENAMEX> and uh
 		and you know it is just a picnic and
 		spend <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		go fishing and stuff like that
 	
 	
 		how many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> usually show up
 	
 	
 		oh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about ten</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh it is not that big
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">huh-uh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because
 	
 	
 		it
 	
 	
 		um
 		we've had sort of
 		weekends like that too but i never thought of it really as a reunion
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i sort of think of a reunion with my uh
 		all the extended family
 	
 	
 		everybody yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah that would be hard for us because most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> is out in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> and some is in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX> and it gets
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		kind of hard to get everybody get everybody organized
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> is there someone do you all just sort of chip in and help out with stuff when you are there or
 	
 	
 		uh yes yeah my my uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> has a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> out there anyway and there is there is uh he keep us
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> down there
 		year-round so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		so he doesn't live there though
 	
 	
 		uh no it's it's it's like a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country country</ENAMEX> home
 	
 	
 		vacation home
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah it sounds nice
 		um are there <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> that are there too or mostly adults
 	
 	
 		yeah the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandchildren</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		just a few it just depends uh
 		uh uh all my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX> are dead so uh there is there are not you know  none of them are there and and uh then an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncle</ENAMEX> is dead so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the the big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> is a lot smaller that it used to be
 	
 	
 		um-hum are you all located in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh yeah we're in we are all uh
 		like they live up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sherman</ENAMEX> it is near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lake</ENAMEX> Texoma
 	
 	
 		um-hum but
 	
 	
 		and uh all of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> live in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> area too so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		do it that to me is you know
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> i know of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> i know of and that is about it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> the rest of it is sort of a big void to me
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but uh
 		you know we have uh
 		well we all got together it was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about two years ago</TIMEX> for i was i'd graduated from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> and um
 		i was going to live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> and so my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> invited it wasn't just family it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> too
 		but um we all got together for just a party
 		and that was kind of fun
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		nice to have everybody be together at once and things like that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> reunion
 	
 	
 		well
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		not quite <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> but uh
 		it was sort of a reunion before leaving it was fun it was on um
 		New <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Year's Day</TIMEX> so it was almost a celebration of the new year too at the same time
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that was kind of fun
 		but um
 		who was it a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of mine had a big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> reunion <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of years ago</TIMEX> and you know everybody flew in from all over the place for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX> and it really sounded like it was fun
 		but
 		i am not quite sure what i would do i think it'd be fun to like rent a big
 		mansion or <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> someplace
 		and have everybody meet someplace where they do not really know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and have different areas to explore and things like that so that'd be kind of fun
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		meet in the middle
 	
 	
 		yep
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		where nobody lives
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but at least that way it is at nobody's <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> so nobody one no one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> is responsible for everything
 	
 	
 		yeah and they don't have to clean up afterwards yeah
 	
 	
 		yep
 		that's for sure the cleaning up can be a mess
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but um do you have horses or anything at your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>'s farm
 	
 	
 		i'm i'm sorry
 	
 	
 		does your does your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> have horses there
 	
 	
 		uh no he doesn't really have any any uh uh domestic livestock anyway
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the he leased uh to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cattle</ENAMEX> to feed on
 	
 	
 		i see so it's so he really does use it as a vacation <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> it is not like a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farm</ENAMEX> that he has somebody else run for him or something like that
 	
 	
 		yeah pretty much he has a garden and uh a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fruit</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> and blueberry <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">bushes</ENAMEX> and things
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well that sounds nice do <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> actually pick the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fruit</ENAMEX> and things
 	
 	
 		um-hum and then there is wild blackberries there too
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so
 		he gets
 	
 	
 		yeah i used
 		we used to go pick wild blackberries at my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>'s property but we never got enough i used to make <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">jam</ENAMEX> but i never had enough to really make you know more than a jar or something
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		so it wasn't so worth it
 	
 	
 		yeah it is kind of they're kind of off and on it seems like
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		depends on the rain
 	
 	
 		that sounds is does he have a lot of land to go walking around and things there
 	
 	
 		um it is uh it is uh eighty acres
 	
 	
 		well that is pretty big
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i do not know how they do scale down there you know here it would be a huge amount of land
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> here that has a lot of space is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">four acres</NUMEX> as opposed to
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tens</ENAMEX> of acres
 	
 	
 		yeah and
 		and uh and most of it you know you just spend time on maybe <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> acres of it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh because that's where the ponds are and
 		where everybody fishes
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we kind of have a an infor mal contest
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncle</ENAMEX> uh put some bass in uh his pond <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years ago</TIMEX> well he put some crappie too but the bass we have not been able to catch any of the adult bass yet so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they're in there but
 		they're real spooky
 	
 	
 		yeah i think my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> put some we have a little pond at ours at his vacation ho me too
 		and yeah i mean really little and they were having problems with too many goldfish because we had put some goldfish in and there were too many little goldfish and so the big ones never got bigger
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh somebody suggested to get a bass
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so they went fishing and caught a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bass</ENAMEX> near some place and put it in there and never saw it again
 	
 	
 		never saw the bass
 	
 	
 		no so we do not know if it is living or
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh it is probably in there just burping goldfish
 	
 	
 		yep
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		we still have lots of little goldfish they propagate pretty well those little fish
 	
 	
 		yeah they really do
 	
 	
 		this
 		yeah because we started we have got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> in there now and we started with i think <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty little</TIMEX> feeder <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> that i picked up for a dollar you know many no matter how many it was for a dollar
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and
 		and some of them are probably
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">inches</NUMEX> long but he wants your really big ones you know the ones that get to be like a foot and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a half</NUMEX> long
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		and
 	
 	
 		they have there's a uh
 	
 	
 		it
 	
 	
 		you might put some like some yellow <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">catfish</ENAMEX> in there i do not know if they'd live very well up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> but
 		they get huge
 		and uh they routinely use them for bait for uh goldfish for bait for yellow catfish
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 		well we we'd want to put some small ones in so they do not eat the big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> the goldfish too  but yeah we could see i do not know if yellow <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">catfish</ENAMEX> live up this way but <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">catfish</ENAMEX> do i think
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah they live in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mississippi River</ENAMEX> all the way through <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota</ENAMEX> and up into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		so that you mean well we could try it that is a good idea
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		he's he was trying to catch them you know using little uh
 		i forget there's little uh nets you can use to catch <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> to use as feeder <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> and things like that minnow nets or something my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> was taking those and trying to catch the goldfish and it was really funny because uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		uh
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time he left the net in the pond and he like would put some tuna <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> or things in the middle of it to attract the fish
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh he left it in the middle of the pond and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">that night</TIMEX> he came out and the trap was gone and it was a raccoon that had taken it
 	
 	
 		
 
 		right
 	
 	
 		so it was really funny and you could see that you know you could see where the trap the trap was dragged and things like that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so
 	
 	
 		yeah that's what happens
 	
 	
 		but do you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> have fishing competitions while you are there
 	
 	
 		yeah  and uh
 		we feed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">catfish</ENAMEX> they feed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">catfish</ENAMEX> like uh
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every couple of weeks</TIMEX>
 		and uh and sometimes that's the best time to catch them
 	
 	
 		when they're feeding
 	
 	
 		yeah because they'll just they will just come after anything then
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and you could catch a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> anyway during that time
 	
 	
 		what do you feed them
 	
 	
 		uh mixed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Purina</ENAMEX> uh it is uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat food uh catfish</ENAMEX> food
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		yeah but
 	
 	
 		i mean it's especially made for <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">catfish</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah well i do not know how much different it is from <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> food but you know it's um it looks like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Purina High Pro</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		that's funny
 	
 	
 		but they come up to the top and it is the best time to take pictures because they come up to the top and you can see their whiskers come through the water and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they're the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">catfish the big catfish</ENAMEX> just kind of vacuum the top of the water
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		i have never seen catfish you know except in
 		filleted  filleted on a plate i think maybe i think i have seen once or twice in like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i've never seen them just alive someplace that would be fun to see
 	
 	
 		well they are really funny fish when you catch them they make a kind of a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a burping</NUMEX> growling sound at you
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they try to hit you with their tails
 	
 	
 		how big do they get
 	
 	
 		oh well the channel <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">catfish</ENAMEX> get up to uh i think the world record is fifty something pounds
 	
 	
 		okay but how long in feet
 	
 	
 		um that that is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only about three</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a half feet</NUMEX> long
 	
 	
 		do you know
 		that's pretty big though
 	
 	
 		yeah they get real fat
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 		from the time they they stay slender until they get to be uh <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">eighteen inches</NUMEX> long and then they start to widen out
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> we were up there one time and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> was fishing and i think that was when she was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> and she caught a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">catfish</ENAMEX> by accident she was fishing for sunfish and she said here and she handed me her rod and reel
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and and uh you know
 		it it was just pulling drag out
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it swimmed wherever it wanted to
 	
 	
 		yeah that sounds amazing i'll have to see them sometime
 		but all righty
 	
 	
 		okay it was nice talking to you
 	
 	
 		nice talking to you too uh enjoy your uh weekend
 	
 	
 		okay bye-bye
 		yeah have a nice <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Memorial</ENAMEX> weekend
 	
 	
 		okay you too bye-bye
 		
 		
 	