
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i think i get most of my news uh in headlines from the radio and then i follow up by reading the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> and news <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> about things that attract my attention
 	
 	
 		well i i do about the same i guess but in a different fashion i i i'm from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> originally and now that i live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> i live in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the winter</TIMEX> and then go back up north in the in the summertime
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i i feel that the the only legitimate paper although it might sound a little elitist is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> i've always read the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> when i was younger and i try to find now that it has a national edition i read that i also read uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i i i guess i do watch uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McNeil Lehrer</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">P B S</ENAMEX> because i i lean to that coverage and and i've guess i'm
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		i like them but they take so long i don't always have time
 	
 	
 		yeah well yeah that's a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">whole hour</TIMEX> show actually it's <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an hour</TIMEX> show <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">each evening</TIMEX> and and uh we we turn it on when we start dinner we seem to start dinner around <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> and finish it up
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i find that i'm leaning on uh i travel a great deal uh even overseas and i find that i lean on uh C <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N N</ENAMEX> quite a bit for concise and quick stuff and i'm
 		i'm i i'm quite satisfied with the way they put it out i mean i i don't believe everything they say but it's it's coverage you know
 	
 	
 		yeah i think C <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N N</ENAMEX> does a pretty good job i had not watched them very much except when i was abroad until the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gulf War</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and they seemed to have the best coverage they had more information sooner than most of the other networks
 	
 	
 		uh
 		well yeah i i i uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Arnett</ENAMEX> was reporting direct from uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> i think this is scandalous the way everybody's picking on him i i think that what he he reported what he saw and if you didn't like it that was just too bad you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		well uh i know that the coverage he was allowed to present was slanted but i think they said that frequently enough that  you shouldn't criticize the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> for giving us one perspective uh
 	
 	
 		yeah oh yeah i mean i
 		no
 		that that's right i think so and and i guess if it comes to um to magazines i don't read i used to when i was younger i subscribed to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U S News and World Report</ENAMEX> i i have seemed to
 		slide away from that and rely more on the local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> or
 		i i i also subscribe to something called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Press</ENAMEX> which is uh a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> that only talks about other uh excerpts from the world press which sort of gives you a different slant than it's not
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		as slanted as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> or as biased perhaps as a local paper
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but uh that i guess and the radio uh i listen to P B S radio a lot and i also listen to uh these <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty four hour</TIMEX> news <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX> when i'm driving i
 	
 	
 		yeah we have a C B S <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty four hour</TIMEX> station that i listen to on the way to and from work and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		do you read uh are you from southern or northern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		northern i'm from uh the peninsula <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Palo Alto</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so so well
 		yeah is that what is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX> paper out there is uh the major paper
 	
 	
 		well it's horrible The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX> paper is just wretched
 	
 	
 		yeah that's a terrible paper
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so i subscribe to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">San Jose Mercury News</ENAMEX> um uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Palo Alto</ENAMEX> is about midway between well it's a whole lot better than that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX> paper and
 	
 	
 		is that pretty good
 		oh the what is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chronicle</ENAMEX> isn't it
 	
 	
 		yeah there's the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chronicle</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Examiner</ENAMEX> but they're uh both run by the same people
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh yeah they just they really are probably the worse papers i've ever read i
 	
 	
 		they're just horrid so we read the
 	
 	
 		yeah well can you get the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L</ENAMEX> A paper up there that's a pretty decent paper isn't it or
 	
 	
 		uh we can but i don't like it so we subscribe to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mercury News</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		yeah well that's another one i read i forgot that i read the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> not as in depth as i used to because they their articles seem to be getting even longer and longer but
 	
 	
 		yes well again i read that uh  <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> columns on the front
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah uh i think i i agree with you that the problem seems to be they don't have enough time to do all the stuff i feel pretty well versed in in what i'm doing because i i do spend more time on that than i do say on sports or
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		although i watch that i spend a lot of time reading about these things i'm quite interested i find it very exciting to for the coverage we have now today
 	
 	
 		yes and i think we do get pretty good coverage i don't feel that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> is being shortchanged by the uh the news coverage
 	
 	
 		the
 		if anything they i think they listen
 	
 	
 		we almost have too much
 	
 	
 		well i don't know i i hear a lot of criticism about listening to these the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Rathers</ENAMEX> of the world and and listening and taking their word for it or their comment actually they i think they slant things but
 	
 	
 		well i cannot stand <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Rather</ENAMEX> i remember him when he was a local newscaster in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> and i hated him then
 	
 	
 		
 
 		no kidding oh well i didn't know that yeah
 	
 	
 		and i would not watch that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> for money and  he and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara Walters</ENAMEX> just really turn my stomach so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah was was  he
 	
 	
 		uh i watch <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Jennings</ENAMEX> and uh and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Brokaw</ENAMEX> sort of alternate
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well how do you feel about it i guess i i got to say if that's the subject if the subject is do i feel that we're well enough equipped to i don't know if if it said that i feel i'm well enough equipped
 	
 	
 		do we get enough news or something like that do we get uh the do we get the news that we want and i do i really think
 	
 	
 		yeah to yeah
 		yeah i think i do too i think you have to let uh you yous got to segregate some of it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		well that's about all i have to say
 	
 	
 		okay well nice to talk to you bye bye
 	
 	
 		nice talking to you bye bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	