
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		okay
 	
 	
 		i don't think i've ever met anybody that thought they were paying too little taxes
 	
 	
 		i haven't either i know i pay too much but
 	
 	
 		so so i assume that we're going to agree that we all pay too much taxes
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but then the question is are we getting what we pay for and and i think we don't
 	
 	
 		well
 		i i agree i agree
 	
 	
 		i think we pay far too much for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bureaucrats</ENAMEX> and pork barrel projects
 	
 	
 		
 
 		right
 		absolutely i  fortunately we don't have state income tax i know you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> do and
 	
 	
 		right well i lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> for a long time so i was really hit hard by the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">nine percent</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">California</ENAMEX> tacked on to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s
 	
 	
 		and it's heading that way though
 		
 
 		oh gosh
 		well i think in within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next few years</TIMEX> we're going to have it here they're trying
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i know <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> uh just raised their sales tax again because uh i was visiting in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> and uh uh i went bought a few things and i think your sales tax is higher than ours now
 	
 	
 		yes i know we're just taxed
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		probably is i'm telling and i pay enough in i pay income tax that some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> make and it really just tears me up i can't believe how much i pay but and for for what i don't know what i get for that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well i really do believe that there are huge quantities of money wasted on unnecessary unnecessary uh bureaucracy and on just flat stupid things
 	
 	
 		i do too
 		i do too i know there are
 	
 	
 		we have
 		we have uh <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">hundreds of thousands of dollars</NUMEX> going to uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to supervise <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who supervise <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who supervise <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and when it all comes out they don't do much supervising anyway
 	
 	
 		yes
 		you know and
 		i know it or uh
 		uh who cares about the sex life of a tsetse fly and why do we have to have you know
 	
 	
 		well actually as a matter of fact that sort of research i think is worth spending some money on because the uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		basic research really is what's made our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> uh get to where it is in its ability to compete
 	
 	
 		right
 		and i don't mind spending on on defense either uh that doesn't bother me at all course i work in a defense project <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> so naturally i'm for it but
 	
 	
 		no
 		well i you i don't mind spending on defense for things that work but i mind having <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> uh uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> spend money to create <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five thousand</NUMEX> pages of documentation to order something
 	
 	
 		yes right
 		right and you know those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> that that say they you know the
 	
 	
 		this is crazy
 	
 	
 		uh <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">seven hundred dollar six thousand dollar</NUMEX> toilet seat in reality it probably really does cost that because of all the paper work the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> requires that you have to go through to make that toilet seat to sell it to them it probably does cost <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">six thousand dollars</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		exactly
 		yeah i think the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">six hundred dollar</NUMEX> toilet seat is probably a legitimate expenditure given what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> requires of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX>'s probably not making very much profit on that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right
 		uh no and no no
 	
 	
 		but the probably <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five hundred dollars</NUMEX> of that toilet seat is going to uh ridiculous kinds of of paper work and supervision
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh um-hum um-</ENAMEX>hum i know absolutely
 	
 	
 		um are are you familiar with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grace Commission</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no what is it
 	
 	
 		well i don't remember exactly when when that started but it was back in the early eighties i think uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Grace</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WJ Grace</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Company</ENAMEX> was uh appointed by i believe <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> to um
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		create a commission to investigate government purchasing and expenditures and see if there wasn't a way to save money
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and he came uh he and his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of course he didn't do it but he got <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to do it came up with a a whole book's worth
 		of recommendations for making the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> run more like a business and he said that you know the the kinds of things the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> does even in renting <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">space</ENAMEX> would drive a business bankrupt
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> purchase things because of the rules that require them to buy certain kinds of things in certain ways
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 	
 	
 		that are totally irrational they buy more than they need or less than they need or many times as much as they need in little quantities when they ought to be able to um
 	
 	
 		yep
 	
 	
 		you know deal like a business and uh get things in quantity that will uh you give them a discount
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		they ought to pay their bills on time one thing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> does is is stretch out the payments
 		so that they end up paying penalties for things that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> could have paid for the minute it was due and taken the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> percent uh credit for early payment
 	
 	
 		right
 		right i know that
 	
 	
 		anyway there was this whole book that came out and i read some excerpts from it and every single thing they recommended was so eminently eminently sensible and and
 	
 	
 		i know they just
 	
 	
 		it just astonishes me that we have not put more of that into practice
 	
 	
 		i know it i know it just mind boggles your mind when you think think and it's it's scary to think that these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> are up there running running our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> that that approve of all this stuff
 	
 	
 		and everytime
 		right
 		and everytime the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> changes and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> move <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> they redecorate the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> they spend <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">half a million dollars</NUMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Speaker</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> to renovate an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> that had been
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		redone <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">less than three years</TIMEX> earlier
 	
 	
 		i know it isn't that sick isn't that that's our tax dollars
 	
 	
 		and then they come up with these crazy projects to do things like spend <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">seven hundred thousand dollars</NUMEX> to make <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lawrence Welk</ENAMEX>'s birth place a shrine
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i mean i do not need a national <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> around <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lawrence Welk</ENAMEX>'s birth place
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i don't either
 	
 	
 		and i can think of a whole lot better things to do with <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">seven hundred thousand dollars</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		i know it but you know what can you do there's really i don't even i really don't what know what we can do about it uh the ways to other than
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well i don't think it does much good but i write my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Congressman</ENAMEX> all the time i've got a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">congressman</ENAMEX> who is very concerned about uh uh irrational expenses and who is a real fiscal conservative
 	
 	
 		responsible
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		that's good
 	
 	
 		and and so one of the things i do is donate money to his campaigns and uh write to him when i see things that outrage me
 	
 	
 		uh-huh well t hat's good
 	
 	
 		and uh i don't know that it's going to help any but if he got uh if if a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Congressmen</ENAMEX> get that kind of input from their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">constituents</ENAMEX> maybe they'll do a little something
 	
 	
 		um-hum something be done maybe  yeah that's a key is maybe i know i uh i
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		donate to work we have uh a thing to you can donate but of course what we're donating our uh political <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> that we're dono donating is
 		whoever is is for the defense <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> you know of course our defense budget that's who our money our money goes to we really don't have any say so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well i'm in favor of spending money on a strong defense but not of wasting it and some of the things that we do uh like have
 	
 	
 		i wouldn't either
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> different kinds of incompatible computer equipment for the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX> it's just dumb
 	
 	
 		yes yes that's dumb
 	
 	
 		there's no reason why we shouldn't have somebody take a look at uh all of the things that the various services use and make them interchangeable
 	
 	
 		absolutely i just what's wrong with that i
 	
 	
 		then the same spare parts can be used in  in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX> maybe
 	
 	
 		that's right
 		yeah yes i know
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		i can't understand but
 		i know our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> my property tax goes up all the time i'm right at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DFW</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airport</ENAMEX> so we're we
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		we should be getting a tax break because we get all  the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> i live in gets all of the uh revenue from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DFW</ENAMEX> because it's in our city limits but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it doesn't all it's  they're just building these great big fancy <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> and uh uh taxes are just going up and up but course my property the value of my <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">home</ENAMEX>'s going up too so that doesn't hurt that's always good
 	
 	
 		um
 		well that's good but that's that's small comfort because it doesn't bring you any income until you sell it
 	
 	
 		that's true  you got that right
 	
 	
 		
 
 		now we don't have uh property taxes going up as much as you all do because we had proposition thirteen that says uh once you have had your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> appraised then they can only raise the taxes
 	
 	
 		you got
 		enough's enough
 	
 	
 		i believe it's two percent or maybe it's <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">three percent</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> uh until you sell and then it's reevaluated
 	
 	
 		that's great
 		oh okay well that's a good idea
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and that's that helps <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on fixed incomes and older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who have <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> that have gone up in value a lot but who don't want to move out of them
 	
 	
 		sure
 		yeah i keep reading where they say in in  in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> area where the
 		the property thing is just going to bust one of these days you know or and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX> too i think the prices prices of real estate is so high
 	
 	
 		well the prices are so high i don't see how they can keep going up
 	
 	
 		no i don't and they say that it's going to come you know a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> are moving out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> because they can't afford <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> can't afford to live there to work there so they're moving i know <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Silicon Valley</ENAMEX> they say is just
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Silicon Valley</ENAMEX> and they uh the the reason that the prices have gone up so high is that there just isn't anymore land left to build on most of the
 	
 	
 		oh are you
 		oh
 	
 	
 		surrounding land is all uh in preserves of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sort</ENAMEX> or other and it can't be developed so there's very little property that hasn't already been built on
 	
 	
 		oh okay um-hum
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the problems our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> is having is that uh with
 		all of the environmental requirements and the antidevelopment <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> taking over the city council we've driven out some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> which were paying a lot of our taxes
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		and so now they're going to have to assess us because they we've driven out the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> that were paying the freight
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		now that's a shame
 	
 	
 		yeah for instance we have the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Stamford Shopping Center</ENAMEX> which was uh paying oh i think it was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about a quarter</NUMEX> of our
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> budget because of the sales taxes that were collected there and in this recession a lot of those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> have had poorer receipts and so their sales taxes have dropped and we're about <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a million dollars</NUMEX> below budget
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		primarily because of the sales tax drop off and that uh and also <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hewlett Packard</ENAMEX> was uh headquartered headquartered here and so everything that they sold the sales taxes uh were paid
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	