
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat</ENAMEX> what do you wear to work
 	
 	
 		well it depends on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>  and what i feel like i don't have a
 	
 	
 		
  
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		a real like strict dress code as far as you know suits and everything i can wear pretty much what i want as long as it's decent
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know i can wear blue jeans i can wear a dress i can dress up
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so it just depends on the mood i'm in and where i'm going you know if i got a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customer</ENAMEX> coming in then i'll dress up If not you know hey
 	
 	
 		yeah my my schedule yeah my schedule's pretty similar i um i teach so on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the days</TIMEX> i teach i teach <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple days a week</TIMEX> so whenever i teach i try and wear a tie
 	
 	
 		blue jeans
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh but that's i wear normally just wear like
 	
 	
 		well that's all
 	
 	
 		khaki pants and a shirt and tie i never wear a sport coat that's ridiculous but then most of the time you know then i just have to uh i can wear jeans or
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 	
 	
 		or just casual clothes i think they i think they frown on shorts and sneakers but i think i could probably get away with jeans and sneakers uh
 	
 	
 		oh we can't even wear shorts
 	
 	
 		yeah i could well if i don't have to see students
 		and uh i'm just in my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lab</ENAMEX> and no one sees me then i'm probably okay
 	
 	
 		oh no shorts are no no go here you can't wear shorts you can't wear uh like halters and stuff like that and to me really you can't wear anything that's
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh outside clothing you know like for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> time and uh in the winter time i guess you can pretty much wear what you want as long as it's presentable that's what i consider
 	
 	
 		right um-hum
 		yeah well that makes sense
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know just don't get too outrageous here
 	
 	
 		yeah as long as you're clean and yeah that makes a lot of sense
 	
 	
 		and not too dressy like you know after <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> stuff i've never some of them get sort of touchy too so
 	
 	
 		
 
 		uh-huh yeah that's true
 	
 	
 		and uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> you see you have you can't wear halters or nothing like that i mean at all
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		like even if you got a jacket on you got to have a bra on and all that stuff
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		which no big deal  to me  so but as far as dress for dressing for work that i don't it doesn't bother me i'd prefer if we had a uniform
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i really would to save a lot of money if you had a uniform
 	
 	
 		yeah that would matter that would
 	
 	
 		because when i while i was in the service and see i had clothes that i could wear whenever i got ready but
 		you had to wear that uniform to work and so you knew what you was going to wear wasn't no what am i going to wear today
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah and you don't have to worry about fashion and stuff too you know buying nicer clothes and things yeah that makes a lot of sense
 	
 	
 		nope
 		that's right
 		i wouldn't mind having a uniform <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> think i'm crazy but
 	
 	
 		well you know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">waitress</ENAMEX> and she has like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> uniforms that she sort of wears in rotation and she likes that you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		that's right
 		yeah because it it doesn't mess up your clothes either
 	
 	
 		um-hum yeah your your
 	
 	
 		you know because like at work if something gets on my clothes and ruins it it's just ruined
 	
 	
 		um-hum that's right where the the uniform as as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">waitress</ENAMEX> now your uniform really it might be a little expensive when you first buy it but you know that's it doesn't it's made of polyester so it doesn't stain like <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cotton</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wool</ENAMEX> would you know
 	
 	
 		yeah well see if you work at a fast food because i work at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wendy's</ENAMEX> sometime on the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekends</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they give you the uniform so it it's supplied so you know if it messes up hey it's their  uniform they messed it up you only wear it you know to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wendy's</ENAMEX> so if you mess it up at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wendy's</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah um-hum
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		there's no big deal
 	
 	
 		yeah well that makes sense yeah that makes a lot of sense
 	
 	
 		but you know uh of course <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> i'm sure if they ever went to uniforms they're not going to just give them to you
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		that's something
 	
 	
 		
 
 		but now some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> around here do wear uniforms you know the facility <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> or maintenance <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX> and all of them have have <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh yeah</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		that's probably the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that probably the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are prone towards getting dirty
 	
 	
 		yeah the yeah that's what they are too
 	
 	
 		yeah with the type of job that you have you might be getting dirty either either manual label labor where you'll perspire heavily or uh or where you'll come in contact with uh oil and things
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah because they're always in the high space up you know working on stuff
 	
 	
 		right um-hum
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and all i do is i sit at a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">desk</ENAMEX> and program but that's not going to get me dirty  so
 	
 	
 		yeah that's what yeah i find too um if you're a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">programmer</ENAMEX> do you get cold does your how's your air conditioning work
 	
 	
 		well uh mine it works pretty good i have a sweater at work because sometimes it gets chilly and everything you know but uh but the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>'s like that i'm not in a clean <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> or nothing so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh oh see yeah because my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> is really heavily air conditioned because i guess they they keep the air conditioning on all the time where they don't in a lot of the other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> because of the computers and um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah well see i just have my the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> is computerized okay and so it's all air conditioned but my my computer is like by my desk and then
 	
 	
 		right um-hum
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you go to another <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">cube</NUMEX> and then somebody else's but uh the computer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> now they're real cold and i don't have to work in one of those
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah see sometimes my air conditioning gets really cold i think it's probably because my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> is one of the only ones air conditioned in a
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		a large area you know probably probably that's why i get because sometimes boy i'll get i'll freeze it's so cold in there especially when it's ninety degrees outside
 	
 	
 		oh well then yeah it's just
 		no matter
 		and seems like it kicks in extra hard
 	
 	
 		right yeah and blows on my legs man <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time i left i thought i was going to i thought i was going to freeze the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> i wore shorts to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> because i was just going to be in my lab
 		and i wanted to be comfortable because i thought the air conditioning would be all turned off you know and jeez if it wasn't the air conditioner wasn't blowing it wasn't fifty <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">five degrees</NUMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		cold huh
 		i think the reason why we can't wear shorts is because then the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> would be in competition
 	
 	
 		that's true a lo t of those nice looking legs yeah
 	
 	
 		see and then you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> couldn't work
 	
 	
 		yeah i was just laughing it's funny that um we get clothing you know because uh i'm i'm in graduate school i only work part time and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we recently we decided we'd buy a sewing machine because that would be a good investment you know and we could make clothes and save money so she's made me shorts
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well of course you know she makes shorts and she says here i made you shorts and they're uh they're a nice material nice checkered plaid material here but
 		but she didn't put a fly in them  you know the pattern she bought didn't have a fly so it's like well they're fine for her but uh you know they're just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">everyday summer</TIMEX> shorts you know but there's no fly
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		you kidding me those are real good for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> to wear so
 	
 	
 		yeah they're not for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> that really changes your the whole way you do your <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX>  so i was laughing i thought that was funny you know because well i i was up at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> and everybody says oh jeez those new shorts they i think they were laughing because they are sort of a wild
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">color</ENAMEX> you know but i was just crossing through to get my mail and stuff
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		now my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> now he he golfs every weekend
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so he's got different outfits
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and he cracks me up with these color codes
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		the uh his aqua colors and i tell him see only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like you on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">golf course</ENAMEX> wears them colors  that's the only place you could probably wear it you know
 	
 	
 		
 
 		that's probably true without being laughed at uh-huh yeah i'm not i've never i laugh at the wardrobe my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father-in-law</ENAMEX> wears golf clothes and it's the only time he puts on those funny clothes yeah he doesn't wear those in the back yard or casually around
 	
 	
 		yeah uh-huh
 		now oh yeah
 		yep
 		no just when they go to play golf
 	
 	
 		just when they go to play <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">golf</ENAMEX> they wear those funny clothes hat's true
 	
 	
 		now i think <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX> now <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX> has a strict dress code when i uh i went to apply for them before i came here and they men they used to have to they have to wear white shirts i don't care what their job is they have to wear a suit
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		um-hum yeah
 	
 	
 		and see to me that's ridiculous because you're working with all that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">xerox</ENAMEX> machines and stuff like that all that black ink huh-uh no give me a break dude no i think them them <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> should be able to wear blue jeans
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know because that stuff gets really bad
 	
 	
 		yeah but they have that dress code i i you know i also know um <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EDS</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">uh EDS</ENAMEX> i have some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> that interviewed with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EDS</ENAMEX> and uh you know they interviewed while they were in college so they didn't really have a suit with them and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> said to them well your second interview would be
 	
 	
 		they have a dress
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		here but  oh and on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that day</TIMEX> i would say wear a suit because i guess they just had on a sport coat and the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> even had like um a gel in his hair you know his hair was sort of slicked back
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know which is popular with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and and she says oh and you know uh i wouldn't put the gel in my hair you know in other words you're to borrow a suit <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two or three</NUMEX> piece suit
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		with no gel in your hair you know and that would she made it pretty clear during the interview you know the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first</TIMEX> interview how they were supposed to dress for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> interview you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		God
 	
 	
 		so i thought that was really funny too you know
 	
 	
 		i don't think that should be your hair i mean yeah i guess so because some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> do get wild with their hair
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know with these haircuts now  some of these haircuts boy i tell you i
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i don't know
 	
 	
 		i don't think my hair has probably changed in
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's funny because my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> is fifteen
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and he's into this fading crap you know
 	
 	
 		he he's into what
 	
 	
 		
 
 		the fade like it looks like no hair uh
 	
 	
 		uh oh really
 		
 
 	
 	
 		wait <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a minute</TIMEX> and so he has hair though he can i can only let him fade it a little bit
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i tell him he's got to have hair all over or none one or the other you know you're not going to be going around with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine hundred ninety nine</NUMEX> parts in your head and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s names carved in your head and
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		no no  huh-uh  and not going no where with me he's not
 	
 	
 		yeah i see them i see the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> with the the things cutting their hair all the time
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i told him no no hum-um we can't have that
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i'm not one of them liberated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> i guess i don't know
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well that's you know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> was the same way i thought it was really funny back in the nineteen seventies my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> came home with cowboy boots on while was growing up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> called my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tex</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about the next four weeks</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know and other than calling him Tex he barely talked to him because he was so angry he was wearing cowboy boots
 	
 	
 		well down here that's no big deal
 	
 	
 		yeah i thought it was just so funny you know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> we're not in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		it was very funny you know and all that over a pair of cowboy boots and it was finally my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> convinced him she you know the cowboy boots give you about uh <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">an inch</NUMEX> lift you know they sort of have a heavier heel
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and she and we're all short the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>'s short so she said well <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam</ENAMEX> if he wears <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cowboys</ENAMEX> that gives him another inch and it just may be
 		
 		
 	