
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">okay Pat</ENAMEX> can you tell me uh
 		what actually they want what everyday occurrences are
 	
 	
 		define everyday occurrences
 	
 	
 		right or do you have
 	
 	
 		every time you use a credit card every time you log in to a computer terminal particularly where you have access to a network to a network
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		anybody can with the right kind of skill and tools
 		get very much involved in those things which are on your system that you don't particularly want exposed that's why we have such security measures for our corporate information
 		yeah if you absolutely
 	
 	
 		that's a point um
 		um actually um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> using credit cards the information that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> that you give it to
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		has of uh  available to them is very limited that's to just your name i guess um you don't have to tell where you live
 		you don't have to put your phone number down
 		some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> uh ask you for it but you're not required to give that information
 	
 	
 		that's right when was the last time that you used a credit card that they didn't ask for your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX>'s license as well
 	
 	
 		oh very very few up here yeah yeah they just don't they don't ask for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX>'s license um
 	
 	
 		really um
 		well most of our checks are even printed with our address our social even our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX>'s license numbers are printed on there
 	
 	
 		yeah see my
 	
 	
 		because they require that
 	
 	
 		yeah my checks are it's just my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and my name no address
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so it's just names on the check so no one can you know i mean they can i suppose with a little leg work if they wanted to
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but the average <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s not going to do that anyhow
 	
 	
 		right but we're talking about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are interested in invading your privacy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who have a reason to do that
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are interested in building data bases of information about your financial background your educational background
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		uh one of the biggest fraud scams that i've heard of recently is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who have access to such information and they find out who's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">widow</ENAMEX> and what she's worth and then they present themselves to her as a uh a rich suitor
 	
 	
 		oh okay that's yeah i
 	
 	
 		and bilk her out of anything that she has those are
 	
 	
 		i've read articles about that but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have to be pretty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gullible um</ENAMEX> either that or or especially <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">widows</ENAMEX> um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		there are very vulnerable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> though older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are very vulnerable to such things and they tend to to
 	
 	
 		old people
 		right
 		right and and some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> some of the older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> today uh their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s handled all the finances so now they find themselves left out in the cold and they're really really not savvy as far as it comes to finances to handling their own personal affairs
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		uh
 		well on the other hand how can you be savvy with so much out there <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> there are so many clever scams
 		and and many of them are computer based and they're based on information that's available
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		in the public realm
 	
 	
 		i'm i'm still not convinced that
 		they can get you if you're if you're aware <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of all you never should give your your uh credit card numbers over the phone to anyone
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		which is which is kind of basic
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 		they <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> may generate lists are if you subscribe to a magazine i guess they sell lists of names to other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> but they'll send you junk mail usually
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		that's right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> and you can stop that easy enough just go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">post office</ENAMEX> and just have your name taken off
 	
 	
 		um-hum did you have you registered for a conference recently
 	
 	
 		uh yes i have
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">okay</ENAMEX> did they ask for your fax number
 	
 	
 		no they did not
 	
 	
 		okay i registered my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> for several conferences in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past six months</TIMEX> and they'll ask for your telephone number and they'll also ask for a fax number you would think on the surface that that is for
 		rapidly sending you confirmation of your registration or your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX> or something like that not at all those fax phone number lists are being sold in exactly the same way your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> address numbers are sold and you now get solicitations brought over your fax
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and you don't expect it from that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX> therefore you're not as uh
 	
 	
 		yeah but that's uh
 	
 	
 		you know you're not as leery
 	
 	
 		isn't doesn't corporate have a didn't they put a stop on that
 	
 	
 		uh some some cases
 		but that it it exists is what i'm saying those avenues exist
 	
 	
 		yeah right
 		yes they do exist and if someone wants to really find out about you i suppose if they wanted to go to all that trouble they could
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		i heard a story not long ago this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> saw a really attractive young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> and he said hey i'd like to know this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> more so he wrote down her license plate number
 		and he called a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> in motor <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicles</ENAMEX> and got her address and her telephone number and then he called a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> that he had in the credit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bureau</ENAMEX> and he got her financial standing
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		okay
 		from that he also got her social security <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">number</ENAMEX> and certain social security information is
 		uh a matter of is it is accessible if you know somebody in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> so before it was over with he knew that she was divorced she had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> they went to what her average income was he knew that she'd gotten a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> in the divorce because he was able to get those public records
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		he knew all about her
 	
 	
 		yeah you could do that if you really wanted to
 	
 	
 		and he introduced yeah he introduced himself to her he said i think our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> went to school together at such and such school she i don't really remember that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and i mean you know he was relying on her not remembering or
 	
 	
 		right yeah
 	
 	
 		or not being willing to admit that she didn't remember him and just moved right in on her
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		that's and you can do that anyone can do anything that's public record whether it's divorce or anything like that um whether you purchase a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> that's all that's all public record
 	
 	
 		sure
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		um-hum um-hum that's right
 	
 	
 		um what they do with that information <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are really
 		um go out and do it i suppose somebody does the leg work and they generate a list
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 		uh it's uh  i think lists are generated from lists now
 	
 	
 		um-hum that's true i'm still getting lists from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many many years ago</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		and
 		right
 	
 	
 		or getting junk mail from a list that had to have been made <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah we had uh we've got a an account at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sears Roebuck</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and we had moved from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> to another <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> and they've got our address listed now with with double <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX> in it and i've <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trie</ENAMEX> d and tried and tried to get it off but you just can't get it so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		since then we've gotten solicitations from other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> listing both <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX> so i know damn well that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sears</ENAMEX> has sold their list of names out to somebody else
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		of course
 	
 	
 		but there isn't anything you can do about that
 	
 	
 		no you can't stop them from selling your lists although some of them really are honorable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> and they will say if you prefer us not to put your name on a mailing list then we will not
 	
 	
 		right some of the some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">charities</ENAMEX> now will will do that if you chose choose not to have your your name
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		put on a list and i i do that you know we have our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">charities</ENAMEX> that we give to and then we say yes no just don't
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because you do it and then you're on everybody's charity list
 	
 	
 		um-hum and you have to really do some research or you do not find out who is legitimate and who is not and sometimes finding out who is legitimate and who is not is more difficult than finding out public information about people
 	
 	
 		that's right that's exactly right uh most of the funds that a lot of these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> collect
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		go to fund the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> i mean very very
 	
 	
 		absolutely
 	
 	
 		little of the funds get out to do uh anything worthwhile
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		um
 		it all started with the government
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> started keeping tabs on you and whether they
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		those list that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Internal Revenue</ENAMEX> has whether they leak out to the public or not i'm really not sure maybe in some cases they have in the past
 		uh once a list is out it's out forever
 	
 	
 		oh yeah you bet you bet and with computer technology now look how spooky it is for how accessible these things are
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		but the bulk of it probably
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ninety seven</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">ninety eight percent</NUMEX> of all those lists are going just for solicitations um some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> maybe are using them for ulterior motives i'm not really sure
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but the bulk of them is and it's junk mail and you can you can you can get off those junk mail lists you just tell the post office
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so that will limit that amount of stuff
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		i read uh i read and article where this this man
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> sent sent to everything they could possibly get and he was getting
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">reams</ENAMEX> and reams of paper all kinds of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">periodicals</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> and letters and notifications and what he was doing with them he was storing them up and he was using them for fuel
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> to go neat
 	
 	
 		
 
 		during the winter time
 	
 	
 		that's great
 	
 	
 		what i do is on all the credit card solicitations
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		if they have a return envelope with it i write across the face of it no thank you your rates are too high and i mail it back to them
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because now they have to pay the postage so now it's costing them something to do that
 	
 	
 		yeah they don't put as many of those prepaid envelopes in there anymore
 	
 	
 		they don't
 	
 	
 		not as many as i've seen in the past
 	
 	
 		oh up here they do well they're still doing it well it's just like up here we don't there's very very few times i've had to show my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX>'s license for to use a credit card
 	
 	
 		um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and i'm not sure why
 		you know why it's so prevalent down there and
 		maybe it will catch up up here
 	
 	
 		um that's possible i really don't understand that either but my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> some of it sometimes it's very difficult now the gasoline credit cards require your license plate number as opposed to your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX> license
 	
 	
 		yeah we've got the
 	
 	
 		although some of them have a blank on there for it they don't generally enforce using it
 	
 	
 		we've got the ones you just stick your card in the pump
 	
 	
 		um i've not seen one of those
 	
 	
 		yeah so whatever you whatever brand that you buy you just drive up to the pump you put your credit card in it and then it says you know please commence pumping and then when you pump then when you're through
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you put the nozzle back and it says do you want a receipt and if you can push yes if you want <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and if you don't want one you push no
 		
 		
 	