
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		what part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> are you in
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">uh Pennsylvania</ENAMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		oh you are <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East</ENAMEX> or west i'm from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh are you really what part of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		um the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Hills</ENAMEX> area <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Beaver County</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">well</ENAMEX> originally <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Beaver County</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh where are you from
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh Clarion County</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh okay i know where that is
 	
 	
 		i live we live out in the country
 	
 	
 		yeah that's pretty out there What well
 	
 	
 		yeah we have we have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> that live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX>  yeah
 	
 	
 		oh okay yeah i got my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> and my whole <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> there i'm i'm talking to you from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> right now uh-huh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh oh you are do you work do you work for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Instruments</ENAMEX> then
 	
 	
 		
 
 		no my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> does and who how about you
 	
 	
 		oh uh-huh no i'm just my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> works for a computer a computer uh federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> you know
 	
 	
 		place that that needed this well that's okay i guess it's an easy thing to do so you're you have a big do you have a rural <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> or what do you have
 	
 	
 		so
 		yeah
 		uh we have a big old <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farmhouse</ENAMEX> that we've you know remodeled
 	
 	
 		oh that's a uh-huh
 		those are beautiful
 	
 	
 		it had been you know of course a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farm</ENAMEX> it's a farm <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> and we
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah is it a is it a working <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farm</ENAMEX> or is it
 	
 	
 		ours is not a working farm
 	
 	
 		more more i can understand that that's probably what i would uh
 	
 	
 		yeah i have a garden but you know we have a garden but we don't farm
 	
 	
 		yeah i can hear the accent now i hear the  i hear the Western <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX> um we live uh we lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minneapolis</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about five years</TIMEX> we we originally lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> and we met and got married and then
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um actually married in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX> and that's that's not what they want to hear on this call uh at any rate we came back here with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> was transferred around uh up to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota</ENAMEX> and now back to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> with T i
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and we're leasing a uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> story town <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> in a section of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> they call <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh uh-huh
 	
 	
 		and it's uh near a little town called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Plano</ENAMEX> well it's not little any more
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh Grapevine</ENAMEX> do you know Grapevine
 	
 	
 		uh yes that's out near the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airport</ENAMEX> that's <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about forty five miles</NUMEX> from us
 	
 	
 		yeah my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> has a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> there he's trying to sell he he's living now up uh in in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> but uh he  lived lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">Grapevine</ENAMEX> for a long time
 	
 	
 		it's yeah
 		that's why we not sure we we're not sure we want to uh buy down here because we actually we lived up north long enough to appreciate the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um Minneapolis Saint Paul</ENAMEX> is very clean you know in terms of
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and in terms of housing down here um you really have your pick but it's just everything's overpriced for the economy
 	
 	
 		oh it's terrible
 	
 	
 		it really is i mean we're we're in a leased town <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> and it's uh you're probably your teeth will probably fall out figuratively speaking it's <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">nine hundred</NUMEX> a month
 	
 	
 		i
 		oh i'm not surprised
 	
 	
 		but you know what if you if you get anything under <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five hundred</NUMEX> you get into what they call high density living
 	
 	
 		
 
 		uh right right right
 	
 	
 		you know the big apartment <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complexes</ENAMEX> and and i just have no tolerance for that
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah yeah it's not good
 	
 	
 		no i prefer
 	
 	
 		and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> think the income is really great in some of those areas but when they sit down and look at what it costs  to live
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		and uh  of course most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> are you know fairly nice they're uh done up fairly nice uh
 	
 	
 		yeah but like the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> home we're in i don't know how i mean we this is it's like a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">duplex</ENAMEX> like a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> they call it like in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX> and it's nice but it's i mean the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> bought it for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred and ten</NUMEX> and now she can't sell it And our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		right uh-huh right
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well prices have come down on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> the duplexes
 	
 	
 		yeah i mean we'll our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> the attached on the other side they're very nice thank God they paid fifty <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> for it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh my heaven
 	
 	
 		that's how bad it i know
 	
 	
 		well i know up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Connecticut</ENAMEX> the same thing happened and uh it's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are devastated because they paid so much for their home
 	
 	
 		that's right
 		uh-huh yeah i have some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> that live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Westport</ENAMEX> and it's really really bad i mean you
 	
 	
 		but we like our area it like i said it's it's an old <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and everything but uh
 	
 	
 		uh-huh how far where is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Clarion County</ENAMEX> in relation to actually because we're considering moving to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well we're about a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">hundred miles</NUMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's not too bad that's north
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">north</ENAMEX>
 		and yeah and it's it's really not you know not that far
 	
 	
 		are you going up toward uh uh i'm trying to think of the name of that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> that starts with an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M Bradford</ENAMEX> no that's too far north
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bradford</ENAMEX>'s north of us
 	
 	
 		so you're you're not that far north then okay well you're really not too bad yeah
 	
 	
 		no no
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> was it a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> that you've had for quite <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few few years</TIMEX> or that you've
 	
 	
 		well we've been here since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixty six</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh then you have yeah do you have a lot of land or
 	
 	
 		uh we have fifty acres well pardon me we have forty we gave <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> to one of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh my well then
 		there you go did you have a hard time getting used to do you feel like you live in an isolated <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">area</ENAMEX> or
 	
 	
 		
 
 		no not really and and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX> keep creeping closer and closer you know
 	
 	
 		yeah i think that that's um i can remember in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX> when this has to do with <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> uh indirectly but i can remember when upper <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saint Clair</ENAMEX> was out in the you know
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the rural end of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> and now it's  it's a terrible connection
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah it's ours up here we have our rural <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">connections</ENAMEX> are real bad
 	
 	
 		oh well that's okay um
 	
 	
 		but we but we live about <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> miles from probably <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three or four</NUMEX>
 		not large <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX> but you know reasonable
 	
 	
 		but but substantially yeah substantially you know um do you like living in an older <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> and restoring it like that
 	
 	
 		uh yeah we're tired of doing it though we we don't want to do too much more
 	
 	
 		how big is it how many <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">square feet</NUMEX> do you have
 	
 	
 		uh oh golly i really uh we have um
 	
 	
 		well how many <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> do you think yeah
 	
 	
 		uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> downstairs and a pantry and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">upstairs</ENAMEX> we have a bath a bath oh we have a half bath downstairs too we have a bath <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">upstairs</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one two</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedrooms</ENAMEX> and a sewing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> and a junk room
 	
 	
 		a junk room yeah i understand we have that too that's that's large if your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> aren't at home any more that's large if your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> aren't at home any more
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		pardon
 		well it really isn't too big yet we we like a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> say that but um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's we just like it real well and
 	
 	
 		it's enough space for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>  yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah we had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> so and they've all moved you know on they're all out on their own now
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 		oh okay
 		yeah right that's okay well we've got um this this town <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> is pretty big it's <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about eighteen hundred square feet</NUMEX> it's got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedrooms</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">two and a half</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">baths um</ENAMEX> it's really nice
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well it sounds like a good buy
 	
 	
 		yeah it is i mean i would never buy it but leasing it is fine
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um but it's just again the the privacy you know um we had a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minneapolis</ENAMEX> that was on <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">three acres</NUMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> was raised um on a working <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farm</ENAMEX> near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dayton</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh and that makes a big difference
 	
 	
 		right near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dayton Ohio</ENAMEX> and he said you know he's he's slowly getting me to um not feel isolated if we move to to where there's more land
 	
 	
 		uh-huh you really aren't isolated because it's the advantages is your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> is far enough away that you're not bothered by being too close to people
 		but yet you can have your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> uh you can have them in you can go out you uh
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you have more of a choice you're not pressed upon as bad
 		
 
 	
 	
 		that's kind of what like his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> have uh land that they retired to um <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about a hundred</NUMEX> miles out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX> and in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgia</ENAMEX> and it is too far south for me but um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um but i mean they have one of the um when they said log cabin i just laughed that they retired to but they built one of these i mean it's just beautiful
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		it's like a custom you know it's not like what i would think of when i think of old log cabins  you know i mean it's modern it's right right it's modern it's beautiful it's <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> it's you know um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		more luxury
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right yeah
 	
 	
 		but uh i don't what else about housing except it's uh well <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX>'s housing economy i i i think it's holding it's own
 	
 	
 		uh they're yeah i suppose they are now we both of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> who live there have just bought a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> now
 	
 	
 		what part what sections are they in
 	
 	
 		uh in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mount Lebanon</ENAMEX> area
 	
 	
 		yeah that's nice
 	
 	
 		and uh the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> they bought is completely livable they didn't have to do much to it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">great</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the other one is uh uh has you know needs more work done it's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years old</TIMEX> i think and but they have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> too and they they bought what they could afford
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		that's yeah a really good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of mine lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Penn Hills</ENAMEX> and they've been in their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> oh probably about twelve <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> now and um it's it's you know they're going to start to see their return on their investment very soon um but it's a beautiful <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		uh-huh they are beautiful homes
 	
 	
 		i mean my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> lives is it called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Baldwin</ENAMEX> or Bebble i mean he lives all in that same area going from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mount Lebanon</ENAMEX> um it's real pretty up there it's just
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		it is it's real nice
 	
 	
 		and the neighborhoods are stable you know it's uh when you come to this part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> we've been away from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> long enough that you see the difference in housing
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh my you would you do when you move when we <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> got married uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> works for the state and we moved once a year usually
 	
 	
 		oh my goodness
 	
 	
 		and then after they had to start paying to move us
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that suddenly wasn't necessary any more
 	
 	
 		that's what it is here yeah that's why we're at a point now we've uh we're adopting and we have been married <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> plus <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and what happens is uh you just realize that once you get to a certain age the next <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> that you get  we'll be staying in  so
 	
 	
 		right yeah you have to stop some place yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah that's kind of like where we're so we're considering <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX> and we're just kind of you know toying with what exactly where we want to be you know a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> say it doesn't matter where they live if they have a nice <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and but i disagree with that i
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well
 		i do too i've heard too many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> say i hate it here you know they buy a place and they just hate the area
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		i know and it and the economy here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> i mean it it's steady but it's still not going up and i um i just refuse to buy it um if i know i'm not going to be there for at least
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX> uh you you know
 	
 	
 		yeah well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> they're having trouble selling their home they
 	
 	
 		oh i'm sure yeah there i mean you can go down a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> and here he told you this every other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> you know if it's been foreclosed on or you know even big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> um
 	
 	
 		hm
 		right uh-huh
 		oh yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		it's really i mean a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">and</ENAMEX> and it's hard to sell the properties <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JC Penney</ENAMEX>'s from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> came here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a couple of years ago</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they thought they were getting a great deal um because they could get a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five hundred thousand dollar</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> with they call it <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX> lot lines no property <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jean</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh uh-huh uh-huh
 	
 	
 		and it would make you ill to see this
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i mean it would probably be like your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> on uh you know a half a city <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">block</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX> or something
 	
 	
 		i i couldn't handle that
 	
 	
 		yeah i know and that's you know like i can look outside <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">right now</TIMEX> and look into the next unit you know it's across the way and it's landscaped and all that with azaleas but it's still it's still not that private
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		i get tired uh sometimes mowing because we mow you know a good bit of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ground</ENAMEX> around the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> area and i do get tired of that but uh
 	
 	
 		yeah but you have a rider
 	
 	
 		i don't know i don't think i'd want to change it
 	
 	
 		no and your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> have to tell you the truth um i think that if you can keep that that way you know kind of like a homestead
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		
 		
 	