
 
     		
 	
 		
  
 		well i've had a a little bit longer to think here because uh they waited <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about ten</NUMEX> calls before they found you Bob but
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		uh i i've been thinking about the fact that the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Gramm-Rudman Act</ENAMEX> that was eventually originally passed uh to satisfy to satisfy satisfy some of these deficiencies and place a
 		set of handcuffs on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> just doesn't work because now we do things outside the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Gramm-Rudman</ENAMEX> with consent of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> i guess and that doesn't seem to help us to much
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh i mean the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">savings and loan</ENAMEX> was a great example of that that's outside the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gulf War</ENAMEX> was outside so it doesn't it i guess we just don't have the resolve to
 		to really face up and and and follow those instructions if if indeed they are politically viable
 	
 	
 		yeah i believe uh i believe that's right uh i guess uh uh you know really what we've got to do is is face up to the fact that uh
 		our economy just will not support uh all of the programs that you know that the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the the</TIMEX>
 		some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and i think it's you know the minority numbers not in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minorities</ENAMEX> uh you know i'm not talking racial stuff but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minorities minorities</ENAMEX> in numbers  uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh want to have passed uh special interest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> uh have you know their own agenda
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and i think that it's time that uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> faces up to what i think the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in general have faced up to is that we just cannot really support all of those things
 	
 	
 		uh it seems to me that that there's there's a couple of ways that that i've listened to uh various <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> and the opposition and other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> propose and
 		and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> thing that's starting to ring a little true to me is um rather severe cuts in
 		in the defense programs since like closing bases and closing down programs etcetera simply because i i just don't believe as much as they want me to believe some of the special interests that you talk about
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		that uh mother <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> is that much of a threat to us any longer
 	
 	
 		right i i believe that's true
 	
 	
 		i mean we're seeing this thing just crumble if if anything now i see the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> wants <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">another billion two and a half billion</NUMEX> to loan them money because he's afraid of the outright uh chaos and confusion and anarchy because there's no <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> over there
 	
 	
 		well i yeah you know one of the things that i look at uh uh i'm in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> area and uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Armey</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Congressman</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> is one of the the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sponsors</ENAMEX> of the
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		the uh bill that's that called for the closing of military bases
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bases</ENAMEX> that's being closed or that's on the you know on the agenda to be closed is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carswell Air Force</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">base</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort Worth</ENAMEX> which is right you know right close by and when they decided that that was one that needed to be closed
 	
 	
 		yes
 		yes
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		there was really a a huge cry you know from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas Fort Worth</ENAMEX> area about you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		how it's you know that one is the one that should not be closed you know it's it's not fair you know to to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas Fort Worth</ENAMEX> but uh you know when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amory</ENAMEX>'s
 	
 	
 		exactly
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bill</ENAMEX> passed everybody said hey that's a great thing you know we're going to cut back on some of this unnecessary spending
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		just don't gore my <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">ox</ENAMEX> right
 	
 	
 		right and uh you know i think that's the the same case that that you know would hold true for a number of other programs uh
 		we all talk about uh about how the the uh transfer payments you know are not handled correctly uh you know the the welfare programs and some and some of those things and you know they all need major overhauls
 	
 	
 		yes that's right
 	
 	
 		but
 		they all need major overhauls until they're the ones you know until it's the one that that i sponsored or the one that my <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> gets the most benefit from or you know the one that that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> or my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandchildren</ENAMEX> or my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> or grandmother
 	
 	
 		well
 	
 	
 		you know that we've all we all all got a special interest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> that uh you know that's benefiting from some of these uh
 	
 	
 		oh i guess we'd almost have to i mean i don't know it just seems to me we'd almost have to change the way we do business in government if we didn't have special interest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> i mean right down to the state and city levels and so on but i was wondering about
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know i i was a little bit encouraged although it didn't seem to work out too well in this debacle in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the Fall</TIMEX> when they <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Fall</TIMEX> when they
 		they they did levy a tax on some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> richer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i mean they increased that bubble tax there i i was a little encouraged by that because that's another way to cure the deficit is
 		by higher taxes nobody wants to pay higher taxes but i mean there's going to be a crisis one of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> that's going to force us to do it anyway
 	
 	
 		right
 		right i i i  agree with that i i'm an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">accountant</ENAMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CPA</ENAMEX> and i went to a seminar some seminars <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> and uh one of our opening speaker our keynote <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX> this morning
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		yes yes
 	
 	
 		was is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the major <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> or fairly major anyway and one of his comments had to do with the state taxes  the state
 	
 	
 		yes
 		state tax
 	
 	
 		the state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas</ENAMEX> is uh you know is in a little bit of a bind tax wise and one of the proposal is uh to uh have a new state income tax but to have it only on on corporations
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		and of course you know he's corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> corporate uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> and uh that was just not the right thing you know  the the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> are paying too much tax already so it's you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well they pass it on to us anyway i i've never i've never even thought that they that they would absorb that
 	
 	
 		right so the same you know
 		right the same you know same thing applies you know if the tax is is geared to you know or or aimed toward me then it's a bad tax if it's aimed toward you it's a good tax  yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		that's right of course it that that  that's again that that issue just like you sited <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amory</ENAMEX>'s bill on the bases but i i don't know i  it just seems to me
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that uh i mean i it it does seem to me now that <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty</TIMEX> percent i i think i'm correct in this that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">twenty percent</NUMEX> of the federal budget is is is allocated now for debt payments
 	
 	
 		right yeah i believe at least that much
 	
 	
 		or interest payment on the debt but uh yeah and and and i know if i had to pay that much in my out of my salary i mean it it it's
 		it it just seems to me i don't know whether it it that's kind of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colloquium</ENAMEX> just use common sense but it it just seems like there has to be some there will be a crisis at some point
 		when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> programs can't pay off when the when when they can't pay off the the the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">savings and loans</ENAMEX> uh uh situation when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> can't be insured any longer when the pensions can't be insured
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		then <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are really are going to demand something to be done but it appears to me that i don't know if there is any short term or long terms steps without a greater crisis that takes place
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		you know i i think that uh you know i think we're just going to have to  as as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerald Ford</ENAMEX> said we're going to have to bite the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bullet</ENAMEX> and uh uh and
 	
 	
 		yeah but how do you get <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to do that though i mean i i i i i don't even find myself you know i see i i play that game with myself sometimes
 		i know things are a little tough so i say well i'll just charge this on the credit card and i'll pay it off in a little bit and then then every once in a while i get a shock i get the credit card up to <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">six seven thousand</NUMEX> i say this is absolutely insane and we sort of tighten up or something comes by to pay the damn thing off but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right yeah
 	
 	
 		i i i i i think that we're not paying anything off i mean obviously we're not paying anything off we w e've gone from the largest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">creditor</ENAMEX> to the largest <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">debtor nation</ENAMEX> in the last <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years</TIMEX> and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah  and i i guess that's the the problem or you know  as i see it anyway that
 		we as a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> are not prepared to do what we as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> would do and that's you know we cut off our spending and cut off our charging when our when our credit gets out of hand you know
 	
 	
 		yeah that's right
 		yeah i saw some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> on television <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> he was talking about the the the trade deficit he said
 		as long it's so it's so simple that that it was it was kind of it was kind of humorous he said as long as you continue to spend
 		more than you continue to uh sell
 		as long as you continue to buy in your <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> more than you continue to sell you'll have a trade deficit and until that comes under control uh the lending comes under control that that's your problem well i mean i i started to laugh at that i mean it seems so simplistic but
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i guess it is the truth we just keep buying this stuff and we don't have the ability apparently to sell our products overseas
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it is a very complex situation but uh i i guess but as a as an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">accountant</ENAMEX> do you do you find <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are worried when you talk to them about what our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> might do or
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah i think uh i think  not so much about what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> might do but that you know they're worried about what they're not you know what they can't seem to do uh it's you know it's it's everybody seems to agree
 	
 	
 		what they can't seem yes that that that's right
 	
 	
 		that we're really in you know in dire financial situation that something has to be done and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> is that nothing is being done you know
 	
 	
 		yeah i was i guess i was a little comforted by the fact that on this <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gulf War</ENAMEX> uh that we have received uh <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">at least sixty percent</NUMEX> of the money  that we asked for and i i should imagine
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		i don't know how that's coming you know i remember some i i just don't i haven't seen a real accounting of that
 	
 	
 		yeah i have not uh have not seen that
 	
 	
 		so i guess i guess uh uh if i was to take a position now and sum up because i don't want to talk too long is that the short term i guess we have to
 		some how as you say address those issues in the long term we'd either have to we'd have to raise taxes and cut back on some of the big the transfer payments and the military an and just bite that bullet
 	
 	
 		right i and i'm i believe that's right okay okay okay nice talking to you uh-huh bye
 	
 	
 		okay i'm going to cut it off and uh because i've got to go nice talking to you Bob bye-bye
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	