
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">okay</ENAMEX> is uh that a sport you like to participate in
 	
 	
 		no actually i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spectator</ENAMEX> and i'm a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hand spectator</ENAMEX> as a result of my <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s or my late late <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s interest in golf
 	
 	
 		uh-huh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> likes golf also he's uh i guess he'd be a fanatic if he thought he could get away with it  but he he limits it pretty good i um
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		have tried to go out and play <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">golf</ENAMEX> he would love it if i would go out and play with him but i stand there and swing and swing and i can't even hit the ball  yeah i don't either
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		i can't even play miniature golf <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">well  well</ENAMEX> there are just some things that we're good at and other things that we're not but i am very good at watching it on television
 	
 	
 		right um-hum
 	
 	
 		and he was really uh enthusiastic about keeping up with the tournaments he could tell me exactly what day and what time of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> and where the tournaments were going to be held and what the nature of the hole was and
 	
 	
 		oh so he's really into it  wow
 	
 	
 		oh yeah he was a good golfer
 		and as and did some you know instructions at the country <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX> for a while
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		but uh golf tended to be so i am not really deeply involved in any following any of the sports
 		but golf was one that i developed a working knowledge of a lot of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">golfers</ENAMEX> and therefore i enjoyed following those particular players
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right more because of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personalities</ENAMEX> than their sportsman
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well part of it was the personality and their sportsmanship another part of it was i'd pick one out that was different than what my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> was rooting for so  you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitor</ENAMEX> and i became involved in following his career
 	
 	
 		
 
 		right
 	
 	
 		and uh i know that that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Kite</ENAMEX> was his fair haired <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> and he thought he was spectacular i said whoa i'm not going to i'm not going to stay interested in him so
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		i decided <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andy Bean</ENAMEX> was good competition any time they both played why he was just real excited when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom</ENAMEX> was you know shown on the television and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i followed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andy Bean</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we both followed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee Trevino</ENAMEX> into the Seniors
 	
 	
 		oh he's interesting i like to watch him yeah
 	
 	
 		he is he is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> not just a golfer but he's quite a character
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and there are some really really
 		wonderful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the game of <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">golf</ENAMEX> who do give wonderful role models
 	
 	
 		yes yeah i think you're right
 	
 	
 		and i think it's critical it's critical to have a good role model
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		in any field any sports
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		i like to watch those skins games do you ever watch those where they just play for a certain amount you know for each hole they win they get the money for it i think those are pretty exciting
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well i myself really have not seen a whole lot of point to the game of golf you hit a little ball you chase it you go find it and then you hit it again and lose it again
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i know the whole point is to get it in that little bitty hole but seems to me like if they made the hole bigger it'd be easier
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 		oh really  i sometimes wonder why <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> like it so much because they get so frustrated and mad at themselves  when they don't do well
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh i know oh yeah
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buddies</ENAMEX> are not very good they play like maybe once <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX> or less and uh so they all hit like in the low nineties and they think they're having a really good game  so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh yeah well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s average ran in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid</TIMEX> seventies so he wasn't bad
 	
 	
 		wow yeah that is good
 	
 	
 		he was pretty good but as far as influencing young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i think that that is uh that is one of the sports that you can carry into old age you can't play <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">fifty five</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but it is a good healthy wholesome lifestyle and uh anything can be warped
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but i think that that is one of the sports that's a good healthy way to to move into maturity safely um-hum um-hum
 	
 	
 		uh-huh something to stay active at and for a long time
 	
 	
 		that's right that's right and a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">seniors</ENAMEX> a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elderly people</ENAMEX> don't even take up golf until they're you know in their <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		yeah and they can still get good at it
 	
 	
 		that's right that's absolutely right and it's something that
 	
 	
 		yeah well maybe that's what i'll do when i have time later on
 	
 	
 		yeah when you're too old to do anything else go play <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">golf</ENAMEX> yeah  but it's it's also something that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> can participate in
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		or you can both enjoy the same sport and participate in separate circles
 	
 	
 		true
 	
 	
 		you know you can go to the country <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">club</ENAMEX> together you can play with your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> he can play with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> but you've both been out and exercised and you have enjoyed the day
 	
 	
 		right yeah or my favorite just ride around in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cart</ENAMEX> with him
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		go somewhere really nice like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX> and just  look at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">golf course</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you bet you get a lot of exercise that way
 		um-hum well i'll tell you what if
 		if they're not real good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">golfers</ENAMEX> sometimes it is not fun to ride around and listen to their exclamations <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all day</TIMEX> long
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh yeah no my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s pretty tolerant so he's not too bad to watch
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX> had a very short fuse if he did something bad he's liable to take that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX> and throw it as far as he can throw it he's replaced almost as many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clubs</ENAMEX> as he has balls i mean just get so mad he'd just wham that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX> up against a <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX> and break that rascal
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh no yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">gosh</ENAMEX> now my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> has a temper but he doesn't seem to show it on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">golf course</ENAMEX> he's because he'll talk about the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> he plays with doing that and how immature immature he thought it was and stuff so i guess he's real laid back about it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		he he'll come home though and i mean he'll shoot when he was shooting in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> and he'd tell me what a great day he had and about this great shot he made and everything i try not to laugh yeah this one on this one hole
 	
 	
 		uh-huh well i shot in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> but i made this one good one
 		
 
 	
 	
 		did you have to listen to long stories about how on the seventeenth hole i hit it and went this way  those are it's hard for me to  act nice about that when he goes on and on
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		well the one thing that is a is a drawback about it i think is the cost
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		membership in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clubs</ENAMEX> is expensive the equipment is very expensive requires special shoes requires special you know special equipment there's so many
 	
 	
 		right and then they want to play another course that's not they're not a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of and other fees it really is high
 	
 	
 		that's right
 		that's right that's right it it can get very expensive and i can imagine what kind of costs are involved if you're going to try to go pro because you spend <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours and hours and hours</TIMEX> practicing
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and they don't give those sessions away and nor do they give uh instructions away
 	
 	
 		
 
 		right
 	
 	
 		as a matter of fact a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of mine asked me if i thought i'd be interested in g olf i said i don't know i'll have to try it and see i've always watched it and he said well fine he said we'll just take you over to the course he lives near Brookhaven
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we'll just take you over to the course and get you some lessons and let you see if you like it if you do then we can go golf together
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i said oh whoa great i get to walk all around a little green field all day
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but those kinds of things happen though you you get a little taste of it and you say hey this is not bad
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and you really begin to develop an interest in it but i am not an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">athlete</ENAMEX> at all uh you know i'm always the one that got hit by the bat in <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		me either
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and uh hung hung hung my fingernails in the net in volleyball so i am not an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">athlete</ENAMEX> maybe <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">golf</ENAMEX> is a forgiving sport i don't know
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah at least you're just competing you're competing against yourself i guess more than everybody else out there yeah
 	
 	
 		it doesn't appear to be
 		um-hum i really i i haven't really acquired an interest in it but i'm open to try anything you know
 	
 	
 		yeah that's kind of the way i feel
 	
 	
 		the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> thing that is also detrimental as far i'm concerned my skin is very fair so i'm going to have to <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">golf</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the evening</TIMEX> or i'm going to have to <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">golf</ENAMEX> at a time when the heat of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> does not cook me and i don't think
 	
 	
 		oh
 		right
 		
 		
 	