
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 		okay well what movies do you like
 	
 	
 		
 
 		gosh i like just about anything we i think the last one we saw was uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles</ENAMEX> Part 2
 	
 	
 		oh now i love i like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">turtles</ENAMEX> my little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> and he loves them
 	
 	
 		well we don't have any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> but we like them anyway
 	
 	
 		oh that's okay  how old are y'all
 	
 	
 		well
 		um we're late <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenties</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh and you just don't have any yet okay well i've got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		no
 		oh gosh
 	
 	
 		yeah my little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three months old</TIMEX> and my little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> just turned <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> i had his birthday <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> yesterday
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		but he's a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">turtle fanatic</ENAMEX> he even had <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">turtle</ENAMEX> cake <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>  but i've been wanting to see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Turtle</ENAMEX> too is it as good as they say it is
 	
 	
 		
 
 		it was it was actually better than the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> one i thought
 	
 	
 		good
 	
 	
 		what's the last movie you saw
 	
 	
 		Ghost
 	
 	
 		oh we were just when when the topic came up we i was asking my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> right quick what's <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the last</TIMEX> movies we saw he said well Ghost and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Turtles</ENAMEX> i really liked it
 	
 	
 		now Ghost yeah i love tear jerker movies but that wasn't too bad on tear jerker but
 	
 	
 		not too awful bad
 	
 	
 		it was oh it was good movie though i can see why it won so many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Oscars</ENAMEX>  because that was just so good and i like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Demi Moore</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		did you see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pretty Woman</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no but i've been hearing a lot about it i don't we don't get to the video store very often and we don't have cable
 	
 	
 		oh gosh
 	
 	
 		well we don't really want cable it's just you know glued to the TV all the time anyway so we get <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> channels down here  thanks  i'm from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kentucky</ENAMEX> originally and we used to get <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> channels without cable
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know forty well uh i don't think y'all have the same <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX> but here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> we only get <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> channels and that's um
 		do you watch soap operas
 	
 	
 		uh once in a while when i'm home
 	
 	
 		okay you work then okay well we get the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Young</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Restless</ENAMEX> on it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		okay
 	
 	
 		and then uh
 		i think <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Hospital</ENAMEX> and that comes on different channel
 	
 	
 		yeah it does
 	
 	
 		but that's all we get and that's no cartoons for my little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> but we've got a VCR and a lot of tapes
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s a movie fanatic
 	
 	
 		i think you'd really like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pretty Woman</ENAMEX> it was it was really a it made you feel really good it was just a happy movie
 	
 	
 		oh what about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Total Recall</ENAMEX> have you seen that
 	
 	
 		yeah oh i saw that one
 	
 	
 		that's good
 	
 	
 		i i was disappointed in it just because of how violent it was
 	
 	
 		yeah it was violent i try to get away from that my little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> oh he loves Robocop
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and that movie i have to i'll fast forward it everytime they come to the part where there's have you seen it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		the part where they're shooting Mercy
 	
 	
 		i don't like that
 	
 	
 		that it oh that's horrible  that is horrible and their their the language on that's filthy
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i don't see why they have to do that i mean
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i mean know everybody knows that it that the the language is there so they could just ignore it and
 		you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		use different words instead i think
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah i know
 	
 	
 		
 
 		but i i think lately <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pretty Woman</ENAMEX>'s been my favorite i went and bought the video i've probably seen it <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about fifteen or twenty</TIMEX> times
 	
 	
 		um my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> bought me like um uh i think Pretty in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pink</ENAMEX> for my birthday  with a  wait <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a second</TIMEX>  the uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i will in a minute <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kyle</ENAMEX>  sorry um he bought me pretty in pink just a second
 	
 	
 		that's okay
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kyle</ENAMEX> i'm on the telephone i'll be right i'll be right there  sorry  now you're glad you ain't got a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four year</TIMEX> old
 	
 	
 		that's okay
 		
 
 	
 	
 		it this the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time he's interrupted my phone calls
 	
 	
 		now
 		now i haven't seen Pretty in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pink</ENAMEX> that had um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Molly Ringwald</ENAMEX> yeah it was cute but it wasn't i like the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">um Sixteen Candles or sixteenth birthday or</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		does that have <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Molly Ringwald</ENAMEX>
 		i think i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sixteen Candles</ENAMEX> was the name of it
 	
 	
 		yeah oh that was so good of course i was a teenager when i seen that and i loved it
 	
 	
 		i haven't seen it either
 	
 	
 		oh well if you like love stories it's sweet oh it's sweet
 	
 	
 		i do
 	
 	
 		it really is and that's a tear jerker it gets you  i mean it makes you feel really sorry for her  but it's hilarious too especially with that uh little guy in it oh he looks like a little
 	
 	
 		oh gosh
 	
 	
 		i don't know he  looks like a little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> next door
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		but he's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixteen</TIMEX> oh it's a cute movie i can't remember his name he kind of looks like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doogie Howser</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		hm i don't know
 	
 	
 		don't know either he's got curly blonde hair he just a little freckly little
 	
 	
 		but
 		probably know him if i saw him
 	
 	
 		boy yeah if i could remember the name i know you'd know his name because he's played in a few movies but uh
 	
 	
 		i was just thinking another good one i saw not too long ago was um <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sleeping with the Enemy</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay i've heard about that but i can't remember it
 	
 	
 		that that's
 		that's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julia Roberts</ENAMEX>' new movie
 	
 	
 		okay yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julia Roberts</ENAMEX> is good
 	
 	
 		yeah she's this one you know <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pretty Woman</ENAMEX> was kind of a light comedy
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and a romance and and this one was
 		a lot more dramatic
 	
 	
 		wasn't it a murder mystery
 	
 	
 		it it
 		well it
 	
 	
 		like sort of
 	
 	
 		it was like uh it was a mystery it was a mystery she disappeared from her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> who was abusing her
 	
 	
 		oh okay the yeah that's the one i wanted to see where he was on she was on a carnival at a carnival on a ferris wheel or something
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		well did that come on TV or did it come out in the
 	
 	
 		no it came out in the theater
 	
 	
 		oh well
 	
 	
 		and i think you know around here it's already quit playing but i don't i don't know if it's still playing anywhere else
 	
 	
 		oh i i'd like
 	
 	
 		but it was it was it was one of those that kept you on the edge of your seat
 	
 	
 		real good
 		i want to see that yeah i seen the uh previews for it on TV down here it's but it's just been down here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple weeks</TIMEX> i think
 	
 	
 		oh okay because we saw it probably
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four or five months</TIMEX> ago
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX> is
 		well i know it hasn't been that long since i've seen the previews for it but yeah i wanted to see it her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> was that was a dark haired <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> with a beard and moustache or
 	
 	
 		yeah he's uh he was a real psycho in the movie it was it was scary
 	
 	
 		and no he shaved the beard off
 		yeah
 		oh i'd like to see that what about oh there was a
 		we got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">back</ENAMEX> here a while oh i want to see <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">War</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Roses</ENAMEX> too have you seen that
 	
 	
 		oh yeah boy uh i i didn't like it no it was i didn't like the way it ended
 	
 	
 		you didn't
 		i know well the only reason i know why it ended is on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Arsenio Hall</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one night</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Reeves</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		told that you know i can't believe they killed them  or or or who was it <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Reeve</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Douglas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		might have been <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Douglas</ENAMEX> oh that starred in it yeah it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Douglas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Reeve</ENAMEX> wasn't in it at all
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">huh-uh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">okay well Arsenio Hall</ENAMEX> is the one that jumped up and said that i can't believe they killed them and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Reeve</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Douglas</ENAMEX> went after his throat you dummy  so i know that they die but i haven't told my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> we've both been wanting to see it
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 		
 
 		it was i i it was it was weird it was a different movie from anything i've ever seen
 	
 	
 		that's what well we was uh teasing about you know splitting our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> down the middle
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		they did that didn't they and they marked off routes that they could go or something
 	
 	
 		yeah that'd be kind of hard for us we've only got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> bathroom i don't
 	
 	
 		we've got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bathrooms</ENAMEX> but well it might actually if he takes my my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> kind of looks like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trailers</ENAMEX> put together  and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bathroom</ENAMEX> is at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the end of</TIMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> side and one's in the middle of the other so we could do it
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh
 		well that wouldn't be too bad
 	
 	
 		no and he could climb out the window  well and we our whole <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> has you know every <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> leads to
 	
 	
 		
 
 		did
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> so we can you know yeah well yeah you can get around  you just can't go out the front door honey  sorry
 	
 	
 		get around
 		well did you see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fatal Attraction</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah that's coming back on too
 	
 	
 		i know it's going to be on on the on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> and and that's kind of what in a way you know how it kind of bothered you the way it ended and stuff that's kind of how <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">War</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Roses</ENAMEX> was
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		hm well
 	
 	
 		parts of parts of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">War</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Roses</ENAMEX> was funny but then other times it was like it was just deadly serious and it just left you with this kind of uneasy feeling you know
 	
 	
 		eerie feeling or i want to see it though i'd like to see that and uh <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Never Ending Story</ENAMEX> came out on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this month</TIMEX> i think i wanted to see that
 	
 	
 		i i've heard about that but i don't know what it's about
 	
 	
 		The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Never Ending Story</ENAMEX> it's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>'s movie but oh it's good i enjoyed it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i love <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> movies
 	
 	
 		yeah i do too and
 	
 	
 		i mean they're some of the best of that are made
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah and uh well it's about this little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> who uh i think he's up in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">attic</ENAMEX> or some part of school he got locked in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and he got scared but he starts dreaming and this
 		oh he's saving the land of uh oh it's been so long since i've seen it
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		all i know is all's i can really remember is him flying this great big dog this great big huge
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sheep dog</ENAMEX> sort of looking thing it flies through the air and he's trying to save the land from some ooze  but it's really good i mean it sounds kind it it had uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred Savage</ENAMEX> in it
 	
 	
 		oh gosh
 		oh
 	
 	
 		no no no no no did you see that movie with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred Savage</ENAMEX> in it though with uh
 	
 	
 		i don't think so
 	
 	
 		oh he had uh
 		uh oh it was The <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Princess Bride</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		nope i didn't see that
 	
 	
 		you didn't see that that was cute that was real that was a good one i i like i like slapstick comedy
 	
 	
 		so do i and a lot of times we'll go to rent a movie or something and and you're not sure how
 		whether it'll be any good or not so sometimes we stick with the stuff we've heard more about than
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well i heard a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of mine told me she got <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Naked Gun</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX> and she said that was hilarious that
 	
 	
 		yeah now we saw that and i and they're coming out with a sequel to it
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> and a half
 	
 	
 		it was funny
 	
 	
 		it was yeah i want to see that she said she rented it <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX> and said it was real good and
 	
 	
 		and and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Working</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Girl</ENAMEX> is really good
 	
 	
 		now i seen that
 	
 	
 		that was good
 	
 	
 		was that with that blonde she pretended to be the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> or something yeah i rented that <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one night</TIMEX> by myself i was home alone did you see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Home Alone</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yes i did that that that just reminded me of that did you like it
 	
 	
 		i no i haven't seen it yet see we got TV
 		
 		
 	