
   
   
      
         
            Fear of Bombing

            
               GET
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INTERNATIONAL</ENAMEX> PAPERS" BY E-MAIL!
            

            
               For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> and
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> delivery of this column, plus "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX>),
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pundit Central</ENAMEX>" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>), and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment"</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>),
click here. And
if you missed the most recent installments of this column, here they are:
posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, Oct. 9</TIMEX>, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Oct.</TIMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>.
            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times of London</ENAMEX> reported
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgrade</ENAMEX> that a boa <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">constrictor</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madeleine Albright</ENAMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">zoo</ENAMEX> has been impregnated by another boa <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">constrictor</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher</ENAMEX>. Otherwise there was mostly gloom in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, about the prospect of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> strikes on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Serbia</ENAMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>, the front-line <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> into which
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX> will pour if attempts to resolve the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> crisis fail--and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> most exposed to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> military retaliation--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Repubblica</ENAMEX> published a
front-page comment <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> that was deeply skeptical of the use of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX>. It
said that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> and its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">allies</ENAMEX> are about to enter a war against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX>
"without anybody, on either side of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Atlantic</ENAMEX>, having clear ideas about the
objectives or the consequences of a military intervention unprecedented in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Europe</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this second half of the century</TIMEX>."

            Signed by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucio Caracciolo</ENAMEX>, the article said it is impossible to see how <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> action will
help <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanians</ENAMEX> suffering in the woods of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>. Instead, it might turn
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan Milosevic</ENAMEX> into a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">martyr</ENAMEX> and permit him to repress
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanians</ENAMEX> even more ferociously after the bombing stops. The only way to
help the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX> is to open <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>'s border to them while simultaneously
putting large numbers of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> on the ground in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caracciolo</ENAMEX> described <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> policies as so contradictory that
"many believe <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> supports <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>'s independence from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX> without
wanting to say so." "There is no grand plan for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Balkans</ENAMEX>, neither in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>
nor anywhere else," he said. "If we bomb, it won't be to impose a solution, as
we don't have one, but because of a need for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to show signs of
international political life after his many setbacks, because of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> effect
that renders intolerable humanitarian tragedies shown on television at the
expense of all other ones, and in order to save what little credibility remains
to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Balkans</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stampa of Turin</ENAMEX>, however, supported the idea of airstrikes against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Serbia</ENAMEX>
as "a symbolic act" against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>'s intransigence. It said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holbrooke</ENAMEX> gave the impression that he fully understood that "the obstacle to
overcome is not in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pristina</ENAMEX> but in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgrade</ENAMEX>."

            On the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">forthcoming Middle East</ENAMEX> summit at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wye Plantation</ENAMEX> outside <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ha'aretz</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> reported
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> as its main story that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ariel Sharon</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>'s new hard-line foreign
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister-designate</ENAMEX>, will act as a "watchdog" over <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX> to ensure he doesn't make too many concessions to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX>.
The same <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said in an editorial
that the summit is "not the be-all and end-all, because even if the sides sign
some sort of agreement, it will not be able to reverse in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> fell swoop the
feeling of alienation that prevails between them." It added, "After all, it is
not the absence of an agreement, but the failure to implement it, that brought
about the need to meet at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wye Plantation</ENAMEX>."

            
In an editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times of India</ENAMEX> commended
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amnesty International</ENAMEX> for strongly criticizing the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> human rights record in
a recent report. "It accuses the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US</ENAMEX> of refusing to recognise the primacy of
international law, reserving the right to use the death penalty against
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">juveniles</ENAMEX> and of being the only <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, apart from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Somalia</ENAMEX>, to have failed to
ratify the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UN</ENAMEX> convention on the rights of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said. But it
went on to note "that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>'s own record on human rights has been appalling,
with the complaints registered with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Human Rights Commission</ENAMEX>
exceeding <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">30,000</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>."

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Corriere della Sera</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milan</ENAMEX> reported an opinion poll finding that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">52</NUMEX>
percent of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> between <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16 and 24</TIMEX> do not want to have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Forty-three percent</NUMEX> favor the artificial insemination method <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jodie Foster</ENAMEX> is
rumored to have used. <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Only 19 percent</NUMEX> said they definitely want to have a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">principal</ENAMEX> reason cited for this reluctance: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maternity</ENAMEX> is seen as
impeding a professional career.

         
      
   
