
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX> Bio

            By <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerald</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stern</ENAMEX>

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday, Nov.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            To hear the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX> read
"<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania Bio</ENAMEX>," click .

            I wore a black knit hatso
I could be undistinguished in the warand carried a small bagso I could be
mistaken for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX>,

            and once in a whorehouse
while waiting for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of mine to finishI examined the madam on the kitchen
table; and I spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> at either the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Serbian Club</ENAMEX>

            or the post-war <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Literary</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Club</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Atwood Street</ENAMEX> above the pre-war clothing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX>, and ate hot sausage
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sandwiches</ENAMEX> and cold buttermilk across the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> from the first <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carnegie</ENAMEX>
Library

            and made plans for the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next seventy years</TIMEX>. I drove <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andy Warhol</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">East Liberty</ENAMEX> train <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX> in my
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1949</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX>. Believe it or not I bought a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1949</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buick</ENAMEX>

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirteen years later</TIMEX> for
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fifteen</NUMEX> dollars and drove it into a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">junkyard</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six years after</TIMEX>. My first
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">instrument</ENAMEX> was a kind of kazoo and that led naturally to a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> trombone. I
was

            loyal to my own music for
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fifty years</TIMEX> though I detested snare drums and tap dancing, just as I do those
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singers</ENAMEX> now who hold their left fists in the air while holding the
microphone

            inside their mouths. And I
hate short sleeved shirts when they wear them with dark neckties, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">skinny swine</ENAMEX>
knocking on closed doors; and I had a habit of counting bricks, a nice
obsession compared with

            washing hands or touching
car doors, it gave mefreedom with walls so I could handle bulging and sagging
when I had to; and one of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summers</TIMEX> I read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steinbeck</ENAMEX> and made love--in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bedroom</ENAMEX>--

            to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aunt</ENAMEX>'s cleaning
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> in upstate <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX> and learned to adore the small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> with its rows
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sidewalk</ENAMEX> and only a short walk into the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, in
this case up a steep hill,

            the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> more sullen the
farther up you went, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Roman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX> below, the sunlight on the
river, the bridge empty, the outer <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one half</NUMEX>-hidden, I was shocked by the sudden
distance

            and I had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beach</ENAMEX>
jacket with a reddish thorn in one of the pockets, which was my toothpick for
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">thirty-five</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, and a vest to match, and a flattened acorn I kept in the
darkness; and I had a pencil

            I used to keep my balance,
the edges were eaten,the lead was grey, the green eraser was worn down to the
metal, and I had a spiral notebook I kept for emotions, and I folded my
money.

         
      
   
