
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Address your e-mail to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. You must include your address and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX>
phone number (for confirmation only).
            

            
               A
Complaint <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">From Your Hick Readers</ENAMEX>
            

            In the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 23</TIMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott Shuger</ENAMEX> writes of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
Post piece referring to the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bubba</ENAMEX> vote" and notes that "this is a perfect
illustration of the truism that there's still <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'respectable</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, even (especially?) sophisticated newspaper <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, are
allowed to slander--<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southern</ENAMEX> white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">males</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hey, Posties</ENAMEX> , time to rework
that style-sheet."

            Having recently read (with
some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">annoyance</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Lewis</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Day 3 "Dispatch</ENAMEX>"
from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> trial, I had to wonder whether 
                  Slate
               's style
sheet had anything to say about this subject. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> described <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
Warden as having an "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">overripe</ENAMEX> drawl" and being "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southern</ENAMEX>"--but yet notes he is
from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>. Through the rest we get <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX>' sensitive transcriptions of "a
booming <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hick</ENAMEX> drawl," culminating in a contrast to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Barksdale</ENAMEX>, who, we are
told, has escaped hickdom--he "retains only enough of the piney woods patter to
offer a passing imitation of a good ol' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> when he needs to." (As an aside, I
wonder how many times the word "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hick</ENAMEX>" recurred in that short piece?)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> is
most exposed in his transcriptions. At the end of a string of them, he quotes
Warden as pronouncing modems "mode ums." Maybe I'm just another piney woods
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hick</ENAMEX>, but don't we all pronounce it like that? I guess I'll close by quoting a
comment by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lawrence W. Levine</ENAMEX> (in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Black Culture and Black Consciousness</ENAMEX> )
on transcriptions of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">19 th</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">century</TIMEX> black speech made by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX>:

            Even when the
pronunciation of a given word was precisely the same as that of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">collectors</ENAMEX>,
their desire to indicate the exotic qualities of black speech led them to
utilize such misleading and superfluous spellings as wen for "when," fo'k or
fokes for "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX>."

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freeland Oxford</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miss.</ENAMEX>

            
               I Love
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX>
            

            I just wanted to send a clap
on the shoulder to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Lewis</ENAMEX> for his <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Day 3 Dispatch</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>
trial. It had me in stitches. What wonderful caricatures he drew of the people
involved; he brought to life the dynamics of the barely sheathed claws of the
interactions in the courtroom. It was refreshing to have coverage that pointed
out, so humorously, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX>' foolishness and one-upmanship that characterize
this case.

            Thanks for
a great read.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heidi</ENAMEX>
Housten <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bellevue</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wash.</ENAMEX>

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slate Fouled Up</ENAMEX>
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">This morning</TIMEX> my "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Morning</ENAMEX>
Delivery" e-mail included the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Day 3 Dispatch</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> trial. The end
of the article features a prominent "F**k you." I have filters that keep me
from being subjected to that sort of language in my e-mail. I expect more from
your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> than the language used by spammers looking to sell me
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">porn</ENAMEX>.

            Foul
language is a sign of low intelligence. Your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> went for a cheap, shocking
joke instead of thinking of a clever analogy. You can do better. 

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ann</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Porter Lubbock</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>

            
               The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Inescapable George (H.) W. Bush</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jr.</ENAMEX>)
            

            Surely I'm
not the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> to inform 
                  Slate
                that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>, not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush Jr.</ENAMEX> (See the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 16</TIMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>" and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Black Like Whom?</ENAMEX>" by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brent Staples</ENAMEX>.) The former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George H.W. Bush</ENAMEX>. Thus <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ann Richards</ENAMEX>' jibe: "He's missing his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">H.</ENAMEX>"

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lavine Austin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Editors</ENAMEX>' note:
Thanks for the reminder. We've now corrected our error.
            

            
               Black
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton Myths</ENAMEX>
            

            I normally do not write to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> to voice my opinion, because I don't think it will do
any general good, but at this point I can't see what good being silent does. I
am a black <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> and have found it strange that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> have concentrated
so much on how <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-Americans</ENAMEX> feel about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. It has been my experience
that our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> is only brought into the discussion after every other angle
has been covered and, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are being pressured into the "right" opinion. I am
tired of reading that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is somehow black or at least as black as any of
our other public <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>.

            As I read <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brent Staples</ENAMEX>'
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Black Like Whom?</ENAMEX>" I saw <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least several</NUMEX> assumptions run through his
commentary on my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> and public sentiment about us. One assumption is
that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">at least 91 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-Americans</ENAMEX> feel the same way about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
for the same reasons: He is black, he is great because he comes from a single
parent home, or he has a similar background, so we can understand him
better.

            We are not a single-minded
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">community</ENAMEX> that values or devalues <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s private adulterous conduct.
Whatever our general feeling is about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s behavior, why are we being used
at the tail end of the blitz of political inquiry as a rallying tool to bring
more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> out to vote, to produce more negative opinion against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, and
to reaffirm the idea that we somehow don't know what is really going on?

            The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> assumption that
comes out is that we don't understand what is happening when a political
candidate courts our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> issue and then targets us on another
issue. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Staples</ENAMEX> runs through a litany of economic gains that have brought
African-Americans closer to some kind of economic stability (what stability
that is or what marker he uses to measure that stability is unclear), which
African-Americans credit <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> for providing.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Staples</ENAMEX> appears to contrast
the middle-class black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> from the lower-class <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> when it appears
to fit his framework but to ignore it when it does not fit within his argument.
It is hard for me to believe that he would ignore the education or criminal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice</ENAMEX> facts--or that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-Americans</ENAMEX> would ignore the dropping numbers of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> in college and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduate</ENAMEX> school programs, the rising level of blacks
incarcerated, or increasing number of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">jails</ENAMEX>. The failure to include the
holistic view seems even more astonishing given our position in this society,
when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> reviews what is being said and who is asked.

            I realize that we tend to be
held up for our nonmainstream views on issues such as the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> riots,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.J.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willie Horton</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a million</NUMEX> others. We normally will turn the tide
against whomever we <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocate</ENAMEX> for or in defense of, but when it comes to the job
approval rating for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, it seems like the media
attention focused on us is misplaced. If our opinion were valued throughout
this process, I think the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> would have noticed a marked difference in how
we feel about this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>, and the process he has gone
through in order to reach this phase in the impeachment inquiry. On this issue,
I doubt that our approval rating is going to bear on the ultimate question of
whether the entire <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> will rally around the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> as they move to try
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>. The negative perception surrounding our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> was
invoked too late in the game for it to do <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> any good.

            I end my
e-mail as I began it, by asking if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> truly believes that a few chicken
wings given to black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">preachers</ENAMEX>, a few honorable mentions and awards to a couple
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">black poets</ENAMEX>, or visits and speeches to commemorate historic memorials and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visionaries</ENAMEX> within the black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> are enough to lead <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> to rally
behind a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> who has allowed our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> to lose whatever gains were
given to us by a browbeaten <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> of the war-torn <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1960s</TIMEX>. And if he does,
does he think we are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gullible</ENAMEX> enough to buy it as a true understanding by a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of our collective blackness?

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Genevieve Banks</ENAMEX>
            

            Odenton, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Md.</ENAMEX>

            
               True
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Grits</ENAMEX>
            

            It was
quite a surprise to read <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brent Staples</ENAMEX>, the self-appointed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> on what it
means to be black in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, say in "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Black Like Whom?</ENAMEX>" that "all
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-Americans</ENAMEX> have <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Southern</ENAMEX> roots." He'd better brush up on history as well
as geography.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Helen Hopps San</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miguel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El Salvador</ENAMEX>

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brent</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Staples</ENAMEX> responds: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Genevieve Banks</ENAMEX> claims to have read my essay "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Black Like</ENAMEX>
Whom?" but seems to have missed its central arguments. She accuses me of
assuming that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-Americans</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> because he is "black." But I argue
from the beginning that black affection for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> stems from: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) a widespread
sense among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> that the economy is doing better by them than ever before;
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) a deliberate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> program to court black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">churchgoers</ENAMEX> who make up the
heart of the black middle class; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s intuitive understanding that
the black middle class is basically conservative on the issues of crime, unwed
motherhood, and welfare. Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Banks further</ENAMEX> accuses me of ignoring black school
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dropout</ENAMEX> and incarceration rates. To this, I plead guilty. Those factors are
irrelevant to black approval ratings with respect to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
presidency.
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helen</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hopps</ENAMEX> has me dead to rights, however. I did not intend to say that all
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-Americans</ENAMEX> have <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Southern</ENAMEX> roots. But most do. It may surprise you, Ms.
Hopps, but the majority of black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 55 percent</NUMEX>--still live in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American South</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">As late as 1940</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">nearly 80 percent</NUMEX> did. Not much before that,
the ratio exceeded <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX>.
            

            
               Address
your e-mail to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. You must include your address and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX>
phone number (for confirmation only).
            

         
      
   
