
   
   
      
         
            Several <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hundred Years of Solitude</ENAMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Roughly two-thirds</NUMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> through the enthralling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Edo</ENAMEX> show at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">National Gallery of Art</ENAMEX>, there's a
glass case containing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> outsize dishes, each <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a couple of feet</NUMEX> in diameter.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">White</ENAMEX> and cobalt blue, these porcelain dishes have as their decoration fanciful
maps of the world, with the islands of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX>. Like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saul</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steinberg</ENAMEX>'s famous map of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX>'s point of
view, these maps relegate the rest of the world to the truncated periphery,
with such speculative identifications as the "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Land of Dwarves</ENAMEX>" and the "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Land of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Women</ENAMEX>." Of course, by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1830s</TIMEX>, when these dishes were made, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> knew
better but, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steinberg</ENAMEX>'s, the maps capture the cultural confidence of the
playfully arrogant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">islander</ENAMEX>. The humiliating visit of the black <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ships</ENAMEX> of
Commodore <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew Perry</ENAMEX>, demanding trade rights and treaty concessions for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX>, was still <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two decades</TIMEX> away, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> could retain for a
little longer the illusion that their <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two centuries</TIMEX> of peace and feudal harmony
would last forever. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1868</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edo</ENAMEX> was renamed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tokyo</ENAMEX>, the dream was
shattered, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> began the hard work of entering the modern world.

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Edo: Art</ENAMEX>
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1615-1868</TIMEX>," expertly organized by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert T. Singer</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">County Museum of Art</ENAMEX>, shows off <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">roughly 300</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">objects</ENAMEX> from this peaceful
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">interlude</ENAMEX>. Almost all are from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> collections, and many are designated as
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">National Treasures</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Edo</ENAMEX> period extended from the end of the civil wars of
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16 th century</TIMEX> (the source of all samurai films) and the
consolidation of power under the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">warlord</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tokugawa Ieyasu</ENAMEX>, to the Meiji
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Restoration</ENAMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> adopted something resembling a parliamentary monarchy
under the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">emperor</ENAMEX>. The successive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tokugawa</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> established their power base
around their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">castle</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Edo</ENAMEX> and developed a clever system of keeping the feudal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">lords</ENAMEX> (the daimyo) under their tributary thumb. The daimyo were required to
spend alternate <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Edo</ENAMEX>, while their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> lived there all the time, as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hostages</ENAMEX> of sorts. This arrangement called for constant traveling, and these
travels to and from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Edo</ENAMEX> were carried out with a good deal of pomp and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">circumstance</ENAMEX>. Many of the objects on display in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Gallery</ENAMEX> derive
from these ceremonial processions. There are cases filled with elaborate and
witty helmets from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 17 th century</TIMEX>, shaped like the knobby
turbo seashell or with rabbit ears appended; swords designed more to impress
than to kill; saddles decorated with such whimsical and hardly threatening
motifs as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">powder puffs</ENAMEX> and cosmetic brushes.

            The layout of the show is neither by chronology nor by
medium, and the big thematic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">divisions</ENAMEX>--"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Style</ENAMEX>," "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Samurai</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Travel</ENAMEX> and
Landscape," and the like--give the impression that time stood still.
Politically, and to some extent artistically, the impression is accurate. (A
survey of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> art from the landing of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pilgrim</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Fathers</ENAMEX> to the end of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Civil War</ENAMEX>--the chronological extent of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> show--would look
ridiculous laid out on a similar model.) From the stunning <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> of the Style
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">section</ENAMEX>, you ascend one of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">I.M. Pei</ENAMEX>'s sky-lit spiral <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">staircases</ENAMEX> (transformed
into a bamboo and pebble <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">grove</ENAMEX>) to the more austere world of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Samurai</ENAMEX>, "Work,"
and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Religion and Festivals</ENAMEX>." All seems orderly and timeless, just as the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tokugawa</ENAMEX>--with their xenophobia and rigid social class boundaries--wanted it.
Toward the end of the show, though, especially in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">section</ENAMEX> devoted to
entertainment, a sense of historical change enters in. In the pleasure quarter
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Edo</ENAMEX>, the feudal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">divisions</ENAMEX> between commoners and nobility broke down, and
this "floating world" gave birth to new and vigorous forms of popular
entertainment. Sumo <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wrestlers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kabuki</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> were the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrities</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> advertised their prowess in cheap color woodblock prints (see Katsukawa
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shun'ei</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Sumo Wrestlers Kajihama and Jinmaku</ENAMEX> , circa <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1790</TIMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Toshusai Sharaku</ENAMEX>'s The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kabuki Actor Otani Oniji III</ENAMEX> as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Servant</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Edohei , 1794</TIMEX>).

            From the
start of the show, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> opposing tendencies are immediately evident. One is the
retreat from materialism and the modern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> into a monochromatic refuge of
meditative calm. This tendency is associated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zen</ENAMEX> and looks back to the
tradition of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholar</ENAMEX>-aesthete hermit imported <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">centuries earlier</TIMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>.
Everything is pared down, black-and-white, elemental. Some of the finest of all
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Zen</ENAMEX> paintings are on view in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, including the bare-bones <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Circle</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Triangle</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Square</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sengai Gibon</ENAMEX>, perhaps the single most famous Zen
image. At the other extreme is the eager embrace of urban chaos, masquerade,
and color. The woodblock prints of the late <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18 th century</TIMEX> adopt
technicolored effects drawn from many different traditions, including Western
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">perspective</ENAMEX>--which struck <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> as a tricky and artificial set of
rules. Both these contrasting traditions, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zen</ENAMEX> austerity and floating-world
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">carnival</ENAMEX>, brought about a greater individualism in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> art. Zen masters
were known for their eccentric and unpredictable behavior, and a kindred
idiosyncrasy was valued in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Edo</ENAMEX> demimonde.

            
In all the sections of the show, even the least
conducive to frivolity, there is an element of playfulness and oddball
aesthetic daring. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Religion</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Festivals</ENAMEX> section, for example, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> finds
among pictures of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buddhas</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shinto</ENAMEX> deities (see <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ogata Korin, Gods of Wind</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Thunder</ENAMEX> ) a large ink-brushed hanging scroll depicting nothing but
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vegetables</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ito Jakuchu</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vegetable</ENAMEX> parinirvana , circa <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1780</TIMEX>). In the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">center</ENAMEX> is a long white radish with forked roots, surrounded by <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">melons</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">gourds</ENAMEX> and turnips and squash. This painting, as any <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th century</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewer</ENAMEX> would recognize, is a parody of scenes of the dying <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buddha</ENAMEX> surrounded by
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">followers</ENAMEX>. And yet, this painting of mourning <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vegetables</ENAMEX> has a peculiar
gravity about it. Jakuchu, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vegetarian</ENAMEX> who managed his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>'s vegetable
business, seems to have taken <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vegetables</ENAMEX> pretty seriously. More obvious in its
intent to amuse is a striking <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th century Kabuki</ENAMEX> costume with a
shoot-me-here target on the back and an arrow through the bull's-eye. Here
again, though, there is an appealing restraint in the elegant design and muted
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">greens</ENAMEX> of the costume. The most satisfying <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">objects</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Edo</ENAMEX> show are those
that find ways to reconcile the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> opposing tendencies--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zenlike</ENAMEX> austerity and
floating-world flamboyance--of the period.

            There is
another reason, though, for the extraordinary pleasures this exhibition
provides, and that is the uncanny familiarity of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> art for Western
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX>. Exotic and remote as this island world was, it had a special appeal
for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late 19 th century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Europeans</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>. Impressionism, the
most popular of all <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Western</ENAMEX> art movements, is inconceivable without the
provocation of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> art. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Edo</ENAMEX> show includes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">woodblock</ENAMEX> print
depicting an angular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">courtesan</ENAMEX> (by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Keisai Eisen</ENAMEX>) that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vincent van Gogh</ENAMEX> used as
the basis for his own painting ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Courtesan</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1887</TIMEX>), now on view in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">van Gogh</ENAMEX> show elsewhere in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Gallery</ENAMEX>. Because of the tremendous
vogue of such images, collected and reworked by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edgar Degas</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Claude Monet</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Cassatt</ENAMEX> and then adopted in our own popular culture, we recognize
immediately the polymorphous personae of the floating world--the sumo
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">wrestlers</ENAMEX>, the geisha and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">admirers</ENAMEX> (see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kitagawa Utamaro</ENAMEX>, The Mosquito
Net , circa <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1797</TIMEX>), and the swashbuckling samurai.

            And which of our own mountains is more familiar to us than
the cone of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mount Fuji</ENAMEX>? The nomadic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traveler</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lafcadio Hearn</ENAMEX> compared it to an
inverted <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>-open <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX>, or "some exquisite sloping of shoulders toward the
neck." In <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Katsushika Hokusai's Sudden Wind on a Clear Day</ENAMEX> (circa
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1830-1832</TIMEX>), the wind has exposed the whole sweep of the landscape, and the
visible grain of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wood</ENAMEX> reads as the ridges of the mountainside. Returning to
those playful ceramic maps of the world, one notices that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> has dipped
his brush in blue and painted the profile of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Fuji</ENAMEX> on the main <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>.
For a split second it's possible to imagine that it really is the center of the
world.

             

         
      
   
