
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Drawing upon her rich
experience of life, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> to her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>) responds to questions
about manners, personal relations, politics, and other subjects. Please send
your questions for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> to prudence@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Queries should not exceed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> words in
length. Please indicate how you wish your letter to be signed, preferably
including your location.
            

            
               
                  Dear
Prudie,
               
            

            
               I am heartsick about my
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>. Well, actually, about her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boyfriend</ENAMEX>. She's been seeing someone
exclusively for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than a year</TIMEX>. It's exclusive on her part, but everybody
knows he is cheating on her. That is not the only problem. He belittles her in
public and is quite a cheapskate. I have gently tried to tell her she is too
good for this lout, but she will have none of it.
            

            
               I feel
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">helpless</ENAMEX>, and I worry for her. I am the older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>, if you hadn't guessed. Is
there anything to be done?
            

            
               --Banging My Head
Against a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Wall</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Portland</ENAMEX>
            

            Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Bang,</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> is reminded of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">delicious Dorothy Parker</ENAMEX> remark "She has put all her eggs in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> bastard."

            How sad for you to be a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bystander</ENAMEX> while your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> is having a romantic near-death experience. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Alas,</ENAMEX>
the kind of bystander you are is helpless because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in these
relationships have blinders on and defenses in place. Prudie, too, abhors these
transcendentally horny louses, but outside <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">observers</ENAMEX> don't get a vote.

            Your
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>, alas, does not regard <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Lover Boy</ENAMEX> as a problem. Yet. But have hope. The
day will come when your sib will see things clearly for herself, and her loving
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> will be there to help her pick up the pieces. Since you have gone on
record about what you think of this boulevardier , say no more. It would
be the vocal equivalent of throwing good money after bad.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>,
sympathetically

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               My <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> has sales
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX>, and my problem has to do with my traveling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX>. We are in the air a
lot, and in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX>. I am mortified much of the time because
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elaine"</ENAMEX> is always dropping things into her purse. On <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">airplanes</ENAMEX> she helps
herself to the little liquor bottles (she doesn't drink) and those plastic salt
and pepper things. In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> she cleans out the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX> basket and transfers
everything to her purse.
            

            
               I know
when she is seen doing this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> think we are a pair of nuts (and assume
she's doing it for both of us), and I also worry that this is stealing. Can you
help me come to terms with this situation? Thank you.
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">No Sticky Fingers</ENAMEX>
From <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>
            

            Dear No
Stick,

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> is sympathetic to your
traveling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> because, well, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Prudie</ENAMEX> herself is partial to those little
brown <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sugar</ENAMEX> packets in restaurant sugar bowls. While never having had the
inclination to transfer an entire <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX> basket to her handbag, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> has on
occasion taken a particularly good tasting piece of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later</TIMEX>--provided
there is a paper napkin for wrapping. If one was to filch a cloth napkin, that
would be stealing.

            Your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>'s appropriation
of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> put on the table, you should know, is not dishonest. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of you
have essentially paid for everything served to you. Granted, most twosomes
would not polish off the entire contents of a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX> basket, but it is
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">diners</ENAMEX>'. The same is true for the airplane offerings.

            If it will
help you feel better about things, encourage "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elaine</ENAMEX>" to ask the server for a
take-home container for whatever she wishes to transport out of the dining
room. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> finds most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> more than happy to oblige. If, however,
your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">associate</ENAMEX> thinks she is engaging in petty larceny and gets her jollies
from purloined rolls, indulge her, knowing that it is a harmless habit.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, portably

            
               Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
            

            
               I'm a happy-go-lucky,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">75-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">retiree</ENAMEX> who, alas, gets incredibly annoyed when
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">strangers</ENAMEX>--typically on the phone--call me by my <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> name. I'm a liberal
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> and am not old-fashioned, but such pseudo "friendliness" turns me
off.
            

            
               It also makes dealing
with business <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> difficult. Example: Just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX> I called a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">salesman</ENAMEX>
regarding refinancing the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and left my name and number. When he called
back he said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hi John</ENAMEX>, this is Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blank</ENAMEX>."
            

            
               I told him I'd prefer to
be called Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>. He got annoyed and told me he has close-knit relationships
with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>. He then continued to call me <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX> throughout his explanation
of what refinancing involved.
            

            
               When
he finished I told him, again, I did not wish to be called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>. He became
flustered, said goodbye, and hung up. I've not heard from him since. I ask you,
am I out of step with the world? Is it OK for young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretaries</ENAMEX> to assume we're
on a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>-name basis? Quite frankly, I consider such an approach an invasion
of my privacy. I also consider it a put-down. What sayest thou?
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wondering</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tucson</ENAMEX>,
Ariz.
            

            Dear
Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Won</ENAMEX>,

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> is in your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> who presume to use a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> name in a business call seem thoughtless.
They register on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Prudometer</ENAMEX> right next to those who invite you to "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Have a</ENAMEX>
nice day."

            Using the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> name of
someone who is unknown to you is presumptuous, disrespectful, and improper.
Your "Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blank</ENAMEX>," who tried to make a case, yet, for why it was OK to call you
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>, sounds like a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horse</ENAMEX>'s patootie. That he didn't follow up on the financial
transaction is no loss. Surely you will find someone with equal skills who will
call you "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mr.</ENAMEX>"

            Prudie, on occasion, has
asked service <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on the other end of the line who launch into a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>-name
address, "Do we know each other?" This is usually sufficient for them to swing
into a "Mrs.<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">"</ENAMEX> mode. Only a clod would persist.

            What is
behind this pseudo familiarity/equality, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> thinks, is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">casualness</ENAMEX> and a touchy-feely cultural shift that have replaced formality and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">civility</ENAMEX>. Rest assured that you are not out of step--or if you are, that Prudie
is right there with you.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, respectfully

            
               Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
            

            
               I have moved back to my
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hometown</ENAMEX> and renewed acquaintances with old high-school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriends</ENAMEX>. As time
goes on we are becoming closer and spending more time together. The problem is
this: Most of them smoke, and I do not. When we go out to dinner we always sit
in the smoking section. When I visit their homes, they smoke constantly. When
they come to my home, they are forever going out to the balcony to smoke. I
know that breathing this <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">smoke</ENAMEX> is harmful to me. Normally I avoid smoke, yet I
pretend it doesn't bother me with these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>.
            

            
               The
question is, should I consider my own health and the fact that when I am with
them I am inhaling probably a pack of cigarettes? Should I stop seeing them? I
don't really want this, but what else to do? Yes, I could ask them not to
smoke, but since there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> of them who do smoke, it seems like the
majority rules.
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">L.G.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Petersburg</ENAMEX>,
Fla.
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear L.</ENAMEX>,

            Your old high-school
girlfriends are causing you to regress to ... high school. You are feeling that
you've got to go along with everybody else to "fit in." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> is mindful of
the fact that a gemütlich bunch of girlfriends is wonderful, but this
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> is hazardous to your health, the deleterious effects of secondhand smoke
having been accepted by most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.

            It is
interesting that this clique is composed entirely of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">smokers</ENAMEX>. There is a slim
possibility that your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chums</ENAMEX>, out of affection for you, will not smoke in your
presence and would give up the smoking section in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX>. Failing that,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bear</ENAMEX> in mind that the concept of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">majority</ENAMEX> rule applies to elections and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">community</ENAMEX> decisions, not health risks. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> is reminded of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russian</ENAMEX>
expression: Once your head is cut off, there is no use crying about your hair.
If you become ill--or worse--a group of girlfriends will be meaningless. Please
put your lungs before your social life, otherwise <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> will worry.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>,
deep-breathingly

         
      
   
