
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Movies
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Enemy</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buena Vista Pictures</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> like this
paranoid techno-thriller starring <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Will Smith</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gene Hackman</ENAMEX>. The plot (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX>
is wrongfully targeted by rogue <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Security Agency</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operatives</ENAMEX>) stretches
credibility in places, but overall the film is said to be "enormously
entertaining" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael O'Sullivan</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pluses</ENAMEX>: It's
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">full</TIMEX> of cool technology and big explosions, and there's so much creepy
surveillance that it feels "like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kafka</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">steroids</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Rainer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York</ENAMEX> ). (Visit the official site.)

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rugrats Movie</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paramount Pictures</ENAMEX>). Mixed reviews on this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">spinoff</ENAMEX> of
the animated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nickelodeon</ENAMEX> series featuring a pack of wisecracking toddlers. Some
complain that the film doesn't do much to entertain <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> and observe that
"[i]n this yet-to-be-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">potty</NUMEX>-trained universe, poop looms as large as explosions
in action thrillers" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Wloszczyna</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> ). Other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> claim
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rugrats</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are "the funniest bunch of crumb-snatchers to come
down the pike since <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Buckwheat, Alfalfa, and the Our Gang</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gang</ENAMEX>"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">O'Sullivan</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> ). (Find out more about the
Rugrats TV show.)

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Waking Ned Devine</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox Searchlight Pictures</ENAMEX>). This <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> import
warms the cockles of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>' hearts. Featuring the talents of a largely over
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">70</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cast</ENAMEX>, the film focuses on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> of a small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> as they try to cash
in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX>'s lottery ticket after his death. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX>' favorite scene: the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">aging David Kelly</ENAMEX>'s nude <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">motorcycle</ENAMEX> ride through the woods to beat the lottery
official to the ticket-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">holder</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>. Sweet and funny without being corny, the
film "belongs to a small genre of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd-pleasers</ENAMEX> [such as] The Full
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monty</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Brassed Off</ENAMEX> " (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jami Bernard</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily News</ENAMEX> ). (Visit the
official site; 
                  Slate
               's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Edelstein</ENAMEX> is not
charmed: "I see a future for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elderly male actors</ENAMEX> willing to shed their clothes
for laughs, but I don't see myself in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>." Read the rest of his
review here.)

            
               
                  A
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bug's Life</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Walt Disney Pictures</ENAMEX>). The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> computer <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animated ant</ENAMEX>
film of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the season</TIMEX> is said to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> and thorax above its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">predecessor</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Antz</ENAMEX> . Aimed at a slightly younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>, the film bristles with buggy
life and packs in the "gee-whiz moments" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Turan</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times ). The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>' one gripe is that there's almost too much happening at
once on-screen: It's "so dense with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> and illustrative detail that it
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly chokes</NUMEX> on its own banquet" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Corliss</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> ). (Visit the
Web site of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pixar</ENAMEX>, this
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">film's</ENAMEX> animation <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studio</ENAMEX>.)

            

               Books
            

            
               
                  I
Will <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bear Witness: A Diary of the Nazi Years</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1933-1941</TIMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Victor</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Klemperer</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Random House</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> marvel at this diary of a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German Jew</ENAMEX> who
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">obsessively</ENAMEX> detailed both the horrific deterioration of normal life as well as
the kind acts of "good <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Germans</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> call it "richer and more profoundly
disturbing than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anne Frank</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Birnbaum</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Gay</ENAMEX>
writes in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Book Review</ENAMEX> that "even the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> familiar
with <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">material</ENAMEX> must be gripped by these pages" and that the book has a
"concrete, vivid power that is, and I think will remain, unsurpassed." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Read</ENAMEX>
more about this book in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publisher</ENAMEX>'s online catalog.)

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Beach</ENAMEX>: A Saga of Race, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wealth</ENAMEX>, and Memory
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russ Rymer</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HarperCollins</ENAMEX>). Reviews of this book of three essays on the history and
current state of black <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">townships</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> are positive, though each is dotted
with a few quibbles. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rymer</ENAMEX> has a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX>'s gift for telling a story without
violating the mystery at its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">center</ENAMEX>" ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> ), but he also tends
toward oversimplification of race relations and an overly nostalgic take on the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Crow</ENAMEX>. It is "here close to poetic, there baroque and overwritten,
at once rich with insights and maddeningly reductive" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tamar Jacoby</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> ). (Buy the book online.)

            

               Television
            

            

               
                  Winchell
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBO</ENAMEX>; click here for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">showtimes</ENAMEX>). Although <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanley Tucci</ENAMEX> turns in a good performance as the godfather
of gossip, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter Winchell</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> pan everything else in the made-for-TV
film. Complaints: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) The script leaves out crucial parts of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Winchell</ENAMEX>'s story.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) It's based on a book written by one of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Winchell</ENAMEX>'s ghostwriters, who, natch,
makes himself the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> of the film. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) It "doesn't try hard enough to figure
out what made him tick, and tick so loudly" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Shales</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> ). (Find out more about the movie here; read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarah Kerr</ENAMEX>'s review in 
                  Slate
               .)

            
               Recent
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment</ENAMEX>" columns
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Nov.</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">18:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Meet Joe</ENAMEX>
Black ;

            

               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Celebrity</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- I'll Be Home
for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- I Still Know
What You Did <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last Summer</TIMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dancing</ENAMEX> at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lughnasa</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Book -- Fashionable
Nonsense: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Postmodern Intellectuals' Abuse of Science</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Sokal</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jean Bricmont</ENAMEX>;

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Music -- Spirit</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jewel</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Nov.</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie -- The
Siege ;

            

               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Waterboy</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- Velvet
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goldmine</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX>:
The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Invention of the Human</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harold Bloom</ENAMEX>;

            
               Music -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce</ENAMEX>
Springsteen: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tracks</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Springsteen</ENAMEX>;

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Opera</ENAMEX> -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Le Nozze di Figaro</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metropolitan Opera</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Nov.</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
History <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">X</NUMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carpenter</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vampires</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Life Is</ENAMEX>
Beautiful ;

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Living Out</ENAMEX>
Loud ;

            
               Art --"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX> Pollock"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum of Modern Art</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>);

            
               Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- A Man in</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Full</TIMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Wolfe</ENAMEX>;

            

               Music--
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mutations</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beck</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">28:</TIMEX>

            

               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pleasantville</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- Apt
Pupil ;

            

               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Soldier</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX> of the
World: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Rise</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Muhammad Ali</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Remnick</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Evening</ENAMEX> ,
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Minot</ENAMEX>;

            

               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bech</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bay</ENAMEX>: A <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Quasi-Novel</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Updike</ENAMEX>.

            
               --Eliza Truitt
            

         
      
   
