
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Holiday Question No. 148</ENAMEX>:

            By <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cohen</ENAMEX>

            
               A family
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">photo</ENAMEX>, the single word "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Noel</ENAMEX>," a naked babe draped in colored lights sipping
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">champagne</ENAMEX>--there are many styles of holiday card, and now's the time to mail
them. You are invited to describe the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> card sure to be sent by a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">corporation</ENAMEX>, world <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>, or other personage.
            

            by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 a.m. ET</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> to e-mail your answer to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.

            
               Responses
to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s question (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 147</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Convicts; George III</ENAMEX>?":
            

            
               "This seems like the
perfect place to release them." Where? What? Says who?
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Monticello</ENAMEX>; my last
remaining slaves; says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Strom Thurmond</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alex Balk</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Carvell</ENAMEX>
had a similar answer.)

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Mexico</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D.H.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lawrence</ENAMEX>'s oversexed girlfriends; says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frieda</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Kelly</ENAMEX>
            

            "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
op-ed page; tedious narcissistic ramblings; says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maureen Dowd</ENAMEX>."--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miller</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netscape NetCenter</ENAMEX>; our
constant busy signals; says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Case</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Levy</ENAMEX>
            

            "A chartered <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC-9</ENAMEX> at
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">35,000 feet</NUMEX>; <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of turkeys rescued from a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">poultry</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farm</ENAMEX>; says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PETA</ENAMEX> activist
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christie Brinkley</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">'Fly</NUMEX>! Go free!' she said as fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX> looked on in
horror.)"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Carvell</ENAMEX>
            

            Click for more
responses.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
            

            Comedy
attacks. It is difficult to be amusing in praise of something. But risking
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">holiday</ENAMEX> sentimentality (with the ready-made excuse that it's just the chestnut
stuffing talking), I'd like to mention some things I'm thankful for, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carvell</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> (!) responses involving pushing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">poultry</ENAMEX> out of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">airplanes</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer Miller</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> (!) bits of self-revelation about her dark and
ferocious inner life and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Amaros</ENAMEX>' determination that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Olsen</ENAMEX>
twins wander parched and frightened, not merely in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Serengeti</ENAMEX> but during the
dry season. It's this kind of pathological attention to detail that makes
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> industry the envy of the more materialistic parts of the world, and
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">News Quiz</ENAMEX>" such a pleasure to work on. Thank you all very much. (Especially
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> whose feelings I've hurt by not mentioning your names here. I'm
sorry. If this were a TV show, I could run a long list of thank-yous that you'd
ignore on your way to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen</ENAMEX> for another <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX>. And I'd be getting some fat
residual payments, that great <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Writers Guild</ENAMEX> health insurance, and jeez, just
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> paychecks would be terrific. I never should have taken that swing at
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brooke Shields</ENAMEX>.) Happy <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Halloween</TIMEX>, everybody.

            
               The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Feminization of Culture Answer</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oxygen Media</ENAMEX>, a new cable
network for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>; <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of reruns of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oprah Winfrey Show ;</ENAMEX> says
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oprah Winfrey</ENAMEX>.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">channel</ENAMEX> being created by former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nickelodeon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Geraldine Laybourne</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marcy Carsey</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carsey-Werner-Mandabach</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oprah Winfrey</ENAMEX> will "superserve
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laybourne</ENAMEX>. While most of the programming will be original, there
will be plenty of room for reruns of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carsey-Werner</ENAMEX> shows, including
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cybil</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Grace Under Fire</ENAMEX> , said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carsey</ENAMEX>. That's superservice.

            
               Parade of
Fun Extra
            

            Which of
these is a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Macy's Thanksgiving Day Parade</ENAMEX> float from a proud corporate sponsor
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> love, and which is one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Public Interest Research Group</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX>
Most <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dangerous Toys</ENAMEX>?

            
               Toy or
Float?
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peanut</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Circus</ENAMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hasbro</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Teletubby Po</ENAMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Folgers Coffee</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rip Van</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Winkle Wakin</ENAMEX>' Up

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mattel</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baby Dil</ENAMEX>'s
World

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell Atlantic</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maurice</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sendak</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wild Thing</ENAMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Playskool's Talking Pay</ENAMEX>
Phone

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ocean Spray</ENAMEX> Cranberries
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inc.</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Pan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pirate Ship</ENAMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hanes Hosiery's Party</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>!

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>. Unique's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flying</ENAMEX>
Propellers

            10.
Betacarotine

            

               Answers
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. Float--and you know what
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> love with those salted nuts? Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beer</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. Dangerous toy--vinyl face
made with phthalates, cause of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">liver cancer</ENAMEX> in laboratory <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. Float--celebrating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>'
willingness to settle for instant <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX>?

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. Dangerous toy--pieces
could cause choking.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. Float--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are thankful
for reliable local phone service.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. Dangerous toy--plastic
coins can lodge in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>'s throat.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>. Float--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> wave bye-bye
to urinary tract infections.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>. Float--we gather together
to count the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lord</ENAMEX>'s pantyhose.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>. Dangerous toy--but not
nearly as dangerous as rusty flying propellers coated with broken glass.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX>. Actual part of parade,
listed as a "celebrity <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>."

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Disclaimer</ENAMEX>: All submissions will become the property of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> and
will be published at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> 's discretion. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> may publish your
name on its site in connection with your submission.
            

         
      
   
