
   
   
      
         
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 31</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Oct. 31, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            The
cover editorial predicts that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX>'s election
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> will most likely stick to old habits, returning a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">legislature</ENAMEX> much like
the previous one." Defying all the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> punditry, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX> has been a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nonfactor</ENAMEX>. ... A story scientifically explains <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Halloween</TIMEX> legends.
Vampirism may be traced to the disease porphyria, which causes sunlight-averse
skin, retracted gums, and red urine--leading to the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX>-drinking myth.
Several witchcraft panics "occurred in places where <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rye</ENAMEX> was widely cultivated,
and after weather that was propitious for the growth of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Claviceps</ENAMEX> ."
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Claviceps</ENAMEX> is a parasite that, when eaten, causes <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">hallucinations</ENAMEX>.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mother Jones</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November/December 1998</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Oct. 31, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mother Jones 400</ENAMEX> lists the top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contributors</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past year</TIMEX>. No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard M.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helen DeVos</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founders</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amway</ENAMEX>, who gave <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $1 million</NUMEX> to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>. They were rewarded with a special tax cut that saved <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amway $19</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">million</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Donors</ENAMEX>' favorite special interests were telecommunications and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX>. An
accompanying story exposes how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Outback Steakhouse</ENAMEX> coerced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> to
contribute to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Outback</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">PAC</ENAMEX>. Outback then used the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">PAC funds</ENAMEX> to lobby against
national health care and an increase in the minimum wage.

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times Magazine</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 1</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, Oct. 29, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
story says <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> no longer want an ambitious, problem-solving <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>.
Our only consensus is that "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> should serve the ordinary, hard-working
individual--providing safety, public goods like <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX> and the tools
necessary to seek opportunity, like education. It should protect <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from
unfair or excessive aspects of the marketplace." We lack pride in or loyalty to
our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and have no "willingness to put aside personal concerns to serve
a larger cause." ... The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> interviews young <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iranians</ENAMEX> who long for
cultural freedom. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>'s revolution, now <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 years old</TIMEX>, leaves young <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iranians</ENAMEX>
cold. They want to wear shorts, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drink booze</ENAMEX>, and sing pop songs--all banned by
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. Young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> hoped <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>'s new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> would liberalize the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nation</ENAMEX>, but he hasn't so far.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Atlantic Monthly</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 1998</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, Oct. 29, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
story excerpts, with commentary, a forthcoming collection of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Kerouac</ENAMEX>'s
unpublished letters and notebooks. Revealed are <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kerouac</ENAMEX>'s growing distaste for
the other beats and the beat movement, his surprising religious fervor, and a
sweet and earnest nature. A letter to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grove Press</ENAMEX>: "I cant
possibly go on as a responsible prose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> and also as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">believer</ENAMEX> in the
impulses of my own heart and in the beauty of pure spontaneous language if I
let <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> take my sentences, which are my phrases that I separate by dashes
when I 'draw a breath,' each of which pours out to the tune of the whole story
its own rhythmic yawp of expostulation, & riddle them with commas, cut them
in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>, in threes, in fours, ruining the swing ... I know what I'm talking
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about</NUMEX> tho I may get drunk and act childish socially ... I'm an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>,
oldfashioned, devoted."

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monthly</TIMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 1998</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, Oct. 29, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            A
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">35 th</NUMEX> anniversary look at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> assassination includes interviews with several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> and photos galore. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> piece
carefully debunks all the conspiracy theories: the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mob</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fidel Castro</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LBJ</ENAMEX>, and the current vogue theory--that there were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee Harvey Oswalds</ENAMEX>, and
the innocent one got caught. Conclusion: There was one <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oswald</ENAMEX>, and he acted
alone.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 2</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Oct. 27, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's cover story calls <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Wolfe</ENAMEX>'s new novel, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Man in Full</ENAMEX> ,
better than <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bonfire of the Vanities</ENAMEX> . (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> area <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>
will get a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yankees</ENAMEX> cover.) The germ of the novel came when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolfe</ENAMEX> visited a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Georgia</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plantation</ENAMEX> used by its rich <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">quail</ENAMEX> hunting. The result: a
book about an <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">businessman</ENAMEX> caught in debt. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's review
agrees with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's rave. ... The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> cover package predicts how life will be different for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> born
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next millennium</TIMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> born in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> will have twice the life
expectancy of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> born in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1900</TIMEX>. Also, she will be taller and less likely to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">marry</ENAMEX>, will live in a far more racially diverse <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, and will eat
genetically engineered <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> concludes that
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yankees</ENAMEX> are the best baseball <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> ever. Why? They were "as strong on
the mound and in the field as they were at bat; endowed with a bunch of superb
role <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX>; blessed with a rare balance of speed and power; managed by a man
of calming temperament."

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> explains how rap labels spread the word-of-mouth about a new
album. "Street <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX>"--young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> hired by the label--put up posters, give
out illegal (but label-sanctioned) advance bootlegs, and request and dance
enthusiastically to the album at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clubs</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> put
this story on Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 25</TIMEX>.)

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News & World Report</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 2</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Oct. 27, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            The
cover package says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flytrap</ENAMEX> is a nonissue so far in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this fall</TIMEX>'s
congressional elections: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Voters</ENAMEX> aren't linking their ballots to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s fate.
But, says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX> , the election outcomes will directly determine
whether impeachment proceeding are dropped and whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> can set any
agenda in his remaining <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> in office. Accompanying pieces emphasize the
closeness of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">races</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voter turnout</ENAMEX> will be the key deciding factor.

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nation</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 9</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Oct. 27, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            The
cover story frets that
we're overconcerned with terrorism. Yes, terrorism is serious, but it can be
countered with a bit more vigilance from our intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>. Instead,
"<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> is now spending <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$7 billion</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> defending itself against backpack
nuclear bombs, canisters of nerve <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas</ENAMEX> and petri dishes of germ weapons planted
in crowded <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> by an as-yet-unknown <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adversary</ENAMEX>." The 
               Nation
deems this a dubious money grab by defense <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>.

            

               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 2</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Oct. 27, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
story argues that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> is no longer the progressive, trend-setting state
it once was. Instead, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> is growing more conservative: Even its
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> is pro-death penalty and anti-gay marriage.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> elections <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this fall</TIMEX> feature old issues and old campaign tactics, not
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s previous "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX> for charting <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s political future."

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stevenson</ENAMEX>
            

            More Flytrap
...

         
      
   
