
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq Backs</ENAMEX> Down

            
               If you missed the most
recent installments of this column, here they are: posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, Nov.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13</TIMEX>, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Nov. 10</TIMEX>.
            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Star of Bangladesh</ENAMEX>
paints the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> crisis as a pitiful <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> against a ruthless aggressor in an
editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>, saying, " 'Defiance' of a despoiled country
resonates with a total back-to-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">the</NUMEX>-wall desperation." The editorial calls for
the lifting of sanctions on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>, as does <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Dawn</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>, which condemns the "genocidal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> sanctions in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>." Saying that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> was until recently compliant with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N. Security</ENAMEX>
Council weapons <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspectors</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Dawn</ENAMEX> denounces the bias of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UNSCOM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspectors</ENAMEX>
and their insistence on thoroughly searching <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>'s presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palaces</ENAMEX>.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> papers noted that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blair</ENAMEX> backed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to the hilt in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iraqi</ENAMEX>
crisis and said that "absolute and unconditional compliance" was necessary for
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>. In an editorial, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> praised the strong, unified action of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> and said it was time to seize this opportunity while a large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">force</ENAMEX> is
assembled in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gulf</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> is apparently in retreat. The piece also
recommended that with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> now apparently in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">driver</ENAMEX>'s seat, it is time to review the sanctions.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anews</ENAMEX> item in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prague Post</ENAMEX> says that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> are making trouble for
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Czech Republic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> over the broadcast of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Radio Free Europe</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Radio</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liberty</ENAMEX> into their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>. The controversial broadcasts, in the native
languages of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>, began <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 30</TIMEX>. Since then, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iranian</ENAMEX> government
has recalled its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ambassador</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Prague</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> has warned that trade
relations between the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> could suffer. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Czech</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> has
brushed off these claims.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> paper <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ha'aretz</ENAMEX>
says if the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> had struck against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>, it would have spelled
disaster for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s visit to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gaza Strip</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next month</TIMEX>. It
speculates that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX> would have empathized with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iraqis</ENAMEX> and
sought to retaliate for the strikes--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hamas</ENAMEX>, for example, might have
launched an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX>-flag-burning fest.

            Another
op-ed in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ha'aretz</ENAMEX> called "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Saddam Index</ENAMEX>" complains that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> did not formally warn <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> before withdrawing nonessential
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">diplomats</ENAMEX> and cautioning <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> about travel to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the days</TIMEX> leading
up to the recent crisis. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> thus scores very low on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Saddam</ENAMEX>
index, the guiding principle of which is "the longer the advance warning to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>, the greater the level of trust" between the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>.
The editorial detects "symptoms of arteriosclerosis in relations between
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX>." This is further evident, the editorial says, in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way Clinton</ENAMEX> has brushed aside <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin Netanyahu</ENAMEX> since
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wye</ENAMEX>.

            
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jerusalem Post</ENAMEX> carries a story titled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Arafat Warns: Our rifles</ENAMEX>
are ready," portraying an angry <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yasser Arafat</ENAMEX> defending the right of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX> to pray in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX> responded by saying that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arafat</ENAMEX>'s
stance "endangers the entire <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oslo</ENAMEX> agreement and casts a very dark shadow over
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wye</ENAMEX> agreement as well." This comes, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> notes, at a time of
increased cooperation between the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sides</ENAMEX>.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Middle East Times</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX>
has a lead editorial railing against the portrayal of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX> movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Siege</ENAMEX> . "With the exception of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Haddad</ENAMEX> and a
miserable-looking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">courier</ENAMEX> who gets caught as he tries to bring in cash for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">terrorists</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arabs</ENAMEX> here are either <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX> or non-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> who provide a
poor-looking backdrop," it said.

            An article in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moscow Times</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> is
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">exporting grain</ENAMEX> even as it imports it. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> has already exported <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.5 million</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">tons</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wheat</ENAMEX>, even as humanitarian aid in the form of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2.5 tons</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wheat</ENAMEX> pour
into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. The reason: It is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times
more profitable to sell <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wheat</ENAMEX> abroad as to sell it in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>. Wisely, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> has stipulated that the imported aid grain not be re-exported for
profit. But as <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analyst</ENAMEX> said, "You can't put a 'Made in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>' brand on
every <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">grain</ENAMEX>."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South China Morning Post</ENAMEX> writes
the home <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> got very testy over visiting foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>'
preoccupation with the arrest and trial of former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Deputy Premier</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anwar Ibrahim</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> notes the deep disappointment in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malaysia</ENAMEX> over the no-show by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, who stayed home to cope with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> crisis and sent Vice
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> instead. Even <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madeleine Albright</ENAMEX> was
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">prematurely</ENAMEX> summoned home from the summit.

         
      
   
