
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">141</NUMEX>:

            By <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cohen</ENAMEX>

            
               Accepting
his new post as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Whitaker</ENAMEX> asked his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX>,
"What can we do to make <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> a must-read?" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> are invited
to offer suggestions.
            

            by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon ET</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> to e-mail your answer to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.

            
               Responses
to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s question (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 140</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Don't Legislate; Medicate":</ENAMEX>
            

            
               According to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychiatrist Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Krueger</ENAMEX>, "Part of the reason so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> take these
types of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> tend to have trouble admitting they have a problem."
What types of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>?
            

            "Sex-change
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hormones</ENAMEX>."--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ariel Kaminer</ENAMEX>
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Chocolate</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">G.C.</ENAMEX>
            

            "Unclear antecedent
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">blockers</ENAMEX>."--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Colleen Werthmann</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roofies</ENAMEX>. 'It turns out
many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> have a more satisfying sexual experience if unconscious,' explained
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Krueger</ENAMEX>. 'Yes, I do happen to be single. Why do you ask?' "--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Sherman</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Crack</ENAMEX>. 'Of course,'
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Krueger</ENAMEX> said, 'I may be oversimplifying.' "--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Carvell</ENAMEX>
            

            Click for more
responses.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Full</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Responsibility Wraparound</ENAMEX>
            

            Responses to "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">News Quiz</ENAMEX>"
naturally vary in both quality and quantity. Fill in the blank, for example,
typically sparks the most responses. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s question generated <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only about half</NUMEX>
the usual returns, and here's why: It's not very good. And here's whose fault
it is: <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX>. Devising the question calls for the deft and tactful art of the
straight <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, for playing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Burns</ENAMEX> to your <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gracie Allen</ENAMEX>. It's not just a
matter of lobbing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> over the plate for you to hit out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX>. It's
putting <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> over the plate that, when you clobber it, erupts in a shower of
confetti that coalesces into a single <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">scarlet flamingo</ENAMEX> that flies over to the
box seats and bites <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Steinbrenner</ENAMEX> on the ass. But not <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.

            The drug
metaphor is opaque and clumsy. And the central premise invites the too-familiar
gender-wars responses. Plus, there is something uncomfortable about male
admissions of inadequacy; it's like pleading guilty to a burglary so you won't
get nailed for a murder. Incidentally, the most common response was, as many of
you suspected, jokes about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>'s reluctance to ask for directions. However,
we've declined to run such observations out of respect for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Seinfeld</ENAMEX>. And
again, it's all my fault for leading you into this swamp. I'll try to do better
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX>. And I'll never again use a manly baseball metaphor. (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Picture me</ENAMEX>
humbly not spitting.)

            
               A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Gram Is</ENAMEX>
Better Than an Answer
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Lifestyle drugs</ENAMEX>.

            As
distinguished from <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicines</ENAMEX> that relieve pain or cure <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">illness</ENAMEX>, many <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> in
this category have failed to meet financial expectations. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Drugs</ENAMEX> to promote hair
growth (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Propecia</ENAMEX>) and to stop smoking (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nicotrol</ENAMEX>) have had disappointing sales.
With the exception of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Viagra</ENAMEX> (with projected <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">first year</TIMEX> returns of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">up to $1</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">billion</ENAMEX>, the most successful drug rollout in history), <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> have been a harder
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sell</ENAMEX> than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, who buy <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">60 percent</NUMEX> of the top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> anti-smoking <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Men</ENAMEX>
tend to abandon such remedies if they're not immediately effective.

            
               Leverage
Your <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Germanness Extra</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> is the ideal to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">male</ENAMEX>. It's strong, and it's all about precision and expertise. We
said: 'If you leverage your <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Germanness</ENAMEX>, that's really potent for this
particular target <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>. It just triggers all the things they want to think
about themselves.' "--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer Laing</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saatchi & Saatchi</ENAMEX>, on
advertising strategy for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beck's</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX>; she does not say if this would have been
a good advertising strategy for the Wehrmacht
            

            "I can smile, but it's
hard to think about whether that stereotype is realistic. As long as you, as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX>, make a joke at your own expense, it's OK."--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Axel Meermann</ENAMEX> ,
global marketing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beck's</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX>; he does not say if it's OK if such
jokes are made by me, as a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jew</ENAMEX>

            "[<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>'s rule was] an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">aberration</ENAMEX>, but not an organic aspect of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> society."--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Henry</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kissinger</ENAMEX> ; he does not say if the rule of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Augusto Pinochet</ENAMEX>, which he helped
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineer</ENAMEX>, was an organic aspect of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chilean</ENAMEX> society

            "To some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, 'Berlin'
still sounds too Prussian, too authoritarian, too centralized."--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chancellor</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerhard Schröder</ENAMEX> ; he does not say if "hell" sounds too hot

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Disclaimer</ENAMEX>: All submissions will become the property of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> and
will be published at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> 's discretion. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> may publish your
name on its site in connection with your submission.
            

         
      
   
