
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Drawing upon her rich
experience of life, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> to her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>) responds to questions
about manners, personal relations, politics, and other subjects. Please send
your questions for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> to prudence@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Queries should not exceed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> words in
length. Please indicate how you wish your letter to be signed, preferably
including your location.
            

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               I can't believe that I'm
writing to you, but I can't get this out of my mind. My very nice <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister-in-law</ENAMEX>
invited us to her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>'s high-school graduation dinner at a nice restaurant
immediately after the ceremony. We agreed to go to both events, graduation and
dinner.
            

            
               My question is this. We
had to leave early because of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby sitter</ENAMEX>, so we got up, kissed the new
graduate, said goodbye to everyone, and thanked our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister-in-law</ENAMEX>. A
relative--not the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX>--said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leaving</ENAMEX> before the bill arrives<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>" If he knew the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX> were supposed to pay for dinner, we didn't. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Embarrassed</ENAMEX>, I gave my
father-in-law money to give to the hostess to cover our <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meals</ENAMEX>.
            

            
               Was I
wrong to assume the dinner was given by my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister-in-law</ENAMEX>? What's the etiquette
about being invited to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> to celebrate a big event? I paid <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this time</TIMEX>,
but what to do next time? (And yes, we gave him a very, very nice graduation
present.)
            

            
               --Definitely Not a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freeloader</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
            

            Dear
Def,

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> is appalled, and
suspects your very nice <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister-in-law</ENAMEX> was raised by <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">wolves</ENAMEX>. At the very least,
if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX> can't manage such a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX> should be informed beforehand
that the celebratory dinner is the gustatory equivalent of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BYOB</ENAMEX>.

            As for
the next time, feel free to ask if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX> treat. If it is, and
you're not feeling <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX>, decline with thanks.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, choosily

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               My
problem is so small, but I have nobody else to ask. Where everybody sneezes
once or twice, I always sneeze at least <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> times--sometimes more. I
have never given it a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> thought, but recently <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> seem to be noticing
my sneezing and commenting on it, some suggesting I see a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX>. Do you think
I should be concerned?
            

            -- Lidia
            

            Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Lid,</ENAMEX>

            Do not
concern yourself with your repeater sneezes. To those nervy enough to comment,
simply say that you love to hear "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Gesundheit</ENAMEX> " over and over again.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, repetitively

            
               
                  Dear
Prudie,
               
            

            
               I work in an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> with
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 40</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. I am in my <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late 30s</TIMEX> and the youngest of the bunch. I like
computers a lot and know much about them, as well as about systems and
programming. Our so-called "computer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX>" is over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">60</TIMEX> and, admittedly, no
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX>. I would say that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">99 percent</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> are real computer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">idiots</ENAMEX>.
Most of the time <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> call on me when they have a problem with their
computers, and until now I have always helped them.
            

            
               Lately, however, I have
found that some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-workers</ENAMEX> have become upset because I was unable to drop
everything and come to their aid immediately. I have decided to no longer offer
this help, as it is not part of the work I was hired to do <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ago</TIMEX>.
            

            
               My
question is: Can an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employer</ENAMEX> ask that you use skills that are not in your job
description just because you have them? I think that the so-called "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX>"
should do what he's being paid to do and that the same goes for me.
            

            
               --With
all good wishes,
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">P.V.</ENAMEX>
            

            Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">P.,</ENAMEX>

            Your take on this matter is
correct, and you are a living breathing exemplar of the old saying "No good
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">deed</ENAMEX> goes unpunished." You've been such a good sport for so long that now it's
expected.

            Here's what to do: Whenever
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> hit you up to deal with their computer problems, tell them to turn to
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">23</NUMEX> in their copy of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dianetics</ENAMEX> . Only kidding. Refer them to the
"computer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX>," explaining that it is his job to help them and that you are
busy doing your work.

            If, by
chance, "the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX>" isn't up to the task, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> has a hunch the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> will
remedy the situation. You might even consider broaching the subject with him
yourself. Would you perhaps enjoy being deputized "the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX>" and
changing your job description?

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, wonderingly

            
               
                  Dear
Prudie,
               
            

            
               I thought you were very
gracious a while back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who wanted to know if you were Prudy
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Crowther</ENAMEX> who went to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bryn Mawr</ENAMEX>. I've been using the Internet for less than a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> but have managed to find several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> with whom I'd been out of touch
for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, and we've re-established contact very happily. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> also have
found me under similar circumstances.
            

            
               Thanks
for your astringent wit and good advice, even if it doesn't apply to
me.
            

            
               --All the
best,
            

            
               Writing a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Book</ENAMEX> on
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Deadline That Has Nothing Whatsoever To Do With Politics</ENAMEX>
            

            Dear
Write,

            Thank you
for the lovely compliments. It is nice to know that the Internet has uses
besides reading 
                  Slate
               . (Prudie jests. She knows you can check
stock quotes, too.)

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>,
connectedly

         
      
   
