
   
   
      
         
            Cannibalism

            Faster than you can say
"<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> revolution," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX> has surrendered his job as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Appropriations Committee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Livingston</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">R-La.</ENAMEX>,
has wrapped up the contest to replace him. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> has already reached
consensus on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Livingston</ENAMEX>: He represents "moderation," as opposed to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">conservatism</ENAMEX>, and "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX>," as opposed to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX>'s emphasis on ideology.
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Support for Livingston Represents Move Toward Pragmatism</ENAMEX>," says <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> front page.

            Other
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership positions</ENAMEX> are up for grabs, too, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> for these
jobs have joined <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Livingston</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX> in the ideology-pragmatism debate.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> was "a revolutionary," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Livingston</ENAMEX> argued <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s This
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Week</TIMEX> ; "I am a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX>." But once again, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> are
failing to grasp the message of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> elections. It's not about ideology.
It's not about competence. It's about self-absorption.

            The performance of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Livingston</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> other leadership
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> illustrates how the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> coup, far from solving
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>'s problems, is moving <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> in the wrong direction. Instead of
confronting the public's <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">material</ENAMEX> concerns, they're engrossed in blaming each
other and promoting themselves. Speaking for the new "management" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Livingston</ENAMEX> advertised himself as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX> who would "provide the legislative
machinery" to implement legislation. When asked about his role as
appropriations <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year's sloppily</TIMEX> assembled <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">trillion</NUMEX> dollar
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">budget</ENAMEX> bill, he replied that he had said at the time, "This is ugly, but we
have to pass it and get out of here and go get re-elected." When asked about
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pork</ENAMEX>-laden <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$217 billion</NUMEX> highway bill, he said <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> of the bill
were right and that he "was opposed in the preliminary" votes but "ended up
voting for the final bill," since "a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are going to have highways
because of that bill and a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are going to have jobs because of that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bill</ENAMEX>." When asked whether <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> had mishandled the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>
investigation, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Livingston</ENAMEX> answered, "I don't know. I personally was trying to
get my appropriations bills out ... and I wasn't paying that much attention to
what was going on." As for the election results, he blamed conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>
who "stayed home from the polls because they're sulking because they didn't get
everything they wanted."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J.C.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Watts</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Okla.</ENAMEX>, who ostensibly represents the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>'s conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wing</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">followed Livingston</ENAMEX> on the show. His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">principal</ENAMEX> diagnosis of the election was
that his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> hadn't heeded his wisdom about appealing to ethnic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minorities</ENAMEX>. "I feel like I've been beating my head on the wall for the last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX> and saying that we've got to reach out," he lamented. Rather than
address the moral implications of this oversight, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Watts</ENAMEX> went on to explain how
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>, by electing him, could capitalize politically on new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audiences</ENAMEX>. "I
haven't just talked about this outreach thing, I've done it," he asserted.
"I've executed the game plan."

            
Finally, speaking for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">incumbents</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>
Boehner, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX>, explained why he should be re-elected as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conference</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boehner</ENAMEX> agreed that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> needed to be changed.
"We have got to manage the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> in a much different way," he said. "There were
no clear lines of responsibility in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX>. No clear lines of
accountability." But when asked about his own responsibility for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>'s
failure, he replied, "Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the conference really believe that with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt</ENAMEX>'s decision to leave, that's enough change--that the problems, in terms of
managing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>, were mostly in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>." When pressed as to
whether he had made any mistakes, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boehner</ENAMEX> bravely allowed, "I don't think it is
any secret to anyone that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX> and I had our share of disagreements over
the last <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX> about how we operated." When asked about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>'s failure
to pass budget bills by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 30</TIMEX>, as required by law, he replied, "No one has
paid attention to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Budget Act</ENAMEX> since it was enacted." And summing up his
rationale for re-election, he emphasized "the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX> that I've provided with
my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>."

            The
conventional media analysis of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> struggle is that <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Watts</ENAMEX>,
fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Largent</ENAMEX>, and other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> are
taking on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Livingston, Boehner</ENAMEX>, and the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pragmatists</ENAMEX>." And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>'s implicit
conclusion is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pragmatists</ENAMEX> would turn the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> toward the mandate for
moderation that was delivered in the elections. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX>'s description of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> coup--"cannibalism"--is more accurate. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> are conveying a preoccupation not with solving the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nation</ENAMEX>'s problems but with protecting themselves individually and devouring
each other. And if there's one thing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">electorate</ENAMEX> seems to disdain more than
the violence of the cannibals, it's the narcissism of their palates.

            
               Recent
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Frame Games</ENAMEX>"
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The C Word": The</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> election didn't kill conservatism. The postelection analysis did.
(posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, Nov. 6, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Election Night</ENAMEX>
Excuses": <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Saletan</ENAMEX> analyzes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> classic postelection spins.
(posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday, Nov. 2, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

         
      
   
