
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Drawing upon her rich
experience of life, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> to her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>) responds to questions
about manners, personal relations, politics, and other subjects. Please send
your questions for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> to prudence@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Queries should not exceed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> words in
length. Please indicate how you wish your letter to be signed, preferably
including your location.
            

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harris</ENAMEX> book ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Nurture Assumption: Why Children Turn Out the Way They</ENAMEX>
Do , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judith Rich Harris</ENAMEX>) suggests that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> contribute nothing to the
development of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. What do you think?
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota</ENAMEX>
Contingent
            

            Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Minn,</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> has only dragonfly
knowledge of this book. That is, she has skimmed the surface by reading a few
reviews. The title suggests the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> is a childless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">geneticist</ENAMEX>. The research,
however, is data-driven and well-supported. Though controversial, the theory
that genes and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peers</ENAMEX> play pivotal roles in development cannot be dismissed.

            While
genetic makeup and peer influence can override some elements of the home
environment, parental attention, input, and example cannot be written off.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> hopes the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harris</ENAMEX> book will not encourage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> everywhere to leave
their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>-rearing duties to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbor kids</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX>.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>,
developmentally

            
               
                  Dear
Prudie,
               
            

            
               My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and I recently had
our <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>. We have a problem concerning gift etiquette. We
received a beautiful blanket from some out-of-town <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> whom we see about
once a year. The blanket has inscribed on it--in large letters--the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX>'s name
and date of birth. The problem is that he was born <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one week earlier</TIMEX> than the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">blanket</ENAMEX> says.
            

            
               We can't decide whether to
tell our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> about the error. If it was the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX>'s mistake, I'm sure they
would want to correct the error. However, if it was the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>' mistake, we
have no desire to embarrass them with their error. (Actually, being exactly one
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week later</TIMEX>, the blanket does commemorate his bris.)
            

            
               What to
do?
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gifted</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grateful</ENAMEX>
            

            Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Gift,</ENAMEX>

            
               Mazel tov! Prudie
suggests you be the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> on your block to start the craze of bris blankets.
You are correct not to want to embarrass the gift givers, and it's a major pain
to deal with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> about replacing customized merchandise. (And luckily, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> can't read yet.)

            Like
misprinted stamps that become valuable because they are mistakes, the
beautiful blanket will have a little extra meaning--plus nice memories--because
of the erroneous date.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, snugly

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               My hubby just went to
have his head stuffed. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> point buck he got with a bow, that is. We live
in a tiny <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cabin</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> are asking where he is going to hang it. "Above
the bed" seems to be their general consensus. To this, proud <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hubby</ENAMEX> replies, "IN
the bed."
            

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) What would <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freud</ENAMEX>
reply?
            

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) What do you
think?
            

            

               Personally, while I'm glad <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hubby</ENAMEX> is happy, I don't want this dead thing
coming between us.
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">JEB</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pa.</ENAMEX>
            

            Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">JEB</ENAMEX>,

            How exciting that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hubby</ENAMEX> shot
a hatrack, I mean, buck, with a bow. I think he is funning with you, as the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southerners</ENAMEX> say, when he tells <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> the trophy will reside in the bed with
the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of you. That, or he has <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mafia</ENAMEX> fantasies and is trying to tell you
something.

            As for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Freud</ENAMEX>'s reply, he is not taking any calls. My own thoughts you already know:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hubby</ENAMEX> is kidding, and the joke shows pride in his accomplishment. And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>
thinks, especially in a tiny <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cabin</ENAMEX>, that the antlers would provide a wonderful
place on which to hang hats and coats.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, practically

            
               
                  Dear
Prudie,
               
            

            
               I am so
disappointed you felt it necessary to opine on this matter. (The matter being
the letter from <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Truthful in Torrance</ENAMEX> re the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s behavior.) Not only did I
think your answer glib, but given the attention this matter has received vs.
that which is warranted, it was also unnecessary.
            

            
               Warmest
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">regards</ENAMEX>,--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard</ENAMEX>
            

            Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rich</ENAMEX>,

            Do you
know what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> finds wonderful? That you disagree with her yet sign your note
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warmest</ENAMEX> regards." Civility reigns.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, warmly

         
      
   
