
   
   
      
         
            Black <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Like Whom</ENAMEX>?

            Like it or not,
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-Americans</ENAMEX> have inherited a historical exemption that allows them to
employ racial pejoratives freely and even playfully. But the exemption has been
strained to breaking point in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Flytrap</ENAMEX>, as black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX> struggle to
explain why the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">electorate</ENAMEX> supports <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> so much more
vigorously than the white one does.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sociologist Orlando Patterson</ENAMEX> conjectured reasonably enough on the New

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times</ENAMEX> op-ed page that black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> rushed to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s aid because
they feel historically vulnerable to invasions of privacy like those committed
during the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> investigation. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Novelist Ishmael Reed</ENAMEX> stepped closer to an
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">incendiary</ENAMEX> line, writing in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baltimore Sun</ENAMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">affinity for Clinton</ENAMEX> stems partly from the fact that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> has "a black
style" and even "walks black." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nobel Laureate Toni Morrison</ENAMEX> crossed into the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fantastical</ENAMEX> when she wrote in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is "blacker
than any actual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who could ever be elected in our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s lifetime."
Explaining what she meant by "blackness," <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morrison</ENAMEX> listed single motherhood,
poverty, saxophone playing, and an uncontrollable desire to eat at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald's</ENAMEX>.
Emboldened by this example, white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberal playwright</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arthur Miller</ENAMEX> suggested on
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> op-ed page that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s "blackness" resides in the fact he
came from "a broken home" with "an alcoholic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>."

            The deconstruction of so-called "blackness" might pass
muster as a parlor game, but it's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lame</ENAMEX> as political analysis. The notion that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks cleave</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> because he does the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pimp</ENAMEX> walk, eats fried <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chicken</ENAMEX>, and
reminds them of unwed motherhood trades on noxious racial stereotypes and
implies that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-Americans</ENAMEX> lack the ability to make rational political
decisions. It also shortchanges the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>, which conducted a brilliant
campaign to court black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> directly.

            Any
pollster worth his paycheck knows that political approval ratings are based
almost entirely on economic concerns. By that standard, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-Americans</ENAMEX> have
done better under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> than under any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> back to and including
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>--whose enlightened policies on urban aid and public health surely qualify
him as the "blackest" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of all time. This point is borne out in this
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>'s poll results from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joint Center for Political and Economic Studies</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>. For the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joint Center</ENAMEX> survey, black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were more
likely than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX> to report that they were better off financially--by a margin
of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">51 percent</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">31.5 percent</NUMEX>.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s favorable ratings among the black
elderly (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">100 percent</NUMEX>) are astonishing given that this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> disapproves
strongly of the death penalty, which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> supports with gusto. These <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>
have given <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> a pass on this issue, telling him that he can burn the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> he wants as long as black economic fortunes remain good. Combine
those fortunes with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s support of affirmative action and his
appointments of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX> positions--and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12 years</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican</ENAMEX>
assaults on equal opportunity--and it should come as no surprise that blacks
are enthusiastic about this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> helped itself with a brilliant outreach campaign that went around the
sometimes surly <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congressional Black Caucus</ENAMEX> and reached black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> directly
through their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ministers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> that carried out this plan was
officially called the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House Office of Public Liaison</ENAMEX>--but was more
colloquially known as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Negro Affairs</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexis M. Herman</ENAMEX> ran this
effort so well that she was later named <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor</ENAMEX>. While at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>, her job included bringing in powerful black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ministers</ENAMEX>, who were more
than happy to take photo opportunities with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX> Bill. They prayed and ate
with him and prayed some more. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> returned the visits in triplicate, with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">church</ENAMEX> appearances that cemented his support--while enhancing the reputations
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ministers</ENAMEX> he visited. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torquemada</ENAMEX> arrived at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> gate,
black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ministers</ENAMEX>--many of whose <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church services</ENAMEX> are broadcast on
radio--unleashed a torrent of appeals on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s behalf. Faced with a surge
among its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">constituents</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congressional Black Caucus</ENAMEX> scrambled to the front
of the parade.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> visits were more than singing and chicken
dinners. He delivered his toughest talks on welfare from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> pulpits. He
realized intuitively what many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> have always failed
to see: that the black middle class is prime conservative timber--angry about
crime, intolerant of social pathology, and deeply scornful of the traditional
welfare system. Given how this strategy paid off--pleasing both conservative
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX> and the black middle class--<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> will surely
duplicate it in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>.

            Black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, particularly
black <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southerners</ENAMEX>, have endured political contempt for so long that many of
them have come to assume that any white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who treats them with respect
must somehow be black under the skin. But the claim that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has a "black"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> of being not only goes too far but is also sociologically imprecise.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Southerner</ENAMEX>, like his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elvis</ENAMEX>; what that means is that they both
grew up close to black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, with open access to black culture, a lot of
which is synonymous with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> pop culture. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Baptist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">South</ENAMEX> were segregated--but they sang the same hymns and preached the same
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sermons</ENAMEX>. Given that all <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-Americans</ENAMEX> have <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Southern</ENAMEX> roots, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
personal style and patterns travel easily from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> to another.
In short, he is more comfortable in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> of black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faces</ENAMEX> than any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> before him. This is what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Toni Morrison</ENAMEX> and others were trying to say
when they described him as "black."

         
      
   
