
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate Goes Postal</ENAMEX>

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate Goes Postal</ENAMEX>
            

            Starting
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX>, you'll be able to sign up for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> new e-mail services from

                  Slate
               . 
                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Afternoon Delivery</ENAMEX> will include a
selection of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that day</TIMEX>'s analysis and commentary from 
                  Slate
               's
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">newsier</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">departments</ENAMEX>, such as "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>" and "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Explainer</ENAMEX>." 
                  Slate
               
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Evening Delivery</ENAMEX> will include a selection of new 
                  Slate
                cultural
coverage and reviews. <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Morning</TIMEX> delivery of "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" will, of course,
continue, as will weekly e-mail delivery of our print-out edition,

                  Slate
                
               on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paper</ENAMEX> . These new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX> will be available free
of charge to 
                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subscribers</ENAMEX>. Click here to
subscribe to 
                  Slate
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX>. Click here to sign up
for any or all of our e-mail delivery services. (The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> new ones won't be
available for sign-up until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX>.)

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wise Men</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wise Guys</ENAMEX>
            

            Where are the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wise</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Men</ENAMEX> who
could lead us out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX> morass? That is the mournful keening you hear
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about half</NUMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>. They lament the passing of
an alleged era when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figures</ENAMEX> of towering prestige and gravitas would swoop in
like superheroes when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">democracy</ENAMEX> had tied itself in one too many knots. Gently
but firmly, they would guide us to safety, then disappear back into their
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">walnut</ENAMEX>-paneled <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clubs</ENAMEX> until needed once more. If only we had such <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Wise Men</ENAMEX> today
(not excluding the possibility of a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wise Woman</ENAMEX>, of course), they would be able
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">broker</ENAMEX> a deal between the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, sparing the
nation the prolonged agony of impeachment. (To hear the keening, check out this
recent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> piece by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">R.W. Apple Jr.</ENAMEX>)

            The other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
finds the idea of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wise</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Men</ENAMEX>-to-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">the</NUMEX>-rescue <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pompous</ENAMEX>, patronizing, and
undemocratic. This <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> includes both those who relish the prospect of
impeachment and those who think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> should hang tough.
(
                  Slate
               's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Plotz</ENAMEX> falls into this category. See his recent
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dispatch</ENAMEX>.")

            In a recent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York</ENAMEX>
Times op-ed essay titled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"No Time for Partisans"</ENAMEX> (not available in the
Times Web site free space, unfortunately) <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> distinguished <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
figures call for "responsible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> on both sides" to make a deal. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> are former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lloyd Cutler</ENAMEX>, former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Attorney General</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicholas Katzenbach</ENAMEX>, former appellate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abner Mikva</ENAMEX>, and former <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Hamilton</ENAMEX>. Certainly if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX> is a job for <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wise Men</ENAMEX>,
these are the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wise Men</ENAMEX> for the job.

            But is it, and are they? Next
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX> (beginning <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX>, we hope) we will conduct a 
                  Slate
               
e-mail "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dialogue" on Wise Men to the Rescue</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doubter</ENAMEX> will be <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Kristol</ENAMEX>,
TV pundit and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly Standard</ENAMEX> . That makes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kristol</ENAMEX>, among
more glorious attributes, 
                  Slate
               's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX> in a downtown <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>
office <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>--which may answer the question several distressed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> have
asked: Why so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> in 
                  Slate
                from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly</ENAMEX>
Standard ? Answer: They're just so ... handy . In this case, though,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kristol</ENAMEX> and the Standard are the leading voices urging <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> not
to flinch or compromise on impeachment, so we're especially delighted to have
his participation. So delighted, in fact, that we'll refrain from making any
jokes tying <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX>'s skepticism about <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wise Men</ENAMEX> to his former employment as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quayle</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief of staff</ENAMEX>. (Actually, we couldn't quite work out a good one.
Suggestions welcome.)

            Defending
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wise Men</ENAMEX> as a concept and as a solution to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX> will be <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Hamilton</ENAMEX>. As
the youngest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Four Would-Be Wise Men</ENAMEX>, he probably has the thinnest
patina of wisdom. That is no measure of relative actual wisdom, of course. But
if we had to guess, it probably means he's doing most of the work.

            
               Poetry
in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Motion</ENAMEX>
            

            When we
imagine the life of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet laureate</ENAMEX>, we see--through a dreamlike fog of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sherry</ENAMEX>--a berobed figure lounging on a waterlily, floating gently through an
Arcadian landscape, quill pen in hand but used more as a prop than for the
actual production of poetry. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Pinsky</ENAMEX>--also poetry <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of

                  Slate
               --is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">laureate</ENAMEX> who does not rest on his laurels, a
Stakhanovite among poets. He has no <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fewer than three</NUMEX> new books out at the
moment. The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Handbook of Heartbreak: 101 Poems of Lost Love and Sorrow</ENAMEX> is
an anthology published by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morrow</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sounds of Poetry: A Brief Guide</ENAMEX> is a short prose book about
hearing poems, with no diagrams or jargon, published by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farrar Straus</ENAMEX> &
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Giroux</ENAMEX>. And <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Penguin Audiobooks</ENAMEX> has brought out an edition of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pinsky</ENAMEX>'s
translation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dante's Inferno</ENAMEX>, read by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pinsky</ENAMEX> himself, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louise Glück</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seamus Heaney</ENAMEX>.
Pinsky queries if we count an audiobook as a book. As a card-carrying new
medium ourselves, we sure as heck do.

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
