
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Eyes on the Prize</ENAMEX>

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">These days</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studios</ENAMEX> are
inordinately attentive to my viewing habits. As a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the National
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Society of Film Critics</ENAMEX>, which votes a slate of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year-end</TIMEX> prizes, I'm fielding
calls from eager <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">publicists</ENAMEX> who want to make sure I've seen all those
award-worthy movies featuring all those award-worthy performances. I've tried
to stay mum, so as to keep my voting options open, but it's hard for a guy
brimming with opinions to be circumspect. Beloved ? A worthy effort.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oprah</ENAMEX>? Worthiness incarnate; I feel unworthy even to sit in judgment. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Meryl</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Streep in Dancing</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lughnasa</ENAMEX> ? <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ian McKellen in Gods and Monsters</ENAMEX> ?
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leonardo DiCaprio</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Celebrity</ENAMEX> ? Damn worthy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX>. (I enthused about
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DiCaprio</ENAMEX> when the sour <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Celebrity</ENAMEX> opened the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">New York Film Festival</ENAMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX>; since it shows up in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">theaters</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>, you might want to click
here so
that I don't have to quote myself.)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Streep</ENAMEX>
should be awarded a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rubber chicken</ENAMEX> for irradiating us with her yokel devotion
in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">One True Thing</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>), but in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dancing</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lughnasa</ENAMEX> she goes a
long way toward winning back her good (well, pretty good) name. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kate Mundy</ENAMEX>,
the stick-in-the-mud <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">schoolteacher</ENAMEX> who presides over <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> younger, unmarried
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sisters in 1936 Donegal</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX>, she holds her facial muscles tense and
signals with her eyes her exhaustion from keeping them so fiercely in place. It
is a terrible responsibility, upholding her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">society</ENAMEX>'s values and preventing her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">siblings</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael</ENAMEX>, the illegitimate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> of her youngest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christina</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Catherine McCormack</ENAMEX>), from descending into chaos and impoverishment. Not to
mention the fact that she's regarded by all as a stupid <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">goose</ENAMEX>--or, as they call
her in town, mocking her sexlessness, "the gander."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Streep</ENAMEX>'s performance is layered and compelling, but the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">film</ENAMEX> doesn't click. Closely based on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian Friel</ENAMEX>'s play, it wilts in
translation the way <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Friel</ENAMEX>'s potent but static dramas always do. On <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stage</ENAMEX>, every
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>, every prop, every interjection has a precise symbolic function; on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">film</ENAMEX>, those elements no longer stand out in relief. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dancing</ENAMEX> at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lughnasa</ENAMEX> (it's pronounced LOO-nassa), the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> reside in a sterile and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">repressive Ireland</ENAMEX>--but one in which the pagan past continues to bubble up,
most visibly in the harvest feast of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lughnasa</ENAMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peasants</ENAMEX> take to the hills
to build fires, drink to even greater excess than usual, and dance
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">orgiastically</ENAMEX>. The rite is liberating but also frightening: Remove a cork from
a bottle so pressurized, and the contents are apt to explode.

            The story,
narrated by the now-grown <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX> in the shopworn manner of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Glass</ENAMEX>
Menagerie , is set in motion by the return of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Uncle Jack</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gambon</ENAMEX>) from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX>, where he has toiled as a missionary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">priest</ENAMEX>. Delusional,
barely remembering his <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX> becomes a rambling (and, to the local
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">priest</ENAMEX>, horrific) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> for paganism, encouraging all his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">emulate Christina</ENAMEX> and have "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> of love."

            
There isn't much else in the way of a plot.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kate</ENAMEX>'s position at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>, which is overseen by the local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">priest</ENAMEX>, is
imperiled by the subversive presence of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX>'s handsome dad
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rhys Ifans</ENAMEX>) roars back on a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">motorcycle</ENAMEX> to flirt with marriage to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christina</ENAMEX>:
Will he stay or go fight the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Fascists</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX>? Each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> chafes in her own
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kate</ENAMEX>'s oppressive rule--especially <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rose</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sophie Thompson</ENAMEX>), the
"simple" <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, who might or might not be having an affair with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> have abandoned him for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>. A weaving <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factory</ENAMEX> is opening nearby
and threatens the household income. In venerable <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chekhovian</ENAMEX> fashion, what
happens on the surface only hints at the titanic plates that shift beneath, but
the actresses--especially <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Streep</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thompson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathy Burke</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brid Brennan</ENAMEX>--are
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">supreme</ENAMEX> at conveying what's at stake. They create an indelibly glowering
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ensemble</ENAMEX>.

            So why
isn't Dancing at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lughnasa</ENAMEX> more involving? It's probably because the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat O'Connor</ENAMEX>, can't tell the difference between images that express
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Friel</ENAMEX>'s themes and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hibernian</ENAMEX> wallpaper, and because his idea of expansive,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pictorial</ENAMEX> beauty proves no substitute for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Friel</ENAMEX>'s powerfully compressed stage
pictures. In the theater, the radio that crackles on and off signals a world
elsewhere; and when it's repaired and the stage is flooded with music and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sisters</ENAMEX>--beaten down, confronted with only the grimmest of economic and social
prospects--begin to dance and then lose themselves in the freedom of the dance,
the moment is truly cathartic. On-screen it means the movie's almost over.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> think I'm kidding when I say that my favorite film
is The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Bride</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frankenstein</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1935</TIMEX>), but I can't imagine how I'd have
survived an especially grisly puberty without the comfort of watching <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Karloff</ENAMEX> express his anguish to an uncomprehending world through a misshapen
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> and halting language. Few films have ever offered so inspired a blend of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sentimentality</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grand Guignol</ENAMEX> horror, and sophisticated <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX>, or such
deliriously inventive laboratory <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bric-a-brac</ENAMEX>. The film's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Whale</ENAMEX>,
has long been venerated for this and other droll <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">'30s</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">entertainments</ENAMEX>, among
them The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Old Dark House</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1932</TIMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Invisible Man</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1933</TIMEX>).
Lately, he has also been scrutinized for being openly homosexual in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">an era</TIMEX> when
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gay directors</ENAMEX>, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Cukor</ENAMEX>, kept that part of their lives rigidly
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">compartmentalized</ENAMEX>. But not even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Ehrenstein</ENAMEX> in his trenchantly gossipy new
book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">on the Hollywood closet, Open Secret</ENAMEX> , wants to make the case that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Whale</ENAMEX> was penalized for his sexual preferences. If anything, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> seems
to have suffered from a surfeit of dignity, proving too proud to overcome the
loss of a powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patron</ENAMEX> and a couple of ambitious flops. Comfortably rich, he
took to painting and traveling before a series of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">strokes</ENAMEX> drove him to drown
himself in his swimming pool--a suicide, though that fact was concealed from
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25 years</TIMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gods</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monsters</ENAMEX> ,
based on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Father</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frankenstein</ENAMEX> , a novel by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Bram</ENAMEX>, explores
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last days</TIMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ian McKellen</ENAMEX>) through the prism of a (fictional)
friendship with a handsome, muscular, and heterosexual groundskeeper, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boone</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brendan Fraser</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> have been unanimous in predicting statuettes in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McKellen</ENAMEX>'s future. Why? The movie is psychologically thin, artistically flabby,
and symbolically opaque. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Whale</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frankenstein</ENAMEX> films weren't personal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">testaments</ENAMEX>, but in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Gods and Monsters</ENAMEX> they're raided for murky fantasy
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sequences</ENAMEX>. In one, the groundskeeper is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monster</ENAMEX> staggering around with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Whale</ENAMEX> in his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX>; in another, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Whale</ENAMEX> is laid out on a laboratory slab being
operated on by the groundskeeper. What's the metaphor? The script, meanwhile,
is the stuff of bad <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> plays, with spurious excuses for conflict
(<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boone</ENAMEX> storms out when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Whale</ENAMEX> speaks tenderly of the naked, young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> who once
populated his pool) and a long, climactic monologue about a (fictional) wartime
trauma that ostensibly shocked <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Whale</ENAMEX> into keeping his past under wraps. In
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bram</ENAMEX>'s novel, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boone</ENAMEX> is vaguely dangerous, a plausible suspect in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Whale</ENAMEX>'s death,
but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fraser</ENAMEX> plays him (ingratiatingly) as a lovable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lunk</ENAMEX>, and the conception
removes whatever tension the material might have had.

            As <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Whale</ENAMEX>,
McKellen wears his elegance lightly. His face is fascinatingly <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> tiered: lean
in long shot, in close-up its features distend to the point of acromegaly, the
mouth going slack with lust. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Whale</ENAMEX>'s plangent ruminations are slack as
well: "I've spent much of my life outrunning the past, and now it floods all
over," he tells <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boone</ENAMEX>, in what is surely the most generic line for a "memory
play" ever written. "Something about your face makes me want to tell the
truth." All this mawkishness would likely have annoyed the real <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Whale</ENAMEX>, who
exited the world on his own terms and steered clear, in his art, of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">banality</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">W></ENAMEX>aking <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ned Devine</ENAMEX> is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s stab at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Full</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monty</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>), which made <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $100 million</NUMEX> and even snagged an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oscar</ENAMEX>
nomination. Set in a quaint olde <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> seacoast <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">village</ENAMEX>, it tells the story of
an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elderly</ENAMEX> lottery <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackie O'Shea</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ian Bannen</ENAMEX>), who learns that one of
his fifty-odd <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> holds the winning ticket to a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">7 million</NUMEX> pound drawing.
By a process of elimination, he and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buddy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael O'Sullivan</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Kelly</ENAMEX>)
end up at the remote stone <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ned Devine</ENAMEX>--whom they find dead in his
armchair with the ticket between his fingers, the shock of his windfall having
felled him. As <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Devine</ENAMEX> has no living relations, it makes sense for the
impoverished old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> to cook up a scheme by which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX> will assume the dead
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fisherman</ENAMEX>'s identity, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pair</ENAMEX> will divide the money between
themselves.

            It was no surprise to read
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kirk Jones</ENAMEX>, the film's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>, doesn't hail from a small town
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Irish Republic</ENAMEX> or anywhere close. He makes TV commercials in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>.
Deciding he'd like to make an eccentric regional comedy with universal themes,
he journeyed to a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">village</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX>, set himself up in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pub</ENAMEX>, and took notes
on what he saw and heard. Then he wrote a script that's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> part <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Forsyth</ENAMEX>'s
Local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Hero</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1983</TIMEX>), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> part <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Preston Sturges</ENAMEX>' <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX>
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1940</TIMEX>), and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about five</NUMEX> parts synthetic whimsy.

            The movie
is a passable entertainment--call it <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Half Monty</ENAMEX> . It has standard
issue (but funny) farcical sight gags and a score of panpipes to provide the
requisite undercurrent of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Celtic</ENAMEX> melancholy. There's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witchy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret Hamilton</ENAMEX>
type (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eileen Dromey</ENAMEX>) who rides some sort of electric wheelchair and attempts to
spoil the whole caper. There's also a stock ingénue (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Lynch</ENAMEX>) who loves the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">town</ENAMEX>'s endearing <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pig</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmer</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Nesbitt</ENAMEX>) but won't marry him because he
smells so bad--and I'm not oversimplifying. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Waking Ned Devine</ENAMEX> might have
been a snooze if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> hadn't stocked it with a slew of old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">magically</ENAMEX> lived-in visages. The owlish <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bannen</ENAMEX> can twinkle without looking
dear--there's something saturnine in that face. As his <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed Norton</ENAMEX>-ish sidekick,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kelly</ENAMEX> walks off--or, rather, rides off--with the picture, his skeletal frame
planted buck naked on a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">motorcycle</ENAMEX> as he rushes to reach <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Devine</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> before
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> from the lottery. I see a future for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elderly male actors</ENAMEX> willing to
shed their clothes for laughs, but I don't see myself in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>.

            The term "slice of life" has come to mean dreary
naturalism, but for the superb <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard LaGravenese</ENAMEX>, who wrote and directed
Living <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Out Loud</ENAMEX> , that slice includes fantasy, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fairy</ENAMEX> tale connections,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">sultry musical interludes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridges</ENAMEX> that lead out, and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridges</ENAMEX> that lead
nowhere. The movie, one of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX>'s most pleasant surprises, is the
antithesis of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Todd Solondz</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Happiness</ENAMEX> , a humanist's answer to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Solondz</ENAMEX>'s
evident conviction that life is all dead ends. When her cardiologist <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Donovan</ENAMEX>) leaves her, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judith Nelson</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holly Hunter</ENAMEX>) goes out into the
world, her pain making her receptive to everything and everyone--from the
elevator <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danny DeVito</ENAMEX>) who returns her friendship with uninvited
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">amorousness</ENAMEX> to the torch <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singer</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Queen Latifah</ENAMEX>) who takes her to after-hours
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">clubs</ENAMEX>, where she dances ecstatically with young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>. Living Out Loud
becomes an ode to openness, to letting in everything that the world throws at
you. The movie made me remember why I like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holly Hunter</ENAMEX>. (I don't always
remember.) Her delivery isn't moist--it's prickly and blunt, and she can jabber
convincingly, so that the jabbering takes on a life of its own and leaves her
(sometimes horrified) in the dust. I might even vote for her.

         
      
   
