
   
   
      
         
            The C Word

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Cynics</ENAMEX> think postelection
spin is just a one-dimensional game of manipulating expectations and persuading
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> that you surpassed them. For the most part, that's true. But spin can
also be profound. It can address more than who's up and who's down. It can
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">redefine people</ENAMEX>, issues, and events by rotating their facets so that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> see
them from new perspectives. For this reason, the contest of interpretation that
consumes the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24 hours</TIMEX> after an election is as important as the election itself.
It defines the election and its mandate.

            This is
what's happening to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican Party</ENAMEX> in the wake of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s elections. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> has built a career and a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">movement</ENAMEX> by manipulating
terms such as "liberal" and "welfare state" to caricature and marginalize his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX>. Now the tables are turned. The word "conservative" is being
manipulated by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX> and the media to caricature and marginalize
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>. If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> isn't careful, the C word could go the way of the L
word, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> could go the way of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX>.

            Around <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Election Night</ENAMEX>, under fire from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX>
over the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>'s mounting disappointments, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">flacks</ENAMEX> began falling back
on their safest success story: the victories of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeb Bush</ENAMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> gubernatorial races. This defensive maneuver quashed one
dangerous story line--"Why are all the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> losing<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>"--at the expense of
opening another: "Why are all the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> except the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> losing<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>"

            The media
took up this question and, over <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the next two hours</TIMEX>, hammered out a consensus:
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Moderate</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> were winning, while "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ideologues</ENAMEX>" were losing. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> became <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Exhibits A and B.</ENAMEX> As network <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">anchors</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> batted around and
refined the theory, the previously sacrosanct C word began to creep into the
discussion, alongside "right-wing" and "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">extremist</ENAMEX>." "Bad night for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX>," declared <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Jennings</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Schneider</ENAMEX> contrasted
the success of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>'s moderate "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governors</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wing</ENAMEX>" with the defeat of "the
congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wing</ENAMEX> that's been dominated by conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ideologues</ENAMEX>." By
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Plante</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX> were recycling the
conventional wisdom that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">losers</ENAMEX> were "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX>."

            
Political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">factions</ENAMEX> on all sides encouraged this
theory. Moderate <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudy Giuliani</ENAMEX>, angling for
advantage within the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>, touted the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> as evidence that the party
should spread "a broader tent." Gloomy conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX>, eager to finger
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">culprits</ENAMEX>, accused congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> of having provoked needless
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hostility</ENAMEX>.

            The three
most accomplished spinners of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> egged on the conflict. On
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike McCurry</ENAMEX> predicted that "right-wing <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>" in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> wouldn't
take kindly to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>'s "conservatism with a compassionate face." This
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">deliciously</ENAMEX> backhanded phrase--an allusion to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Czechoslovakia</ENAMEX>'s "socialism with
a human face," which was crushed by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">tanks</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1968</TIMEX>--conveyed three
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">corrosive</ENAMEX> messages: that conservatism lacked compassion to begin with, that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> couldn't tolerate compassion, and that for this reason,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">conservatism</ENAMEX>, like socialism, was doomed. On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nightline</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX> predicted a "civil war" between "the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">moderates</ENAMEX>," citing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">Bushes</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governors</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">latter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faction</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rahm Emanuel</ENAMEX> predicted that "the extreme right" would tighten
its control over the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">moderates</ENAMEX>." Before <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night</TIMEX> was over, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennings</ENAMEX> was
asking whether "we're going to see a real power struggle now between moderate
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governors</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>," and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> analyst <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX>
Will was predicting a showdown in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>, with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">moderates</ENAMEX> rallying around <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">W. Bush</ENAMEX>.

            If the consensus interpretation of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> elections is
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">moderates</ENAMEX> won and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> lost--and that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> represent
what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">moderates</ENAMEX> are and what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> aren't--then conservatism, as a word
and as a philosophy, is in deep trouble. This is what happened to liberalism
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two decades ago</TIMEX>: It became associated with everything on the left that seemed
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">immoderate</ENAMEX>. If, conversely, conservatism were to become associated with
everything on the right that seems immoderate <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, the list would include the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> investigation, moral intolerance, racism, and disregard for the material
concerns of ordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.

            These were
precisely the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX> pasted on conservatism in the decisive <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> after
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s elections. TV <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> repeatedly identified
conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ideologues</ENAMEX> with the impeachment inquiry. They portrayed the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coalition</ENAMEX> as conservatism's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">standard-bearer</ENAMEX>, declared the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">coalition</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates losers</ENAMEX>, and contrasted this with the success of "the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">centrist</ENAMEX>,
pragmatic <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governors</ENAMEX>." They exalted the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX>' outreach to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hispanics</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, and implied that other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> had written
off these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orrin Hatch</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX>, agreed on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nightline</ENAMEX> that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> had neglected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minorities</ENAMEX>. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russert</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cokie Roberts</ENAMEX> were chiding the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> for confining its appeals
to white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>.

            
Just as liberalism was reduced to a synonym for
weakness, conservatism is being reduced to a synonym for meanness. Even the
defeat of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al D'Amato</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.Y.</ENAMEX>, who was renowned for gobbling up federal
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pork</ENAMEX> and was endorsed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s leading gay rights group, is being
celebrated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> as "a public verdict on the
bare-knuckle style of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republicanism</ENAMEX> that has become the fashion in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>,"
in contrast to the "conciliatory style" of "moderate" <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>. Worse yet,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX>' enthusiasm for the impeachment inquiry and for moral issues in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">general</ENAMEX> is being framed as a distraction from <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">material</ENAMEX> concerns such as health
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">care</ENAMEX>, education, and retirement security. On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> show <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russert</ENAMEX> declared the gubernatorial contest in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alabama</ENAMEX> "a very
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">instructive race</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fob James</ENAMEX>, according to business <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> down
there, emphasized prayer in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> rather than jobs for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> who graduate from
school." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russert</ENAMEX> concluded, "The perception is [that] <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> are
more interested in cultural issues, in philosophy and ideology, than they are
in the pragmatic performance of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governors</ENAMEX>."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">maestro</ENAMEX> of demonization, recognizes this unfolding catastrophe and is
desperately trying to avert it. He appeared on every network <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> to
insist that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> and other victorious <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governors</ENAMEX> such as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Pataki</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John Rowland</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Connecticut</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tommy Thompson</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wisconsin</ENAMEX>), and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Engler</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michigan</ENAMEX>) were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX>. He argued that
these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governors</ENAMEX> shared the congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> agenda enshrined in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">1994 Contract With America</ENAMEX>. "Every single one of them is a tax-cutting,
reform-the-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> declared on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>. The
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>, at his postelection news conference, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> accused the media
of misrepresenting the victorious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governors</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">moderates</ENAMEX> rather than
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX>. And he pointed out that indisputably conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> had
won contests, such as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> races in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kentucky</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> has a point. In their haste to proclaim <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s
elections a repudiation of conservatism, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> have oversimplified some
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">winners</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">moderates</ENAMEX> and some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">losers</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX>. Results that don't fit
the theory, such as the defeat of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Fong</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> race, have
simply been ignored--as has the fact that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> retained their
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">majorities</ENAMEX> in both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX>. Meanwhile, plenty of other good explanations have
been offered for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>'s setbacks. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> think <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>
alienated conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> by giving up on tax cuts and caving in to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
in the budget negotiations. Others blame <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> for muting substantive
conservative issues such as education reform in a misguided wager that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> scandal would bring conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> to the polls. Others blame the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>'s scandal ads for stirring up <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>.

            Poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt</ENAMEX>. What's being done
to him and his conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">allies</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> is just as unfair as what they've
spent their careers doing to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX>. And just as effective.

            
               Recent
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Frame Games</ENAMEX>"
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Election Night</ENAMEX>
Excuses": <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Saletan</ENAMEX> analyzes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> classic postelection spins.
(posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday, Nov. 2, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap Ad</ENAMEX>
War": Why the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>'s new ads are too clever by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>. (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, Oct.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

         
      
   
