
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">146</NUMEX>:

            By <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cohen</ENAMEX>

            
               Fill in
the blank. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rolf-Ernst Breuer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Deutsche Bank</ENAMEX>, may acquire
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bankers Trust</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$9 billion</NUMEX> despite declaring, "Our motto is
'__________ <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>.' "
            

            by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon ET</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> to e-mail your answer to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.

            
               Responses
to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>'s question (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 145</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Standard Features"</ENAMEX>--
            

            
               I give
the headline, you give the story. From <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">London Evening</ENAMEX>
Standard : "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Blow to Singer With No Sideways</ENAMEX>."
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cocaine</ENAMEX> delivery to rock
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">stars</ENAMEX> has become so urgent that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couriers</ENAMEX> are being given terse, even
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">breathless</ENAMEX>, instructions to make no detours."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Shade</ENAMEX>
            

            "Seamstress Trudie
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newell-Poit of Wainscotting</ENAMEX>, disgusted at her sewing machine's poor
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cross-stitching</ENAMEX>, smashed it with a sledgehammer in Piccadilly
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Circus</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew</ENAMEX> "Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Girl</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Solovay</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Snow</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Martin</ENAMEX>
Willett , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Smith</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karla Nedel</ENAMEX> had similarly
stitcherific answers.)

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A West End hooker who</ENAMEX>
once had noted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novelist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isaac Bashevis Singer</ENAMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">client</ENAMEX> offers reminiscences
of her technique."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Carvell</ENAMEX> (similarly literary, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simon</ENAMEX> )

            "English translations of
Welsh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> names."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doug Ingram</ENAMEX>
            

            "Don't they know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karen</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carpenter</ENAMEX> is dead?"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wendy Casey</ENAMEX>
            

            Click for more
responses.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
            

            Most responses played with
pop star excesses. Listed like that, it's clear that our rock 'n' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rollers</ENAMEX> have
compiled a sadly unimaginative roster of debauchery, largely relying on sex and
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>--those <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">tired horses</ENAMEX> of the dissolution troika. How square. How
disappointing. Even the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, that drab national <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>, has been accused of
similarly unsurprising antics. Where's the youthful <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Byronic</ENAMEX> madness, the
heedless Lucullan feast of endangered bald eagles slow roasted over flaming <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">da</ENAMEX>
Vinci drawings? Where's the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caligulan</ENAMEX> blood frolic? How uninspired is the
surgical selfishness of leaner noses and plumper bosoms. Where is the face
sleekened by cheek bones transplanted from a high-school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cheerleader</ENAMEX> kidnapped
off the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wichita</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kan.</ENAMEX>?

            I embrace
my middle-aged, middlebrow destiny, regularly dozing off around <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9:30</TIMEX> in front
of a Merchant-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ivory</ENAMEX> movie on public television. Would that our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rockers</ENAMEX> were as
accomplished at embodying their own philosophy. You'd think they'd have some
pride in workmanship.

            
               Opera
Ration Answer
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Opera</ENAMEX> diva <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jessye Norman</ENAMEX> lost
her bid to sue for libel over a "vulgar and undignified" quip about her
size.

            A story in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Classic</ENAMEX> CD
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">magazine</ENAMEX> said that when the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">53-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singer</ENAMEX> became trapped in swinging doors
on the way to a concert and was advised to turn sideways to release herself,
she replied, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Honey</ENAMEX>, I ain't got no sideways."

            Miss <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman</ENAMEX> said the remark,
which she insists she never made, held her up to ridicule, mockery, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">contempt</ENAMEX>, and conformed to a "degrading racist stereotype of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-American</ENAMEX> heritage."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lord</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Gibson</ENAMEX> ruled that these words could never convey that defamatory
meaning: "I could have wished Miss <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman</ENAMEX> had told the hoary old joke contained
in the subject of this libel action as it would have shown that, in addition to
possessing the remarkable vocal and dramatic talents which have made her
world-famous as a distinguished opera <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singer</ENAMEX>, she had an engaging sense of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">humour</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Unhappily</ENAMEX>, she has taken offence at the false attribution to her of the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> words."

            
               Season's
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Greetings Extra</ENAMEX>
            

            It's not too soon to order
those holiday cards, and there's a colorful, inexpensive, and sinister
"<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s most aggressive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defender</ENAMEX> of firearms ownership."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brasco</ENAMEX> greeting cards
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$11.95</NUMEX> a dozen) feature various pictures of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brasco</ENAMEX> (TM) the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liberty Bear,</ENAMEX>
first seen in the coloring book (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5.95</NUMEX>) designed by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erik Zelman</ENAMEX>,
the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> (?) of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aaron Zelman</ENAMEX>, executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JPFO</ENAMEX>. " 'Inoculate'
your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> from the anti-gun lies being taught as education in our schools
and in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mass</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Media</ENAMEX>."

            If you think about it, it's
nice that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aaron</ENAMEX> has taken his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> into the family gun nuttery business. If you
don't think about it too hard.

            Among the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brasco</ENAMEX> greeting
cards:

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Some Laws Are Bad</ENAMEX>": Brasco
the firearm ownership preservation bear wears a yellow cowboy suit and carries
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">rifle</ENAMEX>. This could refer to the kosher laws that put pork <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chops</ENAMEX> out of bounds,
but I doubt it.

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Firearms Can Be Fun</ENAMEX>": Brasco
proudly shows his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">target</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>. Both have <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">rifles</ENAMEX>; both wear ear <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protectors</ENAMEX>.
They may be gun nuts, but they're still health conscious.

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dialing 911 Can Be Useless":</ENAMEX>
A nervous looking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brasco</ENAMEX> holds the phone; his bathrobe-wearing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> holds a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX>.
Outside the window lurks a bad bear with an eye patch. Apparently the bad bear
didn't show as much concern for eye/ear protection as do <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brasco</ENAMEX> and his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>.

            "The
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> Want <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Your Guns</ENAMEX>": A sadistic <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> prison <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guard</ENAMEX> bear deliberately
spills a cup of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> just out of reach of a very thirsty <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brasco</ENAMEX> on the floor
of his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX>. I don't begin to understand the ideological assumptions behind
this one, but if I had any connection to those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Berenstein Bears</ENAMEX>, I'd be talking
to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>.

            This <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milwaukee</ENAMEX> organization
also does an odd and scary line of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> gun nut T-shirts. Order or get more
information at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">jpfo</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">org</ENAMEX>.

             

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Disclaimer</ENAMEX>: All submissions will become the property of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> and
will be published at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> 's discretion. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> may publish your
name on its site in connection with your submission.
            

         
      
   
