
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Dolce</ENAMEX> Vita

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara Kopple</ENAMEX>'s recent,
ironically titled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wild Man Blues</ENAMEX> chronicled the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> tour of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woody</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dixieland</ENAMEX> jazz <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">band</ENAMEX>. Those who endured it (I felt caged, which
might have been <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kopple</ENAMEX>'s intent) saw the celebrity polite but frozen-faced as
star struck <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">well-wishers</ENAMEX> attempted to make conversation with him, then moaning
that he wished he could be back in his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> or editing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>. I'm
not sure if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen</ENAMEX> was ever a public <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>, but his social skills have visibly
eroded after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25 years</TIMEX> of self-imposed isolation--of hiding behind his wealth
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrity</ENAMEX>. If anyone was not in a position to give us insight into
the corrosive vacuity of our culture it's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen</ENAMEX>, who's so out of touch that he
reportedly cast <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kirstie Allen</ENAMEX> in his last film, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deconstructing Harry</ENAMEX> ,
without ever having seen <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cheers</ENAMEX> , and whose idea of sexual audacity in
his new one is to have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hooker</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bebe Neuwirth</ENAMEX>, another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX> he never saw on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cheers</ENAMEX> ) teach a repressed hysteric (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judy Davis</ENAMEX>) how to give a blow job
by sliding a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">banana</ENAMEX> in and out of her mouth.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen</ENAMEX>
doesn't go to big premieres or <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Academy Award</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Celebrity</ENAMEX> is
his idea of what he's missing. The movie, which was the celebrity studded
opening <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> attraction of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">New York Film Festival</ENAMEX> and will soon arrive at
a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">theater</ENAMEX> near you, is more entertaining than it ought to be--but then, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen</ENAMEX>
has evolved into a first-rate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Ebert</ENAMEX> ridiculed
something I wrote about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deconstructing Harry</ENAMEX> : "The result is more
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rambunctious</ENAMEX>--and more fun--than any movie he has made in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. What puzzles
me is why it still adds up to something so anemic and coldly distasteful." It's
always nice to be noticed, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ebert</ENAMEX>'s implication--that it's silly to be
conflicted about the work of an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>, even one whose technical and emotional
smarts have matured at different rates--is willfully obtuse. As a piece of
cinema music, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Celebrity</ENAMEX> is limpid and graceful, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sven Nykvist</ENAMEX>'s
black-and-white photography gives the images a luster that's often
exhilaratingly at odds with the degeneracy being portrayed. Episode after
episode has a pleasing shape, with wittily protracted takes and on the button
punch lines. But--here we go again, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger</ENAMEX>!--I found the movie cheap, muddled,
and thoroughly devoid of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">insight</ENAMEX>. (If you think I'm divided on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger</ENAMEX>,
you should hear me on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>.)

            The picture's entree into this dolce vita is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kenneth</ENAMEX>
Branagh as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee Simon</ENAMEX>, a celebrity-profiling magazine <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> and failed novelist
who's also peddling an action screenplay ("but with a strong personal crisis").
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX> comes on to virtually every beautiful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> he meets and has an amazing
amount of success for someone so otherwise unsuccessful and so thickened with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dissipation</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Branagh</ENAMEX> plays the part with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woody Allen</ENAMEX> stammer--maybe the
dumbest creative decision he has made since casting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert De Niro</ENAMEX> as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frankenstein</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monster</ENAMEX>. As written, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> has no <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Branagh</ENAMEX>'s
mimetic turn allows him to skip along the surface of the part while <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> whisper, "He sounds like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woody Allen</ENAMEX>!" <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nearly 30 years ago</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen</ENAMEX>
wrote a brilliant short story about a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who goes to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> to visit a
dying acquaintance and then returns on a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> basis, portraying himself as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">saint</ENAMEX>, because he has the hots for the attending <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurse</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen</ENAMEX> brings the same
lacerating self-hatred to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protagonist</ENAMEX> here, but with no new wisdom; forced
to explain himself, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX> can only stammer incoherently. In <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Long Day's Journey</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Into Night</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eugene O'Neill</ENAMEX> has <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edmund Tyrone</ENAMEX>, his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alter ego</ENAMEX>, announce,
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stammering</ENAMEX> is the native eloquence of us fog <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>." For <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen</ENAMEX>, stammering is
the acquired eloquence of obfuscators. His fog is self-induced.

            It's also
protective. The very idea of public culture seems to fill him with dread, and
it's hard to think of a single piece of meaningful social intercourse in the
entire movie. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> are bimbos or phonies or--worst of
all!--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lee</ENAMEX>'s jittery <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ex-wife</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Davis</ENAMEX>), turns the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of a sweet
producer (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Mantegna</ENAMEX>), who puts her on television to interview billionaire
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vulgarians</ENAMEX> and exhibitionistic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">freaks</ENAMEX>. She becomes a celebrity and achieves
solidity, while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX> remains arrested--chasing glassy-eyed supermodels and flaky
twentysomething actresses. He is in a star-studded hell.

            
For someone so appalled by celebrity, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen</ENAMEX>
exploits it deftly, casting big-name <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> to fill out parts that would
otherwise be recognized as pathetically underwritten. In <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Celebrity</ENAMEX> , he
gets a lot of mileage out of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX> (playing yet another poetically
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">discombobulated</ENAMEX> basket case--gorgeously), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Winona Ryder</ENAMEX> (even more breathtaking
in black-and-white), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mantegna, Famke Janssen, Gretchen Mol</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melanie Griffith</ENAMEX>
(giving <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX> a blow job), and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leonardo DiCaprio</ENAMEX> as a hotel <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> trashing, pretty
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy superstar</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen</ENAMEX> gets more than he deserves from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">DiCaprio</ENAMEX>, whose brief
appearance is the highlight of the picture. He's meant to embody everything
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">shallow</ENAMEX> and psychotic about stardom (the conception is out of tabloid tales of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnny Depp</ENAMEX>), but the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> has never looked as beautiful, with the chiseled
insolence of a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elvis Presley</ENAMEX> and the bearing of a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> god. Every idea
in the sequence is banal, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DiCaprio</ENAMEX> reminds you why movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> sometimes
deserve to be worshipped.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Perpetually</ENAMEX> dissatisfied, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen</ENAMEX>'s protagonist hops from one fabulous babe to
another but never comes close to wholeness. His one attempt at something
solid--a novel--is vindictively destroyed by a jilted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lover</ENAMEX>. (There's only one
copy--a device that was stale <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a century ago</TIMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hedda Gabler</ENAMEX> burned Ejlert
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lovborg</ENAMEX>'s manuscript and in the age of word processors is just inane.) In
linking <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX>'s self-destructiveness to the culture in which he's enmeshed, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen</ENAMEX>
reminds me of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX>, who blamed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Smith</ENAMEX>'s drowning of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> and the counterculture, before it was revealed that the young
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">woman</ENAMEX>'s disturbed psyche had more to do with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">nocturnal</ENAMEX> visits of her
stepfather, a higher-up in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican Party</ENAMEX>. In one sequence, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen</ENAMEX>
ridicules plastic surgeons and the aging, wealthy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who cling and kowtow to
them. This from a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> in his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid-60s</TIMEX> who casts himself opposite increasingly
younger starlets, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who argues that taking up with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> barely out of her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teens</ENAMEX> is a mark of purity! <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen</ENAMEX>'s sanctimoniousness makes me understand why
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> trash hotel <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX>.

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Celebrity</ENAMEX> , the protagonist peddles a script about
"an armored car robbery, but with a strong personal crisis." That sounds a
little like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronin</ENAMEX> , which has won rave reviews for its poker-faced
depiction of rootless professional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assassins</ENAMEX> (among them <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert De Niro</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jean Reno</ENAMEX>) who get double- and triple- and quadruple-crossed and come to
question the meaning of their existence. Well, not really: The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> gets
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">double-crossed</ENAMEX>, too, in the climax, but by then so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have had their
heads casually blown off that it's hard to care who's doing what to whom and
why. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Directed</ENAMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veteran</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Frankenheimer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ronin</ENAMEX> doesn't have the
shorthand syntax of a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">'90s</NUMEX> thriller. It has a gritty feel and a tight,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">methodical</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-thing-after-another tempo. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Bystanders</ENAMEX> are mowed down, innocent
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are blown away, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> go careening down twisty <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Frankenheimer</ENAMEX> just keeps barreling ahead, substituting noise and brutality for
a point of view. (Or does he want us to think that his emotionless linearity is
an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Existential</ENAMEX> point of view?) I was absorbed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ronin</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an hour</TIMEX> or
so, but gradually realized that I was wearing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">De Niro</ENAMEX>'s dyspeptic scowl. A
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Maalox</ENAMEX> thriller.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clay Pigeons</ENAMEX> gets off
to a jolly start before petering out into hiply modernist irresolution. Both
violent and absurd, it features a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Joaquin Phoenix</ENAMEX>) who's guilty of a
sexual indiscretion but gets more than he bargained for when the distraught
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mistress</ENAMEX> commits suicide and makes it look like a murder
committed by--guess who? Pretty soon <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Phoenix</ENAMEX> is under suspicion for a whole
bunch of killings he didn't commit, including those of a prolific serial
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">killer</ENAMEX>. The film, smoothly directed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Dobkin</ENAMEX>, has a neat farcical
structure but is too in love with its overly tight-lipped <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protagonist</ENAMEX> and
deadpan pacing. See it for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jeneane Garafolo</ENAMEX> as a sour, sarcastic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vince Vaughn</ENAMEX> as a rhinestone cowboy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">trucker</ENAMEX> whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">unlined</ENAMEX> face and bland
bonhomie grow more hilariously creepy with each passing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">corpse</ENAMEX>.

            
               What <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dreams May Come</ENAMEX>
weds an epic, sometimes visionary, depiction of the afterlife to a script and
story with fewer psychological layers than the average <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hallmark</ENAMEX> card. Featuring
the random deaths of young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, fatal automobile accidents, a suicide, and
a lot of after-death romping amid watercolored lilies, it's about as deadly as
a movie can be without literally emitting <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mustard gas</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
