
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft Trial</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> antitrust
trial opened <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>, and it wasn't hard to figure out the theme of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX>'s case. "On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Day 1</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Targets Gates</ENAMEX>," declared the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> 's front-page headline: "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Government Portrays Microsoft</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cagey, Ruthless</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> called the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOJ</ENAMEX>'s
opening statement "a pointed personal attack on the credibility and integrity"
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Boies</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOJ</ENAMEX>'s lead <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX>, focused his statement on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">juxtaposing</ENAMEX> video clips of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX>' deposition, in which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX>
asserted his innocence, with e-mail messages and memos that allegedly
contradicted those assertions.

            For
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> has treated the antitrust case as a silly nuisance. Rather
than attack the case the way it has purportedly attacked its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> has largely ignored it, instead using its rebuttal opportunities to
proclaim itself a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producer</ENAMEX> of wonderful products and a dogged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">servant</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX>. In his opening statement <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> lead <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>
Warden associated the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> with "the march of progress driven by science and
technology."

            This narcissistic nice-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> act can't go on. In politics,
when you're attacked, you attack back. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> has demonstrated
the ugly efficacy of this strategy throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>
investigation. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekend</TIMEX> after the scandal broke, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> strategist
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Carville</ENAMEX> went on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> to declare "war" on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Independent</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Counsel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>. "The real focus here is on the methods [and] motives of
the independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carville</ENAMEX>. He accused <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> of "wiring" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in
hotel bars and plying them with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">whiskey</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Two days later</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX> called
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> "a politically motivated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX> who is allied with the right-wing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>." This line of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">attack</ENAMEX>, pursued relentlessly over the
following <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX>, destroyed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s credibility. By the time <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> sent his
report to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, polls indicated <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> the public placed no faith in his
findings.

            If
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> was to adopt the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> strategy, who would be its logical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">target</ENAMEX>?
Let's see. Whom does the DOJ portray as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s chief <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Netscape</ENAMEX>.
Whose <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> meeting with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> is the centerpiece of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOJ</ENAMEX>'s case?
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Netscape's</ENAMEX>. Whose notes from that meeting are the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOJ</ENAMEX>'s key evidence? Netscape
executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marc Andreessen</ENAMEX>'s. Who is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s opening <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX>? Netscape
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Barksdale</ENAMEX>. Which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s browser did the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOJ</ENAMEX> ask <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> to offer
to Windows <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">98</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Netscape's</ENAMEX>. And who has most aggressively lobbied the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOJ</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> to prosecute <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Netscape</ENAMEX>.

            
In its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 19</TIMEX> response to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barksdale</ENAMEX>'s written
testimony, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> signaled an increasing willingness to go on the attack.
"Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barksdale</ENAMEX>'s inflammatory comments about the [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>] meeting [are]
misleading and self-serving comments from a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that is trying to attack
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> interference, rather than by competing in the
marketplace," charged <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>. "Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barksdale</ENAMEX> apparently believes that
government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> know better than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX>, when it comes to
which browser is the best. ... Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barksdale</ENAMEX> appears to believe that the
government should protect <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Netscape</ENAMEX> from the rigors of free market competition."
On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 20</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s media relations Web page steered <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> to a
Times op-ed that called Netscape "a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX> of predatory pricing."

            Why <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> has previously
eschewed this approach is anyone's guess. (
                  Slate
                has no inside
information on this question.) Maybe the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> feared it would sully its
image by openly slinging <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mud</ENAMEX> at a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitor</ENAMEX>. Maybe it wanted to deprive
Netscape of all publicity, including bad publicity. Maybe it thought the
antitrust case was legal rather than political and that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> were the only
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> that matters. The best bets are: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> thought itself so
obviously virtuous that it didn't need to defend its conduct. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) Since
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> understands business far better than politics, it treated the
antitrust fight as though it were just another marketing campaign.

            Well, it
isn't. For all its fearsomeness as an economic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> has yet to
appreciate that the weapons it is now facing--embarrassing memos and video
clips--are the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> of politics, not of business. Welcome to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, Mr.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX>.

            
               Recent
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Frame Games</ENAMEX>"
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace</ENAMEX>
Therapy": Is the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> deal a new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapter</ENAMEX> or a reminder of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX>?
(posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday, Oct. 28, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">St.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew"</ENAMEX>: The
political use of a gay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s gruesome death. (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, Oct. 16</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>)
            

         
      
   
