
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Positively Fourth-Rate</ENAMEX>

            All forms of appreciation
suffer from a tendency toward one-upmanship. There are theater <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buffs</ENAMEX> who will
only recommend a play that has just closed. There are art <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lovers</ENAMEX> who rave about
paintings locked in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">basement</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hermitage</ENAMEX>. But to my mind, there are no
aficionados more annoying than music <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mavens</ENAMEX> who prattle on about bootlegs. What
a coincidence that the really great records are the ones you can't get.

            The most
obsessive bootleg hounds are those devoted to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dylan</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Week after week</TIMEX>, the
otherwise delightful <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Rosenbaum</ENAMEX> fills his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Observer</ENAMEX> columns
with paeans to recordings you can't hear, some of which even he hasn't heard,
recordings that may not, in fact, even exist. To <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> of history <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sean</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilentz</ENAMEX>, writing in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dissent</ENAMEX> , the best Dylan song of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX> was the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">unreleased</ENAMEX> (until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>) "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Blind Willie McTell</ENAMEX>." The worst offender, bar none, is
rock <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greil Marcus</ENAMEX>, who recently wrote a whole book, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Invisible</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> , in praise of the most famous of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dylan</ENAMEX> bootlegs, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Basement</ENAMEX>
Tapes. These recordings, which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dylan</ENAMEX> made with <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Band</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1967</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Woodstock</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.Y.</ENAMEX>, circulated clandestinely until <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia</ENAMEX> finally released a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> LP
selection in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1975</TIMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ihappen</ENAMEX> to think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marcus</ENAMEX> is right about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Basement</ENAMEX>
Tapes--they're the exception to the rule of overrated bootlegs. Where he is
less persuasive is in his conviction that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia Records</ENAMEX> is still holding
back <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dylan</ENAMEX>'s best work. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marcus</ENAMEX> devotes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> pages of his book to the
magnificence of a song titled "I'm Not There," which is so underground it isn't
even on the illegal <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Basement Tapes bootlegs</ENAMEX>. "There is nothing like 'I'm Not
There' ... in the rest of the basement recordings or anywhere else in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bob</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dylan</ENAMEX>'s career," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marcus</ENAMEX> writes, comparing it to the last page of Moby
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick</ENAMEX> . The real point, of course, is that try as you might, you'll never
hear this song.

            Why do
these 50ish <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> obsess like this about lost <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dylan</ENAMEX> recordings? <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> reason is
that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dylan</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX> whose output in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1960s</TIMEX> was so voluminous that no
record <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> could keep up with it. Before he finished cutting an album, he'd
have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half a dozen</NUMEX> new songs to try to squeeze in. <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">On Bob Dylan: The Bootleg</ENAMEX>
Series, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Volumes 1-3</ENAMEX> , which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia</ENAMEX> released in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>, you can hear the best
of those that didn't make it. These include the uplifting, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Guthrie</ENAMEX>-esque anthem
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Paths of</ENAMEX>
Victory" and the Shakespearean ballad "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Seven Curses"</ENAMEX> (a
version of the story in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Measure for</ENAMEX> 
               Measure ), both of which were
bumped from <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Times They Are A-Changin'</ENAMEX>. These are fine songs, well
worth hearing. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dylan</ENAMEX> left them off to make room for songs such as "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">When the Ship Comes</ENAMEX>
In" and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">One Too Many Mornings"</ENAMEX>--masterpieces of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> popular music
that I expect <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> will be singing and listening to in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a hundred years</TIMEX>. Dylan
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1960s</TIMEX> was writing at such a pitch of inspiration that even his
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">second-rate material</ENAMEX> is pretty fine.

            
But the release of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dylan's</ENAMEX> second-rate material
has only caused his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> to bay louder for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">third-rate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dylan</ENAMEX>. The hype is
encouraged by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia</ENAMEX>, which profits by releasing more and more unfinished
songs, rejected versions, live recordings--and before long, voice mail
messages--from its <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">vaults</ENAMEX>. Evidence that the law of diminishing returns has set
in is provided by the latest archival release, the so-called <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1966</TIMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royal Albert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Hall Concert</ENAMEX>." For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">collectors</ENAMEX> have paid good money for unreliable copies
of this bootleg. Now the performance, which actually took place not at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royal Albert Hall</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> but in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manchester</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Free Trade Hall</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 17</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1966</TIMEX>, is out on a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> CD set, which is being sold as Volume <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> in the Dylan
"bootleg series."

            Critics
are legitimately fascinated with this concert, which occurred at a crucial
moment both in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dylan</ENAMEX>'s career and in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> cultural history. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dylan</ENAMEX> went from
protest-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folk</ENAMEX> to mod-rock around the same time the civil rights movement went
from nonviolence to black power, soft <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> turned to hard <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>, and so on.
The story begins <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nearly a year earlier</TIMEX>, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 1965</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dylan</ENAMEX> turned up with
an electric guitar at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newport</ENAMEX> Folk <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Festival</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enraging</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pete Seeger</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alan</ENAMEX>
Lomax, and various <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">followers</ENAMEX> of the folk revival, who were only interested in
"authenticity" and political dissent. (A hilarious, chilling document is the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Stalinist</ENAMEX>-sounding "open letter" published by folk music <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commissar</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Irwin Silber</ENAMEX>
in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sing Out</ENAMEX>! <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">magazine</ENAMEX>, in which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Silber</ENAMEX> accused <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dylan</ENAMEX> of abandoning
protest music for songs that were "inner-directed ... inner-probing,
self-conscious.")

            Dylan, though shaken by the fury of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX>, pressed
ahead, trading his work shirt and jeans for a velveteen <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nehru</ENAMEX> jacket and
playing amplified rock 'n' roll. During <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next year</TIMEX> he was booed at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nearly</TIMEX>
every stop in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Levon Helm</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drummer</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Hawks</ENAMEX>, which
was to become <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Band</ENAMEX>, was driven off the tour by the abuse. Dylan dealt with
the stress by ingesting huge quantities of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> and generally acting like a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bastard</ENAMEX>. At the end of the tour, he broke his neck in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">motorcycle</ENAMEX> accident. He
didn't perform live again until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1974</TIMEX>, by which point, of course, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '60s</TIMEX> were
over. A lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dylan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worshippers</ENAMEX> seem to fixate on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1965-66</TIMEX> as the moment before
the fall of the counterculture. Like <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX> obsessed with the
mistakes of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kerensky</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, they keep going over the familiar story,
wondering if things might somehow have turned out differently.

            The problem is that
especially after this buildup, the "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royal Albert Hall</ENAMEX>" bootleg is
disappointing. It was a reasonably good concert, but hardly an outstanding one.
As he did in every concert on that tour, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dylan</ENAMEX> soloed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first half</TIMEX> with
his acoustic guitar and harmonica and played electric guitar with his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX> in
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> was a concession to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX>, but it bored him
silly, and you can tell. The songs themselves are beautiful. His rendition of
"," which some read as his farewell to the folkies, is affecting, in its
drug-induced, nonsensical way. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dylan</ENAMEX>'s performance adds little to the
studio version, doing nothing to explicate the obscurities of the lyrics, such as
why "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Baby Blue</ENAMEX>" has reindeer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">armies</ENAMEX>, or where they're going home to. He strums
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">listlessly</ENAMEX> in this ponderous <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11 ½ minute</TIMEX> version of "." The gibberish about
Einstein sniffing drainpipes just reminds you that he was stoned senseless. A
truly dreary <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nine minute</TIMEX> rendition of "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mr. Tambourine Man</ENAMEX>" follows.

            The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>
half of the concert begins with a rousing song called "," which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dylan</ENAMEX> never
released on record, and which, after you've listened to the acoustic side, is
like watching a black-and-white movie turn to color. The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Band</ENAMEX>-to-be is tight
and focused, and there's less burden on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dylan</ENAMEX>'s quasinonsense
lyrics when they have <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garth Hudson</ENAMEX>'s organ behind them. It's amazing to
hear booing and loud slow clapping meant to prevent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dylan</ENAMEX> from playing an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">electric</ENAMEX> version of "." That's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick Danko</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bassist</ENAMEX>, singing harmony on the
word "behind," creating a perfect rock moment. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amazingly</ENAMEX>, half the audience
hated it. At the end of the set, someone in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> yells out the word "." To
which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dylan</ENAMEX>, after a pause, by sneering back the title of a song he just
played: "I Don't Believe You." Then after another pause he bellows, "" before
cranking into "Like a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rolling Stone</ENAMEX>." He played no encores.

            
The hostility and weirdness surrounding this
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tour</ENAMEX> also come across in Eat the 
               Document , a film that has been
showing at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum of Radio</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Television</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> to coincide with
the release of the record. <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">This hourlong</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">work</TIMEX>, which was commissioned by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>
but never shown, is another famous bootleg--it has circulated in
samizdat for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>--and also an overrated one. Coming after Don't
Look Back , the superb cinema vérité documentary <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D.A. Pennebaker</ENAMEX> made
about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dylan</ENAMEX>'s previous <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> tour in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1965</TIMEX>, Eat the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Document</ENAMEX> , which
was edited by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dylan</ENAMEX> himself, is a pointless coda. Other than the snippets of
concert footage and a few curious glimpses, it's a mishmash of drug-addled
camera confusion.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Overrating Bob Dylan</ENAMEX>'s
unpublished fragments probably won't do any damage to his real achievement. But
it is oddly disrespectful--like arguing that the rough draft of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Great</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gatsby</ENAMEX> was better than the novel <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">F. Scott Fitzgerald</ENAMEX> published. The
tendency to prefer obscure, unproduced recordings seems like the latest version
of the old folkie quest for the grail of authenticity. And it's equally
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">wrongheaded</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dylan</ENAMEX> sang his best songs on records that came out and became
instantly famous. Insisting otherwise makes him into a kind of idiot <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">savant</ENAMEX> who
could create but not choose. It elevates the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> and diminishes the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
