
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Back of Virtues</ENAMEX>

            During <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past year</TIMEX>, public
opinion about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Independent Counsel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>'s investigation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has polarized into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>. The right holds that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> has
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">valiantly</ENAMEX> defended justice and the rule of law against a scoundrel <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>.
The left dismisses <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> as a duplicitous, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">right-wing assassin</ENAMEX> bent on
destroying a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> who serves the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. It took <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> to discredit
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>. It took him <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a single day</TIMEX> to disprove the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>.

            It's
impossible to dismiss <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s testimony before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Judiciary Committee</ENAMEX> as
the performance of a villain. Through <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> of hectoring, cheap shots, and
generally ill-mannered behavior from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> kept his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">composure</ENAMEX> and courtesy. He absorbed the questions seriously, answered them in a
straightforward manner, and offered clear explanations for nearly every aspect
of his conduct that was brought into question. He seemed honest, kind,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">thoughtful</ENAMEX>, and fair--a perfect independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX>.

            And yet, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s investigation has been a moral disaster,
the equivalent of a high-speed chase in which an armada of police <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cruisers</ENAMEX>
crumples <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> and injures scores of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pedestrians</ENAMEX> in pursuit of a rowdy
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-ager</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gazing</ENAMEX> back at the wreckage, the interesting question is not the
crude choice posed on political chat shows--"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Starr</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hero or Villain?</ENAMEX>"--but
the subtler mystery more often explored in novels: How did such a good person
do such bad things? How does virtue become <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice</ENAMEX>?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s essential virtues are
his dedication to the truth, his respect for the law, and his solid moral
convictions. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> speaks, he looks like a confidence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> trying to
figure out which line to feed you. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> speaks, he looks like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> with
nothing to hide. If I were <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>, I'd never let him take a polygraph
test. If I were <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>, I'd pay for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nearly a year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> has
searched doggedly for the truth about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> affair, while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">henchmen</ENAMEX> have obstructed him.

            What we've
learned from this search is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> had a shameful affair with an intern
and covered it up--but also that the truth wasn't worth the search. In pursuit
of the truth, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> wired <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Tripp</ENAMEX> to record her young "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>."
They confronted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>, told her she could go to jail, and suggested she
would be unwise to call her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> or her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> tried to make a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">bookstore</ENAMEX> cough up records of her purchases. He sought to abridge the
attorney-client privilege by commanding <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vince Foster</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> to divulge what
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Foster</ENAMEX> had told the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> before committing suicide. He compelled <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret</ENAMEX>
Service <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> to testify about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s trysts. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s hunt for the
truth trampled privacy, loyalty, and security. At <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s hearing, he
conceded that his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> had investigated whether an unhelpful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX> might be
obliged legally to give up her adopted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>. "My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> work very hard
and diligently to find relevant evidence," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> offered.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> saw the black-and-white of truth and
falsehood but not the spectrum in between. He accused <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> of perjury--a
felony--in part for playing silly word games in his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">grand jury</ENAMEX> testimony. Never
mind that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> had confessed to the essential points: that he had engaged in
an inappropriate relationship with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> and had tried to hide it from Paula
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>. Convinced there could be only one truth, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> overlooked
others. He failed to see how what looked to him like a conspiracy to silence a
witness in a sexual harassment case could look to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> like a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">slapdash</ENAMEX> scheme to hush up an affair. And his report presented sexual truths
that serve no decent purpose.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s
confidence that he was obeying the law insulated him from examining his
behavior in moral terms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pressuring Lewinsky</ENAMEX> to secretly tape-record <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vernon Jordan</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betty Currie</ENAMEX> was distasteful but legal, so <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s agents
did it. "This is all traditional prosecutorial activity," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> asserted at the
hearing. Forcing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> to testify about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s sex
life was indecent and reckless but constitutional, so <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> did it. And leaking
to--or, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> put it, "briefing"--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> about the case on condition of
anonymity was sneaky and unfair, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> decided it was OK because it was
legally defensible. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Kendall</ENAMEX> challenged the
propriety of these briefings, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> dismissively replied, "You're asking
[about] press policy as opposed to constitutional issues."

            By all accounts, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> convictions. But
firm convictions also inhibit doubt, self-criticism, and learning. The moral
confidence that kept <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> admirably untroubled in the face of partisan insults
during his testimony left him equally untroubled by his own genuine errors.
Should he have quit the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitewater</ENAMEX> investigation after temporarily accepting a
job at a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX> funded by a notorious <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> hater? Gosh, no. So pure was
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s heart that he hadn't realized it would look bad. Later, when he sought
approval to investigate the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> affair, should he have disclosed that his
law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> had been contacted to represent <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> and that he had spoken to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> several times about constitutional aspects of their case? "It just
did not occur to me," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> candidly told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX>. Should he have
disclosed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months ago</TIMEX> that he had found no evidence of wrongdoing by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> files matter? Golly, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>, he hadn't thought it was necessary to
say so.

            Where
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> invokes false subjectivity ("It depends on what the meaning of the word
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'is'</ENAMEX> is"), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> invokes false objectivity. His favorite cloak is
"professionalism." Confronted with questions about the loaded language of his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">report</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> it was "a professional product." Unable to
distinguish his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ego</ENAMEX> from his credo, he accused <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> of obstructing justice
by asserting executive privilege against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s investigation. "It's our
professional judgment that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> engaged in abuse of his authority" by
so doing, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> testified. Given that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> were right,
anyone who saw things differently was wrong. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> suggested
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> had detained his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX> improperly, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> issued an equally
one-sided press release portraying the encounter as a joint shopping and dining
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">excursion</ENAMEX>. "I felt duty-bound to provide public information that I thought was
appropriate," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> testified. Likewise, his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> often briefed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> on
background because "we have the duty to engage in a proper public information
function," particularly "to combat <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">misinformation</ENAMEX>." When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kendall</ENAMEX> asked why
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> conducted these briefings on background rather than on the record,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> explained, "We do not want to in any way be part of [the] story." It
wasn't necessary to disclose that the "information" had come from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>, since his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> was above reproach.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> think these excesses and
failures make him a bad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>. But this inference oversimplifies <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>, just as
he oversimplified the scandal. If <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> are wrong to preach that the
lesson of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> was the unraveling of a morally bankrupt <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX>
are equally wrong to preach that the lesson was the unraveling of a morally
bankrupt <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s failures stemmed not from evil but from errant
good. That lesson won't suit either side's assumptions. But then, that's the
point of lessons.

            There is
another side to this paradox. Just as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s virtues turned vicious, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
vices sometimes turn virtuous. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lacking Starr</ENAMEX>'s faith in absolute truth, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
sees every side of every issue. That's how he absorbed and finessed <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> demands in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> peace process. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lacking Starr</ENAMEX>'s
confidence in the law, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> sees where the law is too blunt an instrument to
honor and promote good values. That's why his views on abortion and
homosexuality emphasize religious belief and personal responsibility rather
than legislative prohibition. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lacking Starr</ENAMEX>'s moral certitude, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
recognizes his own worst instincts and is capable of transcending them. That's
why he resisted the temptation to bomb <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 14</TIMEX>, when the political case
for it was open and shut, but the moral case was dubious. To heed the better
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">angels</ENAMEX> of your nature, you must know the devils <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>.

         
      
   
