
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Drawing upon her rich
experience of life, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> to her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>) responds to questions
about manners, personal relations, politics, and other subjects. Please send
your questions for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> to prudence@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Queries should not exceed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> words in
length. Please indicate how you wish your letter to be signed, preferably
including your location.
            

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Hello</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               I have
discovered that a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">34-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-worker</ENAMEX> believes in creationism. With all the
evidence pointing toward evolution, how can this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> accept it? The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">co-worker</ENAMEX>'s argument is that scientific evidence is not reliable because
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> usually change their position after new evidence is discovered. I
have tried various arguments to convince this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> but with no luck. How can
I convince him/her otherwise? Thank you.
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Darwin</ENAMEX>
            

            Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dar</ENAMEX>,

            How can
you convince this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>? You can't, and you should stop feeling this is your
job in life. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> cannot be moved from some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">positions</ENAMEX>, and that's just
the way it is. All scientific advance is done in small increments. The evidence
for natural selection as the guiding force for the evolution of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX> has
been accrued over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past 100 years</TIMEX> and is compelling. Your co-worker does not
understand scientific method and may belong to a religious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> that has
creationism as part of its credo. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> suggests you dismiss the inclination
to educate your office <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mate</ENAMEX>--and please don't open up any discussions about the
shape of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">earth</ENAMEX>.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, roundly

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hey</ENAMEX>
Prudie,
               
            

            
               Are your infrequent
updates due to your contract, an inscrutable sense of timing, or a lack of good
questions? I suppose the snarky answer would be "all of the above," but my real
agenda is to see your Q's and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A's</ENAMEX> more often, so I'll do my part and lob a plea
for advice.
            

            
               I still have a friendly
(like best-friendly, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soul mate</ENAMEX>, love of my life so far) relationship with a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who is somewhat capricious with her address and my heart. We are no
longer "together," but our relationship hasn't really changed except for no sex
and that she's dating and I'm supposed to be. I know I should move past her,
but no one I've ever met has had this effect on me, nor the rapport. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dating</ENAMEX> is
a pain, and sex with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strangers</ENAMEX> is iffy--not only because of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>, but also I've
been told that <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">hepatitis</ENAMEX> C (spread in the same ways as <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>) will kill more
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX>.
            

            
               What's
a modern <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> to do?
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frustrated</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L.A.</ENAMEX>
            

            Dear
Frus,

            Your poetically stated
problem gave <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> a pang of sadness. What you need, dear <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>, is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">acceptance</ENAMEX> of the way things have evolved: Your "it" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> stopped
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reciprocating</ENAMEX>. If you find the best-friendliness, sans sex, too painful a
reminder of loss, you might find it useful to let the relationship move into
memory by stopping contact. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> is not suggesting you adopt the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">national</ENAMEX> deformity of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>, the stiff upper lip, but that you steep yourself
in your regrets and then exit feeling stronger in the broken places.

            You are lucky in that now you
know what wonderful feels like. Such knowledge bodes well for finding it again
... this is something <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> can vouch for.

            Two little
afterthoughts: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) While <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> receives beaucoup de letters seeking
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX>, she would never discourage anyone from writing to ask advice. After
all, what's a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> for? <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) You are correct to be wary of sex with strangers
(and even <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> one knows).

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, solicitously

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               My
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> since high school--over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30 years ago</TIMEX>--has evolved into a very
conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>, unfortunately to the point of bigotry in my view. For
example, she is fearful that her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5-year-old</TIMEX> will someday date a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> of
another race, and she defends those who (as she puts it) "want to preserve
their traditions." She also continually complains about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX> of her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">maid</ENAMEX>. What puzzles me about her nattering on is this: She is well aware of my
opinions, which are completely opposed to hers--so why is she always gassing on
like this? What do you think? Thanks for your time.
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Sick of Listening</ENAMEX> to
This Crap
            

            Dear
Sick,

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">People</ENAMEX>
natter on about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX>, knowing there is disagreement, with a twofold agenda.
One is in the hope of changing someone's mind, the other is to needle ... in
effect saying, I am right. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> speaks from experience, being, herself, the
natterer on the subject of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. Prudie was bombarding a close
relative with material critical of Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. That is, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> did this until
the close <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relative</ENAMEX> said the genteel version of "knock it off." There are some
subjects about which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are unlikely to be swayed, and the friendly thing
to do is agree to disagree.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, agreeably

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               Yours
is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> column I read when I get <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">each</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> and was the single
deciding factor when I chose to buy in to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> . I'm not saying I agree
with you <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">100 percent</NUMEX> of the time, because that would be very boring, but we do
agree close to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">90 percent</NUMEX>. Anyway, you're my fave, so I hope this makes up for
the rude
letter from Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keck</ENAMEX>. She certainly could have been more polite in writing
to you.
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlie</ENAMEX>
McDannald <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort Walton Beach</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fla.</ENAMEX>

            Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlie</ENAMEX>,

            You were
kind to let <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> know of your solicitous sentiments. She has, happily,
recovered from the jolt registering <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6.2</NUMEX> on the hostility scale and understands
that into each life a little <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keck</ENAMEX> must fall.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>,
appreciatively

         
      
   
