
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bleak Houses</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Todd Solondz</ENAMEX>, the skinny guy
with the thick glasses and oddly passionate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drone</ENAMEX>, had an art-house smash in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> with Welcome to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dollhouse</ENAMEX> , which reinforced the perception that
art-house <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">smashes</ENAMEX> are pictures that take one bleak, uncommercial idea and
pummel you into a stupor with it. Telling the story of a myopic adolescent girl
who's persecuted by her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peers</ENAMEX> and slighted by her suburban <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> (which
reveres her pretty little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>, a goody-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-shoes in a tutu), Solondz
prolonged his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroine</ENAMEX>'s humiliations until I wanted to scream, "I GET IT
ALREADY!" He was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">maestro</ENAMEX>, all right, but of the sadistic kind, and the
movie's laughs didn't leaven its punishingly untranscendent misery--they
condensed it. This was the world as seen through glasses so thick they barely
let in light.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Solondz</ENAMEX>'s
new foray into misery, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Happiness</ENAMEX> , lays it on even thicker. This time,
however, he spreads the pain around, and he brings in sundry instruments to
share in the playing of his lone theme. The upshot defies categorization.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Happiness</ENAMEX> is an aching roundelay, a triumphantly benumbed ensemble farce
that mingles condescension and compassion in a manner that's disarmingly--and
often upsettingly--original.

            Before I go any further: You should know that I have
collaborated with the co-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producer</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Happiness</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christine Vachon</ENAMEX>, on a
new book called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Shooting to Kill</ENAMEX> , which may be ordered by clicking here.
(Just kidding. Wait <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a minute</TIMEX>, I'm not kidding. Click here before you do anything else.) I was around for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pre-production</ENAMEX> and made a few casting suggestions (politely ignored), went on a
stupefyingly dull "tech scout" with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> and key <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX>, watched some
scenes being shot, and got steady gossip from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christine</ENAMEX> that I can't share with
you although I might if you e-mail me proof that you've bought the book. I
thought about recusing myself, but I have no direct financial ties to the
picture and think it's one of the most interesting of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX>. Why should I
deprive myself?

            

               Happiness revolves around <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> who live some distance from a
large metropolis, but the relationship to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chekhov</ENAMEX> ends there. The place is
suburban <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX>. Sweet, tremulous <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joy Jordan</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane Adams</ENAMEX>), the youngest,
has turned <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30</TIMEX> and still lives in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mona</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louise Lasser</ENAMEX>)
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lenny</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben Gazzara</ENAMEX>), who have a condo in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> and are in the throes of a
vexingly tentative separation. Middle <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helen</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lara Flynn Boyle</ENAMEX>) is the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> of arty, titillating short stories and a magnet for studs and weight
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">lifters</ENAMEX>; she resides in a dim high-rise down the corridor from two unrelated
fatties, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kristina</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Camryn Manheim</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Philip Seymour Hoffman</ENAMEX>). The
latter, a compulsive obscene phone <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">caller</ENAMEX> who longs for his sleek, chic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">neighbor</ENAMEX>, is the psychiatric <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Maplewood</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dylan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Baker</ENAMEX>), who
happens to be the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helen</ENAMEX>'s older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>, chipper <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trish</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cynthia</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stevenson</ENAMEX>)--and also a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pedophile</ENAMEX> who, in the course of the film, drugs little
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> and has (off camera) sex with them.

            
Pedophilia, rape, murder, suicide,
dismemberment, obscene talk: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Happiness</ENAMEX> is about the sense of
incompleteness that these seemingly disparate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> carry inside them--and,
more important, the ways in which their prodigious longings manifest themselves
in their sexual predilections. And yet these kindred spirits almost never
acknowledge a connection. Their similarities don't mitigate their aloneness,
and talking about their problems doesn't help much, either. It's no accident
that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Solondz</ENAMEX>'s pedophile <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protagonist</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shrink</ENAMEX> and that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> who
get things off their chests go ahead and act on them anyway. There's no such
thing as catharsis: Come once, you'll want to come again and again and
again.

            The
pre-title sequence sets the drolly excruciating tone. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joy</ENAMEX> has just told <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andy</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jon Lovitz</ENAMEX>) that she thinks they should stop seeing each other. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Solondz</ENAMEX> goes
so tight on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lovitz</ENAMEX>'s ample flesh that he could sweat off the screen and onto
your lap. But as his strangled monosyllables give way to lavish verbal abuse
the shots go wider, so that we take in the romantic restaurant awash in fake
<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">plants</ENAMEX> and frippery--a setting that mocks this unhappy couple the way the
movie's very title hangs over it like a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mushroom</ENAMEX> cloud. Solondz keeps
Happiness right on the border between irony and empathy. The gags are
often easy, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> are in an authentic hell. And there isn't a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">trace</ENAMEX> of irony in the skinny, frazzled <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adams</ENAMEX>, who's as raw as a newly birthed
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">gazelle</ENAMEX>. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX> know how to exploit their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX>' vulnerabilities, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Solondz</ENAMEX> seems to have scraped off layers of his leading <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX>'s skin--it's so
translucent you can almost read her organs.

            At the other extreme, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hoffman</ENAMEX>, as one of the two fat
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX>, is encased in his flab like a tortured <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoner</ENAMEX> of war. His doleful
low tones and operatic mouth-breathing give even his vilest lines a dopey
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sweetness</ENAMEX>. In fact, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Solondz</ENAMEX> compels us to collude with even his most unsavory
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Baker</ENAMEX>'s pedophile is so furtive that he's almost immobile, but we
register the darting eyes under the bland, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodgers</ENAMEX>-like <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">façade</ENAMEX>, and as he
waits for a little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> to eat a drugged tuna sandwich, we hold our breaths the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> we did in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Psycho</ENAMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman Bates</ENAMEX> watched the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marian Crane</ENAMEX> almost not sink into the swamp. The only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> whose pain we
don't feel is also the only "normal" <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stevenson</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trish</ENAMEX>--a sugary,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">passive</ENAMEX>-aggressive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gargoyle</ENAMEX> who embodies everything that made some of us flee
the suburbs for the urban jungle.

            Not all of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Happiness</ENAMEX> is as consistently inspired. The scenes of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joy</ENAMEX> at work
(wanting to do good, she crosses a picket line to take a job teaching English
as a second <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">language</ENAMEX>) are coarsely conceived, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mona</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lenny</ENAMEX>,
don't exist on the same level as the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boyle</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helen</ENAMEX> is a thin
dirty joke rescued only by a good punch line (and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boyle</ENAMEX>, who drops her voice to
a husky whisper, looks wildly out of place in this clearly <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>). But
some of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-joke roles turn out to have more under the surface than is at
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> apparent. In one scene, fat <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kristina</ENAMEX> tells <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen</ENAMEX> about a horrible deed
she has committed and, while her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">listener</ENAMEX> attempts to process it, appalled,
tucks into an ice cream sundae. That might have been the cheapest kind of fat
gag, but because of the way it's shot and acted, our responses don't end with a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">snicker</ENAMEX>. We can see that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kristina</ENAMEX> is living a life of nightmarish deprivation,
and getting the only kind of pleasure that she knows.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Waters</ENAMEX> once said that he would like to
make a film that received an <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">X</NUMEX> or NC-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17</NUMEX> rating with no foul language or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">genitalia</ENAMEX>--"it would just be so offensive to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s values." Happiness
certainly has foul language, as well as a (brief) shot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joy</ENAMEX>'s uncovered
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">breasts</ENAMEX>, but what's truly shocking is its unblinking gaze--hard and clinical
but also nonjudgmental. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scenes in which Maplewood</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rufus Read</ENAMEX>) asks his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> about masturbation come close to being healthy . But the context is
too spooky, and the conversations creep into the red <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">zone</ENAMEX> when the father
offers to demonstrate his technique.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Solondz</ENAMEX>'s writing doesn't
cut very deep, but it does swing wide, smashing taboos on all sides--the film
is the dark side of There's <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Something About Mary</ENAMEX> . And in some ways, it
couldn't have had a more fitting launch. At the same time that the picture was
winning an international <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prize</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cannes Film Festival</ENAMEX> (where it
was shown outside the main <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competition</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Universal</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studio</ENAMEX> that financed it
(through its recently acquired "indie" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wing</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX>), unloaded it in a
panic--largely because its new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bronfmans</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seagram</ENAMEX>, feared being
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associated</ENAMEX> with a movie that featured a pedophile. That the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">booze</ENAMEX>-peddling
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bronfmans</ENAMEX> wanted nothing to do with a film that functions as the opposite of an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">intoxicant</ENAMEX> is the kind of irony with which Happiness teems.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX> did choose to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">release The Celebration</ENAMEX> , a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Danish</ENAMEX> dysfunctional family drama that treats
matters of incest and perversion with a tad more taste. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Children</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">siblings</ENAMEX>,
nieces, and nephews all gather at a prosperous estate to celebrate the
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">60 th</NUMEX> birthday of its formidable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patriarch</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henning Moritzen</ENAMEX>), who
turns out to have had monstrous designs on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of his own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. You've seen
this sort of picture before: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> get drunk and drag skeletons out of
closets, and the tension between the formal dinner party <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rituals</ENAMEX> and the truths
that simmer beneath the surface give way to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Walpurgisnacht</ENAMEX> . The
anti-patriarchal content is fairly routine, but you should see the movie anyway
because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Vinterberg</ENAMEX>, is a great, hypersensitive filmmaker
whose edgy, grainy, caught-on-the-fly camerawork seems to make the very
celluloid shiver with rage.

         
      
   
