
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Movies
            

            

               
                  Pleasantville
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Line Cinema</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> are lukewarm about this
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Truman Show</ENAMEX> knockoff. The premise: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> '90s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are transported into a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Father</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Knows Best</ENAMEX> -type sitcom and shake up its prissy black-and-white
world. Their latter-day innovations: emotion and--as a sign that an individual
has experienced it--color. This divides the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camps</ENAMEX>, color and
black-and-white, whereupon the film goes downhill. Rife with moral didacticism
and lapses in logic (how can the black-and-white mobs get so angry yet not
burst into color?), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pleasantville</ENAMEX> turns into a "leaden political
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">parable</ENAMEX>" about intolerance (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Morgenstern</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> ).
(This <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> site has a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pleasantville</ENAMEX> message <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX>.)

            
               
                  Apt
Pupil
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sony Pictures Entertainment</ENAMEX>). After <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bryan Singer</ENAMEX>'s
surprise hit <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Usual Suspects</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Apt Pupil</ENAMEX> is deemed a
disappointment. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-ager</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brad Renfro</ENAMEX>) discovers an old <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> war criminal
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ian McKellen</ENAMEX>) living under a false name in his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> and blackmails him into
giving detailed accounts of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> atrocities. Renfro offers up the "dead-eyed
sang-froid only a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suburbanite</ENAMEX> can pull off" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lisa Schwarzbaum</ENAMEX>,
Entertainment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly</ENAMEX> ), and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McKellen</ENAMEX> is called "a supremely gifted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX>
at the top of his form" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jay Carr</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Globe</ENAMEX> ). The film is said
to be uneven, though, and when you add directorial missteps to the
uncomfortable subject matter, the result is pans mixed with queasily laudatory
reviews. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Watch</ENAMEX> the trailer at the official
site.)

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Soldier</ENAMEX>
               
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner Bros.</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> call this painfully predictable and clichéd futuristic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sci-fi</ENAMEX> film a "mechanical, violent military-porn fantasy"(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schwarzbaum</ENAMEX>,
Entertainment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly</ENAMEX> ): <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shane</ENAMEX> meets <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Terminator</ENAMEX> meets
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Road Warrior</ENAMEX> . An extremely buff <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kurt Russell</ENAMEX> plays the title <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldier</ENAMEX> of
the future who, when decommissioned, is relegated to the horrors of the slag
heap planet, where he discovers human emotion and rises to the defense of his
fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">outcasts</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Soldier</ENAMEX> 's small number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> call it a "sanctimonious
kick-ass movie" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carr</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Globe</ENAMEX> ). (Visit the official site.)

            

               Books
            

            
               
                  King
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">World: The Rise of Muhammad Ali</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Remnick</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Random</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> takes on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the most
written-about sports <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figures</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> history and "succeeds, more than any
previous book, in bringing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ali</ENAMEX> into focus" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen Barra</ENAMEX>, the Wall Street
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> lavish praise on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Remnick</ENAMEX>, not just for his analysis of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ali</ENAMEX> but because he is said to have brilliantly invoked the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> intersection
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">boxing</ENAMEX> and race relations in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1960s</TIMEX>. (Explore this <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">gallery</ENAMEX> of photos of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ali</ENAMEX> that have appeared in the New York
Times . Free registration required.)

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Evening</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Minot</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Knopf</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reviewers adore Minot</ENAMEX>'s
"stunning" and "elegant and polished" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michiko Kakutani</ENAMEX>, the New York
Times ) new novel. The book enters the mind of a dying <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> and explores
her painkiller-enhanced memories of her one great encounter with love. Critics
agree that the novel lapses at times into "breathless overwriting" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David</ENAMEX>
Wiegland, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">San Francisco Chronicle</ENAMEX> ) but remains "a narrative of
considerable ambition and complexity" ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> ). (Read an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">excerpt</ENAMEX> and an interview with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> here.)

            
               
                  Bech
at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bay</ENAMEX>: A <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Quasi</ENAMEX>-Novel
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Updike</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Knopf</ENAMEX>). The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> installment in
the adventures of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Bech</ENAMEX>, an aging urban <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>, is deemed "one of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Updike</ENAMEX>'s less ambitious works" but still "filled with pleasures" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian Morton</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Tribune</ENAMEX> ). Although said to be occasionally self-indulgent,
this collection of interconnected stories is hailed as generally witty, and its
sendups of the publishing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> are reported to have hit home. However,
critics also suspect that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Updike</ENAMEX> is getting tired of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bech</ENAMEX>. (Read an excerpt from the book. Free registration required.)

            
               Recent
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment</ENAMEX>" columns
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">21:</TIMEX>

            

               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Beloved</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bride</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chucky</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Practical</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Magic</ENAMEX> ;

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> -- Corpus
Christi , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Terrence McNally</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Manhattan Theatre Club</ENAMEX>);

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Music -- Live:</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1966</TIMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dylan</ENAMEX>;

            

               Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- The Poisonwood Bible</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara Kingsolver</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">14:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Man</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- The
Mighty ;

            

               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Slam</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- A <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Night</ENAMEX> at
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roxbury</ENAMEX> ;

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dance -- Swan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Lake</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neil Simon Theatre</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>);

            
               Book -- Work in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Progress</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Eisner</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Schwartz</ENAMEX>;

            

               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pure Drivel</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Martin</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7:</TIMEX>

            

               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Antz</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- What Dreams</ENAMEX>
May Come ;

            

               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Happiness</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- I Married a</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Philip Roth</ENAMEX>;

            
               Television -- The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Secret Diary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Desmond Pfeiffer</ENAMEX> ;

            

               Art --"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Van Gogh</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Van Goghs</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Masterpieces</ENAMEX> From the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Van Gogh Museum</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Amsterdam</ENAMEX>."

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30:</TIMEX>

            

               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ronin</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Urban</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Legend</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Book -- <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">Cities</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Edgar Wideman</ENAMEX>;

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Opera</ENAMEX> -- A Streetcar
Named <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Desire</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Music -- Painted
From Memory , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elvis Costello</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burt Bacharach</ENAMEX>;

            

               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Felicity</ENAMEX> ;

            

               Art --"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">From Van Eyck to Bruegel: Early Netherlandish Painting in the</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metropolitan Museum of Art</ENAMEX>."

            
               --Eliza
Truitt
            

         
      
   
