
   
   
      
         
            Party Tricks

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of my favorite classroom
tricks is to auction off a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20</NUMEX> bill. I explain in advance that the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20</NUMEX> goes to
the top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bidder</ENAMEX>, but the top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bidders</ENAMEX> have to pay whatever they bid.
That way, if <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> bid <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">at least $10</NUMEX>, I come out ahead.

            In fact,
it's far better than that. As soon as <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> are rash enough to enter the
bidding, I'm almost guaranteed an astronomical profit. Once <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mickey</ENAMEX> bids a
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">nickel</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Minnie</ENAMEX> bids a dime, both are trapped: There's never a right time to
drop out of the auction. If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mickey</ENAMEX> quits now, he loses his <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">nickel</ENAMEX>, but by
staying in he can quite reasonably bid <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a quarter</TIMEX> for a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20</NUMEX> bill. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Minnie</ENAMEX>, of
course, raises her bid to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">half a dollar</NUMEX>. After a few rounds, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mickey</ENAMEX> has bid <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$9</NUMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Minnie</ENAMEX> goes to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mickey</ENAMEX> can't quit without throwing away <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$9</NUMEX>; instead he
takes the far more sensible route of bidding <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$11</NUMEX> to get <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20</NUMEX>. Now my profit is
in the bag.

            But that's only the beginning. After a few more rounds,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Minnie bids $18 and Mickey</ENAMEX> bids <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$19</NUMEX>. Now <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Minnie</ENAMEX> can either bid <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20</NUMEX> to get <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20</NUMEX>
or drop out and pay <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$18</NUMEX> for nothing; she bids <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20</NUMEX>. At this point, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mickey</ENAMEX>
can either bid <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$21</NUMEX> to get <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20</NUMEX> (accepting a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1</NUMEX> loss) or drop out and pay <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$19</NUMEX> for
nothing; he opts for the lesser of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> evils and bids <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$21</NUMEX>. Similar reasoning
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">leads Minnie</ENAMEX> to bid <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$22</NUMEX>. The spiral stops escalating only when one or the other
runs out of money or exhausts my willingness to extend credit. If my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>
were sufficiently wealthy (and sufficiently shortsighted to enter the auction
in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place), I could earn a lifetime's income in a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">50 minute</TIMEX> class
period.

            My auction
game is a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">crude</ENAMEX> but instructive metaphor for political campaign spending. It
might even be a reasonably accurate metaphor if we lived in a world where the
biggest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spender</ENAMEX> always wins. In any contested election, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> would
continue to spend until they had exhausted all their own and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resources</ENAMEX>. Foreseeing that outcome, no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX> would ever contest an
election. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> to file would always win by default.

            
But in our world, outspending your opponent
doesn't always make you a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX>--it only increases your probability of
winning. And beyond a certain point, it doesn't increase your probability by
very much: The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> who runs <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10,001</NUMEX> commercials has little advantage over
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> who runs <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10,000</NUMEX>. So, sooner or later, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> reach a point
where <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> more commercial just can't justify its cost. That puts a natural
limit on what they're willing to spend. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mickey</ENAMEX> will always bid another dollar
to get a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20</NUMEX> bill, but he won't always bid another dollar to get a slightly
increased chance at a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20</NUMEX> bill.

            All this is important
because campaign finance reform is important, and you can't predict the effects
of campaign finance reform unless you think about the incentives it creates for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>. Let me offer a few potential scenarios.

             

            First, imagine the most simple-minded of all possible
reforms: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> subsidizes each of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> to the tune
of, oh, say, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 million</NUMEX> apiece. You might expect that plan to backfire by
encouraging the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> to spend more. But think again: The subsidies don't
affect the cost of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10,001</NUMEX> st commercial, and they don't affect
its benefit--so if a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> has already decided not to run that commercial,
he still won't want to run it. Therefore, total expenditures don't change--they
just get covered by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX> instead of the fat <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX>. (The only exception
is if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> is literally out of money and never had the option of
running the commercial without the subsidy.)

            Here's a different <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">scenario</ENAMEX>:
Suppose that instead of giving <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 million</NUMEX> apiece to the top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>, the
government agrees to give <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a million</NUMEX> to any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> who meets certain
criteria--say, a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX> showing in major opinion polls. Now the main effect
is to encourage new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> to enter. With more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> must there be
more total expenditure? Not clearly. Suppose, for example, that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> are in the middle of a hotly contested race for the presidency
when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Colin Powell</ENAMEX> suddenly throws his hat in the ring--and suppose that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Powell</ENAMEX>
has a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20 percent</NUMEX> chance of winning. Then <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> are no longer battling
each other for the presidency; they're battling each other for an <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">80 percent</NUMEX>
chance at the presidency. With the value of the prize diminished,
they'll be willing to spend less in its pursuit. So what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Powell</ENAMEX> spends is at
least partly offset by what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> choose to save.

            That
example points to an important general principle: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Total</ENAMEX> expenditure is
determined by the value of the prize, whether we're talking about presidential
campaigns or state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lotteries</ENAMEX>. If the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Powerball</ENAMEX> jackpot is worth <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50 million</NUMEX> and
less than <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50 million</NUMEX> worth of tickets have been sold, then the odds are
favorable--and rational <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">betters</ENAMEX> will rush in to buy tickets, guaranteeing that
at least <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50 million</NUMEX> in tickets will be sold. Likewise, if the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">presidency</ENAMEX> is worth <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50 million</NUMEX> and there are many potential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> with
essentially identical chances of winning, they'll keep entering the race until
they've collectively spent <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">at least $50 million</NUMEX>.

            
In a state lottery, your odds of winning depend
only on how many tickets you hold compared with everyone else. That's what
guarantees that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> will keep buying tickets as long as the odds are in
their favor. That's a good analogy to an election with many equally plausible
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> whose odds of winning might depend only on how much they spend
compared with everyone else. But if some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> tower over others, the
analogy breaks down. If you know that the state lottery is likely to be rigged,
you'll buy fewer tickets. And if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> believe that an election is
"rigged," in the sense that the favorite will probably win regardless of
expenditures, they'll buy fewer campaign commercials.

            That
means there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only two</NUMEX> kinds of reform that have any chance of actually
reducing total expenditure on presidential elections. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> is to reduce
the value of the presidency itself, say by putting new limits on presidential
power, or installing a permanent independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX>, or requiring the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> to sleep on a bed of nails. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> is to reduce the uncertainty
about who's going to win.

            How do you reduce uncertainty? The most drastic way is to
allow <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>. This makes the outcome completely certain and drives
campaign expenditures to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX>. Short of that, you could try to deliver
information about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> that might drive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> to make up their minds
on some basis other than political advertising--for example, you could sponsor
a series of debates.

            But that cuts both ways.
Suppose it's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> has a slight but
not insurmountable lead in the polls. Now <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> trounces <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> in a debate,
substantially widening his lead, and making it all but certain that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> will
win. <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Rational creatures</ENAMEX> that they are, both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> reduce their
expenditures rather than try to change a foregone conclusion. But suppose, on
the other hand, that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> wins the debate, closing the gap, and putting the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> into a virtual dead heat. Then expenditures will rise as each
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">candidate</ENAMEX> fights to resolve the new uncertainty in his own favor.

            If the debates essentially
substitute for commercials, then they're equivalent to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">scenario</ENAMEX> where the
government gives a certain amount of money to each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>, and expenditures
don't change. If the debates are fundamentally different from commercials, then
they're equally liable to cause the race to tighten or to widen, and
expenditures can go either up or down. Of course, debates have civic virtues
other than their effects on spending, so this is not an argument against them.
But it is an argument for being realistic about what we can and cannot
change. Whenever there's a big <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prize</ENAMEX> to be won--whether it's a lottery jackpot
or the presidency of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> will find a way to spend a lot
of money trying to win it.

         
      
   
