
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alice</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, like, I suppose,
the rest of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, is alive with echoes of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX>--for
obvious reasons. How do <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s offenses compare with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>'s? What light does the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> case throw on the definition of "high crimes
and misdemeanors"? What precedent does <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>' procedure in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX>
case establish for the procedure in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> case?

            I do not
propose to add to the volume of punditry on such questions. But I can add a
footnote on the question of what it was like being an innocent in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> during the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX> affair. I use the word "innocent," of course, to
mean not just "not guilty" but also "unaware" or "naive."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iwas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council of Economic Advisers</ENAMEX>
during the whole business. I was at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Homestead</ENAMEX>, in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hot Springs</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Va.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunday</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 18, 1972</TIMEX>, when I read, in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , of the
break-in at the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX> Office <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Building</ENAMEX>. The previous evening I had given a
speech to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Virginia Bankers Association</ENAMEX> about the wonders of the economic
situation. Only a little before that I had held a press conference announcing
that the economic statistics of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first quarter</TIMEX> were the best in recorded
history--or, I cautiously added, "at least in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> era." We seemed to
be on our way to an orderly dismantling of price and wage controls. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>'s
re-election in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX> seemed assured, the only question being which
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> would be defeated most decisively. The <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX> break-in
did not look like a cloud on our, or my, horizon.

            For the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next two years</TIMEX>, up <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">almost</NUMEX> to the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last days</TIMEX>, I could see the cloud getting
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">darker</ENAMEX> and darker but did not believe the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> presidency would come to a
premature end. For <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> thing, I had my own experience with the extent of bias
and animosity in the press against anything having to do with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>. During
many <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, before I entered the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>, I had had
friendly relations with many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX>. I was then associated with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee for Economic Development</ENAMEX>, the least conservative of the business
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organizations</ENAMEX>, and we were the "good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX>" to the liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX>. But these same
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> became my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX> and, I felt, misrepresented me as soon as it became
apparent I was devoted to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>. As it happened, one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s chief
pursuers in the press, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carl Bernstein</ENAMEX>, of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , had been
my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Silver Spring</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Md.</ENAMEX>, and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s. He had been a
likable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>, but I put no great stock in his professionalism or objectivity. So
I did not believe the press was giving an accurate account of what had
happened.

            
At <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 a.m.</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each day</TIMEX> I participated in a meeting
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>, presided over by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief of staff</ENAMEX>--first Bob
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Haldeman</ENAMEX> and later <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Haig</ENAMEX>. Almost every <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1973 and 1974</TIMEX>, we were
given a status report on the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX> case, the constant refrain of which was
that everything was going to come out all right. I don't believe anyone was
lying to us. But no one told us--and perhaps didn't know--how the legal and
political process was going to unfold.

            Still, I
don't underestimate the importance of my own unwillingness to believe. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>
had honored me by making me <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> and then <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council of Economic</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Advisers</ENAMEX>. He had treated me with respect and offered me his friendship. I was
unwilling to believe that he had behaved in a way that a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>,
even <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> composed mainly of his political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX>, would consider deserving of
impeachment.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Ican</ENAMEX> think of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> economic policy decision that was
probably influenced by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX>. By the beginning
of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1973</TIMEX>, after the election, the wage-price control system began to come
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">unglued</ENAMEX>. The world food supply had fallen because of bad weather in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">El Niño</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pacific</ENAMEX>, food prices were rising beyond our control, and with
food prices rising it was hard to restrain wages. When I spoke with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leonard</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garment</ENAMEX>, then the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX>, he said the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> was in trouble and
asked whether we couldn't have some kind of economic spectacular to help
bolster his public support. Perhaps because I didn't have enough imagination, I
had no comfort to give him.

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> suggested to me that we might have another wage-price freeze,
like the one we had imposed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 1971</TIMEX> that had been so popular. I replied,
smart-alecky, that you can't step in the same river twice. He came back with
the wittiest words I ever heard from him: "Yes, you can, if it's frozen."

            
That was not the end of the matter. The
economic situation continued to deteriorate and, as I now see, so did the
political one. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> brought back as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counselor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Connally</ENAMEX>, who, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1971</TIMEX> and
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1972</TIMEX>, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX>, had been his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">specialist</ENAMEX> in long-ball
economic policy. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> wanted his economic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX>, thus fortified, to
produce a dramatic economic policy that would improve the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s economy and
his political standing. A new wage-price freeze was one of the options to be
considered. But none of us, not even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Connally</ENAMEX>, wanted that. The president
repeatedly asked us to reconsider. After several uncomfortable <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX> he
decided, without the benefit of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX>, to impose the freeze anyway. It
was an immediate flop and did not last long. Then we reverted to unspectacular,
even painful, economics.

            As I look
back at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">those days</TIMEX> I am impressed by the way in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> continued
to perform his duties in what was surely a time of great stress for him. Of
course, I was not an intimate, and I did not see him in his private moments.
But still, I had many meetings with him, and he showed no signs of distraction
or impatience. He would take notes on his yellow pad and sum up the sense of
our meetings in an orderly manner, as he had always done.

            Near the end, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 1974</TIMEX>, I went out to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Clemente</ENAMEX> to
draft what was to be, although we didn't know it at the time, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>'s last
address as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> before his resignation message. The speech was long and, I
can now see, rather platitudinous. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> read all the drafts. He discussed
them with me and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roy Ash</ENAMEX>, who was then the budget <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>, and he delivered
the final speech with vigor on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 25</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>.

            It was on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> flying
back to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> that we got news of votes in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> that made
impeachment extremely likely. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Two weeks later</TIMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>, and I were in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Room</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>, tears streaming down our cheeks as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> said farewell to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
