
   
   
      
         
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 7</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Nov. 7, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            The
cover editorial marvels that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has been
shown to be "a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liar</ENAMEX> and a philanderer" yet "still he comes back laughing." But
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> should pursue impeachment, regardless of the election results: "If
they believed that they had grounds for an inquiry, it should be a thorough
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, for this election has no effect on those grounds." ... An essay says our two-party system is dissolving, especially at the
state level. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> look more and more like each other. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governors</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tommy Thompson</ENAMEX> are the leading edge of
this movement. State <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> don't care about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>: They just want
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> who get the job done. ... <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Economist</ENAMEX> , marking its
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Science and Technology</ENAMEX>" section's <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">20 th</NUMEX> anniversary, offers a
challenging science quiz. Question No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>: "What is unusual about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sheep</ENAMEX> on
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Scottish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Foula</ENAMEX>? a) They eat sea <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">birds</ENAMEX>. b) They eat seaweed. c)
They eat each other." If you are going take the quiz, stop reading now. The answer is a).

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 23</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, Nov. 6, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            The lead
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> in the election cover package heralds the onset of "liberal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">centrism</ENAMEX>"--cautious reform pegged to New Deal themes. Similarly, the cover
editorial attributes the election results to a groundswell of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
moderatism: Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are happy, so why vote for radical changes? ...

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">TNR</ENAMEX> criticizes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pols</ENAMEX> on both sides of the campaign finance debate. One
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> warns <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> (notably soft money spurning <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russell Feingold</ENAMEX>, the
narrow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victor</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wisconsin</ENAMEX>) not to obscure "real" themes by overemphasizing
campaign finance reform. Another piece raps <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Republican National Senatorial</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mitch McConnell</ENAMEX> for allowing money to substitute for good
politics.

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times Magazine</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 8</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, Nov. 5, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
story profiles <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George C. Wolfe</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producer</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joseph Papp Public</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX>. Wickedly smart, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid tongued</ENAMEX>, and black, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolfe</ENAMEX> deeply intimidates
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX>, choreographers, and theater <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">honchos</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wolfe</ENAMEX> battled kidney
failure and won. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX> he's stubbornly producing an expensive and risky
version of On the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Town</ENAMEX> , despite severe doubts in the industry that the
musical could ever be a success. ... A fascinating story describes and
denounces solitary confinement, a punishment now inflicted on <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">8 percent</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
percent of prison <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inmates</ENAMEX>. Out of their cells for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">just one hour</TIMEX> a day, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inmates</ENAMEX> grow slowly insane and even more violent and unstable than when they
entered <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX>. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychologists</ENAMEX> believe the treatment is inhumane. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Wardens</ENAMEX>
disagree. ... A story profiles famous horse race <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prognosticator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beyer</ENAMEX>. Beyer, the racing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , dropped out
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX> to follow <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horses</ENAMEX> and invented a race analysis system that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">revolutionized horse</ENAMEX> play.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 9</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Nov. 3, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's cover package attacks corporate welfare: "In some ways, it
represents pork-barrel legislation of the worst order. The difference, of
course, is that instead of rewarding the poor, it rewards the powerful." In
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> subsidized a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shipyard</ENAMEX> to the tune of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$323,000</NUMEX> per
job--the jobs themselves will pay <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $50,000</NUMEX> each. Corporate welfare lets
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> claim they've created new jobs while wasting your tax money. The
package is by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populist muckrakers</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald Barlett</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Steele</ENAMEX>, who won fame
and notoriety for their <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inquirer</ENAMEX> series
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">America: Who Stole the Dream?</ENAMEX>" ... 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's cover
package surveys hot new tech <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Silicon Valleys</ENAMEX> have sprouted in
places such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boise</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Idaho</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambridge</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>; and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bangalore</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>. Keys to
tech success: nearby research <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX>, an educated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">talent</ENAMEX> pool,
free-flowing venture capital, and that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Valley</ENAMEX>-style, go-for-broke,
entrepreneurial spirit.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> notes the rising popularity of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palaces</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Palaces</ENAMEX> let animated "avatars"--characters
Netizens create for themselves--interact in a graphic environment. When you
type words, they appear in a thought bubble above your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">avatar</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>. Current
popular <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palaces</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South Park</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palace</ENAMEX> and, you guessed it, porn
sites.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News & World Report</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 9</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Nov. 3, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            The
cover story reports on new <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> tests confirming that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thomas</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jefferson</ENAMEX> fathered <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> by his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slave</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sally Hemings</ENAMEX>. Many Hemings
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">descendants</ENAMEX> were unaware of any <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-American</ENAMEX> ancestry (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hemings</ENAMEX> was a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mulatto</ENAMEX>) and equally unaware that they were related to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. An
accompanying article traces the evolving debate among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historians</ENAMEX>, several of
whom proclaimed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jefferson</ENAMEX>'s purity and must now admit to grave error. Another
piece wonders how the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jefferson</ENAMEX> legacy might change: "While it will require a
rather large stretch to transform <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jefferson</ENAMEX> from a thinking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s racist to a
multicultural <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX>, some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentators</ENAMEX> are sure to make the leap." ... A
story challenges the fairness of the death penalty, noting the
significant numbers of death row <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inmates</ENAMEX> who have been found innocent before
they could be executed. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX> has executed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, but found <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> more on
death row innocent. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Six</NUMEX> of those <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minorities</ENAMEX> accused of crimes against
white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 9</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Nov. 3, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            An essay
argues that True at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First Light</ENAMEX> , labeled as an <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ernest Hemingway</ENAMEX> novel,
should not have been published. The book was winnowed from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 800</NUMEX> pages
to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about half</NUMEX> that length in a ham-handed editing process that would have
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">horrified Hemingway</ENAMEX>, who carefully chose every word he wrote. Besides, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Papa</ENAMEX>
requested that none of his unfinished work be posthumously published.
... A cautionary tale of the Internet boom chronicles the failure of a
tech startup called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">PointCast</ENAMEX>. An early "push technology" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">PointCast</ENAMEX> was
on the verge of being bought out for huge dough. Suddenly, the bottom dropped
out when push fell from favor and "portals" became the next big thing.

            

               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 9</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Nov. 3, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
story praises <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin Netanyahu</ENAMEX> for standing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> in negotiations with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palestinian Authority</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bibi</ENAMEX> has savvily refused to concede territory to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX>, knowing that he will need land as a bargaining chip during <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">final</TIMEX>
settlement talks. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yasser Arafat</ENAMEX> controls <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">less than half</NUMEX> the land he expected
to control by now.) The piece warns that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 4, 1999</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arafat</ENAMEX> has vowed to
declare an independent <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, could be the launch date for a brutal
war.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stevenson</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
