
   
   
      
         
            

            
               The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Speaker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Speaks</ENAMEX>
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Eight</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker presumptive</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Livingston</ENAMEX>, then an obscure junior
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">congressman</ENAMEX>, and 
                  Slate
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">'s Jacob Weisberg</ENAMEX>, then an obscure writer
for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX> , were both on an official <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">delegation</ENAMEX> to
certify the legitimacy of an election in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Guatemala</ENAMEX>. It was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> administration
policy that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">democracy</ENAMEX> was spreading in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Latin America</ENAMEX> and that the election was
going to be fair. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weisberg</ENAMEX> wrote in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNR</ENAMEX> about his adventures:

            When we arrived back at
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Electoral Headquarters</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hotel El Dorado</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two hours</TIMEX> before the
polls closed, our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">delegation</ENAMEX> was already working on its statement. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob</ENAMEX>
Livingston, a bluff <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisiana</ENAMEX>, had somehow
become our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> and was summing up the prevailing consensus that the
election was free and fair. I pointed out that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least two</NUMEX> of us had heard
charges of vote buying. "Vote buying isn't fraud," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Livingston</ENAMEX> bellowed. "I
could show you vote buying all over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisiana</ENAMEX>."

            The logic
here is that of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tallulah Bankhead</ENAMEX>'s famous remark about <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX>: "Of course
it's not addictive, darling. I use it all the time." But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Livingston</ENAMEX>'s exquisite
ethical sensitivity should serve the new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX> well as he presides over
congressional investigations of presidential perjury, campaign finance abuse,
and so on.

            
               Where in
the World Is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Lewis</ENAMEX>?
            

            Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> find it
suspicious that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Lewis</ENAMEX> has stopped filing dispatches from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>
antitrust trial, and they do not accept our explanation that he got bored,
found the hard wooden seats nightmarishly uncomfortable (especially combined
with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>'s power-mad restrictions on leaving to go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bathroom</ENAMEX>), felt
he had said most of what he wanted to say, has a pressing book deadline, and so
on. They think he was canned because his reports were critical of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>.

            It's not
true. It simply isn't true. There is no evidence for it because it's not ...
not--well, it's all nonsense, is what it is. In short, it's not true. And if
we're stammering a bit, that may reflect the strain of not making any jokes.
Because we wrote a jokey little item in this space <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks ago</TIMEX> about having
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> killed and whatnot, and some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have taken it seriously. We hope that

                  Slate
                hasn't attracted the kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readership</ENAMEX> that needs the word
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">PARODY" or "SATIRE" or "HUMOR</ENAMEX>" stamped on every bit of good-hearted raillery
(and we hope that what we publish in these genres is funny enough not to
require labeling).

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> is alive and well and willing to testify
that 
                  Slate
                expressed nothing but disappointment at his entirely
voluntary decision that he'd had enough. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> part of the problem here may be a
misunderstanding of how journalism, especially magazine journalism, works. How
mysterious is it, really, that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> should drop out of a project before it
is completed? Answer: Not very. Does such an occurrence justify paranoid
speculation about corrupt motives and conflicts of interest? Answer: No, not at
all. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> might suppose that it is highly unusual for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> to agree
to produce <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">some</NUMEX> piece of writing and then fail to produce it, perhaps offering
a variety of whiny and often hypochondriac excuses about hard wooden benches
and so on. That is because many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> do not know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>. In fact, such
behavior is extremely common. In fulfilling perhaps <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of a medium-term oral
agreement to cover a trial of uncertain duration and with long periods of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">boredom</ENAMEX> and discomfort, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Lewis</ENAMEX> is actually above average! So we thank
him for his dispatches and invite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> to check out his
replacements: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herbert Stein</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jodie T. Allen</ENAMEX>, and others still to come.

            Warning: The previous
paragraph contained jokes.

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
