
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">147</NUMEX>:

            By <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cohen</ENAMEX>

            
               "This
seems like the perfect place to release them." Where? What? Says who?
            

            by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 a.m.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> (please note the early deadline) to e-mail your answer to
newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.

            
               Responses
to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s question (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 146</ENAMEX>)--"Funny as a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Banker</ENAMEX>":
            

            
               Fill in the blank.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rolf-Ernst Breuer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Deutsche Bank</ENAMEX>, may acquire <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">America</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bankers Trust</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$9 billion</NUMEX> despite declaring, "Our motto is '__________
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>.' "
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Our Teutonic</ENAMEX> sense of
order demands that we acquire a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> starting with the letter 'A'
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Coppersmith</ENAMEX>
            

            "Sell off the hedge funds
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Levy</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Brat</ENAMEX> first."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miller</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Gerber</ENAMEX> had a similar answer.)

            "If we're going to buy
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bankers Trust</ENAMEX>, let's wait until <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Hope</ENAMEX> dies <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Carvell</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kill Pvt. Ryan</ENAMEX> first.
(But no, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>, that's not fair, and you know it. You can be the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">birthplace</ENAMEX> of
Heidegger, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hegel, Leibniz</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bach</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beethoven</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brecht</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Luther</ENAMEX>, but you
start one little world war ... OK, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>.)"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Kelly</ENAMEX>
            

            Click for more
responses.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
            

            Ask a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> question, expect
a <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX> answer, which to those of us with delicate bourgeois
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sensibilities</ENAMEX>, risks trivializing the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX>. With sufficiently dark humor,
any topic can be fair game. But the enormity here is so daunting. From one
point of view--<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX>-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Apt Pupil</ENAMEX> is unacceptable because it uses the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holocaust</ENAMEX> as dramatic fodder for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lame</ENAMEX> and shallow drama, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hogan</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Heroes</ENAMEX> is acceptable because its dimwitted POW humor steers clear of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holocaust</ENAMEX>. Needless to say, this is not a position one could defend for very
long. It's a tough call, particularly given the good will of "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">News Quiz</ENAMEX>"
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">participants</ENAMEX>.

            More
cheering: The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Anti</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defamation League</ENAMEX>'s survey describes a continuing drop in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s "hard core anti-Semites"--from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">29 percent</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1964</TIMEX>, to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20 percent</NUMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>, to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">12 percent</NUMEX> currently. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clyde Haberman</ENAMEX> notes in the New York
Times , "The older and more poorly educated a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> was, the more likely he
was to hate <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>." If only there were some kind of greeting card to send these
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, maybe--given their poor education--featuring a cartoon bear.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Deutsche</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marks the Spot Answer</ENAMEX>
            

            "Our motto
is 'Europe <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>,' " said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rolf-Ernst Breuer</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last March</TIMEX>, leading many to believe
that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Deutsche Bank</ENAMEX> would not expand into the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. But <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Deutsche</ENAMEX>
confirmed its <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$9.67 billion</NUMEX> offer for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bankers Trust</ENAMEX>, a cash transaction that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">billion</ENAMEX> in assets.

            
               Free
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Speechless Extra</ENAMEX>
            

            Question: "They're really in
the vanguard of setting the agenda for the corporate culture along the lines of
the radical gay movement." Who is?

            Answer: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Levi Strauss</ENAMEX> &
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Co.</ENAMEX>, says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Donahue</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catholic League</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Religious</ENAMEX> and
Civil <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Rights</ENAMEX>.

            For an <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> prevention event,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Levi</ENAMEX>'s planned to display a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX> decorated with condoms at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wollman</ENAMEX>
skating <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rink</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central Park</ENAMEX>, the well-known public space. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donahue</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX>, the same <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> that protested the opening of Corpus
Christi , pressured the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rink</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> into canceling the event. With
characteristic commitment to free speech, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudolph Giuliani</ENAMEX> applauded the
cancellation, calling the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Levi</ENAMEX>'s plan "one of the most idiotic ideas I've ever
heard of."

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Disclaimer</ENAMEX>: All submissions will become the property of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> and
will be published at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> 's discretion. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> may publish your
name on its site in connection with your submission.
            

         
      
   
