
   
   
      
         
            Polls, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Popes</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peers</ENAMEX>

            
               GET
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INTERNATIONAL</ENAMEX> PAPERS" BY E-MAIL!
            

            
               For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> and
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> delivery of this column, plus "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX>),
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pundit Central</ENAMEX>" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>), and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment"</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>),
click here. And
if you missed the most recent installments of this column, here they are:
posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Oct. 13</TIMEX>, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, Oct.</TIMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>.
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Frankfurter Allgemeine Zeitung</ENAMEX> said
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> crises have proved that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> is vital. In a front-page editorial headlined "Without <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> Nothing
Works," it recalled past <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> efforts to make <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> less dependent on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> so as to encourage <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> to rejoin the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alliance</ENAMEX>'s military
structure. Not only did <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> not do so, but the failure of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">West European</ENAMEX> will
over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX> and the sheer complication of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> problem made <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
leadership essential in both cases.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Le Monde</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> marked <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>'s
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">20 th</NUMEX> anniversary of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Paul II</ENAMEX>'s election to the papacy by
commissioning an opinion poll that shows <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">53 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> think he
should resign. <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Nineteen percent</NUMEX> disapprove strongly of the way he has done his
job, and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">34 percent</NUMEX> say they have major reservations. Even among practicing
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French Roman Catholics</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 14 percent</NUMEX> totally approve of him.

            In extensive coverage of the anniversary, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Italian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> made much of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> ever papal participation in a TV chat show.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pope</ENAMEX> telephoned a popular show called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Door to Door</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10:30 p.m. to</TIMEX>
thank <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> in a special program about his pontificate for their
comments. The show's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruno Vespa</ENAMEX>, is reported to have been reduced to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">stutters</ENAMEX> when the call came through.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Repubblica of Rome</ENAMEX> reported
that messages to be read out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> at the ceremony in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">St. Peter's Square</ENAMEX> will
include ones from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin Netanyahu</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yasser Arafat</ENAMEX> inviting the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pope</ENAMEX> to
visit <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year 2000</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said he has agreed to go. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Stampa of Turin</ENAMEX> ran an
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> praising the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pope</ENAMEX>'s efforts to reconcile the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catholic Church</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>,
despite the recent controversy over the canonization of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX>-born
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nun</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edith Stein</ENAMEX>, who died at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Auschwitz</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ha'aretz</ENAMEX> expressed
optimism in an editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> about upcoming <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> talks in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ariel Sharon</ENAMEX>'s appointment as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foreign minister</ENAMEX> does not necessarily
bode any intention of sabotaging the withdrawal agreement," it said. "In
addition to the problems that his appointment might arouse, it can also be seen
as a signal to the right-wing section of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> that its position will
be given full expression in the summit talks." The editorial added that "if the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">delegation</ENAMEX> returns from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> empty-handed, a lot of explaining will
have to be done."

            
The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> press was dominated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> by a
debate in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House of Lords</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s planned abolition of the
parliamentary rights of hereditary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peers</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is committed to
excluding them from the upper <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parliament</ENAMEX> but has yet to reveal its
proposals for further constitutional reform. The hereditary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peers</ENAMEX>, nearly all
of them <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX>, did not argue with the case for their own abolition, but
repeatedly pointed out that a nonelected chamber consisting exclusively of
government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominees</ENAMEX> would be even less democratic than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> dominated by people
who had arrived there by accident of birth. Even the liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX>, which strongly
supports reform, insisted in an editorial that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> be held to its promise that "the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Transition Chamber</ENAMEX> will not last forever."

            The conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Telegraph</ENAMEX> revealed that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">queen</ENAMEX> has decided, by her own choice, to do away with some of the
ceremonial that has traditionally surrounded the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Opening of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parliament</ENAMEX>. When this takes place <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next month</TIMEX>, such <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> as the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Silver Stick</ENAMEX>
in Waiting will not take part. "The sight of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Great Officers</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX>
walking backwards ahead of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sovereign</ENAMEX> will remain unchanged, however. It is
understood that they were offered the option of walking forwards, but
declined." All except the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lord chancellor</ENAMEX>, although, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telegraph</ENAMEX>
reassures its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>, "his request to walk forwards stems from a desire to
avoid an accident rather than from any modernising zeal."

         
      
   
