
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Movies
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American History X</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Line Cinema</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward Norton</ENAMEX>'s performance
as a white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supremacist</ENAMEX> who mends his ways has <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> predicting an <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Oscar</ENAMEX>. The
film itself is panned. Nitpicks: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">antihero</ENAMEX>'s conversion is unconvincing.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) The film begins as an intelligent exploration of the origins of hate and
ends as a hackneyed cautionary tale. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) "[<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">I</ENAMEX>]n its visual heart of hearts [the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">film</ENAMEX>] loves the style and swagger of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazis</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Hunter</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> ). Playing a fellow prison <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inmate</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Norton's</ENAMEX>, newcomer
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guy Torry</ENAMEX> catches the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX>' eyes. (
                  Slate
               's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Edelstein</ENAMEX>
says the film "has the soul of a guidance <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counselor</ENAMEX>." Read his review here.)

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Carpenter</ENAMEX>'s Vampires
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sony Pictures Entertainment</ENAMEX>). Critics
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pan John</ENAMEX> ( <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Halloween</TIMEX> ) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carpenter</ENAMEX>'s gore-fest about a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vatican</ENAMEX>-employed
vampire slayer in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Mexico</ENAMEX>. An interesting mix of genres (vampire and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Western</ENAMEX>) winds up as a hokey mess: "[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX>]his gummy mix of fake-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> mumbo
jumbo and teeth-in-neck horror goes limp" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lisa Schwarzbaum</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Entertainment</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> ). "[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX>]he unintended campiness of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vampires</ENAMEX> makes <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Night</ENAMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Living Dead</ENAMEX> look like an episode of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nightline</ENAMEX> " (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX>
O'Sullivan, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> ). But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gene Siskel</ENAMEX> praises the film,
calling it "surprisingly entertaining" ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Tribune</ENAMEX> ). (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Watch</ENAMEX> the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">trailer</ENAMEX>.)

            

               
                  Life <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Is Beautiful</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miramax Films</ENAMEX>). A triumph of the human spirit
or an insult to the murdered <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX>? The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> are evenly split on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer-director</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roberto Benigni</ENAMEX>'s comedy set in a concentration <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX>.
Those in favor say the film is really a fable about parental love, since
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Benigni</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>'s antics are really an effort to shield his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> from the
horrors of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War</ENAMEX> II. Other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> contend "turning even a small corner of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this century</TIMEX>'s central horror into feel-good popular entertainment is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">abhorrent</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Schickel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> ). (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Read Abraham Foxman</ENAMEX>'s New York
Times op-ed piece, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Holocaust Meets Popular Culture</ENAMEX>," which
defends the film. Free registration required. Click here for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edelstein</ENAMEX>'s review in 
                     Slate
                  .)
            

            

               
                  Living Out Loud
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Line Cinema</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holly Hunter</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danny DeVito</ENAMEX>
turn in solid performances as <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lonely</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Manhattanites</ENAMEX> abandoned by their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouses</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Queen Latifah</ENAMEX> sparkles as a wise cabaret <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singer</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York</ENAMEX>
Times ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Maslin</ENAMEX> says the unlikely pairing of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DeVito</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hunter</ENAMEX> succeeds
because it is not a romance but the story of a friendship. Dourer
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> call the older-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>-starts-over plot a "done-to-death feminist
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">premise"</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Wloszcyna</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> ). (Visit the official
site.)

            

               Art
            

            

               "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson Pollock"</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum of Modern Art</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>). This
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">retrospective</ENAMEX>, which includes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over 200</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pollock</ENAMEX>'s paintings as well as a
reproduction of his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studio</ENAMEX>, leaves no doubt as to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pollock</ENAMEX>'s importance to
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> art. "[A]n experience as powerful as any in modern art" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Stevens</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> ). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kimmelman</ENAMEX> calls the
paintings "astonishingly beautiful." (Read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Weisberg</ENAMEX>'s
review in 
                  Slate
                or visit the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">MoMA's Pollock</ENAMEX> site.)

            

               Book
            

            
               
                  A
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Man</ENAMEX> in Full
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Wolfe</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farrar, Straus & Giroux</ENAMEX>). Better than
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bonfire of the Vanities</ENAMEX> . <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Eleven</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> in the making and nominated for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">National Book Award</ENAMEX> before its official publication date, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolfe</ENAMEX>'s new novel
is hailed as a masterpiece by some, given mixed reviews by others. This time,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> say, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolfe</ENAMEX> has included a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> can like, rather than
the usual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cast</ENAMEX> of unappealing caricatures. Praise is tempered with complaints
that the book is "entertainment, not literature" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Updike</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yorker</ENAMEX> ) and that the ending is artificial and "stage-managed" (Michiko
Kakutani, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ). (Read an excerpt from the book here, and
read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Weisberg</ENAMEX>'s review
in 
                  Slate
               .)

            

               Music
            

            

               
                  Mutations
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beck</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Geffen/DGC</ENAMEX>). Beck sheds the hip-hop style of
his <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Grammy-</ENAMEX>winning album <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Odelay</ENAMEX> in favor of a more folk-influenced,
melodic sound. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> call it "his prettiest record to date" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nathan Brackett</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rolling Stone</ENAMEX> ) but predict that the move will disappoint <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> drawn by
the irony-laced style of the last album. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Hirschorn</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> in chief of
Spin , and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerald Marzorati</ENAMEX>, editorial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Magazine</ENAMEX> , discuss the album <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> in 
                  Slate
               's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Music</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Club</ENAMEX>." Also, check out this illustrated, in-depth exploration
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beck</ENAMEX>'s fashion choices.)

            
               Recent
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment</ENAMEX>" columns
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">28:</TIMEX>

            

               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pleasantville</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- Apt
Pupil ;

            

               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Soldier</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX> of the
World: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Rise</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Muhammad Ali</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Remnick</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Evening</ENAMEX> ,
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Minot</ENAMEX>;

            

               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bech</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bay</ENAMEX>: A <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Quasi-Novel</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Updike</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">21:</TIMEX>

            

               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Beloved</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bride</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chucky</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Practical</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Magic</ENAMEX> ;

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> -- Corpus
Christi , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Terrence McNally</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Manhattan Theatre Club</ENAMEX>);

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Music -- Live:</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1966</TIMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dylan</ENAMEX>;

            

               Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- The Poisonwood Bible</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara Kingsolver</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">14:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Man</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- The
Mighty ;

            

               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Slam</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- A <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Night</ENAMEX> at
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roxbury</ENAMEX> ;

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dance -- Swan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Lake</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neil Simon Theatre</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>);

            
               Book -- Work in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Progress</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Eisner</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Schwartz</ENAMEX>;

            

               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pure Drivel</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Martin</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7:</TIMEX>

            

               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Antz</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- What Dreams</ENAMEX>
May Come ;

            

               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Happiness</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- I Married a</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Philip Roth</ENAMEX>;

            
               Television -- The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Secret Diary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Desmond Pfeiffer</ENAMEX> ;

            

               Art --"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Van Gogh</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Van Goghs</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Masterpieces</ENAMEX> From the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Van Gogh Museum</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Amsterdam</ENAMEX>."

            
               --Eliza Truitt
            

         
      
   
