
   
   
      
         
            Election <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Night Excuses</ENAMEX>

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> We did better than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX> said we
would.
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX>,
with typical chutzpah, has predicted the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> could pick up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX> or more <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>
seats. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>, with equal chutzpah, will portray anything less as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> victory.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. We
did better than the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> said we would.
            

            The
conventional wisdom on likely <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> gains has ranged from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>
seats and from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three to five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> seats. If <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> hold the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> below the
upper end of this range, they'll claim victory. If <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> beat the lower
end, they'll claim victory.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> We did well, considering how heavily we
were outspent.
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>
will use this alibi in nearly every close race. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> will claim that
many of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> were outspent, if you count the additional "union
money."

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. We did
well, considering the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s difficulties.
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>
will offer this excuse without acknowledging that it implies the public is
still upset with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s behavior. Simultaneously, they will assert
that the election is a mandate for ending the investigation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s
behavior.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. We did
well, considering the backlash against the investigation.
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> will offer this excuse without acknowledging that the backlash is
mainstream. Instead, they'll portray it as a surge of turnout among diehard
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX>.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. We did
well, considering the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six year</TIMEX> itch.
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>
will point out that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> usually loses <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of congressional
seats in his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">sixth</NUMEX> year. What they won't mention is that the reason <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>
didn't lose those seats in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">his sixth year</TIMEX> is that he lost them in his
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> re-elected the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican</ENAMEX>
majority.
            

            This is
the ultimate <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> fallback. Even if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> somehow loses seats in both
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">houses</ENAMEX>, it can ignore its relative setbacks and reassert its absolute
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">supremacy</ENAMEX>.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> failed to win a filibuster-proof <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">majority</ENAMEX>.
            

            This is
the ultimate <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> fallback. If <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> lose <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fewer than five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>
seats, they'll say they weathered the tide because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> decided not to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">entrust</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> with complete control.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>. We
won the close races.
            

            Both
sides will use this line. "Close races" are the ones your side won. If a race
looked close but you ended up losing it, then it wasn't really close, so you
needn't mention it.

            
               10.
Their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> won on local issues.
            

            A good spinner never
admits that his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> lost because of the national <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>'s
positions. If an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-</ENAMEX>health maintenance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>, pro-public-education
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> wins, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> will say it's because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> liked her positions on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMOs</ENAMEX> and education. If she loses, they'll say its because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> disliked her
position on building a local <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">freeway</ENAMEX>.

            

               11 Their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> won with vicious negative
ads.
            

            If their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> wins, it's because his negative ads distracted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> from the
issues. If your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> wins, it's because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> agreed that the other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> was wrong on the issues--as your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> pointed out in his
negative ads.

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12</TIMEX>. Our
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> lost because of vicious media attacks.
            

            If your
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> ran negative ads and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> didn't and your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> still
managed to lose, you can always accuse the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> of attacking your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>.
This argument comes in particularly handy when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> have criticized your
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> precisely for running negative ads.

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13</TIMEX>. Our
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> lost because he screwed up.
            

            If an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">anti-tax</ENAMEX>, family values <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican</ENAMEX> wins, it's because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> liked his
positions on taxes and family values. If he loses, it's because he was unfairly
savaged by the local press for calling his opponent a putzhead.

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14</TIMEX>. Our
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> did well in a tough district.
            

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Party</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recruits</ENAMEX> each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> by telling her that her district
opposes the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> on the issues. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> spends
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> on the campaign trail repeating this line. Then, on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">election</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> claim that she lost because the district was
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>.

            

               15 Our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> did well, considering he
was up against an entrenched incumbent.
            

            This is
the least bogus spin. Generally, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">incumbents</ENAMEX> do have enormous advantages in
clout, money, and name recognition. But when a challenger has these advantages
and still manages to lose, his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> will invoke the "entrenched incumbent"
excuse anyway.

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX>. Our
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> did well to make the race close.
            

            This is
the corollary to spin No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>. If your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> was blown out, you brush it off
by saying it was never really a race. If your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> wasn't blown out, you
call this an achievement.

            
               17.
Their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> won thanks to a vocal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minority</ENAMEX>.
            

            This will
be the trademark spin of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s elections. Everyone knows turnout will be
low. So if you lose, you can always claim that the silent, nonvoting majority
supported your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>.

            

               18 Their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> won on our
issues.
            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>'s
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> treatment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is an excellent example. Throughout the campaign,
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> call the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> a liberal. After he wins, they say he
won by running as a conservative.

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19</TIMEX>. Our
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> lost on their issues.
            

            If
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Fong</ENAMEX> loses the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> race, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> will say
he blew it because he's a "squish," i.e., a moderate. If <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glenn Poshard</ENAMEX>
loses the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX>'s race, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> will say he blew it because he's
anti-abortion.

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX>. The
polls show <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> support us.
            

            If your
party gets creamed, you can always find comfort in the exit polls. Somewhere in
the blizzard of questions, a couple of findings will suggest that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> sort
of agreed with your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>'s position on something or other, even if they voted
against all your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>. And after all, isn't that what really counts?

            
               Recent
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Frame Games</ENAMEX>"
            

            "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap Ad</ENAMEX>
War": Why the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>'s new ads are too clever by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>. (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, Oct.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace</ENAMEX>
Therapy": Is the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> deal a new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapter</ENAMEX> or a reminder of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX>?
(posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday, Oct. 28, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

         
      
   
