
   
   
      
         
            Our <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Revels Now Are Ended</ENAMEX>

            
               Our
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Revels Now Are Ended</ENAMEX>
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This week</TIMEX> brings the end of
our experimental novel-by<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">-e</ENAMEX>-mail, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Reply All</ENAMEX>. For the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past year</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Angeles</ENAMEX>--have been e-mailing one another in the personae of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> in
their respective locations. Little did they know when they began--the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX>--that they'd get tangled up with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda</ENAMEX>,
Lucianne, and the equally colorful goings-on of our real-life melodrama. If
only the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> could bring that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to a conclusion as well.

            The entire <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">44</NUMEX> chapter
Reply All saga can be downloaded as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft Word</ENAMEX> or
an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Adobe</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Acrobat</ENAMEX> document. It's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 60</NUMEX> pages.

            And now that it's over, we
can reveal the identities of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX>: in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">screenwriter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erik</ENAMEX>
Tarloff, whose novel about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Face-Time</ENAMEX> , will be published in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crown</ENAMEX>; in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novelist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francine Prose</ENAMEX>; and, in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
... well, he or she would lose his or her job, so we'd still better not
say.

            Our
thanks to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all six</NUMEX> of them--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>--for an entertaining year.

            
               And
Speaking of E-Mail
            

            If you
like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">your</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> delivery of "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>," or even if you haven't yet
tried getting your fix of 
                  Slate
                this way, sign up for our new
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon and evening</TIMEX> deliveries, featuring 
                  Slate
               's analysis of
breaking news and 
                  Slate
               's cultural coverage (respectively). Click
here to go to
the e-mail sign-up page. It's all free as sunshine to 
                  Slate
               
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subscribers</ENAMEX>.

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
