
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">143</NUMEX>:

            By <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cohen</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX>' answer was "I don't know what you mean 'concerned.' " What was the
question?
            

            by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon ET</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> to e-mail your answer to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.

            
               Responses
to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s question (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 142</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Customs Inspection</ENAMEX>":
            

            

               "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Traditions</ENAMEX> in the West are sometimes hard to break, but we find this to be
particularly egregious," says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rocky Mountain</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coordinator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrea Lococo</ENAMEX>.
            

            
               What tradition?
            

            "Splitting an appetizer
with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Calista Flockhart</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric Zicklin</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Ford</ENAMEX> stories in
which nothing happens."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Kelly</ENAMEX>
            

            "Making all rookie <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rocky</ENAMEX>
Mountain coordinators prove their dedication by spending a night in a bedroll
with a grizzled old prospector."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Franzen</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hunting</ENAMEX> and killing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homosexuals</ENAMEX>. Even if they use the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beth Sherman</ENAMEX>
            

            "Describing the behavior
of physical objects using a set of rules, instead of acknowledging the actual
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witches</ENAMEX> and elves behind it all."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenton A. Hoover</ENAMEX>
            

            Click for more
responses.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
            

            The implacable logic of the
Top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX> format sadly demanded the exclusion of many fine entries premised on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bestiality</ENAMEX> (surely more generically rural than strictly Western?) and prairie
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">oysters</ENAMEX> (so delightfully disgusting, as are many of the odd foods of strange
lands eaten by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with comical names). A more Freudian quiz might wonder
why so many responses involved having sex with, and eating the sexual bits of,
some other <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX>. This quiz does not.

            It does wonder if this
question promotes an unattractive regionalism, as if it were a personal
accomplishment to be born in, say, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>? But perhaps what makes this
chauvinism necessary is the disproportionate power of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West</ENAMEX>--too many
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX>, too much public money, too many movie locations--and the uses to
which that power is put. Or, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Leherer</ENAMEX> sang in "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Wild West Is Where I</ENAMEX>
Want To Be," in the only line I can recall, "Where the scenery is attractive,
and the air is radioactive."

            Thus, in
the moral cartography of "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">News Quiz</ENAMEX>," urban trumps rural, and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East</ENAMEX> beats West.
Then does <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastern</ENAMEX> rural supersede Western urban? <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Vermont</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX>?
That's a complicated question I wouldn't want to tackle before I've had a
snack. And some sex. With <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> different creatures. That's the way we like it
back <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Wily</ENAMEX>
Answer
            

            Killing coyotes.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Hunters</ENAMEX> from across the West
gathered in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wyoming</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last weekend</TIMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Coyote Calling</ENAMEX>
Contest--"calling" in the sense of luring and then shooting <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">545</NUMEX> that
responded. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrea Lococo</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fund for Animals</ENAMEX> particularly disdains "killing
for kicks, for fun and money, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> sport."

            Speaking for the affirmative,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sheep rancher Dan Thompson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founder</ENAMEX> of the contest: "About the worst thing to
happen to hunting was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Walt Disney</ENAMEX>. The animated voice doesn't make them human.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">coyote</ENAMEX> is smart, elusive. I respect him. I don't hunt him because I hate
him."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Fifty-nine thousand</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sheep</ENAMEX> and
lambs fell prey to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wyoming</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100,000</NUMEX> coyotes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coyote Calling Contest</ENAMEX> will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next weekend</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Elko</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nev.</ENAMEX>

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re-Targeted Extra</ENAMEX>
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>.
"Democracy confers a stamp of legitimacy that reforms must have in order to be
effective."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Chides New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX> for taking <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> to ultimately deny <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">parade</ENAMEX> permits to his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foes</ENAMEX> while swiftly granting permits to those whose views he endorses.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. "We
should just bomb the hell out of him, get it over with."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pvt. Michael</ENAMEX>
Bucci
            

            Thinks
firing isn't good enough for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Roth</ENAMEX>, former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of programming, who
aired low-rated, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soul</ENAMEX>-deadening shows.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. "They're
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hideous ideologues</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pseudo</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marxists</ENAMEX>, pseudo <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">feminists</ENAMEX>, pseudo historicists and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">disciples of Foucault</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harold Bloom</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judges</ENAMEX> the
cast of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Friends</ENAMEX> after watching a single episode, and it was one of the
old ones in syndication.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. "He is a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">coldblooded</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fellow</ENAMEX> who winds up loving absolutely no one."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harold</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Bloom</ENAMEX>
            

            Attacks
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">magician David Copperfield</ENAMEX> for no apparent reason.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. "She's
wholly normative--a miracle of healthiness, good sense, lovability."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harold</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Bloom</ENAMEX>
            

            Sucks up
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Claudia Schiffer</ENAMEX>--after knocking her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boyfriend</ENAMEX>!--in an inept attempt at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">seduction</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. "I didn't
want it to end."<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Larry King</ENAMEX>
            

            Praises
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Quiz</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s 
                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table of Contents</ENAMEX>.

            
               Original
Targets
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Malaysian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, for suppressing dissent

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein</ENAMEX>, who will ultimately break his vow

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. College
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shakespeare</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> who differ with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harold Bloom</ENAMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Hamlet</ENAMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>.
Rosalind

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. Meet
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Black</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">All blurbs for News Quiz on the</ENAMEX> 
                  Slate
                Table of
Contents <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> are inexplicable praise for this movie.)

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Disclaimer</ENAMEX>: All submissions will become the property of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> and
will be published at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> 's discretion. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> may publish your
name on its site in connection with your submission.
            

         
      
   
