
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Address your e-mail to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. You must include your address and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX>
phone number (for confirmation only).
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Extramarital Chatter</ENAMEX>
            

            Not only did <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Timothy Noah</ENAMEX>'s
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 2</TIMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>" contain major factual errors, the comparisons it drew
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between the present-day</TIMEX> situation and that of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Jefferson</ENAMEX> is very
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">disheartening</ENAMEX>. There are fewer similarities than this rush to analyze and spin
realizes.

            Most glaring was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Noah</ENAMEX>'s
statement regarding the basis for his conclusion. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> bases this on the
confirmation of his extramarital affair with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sally Hemings</ENAMEX>." This was not an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">extramarital</ENAMEX> affair under any circumstances. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jefferson</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha</ENAMEX>, was
deceased. This makes "extramarital" very difficult. In addition, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hemings</ENAMEX> was
the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jefferson</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jefferson</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hemings</ENAMEX> engaged in a
long-term, and perhaps monogamous, relationship for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">almost 30 years</TIMEX>! She even
accompanied him during his tenure in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>. Where is the correlation to our
modern day <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>?

            I find it easier to
understand <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Noah</ENAMEX>'s claims of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jeffersonian</ENAMEX> hypocrisy. However, even a minute
understanding of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jeffersonian</ENAMEX> history would inform <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Noah</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX> for
decades have considered the inconsistencies among <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jefferson</ENAMEX>'s statements and
actions a hot topic for study.

            Your
inaccurate presentation of history is dangerous. Slow down, take a deep breath,
and be careful if you plan to play <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX>.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David</ENAMEX>
Starmer
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlottesville</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Va.</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Timothy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Noah</ENAMEX> replies: Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starmer</ENAMEX> is right. I am wrong. The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">item</ENAMEX> has been
corrected.
            

            
               Connector
Pork
            

            In "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Foghorn Leghorn Meets</ENAMEX>
an <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Owl</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Plotz</ENAMEX> states, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Inglis</ENAMEX> is so principled, in fact, that he
votes against funding pork projects in his own district. In <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> famous
case, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inglis</ENAMEX> helped kill federal funding for a needed <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">highway</ENAMEX>, requiring the
state to build a toll <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> instead. He has not been forgiven."

            I have certainly forgiven <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bob</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inglis</ENAMEX>. I'm a native <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">New Yorker</ENAMEX> who relocated to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greenville</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">S.C.</ENAMEX>, 10 years
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ago</TIMEX>. In the eyes of my conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> I am a liberal--I consistently
vote <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> and will probably vote for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fritz Hollings</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> thing that
inclines me to vote for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inglis</ENAMEX> is his attempts to kill the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern Connector</ENAMEX>
(the "needed highway" of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plotz</ENAMEX>'s example).

            If there ever was a highway
project that could be defined as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pork</ENAMEX>, it's the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Southern Connector</ENAMEX>. It's a
highway connecting <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> areas already well connected to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Interstate Highway</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">System</ENAMEX>, and will only benefit <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> traveling from the area southwest of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Greenville</ENAMEX> to the area southeast of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greenville</ENAMEX>, and vice versa. Those <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> areas
are already connected by <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">I-85</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">I-385</ENAMEX>. It seems to me an unnecessary expense
to spend many <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">millions of dollars</NUMEX> to reduce a few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s travel time by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX>. The only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greenville</ENAMEX> who support the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Southern Connector</ENAMEX> are
the highway <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contractors</ENAMEX> who will benefit financially from the project.

            While I
disagree with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inglis</ENAMEX>' social agenda, I must admit it's nice to have a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX> who recognizes that there is no such thing as good <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pork</ENAMEX>.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al</ENAMEX>
Vyssotsky
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Greenville</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">S.C.</ENAMEX>

            
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">King</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>
            

            It might
be useful to your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 2</TIMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Explainer</ENAMEX>" to know the reason that "actions in equity" don't get a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> trial. Cases in chancery or equity were/are different from suits brought
under the law. In a lawsuit, you are relying on established rights that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">king</ENAMEX> had laid down; the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jurors</ENAMEX> used to be <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> who
were "familiar" with the subject and who, when shown or told what the statute
said, could make a fair decision and resolve the controversy. Chancery matters
were more like personal problems taken up before the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX> or his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chancellor</ENAMEX>
(chief-of-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>-type <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>). In these cases, you were asking the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX> for a
specific, particularized kind of help (a divorce, apportionment of an estate,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">etc.</ENAMEX>), and the king's ruling was more narrowly applied to you. So, for example,
in this case, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> want the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chancellor</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> to enjoin or
forbid certain <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> practices or conduct. You can't point to a bright-line
rule to make the decision; rather, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> is asked to weigh the equities and
say, "This or that doesn't seem fair to me, and so I order you to do
differently." In law, you say, "The contract/statute/what-have-you says your
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">remedy is X.</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">In chancery</ENAMEX>, you say, "This seems about right to me."

            -- Dianne
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carr</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gloucester</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Va.</ENAMEX>

            
               Good
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lord</ENAMEX>!
            

            Regarding
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 29</TIMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>," I'm afraid you misunderstand how the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> legal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">system</ENAMEX> operates. The appeal is not to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House of Lords</ENAMEX>, with its mixture of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hereditary</ENAMEX> and appointed-for-life peers (the hereditary part is soon to be
swept away by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Labor</ENAMEX>). The appeal goes to the law <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lords</ENAMEX> who sit in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lords</ENAMEX>. They are our equivalent of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> and are made up of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s most distinguished <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX>. Their average age is similar to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justices</ENAMEX>' (which makes them relatively "aging," as you would
expect), but it is a mistake to think they are necessarily "conservative." In
fact, they are pretty liberal <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX>--though it does not follow that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pinochet</ENAMEX> will lose the appeal.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neil</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Editor</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scotsman</ENAMEX> , and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Business</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>

            
               
                  Blue
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Is</ENAMEX> Big
            

            Reading
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Brinkley-Sarah Lyall</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Breakfast Table</ENAMEX>" on the subject of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> press provincialism, I
was horrified to see your <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondents</ENAMEX> describe a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blue Peter</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">presenter</ENAMEX> (recently fired for snorting <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">coke</ENAMEX>) as a "minor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrity</ENAMEX>." Excuse me.
A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blue Peter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presenter</ENAMEX> is not a minor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrity</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blue Peter</ENAMEX> is
huge. Damn near every <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between the ages of six and 10</TIMEX> watches
that show <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every week</TIMEX>! A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blue Peter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presenter</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judy Garland</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">England</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Howard</ENAMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brady</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> rolled into one! It's a deeply lodged
part of the national psyche, and the repository of all manner of naughty
pre-adolescent longings! <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Twenty years</TIMEX> on, I can still recite verbatim an
ingeniously laconic love poem sent to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blue Peter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presenter</ENAMEX> of my
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lesley Judd</ENAMEX> is really fantastic,/ Doing her nut with sticky-back
plastic." (You had to have been there, I guess.) In short, I doubt many
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foreigners</ENAMEX> have heard of Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rogers</ENAMEX>, but if he were caught snorting <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">coke</ENAMEX>, I
rather think it would be considered news.

            

               --Larissa MacFarquhar
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baltimore</ENAMEX>

            
               Address your e-mail to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. You must include your address and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX>
phone number (for confirmation only).
            

         
      
   
