
   
   
      
         
            Why Buy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bose</ENAMEX>?

            You've seen the ads. "The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bose Wave Radio</ENAMEX> is no ordinary radio." It's "a sonic marvel," a "genuine
breakthrough." Such a little thing--barely the size of a shoe box--yet it puts
out the "full, rich sound" of a "primary music system." It costs <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$349</NUMEX>,
startlingly high for a clock radio but not unreasonable if the claims are not
overstated.

            Are the
claims overstated? Come on. How could they not be?

            Not that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bose</ENAMEX> is bad. In fact, it may be the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>-best tabletop radio out there. But just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this month</TIMEX>, what may be the best
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tabletop</ENAMEX> radio hit the market. It's the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambridge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SoundWorks Model 88</ENAMEX> and, at
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$199</NUMEX>, it's very nearly everything the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bose Wave</ENAMEX> claims to be--at a little over
half the price. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambridge</ENAMEX> delivers a smoother, more coherent, more
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rhythmic</ENAMEX>, more dynamic, more tonally true picture of the music.

            For example, on a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vladimir</ENAMEX>
Horowitz piano solo, the keys sounded clangy, a bit metallic, on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bose</ENAMEX>; they
were warmer, but no less hammered, on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambridge</ENAMEX>. When the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">quartet</ENAMEX> Anonymous
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> sang a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">medieval chant</ENAMEX>, I wasn't sure on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bose</ENAMEX> if there were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singers</ENAMEX>
(were there <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>? <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>?)--there was no doubt at all on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambridge</ENAMEX>. When the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heath Brothers</ENAMEX> played a hard-bop jazz tune, the hi-hat cymbal sounded smeared
on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bose</ENAMEX>. I couldn't hear the accent on the beat. On the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambridge</ENAMEX>, I got
the percussive thwack as well as the shimmering whoosh all around it. And
though the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bose</ENAMEX> hit the low octaves of the acoustic bass, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambridge</ENAMEX> caught
the finger-pluckings of the bass strings.

            The
differences weren't night and day. But they were of the sort that, over time,
make you feel at ease or slightly tense--and which, in a moment of leisure,
make you want to stop and really listen or move on to something else.

            
After a while, I hooked up each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> to a
compact disc <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX>. (Both radios sport input jacks in the back for plugging in
a CD <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX>, computer, tape deck, television, or VCR.) I used not some humdrum
portable but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Discovery/Pentagon</ENAMEX> CD-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">70</NUMEX>, a top-of-the-line machine that
retails for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5,000</NUMEX>. And I pulled out <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of my most sonically demanding
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">discs</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henryk Gorecki</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Third Symphony</ENAMEX> , by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">London Symphony</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Orchestra</ENAMEX>, on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nonesuch</ENAMEX>; and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kendra Shank's Afterglow</ENAMEX> , a
chanteuse<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">-plus</NUMEX>-jazz-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">trio</ENAMEX> session, on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mapleshade</ENAMEX>.

            Those
familiar with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gorecki</ENAMEX> know that, on some full-size (if not very good)
stereo systems, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the first minute</TIMEX> or so--bass violins growling quietly--comes
off as a vague rumble, its melody barely audible. Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bose</ENAMEX> and the
Cambridge navigate this passage clearly. However, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambridge</ENAMEX> gets more of
the bowing on the basses, more of their rhythmic inflections. When a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>,
louder bass line starts in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about a minute</TIMEX> into the piece, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bose</ENAMEX> cracks up
for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a second</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambridge</ENAMEX> doesn't exactly keep everything straight (teeny
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speakers</ENAMEX> and teenier amplifiers can do only so much), but it keeps going--it
doesn't lose the thread.

            On the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shank</ENAMEX> disc, when she modulates her voice, accenting
a certain word or dipping another to a whisper, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bose</ENAMEX> makes it sound as if
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineer</ENAMEX> is sharply turning up or down the volume. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambridge</ENAMEX> gets the
subtleties right.

            How do
these radios eke such relatively big sounds out of such small boxes? The Bose
isn't exactly a technical "breakthrough," but it is clever. In the back of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speakers</ENAMEX> is a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX> foot tube that has been folded into a thin, tight maze to fit
inside the radio box. The frequency of a sound wave is defined by its length:
The longer the wave, the deeper the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bass</ENAMEX>. Such a long tube gives sound waves
lots of room to enlarge. Each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX> is also powered by an amplifier equipped
with circuits that boost the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bass</ENAMEX> as you turn up the volume. However, once the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speakers</ENAMEX> get to the middle and upper octaves, their limitations become more
apparent; hence, the steely pianos, smeared cymbals, ungainly dynamics, and the
rest.

            
The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambridge</ENAMEX> SoundWorks <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">88</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">half an inch</NUMEX>
taller but otherwise the same size as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bose</ENAMEX>, takes a different approach. Its
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bass</ENAMEX> comes from a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">4 1/2 inch</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">woofer cone</ENAMEX>, which takes up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two-thirds</NUMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">radio</ENAMEX>'s internal space and is powered by its own amplifier. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> smaller
main <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speakers</ENAMEX>, each of which has its own amp, are freed up to focus their
energies on the less burdensome middle and treble octaves. (The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">88</TIMEX> also has a
separate volume knob for the woofer, so you can adjust the bass level, which
would otherwise depend greatly on room placement.)

            The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">88</NUMEX> is
designed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Kloss</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hi-fi</ENAMEX> legend who made his mark (with the KLH
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speakers</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1950s</TIMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Advents</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '60s</TIMEX>) by figuring out how to
manipulate electronics so that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX> sounds smooth from octave to octave.
He applied <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">47 years</TIMEX> of experience with this art to the rather skimpy components
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Model 88</ENAMEX>, which explains how he gets such a smooth, coherent sound from
not only a small <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">box</ENAMEX> but also a cheap one.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bose</ENAMEX> is the property of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amar Bose</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> long regarded as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hi-fi</ENAMEX>'s most brilliant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">marketer</ENAMEX> but whose products tend to be built around a
technical fad. His <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Bose 901</ENAMEX> loudspeakers, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s premium line for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX> cones, positioned all over the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cabinet</ENAMEX>, so that the
sound bounces around your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> "just like in a concert <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hall</ENAMEX>." <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> problem,
among many, is that most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s living <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> aren't <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carnegie Hall</ENAMEX>; as a
result, the music just sounds muddy. His methods also encourage high prices:
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">The 901s</TIMEX> cost <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,400</NUMEX> a pair (some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> make <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$300</NUMEX> speakers that sound
better) because <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> cones cost more than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two or three</NUMEX>; the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wave</ENAMEX> radio costs
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$350</NUMEX> because that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX> foot tube was a bear to design. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wave</ENAMEX> is one of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bose</ENAMEX>'s
better devices. But he stretched too far, in his price tag and his claims, and
now <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kloss</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambridge</ENAMEX> has delivered his comeuppance.

            (Both radios are sold through
mail-order, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bose</ENAMEX> from [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">800</ENAMEX>] <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">681</NUMEX>-BOSE, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambridge SoundWorks</ENAMEX> from [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">800</ENAMEX>]
FOR-HIFI.)

         
      
   
