
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">140</NUMEX>:

            By <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cohen</ENAMEX>

            
               According
to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychiatrist Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Krueger</ENAMEX>, "Part of the reason so many women
take these types of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> tend to have trouble admitting they have
a problem." What types of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>?
            

            by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon ET</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> to e-mail your answer to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.

            
               Responses
to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s question (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 139</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Notions":</ENAMEX>
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toys</ENAMEX>, comic books, nail
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">polish</ENAMEX>, and jewelry. What's the connection?
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Things John Glenn</ENAMEX> played
with while the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">astronauts</ENAMEX> were doing actual work."--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jon</ENAMEX>
Hotchkiss
            

            "Items currently preferred
as currency over the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> ruble."--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alex Balk</ENAMEX>
            

            "Oh, God. Is there another
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'new</ENAMEX> look' <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">for Superman on the way?</ENAMEX>"--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Solovay</ENAMEX>
            

            "Items that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blair Cabinet</ENAMEX> have officially been 'urged to discard.' From their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX>,
anyway."--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Bodow</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Rakoff</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Ricci</ENAMEX> had
similar answers.)

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tie-in</ENAMEX> merchandise from
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Siege</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed Zwick</ENAMEX> gave to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al Iman School</ENAMEX> to 'smooth
things over with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX>.' "--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Radosh</ENAMEX>
            

            Click for more
responses.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
            

            It is, of
course, the juxtaposition of childish amusements and adult ornamentation that
makes this list so pleasingly perverse. Similarly, it is the odd juxtaposition
of references that makes "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">News Quiz</ENAMEX>" responses so perversely pleasing: (click
for more, and you really should because there's terrific stuff on Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sontag</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Jackson</ENAMEX>'s ass, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glue sniffing</ENAMEX> and the ruble, IPOs and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sandler</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MacGyver</ENAMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>. It's the kind of high-low juxtaposition--of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reference</ENAMEX>, of language, of moral importance--that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woody Allen</ENAMEX> executes so
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">wonderfully</ENAMEX>, such as in this excerpt from "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Scrolls</ENAMEX>": "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whosoever</ENAMEX> shall not
fall by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">sword</ENAMEX> or by famine shall fall by pestilence, so why bother
shaving<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>" Now, sadly, his personal life is itself reduced to a comic
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">juxtaposition</ENAMEX>. And if you enjoy that sort of thing, here's a little
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">juxtaposition</ENAMEX> game you can play when you spot odd pairings of the bald and the
beautiful; it's a betting game called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Date or Daughter?</ENAMEX>" Enjoy.

            
               Parochial
Answer
            

            As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Radosh</ENAMEX> and others
knew, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> may not bring any of these items to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al Iman School</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Queens</ENAMEX>,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Long Island</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>.

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">480,000</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>--one in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>--attend one of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,400</NUMEX> registered parochial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>, which
are mostly <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX>. Nationwide, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about one</NUMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50 million</NUMEX>
schoolchildren attend religious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>, of which <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 200</NUMEX> are
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Islamic</ENAMEX>.

            On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Supreme</ENAMEX>
Court let stand a ruling permitting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayer</ENAMEX>-financed vouchers to send <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> to
Milwaukee parochial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>.

            The court
also let stand a ruling giving royalty rights to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kingsmen</ENAMEX> for their <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1963</TIMEX>
hit recording of "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louie</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louie</ENAMEX>." But don't try singing it in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">halls</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iman</ENAMEX>.

            
               Dream
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Team Extra</ENAMEX>
            

            Match the
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">60 Minutes II</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondent</ENAMEX> with the impressive attribute ascribed to
him or her by gushing executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff Fager</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan</ENAMEX>
Rather

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simon</ENAMEX>

            Vicki
Mabrey

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlie Rose</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A.</ENAMEX> "An
amazing hunger for stories."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B.</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A</ENAMEX>
workhorse like no other."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">C.</ENAMEX> "A fresh
face."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D.</ENAMEX> "Fishlike
gills that let him breathe underwater."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">E.</ENAMEX> "The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Beatles</ENAMEX> of the puppet world."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">F.</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A</ENAMEX>
fatuous worldview expressed in banal language."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">G. "Which</ENAMEX> one is he
again?"

            

               Answers
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">A. Charlie</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rose</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B. Dan</ENAMEX>
Rather

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Vicki</ENAMEX>
Mabrey

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D.</ENAMEX> Aquaman
(not signed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS News</ENAMEX>)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">E.</ENAMEX> How
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caroll</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Big Bird</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spinney</ENAMEX> describes the late <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Henson</ENAMEX> (not signed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX>
News, but wouldn't you be more inclined to watch if he were?)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">F.</ENAMEX> Some wise
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">guy</ENAMEX> describing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Rather</ENAMEX> (OK, it was me)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">G. Same</ENAMEX> wise
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">guy on Bob Simon</ENAMEX>

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Disclaimer</ENAMEX>: All submissions will become the property of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> and
will be published at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> 's discretion. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> may publish your
name on its site in connection with your submission.
            

         
      
   
