
   
   
      
         
            Sambo Returns

            It only took <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few days</TIMEX> of
national publicity to force a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> to cancel a course on the
theme that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slaves</ENAMEX> were happy on the plantation. But this idea is
popping up elsewhere: not just among the conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defenders</ENAMEX> of the Old
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South</ENAMEX>, but even on the left.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ball</ENAMEX>, a scion of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slave owners</ENAMEX>, won a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">National Book Award</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slaves</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Family</ENAMEX> , a sentimental genealogy of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clan</ENAMEX>. The book
exudes what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arthur Schlesinger Jr.</ENAMEX> once called "doughface" liberalism. Ball
marvels that he may possess <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of black "blood kin" who are descended
from his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ancestors</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">captives</ENAMEX>. He suggests with a can't-we-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">just</NUMEX>-get-along
naiveté that they're really all part of the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slavery</ENAMEX>'s barbarism
gets lost in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ball</ENAMEX>'s New Age journey of self-discovery.

            Meanwhile, new DNA evidence strongly indicates that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thomas</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jefferson</ENAMEX> did indeed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father children</ENAMEX> by his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slave</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sally Hemings</ENAMEX>. Because
Hemings was the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jefferson</ENAMEX>'s deceased <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, and because their
relationship may have lasted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX>, the story has taken on a romantic
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">coloration</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Historian Eric Foner</ENAMEX> mocks that it is as if "he and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sally</ENAMEX> were a
kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Romeo and Juliet</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX>-crossed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lovers doomed</ENAMEX> by an inflexible
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">society</ENAMEX>."

            The
college course was titled "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">War</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern</ENAMEX>
Independence." (That's <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">the Civil War</ENAMEX> to y'all.) At <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Randolph</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community College</ENAMEX>
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Archdale</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.C.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sons of Confederate Veterans</ENAMEX> have been
teaching, as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Associated Press</ENAMEX> reported, that "most slaves were happy in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">captivity</ENAMEX> and that many served as loyal <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southern</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX>." According to one
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">instructor</ENAMEX>, "These <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> [i.e., the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">slaves</ENAMEX>] loved the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX>. They weren't
looking for some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yankees</ENAMEX> to come down here and save them."

            
Any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> can tell you that much of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sunny Slavery Scenario</ENAMEX> is nonsense. Few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slaves</ENAMEX> fought for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Confederacy</ENAMEX>,
though <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">180,000</NUMEX> former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slaves</ENAMEX> fought for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North</ENAMEX> . And <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slaves</ENAMEX> did want
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> to free them. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leon Litwack</ENAMEX> recounts in his copiously
researched Been in the Storm So Long , they rejoiced to the skies when
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">troops</ENAMEX> arrived to liberate them. They considered it a deliverance of biblical
proportions.

            Still, leave aside the
course, which was canceled <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Thursday</TIMEX> after protests from the National
intentionally set up any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> that is offensive to anyone in our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> ...
and, obviously, this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> has done that," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> said.) What
was the true <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> of bondage in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">American South</ENAMEX>? On that
question, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historians</ENAMEX> have never agreed. Opinions have shifted with the
prevailing political and cultural winds, and the issue remains alive.

            For this,
the left is as responsible as the right. Confederate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enthusiasts</ENAMEX> have made free
use of liberal arguments for academic freedom, tolerance, and multiculturalism.
They say they are just exercising their right to teach their version of events.
("Everybody can celebrate their culture, but we can't," groused another course
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">instructor</ENAMEX>.) Left-wing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX> have also done the most work to refute the view
of slavery as a crippling experience.

            Alittle historiography is in order. Not so long ago, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Randolph Community College</ENAMEX> view of slaves as happy in their bondage--smiling,
singing "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sambos</ENAMEX>"--was the dominant view, even among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX>. (The "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX>," of
course, were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX> who in general believed themselves innately superior to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX>.) Led by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southern</ENAMEX>-born <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ulrich Phillips</ENAMEX>, whose <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Negro</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slavery</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1918</TIMEX>) was the standard work in the field for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX>, leading
academic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historians</ENAMEX> portrayed slavery as a benevolent, paternalistic
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">institution</ENAMEX> that benefited blacks by civilizing them. In this view, it was
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX> who suffered under the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slave</ENAMEX> system, since before <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">the Civil War</ENAMEX>, slavery
had become far less profitable than the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North</ENAMEX>'s capitalist labor arrangements.
Yet <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slave owners selflessly</ENAMEX> bore this burden so their slaves could enjoy
continued care and goodwill.

            It wasn't
until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1956</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Stampp</ENAMEX> published The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peculiar Institution</ENAMEX> , that
the historical profession--and the textbooks that take their cues from
it--seriously revised the picture of bondage. Besides cataloging the
brutalities of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slave owners</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Stampp</ENAMEX> showed that slaves actually did not
appreciate the experience. He noted their rebelliousness: their efforts to rise
up and throw off their shackles, the ways they cagily resisted their work
requirements, the lengths they went to in feigning contentment to elude
harsh treatment from their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masters</ENAMEX>. The happy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sambo, Stampp</ENAMEX> claimed, was just a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ruse</ENAMEX>.

            
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Three years later</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stanley Elkins</ENAMEX> published the
equally monumental <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slavery</ENAMEX> . Though a liberal like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stampp</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Elkins</ENAMEX>
accepted the notion of the docile, contented <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sambo</ENAMEX>--though hardly as evidence
of slavery's mildness. Influenced by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychoanalyst</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruno Bettelheim</ENAMEX>'s
research showing that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> concentration camps "infantilized" their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inmates</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Elkins</ENAMEX> argued that the "closed system" of slavery was so cruel and
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all</NUMEX>-encompassing that none but the most stouthearted could survive without
their wills being broken or their psyches damaged. Liberal social <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">latched</ENAMEX> onto <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Elkins</ENAMEX>' theory as a rationale for creating policies to tear down
the barriers that were impeding black advancement in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1960s</TIMEX>.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sociologist Nathan Glazer</ENAMEX> reviewed <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Slavery for Commentary and</ENAMEX>
gave a copy to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Patrick Moynihan</ENAMEX>, then an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lyndon Johnson</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1965</TIMEX> came the famous <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moynihan</ENAMEX> report on the condition of
black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>. Influenced by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Elkins</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moynihan</ENAMEX> suggested that slavery--and the
barriers to male employment imposed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Crow</ENAMEX>--had instilled in
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-American</ENAMEX> culture such recurring features as broken <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">illegitimacy</ENAMEX>. He called for governmental action to undo the damage.

            Next, left-wing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historians</ENAMEX> rose up to defend black culture
against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moynihan</ENAMEX>'s characterizations. In doing so, they partly absolved
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">slavery</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herbert Gutman</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Black Family in Slavery and Freedom</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1750-1925</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1976</TIMEX>) showed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slave families</ENAMEX>, while often broken up when
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> were sold or assigned to different <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plantations</ENAMEX>, were remarkably
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">monogamous</ENAMEX> and stable. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1974</TIMEX>, the radical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eugene Genovese</ENAMEX> (who has
since become a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservative</ENAMEX>) published <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Roll</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jordan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Roll</ENAMEX>: The
World the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Slaves Made</ENAMEX> . Now a staple in college history <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courses</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Roll</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX>, Roll painted a picture of slaves not as mere <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> of oppression
but as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">creators</ENAMEX> of a vibrant life. While obviously constrained by their
bondage, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> nonetheless forged a culture rich with religious observances,
folk tales, family traditions, song, and so on. Genovese transformed the debate
by making slaves, at long last, central and even powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> in shaping
their own lives.

            Many on the left thrilled to
this portrait. Neither <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Genovese</ENAMEX> nor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gutman</ENAMEX> would ever argue, like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sons of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Confederate Veterans</ENAMEX>, that slaves were happy in their condition as slaves. But
they might agree that slaves were sometimes happy despite their
condition as slaves. And it's here that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Left</ENAMEX>'s scrupulous scholarship
inadvertently dovetails with the right's racist interpretations. Thanks to
Gutman, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Genovese</ENAMEX>, and their left-wing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peers</ENAMEX>, we now know that the notion that
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Slaves Were Happy</ENAMEX>," as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> headline put it, is not
necessarily false.

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early decades</TIMEX> of this
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">century</ENAMEX>, when racist views were the norm, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phillips</ENAMEX>' picture of slavery as
benevolent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX> held sway. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1956</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stampp</ENAMEX>'s view of slaves as being
just like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX> except for their subjugation reflected the tenets of postwar
liberalism. In the era of black power, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Left</ENAMEX> assertions that slaves made
their own lives resonated loudly. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> we have a therapeutic culture. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president champions</ENAMEX> a touchy-feely "national conversation" on race, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defenders</ENAMEX>
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Confederacy</ENAMEX> just want to tell their side of the story, school officials
worry about offending the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed Ball</ENAMEX>, inspired by the confirmation
of shared <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX>, wants to use his book profits to fund interracial dialogue.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slavery</ENAMEX> has returned as little more than a failure to communicate.

         
      
   
