
   
   
      
         
            Party of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Virtue</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Party</ENAMEX> of Vice

            
               "Campaign <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">'98</TIMEX>"
dispatches from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Carolina</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">governor</ENAMEX>).
            

            The important thing for a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pundit</ENAMEX> is to be sure of his or her opinions. There is no penalty for being sure
of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> thing now and sure of something else later. Until <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6 p.m. ET</TIMEX>, when the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> returns came in, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> were certain that there would be no
"message" <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX>. This would be a status quo election, no big issues were
galvanizing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>, nothing enormous would be decided.

            But by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7:45 p.m.</TIMEX>, the effort
to impeach <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> was "dead as a dodo," and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MSNBC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> were
wondering how long it would be till enraged <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> deposed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX>
as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>. By <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 p.m.</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chuck Schumer</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Senate</ENAMEX>
victory was announced, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the evening</TIMEX> had officially become a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rout</ENAMEX>.

            The best
line of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night</TIMEX> came from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred Thompson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tenn.</ENAMEX>, when some cable news
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">anchor</ENAMEX> asked him to assess the election results so far: "When these things
aren't going your way, you say, 'It's still early.' So, I guess it's still
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early</TIMEX>."

            In terms of seats changing hands, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic</ENAMEX>
victory--though remarkable--is very small. <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Tonight</TIMEX>'s real landslide victory
belongs to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>. First, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Party</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Virtue</ENAMEX>. It was a clean sweep
for the good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX>. In tight race after tight race, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> have rejected the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">venal</ENAMEX> and the wicked. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX> dumped embarrassing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lauch Faircloth</ENAMEX>
in favor of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Edwards</ENAMEX>, who can't possibly be worse. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alabama</ENAMEX> dropped its
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">ill</ENAMEX>-behaved <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fob James</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">New Yorkers</ENAMEX> had the wisdom to retire their
chief sleaze, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al D'Amato</ENAMEX>, in favor of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schumer</ENAMEX>, who has all <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D'Amato</ENAMEX>'s good
qualities and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only half</NUMEX> of his bad ones. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maryland</ENAMEX> re-elected a harmless
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mediocrity</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parris Glendening</ENAMEX>) over a holy terror (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellen Sauerbrey</ENAMEX>). And
to prove that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Party</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Virtue</ENAMEX> is bipartisan, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX> may drop ethically
challenged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carol Moseley</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Braun</ENAMEX>. Any one of those results constitutes a
minor improvement in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> politics. All of them together constitute a near
miracle.

            (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tonight</ENAMEX>'s actual miracle:
Reform <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Party</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Body</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ventura</ENAMEX> leads in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX>'s race. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> has had plenty of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">athlete politicians</ENAMEX> and plenty of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor politicians</ENAMEX>. Now, at last, we can have both in one package: a pro
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">wrestler</ENAMEX>.)

            The other
big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">winner</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, oddly enough, was the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Party</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice</ENAMEX>. There is much
crowing about the resurgence of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic Party</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX>, given Fritz
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hollings</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> victory, gubernatorial upsets in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Carolina</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alabama</ENAMEX>,
and a probable gubernatorial win in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgia</ENAMEX>. Why has this happened? Because the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Party</ENAMEX> has become the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lottery Party</ENAMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgia</ENAMEX>, retiring <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zell Miller</ENAMEX> instituted a hugely popular state lottery that has raised <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">tens</NUMEX>
of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">millions of dollars</NUMEX> for public education. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roy Barnes</ENAMEX>, who promised
to continue <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miller</ENAMEX>'s policies, is winning the election to succeed him. In
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alabama</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Carolina</ENAMEX>, the incumbent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governors</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> conservative
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> Fob <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Beasley</ENAMEX>, resisted efforts to start
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Georgia</ENAMEX>-style <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lotteries</ENAMEX>. They are both getting thrown out of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>, defeated
by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> running on pro-lottery <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">platforms</ENAMEX>. Who says the lottery is a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sucker</ENAMEX>'s gamble?

            As they do during the final
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX> of every campaign, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Turnout Bores</ENAMEX> have hijacked the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">'98</NUMEX> election. They
have persuaded most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> that this campaign is a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pudding</ENAMEX> without a
theme, that there are no galvanizing issues, and that everything hinges
on which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> does a better job getting its core <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> to the polls. (The
question: Can my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">seniors</ENAMEX> beat your <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX>?)

            Never mind that every
election hinges on turnout. Accept that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Turnout Bores</ENAMEX> are onto something.
In fact, why not take their theory a step further? The election depends on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">turnout</ENAMEX>. And what, more than anything, does turnout depend on? The weather, of
course.

            To that
end, 
                  Slate
                offers <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a real Election Day</TIMEX> forecast, predicting the
outcomes of close <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> and gubernatorial races based on the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> weather
map in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> . (Why <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> ? It does not suffer
from the notorious liberal meteorological bias that afflicts the New York
Times and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> .) 
                  In the interest of accuracy,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> has updated the predictions based on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> 's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> forecast.
The updated predictions appear in italics after the original
predictions.
               
            

            According to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> , most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> will
experience cloudy but good weather <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rain</ENAMEX> will fall from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Idaho</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Georgia</ENAMEX>. At <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> glance, the map looks like good news for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>: They have
close races in many of the rain-drenched <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rain</ENAMEX> generally benefits
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>, who can count on fervent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> to get to the polls in any
weather. But a closer analysis of the weather map suggests Mother Nature
actually favors the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>. (The survey starts in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northeast</ENAMEX>
and works its way clockwise around the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. It covers most but not all
close <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> and gubernatorial races.)

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cool</ENAMEX> and
cloudy but no <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rain</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> should turn out smartly in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>, helping
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chuck Schumer</ENAMEX> unseat <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al D'Amato</ENAMEX>.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maryland</ENAMEX>: There is a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">30 percent</NUMEX> chance of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rain</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX>, which means
that there is a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">30 percent</NUMEX> chance of an <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellen Sauerbrey</ENAMEX> victory in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX>'s race. Her fervent <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">followers</ENAMEX> would go to the polls in a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">typhoon</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parris Glendening</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> are so unenthused that they'll
stay <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> if it merely drizzles. It's raining in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> this morning:
Chalk this one up for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sauerbrey</ENAMEX>.
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX> : A deceptive forecast.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rain</ENAMEX> ought to help incumbent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lauch Faircloth</ENAMEX>, but it actually favors
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> challenger <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Edwards</ENAMEX>. Showers are expected only in the
western <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, which is especially conservative. The rain
could suppress <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> turnout in the west without lowering <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">turnout</ENAMEX> in the center of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edwards</ENAMEX> scores an upset. The updated
forecast suggests it will rain across the entire <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, suppressing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic</ENAMEX>
turnout too. This will help <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Faircloth</ENAMEX> win.
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Carolina</ENAMEX> : As in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX>, the election could hang on how far east it rains. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northwestern</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Carolina</ENAMEX>, the only part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> that's supposed to get rain, is
heavily <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>. If this forecast holds, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> upstate may stay home,
but <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> in the southeast won't. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fritz Hollings</ENAMEX> should
hold his seat, and gubernatorial candidate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Hodges</ENAMEX> should upset <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Beasley</ENAMEX>. If it rains across the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Inglis</ENAMEX>
could go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beasley</ENAMEX> could keep the governorship. More bad
news for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s forecast calls for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rain</ENAMEX> across the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. Beasley
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inglis</ENAMEX> benefit.
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Georgia</ENAMEX> : <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Showers</ENAMEX> over
the entire <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> will deter <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">incumbent Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Coverdell</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> gubernatorial candidate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guy Millner</ENAMEX> will win their tight races.
It stops raining in the western <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, perhaps raising turnout
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Democratic Atlanta</ENAMEX>.
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kentucky</ENAMEX> : A bitter <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pill</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scotty Baesler</ENAMEX>,
who has been running even against <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Bunning</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bunning</ENAMEX>'s campaign
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> was quoted on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> saying that "if it rains, we win." Forecast: rain
across the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> pick up a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> seat.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nevada</ENAMEX> : <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dry</ENAMEX> and warm, as always. This
will slightly help <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">incumbent Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Reid</ENAMEX> in his tossup race with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Ensign</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> : Clear
weather throughout the state keeps turnout high and aids <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> Sen.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara Boxer</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> gubernatorial candidate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gray Davis</ENAMEX>. They win
easily. Rain in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Northern California</ENAMEX> could cut <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">turnout</ENAMEX>. This may
lead <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> challenger <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Fong</ENAMEX> and gubernatorial candidate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lungren</ENAMEX> to upset victories.
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> : <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News</ENAMEX>
flash: It's not going to rain in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX>! <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Turnout</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> will
be heavy, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patty Murray</ENAMEX> will hold off <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> challenger <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX>. Oops! Now it is supposed to rain in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX>.
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wisconsin</ENAMEX> : <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold</ENAMEX> but
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dry</ENAMEX>, which should give a small boost to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russ Feingold</ENAMEX>.

            And the wild card pick:
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carol Moseley</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Braun</ENAMEX> has been rising in the polls, but she
still seems to trail <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> challenger <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Fitzgerald</ENAMEX>. Good news for
Moseley-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Braun</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>, her stronghold, will have dry
weather, and heavily <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> downstate <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX> will be soaked. She holds
her seat against all expectations. The new forecast says <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> weather
will be "dismal," just as bad as it is downstate. Sorry, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carol</ENAMEX>.
            

            (We promise that these

                  Slate
                predictions are just as reliable as the weather forecasts
they're based on.)

         
      
   
