
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">149</NUMEX>:

            By <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cohen</ENAMEX>

            
               Fill in
the blank.
            

            
               The pay is bad, the
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> are irregular, and there's that nettlesome <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> background check. Small
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">wonder Shirley Phillips</ENAMEX> says, "Being a ___________ makes one feel subhuman and
as low on the totem pole as one can get."
            

            by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> to
e-mail your answer to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.

            
               Responses
to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s question (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 148</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Season's Grating":</ENAMEX>
            

            
               A family photo, the
single word "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Noel</ENAMEX>," a naked babe draped in colored lights sipping
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">champagne</ENAMEX>--there are many styles of holiday card, and now's the time to mail
them. You were invited to describe the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> card sure to be sent by a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">corporation</ENAMEX>, world <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>, or other personage.
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cover: 'With best wishes</ENAMEX>
for the holy <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">missionaries</ENAMEX> to the pre-born.' Inside: 'You've
just been exposed to anthrax!' "-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katha Pollitt</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Picture: A</ENAMEX> still from
Beloved . Message: 'For your consider ... I mean, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Happy Holidays</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Love</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oprah</ENAMEX>.' "-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Radosh</ENAMEX>
            

            "From the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Philip Morris</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Co. Outside Santa</ENAMEX>'s workshop, in subzero temperatures, the elves hang out
during their cigarette break."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danny Spiegel</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">From Lewis Lapham</ENAMEX>. No
illustration, just text. Its tone somehow both baleful and bemused, wistful yet
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">wan</ENAMEX>. It starts with a quote from either <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Adams</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alexis de Tocqueville</ENAMEX>,
and I stop reading it <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about a quarter</NUMEX> of the way through."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kelly</ENAMEX>
            

            "A damp, illegible <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Easter</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">card</ENAMEX> signed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Yeltsin</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Carvell</ENAMEX>
            

            Click for more
responses.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
            

            A slightly
Lenovian question, perhaps--it's easy to picture him holding up the komedy
kards, then rushing out to buy another kollectible kar--but it was redeemed by
some deft responses. I can only plead holiday malaise. Or seasonal affective
disorder. (It gets dark so early when you lie in bed brooding until <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 in the</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX>.) Oh, wait, I know what it was--overwork. And then that rush, rush to
get away for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the holiday weekend</TIMEX>, bustling off to catch the high-speed maglev
train that would whisk me swiftly and economically to the countryside, where,
refreshed by the more historically nuanced brooding of my jolly <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chekhovian</ENAMEX>
family, I'd wander the woods and fields, dodging bullets from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hunters</ENAMEX> too
groggy on <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">turkey tryptophans</ENAMEX> to distinguish between a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">deer</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jew</ENAMEX>. Or maybe
just groggy enough. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Boy</ENAMEX> could I use a drink purchased at a cash bar.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Home</ENAMEX> for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holidays Extra</ENAMEX>
            

            Some activities from the most
recent "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Weekend</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guide</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Reading</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pa.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eagle</ENAMEX> .

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Grill Fire Company Bingo</ENAMEX>.
Free! <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Coffee</ENAMEX>, doughnuts, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">candy</ENAMEX>, hot <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chocolate</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tea</ENAMEX>, and dappers to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New-comers</ENAMEX>."
(I'm so full after the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX>, doughnuts, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">candy</ENAMEX>, hot <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chocolate</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tea</ENAMEX>, I
can't eat a single dapper. Assuming it is something you eat.)

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hog Butchering</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Landis</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Valley Museum</ENAMEX> will present <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteers</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Landis Valley Cookbook Committee</ENAMEX>,
in traditional dress, demonstrating the various steps to preparing a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">hog</ENAMEX> for
consumption. Skills on display will be: scalding, sausage stuffing, lard
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rendering</ENAMEX>, scrapple making, and much more." (Like after a scalding demo, I'd
even think about more.)

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Virginville Hotel</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">All</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Can-Eat Shepherd's Pie</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Pork 'n' Sauerkraut</ENAMEX>." (It's a heck of a bargain,
but after the scalding and the lard rendering, I've pretty much had a full
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">evening</ENAMEX>'s porkertainment.)

            "The Reading <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Comedy Outlet</ENAMEX> at
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sheraton Berkshire</ENAMEX> presents <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">'Giggles & Ribs,' a comedy Dinner Package</ENAMEX>."
(I like giggles, and I love ribs, and yet ...)

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">2 nd Story Lounge</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Exotic Night Club</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2-for-1</NUMEX> private dances. Closed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thanksgiving</TIMEX>. Happy
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thanksgiving</ENAMEX>!" (So you're saying if I want an inexpensive private dance on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thanksgiving</ENAMEX>, too bad for me???)

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Deer Chaser Native</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American-Lakota Dance Troupe</ENAMEX> will perform <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Narvon Valley</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bison Farm</ENAMEX>, in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lancaster County</ENAMEX>." (No doubt fascinating, but is it <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> for
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>?)

            "Experience the magic of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Appalachian Pet Farm</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cougars</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bear</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Monkey</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reptile</ENAMEX> room
open." (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> isn't <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> without monkeys and reptiles.)

            Not really a weekend
entertainment but a holiday bargain: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beer Mart on Morgantown Road</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">announces</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Beer Makes a Great Gift</ENAMEX>. Gift Certificates and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Variety Packs</ENAMEX>."
(It's like the gift of the drunken, bloated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Magi</ENAMEX>.)

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Disclaimer</ENAMEX>: All submissions will become the property of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> and
will be published at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> 's discretion. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> may publish your
name on its site in connection with your submission.
            

         
      
   
