
   
   
      
         
            

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 30</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, Nov. 13, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
story claims that probable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX> apparent <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Livingston</ENAMEX> will face the
same bickering and upheaval that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX> did. Why? <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> coalition
is still wildly divided ideologically; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) rules that impose term limits on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> chairs mean <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> are always jockeying for their next
powerful position; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) the self-imposed term limits of many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> encourage them to eschew working within the system in favor of making
trouble.

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times Magazine</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 15</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, Nov. 13, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            A special
issue about status. (It follows special issues about money and business travel:
We get the idea, already.) An essay distinguishes between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> and status:
Class is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Old World</ENAMEX>, assigned and never changing. Status is <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX>, attained
and fought for. Accompanying short pieces reveal status symbols for various
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cliques</ENAMEX>. For retirement-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">villagers</ENAMEX>, a valid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX>'s license; for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vegetarians</ENAMEX>,
eating only raw <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">foods</ENAMEX>; for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gamblers</ENAMEX>, winning so much that you're
banned from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">casino</ENAMEX>; for gay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, an adopted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX>; for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">priests</ENAMEX>,
fancy cuff links, their only outlet for vanity.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 16</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Nov. 10, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX> is on both
covers, post-mortems on his resignation and the elections are inside. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">newsweeklies</ENAMEX> agree that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX>'s ego did him in. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">salutes</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX>'s soldierly campaigning: She swung
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> especially, in almost all the races she worked on. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> reason
why: As a wronged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> is unassailable by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> gets the best quote from Jesse "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Mind</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ventura</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor-elect</ENAMEX>:
"In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX> I was at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Minnesota</ENAMEX>, and all these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> said, 'We're
voting for you.' And so I asked them, 'Why are you voting for me?' And the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> said, ' 'Cause you're cool.' And I thought, 'Well, good
enough. I'll take that.' I am cool. ... <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mentally</ENAMEX>, I'm still <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">22</NUMEX> in a lot
of ways."

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George</ENAMEX>
Stephanopoulos outlines keys to an <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> presidential campaign: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) He must
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">express</ENAMEX> a clear agenda, not just be "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> without the personal baggage." <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>)
He must parry <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX>' attacks better. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) He needs to get lucky the way
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> did in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>.

            

               Time notices the meteoric rise of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Onion</ENAMEX> , once a small
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Wisconsin</ENAMEX> humor 'zine, now a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> on the Web. Its secret is
deadpan parodies of news stories (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Report: Drug Use Down Among Uncool Kids</ENAMEX>").
Books and TV specials are on the way.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News & World Report</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 16</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Nov. 10, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            The lead
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> leaps onto the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> bandwagon. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>,
who gets high marks for his positivism and inclusiveness, may succeed in the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">race</ENAMEX>, because he can steer clear of the flailing <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>. Obstacle: He may not have the guts to withstand a "<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX>-grinder"
campaign. ... A story asks if <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> is the new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Weimar</ENAMEX>. Parallels abound, from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tottering</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> (akin to weak pre-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler President Hindenburg</ENAMEX>) to
vulturous oligarchs (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Weimar</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tycoons</ENAMEX>) to the staggering inflation and recession.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> important differences: As yet, no proto-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> figure has emerged in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weimar</ENAMEX> didn't have itself as an example to avoid ... An
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> surveys <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX>'s economic woes and finds glimmers of hope,
from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malaysia</ENAMEX>'s currency stability to the nationalization of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Korea</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 16</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Nov. 10, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            An essay
hates the new "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">super-Capone</ENAMEX>" strategy used by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kenneth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> nailed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capone</ENAMEX> for tax evasion instead of murder. Now,
zealous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> in search of big game use even pettier crimes to indict
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> of the true target, coercing testimony with the threat of legal
action. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> pressured <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathleen Willey</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julie Hiatt Steele</ENAMEX> by
questioning the legality of her adoption of a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Romanian</ENAMEX> orphan. "[I]nvestigative
techniques that seem perfectly reasonable when they're applied to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">murderers</ENAMEX> or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mafia</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dons</ENAMEX> may be unreasonable when they're applied to speeders, jaywalkers, or
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty-five-year-old</TIMEX> seductresses." ... A story follows a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Montana</ENAMEX> punk
band named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sputnik</ENAMEX> on its shoestring-budget tour of small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clubs</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Punks</ENAMEX> face a
dilemma: If they stay underground, they can't support themselves and they're
miserable; if they get popular, they've sold out and will be both self-loathing
and rejected by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sputnik</ENAMEX> hasn't had to face the latter problem yet.

            

               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 16</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Nov. 10, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            An essay
argues that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> did not reject <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> because of the way they handled
the scandal. In fact, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> won because they have seized congressional
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> of issues such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>, and education, despite the
fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governors</ENAMEX> are winning with those same issues. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>'s "bedrock
strength is its willingness directly to confront troublesome questions of
public and private morality. ... Someone must step forward who is capable of
making the case for conservative principle as the animating force of a
governing <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>." ... A funny set of dispatches chronicles
Election <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Night at</ENAMEX>, among other places, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">DNC</ENAMEX> victory party (hastily assembled
when it became clear there was something to celebrate), the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RNC</ENAMEX> "victory" party
(still termed so despite being less than victorious), the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFL-CIO</ENAMEX> headquarters
(where they wouldn't watch <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> news because of a labor dispute), and a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marietta</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ga.</ENAMEX> filled with glum <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nation</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 23</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Nov. 10, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            The
cover package assesses
the future of progressive politics. A postelection editorial on ballot measures
asserts that progressives won big on campaign finance reform (in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX>), but lost on cultural issues (gay marriage bans in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alaska</ENAMEX>). (For 
                  Slate
               's take on this theory, see "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Triumph of ...</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Liberalism?</ENAMEX>") ... An article cheers the ascendance of "living wage"
movements in local politics. The author argues that these movements, which aim
to bring higher wages and more benefits to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>, are beneficial even if they
force some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> that support them.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 7</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Nov. 7, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            The
cover editorial marvels that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has been
shown to be "a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liar</ENAMEX> and a philanderer" yet "still he comes back laughing." But
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> should pursue impeachment, regardless of the election results: "If
they believed that they had grounds for an inquiry, it should be a thorough
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, for this election has no effect on those grounds." ... An essay says our two-party system is dissolving, especially at the
state level. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> look more and more like each other. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governors</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tommy Thompson</ENAMEX> are the leading edge of
this movement. State <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> don't care about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>: They just want
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> who get the job done. ... <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Economist</ENAMEX> , marking its
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Science and Technology</ENAMEX>" section's <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">20 th</NUMEX> anniversary, offers a
challenging science quiz. Question No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>: "What is unusual about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sheep</ENAMEX> on
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Scottish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Foula</ENAMEX>? a) They eat sea <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">birds</ENAMEX>. b) They eat seaweed. c)
They eat each other." If you are going take the quiz, stop reading now. The answer is a).

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stevenson</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
