
   
   
      
         
            On <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malaysia</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Murder</ENAMEX>

            
               If you missed the most
recent installments of this column, here they are: posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Nov.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17</TIMEX>, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, Nov. 13</TIMEX>.
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sydney Morning Herald</ENAMEX> led with a
story on the attempt by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rupert Murdoch</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Corp</ENAMEX> to start a
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> TV <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX>, calling its effort "an ambitious campaign to shake up
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Australia</ENAMEX>'s television industry." Current foreign ownership laws prevent
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX> from acquiring a TV <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX>, since he already owns <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">70 percent</NUMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Australia</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>. Nonetheless, his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> is pressing for meetings with the
government to change the policy.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation</ENAMEX> conference in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuala Lumpur</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malaysia</ENAMEX>, has
concluded--to little end, said a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 19</TIMEX> report in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herald</ENAMEX> : The
summit was "plagued by internal fighting over free trade and human rights" and
yielded only a meaningless communiqué. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South China Morning Post</ENAMEX>, more
optimistic about the "pledge to mount a region-wide economic growth campaign
and launch simultaneous stimulus measures across the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia-Pacific</ENAMEX> to lift the
region out of its slump," reprimanded <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> for his
comments on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Malaysian</ENAMEX> human rights issues. "There is still a world of
difference between speaking to a political <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forum</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> and at an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX>
banquet where you are the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guest</ENAMEX>," scolded an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SCMP</ENAMEX> editorial, adding that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s criticism of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Malaysian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> for imprisoning former Deputy
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anwar Ibrahim</ENAMEX> has probably "sharpened the divide" between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>.

            Meanwhile, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> papers focused on the defeat in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House of Lords</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s proportional representation bill. The vote,
the papers concurred, leaves <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> elections in chaos. It marks
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX> and final defeat of this particular bill and the most serious defeat
of any government bill since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX>. Had it passed, the bill would have altered
the system to allow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> to elect a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> rather than a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>. Some
papers, including the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Telegraph</ENAMEX>, noted that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tory</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lords</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Viscount</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cranborne</ENAMEX> has said that if the bill is reintroduced, his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> might follow
parliamentary traditions and "cooperate."

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>
Times feature took up the debate over whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, soon to grace the cover of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vogue</ENAMEX> , is "the sexiest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> alive"
or merely "has matured as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First Lady</ENAMEX> better than a fine <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX>." For this
"once-bespectacled feminist who recently turned <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">51</TIMEX>," gushes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> ,
"her new role as cover <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> is merely belated proof of her transformation--no
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">snorting</ENAMEX>--into one of the most revered and glamorous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First Ladies</ENAMEX> ever."

            
Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jerusalem Post</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ha'aretz</ENAMEX> led
with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>'s imminent pullback from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Bank</ENAMEX>--the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> phase of
implementing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wye</ENAMEX> agreement. The pullback, which may take <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">only a few hours</TIMEX>,
is scheduled to take place <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> in conjunction with the release of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">250</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prisons</ENAMEX> and the opening of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palestinian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">International Airport</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gaza</ENAMEX>. Before signing off on the pullback, however, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX> will review <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> compliance to date with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wye</ENAMEX>. According
to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ha'aretz</ENAMEX> , settler <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> deluged <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parliament</ENAMEX> with <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last-minute</TIMEX>
letters, faxes, and phone calls protesting the move.

            From
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgrade</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX>, text from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Radio B92</ENAMEX> gives us the latest on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kosovar</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">negotiators</ENAMEX> have called for a referendum to determine the future
political status of the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">90 percent</NUMEX> ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">province</ENAMEX> in southern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Serbia</ENAMEX>.
A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> rapid response <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> to rescue international <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monitors</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> could be
ready by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early December</TIMEX>. Meanwhile, in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgrade</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">several hundred</NUMEX> teaching staff
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgrade</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">University</ENAMEX>'s philology <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> stopped work for an
hour <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> to protest the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s dismissal of certain faculty
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>. This is a prelude to a planned full-fledged boycott starting <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov.</TIMEX>
23.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News International</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> both ran brief
reports on the massacre of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>. The unidentified <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">killers</ENAMEX>, said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News International Pakistan</ENAMEX> ,
used the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> to scrawl "This is the end of black magic" on the
walls. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> noted that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">region</ENAMEX> have faced
harassment by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Sunni</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX> because they oppose the imposition of Shariat
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Islamic Law</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Zimbabwe</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> reported what it called "one of the most disgraceful
incidents of unbecoming behaviour at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parliament</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Zimbabwe</ENAMEX>": A female
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parliament</ENAMEX> was verbally and almost physically attacked--"nearly
beaten up"--by a fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">legislator</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Members</ENAMEX>' Bar <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attacker</ENAMEX>
claimed the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> was part of a reactionary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gang</ENAMEX> plotting to remove the city
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> from office. The incident, said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> , is being
investigated.

         
      
   
