
   
   
      
         
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate Family Values</ENAMEX>
            

            Attentive online readers
will notice a slight change in our design, if not by the time you read this
then in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next few days</TIMEX>. The purpose is to reflect the launch of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s
new "portal site," msn.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.
As <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">followers</ENAMEX> of Internet fashion are aware, portal <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> are the flavor of the
moment, as various online <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">giants</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">America Online</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yahoo, Netscape</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>--compete to be your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guide</ENAMEX> through the maze of the Internet. A portal
site is a Web page with useful features such as a Web search engine, your local
weather, sundry links, perhaps a stock ticker, news headlines, a small button
that says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">"Click</ENAMEX> here or we e-mail your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> that you've been playing Solitaire
again," and so on. The idea is that you make it your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> page, or at least
come to it often, and that way the sponsoring <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> will get lots of traffic
and make lots of money by ... by ... well, we're all still working on that.
It's the Internet after all.

            Anyway, 
                  Slate
               
conducted a scrupulously objective study of the major portal <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> and
concluded that msn.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX> was
the one we preferred to be associated with. By special arrangement with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">America</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Online</ENAMEX>, however, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> who access 
                  Slate
                through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX> will get a
special set of pages that shield them from any special temptation to visit
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">msn</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> properties. Instead, they will continue to enjoy
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX>'s own self-promotions as usual. Of course <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> are free to check
out msn.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX>, just as other 
                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> are free to visit
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">aol</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Nobody has a monopoly here, as we keep telling <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Reno</ENAMEX>.

            We can't
resist noting, finally, that if your primary interests are news, politics, and
cultural commentary, our "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate Links</ENAMEX>" page doesn't make a bad "portal site." There you'll
find links to all the major <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnists</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentators</ENAMEX>, movie and other arts
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">reviewers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> and foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>, and other tasty treats. Make it your
home page--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> won't mind.

            

               Partisanship: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> Wobbles
            

            There is nothing especially
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberal</ENAMEX> about the behavior that has got <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> in hot
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>. Nor is there anything especially <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> or conservative about
Special <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prosecutor Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>'s alleged excesses. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> have
attempted to associate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Flytrap</ENAMEX> with the political and cultural values of the
1960s--let it all hang out and so on--though they also have insisted that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">feminists</ENAMEX> are betraying feminism's roots in the same period by failing to
condemn the male <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">perpetrator</ENAMEX>. Surely the latter critique is closer to the mark.
If the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> affair smells of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">any past decade</TIMEX> it is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1950s</TIMEX> and
the pre-feminist workplace culture reflected in movies like <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Seven Year</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Itch</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Apartment</ENAMEX> .

            But
basically this scandal is nonideological and so are the arguments around it. So
the strong tendency of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> to see <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Flytrap</ENAMEX> differently is
especially impressive. There is nothing wrong with partisanship--when it's
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about</NUMEX> principled ideological disagreement. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beast</ENAMEX> stands for strong,
mutually antagonistic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> everywhere," says the press magnate, Lord
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Copper</ENAMEX>, in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Evelyn Waugh's Scoop</ENAMEX> . That is a pretty good attitude to have
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about</NUMEX> domestic politics. If there's anything worse than partisanship, it's
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bipartisanship</ENAMEX>. This is not merely the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX>'s professional preference for
disagreement over agreement. It is a suspicion that rising above partisanship
usually means rising above democracy. (See <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Plotz</ENAMEX>'s "Flytrap
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>" dispatch on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wise Men</ENAMEX>.") Nevertheless, it is remarkable
that on a series of essentially apolitical issues on which reasonable people
can differ, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> are almost all on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> side and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>
are almost all on the other.

            
How does it happen? Empty, principle-free
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">partisanship</ENAMEX>--the bad kind--is the obvious answer. It is tempting to apply this
analysis only to whichever side you happen to disagree with. But unthinking
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">partisanship</ENAMEX> can strike anyone at any time. Consider the sad case of an online
magazine <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>. Call him "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">K.</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> was working on an article--and working himself
up into a fine froth--on the subject of legal "hairsplitting." What is wrong
with it? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> does not go as far as those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defenders</ENAMEX> who say that you have
the right to lie under oath if the questions are ones you should never have had
to answer. But he was strongly tempted by the notion that if you shouldn't have
been asked the question, responding with fatuous evasions is perfectly OK.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> had spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$40 million</NUMEX> not so much investigating a crime as
arranging for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. If a bizarre definition of sex could allow <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mislead</ENAMEX> without falling into a perjury trap, he was not merely within his
rights but perfectly justified.

            As <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> was thinking this
through, though, the line of reasoning started to seem familiar. Wasn't this
exactly <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elliott Abrams</ENAMEX>' argument? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abrams</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assistant secretary of state</ENAMEX> under
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>, pleaded guilty to misleading <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iran-Contra</ENAMEX>
affair, but was pardoned by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>. His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defense</ENAMEX> (for which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> had
contempt at the time) was that he intended to mislead but was technically
telling the truth. For example, he stagily denied that any foreign money was
being used to finance the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">contras</ENAMEX>--although he himself had been involved in
soliciting such money--because the check hadn't yet arrived. When the deception
came out, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abrams</ENAMEX> sermonized that sneakiness in the defense of liberty is no
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice</ENAMEX>, and many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> supported him in that.

            There are
differences, of course. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>' right to question an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assistant secretary</ENAMEX> of
state about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> foreign policy will seem clearer to many than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s right to
ask the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> about a sexual affair, but a few will think the opposite.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abrams</ENAMEX> felt he was defending liberty in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nicaragua</ENAMEX>, while others might
characterize his deception as an effort to subvert democracy in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>. So what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abrams</ENAMEX> did to prevent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> from enforcing a policy he
disagreed with is either much worse or much better than
lying-through-technicalities to protect your right to privacy from an
overzealous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> has no trouble deciding which it is now that he needs
a few second-order considerations to refine his argument. But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX>'s indignant
objection to hairsplitting <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a decade ago</TIMEX> and his indignant sympathy for it now
took no account of such nice distinctions.

            The clips from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Abrams</ENAMEX> episode are a hilarious reminder
of how partisan indignation can survive a total reversal of position on an
issue. The thundering <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">condemnations</ENAMEX> of the special <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX> back
then are just like the thundering <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">condemnations</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, down to the
very phrase, "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$40 million</NUMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> used to defend any
conceivable expression of "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX> privilege" over <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX>--now <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> do that, while <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> take up the old cry of
"imperial presidency." When <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> were in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dock</ENAMEX>, the Wall
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Street Journal</ENAMEX> editorial page used to opine about "prosecutorial
discretion"--the apparently noble principle that you don't necessarily
prosecute a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> just because he did something illegal--and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> used to mock it
for that. Now the conservative mantras are "perjury is perjury" and "no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> is
above the law"--and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> finds himself tempted by the idea that it isn't the end
of the world if a perjurer gets away with it.

            The strangest role reversal
is going on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">right now</TIMEX> and concerns democracy itself. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX>, and as late
as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>, a major <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> theme was a sort of taunting, nyah-nyah populism.
They thought the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> was with them and always would be. Remember term limits?
The notion of representative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">democracy</ENAMEX> took multiple hits. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Politicians</ENAMEX> were
considered inherently inferior to "the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>." There was no patience for the
good old Burkean conceit that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">legislators</ENAMEX> should sometimes rise above the
wishes of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">constituents</ENAMEX>. Those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>' wishes expressed in polls even
trumped the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>' own wishes as expressed at the ballot box (since the
essence of term limits was to limit the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>' right to vote for whom they
wanted).

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">These days</TIMEX>, though, the polls
show that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> pretty clearly don't want <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> impeached. And so
we hear a lot of talk about rising above politics and ignoring the polls and
doing the right thing not the popular thing. There have even been some
frustrated musings among conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are
not necessarily all-wise. They can be duped. They make mistakes. This was a
note <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> used to strike a lot in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX>, and he's glad he doesn't have to
strike it anymore. But he's trying to avoid the opposite note--"the people
agree with me, so I must be right." Just in case.

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
