
   
   
      
         
            Peace vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX>

            
               If you missed the most
recent installments of this column, here they are: posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Nov.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX>, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, Nov. 20</TIMEX>.
            

            Issues of justice and
reparation for past abuses of human rights dominated much of the world's press
over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past few days</TIMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> and the rest of western <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, the crisis
over the detention of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Augusto Pinochet</ENAMEX> remained a hot story. Several
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British Sunday</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> reported an imminent deal between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chile</ENAMEX> that
would allow the general to be sent home to face trial there. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Ministers</ENAMEX> back
Chile offer to try <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pinochet</ENAMEX>" was the main front-page headline in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Observer</ENAMEX> , and "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labour</ENAMEX> in secret deal to send <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pinochet</ENAMEX> home" was the
headline in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Sunday Telegraph</ENAMEX> .

            But this
potential face-saving way out of the crisis was dismissed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s papers,
which reported that no deal had been reached. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> said that the only
possible grounds by which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British Home</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Straw</ENAMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
equivalent of the interior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX>) could now refuse proceedings for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pinochet</ENAMEX>'s extradition to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX> were compassionate ones, taking into account
his age and health, but this argument was rejected in an editorial in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX>. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chilean</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foreign minister</ENAMEX>'s 'offer' that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pinochet</ENAMEX>
stands trial at home kills the health question: if he is well enough to stand
trial there, why not here and in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX>?" the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX> said.

            On its front page, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX> claimed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> is "quietly putting
pressure on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Government</ENAMEX>" to have <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pinochet</ENAMEX> sent home. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary of State</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madeleine Albright</ENAMEX>, has raised the issue twice in the last
fortnight with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foreign</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin Cook</ENAMEX>," it said, adding that
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>'s involvement has added to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s dilemma. The
Independent,
another <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> liberal <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX>, led
its front page <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> with a report that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Straw</ENAMEX> would face a "huge revolt"
within the governing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor Party</ENAMEX> if he allowed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pinochet</ENAMEX> to return <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">home</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> press has been divided on the issue along political lines, with the
conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Telegraph</ENAMEX> calling for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pinochet</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">repatriation</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Independent</ENAMEX> opposing
it.

            On the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">continent</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s decision by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British Law Lords</ENAMEX> to deny <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pinochet</ENAMEX>
immunity from extradition to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX> was heralded as one of major international
importance. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">El Mundo</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Wednesday</TIMEX> called it "a truly historic decision" in
defense of human rights, but the conservative Le <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Figaro</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> described it as "a bad decision" made
under political pressure. "For the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time, perhaps, a juridically
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">incompetent</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tribunal</ENAMEX> has rendered a verdict of universal significance," it
said. "Since no international <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tribunal</ENAMEX> exists to judge such events, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">English</ENAMEX>
took the place of this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX> which it is now more than ever necessary to
create." Devoting <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> full pages to the issue on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Le Monde</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Straw</ENAMEX>'s
legal obligation to give a "well-motivated" decision on the matter an "almost
impossible" <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to fulfill.

            
On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Le Monde</ENAMEX> reported on an
inside page that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pinochet</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> were pleading "mental indisposition" as
grounds for sending him home, but it devoted its front-page lead to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">44</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nation Washington</ENAMEX> conference on the restitution to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust of</ENAMEX>
possessions stolen from them by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazis</ENAMEX> and their foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">collaborators</ENAMEX>,
describing it as the most important such meeting ever held. It also published a
long article on the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paris Museum of the Art</ENAMEX> and History of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Judaism</ENAMEX>, "which
finally makes the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> cultural heritage enter into the collective French
memory."

            In an
editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, the same <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> recalled the crimes against humanity
committed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Congolese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dictator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laurent Désiré Kabila</ENAMEX>--held responsible by
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">up to 300,000</NUMEX> deaths--who has been attending a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franco</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> peace summit in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>. Justifying his attendance, Le
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monde</ENAMEX> said that "war brings inhumanity with it and peace is obviously the
first condition of the rights of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pinochet</ENAMEX> was squeezed off the front pages of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> by the case of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurdish</ENAMEX> rebel <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abdullah</ENAMEX>
Ocalan, whom <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> has refused to extradite to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX> because its laws forbid
extradition of anyone to a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> that practices the death penalty. Ocalan was
arrested in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>'s request, but <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bonn</ENAMEX> has now dropped its request
for his extradition and has jointly proposed with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> that he be tried for
terrorist crimes by a currently nonexistent international <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tribunal</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX>
remains furious, and most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> led <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> on negotiations being held
with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> that would allow <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ocalan</ENAMEX> be extradited to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> from
which he was expelled to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX> without any warning to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX>
government.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Die Welt</ENAMEX>, under the front-page
headline "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>--A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Year of Catastrophes</ENAMEX>," reported the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Worldwatch Institute</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> as saying that a record <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">32,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have already died <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> in
natural disasters around the world.

         
      
   
