
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Message Trap</ENAMEX>

            Everyone agrees: The
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> were beaten by a lack of message.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> pointed it out
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">right</TIMEX> after the election. He told his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>, according to the New York
Times , that "the election's message was that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> wanted elected
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> to address pocketbook issues like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>, health care,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">education</ENAMEX> and the minimum wage." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX> couldn't have agreed more. "I
think we probably underestimated the need to really aggressively push a much
stronger message about cutting taxes and saving <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>, winning the
war on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>, reforming education and national defense," said the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX> the
day before he realized that that underestimate would cost him his job.

            By the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">weekend</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberal pundits</ENAMEX> and conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pols</ENAMEX> were joined in messageful
chorus. "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> misread the meaning of their <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> victory. ...<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Voters</ENAMEX> want
government to solve problems in education, the environment, child care and
health care," counseled liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">E.J. Dionne</ENAMEX>. "What we need to do
under my speakership," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX> apparent <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Livingston</ENAMEX>, "is not only
articulate the message but to provide the legislative machinery that it takes
to back it up." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aspiring House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Majority Leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Largent</ENAMEX>, chimed in, "I
think the first thing that we have to do is develop an agenda that can unify
our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>. ... We have to have <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> solutions in education, HMO reform,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>, get back to limited <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, lower taxes and strong
defense."

            Oh really?

            Where, may I ask, is the
evidence that the public is hot for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> that promises activist solutions to
problems that confront it and its progeny? Surely not from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Election Day</TIMEX> exit
polls. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> , for example, queried <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> about the one
issue that "mattered most" in deciding which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> to vote for.
"Education," said an underwhelming <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">25 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>. And even at that, how
many of those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> really had education foremost in their frontal lobes?
Remember that, in key elections, "education" was the trade name for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> of
less reputable pursuit. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX> who actively
supported legalized gambling measures (with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s share of the take
earmarked for education) scored unexpected victories over anti-gambling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Voters</ENAMEX> who opposed the lottery and video poker interests told
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pollsters</ENAMEX> forthrightly that they were "against gambling." <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Voters</ENAMEX> who favored
legalizing gambling said they were "for education."

            Trailing
behind education in the exit polls were issues such as "morals and ethics" (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19</NUMEX>
percent), "the economy and jobs" (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">14 percent</NUMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">11 percent</NUMEX>),
and taxes (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">8 percent</NUMEX>). As for "health care," the occasion of much bipartisan
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">huffing</ENAMEX> and puffing about the need to save <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> from the ravages of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMOs</ENAMEX>,
it commanded the top interest of a mere <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">7 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>. That was scarcely
more than the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5 percent</NUMEX> who dared the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pollsters</ENAMEX>' scorn by admitting outright
that "the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> matter" concerned them most. In fact, if you add the
coded "morals and ethics" vote to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> category, it virtually
ties for <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place among <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX>.

            
What the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> would do well to keep in mind is
that, at least in times of peace and prosperity, most times the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> public
doesn't want the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> to bother it. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> expect the government
to keep the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> checks and highway money coming and run the courts
and stuff like that. But sweeping reforms--even when they really would be
prudent for the future--make the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">electorate</ENAMEX> uncomfortable. Take "saving
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>," for example, a goal that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pols</ENAMEX> from both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> like to pop into the
same sentence with "curbing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMOs</ENAMEX>." There's no way to make <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> solvent for
the long term except by raising taxes to pay for it or by letting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMOs</ENAMEX> and
their ilk limit some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s access to some kinds of care. Pick your poison
or, more wisely, shut your mouth.

            Of course that doesn't mean
that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> should go back to talking about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX> or even about that
"social agenda" that makes so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> uneasy. After all, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> do
like their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> to flatter them by pretending that they are truly
concerned about important things like making <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> smarter and safer and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">healthier</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> should take a page out of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>'s playbook and
promise the public <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100,000</NUMEX> new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> or cops or drug enforcement <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> or
whatever. Never mind that the money will only pay for a fraction of that (and
that by the time it's spread by formula to every <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> or precinct, it might
not fully support a single hire). Or call for another tax break to subsidize
the cost of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">day-care centers</ENAMEX> or hiring the disadvantaged or
whatever. Sure, most of the subsidy will end up paying for things that would
happen anyway, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like the idea of tax breaks and nobody ever bothers
to check on who got to pocket the lost revenue.

            Next time, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>, recruit some
more attractive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> who don't scare the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> with their moralistic
fervor. But meanwhile, don't weigh yourself down with some heavy-breathing
message that ends up forcing a debate in which a lot of painful choices will
inevitably be laid bare. That was your strategy <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last January</TIMEX>, when you
deliberately scheduled <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only 89 days</TIMEX> for voting business <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> with
precisely that sort of inaction in mind. And according to the polls, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>
has never been more popular than it was just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few months ago</TIMEX> when what it was
doing was nothing much.

         
      
   
