
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">White</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Dark</ENAMEX>

            Conversion narratives--tales
of evil, reactionary, or addicted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who reform--share one complicating
trait: Their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protagonists</ENAMEX> tend to be more compelling in the throes of their
particular depravity than after they "come to their senses." In rare cases that
irony is underlined, as in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Drugstore Cowboy</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>), in which the title
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Dillon</ENAMEX>) stops using <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> and seems suddenly smaller and more
vulnerable--and easy prey for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">freaks</ENAMEX> he had previously dominated. But
mainstream cinema, which insists on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroes</ENAMEX> who are both <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">square</ENAMEX> and hip, has a
tough time exploring the paradox that virtue is a great charisma <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">killer</ENAMEX>. It's
certainly unexplored in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">History X</ENAMEX> , in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward Norton</ENAMEX> plays
a racist, homicidal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">skinhead</ENAMEX> who's never more mythically transfixing than in
the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">seconds</TIMEX> before he stomps on the neck of a prone <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-American</ENAMEX> car <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thief</ENAMEX>.
When he returns from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> to his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Venice Beach</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX>, home, with his hair
grown back and his bloodlust replaced by an air of wary contemplation, both he
and the movie shrink to the proportions of a TV set.

            Some of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">History X</ENAMEX> is sharp, red-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat melodrama</ENAMEX>, with sensational acting
and scenes of violence at once thrillingly kinetic and revolting. But the film
has the soul of a guidance <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counselor</ENAMEX>, and whenever it seems poised to go where
no commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> picture has gone before--to a place where our responses
are gummed up, where we can grasp simultaneously the horror and the allure of
the white supremacist movement--it snaps back into easy moralizing,
demonization, and naive notions of how <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> change. It's a frustrating piece
of work--much too vivid to laugh off, too psychologically elided to take
seriously.

            What it has is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Norton</ENAMEX>, who is a stunning <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pictorial</ENAMEX> object.
In the opening, black-and-white sequence, his <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Derek Vinyard</ENAMEX> gets interrupted in
the throes of animalistic sex with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stacey</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fairuza Balk</ENAMEX>) by his
younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danny</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward Furlong</ENAMEX>), who tells him that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> are
stealing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">van</ENAMEX>. Clad only in boxers and boots and with a huge, thick
swastika tattooed over his heart, he snatches a revolver and charges into the
street. The camera hugs his long torso and ropy muscles; starkly white against
the black of the sky, he seems stripped down to pure hatred.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Norton</ENAMEX> is
an amazing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX>, a hot-dog whose delight in transformation is infectious.
Here, he curls his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> into a sneer, and he's probably the only white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> in
movies who's wiry enough to trounce a bunch of black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> on a basketball court
and not leave the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> snickering in incredulity. Better yet, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Norton</ENAMEX> gives
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Derek</ENAMEX> a mind as keen as it is caustic. Confronting his mother's liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX>
date (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elliott Gould</ENAMEX>) at the dinner table, he drives home the point that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodney</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX> was a multiple <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">felon</ENAMEX> high on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCP</ENAMEX> who could easily have run over a child
before the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> cops stopped him on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">highway</ENAMEX>. You say black people
need affirmative action to overcome historical injustice<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> freed
the slaves <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">130 years ago</TIMEX>," he inveighs. "How long does it take to get their act
together?" Compare <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Norton</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Cruise</ENAMEX> in the early scenes of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Born on the</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Fourth</NUMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>), in which the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> telegraphs like crazy that his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>'s jingoistic declarations are <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bull</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Norton</ENAMEX> rants convincingly, like a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> whose rage has taken on a runaway life of its own.

            
He is meant, of course, to be a lost soul.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Derek</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> was a fireman killed by a black <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealer</ENAMEX> while battling a
blaze in a crack den. Now, the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> has found a substitute <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cameron</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stacy Keach</ENAMEX>), a glowering fount of white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supremacist</ENAMEX> hate literature who uses
his protégé to enlist and incite other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youths</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American History</ENAMEX> 
               X
reaches <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a pinnacle</NUMEX> of ghastliness when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cameron</ENAMEX> sends <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Derek</ENAMEX> and his fellow
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">skinheads</ENAMEX> into a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Korean</ENAMEX>-purchased <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">supermarket</ENAMEX>, the new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> of which has
allegedly replaced "real <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>" with cheap, illegal immigrant labor. The
assault--an orgy in which fixtures are smashed, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> pummeled, and a
Hispanic cashier pinned to a conveyer belt and doused with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk</ENAMEX> ("She looks
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">white</ENAMEX>!")--is terrifying not just because it's sadistic but also because its
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sadism</ENAMEX> is suffused with righteousness.

            Sequences
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Derek</ENAMEX> as a skinhead are flashbacks and shot in febrile black-and-white. The
present is in (less arresting) color, with a framing device that's
groan-inducingly earnest. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">The day</TIMEX> before his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> is due to be released from
prison, the now-skinheaded <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danny</ENAMEX> responds to a high-school assignment to write
an essay about a civil rights <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> with a paper on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>'s Mein
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kampf</ENAMEX> . The scholarly, patrician black principal (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Avery Brooks</ENAMEX>) threatens
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> with expulsion unless he delivers a substitute essay <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the following day</TIMEX>:
an analysis of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>'s crime and its impact on both their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">society</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>! Assigned by a fair-minded black principal with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
doctorates! Can we skew the case any more, please? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brooks</ENAMEX>, the bulwark of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">liberal</ENAMEX> humanism at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">furthest</ENAMEX> reaches of the galaxy on the stultifying TV
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">series Star Trek: Deep Space Nine</ENAMEX> , is too comfortable dropping
high-toned pronouncements such as "Your rhetoric and your propaganda aren't
going to save you." And when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Derek</ENAMEX> gets out of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX>, we see that the
principal has reached him, too--that he's ready to exchange a dark white father
for a white dark <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>.

            For the movie's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David McKenna</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tony</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kaye</ENAMEX>, the universe consists of white supremacists and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX>, with no one of
note in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between</TIMEX>; and the protagonist's <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison metamorphosis</ENAMEX> from one pole to
the other is the natural consequence of falling afoul of some big <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> white
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> and getting tight with a garrulous, congenial black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inmate</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guy Torry</ENAMEX>)
during laundry detail. I wish it were more complicated and that the Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nice</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guy</ENAMEX> who gets out of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> had more to say than "How did I buy into this shit?
I was pissed off." The struggle for his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid brother</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soul</ENAMEX> turns out to be no
struggle at all. And, in light of his conversion, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Derek</ENAMEX>'s former supremacist
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chums obligingly</ENAMEX> turn into hissing vampires, snarling at his expressions of
tolerance as if they've just been flashed the crucifix and sprayed with holy
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kaye</ENAMEX> clinches the case by showing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Derek</ENAMEX> in the shower having a vision of
himself and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> as innocent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> on the beach, staring in
wonderment at seagulls.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Brit</ENAMEX> who
made his fortune with glossy commercials, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kaye</ENAMEX> was apparently unsatisfied with
the cut of the picture he turned in, and at last report was holed up in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Chateau Marmont</ENAMEX> issuing proclamations of the film's inadequacy. I don't know
what he originally had in mind--or whose idea the garish, inconclusive ending
was--but <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">History X</ENAMEX> isn't that bad. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kaye</ENAMEX> has a punchy way with
montage, and the script has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> card up its sleeve: the climactic
revelation that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Derek</ENAMEX>'s revered fireman <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Russ</ENAMEX>) was himself a racist
who urged his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> at the dinner table not to get too cozy with niggers or their
literature. It's a testament to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Norton</ENAMEX>'s utter immersion in the role that he
can even halfway connect the dots between this fundamentally sweet, brainy kid
and the magnetic, white trash <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monster</ENAMEX> who'll haunt our minds long after the
movie's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberal</ENAMEX> pieties fade into static.

            
Life <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Is Beautiful</ENAMEX>, written and directed by and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">starring Italian Roberto Benigni</ENAMEX> (he starred in Down by Law , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX>), has
won international acclaim for wedding sentimental, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chaplinesque</ENAMEX> slapstick to a
story that finishes up in a concentration <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> being gassed and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">roasted</ENAMEX>. In principle, I'm all for flouting hobgoblinish rules of consistency,
and I think that farce--a violent genre that feeds on desperation--is often
wasted on trivial conflicts. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dario Fo</ENAMEX>'s play <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Accidental Death</ENAMEX> of an
Anarchist proved that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grouchoesque</ENAMEX> clown could be an anarchic avenger,
driving fascists to apoplexy; and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lina Wertmuller's Seven</ENAMEX> Beauties
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1976</TIMEX>), however gross and ham-handed, at least suggested that a concentration
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">camp</ENAMEX> could function as a legitimate setting for a black-comic parable about a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">parasite</ENAMEX>'s struggle to survive at all costs.

            But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benigni</ENAMEX>'s movie made me
want to throw up. He has cast himself as a prankish <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jew</ENAMEX> who wins the heart of a
pretty maiden (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nicoletta Braschi</ENAMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fathers</ENAMEX> a cute, skinny <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>; and gets carted
off by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazis</ENAMEX> to a death <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX>. The conceit is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benigni</ENAMEX> tries to keep the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5-year-old</TIMEX> from realizing what's going on by pretending that the whole thing is
a game and that if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> gets through it without crying or complaining he
wins a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">tank</ENAMEX>. In an essay in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward Rothstein</ENAMEX> refers
to the "enchantment of fascism" being "undone" by "other spells, some recalling
the innocence of childhood"--and, indeed, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Benigni</ENAMEX>'s routines are sometimes
childishly liberating, conjuring up Fo, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harpo Marx</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danny Kaye</ENAMEX> in his
double-talk mode. It half-works right up to the point where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> start
getting gassed, and then <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Benigni</ENAMEX>'s moist-eyed heroism and tenacious faith in
his own irresistibility start to seem like a monstrous ego trip--a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clown</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">megalomania</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Lewis</ENAMEX>--speaking of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">megalomania</ENAMEX>--tried something similar in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '70s</TIMEX>, with a film about a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clown</ENAMEX> who
leads a group of laughing tots into the death <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chamber</ENAMEX>. The picture reportedly
ended with a shot of black smoke coming out of the stack--but we'll never know
because <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Day the Clown Cried</ENAMEX> was judged too obscene to be released,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> went back to parading <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doomed kids</ENAMEX> across the TV screen in telethons,
while <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> goggled at his stamina, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> nominated him for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nobel Peace Prize</ENAMEX>. I wish <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Life Is Beautiful</ENAMEX> had fallen into the same
black hole. Its subject isn't the power of "enchantment" but the power of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Benigni</ENAMEX> to celebrate, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Lewis</ENAMEX>-like, his own beautiful <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">martyrdom</ENAMEX>. Imagine
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harpo Marx</ENAMEX> giving the hot foot to a pompous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX>, who takes out a machine
gun and blows him away: That's how cheap <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Benigni</ENAMEX>'s hash of farce and tragedy
is. It's a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas</ENAMEX>, all right.

         
      
   
