
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Drawing upon her rich
experience of life, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> to her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>) responds to questions
about manners, personal relations, politics, and other subjects. Please send
your questions for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> to prudence@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Queries should not exceed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> words in
length. Please indicate how you wish your letter to be signed, preferably
including your location.
            

            
               
                  Dear
Prudie,
               
            

            
               Please don't laugh. I
have a dilemma about being a house <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guest</ENAMEX>. It is to flush or not to flush. When
I stayed with an old schoolmate on a business trip, it was in her small
apartment with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bathroom</ENAMEX>. Her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> was on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> side of the loo, and mine
was on the other. I had to go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bathroom</ENAMEX> in the early <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">dawn</TIMEX> and was torn
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about</TIMEX> whether to risk waking her with the noise of the flush or protecting the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">silence</ENAMEX> (and trying to catch up with it in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX>, before she
did).
            

            
               What
would <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> advise?
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hamlet</ENAMEX> in the
WC
            

            Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Ham,</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> is
not laughing, she is merely smiling with recognition, having had to consider
the same question on occasion. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Decorum</ENAMEX> and politesse dictate that you opt for
the flush. An exception might be if your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX> or hostess has mentioned being an
extremely light sleeper who, once awakened, is unable to fall back asleep. An
alternative if you simply can't bring yourself to push the handle down in the
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">middle of the night</TIMEX> would be to put a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX>-It note on the closed lid advising,
"Please flush." Admittedly this may call for more wakefulness than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> may have
given <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the hour</TIMEX> and the circumstance. If you choose silence and can't deal with
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX>-It note, mention your concerns <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the next morning</TIMEX>.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, unflushingly

            
               
                  Dear
Prudie,
               
            

            
               How
long should you date a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> before deciding if he is right for you?
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bewildered</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">D.C.</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Be</ENAMEX>,

            There can
be no specified time after which you know if you've found the right <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX>.
Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> make a good selection almost immediately, just as others can take a
very long time to make a colossal mistake. The romance gods are fickle. Prudie
knows this from experience.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, romantically

            
               
                  Dear
Prudie,
               
            

            
               As a
straight male living in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dupont Circle</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, I have had the same
problem as "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dimmer</ENAMEX>." A good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>, staring at a similar blonde, asked how he
could figure this out fast. I responded with the best indicators I know. Feet,
hands, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam</ENAMEX>'s apple. Almost never fails.
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Singly</ENAMEX>
            

            Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX>,

            Thank you
on behalf of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX>'s male <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> who feel they might fall into the
transvestite trap. It must be true: Takes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to know one ... a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, that
is.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>,
tellingly

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               Because
of my healthy appetite, I am quite fond of all-you-can-eat, buffet style
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">restaurants</ENAMEX>. My question is: How much should you tip the wait <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>? They don't
take your order or bring your food, but they do bring <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drinks</ENAMEX>, remove dishes,
and deliver the check. Your advice will be greatly appreciated.
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Perpetually Hungry</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L.A.</ENAMEX>
            

            Dear
Perp,

            Since the
service you receive is not that of a regular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX>, you might wish to
leave the tipping equivalent of an honorarium. Perhaps <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX> of your bill
would be correct.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>,
expansively

         
      
   
