
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">134</NUMEX>:

            By <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cohen</ENAMEX>

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> are invited to provide a postelection headline that, in a just
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">universe</ENAMEX>, would run <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> in the media outlet of their choice.
            

            by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 p.m. ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> to
e-mail your answer (newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>).

            
               Responses
to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>'s question (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 133</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Not Putz":</ENAMEX>
            

            
               "I didn't
say it. I didn't say it. I was there with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of my campaign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>. We
took copious notes."
            

            
               Up for re-election, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">York</ENAMEX> state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney General</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dennis Vacco</ENAMEX> incensed a big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> with a
remark he denies making. What <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>; what remark?
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vacco</ENAMEX> vehemently denies
telling a convention of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">People</ENAMEX> magazine <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>, 'That <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Princess</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>
was a mean drunk and a lousy lay.' "-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Carvell</ENAMEX>
            

            "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>: the powerful
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX>. The remark: 'From now on, I will refer to other people
who hold my position as "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney generals</ENAMEX>." ' "-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Goldberg</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PETA</ENAMEX>. 'Who's fucking this
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX>?' "-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Rogers</ENAMEX>
            

            " 'Let us take a brief
moment of silence for the late <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Hughes</ENAMEX>,' to the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">semiannual</TIMEX> convention of
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Poetesses Who Love Anguished, Theatrical Histrionics</ENAMEX> (PLATH)."-- Noah
Meyerson
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Native Americans</ENAMEX>: 'Me
win, me passum heap big law ... bring back <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. John's Redmen</ENAMEX>.' 'I <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> ... I
love the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Native Americans</ENAMEX>. I'm indebted to them ... I keep losing at their damn
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">casinos</ENAMEX>. But seriously ...' "-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alex Balk</ENAMEX>
            

            Click for more
responses.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
            

            Is it
possible to make a joke about an offensive remark without making an offensive
remark? Tricky. Perhaps more than anything else, context counts. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lenny Bruce</ENAMEX>
built a routine around the idea that repeating the word "nigger" over and over
and over very, very fast could strip it of its cruel power, reducing it to an
impotent sound. But the context was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce</ENAMEX>'s entire life. The risk is falling
into the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Cops and Firemen</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blackface Defense</ENAMEX>. When these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fellows</ENAMEX> were caught
on tape (a delightfully <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Clarkish</ENAMEX> phrase) on an appallingly racist parade
float, they pleaded satire. Here the context is the history of the New York
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Police</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fire</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">departments</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> traditionally short on anti-racist
parodists, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commissioners</ENAMEX> of both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX> gave these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> the boot.
(This, of course, raises <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">First Amendment</ENAMEX> questions about odious speech, but
that's another question.) So where does that leave "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">News Quiz"</ENAMEX>? Just a little
uneasy. But not wallowing in a moral swamp, like those cringing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thieves</ENAMEX> at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time magazine</ENAMEX>. And that's a comfort.

             

            
               Señor
Answer
            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic</ENAMEX> New
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yorkers</ENAMEX>.

            The remark: "You don't stand
outside a bodega and ask the bandito if he would have killed someone if there
was a death penalty."

            The context: replying to a
question about the ineffable deterrent value of the death penalty.

            The denial: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vacco</ENAMEX> admits to
"bodega," refutes "bandito."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">source</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rob Goldblum</ENAMEX>,
managing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jewish Week</ENAMEX> .

            The other admission: Vacco
acknowledged that he was virtually guilty of murdering <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Buffalo</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barnett</ENAMEX>
Slepian, "just as if I'd pulled the trigger myself."

            Correction: No, he didn't. He
takes no responsibility whatever.

            His
election <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponent</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eliot Spitzer</ENAMEX> recalls that when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vacco</ENAMEX> was a federal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX> he was so egregiously lax in protecting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">abortion clinics</ENAMEX> that he was
removed from a case by a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Buffalo</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> and replaced with a special
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX>.

            
               Inductive
Reasoning Extra
            

            These
names were among the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> coughed up by an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Infoseek</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> search. A search
for what?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glenn</ENAMEX>

            DeForest
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kelly</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Frances</ENAMEX>
Farmer

            
Storm-drenched New Zealanders

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jordan</ENAMEX>

            Adolf
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Hitler</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Roley</ENAMEX>
(according to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aja</ENAMEX>)

            Kerri
Strug

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jeep</ENAMEX>

            Helpful
truck drivers

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbus</ENAMEX>

            Residents of
Dumwoody, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ga.</ENAMEX>, who support <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> research

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Craig</ENAMEX>
Breedlove, auto speed-record holder

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom</ENAMEX>
Selleck

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda</ENAMEX>
Tripp

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eddie</ENAMEX>
Rickenbacker

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marquis de Lafayette</ENAMEX>

            
               The
Category
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroes</ENAMEX>.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Disclaimer</ENAMEX>: All submissions will become the property of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> and
will be published at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> 's discretion. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> may publish your
name on its site in connection with your submission.
            

         
      
   
