
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Flytrap Ad War</ENAMEX>

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one week</TIMEX> before the
TV ads around the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, reminding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s misconduct
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> affair. (To download video of the ads, click here.)
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> pounced on the ads, calling them a clumsy rehash of old charges and
predicting that they would backfire by antagonizing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> who are sick of the
scandal. This is a classic case of self-fulfilling characterization. The ads
are actually far more sophisticated than the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> admit. But if the press
buys the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>' simplistic representation of the ads, they will indeed
backfire.

            The ads
do not rehash the case brought by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Independent Counsel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>. Instead,
they take into account the political reactions that have since transpired: the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">public</ENAMEX>'s fatigue, the backlash against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>, the demise of the impeachment
process, and the scandal's decline as a news story. The ads counter or, in some
cases, exploit these common reactions, which can be summarized as follows:

            

               Reaction <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> is a partisan
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">zealot</ENAMEX>." When the scandal broke in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> was the center of
attention, suspicion, and denunciation. His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">surrogates</ENAMEX> responded by diverting
scrutiny to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s alleged misdeeds. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Millions</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> would like to vote
against both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>. With that in mind, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> ads push <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> back to
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">center</ENAMEX> stage. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> ad, titled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">One Person</ENAMEX> , shows video footage of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> wagging his finger in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX> as he falsely denied his affair with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>. "There's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who doesn't want the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> in charge," the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">narrator</ENAMEX> reminds <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX>. The ad never mentions the scandal, nor does it
include the audio of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s denial. It doesn't need to. We all remember the
wagging finger.

            Making the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> the issue is a classic opposition-party strategy. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> captured <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> by framing the election as a referendum on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX> "tax increase" (a k a deficit-reduction package) and his failed
national health insurance proposal. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, they conceded <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
re-election and warned <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> control of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> would give
him a "blank check." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> ads make the same point, relying this time
on the word "balance." "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> are the balance we need," says the tag line
of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> ad. "For balance, vote <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>," says another.

            

               Reaction <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s offenses aren't
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">impeachable</ENAMEX>." For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several weeks</TIMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX>, it looked as
though <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> might remove <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> from office or force him to resign. But
public support failed to materialize, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s report ignited a backlash, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> lost its nerve. Now it looks as though <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> will escape punishment.
That's good for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> but perhaps bad for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>. If impeachment is moot,
the most obvious way to punish <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is to vote against his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> in the
elections.

            This is
the message of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> ad, titled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Reward</ENAMEX> . Its language is
a textbook frame job: "In every election, there is a big question to think
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about</TIMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX>, the question is: Should we reward <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>? Should we
make the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> more powerful? ... And should we reward not telling the
truth? That is the question of this election: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reward Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>, or vote
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>?" Since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> won't be impeached, the ad suggests, his reward or
punishment is in your hands. "Electing <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> is a way [<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>] can punish
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>," says a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strategist</ENAMEX> who helped design the commercials.

            

               Reaction <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>: "Stop the investigation and
prosecution." Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> find <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s behavior reprehensible but don't
think it should be prosecuted by an independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> or investigated by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>. They think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> had sex with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> and lied about it, but they
don't consider this a crime. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s surrogates have exploited this paradox
by accusing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, and conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> haters of
conspiring to "criminalize" their war against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>.

            The ads
respect this distinction by focusing entirely on morals and lying to the
public. The most striking thing about them is that they avoid any mention of
the charges <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> has leveled against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. Instead, they highlight the
moral rather than legal aspects of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s offenses. And rather than dwell on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">offstage</ENAMEX> lies to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> or to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">grand jury</ENAMEX>, the
ads spotlight his center-stage lies to the public on television. They don't
mention sex, the affair, or anything that ordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> might deem private.
Only <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s public deceit is at issue.

            
The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> ad, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">What Did You Tell Your</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Kids</ENAMEX>? , illustrates the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> strategy. It features <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> young suburban
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> talking to another. "What did you tell your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>?" asks the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>.
"I didn't know what to say," answers the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> replies: "It's
wrong. For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven months</TIMEX> he lied to us." Like the finger-wagging scene in One
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Person</ENAMEX> , this ad reminds <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> not of what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> did to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>
but of what he did to us . It doesn't say his lies were criminal; it
merely says they were wrong. This isn't an abstract matter of law, the ad
suggests. It's about your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>.

            A <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX>
ad, reportedly set to begin airing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, drives home the point. "Remember
when he looked us in the eye?" asks the narrator as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> wags his finger.
"Then the legal mumbo jumbo," the ad recalls. It goes on to quote the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Party</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX>'s praise for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s "moral <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX>." Again, the
point is to bypass the troubled legal case against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and to focus instead
on the overwhelming moral case. Indeed, the ad accuses <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, rather than his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>, of invoking "legal mumbo jumbo" to obscure the immorality of his
misconduct.

            

               Reaction <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>: "Get on with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s
business." Once <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> took up <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s report, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">electorate</ENAMEX>'s hostility
to the investigation shifted to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>. Each of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> ads
acknowledges and answers the public's desire to see other issues discussed.
"But aren't there other things to do?" asks the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> in What Did
You Tell Your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Kids</ENAMEX>? The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> then explains that "the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>
are doing them. They cut taxes, they helped balance the budget, and they're
putting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on welfare back to work."

            The first
ad, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Person</ENAMEX> , addresses this complaint in a different way, by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">situating Clinton</ENAMEX>'s lies about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> in a larger critique of his honesty
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about</NUMEX> public matters. It begins with video clips of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> contradicting
himself on how long it will take to balance the budget. The ad dwells entirely
on fiscal questions such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>. Only at the end does it show him
wagging his finger about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>. The message is that you should vote against
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> not because he lied about sex but because he lies about everything.

            
Unfortunately for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>, the sophistication
and delicacy of the ads is already being overwhelmed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>'
simplification of them. In a <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Rose Garden</ENAMEX> appearance <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> charged
that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> are trying to "divert your attention" from "the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> and their future." <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>
Majority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Gephardt</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic Party</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> equated the ads
with previous efforts to "investigate" and "impeach" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> over his "sex
life." As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> put it, "The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> will look at these ads and say
enough is enough. Get on with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and talk
about the real issues."

            The
danger for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> is that more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> will see shallow media coverage of the
ads--"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">revives</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> sex scandal"--than will see the ads themselves.
"Scandal ads hit campaign," shouts the front-page headline in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> .
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">President Says Policies Are the Real Issue</ENAMEX>," says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> 's
front page. Images from the ads dominate the front page of the New York
Times , under the oversized caption "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Angles of G.O.</ENAMEX>P. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Attack</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Civility</ENAMEX> may
be the first casualty of any election, but subtlety is always the last.

            
               Recent
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Frame Games</ENAMEX>"
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace</ENAMEX>
Therapy": Is the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> deal a new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapter</ENAMEX> or a reminder of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX>?
(posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday, Oct. 28, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>
Trial": The lesson of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX> is to attack the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">inquisition</ENAMEX>. (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday, Oct. 21, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

         
      
   
