
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Challenge</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Saddam</ENAMEX>

            
               If you missed the most
recent installments of this column, here they are: posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Nov.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX>, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, Nov. 6</TIMEX>.
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberal</ENAMEX> daily
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ha'aretz</ENAMEX> led
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> with a report of the narrow <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX> approval of the Wye
agreement, but in the same front-page
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> it said that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ministry of Construction and Housing</ENAMEX> had published
its <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> tender as part of a plan to build <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6,500</NUMEX> housing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Har Homa</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Jerusalem</ENAMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> say that during the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wye</ENAMEX> summit, they warned
[<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin</ENAMEX>] <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX> not to build on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Har Homa</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> say they believe they have the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX>'s commitment not do
so," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said. On the subject dominating most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Middle Eastern</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">press</ENAMEX>--the prospect of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> military attack on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>-- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ha'aretz</ENAMEX>
quoted <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> as saying that they believe <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> is
"extremely unlikely" to fire <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX> would be
likely to attack <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> only if he felt his reign was seriously imperiled," the
sources said.

            In its
lead
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX>, the conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jerusalem Post</ENAMEX> said that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> defense <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> saw a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
strike on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> as "inevitable," but they also regarded the chances of an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX>
Scud attack on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> as "next to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s orders for
the reopening of all gas mask distribution <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> and the updating of chemical
warfare protection kits were merely a precaution, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> reported. An
op-ed piece by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daoud Kuttab</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jerusalem Post</ENAMEX> noted a
dangerous trend for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">militants</ENAMEX> always to raise their level of
violence in periods between the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> steps toward genuine peace and its actual
implementation. Calling on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yasser Arafat</ENAMEX> "to stand side by side
after any anti-peace incident and publicly repeat their unified commitment to
peace and security for both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peoples</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kuttab</ENAMEX> wrote that if they did this "there
is no doubt that, in time, peace will indeed be at hand."

            In a front-page editorial, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Stampa</ENAMEX> noted that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, no longer the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lame duck</ENAMEX>"
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX> had called him <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only a few days ago</TIMEX>, has now decided to deliver "a
definitive blow" against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX>. Saying the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gulf</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> are
all against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> military action, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Stampa</ENAMEX> said that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, who has
"truly resumed the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> of the world," has decided to go ahead on his
own. Corriere
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">della Sera of Milan</ENAMEX> reported from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> also opposes an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX> strike against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>.

            The
conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> Le
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Figaro</ENAMEX> said in a front-page editorial that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX> had made "a fatal error"
by assuming that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> would emerge weakened from the midterm elections
because of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> affair. "The result: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the six-year</TIMEX> duel between
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX> has reached a point of no return. ... The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> president
has <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> to create for himself a place in the history books other than
that of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">debauchee</ENAMEX> who was lucky to reign over a period of prosperity," Le
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Figaro</ENAMEX> said. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> wants to lance the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> boil, and it is
ready to do so on its own at any moment." But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> blamed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX>'s
intransigence for this situation. "If one really wishes <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> well and wants to
end an international crisis, one must get rid of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX>," it said. "The
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> strike would therefore only be the prelude to a long offensive."

            
The liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Libération</ENAMEX>, said <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> was
disappointed by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>'s response to its neutrality in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> showdown with
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. "It is difficult to propose mediation when one doesn't
understand the position of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>," it quoted a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> government
source as saying. But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Libération</ENAMEX> added that, despite its
"disappointment," <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> was still not ready at this stage to participate in
any <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> strikes against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>.

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> ran a hard-line
editorial saying that "it will not be enough this time for fire-power to be
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">marshalled</ENAMEX> and then abandoned on some diplomatic pretext. ... <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> must now
accept an expanded <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Unscom</ENAMEX>, with a larger proportion of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX>, unimpeded authority, and an unrestricted timetable," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said.
"Anything less than this would only represent another escape for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iraqi</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dictator</ENAMEX> and more danger for the world."

         
      
   
