
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Warrior Queens</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth</ENAMEX> is a lurid
paraphrase of the old <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Groucho Marx</ENAMEX> line about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doris Day</ENAMEX>: "I knew the Virgin
Queen before she was a virgin." As the movie tells it, she was a sylvan,
redheaded princess (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cate Blanchett</ENAMEX>) given to gamboling with her fella (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joseph</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fiennes</ENAMEX>) between periods of internment in the Tower of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> on charges of
conspiring to overthrow her <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>, the heatedly <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catholic Queen Mary</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathy Burke</ENAMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Henry VIII</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anne Boleyn</ENAMEX>, and
therefore dubbed a bastard by the papists, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Protestant</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth</ENAMEX> ascends the
throne to find the air still thick with smoke from roasted heretics, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> of
skulking <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholics</ENAMEX> plotting her assassination, and a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">council</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisers</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lords</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bishops</ENAMEX>, sundry old boys) who snigger openly at the prospect of taking
orders from a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>. Only a strategic marriage to a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Spaniard or a Frenchman</ENAMEX>
will mollify all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">factions</ENAMEX>, her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisers</ENAMEX> insist, but the pickings prove dismal.
(Her <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suitor</ENAMEX> enjoys wearing dresses.) After skulls are smashed, throats
slit, and bosoms skewered in the name of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christ</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth</ENAMEX> decides to: a)
"unsex" herself and become a symbol--the Virgin <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Queen</ENAMEX>, married only to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>;
and b) entertain dissenting opinions exclusively from those whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heads</ENAMEX> are
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">affixed</ENAMEX> to spikes.

            You can't
be both a queenly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">queen</ENAMEX> and a womanly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>, says the script (by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hirst</ENAMEX>)--at least not in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1554</TIMEX>. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shekhar Kapur</ENAMEX>, made the same point
in his grim <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> epic The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bandit Queen</ENAMEX> , against a backdrop of
scrubby plains along the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ganges</ENAMEX>.) Is this feminist take historically accurate?
Probably, although the evidence suggests that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth</ENAMEX> had developed a head
for stratagems earlier in life (her position had been precarious since the
beheading of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>) and came to the throne with few girlish illusions
about How Things Work in a barbarous <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>.

            That said, the movie's approach makes for juicy melodrama.
The tone of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth</ENAMEX> comes <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">nearer</NUMEX> to the nihilistic relish of Jacobeans
such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Ford</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Webster</ENAMEX> than to the more sorrowful horror of the
Elizabethan dramatists <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben Jonson</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Shakespeare</ENAMEX>. It's even closer to
a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jacobean</ENAMEX> drama of our own age: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Godfather</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1972</TIMEX>), which it emulates
by cutting back-and-forth between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">queen</ENAMEX> and courtiers in prayer and the roundup
and slaughter of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholics</ENAMEX> on their privies, in bed with their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mistresses</ENAMEX>, and
so on. Their severed heads look on, wide-eyed, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth</ENAMEX> directs her hair to
be shorn--images of her girlhood flashing by as her locks rain down--and then
walks weightily to her throne, now a chalk-faced gorgon.

            With all
due respect to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blanchett</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bette Davis</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glenda Jackson</ENAMEX>, my favorite
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth</ENAMEX> I remains <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miranda Richardson</ENAMEX>'s capricious, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX>-talking psychopath on
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BBC</ENAMEX> comedy <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Blackadder II</ENAMEX> . (Casting about for a new lord high
executioner, she mews to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rowan Atkinson</ENAMEX>, "There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholics</ENAMEX>
simply dying to have their heads sneaked off --and there's no one to
organize it.") But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blanchett</ENAMEX> comes in a close <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>, pulling off the
transition from hapless young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> to coolly ruthless monarch with uncommon
subtlety. Gradually expunging all empathy from her moist, pink eyes and
permitting her visage to ossify, she gives this carnival of carnage an
awe-inspiring <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX>.

            
A more subversive sort of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">queen</ENAMEX> is on display
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Velvet Goldmine</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Todd Haynes</ENAMEX>' musical fantasia on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early '70s</TIMEX> era
of "glam" or "glitter" rock. Here the monarch is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Bowie</ENAMEX>-esque <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singer</ENAMEX>
called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian Slade</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Rhys-Meyers</ENAMEX>) and his spidery, space-age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alter ego</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maxwell Demon</ENAMEX>. The movie opens with a spaceship depositing an infant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oscar</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilde</ENAMEX> on the stoop of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dublin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">townhouse</ENAMEX>. Then it skips ahead to track a jade
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pin</ENAMEX> (it signifies hedonistic liberation) from the custody of a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilde</ENAMEX> to a
swishy fringe creature called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Fairy</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">regal Slade</ENAMEX>, a bisexual
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">superstar</ENAMEX> who carries the news to all the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dudes</ENAMEX>. After that, we're in an
Orwellian <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1984</TIMEX> that's presided over by a vaguely fascist <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and by arena
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rockers</ENAMEX> who serve as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">propagandists</ENAMEX> for a repressively conformist <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>.
Whatever happened to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian Slade</ENAMEX>, the glitter <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>, the visionary
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">exhibitionists</ENAMEX> and gleeful poseurs? Borrowing its framework from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Citizen</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kane</ENAMEX> , the movie follows a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian Bale</ENAMEX>) assigned to reconstruct
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slade</ENAMEX>'s life and solve the mystery of his whereabouts.

            Whatever you make of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Velvet Goldmine</ENAMEX> (opinions have ranged from rapturous to casually
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dismissive</ENAMEX>), it's like no other musical ever made. It's determinedly swirling,
discursive, elliptical. Now the story is told by an omniscient <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">narrator</ENAMEX>, now a
TV <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>, now a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participant</ENAMEX>. Now it's flashing back, now forward. Every
other line of dialogue is a cue for one of its dazzling numbers, largely covers
of songs by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian Eno</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bryan Ferry</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">T. Rex</ENAMEX>. The narrative is a challenge to
keep up with, but then, great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> often invent their own syntax. In the
'80s, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Haynes</ENAMEX> employed <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Barbie</ENAMEX> dolls to depict the rise and wasting away from
anorexia of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karen Carpenter</ENAMEX>. Lucky <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audiences</ENAMEX> who caught
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Superstar: The Karen Carpenter Story</ENAMEX> (it was shelved when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carpenter</ENAMEX> served the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">producers</ENAMEX> with an order to cease and desist exhibition)
began by laughing at this <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">elaborately</ENAMEX> posed, soft-rock femme, only to discover
by the climax that the cultural forces that were eating at her (and that kept
her from eating) had grown heartbreakingly palpable. Poison (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>),
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Haynes' Gen√</ENAMEX>™t-inspired exploration of transgression, didn't overcome its own
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">artiness</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Safe</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>), the story of a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Reagan-era</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">housewife</ENAMEX> (Julianne
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moore</ENAMEX>) convinced that her environment is poisoning her, is an entrancing
meditation on the power of culture to crush the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX>. Despite its ironic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">detachment</ENAMEX>, the film draws you into its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroine</ENAMEX>'s sickly <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Breathing</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oxygen</ENAMEX> from a canister inside a high-tech igloo, she dwindles to nearly
nothing, the modern incarnation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Incredible Shrinking Man</ENAMEX>.

            (It was
partly my passion for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Haynes</ENAMEX>' films that led me to accept a job offer from his
indefatigable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christine Vachon</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> to collaborate on a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">nuts-and-bolts</ENAMEX> book about producing, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Shooting To Kill</ENAMEX> . So my review of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Velvet Goldmine</ENAMEX> --like my review of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vachon</ENAMEX>'s other recent release, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Happiness</ENAMEX> --should be read as the work of
a partisan. But not a blind partisan.)

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Velvet Goldmine , Haynes</ENAMEX> sets out to demonstrate
the power of popular music to change <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s lives--to tell them it's OK to
fashion themselves into anything they please. The core of the movie turns out
not to be the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bowie</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figure</ENAMEX> but the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arthur Stuart</ENAMEX>, who was a witness
to the events he's now reconstructing. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bale</ENAMEX> is such an expressive performer
that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stuart</ENAMEX>'s remembrance of things past attains a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Proustian</ENAMEX> intensity. To him,
Slade was a sexual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">messiah</ENAMEX>. I've never seen a more vivid distillation of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rock</ENAMEX>'s
allure than the scene in which he reverently opens the new <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian Slade</ENAMEX>
album--its centerfold image is a lithe, naked, green-tinged <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maxwell</ENAMEX>
Demon--slips the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vinyl</ENAMEX> out of its paper jacket and, after gingerly setting the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LP</ENAMEX> on the turntable, props a chair under the doorknob to keep the
uncomprehending world at bay.

            But if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Haynes</ENAMEX> wants Velvet
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goldmine</ENAMEX> to be an anthem to the principles <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bowie</ENAMEX> once embodied--the embrace
of artifice and the smashing of conventional sexual roles--he also wants to
portray the rocker as a hollow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opportunist</ENAMEX> who abandoned glam and bisexuality
for the life of a corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">superstar</ENAMEX>, throwing in his lot with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> of
repression. That's a lot to cover. An <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> of stature might have bridged these
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> impulses, but the beautiful, brazenly slim-hipped <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rhys-Meyers</ENAMEX> doesn't make
his lines sound as if he's thinking them up on the spot, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slade</ENAMEX>'s
self-destructive passion for <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Curt Wild</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ewan McGregor</ENAMEX>), the film's fuzzy, sweet
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iggy Pop</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figure</ENAMEX>, seems less an emotional imperative than a thematic <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>.

            A case can
be made that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Velvet Goldmine</ENAMEX> isn't fully filled in, and that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Haynes</ENAMEX>, who
has never shaken off his background as a semiotics major, has made a movie
that's all signifiers. I sometimes found myself wishing he would let the
picture catch its breath, that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">performers</ENAMEX> would stop coming at me in
stroboscopic flashes. But then I'd be swept up in the sinuous motion of his
filmmaking, in the elation of watching point of view passed like a baton from
hand to hand, in the liberating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> of his language and soundtrack. Velvet
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goldmine</ENAMEX> might seem like a collection of baubles, but those baubles are
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">strung</ENAMEX>.

            
Is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brad Pitt</ENAMEX> the worst <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> on earth? The case
could be made, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meet Joe Black</ENAMEX> could serve as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Exhibit A. Pitt</ENAMEX> plays
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> roles in this <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">course schlockfest</ENAMEX>. He's (briefly) a slick but
wholesome yuppie and then (interminably) <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Death</ENAMEX>, who takes over the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s
body when he's thumped by a couple of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> in the movie's most promising
moment. Bleached so blond that he looks like an irradiated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">android</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pitt</ENAMEX> expels
all expression from his face and all tone from his voice. He speaks very, very
slowly. The stunt <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>-works, at least until he's supposed to undergo an inner
transformation and acquire human emotions--whereupon his face remains just as
blank. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pitt</ENAMEX>'s conception of the role is an id√©e fixe by someone who
doesn't appear to have an id√©e in his head.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Martin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brest</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>, is known for shooting a ton of footage and then "finding"
his films in the editing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>. What do you suppose he "found" when he
scrutinized these <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">miles</NUMEX> of celluloid with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pitt</ENAMEX> doing nothing and taking his
sweet time doing it? The first adaptation of this story (originally a play) was
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1934</TIMEX> Death Takes a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holiday</ENAMEX> , which came in at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a perky 78 minutes</TIMEX>. A
conceit this fragile needs to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whiz</ENAMEX> along to keep our disbelief in suspension,
but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meet Joe Black</ENAMEX> grinds on for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three hours</TIMEX> (longer than either
Beloved or Saving <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Private Ryan</ENAMEX> ), and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pitt</ENAMEX> acts as if he has
leased the screen by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony Hopkins</ENAMEX> plays the zillionaire communications baron
whom Death enlists in the hope of understanding the human condition--an odd
choice for a tour guide, since most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s condition doesn't involve personal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">helicopters</ENAMEX>, sprawling <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mansions</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Long Island Sound</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartments</ENAMEX>
that sport <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Olympic</ENAMEX>-size swimming <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pools</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">screenwriters</ENAMEX>, among them the
great <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bo Goldman</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melvin</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Shoot the Moon</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1982</TIMEX>),
labored on this moldy script, which features <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> who ask questions that
begin "Am I to understand that ...?" and a corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">villain</ENAMEX> who directs
another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> to "wake up and smell the thorns." It apparently never
occurred to even one of these overpaid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scribes</ENAMEX> to eliminate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hopkins</ENAMEX>' rueful
realization that he'd "never write the great <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> novel"--no kidding, given
his flagrantly Welsh accent.

            Actually, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hopkins</ENAMEX> gives this
humanistic magnate considerable weight, so that whether or not Death takes him
before he can stop to smell the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">roses</ENAMEX> and make amends to his neglected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
becomes a matter of some suspense. The rest of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cast</ENAMEX> works with equal
fortitude, especially <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeffrey Tambor</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hank "Hey</ENAMEX> now!" Kingsley on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Larry</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sanders Show</ENAMEX> ) as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hopkins</ENAMEX>' milksop <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son-in-law</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marcia Gay Harden</ENAMEX> as his
party planning, perpetually wilting elder <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>. As the younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>,
the dark eyed, spaghetti thin <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Claire Forlani</ENAMEX> has to carry the picture's bathos
on her exquisite shoulders. Her tremulous thoroughbred act wears thin, but it's
hardly her fault: She has to emote like mad opposite a black <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pit</ENAMEX> of death--or
is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Black Death of Pitt</ENAMEX>?

         
      
   
