
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Golden Fleece</ENAMEX>

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX>, the spectrum
of fabric quality ran from beloved natural <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fibers</ENAMEX> down to mediocre <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">cotton</ENAMEX>-poly
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">blends</ENAMEX>, then dipped into trashiness with pure polyester. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> polyester fleece
is the uniform of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hikers</ENAMEX>, climbers, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">backpackers</ENAMEX>, college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who
want to look like them. As in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '70s</TIMEX>, you're nothing in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '90s</TIMEX> if you're
not in polyester--preferably polyester from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Patagonia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The North Face, Marmot</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REI</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L.L. Bean</ENAMEX>.

            Don't
write this off as a mere fashion fad. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Polyester</ENAMEX> is undergoing a renaissance
because fleece is truly a miracle <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fabric</ENAMEX>: It's warm and durable but
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">lightweight</ENAMEX>, and it dries faster than natural <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fibers</ENAMEX>. At the same time, it
feels natural to the touch, not scratchy like the poly of yore. And while
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fleece</ENAMEX> takes over the sweater and sweat shirt market, other synthetic fabrics
are horning in on the long underwear <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX>, with equally good reason.
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Polypropylene</ENAMEX> and other newer polyester <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blends</ENAMEX> beat out <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cotton</ENAMEX> for keeping your
skin <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dry</ENAMEX> and warm. In short, in high performance clothing, fake is great.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fleece</ENAMEX> is a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">100 percent</NUMEX> polyester <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fabric</ENAMEX> that's made like
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">terry</ENAMEX> cloth. First a machine knits the fleece, leaving tiny loops on its
surface, then the fabric is treated in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> ways. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) Napping: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Machines</ENAMEX> smack
the fleece with tiny wires that break the loops. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Combing</ENAMEX>: The strands of
fleece are groomed to stand up <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX> cut straight, thereby creating air-trapping
space. The trapped air creates warmth. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) Shearing: The upright strands are
shorn to a uniform height, which stops the strands from getting tangled up like
dreadlocks, a problem that leads to pilling.

            All this
manufacturing goes on not at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Patagonia</ENAMEX> or The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North Face</ENAMEX> or any of their
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX>--these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> just design and sew the garments. The fleece used
in high end outdoor clothing is made by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> textile <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malden Mills</ENAMEX> and
Dyersburg, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coke</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pepsi</ENAMEX> of fleece. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Malden Mills</ENAMEX> holds a near monopoly on
high performance fleece (to find out why it's a monopoly you can love, click ),
while Dyersburg feasts on the leftovers. By all accounts, both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mills</ENAMEX> produce
superb fabric.

            
So, is all fleece basically the same? It is if
you're the kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shopper</ENAMEX> who only buys premium brands. Otherwise you have to
contend with cheap <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> imports. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> I talked to at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Malden</ENAMEX> and Dyersburg
complained mightily about shoddy <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> fleece flooding the market and
undercutting them. In this case, there's a good reason to buy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>: Most
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fleece</ENAMEX> has been napped, but it hasn't been combed or sheared. Thus <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) Its
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">subpar</ENAMEX> air trapping begets a pitiful warmth-to-weight ratio; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) it tends to
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pill</ENAMEX>. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> fleece will even pill--horrors!--before it leaves the sales
rack! (You can test this by rubbing the fleece with your palm.) To be fair, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> admit that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fleece</ENAMEX> has made great strides, but the West is still
best.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fleece</ENAMEX> is mostly relegated to down-market brands--the name "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Kmart</ENAMEX>" was floated
by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Malden</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokeswoman</ENAMEX>. The top brands proudly announce that they use Malden
(trademark: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Polartec 100, 200</ENAMEX>, or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">300</NUMEX>) or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dyersburg</ENAMEX> (trademark: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">E.C.O.</ENAMEX> or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dyertech</ENAMEX>). All except for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Patagonia</ENAMEX>, that is, which pretends its Synchilla
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fleece</ENAMEX> is something else. Despite costing more and supposedly being better,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Patagonia</ENAMEX>'s fleece is from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Malden</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dyersburg</ENAMEX>, just like everyone else's. If
there's some other difference between them, I don't know about it, because
despite many phone calls and e-mails, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patagonia</ENAMEX> refused to answer my questions
on this point.

            Why not buy the cheapest gear you can find that uses
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> fleece? Because design makes a difference. Compare <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Campmor</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$60</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Polartec 300</ENAMEX> jacket with The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North Face</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$160</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Denali</ENAMEX> jacket, also featuring
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Polartec 300</ENAMEX>. Both use the same fabric, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Malden</ENAMEX>'s excellent heaviest weight
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fleece</ENAMEX>. There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> good reasons to pay <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100</NUMEX> more for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Denali</ENAMEX>, and one
so-so one: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Denali</ENAMEX> has a nylon <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">shell</ENAMEX> over its torso, improving wind
resistance. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Denali</ENAMEX> has more pockets, with zipper closures. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) The Denali
has flaps behind the zippers in its armpit vents (all high-tech jackets have
zippered armpit vents), while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Campmor</ENAMEX> has no flaps, so cold seeps through.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) The cool <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">North Face</ENAMEX> logo and jacket cut will impress your gearhead <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>
more than the budget <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Campmor</ENAMEX> logo and cut.

            To test
the designs of these and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> other popular fleece tops, I went to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duke</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX>'s zoology <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>, where many walk-in refrigerators and freezers
are to be found. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entrants</ENAMEX> in my little competition were the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Campmor</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Face</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marmot E.C.O. vest</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$89</NUMEX>, fleece made by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dyersburg</ENAMEX> from recycled
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">plastic soda</ENAMEX> bottles), and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patagonia Synchilla Snap-T</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$86</NUMEX>, the it-fleece
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">prep-school</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Phish</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> set).

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Duke</ENAMEX>'s walk-in fridge runs a cool <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">40 degrees</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fahrenheit</ENAMEX>. With a long sleeve, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">polypropylene</ENAMEX> T-shirt as a base layer (more on
that later), I wore each fleece in the fridge for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about 10 minutes</TIMEX>. The Marmot
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">vest</ENAMEX> performed best, keeping my torso toasty but, of course, leaving my arms
quite cold. The other fleeces would have been plenty warm during exercise, but
standing still I felt a bit chilly. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North Face</ENAMEX> did a fine job here, while
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Campmor</ENAMEX> faced the aforementioned armpit zipper problem. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Patagonia</ENAMEX> had
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> drawbacks: While in calm conditions the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Snap-T</ENAMEX> was the warmest of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">entrants</ENAMEX>, it was especially nonwind-resistant (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">fridge</ENAMEX> had a fan). That was
in part because it had no nylon lining, but it was still less wind-resistant
than other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX> without a lining. Also, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Patagonia</ENAMEX> had no pockets for
my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hands</ENAMEX>--a shocking oversight.

            Next, I ventured into the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">freezer</ENAMEX>, a chilling <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">minus 8 degrees Fahrenheit</NUMEX>. None of the fleeces came close
to weathering this kind of cold. An outer layer is clearly necessary in these
conditions, even when you're vigorously exercising (which I tried to do in the
freezer until I quickly became lightheaded from the icy air).

            Overall
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">North Face Denali</ENAMEX> jacket, with a great design but at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$160</NUMEX> the
highest price tag by far. Sometimes you get what you pay for.

            General conclusion: Look for designs that minimize <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">fleece</ENAMEX>'s
weaknesses. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fleece</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Achilles</ENAMEX>' heel is that, without a nylon coating, it lacks
any wind <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resistance</ENAMEX>--a slight breeze that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wool</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cotton</ENAMEX> would turn back cuts
right through fleece with a nasty bite. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> other weaknesses of fleece to keep
in mind: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) If you fall onto a nubby carpet while wearing fleece, as I did
intentionally, the fleece gets irreparable bald spots at the impact points.
This is especially relevant to all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s fleece being sold <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX>--tykes
are prone to carpet falls. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fleece</ENAMEX> easily melts, even when exposed for less
than a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> to the flame of a cigarette lighter.

            The things
to look for are a good fit, an attractive look, a nylon <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">shell</ENAMEX>, and ample and
amply sized pockets. Fleece <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">makers</ENAMEX> offer a few other options. Shearling fleece
looks more like <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sheep</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wool</ENAMEX>, with a pebbly texture. Instead of being sheared,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">shearling</ENAMEX>'s strands are coaxed into clumps. Some think the resulting nooks
create better insulation and wind resistance. I didn't try shearling, but no
one I spoke with recommended it. Another option is to blend spandex with fleece
to make it stretchier and more form-fitting. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Malden</ENAMEX> does this with its
Powerstretch fabrics, available in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The North Face's Aurora vest</ENAMEX>, among other
products.

            
Now that fleece is the insulation of choice,
other fake fabrics have grown popular as "base layers." Synthetic long
underwear used to be made of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">polypropylene</ENAMEX>; some of it still is. The advantage
was that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">polypropylene</ENAMEX> dried much faster than <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cotton</ENAMEX>, spreading sweat across
the fabric to increase the sweat's surface area and speed up evaporation. But
the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fabric</ENAMEX> has severe weaknesses, as I found out from testing a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Wickers</ENAMEX> brand
long sleeve T-shirt made of pure <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">polypropylene</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$17.99</NUMEX>): <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) Polypropylene
retains odor (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">just</NUMEX> trust me on this). <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) It's got the same icky feeling against
your skin as groovy <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">'70s</ENAMEX> polyester shirts. Sleeping in it was uncomfortable,
and in time I predict it might cause itch- and abrasion-themed nightmares. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>)
While it spreads your sweat across the fabric surface until it evaporates, the
sweat stays against your skin.

            Lately,
better synthetics have come along. Powerdry, a polyester fabric designed by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malden Mills</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">CoolMax</ENAMEX>, a polyester <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">concoction</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DuPont</ENAMEX>, boast <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> layer
"dimensional wicking," an industry buzz phrase meaning sweat leaves your skin
instantly then spreads out on the top layer of the fabric. I tested a Duofold
short sleeve T-shirt made of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CoolMax</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$15.99</NUMEX>) and an REI zip turtleneck made of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Powerdry</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$34</NUMEX>). According to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Malden, Powerdry</ENAMEX>'s "patented <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">BiPolar</ENAMEX> construction
has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> unique surfaces: the soft inner layer rapidly wicks perspiration away
from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX>, while the durable outer layer spreads moisture for maximum
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">evaporation</ENAMEX>." I have no reason to doubt them. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DuPont</ENAMEX> claims <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">CoolMax</ENAMEX> has
"<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>-channel <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fibers</ENAMEX>" that give it "the fastest drying rate of any <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fabric</ENAMEX>." The
only difference I could detect between them was in their feel against my skin.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CoolMax</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Powerdry</ENAMEX> fared equally well in battling the sweat I worked up
running laps around 
                  Slate
               's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">CoolMax</ENAMEX> gets the nod
because not only does it not retain odor, even when worn for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two days</TIMEX> and
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nights</TIMEX> without deodorant, but it truly feels like silk. I'm going to buy
CoolMax for all my underwear--it's a terrific product.

            If you
missed the link, click to see why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malden Mills</ENAMEX> is a monopoly you can love.

         
      
   
