
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leonard Cohen</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Lit</ENAMEX>

            You could easily have got
the wrong impression of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jos√© Saramago</ENAMEX> from the flood of press reports last week
when it was announced that he'd won <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nobel Prize</ENAMEX> for literature. The
gist of the coverage was that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saramago</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Portuguese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novelist</ENAMEX> known for his
playful excavations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iberian</ENAMEX> history, is the real thing , an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inheritor</ENAMEX>
of the majestic <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> literary tradition and the last best hope for the
serious novel. His life story enhances this image of fragile purity: He's a
late <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bloomer</ENAMEX> who didn't publish a mature work until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">his 50s</TIMEX> and didn't become
famous until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">his 60s</TIMEX>. His picture in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> had something to
do with it too: At <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">75</NUMEX>, squinting and overcome with emotion, he looked like a
mole emerging from an underground <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tunnel</ENAMEX>--or, with his thick eyeglasses and
white-fringed bald <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dome</ENAMEX>, like Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Magoo</ENAMEX>.

            "Even
I've never heard of me!" is how a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of mine meanly translated
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saramago</ENAMEX>'s befuddled expression. That's a wee bit unfair, of course. Although
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saramago</ENAMEX> isn't very well known in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, throughout <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1990s</TIMEX> he
has attracted a zealous international following. Besides, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX>
report that his sentences are long and obscure, his stories intertextual and
ambitious, they miss the real point of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saramago</ENAMEX>, which is that he's really
pretty accessible. Perhaps more than any living <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> I know, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saramago</ENAMEX> gives
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> a taste of the exquisite high you get when you first fall in love
with books. No matter where you sit down with one of his novels, you feel like
you're up past bedtime, reading with a flashlight, taking a break from your
humdrum life to commune with something magic and deep and eternal. The irony is
that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saramago</ENAMEX> uses some very contemporary methods to whip up this madeleine
reminder of classic literature. He's a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>, occasionally a great
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>, but mostly he's a pop <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>, working the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> into states
of childish longing and bliss.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saramago</ENAMEX> is often said to unite his native <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX>
skepticism with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> of magical realism. This is true up
to a point. Like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jorge Luis Borges</ENAMEX>, he flirts with science fiction <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">premises</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">invents</ENAMEX> antique literary texts and then analyzes them. His <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> most Borgesian
works are <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Year of the Death of Ricardo Reis</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1984</TIMEX>), an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hommage</ENAMEX> to the great <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Portuguese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fernando Pessoa</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The History</ENAMEX>
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Siege</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lisbon</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>), in which a proofreader inserts a single
word--"not"--into a single sentence in a book he's checking, thereby
questioning every celebrated theme of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Portuguese</ENAMEX> history. As much as they are
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Year of the Death and History</ENAMEX> are about writing and
what it can and cannot do.

            What
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">distinguishes Saramago</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Borges</ENAMEX> is his tenderness and his explicit, even
obsessive, curiosity about human emotion. Conventional literary history says
that the novel came into its own in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 18 th century</TIMEX>, alongside
individual rights and a modern conception of marriage. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saramago</ENAMEX> tries to figure
out what it means to love when those conditions don't apply. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baltasar</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blimunda</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1982</TIMEX>) is a romance set in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Portugal</ENAMEX> during the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Inquisition</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">suspenseful</ENAMEX> and brilliant <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blindness</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>), his latest book published in
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>, tells the fantastic story of an epidemic that leaves the whole world
unable to see. A quasi-Borgesian conceit, but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saramago</ENAMEX> uses it to ask how
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> love when disaster upsets the social norms. (The answer is atrociously,
although a few good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">souls</ENAMEX> do their best.)

            
Unlike <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Borges, Saramago</ENAMEX> is an outspoken
political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activist</ENAMEX> of a decidedly left-wing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slant</ENAMEX>. As a younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, he cheered
on the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">1974 revolution</ENAMEX> that liberated <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Portugal</ENAMEX> from a long, sleepy
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dictatorship</ENAMEX>. Lately he's supported agrarian reform in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX>, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last March</TIMEX>
he visited the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> jungle to express his solidarity with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chiapas</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebels</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">The day</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nobel</ENAMEX> was announced, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saramago</ENAMEX> was at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Frankfurt</ENAMEX> book
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fair</ENAMEX> to deliver a speech on what it means to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> today. His
party affiliation made the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> so apoplectic that it
published an op-ed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> declaring it all but a crime to give him the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nobel</ENAMEX>
Prize. But he is a most modest militant: At this point in history, he said,
communism is essentially a "spiritual <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>," a compassionate safeguard against
the built-in injustice of capitalism.

            His
politics, rare warmth, and long and many-claused sentences have earned Saramago
a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> comparison, this one to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gabriel Garc√</ENAMEX>≠a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M√°rquez.</ENAMEX> But if he's too human
to be another <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Borges</ENAMEX>, he's too intellectual and urbane to be another <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Garc√</ENAMEX>≠a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M√°rquez.</ENAMEX> His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> don't have <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cousins</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> and colorful,
labyrinthine histories. In fact, we often know next to nothing about his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>, except that they are lonely, bookish rolling stones who gather no
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">moss</ENAMEX>, spending <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">several hours a day</TIMEX> wandering around <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lisbon</ENAMEX> and daydreaming.
(The male <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>, anyway. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saramago</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> tend to be motherly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">souls</ENAMEX> who
either sweetly have sex with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> or else show them how to settle down.)

            Ithink a slightly less literary comparison is in order.
There's a revealing moment in The 
               History of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Siege</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lisbon</ENAMEX> ,
when the shy proofreader <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bachelor</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">his 50s</TIMEX>, is working at home. The
television plays silently in the background, and the proofreader looks over and
notices that, of all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the world, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leonard Cohen</ENAMEX> has appeared on the
screen. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Raimundo Silva</ENAMEX> bent over, turned on the sound, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leonard Cohen</ENAMEX> made a
gesture as if to thank him, now he could sing, and sing he did, he sang of
things only someone who has lived can sing of, and asks himself how much and
for what, someone who has loved and asks himself who and why, and, having asked
all these questions, he can find no answer, not one, contrary to the belief
that all the answers are there and that all we have to do is to learn how to
phrase our questions."

            Note the admiration for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cohen</ENAMEX>
and the chanting musicality of this passage (beautifully translated by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Giovanni</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pontiero</ENAMEX>), the echoes and variations circling around a bittersweet theme. Note
also <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saramago</ENAMEX>'s detached melancholy, his brainy anti-elitism, his characters
who are lovable but archetypal and abstract. All these qualities <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> have
identified as traits of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Great European</ENAMEX> Novel mixed with magical realism are
also the traits of the cool, alienated, allusion-dropping <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singer-songwriter</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cohen</ENAMEX> has always been praised as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet laureate</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">songsters</ENAMEX>. Why shouldn't
Saramago be the songwriter <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">laureate</ENAMEX> of novelists?

            Which leaves me a caveat:
There's a reason most good songs lasts <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">between five and 10 minutes</TIMEX> while a
novel usually demands <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few days</TIMEX>. At some point, ideally, the novel should go
deeper than the song. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saramago</ENAMEX> is never boring--his command over his material
is too impressive for that. He can get a little precious, though, and his
constant musing about fate can get repetitive, less like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leonard Cohen</ENAMEX> and more
like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Mellencamp</ENAMEX>, with his message that "life goes on, long after the
thrill of living is gone." I marveled at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saramago</ENAMEX>'s ingenuity when I reread him
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last weekend</TIMEX>; I also wondered at a few points if, with his brand of cute
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">obscurity</ENAMEX>, he was really <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nobel</ENAMEX> material. But I do know that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> can write a
tune, or at least the literary equivalent, and it sure is catchy.

         
      
   
