
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">138</NUMEX>:

            By <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cohen</ENAMEX>

            
               This
winter the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is testing a new <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1-to-5</NUMEX> rating <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">system</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nebraska</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wyoming</ENAMEX>. Rating what?
            

            by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 p.m. ET</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> to e-mail your answer to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.

            
               Responses
to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>'s Question (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 137</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Stop, Look, And ...":</ENAMEX>
            

            
               A proposal introduced
by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> would impose a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15 day</TIMEX> waiting period. Before you can
do what?
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Anything</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Doyle</ENAMEX>
            

            "Showing affection to your
newborn."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer Miller</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Releasing</ENAMEX> genocidal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dictators</ENAMEX>."--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Rakoff</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andrew Staples</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brooke Saucier</ENAMEX> had
similar answers.)

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Declaring America</ENAMEX>'s
latest foreign policy initiative misguided."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Gregg</ENAMEX>
            

            "Having another spanking,
you very naughty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Floyd Elliot</ENAMEX>
            

            Click for more
responses.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Cross-Cultural Wrap-Up
            

            Judging by your responses,
here's what we know about the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>--bad sex, bad <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>, bad teeth, bad
weather. Their insatiable appetite for royal gossip is cheerfully fed by a
venal press. Their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factories</ENAMEX> manufacture a steady supply of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ephemeral</ENAMEX> pop
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>. And they don't think much of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> and their bountiful supply of
good sex, good <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>, good weather, and--well, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> out of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>.

            This sort of jingoism is
unworthy of "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">News Quiz</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX>, who might charitably have pointed out how
graciously the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> have transformed themselves from a ruthless imperial
power into a vast island <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> that still believes itself to be a ruthless
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">imperial</ENAMEX> power. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Self-delusion</ENAMEX> in others can be so endearing.

            And I'm
sure you all join me in wishing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kate Moss</ENAMEX> a speedy return to her health, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret Thatcher</ENAMEX> to her senses.

            
               Official
Bliss Answer
            

            Before getting married.

            The
government introduced a package of measures to support <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>--by thwarting
"quickie" weddings, making prenuptial agreements legally binding, and improving
mediation services. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conservative Party</ENAMEX> denounced this "unprecedented level
of intrusion into family life."

            
               Press the
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Meat</ENAMEX> Extra
            

            Match
these recent headlines with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> in which they appeared. Hint:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. Loophole sets psychopath
free

            <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Drugs</ENAMEX> more feared than
bullying

            Youths attack <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> with
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">rockets</ENAMEX>

            Opera
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">chiefs</ENAMEX> should be jailed, says <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">MP</ENAMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. "If <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">It Had Been Me</ENAMEX> ... I'd
Have Killed the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C***</ENAMEX>"

            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pram Rage</ENAMEX>

            Breast in the World

            Corrie
Toy-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boy Fun</ENAMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. This Is Appalling

            You Brutes

            Keep Her in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prison</ENAMEX>

            I Hate
This Evil Being

            

               Answers
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Evening</ENAMEX>
Standard
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily</ENAMEX>
Express
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily</ENAMEX>
Mirror
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Disclaimer</ENAMEX>: All submissions will become the property of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> and
will be published at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> 's discretion. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> may publish your
name on its site in connection with your submission.
            

         
      
   
