
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Address your e-mail to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. You must include your address and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX>
phone number (for confirmation only).
            

            
               Virtually all the
e-mail <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> receives is signed. However, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent days</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>
has been flooded with unsigned e-mail responding to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Brill</ENAMEX> article on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>. We are unable to respond individually to this mass of letters,
so here is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Brill</ENAMEX>'s general response:
            

            
               First,
my question for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Starr</ENAMEX> has nothing to do with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s guilt or
innocence. Obviously, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s disgraceful and probably unlawful conduct
is more important than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s, but that does not make <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s apparent
breaking of the law irrelevant. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, it's hilarious to hear <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> say about
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s leaks--as I never did and never would with regard to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>--that breaking a law isn't important because everyone does it, at the
same time that they ridicule the notion that lying under oath about sex would
be OK because lots of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have, or would, do it.
            

            
               A
Question for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Question</ENAMEX>
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Starr</ENAMEX>": In all fairness, let's put <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> to the same measure
of scrutiny.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald E.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dunn Clinton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tenn.</ENAMEX>

            

               Definition of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Leak</ENAMEX>?
            

            In "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A</ENAMEX>
Question for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Starr</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Brill</ENAMEX>'s brilliant writing says nothing that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintons</ENAMEX>' spin hasn't stated from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Day 1</TIMEX>: "Let us seek to destroy anyone that
speaks in a negative regard about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintons</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX> has done the job
asked by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX>. Perhaps now that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintons</ENAMEX> have managed to get the
tables turned by using the very press that acted like piranhas in getting the
story and displaying it on our TV screens for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> and even <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>
should exercise some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> "dumb" defense and reply to the
questions proposed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brill</ENAMEX> with the wisdom of "It depends on how you define
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'leak</ENAMEX>' "?

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Black Tyler</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas</ENAMEX>

            
               Heavy
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gamblers</ENAMEX>?
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plotz</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 12</TIMEX> article "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sin City 1, Puritans 0</ENAMEX>": I am <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">253 pounds</NUMEX> of big-eating
ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX>. I am also, generally, against gambling. So much for your
theory.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lowell</ENAMEX> Mick
White <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>

            
               Genetic
Burden
            

            I could
not believe what I read in the last paragraph of 
                  Slate
               's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 11</TIMEX>
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>." To say that finding a genetic link to a "Founding
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Father</ENAMEX>" will bring forth a feeling of patriotic pride in alienated minorities
is absurd. How can you overlook the fact that this "link" is a result of one
race's dominion over another in the form of slavery? Where is the pride in
that? I cannot overlook the fact that this link is a result of slavery. How
could you?

            -- Roxanna Vanessa
Alvarado <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Culver City</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX>

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Full</TIMEX> of
It
            

            As one
who put in an order at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX> and only just received the book (via <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">FedEx</ENAMEX>)
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two days ago</TIMEX>, can't I get a chance to read <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Man in Full</ENAMEX> before it's
analyzed to death? A quick 
                  Slate
                search on the subject has
returned <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> articles containing the title, though you are certainly not the
only ones on the bandwagon. It seems I can't glance at the New York
Times without seeing an article on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Wolfe</ENAMEX> or his latest work. I suppose
the last <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">straw</ENAMEX> was seeing that you have a "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Book Club</ENAMEX>" debate on the subject. It's a pretty hefty tome, and
I've never been a particularly fast <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX>. Can you give some of us a chance
before giving it all away?

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ryan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kriger</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brookline</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mass.</ENAMEX>

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times Book Review</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yawn</ENAMEX>)
            

            In his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 14</TIMEX> critique of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Book Review</ENAMEX> titled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"A Hundred Years of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lassitude</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Weisberg</ENAMEX> ignores the biggest reason that it is so boring.
(I agree with him on this point!) It is boring because many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> couldn't
care less about <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">70 percent</NUMEX> of the books it reviews. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYTBR</ENAMEX> has become
heavily weighted in favor of reviews of nonfiction over fiction. Nonfiction
works generally appeal to small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">academics</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">devotees</ENAMEX> of any particular
subject, and those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are likely to read the books regardless of what the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYTBR</ENAMEX> says.

            While the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> is perhaps more literate than other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>, it is,
nonetheless, a general circulation <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> and not an academic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journal</ENAMEX>. In a
general circulation <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> I expect reviews of books that are, or
potentially are, of interest to a broad range of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>. I don't think that
means having to pander to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Oprah</ENAMEX> crowd. Many fine works of fiction go
undiscovered <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYTBR</ENAMEX> would be better served reviewing
those.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zimmatore Atlanta</ENAMEX>

            
               Address your e-mail to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. You must include your address and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX>
phone number (for confirmation only).
            

         
      
   
