
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Movies
            

            
               
                  The
Siege
                (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th Century Fox</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> are sour on this what-if
action thriller about terrorism in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>. They say the film cashes in on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>'s fear of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fundamentalists</ENAMEX>, then chastises them for bigotry.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Editorialists</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX> alike call the movie anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Denzel Washington</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Annette Bening</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operatives</ENAMEX>, respectively) are said to be good
but not great. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Willis</ENAMEX> (as a psychotic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> general) is so stamped in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">moviegoers</ENAMEX>' minds as the butt-kicking good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> that he leaves the audience
cheering at all the wrong moments. (Visit the
official site.)

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gramercy Pictures</ENAMEX>). Mixed, but mainly good, reviews
for this lavish costume drama about the first <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Queen Elizabeth</ENAMEX> and her troubled
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ascendance</ENAMEX> to the throne. Some love the "darkly sumptuous, hypnotically
complex" plotting (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Schickel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> ); others call the film
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Masterpiece Theater</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MTV</ENAMEX> generation," riddled with glaring
historical inaccuracies (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rod Dreher</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Post</ENAMEX> ). <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> things draw
praise from all: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) The spectacular art direction; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cate Blanchett</ENAMEX>'s
performance as a feminist Virgin <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Queen</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Edelstein</ENAMEX> reviews the
film in 
                  Slate
               .)

            
               
                  The
Waterboy
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buena Vista Pictures</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> either love it or hate it:
Either the movie "overflows with repellent humor" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joan Anderman</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> ), or it's "loony, unapologetic fun ... an utter hoot" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Maslin</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ). With a voice "like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Truman Capote</ENAMEX> on Seconal" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave</ENAMEX>
Kehr, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily News</ENAMEX> ), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam Sandler</ENAMEX> regresses from the borderline maturity
of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Wedding</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Singer</ENAMEX> back to his trademark sweet, addled, violent
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>--this time in a formula sports-loser-turned-sports-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> flick aimed
at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fraternity</ENAMEX>/junior-high-school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to
read about the making of this film.)

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Velvet Goldmine</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miramax Films</ENAMEX>). This tribute to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">'70s</NUMEX> glam uses a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Citizen Kane</ENAMEX> -style device to explore the rise and fall of a pair of Iggy
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pop/Ziggy Stardust</ENAMEX>-ish rock <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX>. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> (such as the New York
Times ' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maslin</ENAMEX>) nearly fall out of their chairs in awe at the operatic
splendor of the music and pageantry--"blazing with exquisite yet abstract
passions." Others are less impressed by all the stuff-strutting: "[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">E</ENAMEX>]veryone in
the movie has the approximate human weight of a hologram" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Rainer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York</ENAMEX> ). (Read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edelstein</ENAMEX>'s review in

                  Slate
               .)

            

               Book
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Invention of the Human</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harold Bloom</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Riverhead Books</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Reviewers</ENAMEX> call <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bloom</ENAMEX>'s tome "a cloak-bag of ideas, stuffed
with true wisdom and false bombast" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Bate</ENAMEX>, the Wall Street
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bloom</ENAMEX>'s vigor and intelligence in his examination of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX>'s plays make the book a joy to read, despite the fact that he "does
not quite prove his tremendous thesis" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jodie Morse</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> )--that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX> single-handedly created the modern idea of individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personality</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> call <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bloom</ENAMEX> "a master entertainer" who has applied his formidable skills
to the noble project of a general <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX>'s introduction to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yahlin Chang</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> ). (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to buy the book.)

            

               Music
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Springsteen</ENAMEX>: Tracks
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Springsteen</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia</ENAMEX>). This
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> disc collection of old songs--mainly unpublished material with a few
B-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sides</ENAMEX>--is said to provide valuable insight into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Springsteen</ENAMEX>'s progression as
an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>, but the music itself is only so-so. The harsher <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> call it
"iffy ballads and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lame</ENAMEX> roadhouse rock" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff Giles</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> ). Despite
the weakness of some of these recycled scraps, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Springsteen</ENAMEX>'s "unbridled
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">earnestness</ENAMEX> and positive energy" are still impressive (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Browne</ENAMEX>,
Entertainment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly</ENAMEX> ). (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to join an online discussion about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Springsteen.</ENAMEX>)

            

               Opera
            

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Le</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nozze di Figaro</ENAMEX>
               , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metropolitan Opera</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Met</ENAMEX>'s "handsome
and subtle" production (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alex Ross</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> ) leaves critics
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">debating diva Cecilia Bartoli</ENAMEX>'s performance as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Susanna</ENAMEX>. Is she "comically over
the top, attention-grabbing and at times hysterical" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony Tommasini</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ), or is she simply a "captivating comic presence"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Isherwood</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Variety</ENAMEX> )? Not everyone loved the production: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Davis</ENAMEX> says, "[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX>]he characters [are] foggily defined and the
heart of the opera left unexamined." (Here's the
schedule for remaining performances.)

            
               Recent
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment</ENAMEX>" columns
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Nov.</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
History <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">X</NUMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carpenter</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vampires</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Life Is</ENAMEX>
Beautiful ;

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Living Out</ENAMEX>
Loud ;

            
               Art --"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pollock</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum of Modern Art</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>);

            

               Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- A Man in Full</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Wolfe</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">28:</TIMEX>

            

               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pleasantville</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- Apt
Pupil ;

            

               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Soldier</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX> of the
World: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Rise</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Muhammad Ali</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Remnick</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Evening</ENAMEX> ,
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Minot</ENAMEX>;

            

               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bech</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bay</ENAMEX>: A <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Quasi-Novel</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Updike</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">21:</TIMEX>

            

               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Beloved</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bride</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chucky</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Practical</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Magic</ENAMEX> ;

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> -- Corpus
Christi , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Terrence McNally</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Manhattan Theatre Club</ENAMEX>);

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Music -- Live:</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1966</TIMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dylan</ENAMEX>;

            

               Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- The Poisonwood Bible</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara Kingsolver</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">14:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Man</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- The
Mighty ;

            

               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Slam</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- A <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Night</ENAMEX> at
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roxbury</ENAMEX> ;

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dance -- Swan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Lake</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neil Simon Theatre</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>);

            
               Book -- Work in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Progress</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Eisner</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Schwartz</ENAMEX>;

            

               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pure Drivel</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Martin</ENAMEX>.

            
               --Eliza Truitt
            

         
      
   
