
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Address your e-mail to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. You must include your address and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX>
phone number (for confirmation only).
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slate Gets Booted</ENAMEX>
            

            Oh, how the mighty have
fallen. 
                  Slate
               , formerly the new bastion of journalistic
integrity, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">watchdog</ENAMEX> of all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>, has blown it. Or at least <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Weisberg</ENAMEX>
has in "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Positively</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Fourth</NUMEX>-Rate." First, let me say that I very much agree that most of the
time snobbish aficionados trumpeting the obscure B-side, bootleg, or rare
import are nothing but annoying. However, when it comes to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dylan</ENAMEX>, I begin
to suspect that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weisberg</ENAMEX> is not much of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> or a fact checker. First, Greil
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marcus</ENAMEX> does get rather obsessive, but the song "I'm Not There" is readily
available on the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">illegal Basement Tapes bootlegs</ENAMEX>." I personally own it on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
different collections, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> volume collection of all known <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Basement Tapes</ENAMEX>
recordings titled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Genuine Basement Tapes</ENAMEX> (the history of which is
detailed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton Heylin</ENAMEX> in his book <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bootleg</ENAMEX> ) as well as a bootleg
greatest hits collection called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Genuine Bootleg Series, Take 2</ENAMEX> . I
live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kansas</ENAMEX>, the middle of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Midwest</ENAMEX>, and these CDs were easy to find in
local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX>. Anyone with Internet access or living in a larger metropolitan
area should be able to hunt down "I'm Not There" in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">less than an hour</TIMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, I personally
disagree with the given assessment of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1966</TIMEX> concert; I love the whole thing
and, having heard many a live Dylan tape, consider it one of the better live
concerts out there, and certainly one of the best-sounding recordings from the
'60s. The bootleg recording is not like the standard pop album; it is by nature
released mainly for the die-hard <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">collector</ENAMEX>, and while there is a great
deal of dross to sort through, there are a lot of wonderful moments if you take
the time to find them.

            
Furthermore (and what you should be writing about), the bootleg industry is
currently undergoing a revolution in production, thanks to the introduction of
CD-ROM technology, which effectively means that anything ever bootlegged is
readily available. While CD-ROMs with color copies for inserts lose a great
deal of the artifact value boots used to have, the resulting availability is
ample compensation, especially since it has forced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producers</ENAMEX> of traditional,
higher-fidelity aluminum CDs to increase their standards, with better liner
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">notes</ENAMEX>, more photos, and higher quality packages. Bootlegs preserve music that
otherwise would have been lost forever and allow music <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX>, as opposed to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> of pop music, access to a much fuller canon of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">musicians</ENAMEX>' work.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neil</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dryden Lawrence</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kan.</ENAMEX>

            
               Political
Uses of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dead White Woman</ENAMEX>?
            

            Your
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Frame Game</ENAMEX>" title "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">St.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew</ENAMEX>: The political use of a gay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s gruesome death"
strikes me as harsh and callous. While the content of the article on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shepard</ENAMEX>'s murder is thoughtful if analytical in tone, the heading seems to
support the idea of a gay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> as a symbol, but not as an equal. Would you
ever have written "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Political Uses of a Dead White Woman"</ENAMEX>?

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patrick Meade</ENAMEX> New
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">York City</ENAMEX>

            
               Yes,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health Care</ENAMEX> Is Unfair
            

            Thank you for "Sickbed
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Populism</ENAMEX>," your well-balanced article on health maintenance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>.
You are on target with your suggestion. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> should counter with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">logical</ENAMEX>, informative statements that point out the costs involved in
litigation. Sadly, the average <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen</ENAMEX> doesn't seem to understand that
financial settlements are not manna from heaven.

            My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> works in health
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">care</ENAMEX>, and we often discuss related issues. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the major problems HMOs are
facing is inadequate Medicare reimbursement. Someone has to absorb the loss.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">provider</ENAMEX>? I don't think so. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX>? Not politically correct. As a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">society</ENAMEX> we may have to face facts.

            Maybe we
shouldn't save every premature baby regardless of the cost. Maybe we shouldn't
attempt to extend the life of every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX>. We want it all and want it to
be free. Life isn't fair ... never has been. You can bet no one will ever elect
me to public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>. I'm way too truthful.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret T.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richman Metamora</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ill.</ENAMEX>

            
               Nothing
but <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Talk Is Cheap</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sickbed Populism": So HMO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> shouldn't complain because they are getting
"cheap" medical care. Well, I belong to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kaiser Permanente Senior Care</ENAMEX>, for
which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> sends <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kaiser</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$390</NUMEX> (!) per month to care for me. Does <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Plotz</ENAMEX> think that is "cheap"? And the care I have received is not "managed"
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">care</ENAMEX>, but mismanaged care. As soon as I can, I will be changing to some
other plan, which means I will probably have to go back to work to pay for
it.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dee</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Townsend Annandale</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Va.</ENAMEX>

            
               Address
your e-mail to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. You must include your address and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX>
phone number (for confirmation only).
            

         
      
   
