
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Triumph of</ENAMEX>

            As <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> eagerly tout
their break-even performance in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>, and gubernatorial races as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">grand</ENAMEX> triumph, and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">as</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> spin the same numbers into an affirmation of
the conservative status quo, both sides are overlooking the election's most
astonishing results: the ballot initiatives.

            Initiatives have made news
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX> by advancing conservative causes: limits on gay rights,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">immigration</ENAMEX>, and affirmative action. And there were certainly some initiatives
to delight the right <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>, too. Voter initiatives approved in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alaska</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX> banned gay marriage. An initiative in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michigan</ENAMEX> upheld a ban on assisted
suicide. Initiatives in the deep South further restricted the rights of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">prisoners</ENAMEX> (who knew there were any restrictions left to impose?). An Alaska
measure made <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s official language. And a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> initiative
modeled on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Proposition 209</ENAMEX> abolished state affirmative action
programs.

            But the
overriding theme of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> initiatives is not conservative at all. It is that
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>, at least in this complacent year, are a lot more liberal than
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pollsters</ENAMEX> would have you believe.

            Initiatives rewarded both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lefty libertarians</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">paleoliberals</ENAMEX>. On the libertarian front, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alaska</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nevada</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oregon</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX>--put medical marijuana on the ballot, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>
approved (or in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX>'s case, re-approved) it. That means the entire Western
flank of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> now permits marijuana as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oregon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> also
killed an initiative to re-criminalize marijuana possession. Initiatives in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Missouri</ENAMEX> expanded legalized gambling, a libertarian cause
increasingly embraced by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>. And both <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> rejected
bans on partial birth abortion.

            (The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Colorado</ENAMEX> abortion vote is a powerful argument against those who say that
initiatives are dangerous because they are too crude and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> are too easily
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">conned</ENAMEX>. At the same time <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coloradans</ENAMEX> refused to ban partial birth abortion, they
also voted to require parental notification for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> seeking
abortion. The split vote on abortion suggests a subtlety among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> of initiatives rarely acknowledge.)

            
The initiatives also expressed a surprisingly
strong faith in government and a willingness to expand it. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Voters</ENAMEX> gave a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">full-throated</ENAMEX> endorsement to public education. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Californians</ENAMEX> approved a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$9</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">billion school</ENAMEX> bond issue, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rhode Islanders</ENAMEX> OKed a (much) smaller <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coloradans</ENAMEX> rejected a proposal to give tax credits for private school tuition,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South Dakotans</ENAMEX> rebuffed an effort to stop financing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> with property
taxes.

            <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Five</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maine</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michigan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX>--endorsed
ballot initiatives to expand state environmental funding and, in all but
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arizona</ENAMEX>, by huge margins. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South Dakotans</ENAMEX> voted to restrict corporate hog
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">farming</ENAMEX>, as well. Only in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oregon</ENAMEX>, where a massively broad ban on logging was
proposed, did an environmental initiative fail. On animal rights, too, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>
cast ballots for more government regulation, choosing to ban cockfighting in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arizona</ENAMEX>, animal baiting in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Missouri</ENAMEX>, and animal traps and horsemeat sales in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alaska</ENAMEX> did reject a ban of wolf traps, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Ohioans</ENAMEX> voted to
continue the hunting of mourning doves.)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washingtonians</ENAMEX> voted to raise the minimum wage. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Floridians</ENAMEX>
imposed a new waiting period for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> purchases. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arizona</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX> both
passed campaign finance reforms allowing public funding of state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nebraska</ENAMEX>--conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nebraska</ENAMEX>--turned down an effort to impose mandatory
restraints on state spending. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> gender neutralized its constitution (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hampshire</ENAMEX> did not), and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Florida</ENAMEX> passed an equal rights initiative. And, in the
"it may not sound like progress but it is" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX>
overturned <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a 102-year-old</TIMEX> law limiting the property rights of married <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">South Carolinians</ENAMEX> struck the miscegenation ban from the state
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">constitution</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>
afflicted with a foolish optimism may view these initiative victories as a sign
of an impending liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">majority</ENAMEX>. I suspect they represent something else: the
generosity of the prosperous. According to exit polls, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> feel
happy and rich. These votes reflect a generous, expansive mood. Sick people
want to smoke a joint? Let 'em, what harm does it do? More money for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>?
Sure! <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clean</ENAMEX> water? You bet! These are not liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activist</ENAMEX> votes, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cast</ENAMEX> because
the initiatives advance a progressive agenda. They seem to be smile-on-the-face
votes, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cast</ENAMEX> because the initiatives are modest and well-intentioned and, at
worst, harmless.

            
               Weather
Update
            

            On
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> and
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, in homage to the "turnout is everything" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX>, I predicted the
outcome of tight races based on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> weather map. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> is
judgment day. How accurate was the weather forecast election forecast?

            
               New
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">York</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Prediction: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dry</ENAMEX>
weather increases <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">turnout</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chuck Schumer</ENAMEX> wins.

            
               Result: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dry</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">weather</ENAMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schumer</ENAMEX> won.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maryland</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Prediction: If it
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rains</ENAMEX>, devoted <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> vote and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellen Sauerbrey</ENAMEX> unseats <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parris</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Glendening</ENAMEX>.

            
               Result : It rained,
but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glendening</ENAMEX> won easily.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">North</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carolina</ENAMEX>
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Prediction: Rain</ENAMEX>
should suppress <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">turnout</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lauch Faircloth</ENAMEX> wins
re-election.

            
               Result: It rained,
but <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Edwards</ENAMEX> defeated <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Faircloth</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carolina</ENAMEX>
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Prediction: Rain</ENAMEX>
should suppress <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">turnout</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Beasley</ENAMEX> should win
re-election, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Inglis</ENAMEX> should defeat incumbent
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fritz Hollings</ENAMEX>.

            
               Result: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fog</ENAMEX> and rain
across the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hollings</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> gubernatorial challenger <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hodges</ENAMEX> won.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Georgia</ENAMEX>
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Prediction: Showers</ENAMEX>
across the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> might deter <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>, but if it stops raining in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX> that
could be good news for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> gubernatorial candidate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roy Barnes</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Coles</ENAMEX>.

            
               Result: Scattered
showers across the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> but mostly decent weather. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barnes</ENAMEX> won the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">governorship</ENAMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coles</ENAMEX> lost to incumbent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Coverdell</ENAMEX>.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kentucky</ENAMEX>
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Prediction: Rain</ENAMEX>
throughout the state helps <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Bunning</ENAMEX> win the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> seat.

            
               Result: It rained, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bunning</ENAMEX> won narrowly.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nevada</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Prediction: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dry</ENAMEX>,
pleasant weather helps <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">incumbent Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Reid</ENAMEX>.

            
               Result: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dry</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">weather</ENAMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reid</ENAMEX> eked out a victory.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Prediction: Generally
good weather helps <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara Boxer</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gray Davis</ENAMEX>. If it rains in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern California</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Fong</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Lungren</ENAMEX> could win
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">upsets</ENAMEX>.

            
               Result: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Good</ENAMEX> weather
held, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Boxer</ENAMEX> kept her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> seat, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX> won the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX>'s race.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Prediction: If it
doesn't rain in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> turn out for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patty Murray</ENAMEX> and she holds
her seat.

            
               Result: It didn't
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rain</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX> fended off challenger <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Smith</ENAMEX>.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wisconsin</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Prediction: <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold</ENAMEX> but
dry weather boosts <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russ Feingold</ENAMEX>

            
               Result: No <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rain</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Feingold</ENAMEX> defended his seat.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Prediction: If it
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rains downstate</ENAMEX> but is clear in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carol Moseley</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Braun</ENAMEX> might steal a
come-from-behind win.

            

               Result: It rained downstate but not in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>. Even so, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moseley-Braun</ENAMEX>
lost.

            
               Overall
Result for the Mother Nature Index: <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">54 percent</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX> out of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">races</ENAMEX> picked
correctly), which is not much worse than the average election prognosticator
and a lot better than the average weather forecaster.

         
      
   
