
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">145</NUMEX>:

            By <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cohen</ENAMEX>

            
               I give
the headline, you give the story. From <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">London Evening</ENAMEX>
Standard : "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Blow to Singer With No Sideways</ENAMEX>"
            

            by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 p.m. ET</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> to e-mail your answer to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.

            
               Responses
to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s question (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 144</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Best Dais of Your Life":</ENAMEX>
            

            
               A major <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">corporation</ENAMEX> will spend <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$200 million</NUMEX> to install
customer-friendly equipment, including small, mobile, battery-powered <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">podiums</ENAMEX>.
What are the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">podiums</ENAMEX> for?
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX> will deliver
author readings directly to your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>, rendering <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bookstores</ENAMEX> yet more obsolete.
Most of the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$200 million</NUMEX> is being spent not on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">podiums</ENAMEX> themselves but
rather on the small, mobile, battery-powered <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Malachy McCourts</ENAMEX> who
will stand behind them."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Radosh</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney World</ENAMEX>'s new
'presidential debates' bumper <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew Singer</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">James</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Urbaniak</ENAMEX> had a similar answer referencing poetry at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barnes</ENAMEX> &
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Noble</ENAMEX>.)

            "Who cares? It's an
Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>. BUY!"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doug Ingram</ENAMEX> (similarly, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellen</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scordato</ENAMEX> )

            "If you're saying they're
not urinals, I'm really embarrassed."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Miller</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mice</ENAMEX>. It's the cutest
darn thing you've ever seen."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Carvell</ENAMEX> (similarly, with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ross</ENAMEX> Perot
chaser, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carl Spratt</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russ Evansen</ENAMEX> )

            Click for more
responses.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
            

            Small,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mobile</ENAMEX>, battery-powered--is there anything more modern than that? Is there
anything cuter than that? Is there anything more redolent of vulgar erotic
possibilities? If "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">News Quiz</ENAMEX>" were not a quiz but rather a pornographic
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> comic book, dense with misogyny and conveniently available in
omnipresent vending machines on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">platforms</ENAMEX> of swift, efficient commuter
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">railways</ENAMEX>, those would be the attributes of the sexed-up superhero whose
adventures we chronicled, even if it made many of our fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> really
uncomfortable. But here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, to be creeped out by unwanted mass transit
eroticism shoved at you from every direction, you must make do with loudmouthed
cell phone sex on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Long Island Railroad</ENAMEX>. I'm no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economist</ENAMEX>, but I believe
this is the point <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> intends to make in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tokyo</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX>.

            
               On-Time
Answer
            

            As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alfa-Betty Olsen</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marshall Efron</ENAMEX> know (click ), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Airlines</ENAMEX> will be rolling out porta-podia
when there are long lines at check-in counters.

            This space
age table with a radio link to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airline</ENAMEX>'s database is currently being
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">field</ENAMEX>-tested in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX> and will soon be deployed at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAX</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">O'Hare</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La</ENAMEX>
Guardia <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airports</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Armey</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Metaphor Madness Extra</ENAMEX>
            

            Read this allegorical passage
by the newly re-elected <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">majority leader</ENAMEX>, then answer the questions
below.

            "Think
about the poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bass</ENAMEX>; put yourself in his place. You go into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Denny's</ENAMEX> and you sit
down and somebody puts your hamburger in front of you, and you pick it up and
take a bite. All of a sudden, somebody grabs you by the mouth, drags you around
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX>, drags you outside, pulls the hook out of your mouth, and throws you
back into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Denny's</ENAMEX>. That is what the poor <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> goes through."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. What does <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Denny</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">symbolize</ENAMEX>?

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. What does the fish
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">symbolize</ENAMEX>?

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. Where is "out back"?

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. What is the hamburger?

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. What is the hook?

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. What's the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> doing at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Denny</ENAMEX>'s?

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>. Suppose the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> were
really rich, should it pay the same income tax as a poor <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX>, maybe like a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shad</ENAMEX> who works at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Denny's</ENAMEX>?

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">champion</ENAMEX> of family
values, how many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> does the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> have from previous marriages?

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>. How does the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> know
when something is wrong?

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX>. What
do some other <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> think of this <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX>?

            

               Answers
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. A lake, and also the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House of Representatives</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. An incumbent majority
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. A riverbank where it looks
like you won't get re-elected?

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. I'm a little hazy here.
Opposition to gun control, maybe?

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. Look, I don't know. Quit
badgering me.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. Having lunch, I guess, but
maybe they were all out of worms or something? Do they eat <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">worms</ENAMEX>?

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>. Yes. Both should pay <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17</NUMEX>
percent.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Five</NUMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>. "When the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ten</ENAMEX> Commandments
can't be placed in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courtrooms</ENAMEX> (even though a relief of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moses</ENAMEX> adorns the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">chamber</ENAMEX>), and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">schoolchildren</ENAMEX> are harassed by school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> for privately
practicing their faith, something is wrong."

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX>. "It
was time to get rid of him," said a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> who did not want to be identified,
"but in the end the moderates just couldn't go with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Largent</ENAMEX>. It was more like
going with the old devil we know."

            
               Funniness
Enhancer
            

            Reread the
passage, only this time pronounce "bass" with a long a, and picture opera great
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Samuel Ramey</ENAMEX>.

            
               Read More
About It
            

            At the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX>'s Web site,
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">http://</ENAMEX>freedom.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">house.</ENAMEX>gov.

            And if you check, you'll
probably find a lot of bass fishing sites.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Disclaimer</ENAMEX>: All submissions will become the property of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> and
will be published at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> 's discretion. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> may publish your
name on its site in connection with your submission.
            

         
      
   
