
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hussein Faces the End</ENAMEX>

            With <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> papers all
from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wye Plantation</ENAMEX> talks and the desperate <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> efforts to keep them
going, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> reported from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jordan</ENAMEX> has "no more
than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three months</TIMEX> to live." Quoting "a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jordanian</ENAMEX> medical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX>," the paper
said that the king, who has been receiving treatment for lymphatic <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> at
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mayo Clinic</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota</ENAMEX> and has become involved in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli-Palestinian</ENAMEX>
negotiations, might return to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jordan</ENAMEX> earlier than scheduled (he is due back
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 28</TIMEX>) because "he wants to be in his beloved <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in
his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last days</TIMEX>." It added that this prognosis about the king's health had
reached both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> intelligence services.

            Quoting
the newsletter <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foreign Report</ENAMEX> , due to be published <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jerusalem Post</ENAMEX> said that "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein</ENAMEX>" was the main topic of
discussion between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Tenet</ENAMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tenet</ENAMEX> visited
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>. It said there is anxiety in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jordan</ENAMEX> at the prospect of the
king being succeeded by his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crown</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prince</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hassan</ENAMEX>, who is regarded as
"snobbish and loquacious by his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>, who say his sentences are often so
long that by the time they end, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">listener</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> has forgotten how they
started."

            In an editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jerusalem Post</ENAMEX> called
for the adoption of the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Birthright</ENAMEX>" initiative, proposed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Knesset</ENAMEX> member
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yossi Beilin</ENAMEX>, under which every <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> would, on turning
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17</TIMEX>, be given an all-expenses-paid, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three-week</TIMEX> trip to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>. This is because,
"[o]ver <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past 50 years</TIMEX>, identification with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> has been a major
component of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> identity in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Diaspora</ENAMEX> in general, and in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North America</ENAMEX>
in particular. ... <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Restoring Israel</ENAMEX>'s place in the collective <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jewish</ENAMEX>
consciousness should be a top priority of every [<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX>] <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">federation</ENAMEX> on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">North American</ENAMEX> continent."

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Le Monde</ENAMEX> ran an
editorial about the treason trial in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Petersburg</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>, of former
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">submarine Capt.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander Nikitin</ENAMEX> for passing information to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Norway</ENAMEX> about
nuclear radiation levels in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Arctic</ENAMEX> region. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> described
the trial as worthy of "the good old <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> times" and said that, because of
it, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> should be suspended from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council of Europe</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">democratic European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> to which it was admitted in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>. It said the case
recalls "the most sinister practices of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX>" because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nikitin</ENAMEX> has
suffered intimidation, police harassment, and many other abuses instead of
being decorated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> state for sounding the alarm about dangerous
radiation levels. "His fate ought to disturb all the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capitals</ENAMEX> of the West."

            
The nomination of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">55</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th</ENAMEX>
post-fascist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, headed for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time by an ex-Communist, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Massimo</ENAMEX>
d<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">'Alema</ENAMEX>, led several <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, with great emphasis on the
fact that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX> new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ministers</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>. In a front-page
editorial, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Stampa</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Turin</ENAMEX> described it as a well-balanced government born to last, "a clever mix of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">old</ENAMEX> and new," but added that the political compromises it embodies will slow
down decision-making and might "prolong to infinity the already interminable
period of Italian transition."

            In
another front-page editorial, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Stampa</ENAMEX> criticized the new German
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chancellor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerhard Schröder</ENAMEX> for canceling the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 8</TIMEX> commemoration in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World War I.</ENAMEX> The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said it is understandable that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schröder</ENAMEX>'s generation
should want to lift from itself blame that doesn't belong to it. But it added
that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> remains exposed to "the perpetual and human temptation of
nationalism" and has a duty to join in the commemoration.

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> led its front page with a call by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret Thatcher</ENAMEX>
for the immediate release of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Augusto Pinochet</ENAMEX>, who is under arrest in a
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clinic</ENAMEX>. In a letter to the paper from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, where she is on
a lecture tour, the former <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pinochet</ENAMEX> helped shorten
the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">1982 Falklands War</ENAMEX> by supporting <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> and saved many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> lives as a
result. In an editorial, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> supported her stance.

            Following the blocking by the
religious right of the appointment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Hormel</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Luxembourg</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> openly gay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ambassador</ENAMEX>, the liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian of London</ENAMEX> surveyed a group of foreign countries
to establish their attitudes toward gay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">diplomats</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish</ENAMEX>
government said, "We don't inquire"; <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">diplomats</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Netherlands</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sweden</ENAMEX>,
which recognize same-sex <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partnerships</ENAMEX> as equal to marriages, said discretion is
used when posting gay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> to sexually conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>; and a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Swedish embassy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> said the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> has "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two or three</NUMEX>" gay ambassadors
abroad.

            But a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Zimbabwean</ENAMEX> spokesman
pointed out that in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Zimbabwe</ENAMEX>, "sodomy is an offence." He noted, "If the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ambassador</ENAMEX> has been appointed, if we have any information that he is gay, we
can't discriminate against him. But once he starts practising, he has committed
an offence."

         
      
   
