
   
   
      
         
            A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hundred Years of Lassitude</ENAMEX>

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1963</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edmund Wilson</ENAMEX>
published an "interview" with himself in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> issue of the New York
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Review of Books</ENAMEX> . The subject was why a new intellectual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journal</ENAMEX> was needed
and how it came to be. "The disappearance of the Times <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> book
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">section</ENAMEX> at the time of the printers' strike only make us realize it had never
existed," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilson</ENAMEX> explained.

            I'm not
sure what it means that this remark is quoted without comment in the new
anthology that commemorates 100 years of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Book Review</ENAMEX> .
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilson</ENAMEX> was saying the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> book section was relentlessly dull. Does the
Times agree? The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">650</NUMEX> page greatest-hits collection, I'm afraid, supports
the criticism. For all the effect it has had on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s literature, the
Times <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> book section might as well never have existed. Today, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilson</ENAMEX>'s jibe, it remains the drab wallpaper of the book world. If
it vanished in another strike, it is hard to think many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would miss
it.

            Why is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYTBR</ENAMEX> so dreary? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Wolff</ENAMEX>, the media
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> , wrote an article <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few weeks ago</TIMEX>
complaining that the section fails to capitalize on the new commercial
environment in which books are marketed and sold. He thinks the NYTBR
could make more money by being less independent. I kept waiting for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wolff</ENAMEX> to
say he was joking, but apparently he wasn't. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> deserves to be
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">congratulated</ENAMEX>, not scolded, for its determination to avoid pandering to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">trade</ENAMEX> by reviewing self-help manuals or boosting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oprah</ENAMEX>'s book <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX>.

            But
high-mindedness only gets you so far. The real problem with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYTBR</ENAMEX> ,
for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 15 years</TIMEX> or so that I have been reading it without much pleasure, is
its aversion to argument and controversy. Pick up just about any issue and what
you'll find is a kind of literary balm--a quietly reverential attitude toward
books in general, combined with a disinclination to ruffle feathers. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Charles</ENAMEX>
"Chip" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McGrath</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>, has elevated the tone somewhat. More
distinguished <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> contribute longer reviews about weightier books. But
somehow, the section still feels dutiful. It reads as if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> writing for
it and editing it aren't having any fun and don't think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> should
either.

            
Magazine <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> generally try to make articles
as interesting as possible and to make them look even more interesting than
they are. At the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYTBR</ENAMEX> , the principle seems to be reversed: Avoid
anything too interesting and, if you happen to get it anyhow, disguise it. On
the cover, where the widely read "lead" review once began, there is now a
reliably hideous full-page color illustration accompanied by a generic
headline. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Artist</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Adventure</ENAMEX>," says the cover of the issue that comes out on
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>. This is the billing for a new biography of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.C. Wyeth</ENAMEX>, the illustrator
whose family saga is a tasty, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gothic</ENAMEX> tale--something of which you get no hint
unless you read all the way through the "jump." The review is by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam Gopnik</ENAMEX>,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the funniest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> around. But somehow, it feels as if his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">talent</ENAMEX> is
being withheld. You read the review and wish the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> felt he could cut
loose.

            The rest
of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">75</NUMEX> page section contains a mix of strong <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> being stifled (or
perhaps pre-emptively stifling themselves) and weak ones being given too much
space to say too little. This issue contains <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21 regular</NUMEX> reviews, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30</TIMEX> reviews of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s books in a special section, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> brief reviews, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> more paperback
reviews, and a roundup of new science fiction titles. Covering <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">70</NUMEX> plus books in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> (the usual number is more like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">40 to 50</TIMEX>) pleases the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYTBR</ENAMEX> 's
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">advertisers</ENAMEX> in the publishing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> by providing much fertile territory for
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">blurb</ENAMEX> mining. But the rest of us are drowning. Inside the back page, there's
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> article that's not a review, the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bookend</ENAMEX>." <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This week</TIMEX>'s column is by Meghan
Daum, a free-lance <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> who says she can't figure out a topic to write a book
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX>, staggering across the finish line, can only pray that she
doesn't.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> who write for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYTBR</ENAMEX> all have stories
about how the section resists strong criticism and colorful writing. The
problem starts with the bias in favor of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">specialists</ENAMEX>. An <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assistant professor</ENAMEX> of
philosophy given a new biography of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Hume</ENAMEX> is likely to assume an interest
in the subject and focus on the significance of the book to his field. A good
intellectual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> given the same assignment would probably focus more on
the question of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hume</ENAMEX>'s relevance <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> and whether the book is interesting to a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nonphilosopher</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McGrath</ENAMEX> seems to have tipped the balance a bit in the direction
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX>. But since good manners are the rule, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generalists</ENAMEX> often end
up sounding as obtuse as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX>. In the current issue, for instance, a
review of a book about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wal-Mart</ENAMEX> says the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> can't make up his mind about
whether <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wal-Mart</ENAMEX> is good or bad. But the reviewer can't make up her mind either
and passes up the opportunity to say something--anything--about a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that
has transformed <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> culture. The result is waffling squared.

            The tried
and true formula for an <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">800</ENAMEX> word review is to meander on the general topic for
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> paragraphs, summarize the book in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> more, note a flaw in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">penultimate</ENAMEX> paragraph, and close with an upbeat summation on the order of
"Still, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moon</ENAMEX> Over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nova Scotia</ENAMEX> is a valuable contribution to our
understanding of the shifting fortunes of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Atlantic</ENAMEX> eel fishing industry."
The new anthology includes a review of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mein Kampf</ENAMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1933</TIMEX> that follows
this form. It spends <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> paragraphs pondering <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> history, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> describing
the intelligent Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>'s book, and ends with a complaint about his dislike
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>, which the reviewer regards as a flaw in an otherwise impressive
list of accomplishments. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> for a sample of this wacko analysis.)

            
Excessive negativity has evidently always been
discouraged. Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX> have figured out that raves are often played big.
But if the reviewer trashes a book, especially one that is in any way marginal,
the odds diminish that his review will be published. If it does run, it will
probably be in the back, near the ads for electric toothbrushes and the Itty
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bitty Book Light</ENAMEX>. Moreover, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> are likely to blunt the criticism in a
backhanded way. They may, for instance, as I heard from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contributor</ENAMEX>,
apologize for having to cut a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">reviewer</ENAMEX>'s most clever lines "for space." How
much easier, then, to be agreeable.

            Why would
a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> section avoid conflict, the mother's <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk</ENAMEX> of journalism? I think
the instinct stems from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s not unrealistic sense of its own power and
responsibility. Though the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYTBR</ENAMEX> can't hurt <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Clancy</ENAMEX> and probably
can't help most academic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">specialists</ENAMEX>, for a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between</TIMEX>, not
getting reviewed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> or receiving a harsh review can nail the
coffin shut. Other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX> can be cavalier without worrying about
squashing an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>'s budding career. The giant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> can't.

            So the review has grown a large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bureaucracy</ENAMEX> designed to
prevent any unfairness. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Half a dozen</NUMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Preview</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> leaf through the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of books published <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each week</TIMEX> to choose the lucky few that are worth
reviewing, relegating some to the "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Books</ENAMEX> in Brief" section in the back. They
then look for someone qualified to write on the subject, but without any bias.
No one who is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleague</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rival</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> is supposed to
get an assignment. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pre-McGrath</ENAMEX>, it was even forbidden to review a book
published by one's own publishing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>. This near cult of fairness prevents
conflicts, but it also prevents interest. And the bureaucratic approach
prevents the section as a whole from taking positions on--or creating--literary
issues. Are biographies too long? Does women's fiction get short shrift? Is
academic literary criticism headed down a blind <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alley</ENAMEX>? The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYTBR</ENAMEX> isn't
just agnostic on such questions--it doesn't even like to consider them.

            It's instructive to contrast
this with the approach of the leading <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> papers. The book review sections
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunday Times</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunday Telegraph</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Observer</ENAMEX> , as
well as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times Literary Supplement</ENAMEX> and the delightful <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">London</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Review of Books</ENAMEX> , look to conflicts to generate interest. The famous letter
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> --"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sirs</ENAMEX>, of all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who might have reviewed my book,
could you not find one who was not my former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>?"--may be apocryphal. But it
gets at the spirit of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> reviewing, which is that the sometimes petty
clash of literary opinion is good sport. Regular <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX>, on the model
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cyril Connolly</ENAMEX>, the longtime <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunday Times</ENAMEX> , become
trusted guides. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> book reviews are more like publications
revolving around literary life than mere reviews. They contain diaries, poems,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">puzzles</ENAMEX>, and interviews. The best book review section in an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> paper at
the moment--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times Book Review</ENAMEX> --is much closer to this
variety model.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYTBR</ENAMEX> could make
itself more interesting by going halfway <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX>. My suggestion would be to
drop the rules against conflicts of interest in favor of a simple one that says
material biases should be disclosed. Hire a regular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> to write every
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>. (The prodigious <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Wood</ENAMEX>, the most gifted literary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> of his
generation, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">springs</TIMEX> to mind.) Lose the dismal cover illustrations and return to
having a lead review or cover essay. Break the monotony of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX> sequential
reviews with full-length <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> interviews (which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> used to
have), letters from abroad, debates, and a gossip column. Encourage a feisty
letters page. Blow off the brief reviews. Take chances. Crusade. Quit being so
damned responsible.

         
      
   
