
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gays</ENAMEX>

            
               If you missed the most
recent installments of this column, here they are: posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, Nov.</TIMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Nov. 3</TIMEX>.
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>'s biggest
circulation <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rupert Murdoch</ENAMEX>'s tabloid the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX> , asked on its
front page <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, "Are we being run by a gay <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mafia</ENAMEX>?" This was a comment on the
fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blair</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX> member <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX> until lately contained <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> known
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homosexuals</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of them, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Culture</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Smith</ENAMEX>, has been openly gay
for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many years</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Welsh</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Davies</ENAMEX> recently had to resign after an
encounter in a well-known gay haunt in south <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>, which led to him being
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mugged</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trade and Industry</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Mandelson</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair</ENAMEX>'s
election victory <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>, was "outed" <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> on television, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agriculture</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nick Brown</ENAMEX> outed himself on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX> after a former
gay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lover</ENAMEX> tried to sell the story of their relationship to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunday</ENAMEX>
paper, the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">News of the World</ENAMEX> .

            In its front-page editorial,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX> , which used to have a homophobic reputation, claimed that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX> affair had "set alarm bells ringing"--"[n]ot because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> despise <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gays</ENAMEX>,
or fear them, or wish to pillory them," but because "the public has a right to
know how many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homosexuals</ENAMEX> occupy positions of high power." It went on, "Their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sexuality</ENAMEX> is not the problem. ... The worry is their membership of a closed
world of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> with a mutual self-interest ... there are widespread fears that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Members</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parliament</ENAMEX>, even <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ministers</ENAMEX>, are beholden to others for reasons other
than politics."

            The paper
also announced a "hotline" for gay <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MPs</ENAMEX> to phone. "Do you want to come out?" it
asked:

            Are you a gay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">MP</ENAMEX> who'd
like to come out? The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX> has set up a hotline on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">0171 782 4105</TIMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ministers</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MPs</ENAMEX> who are secretly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homosexual</ENAMEX>. Don't worry about the cost, we'll ring you
back.

            I called
several times, but the line was always busy.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX>'s upscale <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX>, welcomed what it saw
as a new public tolerance in the generally favorable response to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX>'s
admission of his homosexuality and said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> that "the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> appear to be
lagging behind the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">electorate</ENAMEX> whose mores reflect a more forgiving view of what
they expect of their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MPs</ENAMEX>. ... <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> politics appear to be undergoing a
similar transformation." "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX>'s elections suggest that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>
either did not care about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s private life, or saw it as
irrelevant to their political choices."

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">liberal Guardian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">accused Murdoch</ENAMEX> of playing a double game by allowing one of his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tabloids</ENAMEX> effectively to "out" a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX> and another to announce "that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">homosexuality</ENAMEX> is a state of being so unremarkable that it is astonishing that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> still think it worthy of comment." Asking how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX> would justify the
News of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World</ENAMEX> 's outing of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX> said in an
editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>: "It is, of course, a futile question. Mr
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX> lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> and can never be held accountable for the effects his
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> papers have on our culture. He cosies up to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> he
thinks might be useful to the promotion of his business interests. He berates
them or threatens to withdraw his affections when they do not jump with
sufficient alacrity to his orders." Of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair</ENAMEX>, who has enjoyed close relations
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said, "With every passing day he has a clearer idea of
Mr <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX> and his true nature. He should sup with a long spoon."

            
In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>, the liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ha'aretz</ENAMEX> led its front
page <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> with a report that political pressure at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX> level was
preventing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> from taking action against <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least five</NUMEX> new hilltop
outposts that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">settlers</ENAMEX> have built in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Bank</ENAMEX> since the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wye</ENAMEX> agreement was
signed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks ago</TIMEX>. "Other than confiscating a single <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">tractor</ENAMEX> last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>--returned to its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> has taken no action to stop the
construction," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ha'aretz</ENAMEX> urged the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX>
government to ratify the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wye</ENAMEX> agreement soon, despite the renewal of suicide
attacks against <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israelis</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX>. It said in an editorial, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A</ENAMEX>
diplomatic policy of vengeance--a vicious circle of terrorism and
settlement--would not only disrupt implementation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Wye accord</ENAMEX>, it would
also steer <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli-Palestinian</ENAMEX> relations away from the path of accord, perhaps
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">irrevocably</ENAMEX>."

            In the conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jerusalem Post</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> Efraim
Inbar of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bar-Ilan University</ENAMEX> said in an op-ed
piece <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israelis</ENAMEX> were now more interested in their personal
security than in the security of their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. "The new notion of personal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">security</ENAMEX> has eclipsed the traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> preoccupation with assuring the
security of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> and its society in the midst of a hostile
environment," he wrote. But he warned against this tendency, saying that
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> society's "unwillingness to sacrifice some of its standard of living to
acquire better defenses against less <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">concrete</ENAMEX> and immediate threats could be
destructive."

         
      
   
