
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Address your e-mail to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. You must include your address and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX>
phone number (for confirmation only).
            

            
               Not All
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Jewish Women Are Like Lewinsky</ENAMEX>
            

            The last
paragraph of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 9</TIMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" struck a discordant note with us. After cataloging
pejoratives associated with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, which a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> is trying to counter in
the media, the paragraph asserts that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> fits them all. This
implies, unfairly and falsely, that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> is somehow representative of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>. That implication is snide and condescending. Surely you wouldn't
be so flippant with a list of pejoratives associated with another minority
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanics</ENAMEX>, for instance--or pretend that one negatively
perceived <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> stands for the whole. The "joke" was anti-Semitic
and unfunny. It is particularly annoying to read this on the anniversary of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kristallnacht</ENAMEX> .

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maud Lavin</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Locke Bowman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott Shuger</ENAMEX> responds:
I did not create the list of pejoratives thought to be associated in the public
mind with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>; the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> did. I also wrote that
eradicating that stereotype was a fine goal. I did not write that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>. I wrote that she fit the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>'s
list and that, given the tremendous exposure she's had <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>, this
certainly reinforces the stereotype and therefore makes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>'s aim more
difficult to achieve. To pretend that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX> is not a problem for the image of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> is like pretending that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.J. Simpson</ENAMEX> is not a problem for the
image of black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>. To notice such things is not bigotry. But wanting to ignore
them is.
            

            
               Holes in
the DNA
            

            Your <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 2</TIMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>" on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jefferson</ENAMEX> and the DNA tests is erroneous. The DNA
tests only prove that a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jefferson</ENAMEX> was the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sally Hemings</ENAMEX>' last
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>. But that could include any of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jefferson</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">male cousins</ENAMEX>--the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX> of
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>. The more important finding is that the DNA tests prove
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jefferson</ENAMEX>--or any other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jefferson</ENAMEX>--could not be the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hemings</ENAMEX>'
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>, the one who was born after she returned from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thomas</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jefferson</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, pregnant at the time.

            Historically, the Hemings
family always claimed that this <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> was fathered by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jefferson</ENAMEX>. The
interesting question now is who was the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> of her first <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>, since he could
not have been a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jefferson</ENAMEX>. And since we can't trace the paternity of her other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> because there are no male <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">descendants</ENAMEX>, the likelihood that the
paternity was from other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> is as likely as any other possible answer, now
that we know that she had her <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> by a non-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jefferson</ENAMEX> family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">i.e.</ENAMEX>, that she had <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least two</NUMEX> different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> from different
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>.

            Finally,
the largest obstacle in proving that it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Jefferson</ENAMEX> who was the father
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hemings</ENAMEX>' last <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> is the fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jefferson</ENAMEX> was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">65 years old</TIMEX> at that time,
with no record of potency for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">almost two decades</TIMEX>. You jump to conclusions too
quickly, forgetting that scientific answers such as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> tests are most reliable
in providing negative answers--and often ambiguous in providing positive
answers.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harold L.</ENAMEX>
Orbach <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kan.</ENAMEX>

            

               Micromiracle
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> is a breath of fresh air in his "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dispatches</ENAMEX>"
on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> case. He reports it to us mortals in a funny and
understandable way without putting in so much information that it becomes
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">unintelligible</ENAMEX>. He is a breath of fresh air. I also think it is commendable
that his articles, although unfavorable to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> in the main, are being
hosted on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>-owned site. This is refreshing.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nugent Crumlin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern Ireland</ENAMEX>

            
               Guatemala
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Gringos</ENAMEX>
            

            I realize
that "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Breakfast Table</ENAMEX>" feature is supposed to be light,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">breezy</ENAMEX>, and chatter-driven, but little did I realize that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathie Lee Gifford</ENAMEX>
was doing double duty <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>. It is heartening to know that despite not
having reaped the obvious benefits of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> colonialism, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guatemala</ENAMEX> still
represents a cheap silver buying opportunity for fat <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> wallets. Hope the
<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">hurricane</ENAMEX> hasn't ruined the shopping down there!

            -- Shalini Devi
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gujavarty Jersey City</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.J.</ENAMEX>

            
               Address your e-mail to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. You must include your address and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX>
phone number (for confirmation only).
            

         
      
   
