
   
   
      
         
            On <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rereading</ENAMEX>

            Old age is the new rage.
That was apparent even before <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Glenn</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">aged 77</TIMEX>, went up into space. There
are more old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> than ever. Many of them have word processors. Many of those
pass their free time writing. And, following the advice of all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> of
writing, they write about what they know, which is old age. So there is a lot
of writing on that subject. Even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy Carter</ENAMEX> has written a book about old
age.

            Wanting
to keep up with this trend, I have just reread the classic on the subject,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marcus Tullius Cicero</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">De Senectute</ENAMEX>." The last time I read it was 68 years
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ago</TIMEX>. I read it then in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Latin</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> I read it in the wonderful <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Loeb Classic</ENAMEX>
Library edition, with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin</ENAMEX> on the left page and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> on the right.
I read the right page. I can hardly believe that I read it in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Latin</ENAMEX> when I was
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">junior</ENAMEX> in high school. And I can't imagine what I learned about old age,
reading it in my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teens</ENAMEX>. We didn't read "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">De Senectute</ENAMEX>" to learn about old age.
My <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> believed that reading <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Latin</ENAMEX>--any <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin</ENAMEX>--made tiny grooves in
your brain that increased your general intelligence--not just your capacity to
read <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Latin</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cicero</ENAMEX> wrote the essay in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">44</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">B.C.</ENAMEX>, when he was 62 years
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">old</ENAMEX>. One might think that was pretty old for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roman</ENAMEX> of that time, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cicero</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">evidently</ENAMEX> didn't think it was old enough to qualify him to discourse on the
subject. He wrote in the voice of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cato the Elder</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year 150</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">B.C.</ENAMEX>, when
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cato</ENAMEX> was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">84 years old</TIMEX>. In fact, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cicero</ENAMEX> did not live to experience much old age.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">The year</TIMEX> after writing the essay he was executed for being on the wrong side of
a political dispute.

            The essay
consists of a long answer by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cato</ENAMEX> to questions posed by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one 35</NUMEX>
and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one 36</NUMEX>. They ask him "on what principles we may most easily support the
weight of increasing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cato</ENAMEX> breaks down the question. He identifies <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>
reasons why old age appears to be an unhappy time: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First</ENAMEX>, it withdraws us from
active pursuits. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, it makes the body weaker. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Third</NUMEX>, it deprives us of all
physical pleasures. And <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX>, it is not far removed from death.

            
He then discusses these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX>.

            Translating the answers into
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>, they almost all consist of saying that the quality of
one's old age depends on the investments one made in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier years</TIMEX>. I don't
refer, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cicero</ENAMEX> didn't either, to financial investments that assure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> a
comfortable income in old age. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cicero</ENAMEX> came from a wealthy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>.) I am sure
that financial investments are important, and I don't suppose <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cicero</ENAMEX> would have
denied that. But there are other kinds of investments implicit in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cicero</ENAMEX>'s
discussion.

            The most
obvious is investment in one's health and bodily strength. I don't think the
Romans of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cicero</ENAMEX>'s time had a cigarette problem. But it seems clear from the
examples he gives that having a satisfactory old age depends on adequacy of
physical exercise and moderation of eating and drinking in the years
before.

            Another investment important for old age is friendships.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cicero</ENAMEX> has <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cato</ENAMEX> say, "I have always had my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">club companions</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cato</ENAMEX> takes pride
in having been instrumental, when he was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30 years old</TIMEX>, in establishing certain
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">clubs</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX>, "and therefore I used to dine with these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">companions</ENAMEX>--in an
altogether moderate way, yet with a certain ardor appropriate to my age, which,
as time goes on, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> mitigates my zest for every pleasure."

            Being a
Stoic, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cicero</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cato</ENAMEX> does not regret but rather welcomes the decline of appetite
for what he calls "sensual" pleasure. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cato</ENAMEX> quotes a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who asked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sophocles</ENAMEX>
whether, being old, he still indulged in "the delights of love." When I look
across the page at the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin</ENAMEX> I see rebus veneriis , which looks more like
sexual love--but it's a long time since I studied <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin</ENAMEX>, and I may be wrong.)
In any case, he praises the value of the intellectual and aesthetic pleasures
in which an old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> can still indulge. But to fully appreciate art, science,
and nature in old age requires some prior investment in cultivating them.

            
An even older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX> reminds me of an
investment for old age at which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cicero</ENAMEX> only hints. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Genesis 24:1</ENAMEX> says, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">And</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abraham</ENAMEX> was old, well stricken in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age</TIMEX>: and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lord</ENAMEX> had blessed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abraham</ENAMEX> in all
things." According to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rabbi</ENAMEX> (I don't want to pretend to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> of such
things), later <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentators</ENAMEX> said that meant that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abraham</ENAMEX> was blessed with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">recognition</ENAMEX> that he had passed the trials of his life with valor and devotion
and could now enjoy a peaceful retirement, content in his own eyes and in the
eyes of God. He had, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s parlance, paid his dues. That is another
investment one can make for old age: so to conduct oneself in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">prior years</TIMEX> that
one can feel one has paid one's dues.

            On the final question of how
to invest to prepare for the proximity of death in old age, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cicero</ENAMEX> is not very
helpful. (Who is?) He offers his "philosophical" view. Death brings at least an
end to those troublesome appetites and may open the way to something better--he
doesn't say what. Perhaps one could indoctrinate oneself in that attitude in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX> and so prepare for old age. But obviously <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cicero</ENAMEX> did not find that
philosophy sufficient. As the introduction to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Loeb</ENAMEX> edition says, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">In</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 45</TIMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> before he wrote "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">De Senectute</ENAMEX>"] the death of his adored and
only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> drove him into a frenzy of writing in an effort to forget his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">grief</ENAMEX>." He did not accept the fact of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tullia</ENAMEX>'s death with the
thought that she had at least escaped all appetites. His philosophy might have
prepared him for his own death; it did not prepare him for the death of one he
loved.

            Later he
wrote an essay titled "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Consolatio</ENAMEX>," which probably dealt with this subject and
which I have not read. If he was rescued from his grief, it was apparently time
and work, not philosophy, that rescued him.

            : <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herbert Stein</ENAMEX> thanks his
high-school <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
