
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace Therapy</ENAMEX>

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last Friday</TIMEX>, after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nine days</TIMEX>
of talks under <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s supervision at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wye River</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plantation</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yasser Arafat</ENAMEX> reached an agreement on the next phase of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> peace
process. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> rushed the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> to complete the
signing ceremony before sundown, the beginning of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> Sabbath. <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Minutes</TIMEX>
after the ceremony ended, the sun set, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> all over the world ceased their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">labors</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> spin <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> went to work, lobbying <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> to
give <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> credit for pulling off the deal.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> could have denied that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wye</ENAMEX> deal was a triumph or that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
deserved credit for it. But this would have been futile. Instead, they
diminished his achievement in a subtler and more effective way. From a
political standpoint, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s true payoff for facilitating the peace deal is
to put the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> scandal behind him. His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX> are trying to
deprive him of that payoff by binding the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> stories together.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> camp's spin in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the days</TIMEX> since the agreement has
made clear that its game plan is to change the subject. In campaign
fund-raising appearances, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> portrayed himself as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peacemaker</ENAMEX> and said
the agreement "reminds us what counts." On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> , when
conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Bauer</ENAMEX> denounced <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s behavior in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>
matter, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic Party</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roy Romer</ENAMEX> paraphrased the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jordan</ENAMEX>'s
praise for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s performance at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wye</ENAMEX>. "This election is not about that
[scandal]," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Romer</ENAMEX>. "This election's about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX>. It's about a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> [of whom] <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein</ENAMEX> [said], 'I've never seen his equal in all the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">presidents</ENAMEX> I've known.' " <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Strategist James Carville</ENAMEX> similarly brushed off
questions about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>: "When you see what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein</ENAMEX> has said about this
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>," asked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carville</ENAMEX>, "who do you believe has got more integrity and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King Hussein</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nelson Mandela</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bennett</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Falwell</ENAMEX>?
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> know this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s doing the job."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sympathizers</ENAMEX> in the media picked up this spin. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s "performance at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wye</ENAMEX>
River disposes of the argument that because of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> affair he cannot be
an effective <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>," wrote <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony Lewis</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> . It
also "put [that] affair in perspective. How trivial it looked compared with the
stakes at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wye River</ENAMEX>." On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Donaldson</ENAMEX> noted that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> would visit the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gaza Strip</ENAMEX> in triumph in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX>. "While the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> are holding [impeachment] hearings in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>," boasted
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Donaldson</ENAMEX>, "Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">President</ENAMEX> will be striding the world like a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colossus</ENAMEX>."

            
Far from denying <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s triumph,
conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> graciously acknowledged it. On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Shelby</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ala.</ENAMEX>, credited <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> for shepherding the
talks. On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Late Edition</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orrin Hatch</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX>, called it "one
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s grandest moments." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brit Hume</ENAMEX> argued that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">achievement</ENAMEX> shouldn't be underestimated. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> is good at peace
processes," agreed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Kristol</ENAMEX>. "Let's give him credit."

            Instead,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> slyly appropriated the theme of a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">front-page</ENAMEX> article, which suggested that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s vices in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> affair
had become virtues at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wye</ENAMEX> summit. The summit, "with its all-night sessions
and constant brushes with disaster, was a setting in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s penchant
for keeping all the balls in the air at once seemed to thrive," said the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> . "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> relied on a personal style of charm, persistence, and
language that could be artfully imprecise," particularly when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX> sought
his assurance that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> would release <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pollard</ENAMEX>. According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adviser</ENAMEX> acknowledged that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> had been encouraging enough about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pollard</ENAMEX> case in a vague way that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israelis</ENAMEX> could have heard a pledge that was never precisely made." In an
acid reference to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> cover-up, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">confidant</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX>'s suggested
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, after initially saying that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pollard</ENAMEX> "is going to be released,"
had taken refuge in "a dispute about the word 'is.' " On <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> ,
former <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> spinner <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX> confirmed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> 's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">thesis</ENAMEX>: "The things that drive you most crazy about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>, in a
situation like this, work. He can see gray. He can understand both sides of the
argument."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX> flattered him in the most sincere
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX>--imitation--by exploiting the ambiguity of the ambiguity thesis. Rather
than celebrate the transformation of his vices into virtues, they argued that
his momentary virtues will revert to vices. "It depended on qualities that he
really had: doggedness, a willingness to stay up <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">all night</TIMEX>, charm," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hume</ENAMEX>.
"And yet, like so much that he does, it was somewhat stained by this seamy
little business about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Pollard</ENAMEX>, in which you can't quite figure out
who's telling the truth, but one suspects that it may not be the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>."
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> pundit <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tucker Carlson</ENAMEX> agreed: "The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> things he did during this
negotiation" were "to stay up <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">all night</TIMEX>" and to "throw a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">temper tantrum</ENAMEX>." In
this light, the traits for which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> lauded <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> at the
signing ceremony took on ironic shadows: his "tolerance," his "flexible mind,"
and the fact that, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX> put it, "he doesn't stop."

            The virtues-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">as</NUMEX>-vices argument
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hurts Clinton</ENAMEX> not only by cementing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> episode as the defining moment
of his presidency but also by obscuring the ways in which he succeeded at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wye</ENAMEX>
by overcoming the vices he displayed in that episode. By some accounts,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s chief contribution at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wye</ENAMEX> was his refusal to buckle in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> showdowns
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX>. But over time, this aspect of his success will be forgotten
because it doesn't fit the pattern. And as the public comes to believe instead
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s flexibility and artifice led to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wye</ENAMEX> agreement, the
agreement's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">antagonists</ENAMEX>--or even its reluctant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">signers</ENAMEX>--will be tempted to
demand that the terms be revised, arguing that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> deceived them and
figuring that he will bend under pressure.

            What will
help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> most in their efforts to link <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wye</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
incorrigible narcissism. <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Hours</TIMEX> after announcing the agreement, he said in a
speech to a conference of religious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>, "I felt that it was a part of my
job as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, my mission as a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX>, and my personal journey of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">atonement</ENAMEX>." Personal journey? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Atonement</ENAMEX>? Perhaps <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX> needn't
bother laboring to make the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> mess the touchstone of his presidency.
He's determined to do it himself.

            
               Recent
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Frame Games</ENAMEX>"
            

            "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>
Trial": The lesson of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX> is to attack the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">inquisition</ENAMEX>. (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday, Oct. 21, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">St.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew"</ENAMEX>: The
political use of a gay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s gruesome death. (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, Oct. 16</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>)
            

         
      
   
