
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">139</NUMEX>:

            By <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cohen</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toys</ENAMEX>,
comic books, nail polish, and jewelry. What's the connection?
            

            by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon ET</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> to e-mail your answer to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.

            
               Responses
to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s question (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 138</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Scaly":</ENAMEX>
            

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This winter</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
government is testing a new <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1-to-5</NUMEX> rating <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">system</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nebraska</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wyoming</ENAMEX>.
Rating what?
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Homosexuality</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'Individuals</ENAMEX> rated <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> through <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> will be issued an identity card protecting them
from violence,' said a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX>. 'Fours and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">5s</ENAMEX>? Well they're just asking for
it.' "-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beth Sherman</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adorableness</ENAMEX> of plains
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim O'Grady</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Katha Pollitt</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Tullis</ENAMEX>
had similar answers.)

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Suitability</ENAMEX> as an
unmarked grave site for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Tripp</ENAMEX>. Whoops! We mean, um, suitability as, um,
landfills."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Carvell</ENAMEX>
            

            "Number of times <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">per hour</NUMEX>
it would be appropriate to refer to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack London</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">'To Build a Fire</ENAMEX>.' "-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doug</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ingram</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fondness for</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">unicameralism</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nebraska</ENAMEX>, of course, gets a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">'5</NUMEX>.' "-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam Bonin</ENAMEX>
            

            Click for more
responses.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
            

            Judging by
your responses, here's what we know about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nebraska</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wyoming</ENAMEX>--bad sex, bad
food, bad teeth, bad weather. No, wait, that's what we knew <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> about
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">England</ENAMEX>, although it's not far off. The big difference seems to be that
everyone in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> is gay, and everyone in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nebraska</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wyoming</ENAMEX> is eager to
beat the stuffing out of them. You would, however, receive an affectionate
reception if you were a domestic animal--sorry again, the term preferred by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">animal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lovers</ENAMEX> is "date." Is bestiality, that perpetual urban smirk at rural
life, actually prevalent in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nebraska</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wyoming</ENAMEX>? Or, to put it another way, in
the sense of asking an entirely different question: Is it really a requirement
of sophistication that a place provides good <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bookstores</ENAMEX>, movies, plays,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">museums</ENAMEX>, music, cuisines, and an opportunity for erotic and intellectual
freedom? As it turns out, yes. But be wary of feeling too proud of yourself
simply for not living in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nebraska</ENAMEX>. The same boast can be made by anyone in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kansas</ENAMEX>.

            

               Precipitate Answer
            

            Winter storms.

            According
to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN Headline News</ENAMEX> (the brisk alternative for those who find <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s regular
news too prolix), the rating system is analogous to that used for hurricanes,
with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> a "minor inconvenience" and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> "life threatening." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Weather</ENAMEX>
Service will evaluate the system in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">spring</TIMEX>.

            
               Life
Under <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Livingston</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Augmented Quotations Extra</ENAMEX>
            

            (Each final sentence added
by "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">News Quiz</ENAMEX>.")

            "It's a different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX>
at the same steering wheel with the same <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas</ENAMEX> in the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>. He's a committed
conservative. Any poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folk</ENAMEX> get in the road, he's gonna run 'em
over."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rep</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Obey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wis.</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Livingston</ENAMEX> is about
running the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">train</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tracks</ENAMEX>. Poor folk wander onto those <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tracks</ENAMEX>:
Boom!"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Souder</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ind.</ENAMEX>
            

            "You will still have a
pro-big business, very much pro-oil industry <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>, and it is still very much a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>. This place will become much less cannibalistic and much less of
a snake pit. But the snake, though limbless, can drive a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> or a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">train</ENAMEX> or
maybe a private <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">jet</ENAMEX> or something right over any damn poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who get in its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Obey</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Format
Change
            

            As of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Quiz</ENAMEX>
converts to the Top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX> format so popular with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>. Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> will continue to
run <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> responses, but Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> will be capped <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at 35</TIMEX>, thus increasing its comic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">density</ENAMEX>. I'm only grateful that we're not switching over to adult contemporary.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Media</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultant</ENAMEX> bastards.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Disclaimer</ENAMEX>: All submissions will become the property of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> and
will be published at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> 's discretion. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> may publish your
name on its site in connection with your submission.
            

         
      
   
