
   
   
      
         
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 21</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Nov. 21, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            The
cover editorial deplores <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s habit of legislating by
lawsuits instead of laws. Class-action lawsuits against tobacco <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> have
led to regulation and taxation while bypassing the democratic process. Next up:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayors</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Orleans</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">San</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francisco</ENAMEX> are now--or soon will be--filing suits against the gun industry.
... A story says the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> is a farce. With no direction, no
discipline, and no <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> to feed its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX> is falling apart.
Modern fighting requires "small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">armies</ENAMEX> of ready-to-go <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX>," not a
huge band of untrained, hungry lugs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Soldiers</ENAMEX> may soon start looting; a
military coup would be likely if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> could ever organize itself.

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 7</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, Nov. 20, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            Two
articles argue that, in lieu of attacking, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s best option with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> is
to support a rebel insurrection. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX> himself is our primary problem,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebels</ENAMEX> are our best bet for getting rid of him. "Providing military support
for the main opposition <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iraqi National Congress</ENAMEX>, is a high-risk
gamble, but it could deliver a high payoff: ending the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Saddam</ENAMEX> problem, solving
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gulf</ENAMEX> security conundrum, and relieving <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>'s fear of attack from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">east</ENAMEX>." ... A story warns that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX> are relying too much
on adjunct <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faculty</ENAMEX>. Part-time <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professors</ENAMEX> are poorly paid, overworked, and don't
have time to devote to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times Magazine</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 22</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, Nov. 19, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
story marvels at the resurgence of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prince Charles</ENAMEX>. After <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>'s death,
disgruntled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> wanted to pass over the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adulterous</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles</ENAMEX> and make his son
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heir</ENAMEX> to the throne. But by hiring a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PR</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> to manage his image, wooing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> with occasional jokes, and bonding with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blair</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles</ENAMEX> has staged an astounding revival. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brits</ENAMEX> now appreciate his many
good works and his affectionate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fathering</ENAMEX>. The story hints that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles</ENAMEX> does
not much like his cold <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> gets a rare private interview with
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prince</ENAMEX> and confirms that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles</ENAMEX> does have "large ears, as advertised."
... An article traces a family of impassioned <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Albanian</ENAMEX> gun-running
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fighters</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brooklyn</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.Y.</ENAMEX>, to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>, where they support the rebel <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liberation Army</ENAMEX> against <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> oppression. Among the poignant details from the
war: In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Albania</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kalashnikov</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">rifles</ENAMEX> are hidden in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">watermelons</TIMEX>; and in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KLA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guerillas</ENAMEX> are so poor they have to eat <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">toothpaste</ENAMEX>.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 23</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Nov. 17, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            Despite the near-attacks on
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> run soft covers: herbal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> and "super" <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's cover piece ("It's great business, but is it good for what ails
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">us?</ENAMEX>") says herbal remedies can work--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saint Johnswort</ENAMEX> does cure some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX>' mild
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">depression</ENAMEX>--but herbs also have nasty side effects. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saint Johnswort</ENAMEX> makes your
skin sensitive to sunlight.) Stunning statistic: <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> visit
alternative-medicine <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">practitioners</ENAMEX> more often than they visit family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> also advises <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> how they can profit from the herbal craze:
Buy stock in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Nutrition and Whole Foods Market</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's
cover package (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Does Bill Ford Have a Better Idea?</ENAMEX>") says the
future of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> is fuel-cell engines--they use <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hydrogen</ENAMEX>, and their only waste is
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>. But don't expect them for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few decades</TIMEX>. Until gas costs more, consumers
won't pay the premium for enviro-friendly <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicles</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> reports on a new
study showing that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> have less free time than ever before: They spend most
of their waking <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> on school, homework, and organized sports. Good news:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Kids</ENAMEX> watch less television. Bad news: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Unstructured</ENAMEX> play encourages independent
thinking and allows the young to negotiate their relationships with their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">peers</ENAMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> ages <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3 to 12</TIMEX> spent <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">only 12 hours</TIMEX> a week engaged in it."

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> exposes how far the pro wrestling industry will go to keep fans
interested. Pro wrestling used to be merely fake athletic spectacle. Now it is
fake athletic spectacle in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> are expected to display sexism,
homophobia, and sociopathic behavior. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Fans</ENAMEX> as young as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7 years old</TIMEX> cheer a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wrestler</ENAMEX> who "bases his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> on the size of his sexual apparatus" and boo
a "gay" tag <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Too Much</ENAMEX>."

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News & World Report</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 23</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Nov. 17, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            The
cover story hails forthcoming <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vaccines</ENAMEX>. Recent insights into how
our immune system works are making <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vaccines</ENAMEX> more effective. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reliable AIDS</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">vaccines</ENAMEX> could be ready <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">within a decade</TIMEX>; cancer <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vaccines</ENAMEX> are further off but
possible. Soon <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vaccines</ENAMEX> will be administered by <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pill</ENAMEX>, mouthwash, or genetically
altered <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">foods</ENAMEX>. ... A story says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX> is admitting dumber <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recruits</ENAMEX>. Needing to
fill vacancies at a time of low unemployment, the armed forces are letting in
more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> who score unacceptably low on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX>'s intelligence
tests. Luckily, most of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recruits</ENAMEX> will clean and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cook</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 23</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Nov. 17, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            An essay
says <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> is out of control. Partisan sniping has become more vicious and
personal because of the transformation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> from fragile coalitions into
ideological <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>. From <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Bork</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarence Thomas to John Tower</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jim</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wright</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>, recent politics has centered on "ethics" and brutal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">name-calling</ENAMEX>. The press encourages this, as there is "considerable peer
pressure to stay cynical." No solution is in sight. ... A story defends
J.P. Morgan, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, not the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ninety</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> thought he'd
engineered the panic of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1907</TIMEX> for his own benefit. In fact, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morgan</ENAMEX> worked
tirelessly to save the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> economy, which was near collapse, and he
benefited little from his strenuous efforts to keep <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> solvent. In fact,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morgan</ENAMEX> was a straight <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shooter</ENAMEX>, an art <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enthusiast</ENAMEX>, and a decent chap.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stevenson</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
