
   
   
      
         
            Blinkmanship

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an hour</TIMEX> before
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX> were scheduled to attack <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX> announced that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> would allow <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> weapons <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspectors</ENAMEX> to resume their
work in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>, which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX> had previously halted. With that, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>
decided that the purpose of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> attack--to punish <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX>'s refusal to
cooperate with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspectors</ENAMEX>--had been rendered moot. So <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> called off
the attack.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Pundits</ENAMEX>
spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next two days</TIMEX> questioning <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s judgment and manhood. They
accused him of "flinching" and letting <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Saddam</ENAMEX> start and stop confrontations as
though the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> were "on a yo-yo." "Does anyone seriously believe that
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> backed down and not the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>?" asked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Kristol</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This Week</TIMEX> . "It was a chance finally to take decisive action, and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> blinked." On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Late Edition</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Page</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> was
having trouble explaining "why it isn't the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> who blinked." "Which
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> blinked<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>" asked the front-page headline in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> .
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diddled</ENAMEX> again," answered the headline over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Safire</ENAMEX>'s column. "It didn't
take much for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX> to get the attack called off, did it?" scoffed
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brit Hume</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News Sunday</ENAMEX> . "We're letting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX> drive our
policy."

            This criticism has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> parts: "blink" and "yo-yo." The
blink critique assumes that the purpose of preparing the attack was to complete
it and thereby hurt <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>. But suppose <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s deeper purpose is--as he
says--to control and eliminate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> of mass destruction. And
suppose he believes--as he says he does--that the best way to do this is
through the weapons inspections, not through a military assault. In that case,
once <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX> agreed to let the inspections resume, the truly resolute course was
to accept the offer and call off the attack.

            The yo-yo
critique focuses on predictability. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First Clinton</ENAMEX> authorized the attack because
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX> had halted the weapons inspections. Then, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX> allowed the
inspections to resume, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> called off the attack. The yo-yo charge implies
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is letting <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Saddam</ENAMEX> manipulate him. What this metaphor nicely
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">obscures</ENAMEX> is the rationality behind <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s predictability. Yo-yos and other
objects follow laws of nature. Humans follow laws of our own making. We've even
invented a name for these laws: "principles." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s principle is that the
inspections must resume. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX> violates that principle, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> will
attack. When <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Saddam</ENAMEX> yields to the same principle, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> will not attack. Yes,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX> can choose the outcome, just as you can choose your fate by deciding how
to answer a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mugger</ENAMEX> who says, "Your money or your life." But do you really
imagine that you're the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> in control?

            
This is what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> tried to explain at his
press conference on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>, "Our willingness to strike ... produced the outcome
we preferred: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX> reversing course, letting the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspectors</ENAMEX> go back
to work without restrictions or conditions." The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX> wasn't buying it. "What
do you say to the criticism that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX> is jerking the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
around, that he is able to provoke a crisis and then end it on his timetable<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>"
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> world they're going to look at it and say, 'OK, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX> won again?' "
asked another. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Berger</ENAMEX> could only reply in exasperation that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX> had
"capitulated" on the key issue of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> inspections. "We have to be able to
take yes for an answer," he pleaded.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pundits</ENAMEX>, captive to the geopolitics of machismo, think saying yes is easy. But
when everyone wants you to say no, saying yes is hard. Yo-yos can't do it.
Neither can cruise <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX>. That's why we have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidents</ENAMEX>.

            
               Recent
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Frame Games</ENAMEX>"
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cannibalism": The</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> coup is taking the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> in the wrong direction. (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Nov.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The C Word": The</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> election didn't kill conservatism. The postelection analysis did.
(posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, Nov. 6, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

         
      
   
