
   
   
      
         
            D'Amatoing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D'Amato</ENAMEX>

            NEW ROCHELLE, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.Y.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OCT.</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">27</TIMEX>--Depending on which high-minded pundit you listen to, you know that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> race between incumbent <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al D'Amato</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chuck Schumer</ENAMEX> is
either <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) the "dirtiest" or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2</NUMEX>) the "ugliest" campaign in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>'s history. It
is a campaign, after all, in which the challenger's slogan is "Too many lies
for too long," where each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> blithely runs ads accusing his opponent of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coddling child</ENAMEX> pornographers, and where virtually the only intelligible
sentences of the so-called debates were "Stop being rude!" and "Let me finish!"
Right-thinking <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">New Yorkers</ENAMEX> (and there are far too many of them) agree: This
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> race is a perversion of democracy.

            The
goo-goos have it wrong. This race has done exactly what a campaign should:
expose the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> in all their nakedness. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Newspapers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentators</ENAMEX>
solemnly observe that this riot of negative ads and name-calling has cost <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$40</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">million</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">roughly $25 million</NUMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D'Amato</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican Party</ENAMEX>, the balance
from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schumer</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>). That's <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $2</NUMEX> for every <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX>. A few
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks ago</TIMEX>, 
                  Slate
               's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven E. Landsburg</ENAMEX> wrote a column arguing that
every <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> has got <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">15 cents</NUMEX> worth of entertainment from the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$40 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> investigation. Well, if there are any <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">New Yorkers</ENAMEX> who haven't got <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2</NUMEX>
worth of diversion out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Schumer-D'Amato</ENAMEX> race, I haven't met them.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schumer</ENAMEX> is stumping <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX>. This is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fitting</ENAMEX>, because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schumer</ENAMEX> would like everyone to believe that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clintonism</ENAMEX> is the
core of his campaign. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brooklyn</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX> has spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last few years</TIMEX>
doing what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> did before his presidential run, shaking off a mostly
liberal record and repositioning himself as a moderate who understands suburban
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schumer</ENAMEX> abandoned his opposition to the death penalty, voted for the
Defense of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Marriage Act</ENAMEX>, and signed on to every crime bill he could find. At
all his campaign appearances, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schumer</ENAMEX> emphasizes that "I am a tough-on-crime
moderate." Like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, he is counting on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> to vote for him because
they have nowhere else to go.

            (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schumer</ENAMEX> resembles <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> in
another way: He takes credit for everything. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schumer</ENAMEX>, I learned from his past
few <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> of campaign appearances, is responsible for the national drop in
crime, the protection of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>, and the budget deal.
Thank you, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">congressman</ENAMEX>! His <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> have coined the
phrase "to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schume</ENAMEX>." It means "to take credit for something that others have
done.")

            But if
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schumer</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> on paper, he certainly isn't in the flesh. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s
appearance with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">first lady</ENAMEX> at a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Rochelle</ENAMEX> senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">center</ENAMEX> makes this
glaringly obvious. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX> appear together, he
radiates the warmth. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schumer</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> appear together, she
does.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> is chatty and informal. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schumer</ENAMEX> has all
the charm of a lawnmower. To a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> of genial, upbeat <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">seniors</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schumer</ENAMEX> serves
vicious attacks on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D'Amato</ENAMEX>. He fires off some good lines: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D'Amato</ENAMEX> votes "like a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mississippi</ENAMEX>, not a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>," and "When the choice
was between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">seniors</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al D'Amato</ENAMEX> chose <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX>." But the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vitriol</ENAMEX> doesn't fit the mood. When he's not flamethrowing, he lectures. He
responds to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> question from an <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">81-year-old</TIMEX> with an endless, learned, and
cringingly dull discourse on health care financing. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schumer</ENAMEX> is no fun. He's a
grind. If he were a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">salesman</ENAMEX>, you'd buy the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> just to get him to leave you
alone. Even his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">loyalists</ENAMEX> don't seem to like him much. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half-dozen</NUMEX> elderly
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> I spoke to after the event all said the same thing: Of course they would
vote for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schumer</ENAMEX>--but mostly because they hate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D'Amato</ENAMEX>.

            (Brief
interruption for speculation about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>'s peculiar behavior. She clearly
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">loathes D'Amato</ENAMEX>, and she makes a point of never referring to him by
name. She calls him only "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chuck Schumer</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponent</ENAMEX>." Here's the peculiarity:
She also never refers to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> by name. She calls him "my
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>" or "the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>," never "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX>." Does this have psychological
significance? Is she so angry that she won't say his name?)

            The lesson of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schumer</ENAMEX> campaign is not that you need to
be <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to beat <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D'Amato</ENAMEX>, given that the overbearing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schumer</ENAMEX> will never be
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. The lesson of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schumer</ENAMEX> campaign is that you need to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D'Amato</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">beat D'Amato</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clintonism</ENAMEX> is relentlessness plus charm. D'Amatoism (which is now
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schumerism</ENAMEX>) is just relentlessness, and to hell with the charm.

            My
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mother-in-law</ENAMEX>, who lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schumer</ENAMEX>'s congressional district and always votes
for him, says she's thinking of supporting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D'Amato</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>: "He's a sleaze.
But he's good for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>." Substitute "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gays</ENAMEX>" or "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Irish"</ENAMEX> or "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX>" or
"cancer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>" or "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bankers</ENAMEX>" for "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>," and you begin to see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schumer</ENAMEX>'s
struggle. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pothole</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX> of the ethnic pork barrel. (He shows up at
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> gatherings wearing a yarmulke with "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alfonse</ENAMEX>" stitched on it.) He relies
on "We owe him" to override <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>' distaste for his viciousness and basic
amorality, and for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18 years</TIMEX>, it has.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schumer</ENAMEX> doesn't yet have the pull to imitate
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D'Amato</ENAMEX>'s pork-barreling (though he would if he could--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schumer</ENAMEX>, for example,
happily obeys Wall Street's bidding on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Banking Committee</ENAMEX> in order to
raise campaign funds). So <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schumer</ENAMEX> has done the next best thing, which is to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">steal D'Amato</ENAMEX>'s campaign style.

            In
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schumer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D'Amato</ENAMEX> finally faces an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponent</ENAMEX> who's as hardheaded, shameless, and
effective as he is. Usually <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D'Amato</ENAMEX> dictates a campaign, and his opponent
desperately plays defense. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schumer</ENAMEX> has turned the tables on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D'Amato</ENAMEX>. The first
day after the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> primary, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schumer</ENAMEX> unleashed "Too many lies for too
long" ads. More recently, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D'Amato</ENAMEX> stupidly (but innocently, I think) called
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schumer</ENAMEX> a "putzhead," then denied having said it. ("<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Putz</ENAMEX>" is a <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Yiddish</ENAMEX> insult
that literally means "penis" but in common usage means "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fool</ENAMEX>.") <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schumer</ENAMEX> has
managed to gin this into an ongoing controversy about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D'Amato</ENAMEX>'s trustworthiness
and to score major points with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>. Since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s murder of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York</ENAMEX> abortion <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schumer</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have subtly tried to connect the
anti-abortion <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D'Amato</ENAMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">extremist right-to-lifers</ENAMEX>.

            And every time <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D'Amato</ENAMEX> has attacked, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schumer</ENAMEX> has fired it
back in his face. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D'Amato</ENAMEX> tried to exploit the ill feelings between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">City</ENAMEX> and upstate. He ran an ad upstate depicting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schumer</ENAMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
City <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shark</ENAMEX> swimming up the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hudson</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schumer</ENAMEX> immediately countered by running the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D'Amato</ENAMEX> commercial in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>, labeling it "the ad <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al D'Amato</ENAMEX> doesn't
want you to see." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D'Amato</ENAMEX>'s latest strategy--to tar <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schumer</ENAMEX> as a lazy,
"part-time" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">congressman</ENAMEX> who skips votes--seems to be backfiring as well.
Newspaper after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> has berated <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D'Amato</ENAMEX> for this patently dishonest
strategy, noting that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schumer</ENAMEX> is probably the hardest-working <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schumer</ENAMEX>,
like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D'Amato</ENAMEX>, is aggressive, opportunistic, and unpleasant in more ways that I
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D'Amato</ENAMEX> is the éminence grise (or perhaps the éminence noire ) of
the corrupt <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Nassau County Republican</ENAMEX> machine. He believes that politics is
about bending the rules for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cronies</ENAMEX> and campaign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contributors</ENAMEX>, and he has been
implicated in more gross behavior than almost any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX> around. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schumer</ENAMEX> is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">clean</ENAMEX>. He doesn't cheat. He may have moderated his views to win, but he is
mostly principled and mostly honest.

            
Even so, out-D'Amatoing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D'Amato</ENAMEX> on the campaign
trail may not be enough. Some signs are promising for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schumer</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A week</TIMEX> out, the
polls are dead even and actually seem to be trending slightly in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schumer</ENAMEX>'s
favor. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D'Amato</ENAMEX> has been distracted by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Putzgate</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schumer</ENAMEX> is getting sweet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PR</ENAMEX>
off <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>'s visit and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s planned campaign appearance <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>.

            But it's hard to imagine
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D'Amato</ENAMEX> will lose. He has saved his war chest. He and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> will spend
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$8 million</NUMEX> on an ad blitz during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the five days</TIMEX> leading up to the election:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schumer</ENAMEX> has saved only a small fraction of that. You can be sure that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D'Amato</ENAMEX> ads will be cheap and distorted, but that at least something from them
will stick to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schumer</ENAMEX>.

            Every
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schumer</ENAMEX> notes that he has never lost an election. But neither has
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D'Amato</ENAMEX>.

            
               Recent
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Campaign '98" Dispatches</ENAMEX>
            

            "The Gambling
Gamble": <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Carolina</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> Bet the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farm</ENAMEX>

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Foghorn Leghorn Meets</ENAMEX>
an <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Owl</ENAMEX>": <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fritz Hollings</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Inglis</ENAMEX>. (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Oct.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

         
      
   
