
   
   
      
         
            Yours, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mine</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ours</ENAMEX>

            The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1956</TIMEX> swords-and-sandals
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">epic The Ten Commandments</ENAMEX> has long since turned into a pillar of kitsch,
but certain moments in the movie remain improbably vivid. One is the sneering
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">query</ENAMEX> put by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slave master</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward G. Robinson</ENAMEX> to the humbled Israelite
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlton Heston</ENAMEX>: "Where is your God now, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moses</ENAMEX>?" Back then, the use of a
personal pronoun before "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">God</ENAMEX>" signaled a clash of civilizations: The outlook of
the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nilotic</ENAMEX> world was being contrasted with that of the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chosen</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX>. Similarly, the our in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Luther</ENAMEX>'s stirring anthem "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Mighty</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fortress Is Our God</ENAMEX>" takes for granted the cultural cohesiveness of the
God concept. Today, the personal pronouns my , his , her ,
their , and our are being deployed before "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">God</ENAMEX>" as never before:
Such locutions have become a pervasive social trope. But it's hard to pin down
just what they now signify. A new polytheism? A divinely sanctioned
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">solipsism</ENAMEX>?

            The most
prominent recent example comes from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 17</TIMEX> speech to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nation</ENAMEX>: "Now this matter is between me and the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> I love most--my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>
and our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>--and our God." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, of course, broke no new rhetorical
ground here. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Commentators</ENAMEX> routinely describe abortion as a matter "between a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>, her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physician</ENAMEX>, and her God" (although former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Symms</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Idaho</ENAMEX>,
in a novel twist, once called abortion a decision between "a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> and his God").
An article in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> about charitable giving
contained the sentence "What goes on in this <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> is strictly between you, your
God, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Internal Revenue Service</ENAMEX>." I have seen references to issues that
lie "between me, my scale, and our God" (an article about dieting); "me, my
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">stylist</ENAMEX>, and our God" (an article about hair care); and "me and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX>
with the radar trap and our God" (an article about highway speeding). The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Dershowitz</ENAMEX> has stated that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> should not have a position
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about</NUMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">client</ENAMEX>'s guilt: "His guilt is a matter for him and his God." Echoing
Dershowitz, an <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX> article in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> , appearing days
after the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> speech, contained the words "between him, his <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">toad</ENAMEX>, and their
God." The article was not about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> but about the subject of a tabloid
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World News</ENAMEX> report titled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Teen Hacks Mom to Death With Hatchet</ENAMEX>
Because <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">She Killed the Toad He Licked to Get High</ENAMEX>."

            The legend on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> coins proclaims, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">In God We Trust</ENAMEX>."
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> taking the oath of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> has historically spoken the words "so
help me God." But if the evidence of common speech is any guide, the idea of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">God</ENAMEX> has been rapidly devolving from the generalized to the particular, from the
awesomely abstract to the intensely (even idiosyncratically) personal.

            There has
always been a tension between these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> concepts of God. I brought the matter
up with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Miles</ENAMEX>, whose book, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">God: A Biography</ENAMEX> , won the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pulitzer</ENAMEX>
Prize for nonfiction. Miles sets the situation into historical context: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">What</ENAMEX>
made the fortune, so to speak, of the God of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>," he observes, "was that he
combined <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> functions previously separate: on the one hand, the function of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mesopotamian</ENAMEX> personal God, a kind of guardian angel whose responsibilities
were concentrated on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> but whose powers were also limited; on
the other, the function of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Canaanite/Mesopotamian</ENAMEX> high God, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El</ENAMEX>, whose
attention to any individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> was slight or unpredictable but whose
powers were universal. Before this historic synthesis, you got either one or
the other. After it, you had the electrifying possibility that the top
God was also our God and even my personal God. After it, of
course, you also had the whole range of unanswerable questions of the sort 'How
could a good God--and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">El</ENAMEX> was an essentially benign, judgelike figure--permit X
to happen to us, or to me?' "

            
Is the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">top God"-"my God</ENAMEX>" synthesis coming
undone? Even as a great deal of the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">top God</ENAMEX>" discussion drifts into remote
realms of cosmology, much of the "my God" discussion becomes ever more
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">individualized</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evangelical Protestantism</ENAMEX> has especially cherished the notion
of a personal God, and this continues to be reflected in the heartfelt speech
of ordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and even of nonbelievers. (Recall the reaction of Lt.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scheisskopf</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, in Catch <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22</TIMEX> , to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yossarian</ENAMEX>'s famous tirade against
God. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yossarian</ENAMEX> asks why she is so upset, since she doesn't believe in God to
begin with. She replies, "But the God I don't believe in is a good God, a just
God, a merciful God.")

            The
personal God of the sincerely born-again <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> bears little resemblance to
a different sort of personalized God, the customized kind that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> acquires as
one might a personal <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trainer</ENAMEX>, though the workouts often are not as strenuous.
This latter sort of personalized God may amount at best to a synonym for
"conscience" or "serenity." The dark analogs of the personalized God are one's
personal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">demons</ENAMEX>--which represent the individually customized version of what
used to go by the nontechnical terms <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bad Behavior or Guilt</ENAMEX> or simply <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evil</ENAMEX>.
(Those malevolent imps are tenacious and bothersome: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert S. McNamara</ENAMEX>, the
former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> of defense, was once seen by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> trying
to "wriggle loose from his personal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">demons</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Tribune</ENAMEX> once
witnessed the <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">tennis</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McEnroe</ENAMEX> "swearing at personal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">demons</ENAMEX>.")

            Another form the personal God may take involves a
fragmentation of the concept of divinity itself. Thus, writing in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yorker</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 1996</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louis Menand</ENAMEX> posited the breakdown of traditional
monotheism into "genetic polytheism," in which personal behavior is
attributable to an individualized genetic pantheon. Where once there was a God
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anger</ENAMEX>, now there is a gene of aggression. Where once there was a God of
Wine, now there is a gene of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">alcoholism</ENAMEX>. In ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greece</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phobos</ENAMEX> was the God
of Fear. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> he is gene SLC6A4, whose specific <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Olympian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dwelling place</ENAMEX> is
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">chromosome 17q12.</ENAMEX>

            And then there is the God
module, which is not so much polytheistic as polymorphous. According to
the temporal lobe the stimulation of which, sometimes manifested in the form of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">seizures</ENAMEX>, can now be correlated with certain intangible mental experiences. One
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vilayanur S. Ramachandran</ENAMEX>, making public his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">team</ENAMEX>'s findings <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late last year</TIMEX> at the annual meeting of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Society of</ENAMEX>
Neuroscience, stated, "We like to suggest there may be neural circuits in the
temporal lobe that may be part of the machinery of the brain that is involved
in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mystical</ENAMEX> experiences and God." The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> have christened these neural
circuits the "God module." "Now this is a matter between me, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> I
love most ... and our god modules." We have not heard these words yet, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lord</ENAMEX>
be praised.

         
      
   
