
   
   
      
         
            The Arrest of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pinochet</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Augusto Pinochet</ENAMEX>, who
was quoted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> as saying he finds <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> "the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ideal</ENAMEX> place to live," has probably changed his mind as he lies in his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">clinic</ENAMEX> surrounded by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">police</ENAMEX>, with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protesters</ENAMEX> chanting hostile slogans
outside. His arrest by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scotland Yard</ENAMEX> in response to a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> extradition
request was unanimously supported by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> press. The center-left daily
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El Pa√</ENAMEX>≠s praised <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> for stripping the former <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chilean</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dictator</ENAMEX> of "an immunity he has used
freely to insult his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>," but warned that there will many hurdles before
he can be brought to trial.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">El Mundo</ENAMEX> said the
arrest has "strong symbolic weight" and that "treating the decrepit tyrant as a
common criminal and forcing him to explain his actions in the face of
international <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice</ENAMEX> is a lesson not just for him but for all others of his
ilk around the world." Even the right-wing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> defended the right of the two
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> who are seeking his extradition from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX> to
investigate the fate of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> who disappeared in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chile</ENAMEX> during his
presidency. "If the former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">general</ENAMEX> decided to run the risk of traveling to a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Union</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, knowing that he was under investigation in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX>, and
now has found himself under arrest, the error of judgment is his and his
alone," it said. "Let justice be done."

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>, however, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> were much more circumspect.
While the liberal <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> paper the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Observer</ENAMEX> welcomed the arrest of "an evil tyrant," saying it shows
that the vaunted new "ethical dimension" to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> foreign policy has "real
muscle," the conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> suggested <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> in an editorial that there had been a
failure of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> diplomacy. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> had a duty to advise <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pinochet</ENAMEX> against
visiting <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> at this time. If it fulfilled that duty, he has only himself to
blame for his present predicament. If not, "the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foreign Office</ENAMEX> acted in a less
than competent fashion." "The fragile post-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pinochet</ENAMEX> political settlement in
Chile explicitly depended on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ex-President</ENAMEX> remaining at liberty," it said.
"<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> was obliged to alert <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chile</ENAMEX> of any development that could threaten her
civil peace. ... An 'ethical foreign policy' should not consist of cheap stunts
that could cause enormous difficulties to a friendly <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">democracy</ENAMEX>."

            Condemning
the arrest, the conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Telegraph</ENAMEX> recalled that "throughout his time in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pinochet</ENAMEX> was an unstinting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ally</ENAMEX> of this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>" and that "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chile</ENAMEX> was
the only <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> to support <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> during the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Falklands</ENAMEX> conflict
(when <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX>, incidentally, was more or less overtly pro-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Argentina</ENAMEX>)." Yet
despite that, "our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, having allowed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pinochet</ENAMEX> to enter its borders for
medical treatment, has now detained him in order to comply with a case brought
by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communist Party</ENAMEX>." In an op-ed piece <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> in the conservative
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tabloid Daily Mail</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oxford University</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Almond</ENAMEX> said the
arrest reeks of hypocrisy and will "not send shivers down the spines of other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dictators</ENAMEX>. ... It will just be an excuse to ignore the cries for justice from
the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of unfashionable dead in too many <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">unquiet graves</ENAMEX>."

            
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Financial Times</ENAMEX> , however, welcomed the arrest <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, saying
in an editorial that it "underlines a belief that no-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> should be above the
law, even if he has been able to negotiate immunity in his own <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>." A
trial of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pinochet</ENAMEX> would, moreover, "show that western <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">democracies</ENAMEX> do not now
believe that torture and murder can ever be excused for political or economic
reasons," it added. The liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX> highlighted the warmth of his
relationship with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret Thatcher</ENAMEX>, to whom he would always send <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers</ENAMEX> and
chocolates on his visits to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>. It also reported that, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years ago</TIMEX>,
when he took a party to dinner at the fashionable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">River Cafe</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>, his payment of the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$800</NUMEX> check was donated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amnesty</ENAMEX>
International to defend his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chile</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jerusalem Post</ENAMEX> also
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">welcomed Pinochet</ENAMEX>'s arrest, saying it is "time we had a little more
globalization of justice. ... When the long reach of justice becomes truly
global, we may make some progress in reminding would-be <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pinochets</ENAMEX> that when it
comes to torture, murder and 'disappearances,' no-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> is above or safe from
international law, anywhere." In another editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>, the same newspaper
reflected on the exclusion of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sinn Fein</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerry Adams</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nobel Peace</ENAMEX>
Prize awarded to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Hume</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Trimble</ENAMEX> for their part in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northern</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX> peace settlement. It said that the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nobel Prize</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX>, stung by
criticism of its award of the prize to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yasser Arafat</ENAMEX>, "clearly wished to avoid
further controversy by making another award to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> closely connected to a
terrorist organisation. ... If it had little choice with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arafat</ENAMEX> because he was
both a primary peace <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> and the undisputed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">committee</ENAMEX> had no such problem with slighting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adams</ENAMEX>, who is neither." The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , however, reserved its main praise for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Protestant</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trimble</ENAMEX>,
who, it said, "in wrenching concessions from the intransigent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">unionists</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern Ireland</ENAMEX>, and carrying them through the peace process despite mounting
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">unionist militancy</ENAMEX> and suspicions of a sell-out to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Irish republicanism</NUMEX>, pulled
off a miracle of biblical proportions."

            Commenting on the appointment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ariel Sharon</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>'s
foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX>, the liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ha'aretz</ENAMEX> said in an editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> that he faces a weighty test
at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wye Plantation</ENAMEX> peace talks. "History is offering <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sharon</ENAMEX> a one-time-only
chance to record to his credit the political step so needed by his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>," it
said. Several <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> stressed the importance to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>
of a successful outcome to the talks. "Failure of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli-Palestinian</ENAMEX>
Summit at <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wye Plantation Would Be Disastrous</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>," said a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saturday</ENAMEX>
headline in Le <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monde</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>.

            The opening of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
government's antitrust lawsuit against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> made the front pages of many
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>, with an op-ed piece in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>'s Financial Times
saying that an eventual ruling by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> "is certain to redefine
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">anti-trust</ENAMEX> law and shape the software industry for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> to come." Meanwhile, a
survey of the most powerful and influential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> carried out for
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunday Times</ENAMEX> by an eminent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychologist</ENAMEX> put <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill</ENAMEX>
Gates <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blair</ENAMEX>. A poll conducted among <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">800</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> theater
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royal National Theatre</ENAMEX> and reported in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunday</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telegraph</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arthur Miller</ENAMEX> as the best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">playwright</ENAMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">century</ENAMEX>.

            To mark <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newspaper Week</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>, the daily <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mainichi Shimbun</ENAMEX> ran an editorial welcoming new <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Japanese</ENAMEX>
freedom of information laws as a major challenge to the newspaper industry.
Information from government <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">ministries</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> will no longer be channeled
exclusively through "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">press clubs</ENAMEX>" but will be accessible equally to everyone
via the Internet, it said. "In order to continue serving as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stewards</ENAMEX> of our
right to know, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> must reform themselves so that they will be able to
offer news on their pages that is distinguishable from that which can be read
off computer screens."

         
      
   
