
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Drawing upon her rich
experience of life, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> to her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>) responds to questions
about manners, personal relations, politics, and other subjects. Please send
your questions for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> to prudence@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Queries should not exceed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> words in
length. Please indicate how you wish your letter to be signed, preferably
including your location.
            

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               I
disagree with your opinion that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nine years</TIMEX> of living together equals marriage.
A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> is either married or not, like being pregnant. While the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> can be
friendly and caring to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>'s live-in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boyfriend</ENAMEX>, he is not a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son-in-law</ENAMEX>
and shouldn't be treated as such. Call me old-fashioned, but I believe
commitment means marriage. Anything less is just dating.
            

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Happily Married</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Ms.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duffy Lewis</ENAMEX>
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mt. Pleasant</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">S.C.</ENAMEX>
            

            Dear
Hap,

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> will split the
difference with you. Of course you are right that not being married is not
being married, and living together does not "equal" marriage. Commitment,
however, need not involve marriage. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> knows committed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couples</ENAMEX> whose
relationships have all the ingredients of a really good marriage, and all
that's missing are recognition from the state and contractual obligation.
Prudie, in fact, can speak of this with firsthand knowledge.

            The age
and experience of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> may be a factor. A committed relationship between
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">twentysomethings</ENAMEX> would, of course, have different underpinnings than one
between middle-aged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who have had, perhaps, a marriage or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> under their
belts.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>,
perspectively

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               Though I do realize that
you are the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> on all things advisory, I would like to suggest a different
solution for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dorothy S.</ENAMEX> on the subject of bad breath. Tic-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tacs</ENAMEX>.
            

            
               Keep
some on your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>, and when confronting the foul offender, produce them, pop
a few into your mouth, and offer them to the co-worker. It may not work, but
I've always gone by the rule "If someone offers you a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tic-Tac</ENAMEX>, take it."
They're also nice because they are not quite as blatant as breath <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mints</ENAMEX> but get
the job done.
            

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hopefully Helpfully</ENAMEX>,
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">R.</ENAMEX>
Kriger
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Brookline,</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mass.</ENAMEX>
            

            Dear
Hope,

            Prudie
thanks you for your diplomatic idea--and guesses the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tic</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tac</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> do, too. As
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brits</ENAMEX> might say, your approach is brilliant. It being only polite to offer
a companion what one is oneself ingesting, you will have spared the offender
embarrassment and, with any luck, caused the smellable breath to be sucked
away.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, refreshingly

            
               
                  Dear
Prudie,
               
            

            
               I am
married to a very nice <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">10 ½</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> older than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">I.</ENAMEX> The problem is I don't love
him. I've tried to explain this to him, but he just keeps apologizing for
things. I feel like I'm living with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>. (By the way, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hubby</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX>, and
I'm <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50</TIMEX>. He makes me feel old before my time and embarrasses me often in
public.) He also lost a very good paying job shortly after marriage, and now
we're in debt up to our eyeballs. How can I make him understand I want
out?
            

            
               --Please Help!
            

            Dear
Plea,

            With this
announcement: "I am filing for divorce." If it's really a no-hoper, you must be
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">assertive</ENAMEX> and spare both of you <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more years</TIMEX> of unhappiness. If <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> sounds
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">lenient</ENAMEX> regarding divorcing, it is because she herself has lost <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than one</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> ... in divorce <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>. Life is too short, my dear, to continue with a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> who feels like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>, makes you feel old, embarrasses you, and has
put you both in debt.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>,
experientially

            

               
                  Prudie,
               
            

            
               I was recently at a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">restaurant</ENAMEX>, and when the bill came, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">waitress</ENAMEX> had written at the bottom,
"Suggested tip: <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">17.5 percent</NUMEX>." Then when the credit card slip came, the
"suggested tip" had been written in. I was appalled for so many reasons ...
that she had to put a suggested tip (as if I didn't know) and that she put it
higher than normal (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> certainly was not above and beyond the call of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">duty</ENAMEX>) and that she further did not give the option of a lower tip.
            

            
               What
does <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> suggest in such a situation? I have no problem with the extra <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.5</NUMEX>
percent above the norm, but to have it forced on me in such a forward manner
seemed extremely rude.
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peeved</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Palo Alto</ENAMEX>,
Calif.
            

            Dear
Peev,

            Everyone knows that a
restaurant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">waitstaff</ENAMEX> has many jobs, but giving instructions for the amount of
the tip is not one of them. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> would give anything to know what you did,
caught off guard as you were. She hopes that you thought fast and lined through
the "notation" and wrote in what you wanted to leave.

            You would
not have been out of line to have brought this aggressive and off-putting
action to the attention of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX>, whichever one was present that
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>. For future reference, should a serving person deliver substandard
service, the diner is perfectly within his or her rights to specify "no tip."
This way it is clear that the lack of a tip is neither an oversight nor
miserliness but a reminder that a tip is a voluntary thank-you for good
service.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, gratuitously

         
      
   
