
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">142</NUMEX>:

            By <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cohen</ENAMEX>

            

               "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Traditions</ENAMEX> in the West are sometimes hard to break, but we find this to be
particularly egregious," says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rocky Mountain</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coordinator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrea Lococo</ENAMEX>.
            

            
               What
tradition?
            

            by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon ET</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> to e-mail your answer to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.

            
               Responses
to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>'s question (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 141</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Newersweek ":</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Accepting his new post
as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Whitaker</ENAMEX> asked his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX>, "What can we
do to make <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> a must-read?" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> were invited to offer
suggestions.
            

            "More shots of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mark</ENAMEX>
Whitaker nude in a bubble bath."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Merrill Markoe</ENAMEX>
            

            "New <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subscribers</ENAMEX> receive
free foot rub from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katherine Graham</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jon Hotchkiss</ENAMEX>
            

            "Pictorial feature:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">'What</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Inside Meg Greenfield</ENAMEX>'s ...?' (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Handbag, Refrigerator, Pocket, Fist</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">etc.</ENAMEX>)"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meg Wolitzer</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Replace George Will</ENAMEX>'s
column with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> photo of him being punched in the nose."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rich</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Harrington</ENAMEX>
            

            "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Next week</TIMEX>'s cover story:
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">'Medical Miracle for Cute Babies Is a Hot New Trend and Proof</ENAMEX> of God's
Existence.' "-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Radosh</ENAMEX>
            

            Click for more
responses.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
            

            While
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> shows an admirable eagerness to improve itself, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> may
already have achieved perfection--and not just by stealing 
                  Slate
               
features and denaturing them into wan imitations but by being acutely attuned
to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s demanding pre-teen <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX>. At <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Booker T. Washington Middle School</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">54</TIMEX>,
a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> public school, current events assignments are traditionally
researched in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> , tough going for most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>. Recently,
some <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11-year-olds</TIMEX> were introduced to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> . "It's so easy!" <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">beamed one</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">sixth</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grader</ENAMEX> who'd struggled with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX>'s exegesis of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab-Israeli</ENAMEX>
peace accords. Told that there was also something called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Time for Kids</ENAMEX> ,
she replied, "Oh, I know, but nobody reads that. We call it <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Idiots</ENAMEX> ." <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Kids</ENAMEX> can be so cruel. So delightfully, perceptively cruel.

            
               Condensed
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quayle</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Art of the Editor Extra</ENAMEX>
            

            (Below, a
tighter version of the former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX>'s op-ed piece in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times</ENAMEX> . Many cuts, no additions, no changes in word order.)

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX> held Antonin
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scalia</ENAMEX> and a derelict. They might be tempted routinely. Fine. High officials
should be able to buy their way out of misconduct. How trivial. Let them get
off easily without any consequences at all. They are acting in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s
best interest. Departing from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> pays dividends."

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Disclaimer</ENAMEX>: All submissions will become the property of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> and
will be published at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> 's discretion. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> may publish your
name on its site in connection with your submission.
            

         
      
   
