
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Movies
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meet Joe Black</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Universal Pictures</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> call this remake of
Death Takes a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holiday</ENAMEX> a "somnolent, emotion-free weepie" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Maslin</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ). Faults: It's way too long (almost <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three hours</TIMEX>), and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brad Pitt</ENAMEX>'s performance as Death is crushingly zombielike. Those who can
tolerate the movie's saccharine <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">overdose</ENAMEX> praise the solid performances by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony Hopkins</ENAMEX>, as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tycoon</ENAMEX> whom <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pitt</ENAMEX> has come to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">escort</ENAMEX> to the other side,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Claire Forlani</ENAMEX>, as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tycoon</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> who falls in love with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pitt</ENAMEX>. (Is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brad Pitt</ENAMEX> the worst <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> on earth? Read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edelstein</ENAMEX>'s review in 
                  Slate
                to find out.)

            

               
                  Celebrity
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miramax Films</ENAMEX>). Critical response to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woody Allen</ENAMEX>'s
cult of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrity sendup</ENAMEX> is all over the map. Some call it "horrifically funny"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Kroll</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> ); others call it "rambling" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Mathews</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsday</ENAMEX> ). Is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Branagh</ENAMEX>'s performance as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woody Allen</ENAMEX>-like
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>--complete with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen</ENAMEX>'s tics and mannerisms--dead on or a mistake? Has
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen</ENAMEX> revealed truths about <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>' celebrity <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lust</ENAMEX>, or is he out of touch
with reality? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maslin</ENAMEX> calls <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leonardo DiCaprio</ENAMEX>'s performance as a bratty bad boy
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> "show-stopping," and most other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> agree. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edelstein</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DiCaprio</ENAMEX>'s
performance "reminds you why movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> sometimes deserve to be worshipped."
Read
the rest of his review in 
                  Slate
               .)

            

               
                  I'll <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Be Home for Christmas</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buena Vista Pictures</ENAMEX>). This
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Planes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">Trains & Automobiles</ENAMEX> with a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> twist is thrashed:
"[It] doesn't make you want to deck the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">halls</ENAMEX> as much as deck those responsible
for it" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Renee Graham</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boson Globe</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Home Improvement</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">heartthrob Jonathan Taylor Thomas</ENAMEX> plays a spoiled college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> who, after a hard
journey home for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the holidays</TIMEX>, sees the error of his ways. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Ebert</ENAMEX> calls it
"unrelentingly corny" ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Sun-Times</ENAMEX> ). (Visit the official site.)

            
               
                  I
Still Know What You Did <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last</TIMEX> Summer
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia Pictures</ENAMEX>). This sequel is
called "as uninspired as its title" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave Kehr</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily News</ENAMEX> ).
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scrubbed</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chipper</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer Love Hewitt</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> up with pop <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brandy</ENAMEX> to
battle the slicker-clad slasher they thought was killed in the original I
Know <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">What You Did Last Summer</ENAMEX> . <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Full</TIMEX> of cheap horror tricks and nowhere near
as good as its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">predecessor</ENAMEX>, the film is a "fairly silly and ultra-gory
schlocker/shocker" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Thomas</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> ). (Visit
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer Love</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hewitt Resource Center</ENAMEX>.)

            

               
                  Dancing at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lughnasa</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sony Pictures Classics</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meryl Streep</ENAMEX> wows
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>. This time her perfect accent is <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX>, the setting a depressed
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1930s</TIMEX>, and the story an adaptation of a stage play <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about five</TIMEX>
unmarried <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX>. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> complain that "for all the crinkle and lilt" of
the dialogue and the top-notch ensemble <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cast</ENAMEX>, the film "sags in the middle"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanley Kauffman</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maslin</ENAMEX> warns that the film is "a
collection of sea changes and splendidly realized small moments rather than a
story of overarching action." (Visit the official site.)

            

               Book
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fashionable Nonsense: Postmodern Intellectuals' Abuse of Science</ENAMEX>
               ,
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Sokal</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jean Bricmont</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Picador</ENAMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">perpetrator</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sokal</ENAMEX>'s Hoax
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> up with another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicist</ENAMEX> to debunk what they call "postmodern
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">relativism</ENAMEX>." Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> are gleeful. "Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sokal</ENAMEX> has delivered the coup de
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">grace</ENAMEX> : a book-length exposé of the scientific ignorance of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s science
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bashers"</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heather MacDonald</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> ). Others say the
book overreaches. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Book Review</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Holt</ENAMEX> compares
it to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> report--both share "a certain confusion about the gravity and
nature of the sins of their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">targets</ENAMEX>." (Read the rest of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holt</ENAMEX>'s review here. Requires free
registration.)

            

               Music
            

            

               
                  Spirit
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jewel</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Atlantic</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> are surprisingly positive
about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singer</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">songwriter</ENAMEX>/best-selling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX>/soon-to-be film <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX>' second
album after the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8 million</NUMEX> copy selling Pieces of You . Musically she has
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">matured</ENAMEX>, and her trademark folksy-bluesy-pop songs are dubbed "sweet, soulful"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Veronica Chambers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> ). The lyrics, however are said to be full
of hokey self-helpisms, and the album "overflows with advice intended to be
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">inspirational"</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jon Pareles</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ). (Buy the album online.)

            
               Recent
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment</ENAMEX>" columns
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Nov.</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie -- The
Siege ;

            

               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Waterboy</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- Velvet
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goldmine</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX>:
The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Invention of the Human</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harold Bloom</ENAMEX>;

            
               Music -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce</ENAMEX>
Springsteen: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tracks</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Springsteen</ENAMEX>;

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Opera</ENAMEX> -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Le Nozze di Figaro</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metropolitan Opera</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Nov.</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
History <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">X</NUMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carpenter</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vampires</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Life Is</ENAMEX>
Beautiful ;

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Living Out</ENAMEX>
Loud ;

            
               Art --"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pollock</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum of Modern Art</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>);

            

               Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- A Man in Full</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Wolfe</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">28:</TIMEX>

            

               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pleasantville</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- Apt
Pupil ;

            

               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Soldier</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX> of the
World: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Rise</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Muhammad Ali</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Remnick</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Evening</ENAMEX> ,
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Minot</ENAMEX>;

            

               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bech</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bay</ENAMEX>: A <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Quasi-Novel</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Updike</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">21:</TIMEX>

            

               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Beloved</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bride</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chucky</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Practical</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Magic</ENAMEX> ;

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> -- Corpus
Christi , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Terrence McNally</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Manhattan Theatre Club</ENAMEX>);

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Music -- Live:</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1966</TIMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dylan</ENAMEX>;

            

               Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- The Poisonwood Bible</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara Kingsolver</ENAMEX>.

            
               --Eliza Truitt
            

         
      
   
