
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Monica's Fast Track</ENAMEX>

            
               GET
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INTERNATIONAL</ENAMEX> PAPERS" BY E-MAIL!
            

            
               For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> and
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> delivery of this column, plus "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX>),
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pundit Central</ENAMEX>" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>), and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment"</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>),
click here. And
if you missed the most recent installments of this column, here they are:
posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, Oct. 23</TIMEX>, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Oct.</TIMEX>
20.
            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times of London</ENAMEX> reported on
its front page <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">that mere hours</TIMEX> after being introduced to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> was having "a sexual encounter" with her: "Those
who worked in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> were later astounded to learn the speed at which
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> first had sexual contact with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>." In a preview of a
TV profile titled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Full Monica</ENAMEX> to be shown on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Channel 5</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next Sunday</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> said she made eyes at him on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the second day</TIMEX> of
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 1995</TIMEX> government shutdown, when interns were given extra duties,
and that they met <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later the same day</TIMEX> at a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> birthday <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>. "At <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> that
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX> Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> beckoned her into a private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> and asked if he could
kiss her," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> went on. "She agreed. <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Two hours later</TIMEX>, he again asked her
to join him, and this time she performed a sexual act."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> said that
it was given access to material in a documentary by an award-winning <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> TV
producer, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony Geffen</ENAMEX>, whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> interviewing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> close to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>. It quoted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Morris</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s former special <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adviser</ENAMEX>, as
saying the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> strategy in dealing with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX> crisis was one of
"deceit, denial and delay. ... The poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> was like a ping-pong ball being
battered back and forth between these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> heavyweights [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kenneth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>], and I feel nothing but compassion for her. If she gets <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three million</NUMEX>
dollars, she deserves <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> for what she's been through."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX>
reportedly said he doesn't believe <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> will impeach the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> for
lying under oath about his relationship with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>, "but they might well
impeach him if evidence comes forward from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>, of
private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">detectives scurrilously</ENAMEX>, sometimes illegally, perhaps under physical
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">intimidation</ENAMEX>, working on stopping these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> from telling the truth. That
could really revolt the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> as, frankly, it does me, and that might
cause him more serious trouble than sex ever did."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> press was split over <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin Netanyahu</ENAMEX>'s chances of getting the support of his government
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wye</ENAMEX> agreement. The liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ha'aretz</ENAMEX> led its front page
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> with the headline "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">PM Facing Tougher Fight Than Expected</ENAMEX>." Having spoken
with several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ministers</ENAMEX> on the phone, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX> has discovered that the
opposition to the agreement is much broader than he thought it would be. The
conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , on the other hand, reported that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX> was confident he could
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sell</ENAMEX> the agreement to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">right-wing critics</ENAMEX>.

            In an editorial titled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Time</ENAMEX>
Out for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trust</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ha'aretz</ENAMEX> said the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> "deserves, at this
stage, a certain grace period to demonstrate to the world that it is capable
both of meeting its commitments and [of] effectively dealing with the radical
right over this highly problematic issue." For the time being, it added, "[t]he
opposition would be well advised to hold off its support for elections." In an
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> titled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Inexcusable</ENAMEX>" in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jerusalem Post</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aaron Lerner</ENAMEX>
condemned the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wye</ENAMEX> agreement as forfeiting <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>'s right to determine
independently whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX> are keeping their part of the
bargain.

            In an
editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>, Le
Monde of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> said that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX>'s readiness to sabotage the negotiations
by demanding the release of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Pollard</ENAMEX> "augurs badly for the application"
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wye</ENAMEX> agreement. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said that the progress made was "still
better than the status quo, which <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> seemed more and more to resemble a
war in disguise."

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bangkok</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nation</ENAMEX> reported <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Friday</TIMEX>
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Thai</ENAMEX> film <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> has recommended that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anna</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">King</ENAMEX> , a new
version of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The King</ENAMEX> and I starring <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jodie Foster</ENAMEX>, not be filmed in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Thailand</ENAMEX> because it would violate the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s lèse-majesté law. This law can
result in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> sentences of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">up to seven years</TIMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who commit acts
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">injurious</ENAMEX> to the reputation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Thai</ENAMEX> monarchy. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rupert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th Century Fox</ENAMEX> could face another controversy over its
application to film <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Beach</ENAMEX> , starring <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leonardo DiCaprio</ENAMEX>, on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Phi Phi</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Island</ENAMEX>. "It has told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royal Forestry Department</ENAMEX> that it would plant <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">some 100</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">coconut trees</ENAMEX> on the national <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> island for the filming," <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">the Nation</ENAMEX>
said.

            In
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>, the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Der Spiegel</ENAMEX> revealed that unpublished films
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adolf Hitler</ENAMEX> have surfaced in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. It said that color films of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> shot by his chief <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilot</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hans Baur</ENAMEX>, who buried them in a garden in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Munich</ENAMEX> toward the end of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX>, were found by an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sergeant</ENAMEX>, who
has kept them in his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past 50 years</TIMEX>.

         
      
   
