
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Matthew</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Newspapers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>
are up in arms <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> over the murder of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew Shepard</ENAMEX>, a gay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> at
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Wyoming</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> straight <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> lured <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shepard</ENAMEX> from a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX>, robbed
him, beat him savagely, and left him for dead. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, according to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern Poverty Law Center</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> were killed for being gay. You've
probably never heard about any of them, but <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> you've heard about
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shepard</ENAMEX>. Consequently, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> who ignored anti-gay violence for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> are
suddenly demanding hate crimes legislation in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shepard</ENAMEX>'s name. How come?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shepard</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">martyrdom</ENAMEX> is in part a function of timing. He received his fatal beating just
before <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">National Coming Out Day</ENAMEX>, for which gay rights <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> had already planned
rallies and media events. His death gave those events a unifying theme and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">icon</ENAMEX>. Furthermore, after the beating, he lay in a coma for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several days</TIMEX>,
allowing media interest to build. By the time he died, everyone with a TV set
had heard of him.

            But the decisive factor in the explosion of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shepard</ENAMEX>
story is the manner of his death. "At first, the passing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bicyclist</ENAMEX> thought the
crumpled form lashed to a ranch <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">fence</ENAMEX> was a scarecrow," began the initial
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> dispatch. The dangling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figure</ENAMEX> turned out to be "the
burned, battered and nearly lifeless <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX>" of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shepard</ENAMEX>, "who had been tied to
the fence <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">18 hours earlier</TIMEX>." According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assailants</ENAMEX> had
"tied their captive to a post-and-rail <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">fence</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pistol</ENAMEX>-whipped him," then
"stole his wallet and shoes and left him tied to the fence." The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> reported that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shepard</ENAMEX> was "strung up on a fence to die in a grotesque
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tableau</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> said he had been "tortured with
cigarette burns." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Tribune</ENAMEX> said "he was pistol-whipped,
strung up spread-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">eagle</ENAMEX>," and "remained there for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">18 hours</TIMEX> in near-freezing
weather--looking like a scarecrow."

            The image
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shepard</ENAMEX> dangling from the fence, still alive and bleeding, evokes two
familiar images. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX>, played up by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> , is the
"compelling image" of "the black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figure</ENAMEX> at the end of a lynch rope, hanging
from a <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberal columnists</ENAMEX> have already
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">likened Shepard</ENAMEX>'s death to that of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Byrd</ENAMEX>, the black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who was dragged to
his death by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> in a pickup <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this year</TIMEX>.

            
The other image is that of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> on the cross.
"There is incredible symbolism about being tied to a fence," one gay activist
told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> . "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> have likened it to a scarecrow. But it sounded
more like a crucifixion." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>'s descriptions of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shepard</ENAMEX> reinforce this
comparison. "His <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">105-pound</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">5-foot-2</NUMEX> body" was said to be "frail and lifeless."
He was "slight of stature, gentle of demeanor and passionate about human
rights," according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> . In life, he had "seemed bright and open
and full of promise." After his death, his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> insisted that he wouldn't
have wanted his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wyoming</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> to be blamed. A fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> mused, "I think
about him out there, tied to a fence for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">18 or 20 hours</TIMEX>--what was going through
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>?"

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shepard</ENAMEX>'s death arrives in
the midst of a battle for public opinion between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gays</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> are struggling to defend <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> arguments. One is
that being gay is different from being black and less worthy of legal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">protection</ENAMEX>. The other is that homosexuality is an affront to morality,
specifically to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> virtue. As a lynching--and as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">crucifixion</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shepard</ENAMEX>'s death devastates both arguments. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anti-gay</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>"
such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Majority Leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Lott</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miss.</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Majority Leader</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Armey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>, are "legitimizing the sort of hate that left <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shepard</ENAMEX> tied to a fence and near death, lynched on account of being gay," says
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Cohen</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Family Research Council</ENAMEX>, by
"demonizing" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gays</ENAMEX>, contributed to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shepard</ENAMEX>'s death while hypocritically invoking
the name of "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus Christ</ENAMEX>," writes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rich</ENAMEX>.

            The day
after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shepard</ENAMEX> succumbed to his wounds, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Terrence McNally</ENAMEX>'s play Corpus
Christi opened on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX>. Outside the theater, religious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX>
assembled to protest the play, which, as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> noted, revolves
around "a gay <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christ</ENAMEX>-like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figure</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protesters</ENAMEX> are missing the point. The
principal long-term threat that has arisen <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> to the stigma against
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">homosexuality</ENAMEX> isn't the depiction of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> as a gay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>. It's the depiction of
a gay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX>.

            
               Recent
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Frame Games</ENAMEX>"
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tainted Jury":</ENAMEX>
Forget tampering, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s impeachment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX> would be struck for cause.
(posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday, Oct. 14, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            "Reverse
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Triangulation</ENAMEX>": How <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s immoderation helps the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> look
moderate. (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday, Oct. 7, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Nixon Analogy":</ENAMEX>
Why the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Flytrap-Watergate</ENAMEX> comparison will backfire. (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, Oct. 2</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>)
            

         
      
   
