
   
   
      
         
            A Question for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Starr</ENAMEX>

            When <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Independent Counsel</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX> testifies before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Judiciary Committee</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> could surprise everyone and accomplish something tangible in the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> minute. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Hyde</ENAMEX>--or, as is more likely, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> member
from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> side--should ask him the following:

            "Mr.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>, I want to give you a chance to clear your name on the serious accusation
made against you by the judge presiding over your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">grand jury</ENAMEX>. As you know,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norma Holloway Johnson</ENAMEX> has ruled that there is a prima facie case that
you or your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> illegally leaked information to the press in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX> instances
involving <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> different news <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>, and you have filed a sworn affidavit
denying those leaks. You have maintained that any communications from you or
your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">deputy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackie Bennett</ENAMEX>--who has been identified as your conduit to the
press--were completely proper. You've argued strenuously that neither you nor
Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX> released any information pertaining to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">grand jury</ENAMEX> proceedings.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">W</ENAMEX>"e all appreciate the need for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> to
keep their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> of information confidential if they have promised
confidentiality. But news <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> are free to release <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> from this
obligation, and that is what I am asking you to do today. "

            So,
would you be willing, right here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, under oath, to tell all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">producers</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> for each of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> news <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> with whom you or
Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX> are alleged to have spoken that you hereby release them from any
promises they or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> working with them made to you or to Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX> to keep
any communications between them and you confidential? And will you, right here,
right now, direct Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX> to release them from any such promises made to
him?

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Finally</ENAMEX>, I would like your assurance, under
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">oath</ENAMEX>, that neither you nor Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX> have ever discussed with these reporters
how they might protect your confidentiality even if you did have to release
them publicly from any promises. This way, these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> could be asked
exactly what Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX> and you told them and they could answer honestly
without violating any pledges of confidentiality.

            "If
you've been unfairly accused, as you insist, sir, you should want these
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> to talk freely and honestly about what you and Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX> did or did
not tell them. And, of course, if you never leaked anything illegally to them
and never swore them to confidentiality, there is no harm in releasing them
from a promise they never made."

            
If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> hems and haws (or refuses to address
the pivotal question of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX>), we'll know that he and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX> are not
willing to put their denials to the test. If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> agrees and is willing to
follow up with a letter to these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX>--or the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigator</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> has appointed to find out about the leaks--could then question
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX>. The questioning would not be the kind of "who were your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>"
fishing expedition that should trouble anyone who worries about a free <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX>.
Rather, the only question would be "What did Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX> and Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> tell you
in connection with each of these stories?"

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX> have
repeatedly claimed that they have nothing to worry about if these or any other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> reveal their conversations.

            This would be a quick,
simple, and (unless <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX> are lying) harmless way to settle a
troublesome issue.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Brill</ENAMEX>
responds to a flood of anonymous e-mail generated by this piece in "E-Mail to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Editors</ENAMEX>."
            

         
      
   
