
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Address your e-mail to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. All <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> must include their address and
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone number (for confirmation only).
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Affirmative Action Wars, Part 38</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judith</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shulevitz</ENAMEX>'s argument in "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Affirmative Action Wars, Part 37</ENAMEX>" is beside the point. Of course,
it is wonderful and advantageous to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX>, just as it would be
wonderful and advantageous to have an internship with a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nobel</ENAMEX> Prize-winning
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> or, for that matter, your own private <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX>. Does that mean <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> who
do not get such internships or their own <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX> are disadvantaged enough to
need them given out by governmental or university administrative decree? Of
course not. Yes, if your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> are best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nobel Prize winners or</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rich</ENAMEX> enough to give you a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> you will have an advantage in procuring these
things. That's life. For the most part, those who really want these things must
earn them. Giving them to some by decree is worse than unfair; it is ultimately
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">corrupting</ENAMEX> to the whole ethic of achievement. It subjects those who get these
things unfairly to widespread suspicion of their own abilities and spreads a
damaging cynicism throughout the culture. In place of a flawed value system of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">achievement</ENAMEX>, it puts an inherently damaging system of victimhood. The point
about the successful minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> who go to lesser <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX> is that,
like the rest of us who don't get the chance to attend <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX>, they have the
opportunity to earn success honestly: They are not shut out.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ladenson Philadelphia</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judith</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shulevitz</ENAMEX> replies:
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Ladenson</ENAMEX> makes
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> classic anti-affirmative-action arguments in his letter: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) It's unfair to
change the rules so that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> can go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) affirmative action
produces a sense of inferiority and insecurity in those it causes to be
admitted.
            

            
               Point <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ladenson</ENAMEX> would
have a much stronger case if <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX> used a single
announced criterion for admission and never varied from it, the way New York
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">City</ENAMEX>'s two true meritocracies, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bronx</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School of Science and Stuyvesant High</ENAMEX>
School, do--they only admit <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> who score well on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bronx</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Science's</ENAMEX> or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stuyvesant</ENAMEX>'s own tests. Then, sure, it would be a flagrant violation of the
rules to let in some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> who didn't meet that standard. But I have
never heard of a single <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> or university judging its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> on the
basis of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> simple, straightforward, and publicly stated criterion. Instead,
college admissions procedures are made up of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of subjective judgments. At
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX>, for instance, there are probably <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">applicants</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> who are
so outstanding there's no question they'll get in. But there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">another 10,000</NUMEX>
who are all good but not quite as great. How will the admissions <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> select
from that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> to fill its remaining <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,000</NUMEX> places? On the basis of any number
of things: <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SAT</ENAMEX> scores and grades, of course--but also how well an essay was
written; how much and what kind of volunteer work was done; notable athletic or
artistic ability; a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> for geographic diversity; recommendations; or the
most entrenched affirmative action program around, whether an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">applicant</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> went to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Ladenson</ENAMEX> assumes that there's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> standard applied
across the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> to everybody except for black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>, and that just isn't
true,
            

            
               Point
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>: As I've argued above, unless you've written a symphony that was performed by
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> Philharmonic by the time you're <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX>, getting into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX> is
something of a crapshoot. Everyone there knows it, and they don't let it make
them insecure. They accept their luck and get on with their lives. Do the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alumni</ENAMEX> feel insecure because the standards used to evaluate
their applications were significantly different (and lower) than those used for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nonalumnae</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>? Ask <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>. Being
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alumnus</ENAMEX> and then getting into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX> himself does not
seem to have made a shrinking violet out of him.
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Feminism</ENAMEX>'s Fetishes
            

            I commend
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judith Shulevitz</ENAMEX> on an excellent column, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Don't Take It So</ENAMEX>
Personally." Her recognition of the grave personal injustice done by the
left to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarence Thomas</ENAMEX> is especially appreciated. It took intellectual courage
to arrive at this conclusion. I hope others will follow you.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Horowitz</ENAMEX> Los
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles</ENAMEX>

            
               Art
Salesmanship
            

            Your measurement in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weisberg</ENAMEX>'s "The 
                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arts</ENAMEX> Index" appears to
be a well-intended method for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> comparisons. However, I am just a little
disappointed that there is no representation in your measurement for popular
music. Call me old-fashioned for caring, but increased popular music
sales typically lead to increased classical or jazz music sales,
due mainly to the effect of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> feeling compelled to enter a music <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> and
look around to see what's new since they were there to buy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thriller</ENAMEX> , or
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Titanic</ENAMEX> soundtrack, or whatever got them in the door the last
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>.

            This is no secret to music
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX>. In the online biz we compete for "eyeballs," but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> need
"footheels" or "toetouches." And, importantly, we can easily determine how much
recorded music is sold at retail from readily available <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>.

            Assigning
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> of index "points" to compare higher or lower music sales at retail
might be deserved and appropriate to measuring the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of the arts.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael P.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patrick</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX>

            
               Rock the
Arts
            

            A quick
run through the high culture jungle of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Weisberg</ENAMEX>'s "The

                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arts</ENAMEX> Index" left me a bit baffled. Why is it that in the
discussion of film the percentage of dollars allocated to independent films was
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">noteworthy</ENAMEX>, but the same wasn't true of music? Or, put another way, why would,
say, a ticket stub to the rockumentary Hype be arts-index-worthy, but
purchasing the soundtrack would not? If 
                  Slate
                wants to be an
alternative to the mass of media, why let the mass of media (in low or high
cultures) dictate the terms? Because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sub Pop</ENAMEX>--in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> quasi-independent case--is
not opera or jazz should be all the more reason for your paying attention.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lance</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Davis Tuscaloosa</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ala.</ENAMEX>

            

               Knowledge <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Is Power</ENAMEX>
            

            I have
just been reading the dialogue on public figures' private lives. I agree with
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> whose <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 1</TIMEX> letter to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Trapped in Monicagate</ENAMEX>,"
suggested that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who say "enough with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX> already" but then read
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX> coverage may be canny rather than hypocritical. The potential outcome
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX> is the impeachment and removal of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>. Do I think the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> have over-covered <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flytrap</ENAMEX>, helping to create the
crisis they report? Yes. Do I think I'd be happy pretending this crisis isn't
happening, allowing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> whose views differ from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX> to have more
information than I have? Not a chance. Remember, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Cardinal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newman</ENAMEX> said,
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Knowledge</ENAMEX> is power." While I disagreed with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Judiciary Committee</ENAMEX>'s
decision to release the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s videotaped testimony before even asking the
questions "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Will</ENAMEX> there be hearings?" and "What's an impeachable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offense</ENAMEX>?" I
watched the tape so that I could understand the spin from both sides and make
up my own mind. I don't think that's hypocritical; I think that's good
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">citizenship</ENAMEX>.

            -- Jen
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Shelton Huntington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">W.Va.</ENAMEX>

            
               Some
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Feature Called "Today's Papers</ENAMEX>"
            

            I commend
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 1</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX> for inserting some fun in the news with the comment
about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carleton College</ENAMEX>. The disclaimer and explanation in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next day</TIMEX>'s
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Papers</ENAMEX> made what was written <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day before</TIMEX> even
more humorous and fun for this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX>. Keep up the good work.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sharon</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson-Cramer Boston</ENAMEX>

            
               No
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amnesty</ENAMEX> for Shuger
            

            So
despite <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amnesty International</ENAMEX>'s reputation and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30 years</TIMEX> experience in human
rights investigations, the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 5</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX> doesn't take it seriously. Why? Because its director
comes from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Senegal</ENAMEX>. So much for objectivity.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerry</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ellis London</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scott</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shuger</ENAMEX> replies:
            

            
               My
question, "Where would you rather be arrested--in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Senegal</ENAMEX>?" was
raised not as an ad hominem assessment of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amnesty International</ENAMEX> report, but
in response to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amnesty honcho</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Senegal</ENAMEX>'s comment that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> criminal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">justice</ENAMEX> system lagged in fairness behind (someplace he called) the world
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">community</ENAMEX>. Yes, there are problems with our system, and yes, there are some
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> that could teach us a thing or two about them. But my point was I
don't believe <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who say most <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> could--because they wouldn't prefer
to be arrested, imprisoned, tried, or sentenced in most <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>.
            

            
               Address
your e-mail to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. All <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> must include their address and
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> phone number (for confirmation only).
            

         
      
   
