
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">144</NUMEX>:

            By <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cohen</ENAMEX>

            
               A major
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporation</ENAMEX> will spend <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$200 million</NUMEX> to install
customer-friendly equipment, including small, mobile, battery-powered <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">podiums</ENAMEX>.
What are the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">podiums</ENAMEX> for?
            

            by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon ET</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> to e-mail your answer to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.

            
               Responses
to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s question (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 143</ENAMEX>), "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A and Q: Bite the Hand That Fed Michael</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis"</ENAMEX>--
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX>' answer was
"I don't know what you mean 'concerned.' " What was the question?
            

            "Are the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ActiveX</ENAMEX> data
objects of a frequency-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">division</ENAMEX> multiplexing DDR SDRAM with full <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">duplex</ENAMEX> VRML
granularity hashing and an <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MVS IA-64</ENAMEX> chip concerned with narrow-band,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">random-access Winsock</ENAMEX> functionality?"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Radosh</ENAMEX>
            

            "Do you understand that
some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spectators</ENAMEX> may be concerned by your nudity in the courtroom
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>?"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Noah Meyerson</ENAMEX>
            

            "Can you give an example
of a sentence that does not contain a preposition?"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer Miller</ENAMEX>
( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tamara Glenny</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doug Ingram</ENAMEX> had similar answers.)

            "Is it true you said of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Barksdale</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marc Andreessen</ENAMEX>, in an inexplicably <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> locution, 'I
don't ever want to hear that those c**<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">ts</ENAMEX> earned <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">one sodding shilling</NUMEX> off their
bloody <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">browser</ENAMEX>'<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>"-- HapppyJack
            

            "He was evading a question
about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Universal</ENAMEX>'s troubled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Babe: Pig in the City</ENAMEX> . He's under oath. It's
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '90s</TIMEX>. They can ask you anything."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Kelly</ENAMEX>
            

            Click for more
responses.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
            

            There is a
kind of pseudo-rebelliousness when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">ant mocks the elephant</ENAMEX>, particularly
when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">ant</ENAMEX> works for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">elephant</ENAMEX> in some insect-sized capacity. But before
things get overly <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aesopian</ENAMEX> (too late for that, you old <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fool</ENAMEX>!) let me tell you a
story about some real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. (Oh no, not another of his tedious stories!) So
you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> stop doing that to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> and listen closely. For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> after
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Electric</ENAMEX> bought <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Letterman</ENAMEX> mocked his new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bosses</ENAMEX> as "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GE</ENAMEX>
pinheads," and all the little <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">ants</ENAMEX> who wrote for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave</ENAMEX> felt sassy and bold. (You
said no <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX>!) A <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">short time</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later</TIMEX>, at the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Late Night</ENAMEX> anniversary
party, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Welch</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GE</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Wright</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">grinned</ENAMEX> and guffawed and slapped <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave</ENAMEX> on the back. "We love it when you call us
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GE</ENAMEX> pinheads!" said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Welch</ENAMEX>. "We get such a kick out that!" said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wright</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave</ENAMEX>
looked embarrassed, as he so often does, for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Welch</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wright</ENAMEX> had taught him a
lesson: When you mock them on television, you don't threaten them; you humanize
them. What sports! They can take a joke! It's the court <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jester</ENAMEX> lesson. And if
you want to know more about it, stop by and talk to me down at the unemployment
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>.

            
               Question
Answer
            

            What non-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> browsers
were you concerned about in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January of 1996</TIMEX>?

            Asked
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> in court by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Boies</ENAMEX>.

            
               Epithet
Extra--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Four Animals</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> Nothings
            

            Match each
metaphor with the object of its scorn.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mad dog</ENAMEX>"

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. "injured lion"

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. "chicken"

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fox</ENAMEX> in the henhouse"

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. "black hole"

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>.
"void"

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">A. Richard Butler</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> weapons inspection <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX>, says the headline in some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B. Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX>, says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ali</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">al-Ali</ENAMEX>, some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kuwaiti</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">C.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, says
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Samir al-Eisa</ENAMEX>, some other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kuwaiti</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D. Barnes & Noble</ENAMEX>'s
ownership of book distributor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ingram</ENAMEX>, says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Avin Domnitz</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Booksellers Association</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">E. Livent</ENAMEX>, the financially
troubled <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX> theater <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> controlled by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Ovitz</ENAMEX>, says <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Breglio</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">F. Data</ENAMEX>
collection on bus accidents, says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Hall</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of the National
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Transportation Safety Board</ENAMEX>.

            

               Answers
            

            
               1A, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2B</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3C</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4D</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5E</TIMEX>,
6F.
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Disclaimer</ENAMEX>: All submissions will become the property of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> and
will be published at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> 's discretion. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> may publish your
name on its site in connection with your submission.
            

         
      
   
