
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Drawing upon her rich
experience of life, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> to her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>) responds to questions
about manners, personal relations, politics, and other subjects. Please send
your questions for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> to prudence@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Queries should not exceed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> words in
length. Please indicate how you wish your letter to be signed, preferably
including your location.
            

            
               
                  Dear
Prudie,
               
            

            
               My
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX> is intelligent, attractive, and affectionate. Maybe too
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">affectionate</ENAMEX>. When we're eating in public she likes to play footsie under the
table. That would be OK--I enjoy playing footsie--but she likes to tease me by
digging her heel into my bare toes (I usually wear sandals), often when I'm
ordering. She then watches me squirm to appear nonchalant in front of our
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">server</ENAMEX>. My question is this: How do I gently ask her to "play nice" without
hurting her feelings?
            

            
               --Ouch! That
Hurts!
            

            Dear
Ouch!

            Without hurting her
feelings? It sounds to Prudie like your dominatrix <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">passive</ENAMEX>-aggressive, with only a tiny quotient of the passive.

            Prudie
does not like to be bossy, but she strongly suggests you do the following,
since she divines you are not going to change your shoes. Next time Miss
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Intelligent</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Attractive</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Affectionate</ENAMEX> decides to stab you with her heel,
scream bloody murder--and don't hold back. You will attract momentary attention
from the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">diners</ENAMEX>, but it will be worth it. (This maneuver is called
sending her neurosis back to her.) If the darling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> asks why you have never
hollered before, simply tell her you were not interested in playing her games,
but now you are.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, poetically

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dearest Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               How may
a proper <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> handle the delicate matter of bad breath when happenstance
forces one into consulting with someone on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>? I don't mean to be
indelicate, but "retching" was very close at hand when that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> talked.
Prudie, this vile odor was beyond belief!
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dorothy S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shreveport</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">La.</ENAMEX>
            

            Dear
Dor,

            Prudie, too, has lived
through this a few times. What she has done is try to seem casual and arrange
her hand so it covers her nose. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> wants to be helpful and alert the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>,
but it is a very difficult thing to do.

            If it is
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than a</NUMEX> passing acquaintance, you might want to risk the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s
embarrassment in order to be helpful, with a remark something like "I hope you
don't take offense, but I feel sure you would want to know that, somehow, your
breath has turned sour," or "your lunch is lingering," or whatever you are
comfortable saying. Granted, it is easier to get away quickly and say
nothing.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, breathlessly

            
               
                  Dear
Prudie,
               
            

            
               Recently you published a
letter asking if you must use skills not in your job description
just because you have them. This is in fact a legal question. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>, for
an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX> of a private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, absent contractual provisions to the
contrary, the answer would be a resounding yes. Not only can <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> ask,
they can require it; and if you refuse more than once to do something your
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">employer</ENAMEX> has asked just because nobody put it in your job description, you
might even be denied unemployment benefits when they fire you.
            

            
               In my experience,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> tend to be relatively uninterested in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> whining about what
someone else should be doing. In the case of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fellow</ENAMEX> who wrote, I would give
priority to my own work but help out to the extent that I could without
neglecting my tasks. It is generally safe to check what the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> wants.
            

            
               This
is not legal advice, do not rely upon it. If you have a problem seek the advice
of an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX>, usual disclaimers, etc., etc.
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AEG</ENAMEX>
            

            Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AE</ENAMEX>,

            Thank you
for your expertise about employment law, at least in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>. The wild card
you may have overlooked is that our computer-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert correspondent</ENAMEX> was not being
asked by his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> to help everybody. Instead, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-workers</ENAMEX> themselves were
falling on his neck seeking help. In addition to job description issues, our
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> was trying to determine where good-guyness intersected with doormathood.
And you raise a pertinent point for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX>: She is not practicing either
law or psychological counseling. She is merely advising 
                  Slate
               
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> who want an outside, unbiased opinion from one of Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kinsley</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">minions</ENAMEX>.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>,
nonprofessionally

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               I am a big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> of your
column and, generally speaking, a supporter of the "always leave 'em wanting
more" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> of thought regarding <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">product</ENAMEX> such as yours. However, while I am
admit I am somewhat underwhelmed by the quantity of your output. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Four</NUMEX>
letters once a week? (Or thereabouts.) That's it?

            
               It's
not as if you were being printed on a paper medium of limited dimension, where
space issues would be an important consideration. In the realm of cybermedia,
you have unlimited space in which to work--yet you limit yourself. I ask that
you consider expanding the scope of your pleasant <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palaver</ENAMEX>, to the enrichment of
us all. After all, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ann Landers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abby</ENAMEX> give it to us <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> with no
diminution of quality or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> interest. You are no less than they.
            

            
               --Sign me, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wanting More</ENAMEX>
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rosamond</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX>
            

            Dear
Want,

            You are
kind to want to see All Prudie All the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>, but 
                  Slate
                is a
banquet table of offerings. We would not want to overdose on the problems of

                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>, would we? As for your reference to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ann Landers</ENAMEX> and
her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> has particular regard for Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Landers</ENAMEX>, and delights in the
observation of many that she resembles her ... though <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, of course, is
somewhat younger.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>,
appreciatively

         
      
   
