
   
   
      
         
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slate Sincerely Flattered</ENAMEX>
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time magazine</ENAMEX>, we
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">notice</ENAMEX>, seems to have started a new feature called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Dear Dr. Notebook</ENAMEX>," which
poses and answers questions that arise from the current news. We can't help
sensing a family resemblance to 
                  Slate
               's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months-old</TIMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Explainer"</ENAMEX> column,
which ... well, poses and answers questions that arise from the current news.
There are differences, of course. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> , as a serious newsmagazine, deals
with issues such as: Why are there <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> masks for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Halloween</TIMEX> but no <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>
masks? Or: How do you clean a mirror-studded leather dress like the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> Prada
showed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milan</ENAMEX>? 
                  Slate
               , by contrast, as a frivolous,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">attitude-besotted Webzine</ENAMEX>, asks (and answers): How does the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> situation
compare with the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX>? Or: What's the difference among all these
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Broder</ENAMEX>?

            Turning
the page in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> , we came across another newish feature called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"News</ENAMEX>
Quiz"--not to be confused with a 
                  Slate
                feature of the same name
started <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several months earlier</TIMEX>. There is nothing proprietary about the name
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">News Quiz</ENAMEX>," of course--and we would not insult the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> of

                  Slate
               's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">News Quiz</ENAMEX>" by suggesting that there is any similarity
between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Quiz</ENAMEX> and the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy Cohen</ENAMEX> produces for us. But it
is remarkable that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> should have gone <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">almost 75 years</TIMEX> without a news
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">quiz</ENAMEX>, only to start <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> shortly after 
                  Slate
                did.

            Brooding about all this, we flung away <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">irritation</ENAMEX> and picked up <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> . The No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> newsmagazine, we noticed,
also has a new front-of-the-book feature, euphoniously titled "The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buzz-O-Meter</ENAMEX>." The gimmick seems to be that you take an issue in the news and
list the various "buzzes" on it--"buzz" No. 2 perhaps contradicting "buzz" No.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> in some ironic or amusing way, "buzz" Nos. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3 and 4</NUMEX> peeling additional layers
off the onion of perception, and so on. Could this, we wondered, possibly be an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hommage</ENAMEX> to the strangely similar technique invented by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Saletan</ENAMEX>
for 
                  Slate
               's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Week/The Spin"</ENAMEX>? Was there a lavish banquet
ceremony of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">thanksgiving</ENAMEX> and celebration of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Will</ENAMEX>'s achievements to which we
misplaced our invitation?

            We
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">consulted Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Ballmer</ENAMEX>, on what, if anything, we
should do about all this. He replied, with simple eloquence, "Have them
killed." But he quickly added, "Unless, of course, that would in any way
violate the antitrust laws."

            
               My Name
Is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael</ENAMEX>, and I'm a 'Scapoholic
            

            Speaking
of the antitrust laws, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> who have been enjoying <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Lewis</ENAMEX>'
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dispatches</ENAMEX>" from the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courtroom</ENAMEX> where government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> are attempting the
most brazen legal challenge to human progress since the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scopes</ENAMEX> Trial should be
aware of the following: Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX>' views do not necessarily reflect those of

                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">magazine</ENAMEX>, its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX>, or its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">advertisers</ENAMEX>. Especially its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX>'. In fact, we were sitting around <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX> trying to recall whose
stupid idea it was to hire <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Lewis</ENAMEX>, a known Netscape <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user</ENAMEX>--sometimes
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>, or more times <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a day</TIMEX>; the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> clearly belongs in Netscape
Anonymous--to cover an event as complex and vital to civilization's future as
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> trial. Oddly enough, no 
                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> could recall
making this tawdry assignment. Nor does anyone recall telling Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> that he
was free to express his views whatever they may be, no matter how fatuous or
uninformed by the slightest understanding of the free enterprise system, and
without considering for a moment that 
                  Slate
                is owned by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>
and that some of its staff <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> have young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and very little talent
that would make us employable at a less saintlike, public-spirited, and
compassionate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>. No one admits to having said to him, "Let the microchips
fall where they may." In fact, no one can recall ever exchanging a word with
Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> before his absurd reports began appearing on our site. He must have
just hacked his way in.

            
               E-Mail
Bonding
            

            
               
                  Slate
               's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> new
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every-weekday</TIMEX> e-mail deliveries are up and running and available as another
free service to 
                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subscribers</ENAMEX>. "
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate Afternoon</ENAMEX>
Delivery " includes some of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>'s updates of 
                  Slate
                news
and business <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">departments</ENAMEX> such as "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Moneybox</ENAMEX>" and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Frame Game</ENAMEX>," along with

                  Slate
               's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> (unlike some rival news quizzes we could
name) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Quiz</ENAMEX>. "
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate Evening Delivery</ENAMEX> " is a selection from

                  Slate
               's cultural reviews and reportage. Each item in both of
these new deliveries is personally selected for you by 
                  Slate
               
Deputy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Editor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Shafer</ENAMEX>, plucked at its very peak of ripeness, and e-mailed
to you so fresh it gleams. (No waiting around for stale, shopworn news and
reviews to be delivered once a week and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> late by certain newsmagazines we
don't care to mention.)

            Click here to sign up
for any or all of 
                  Slate
               's e-mail services, including
"
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Slate Morning Delivery "</ENAMEX> (with "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>"); our weekly
print-out edition, 
                  Slate 
                  on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paper</ENAMEX>
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">;</ENAMEX> or our weekly listing
and description of what's new in 
                  Slate
               . Or, if you haven't yet
done so, click here to subscribe to 
                  Slate
               .

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
