
   
   
      
         
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX>
            

            

               
                  Slate
               's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thanksgiving</TIMEX> schedule: Our weekly text file, 
                  Slate
on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paper</ENAMEX>
               , will be in your e-mail
in-box or available for download <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two days early</TIMEX>, around <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">midday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>. A nearly full
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>'s worth of 
                  Slate
                will also be posted online <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>. After
that it gets pretty quiet around here, but check in throughout <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the long</TIMEX> weekend
for "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" and in case <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> has a postprandial thought or
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>.

            

               Fixings
            

            "So," we e-mailed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven</ENAMEX>
Brill, "did they ask your question?" In 
                  Slate
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founder</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> in chief of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brill</ENAMEX>'s Content proposed a killer question
for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Judiciary Committee</ENAMEX> to ask <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>. The question, which
actually was a long series of questions, boiled down to: "Will you waive any
privileges you have so we can get to the bottom of whether your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> has been
illegally leaking to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX>?" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brill</ENAMEX> replied that several <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> had asked
the question, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> had refused to answer on the grounds that a federal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> had ordered the investigation of these leaks to be kept confidential.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brill</ENAMEX> noted that this order for confidentiality had been requested by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>
himself.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brill</ENAMEX>'s
question could have been a lot simpler. It could have been something like:
"Have you or anyone in your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> leaked information from grand jury testimony
to the press--before or after the testimony was given?" As any newspaper reader
knows, the correct answer to this question is obviously yes. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> couldn't
say yes because he's said variations on no for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> and would be conceding a
public lie. Is this beginning to sound familiar?

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brill</ENAMEX> didn't do it the easy way for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> good
reasons. First, he is admirably opposed to perjury traps, and therefore he
didn't want to be seen as proposing a tooth for a tooth. And in fact he did not
propose one: His question involved stripping away <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s protections against
the truth, not forcing him to repeat the lie under solemn oath. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brill</ENAMEX>,
as a media philosopher, is understandably queasy about using the law to "out"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX>' confidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>. He has an explanation of why it's OK in this
case, but his queasiness <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">moderates</ENAMEX> his delight at putting the screws on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>
the way <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> put them on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>.

            But let
us rise above high-mindedness for a moment. The symmetry between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s case
against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and the case against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> himself is so striking that it would
seem heavy-handed in the plot of an opera. The general <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">arc</ENAMEX> of self-destruction
is the same: Like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> did something wrong but not fatally wrong.
Then he issued a mixture of lies and weasels about it, making it virtually
impossible for him to give an honest answer if asked a straightforward
question. That gave his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX> a way to trap him into an undeniably serious
crime: perjury under oath in an investigation of alleged high crimes by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. In both cases, the investigation itself would
produce the crime.

            Many details are also eerily similar:

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s leaks pretty clearly
violated the federal rules of criminal procedure, just as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s lies in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> deposition pretty clearly violated the perjury laws. But neither
the rules nor the laws are usually enforced in circumstances like these.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prosecutors</ENAMEX> leak all the time.

            As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brill</ENAMEX> points out in the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX> issue of his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s weasels <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">laughably</ENAMEX> echo <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has said oral sex doesn't count. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> has said that leaking grand jury
testimony before it's actually delivered doesn't count.

            Both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> skillfully make
their weasels do double duty: keeping them kosher on a technicality and
misleading the public about the actual facts. Is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> saying he didn't
commit perjury because of the peculiar definition of sex in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paula Jones</ENAMEX>
suit, or is he saying he actually didn't have sex? Is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> saying he didn't
violate the criminal procedure rules because he doesn't believe they apply to
pre-testimony leaks, or is he saying he actually didn't leak? The answer is yes
to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all four</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> has been especially squirmy about this. He has made his
pre-testimony-leaks-don't-apply argument in sealed court papers and also has
publicly denied believing anything so foolish, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brill</ENAMEX> points out.

            Like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> has used
nonexistent or self-imposed secrecy requirements to avoid answering troublesome
questions. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> invoked grand jury secrecy, though you are always free to
reveal your own testimony. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>, as noted, asked for the leak investigation to
be put under seal, then publicly regretted his inability to discuss a matter
under seal.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> is not persuaded by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>'s various novel theories of "privilege" (exemption from testifying)
for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX>, family <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pets</ENAMEX>, and so on. In fact, the very raising of
these privileges in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>--and dropping them when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> says no--is one of
the counts in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s this-is-not-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">an</NUMEX>-indictment of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. Yet <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>,
too, has run a few novel and self-interested public interest theories up the
flagpole, such as his claim that his leaking (if it exists, which it doesn't)
is covered by a rule that allows <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> to reassure the public about the
integrity of an investigation. His investigation's integrity, he notes, has
been challenged. This is a delightful example of what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> call a "bootstrap
argument": If anyone points out that you've broken the rules, that's a
challenge to your integrity, which requires reassuring the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>, which means
you have no longer broken the rules! Anyway, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Kendall</ENAMEX>
pointed out at the hearing, this rule is about official statements, not
anonymous leaks.

            Finally,
despite all the evasive techniques, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> have both told the lies
they struggled to avoid. No one thinks even oral sex, as practiced outside the
laboratory, actually escapes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> suit's stringent definition of
which organs must come into contact with which body parts. As for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>, as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kendall</ENAMEX> pointed out at the hearing, the independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> put out a press
release <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX> broke declaring, "Because of confidentiality
requirements, we are unable to comment on any aspect of our work." (At the
hearing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kendall</ENAMEX> he disagreed with his own press release.)

            
In his massive reply to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brill</ENAMEX>'s massive
"Pressgate" article, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> wrote that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brill</ENAMEX> was "mistaken" to assume that it
was the "practice" of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> or his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> "to release to media the contents of
statements made by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> outside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">grand jury</ENAMEX>." He wrote, "Let me repeat
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">categorically</ENAMEX>: the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OIC</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Independent Counsel</ENAMEX>] does not release grand
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> material directly or indirectly, on the record or off the record." I
suppose the words "practice" and "grand jury testimony" leave <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> a tiny bit
of wiggle room. It would be a joy to watch him perform that particular
wiggle.

            Letters to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brill</ENAMEX>, of course,
are not under oath. At the impeachment hearing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Friday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barney Frank</ENAMEX>,
D-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mass.</ENAMEX>, tried to spring the perjury trap, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> thwarted him by repeating
that he didn't do any illegal leaking (he didn't add "by my definition") and
that he couldn't discuss the matter because it was "under seal" (he didn't add
"at my request").

            But all is not lost.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kendall</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>, not even intending a perjury trap, asked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>
whether anybody had been fired for leaking, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">No</ENAMEX>, because I
don't believe anyone has leaked grand jury information." That's awfully close.
Once again, words such as "believe" and "grand jury information" give <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>
some possible defenses. But invoking such defenses publicly would destroy his
reputation. He could invoke them if called before a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">grand jury</ENAMEX> and hope that
word didn't leak out, but tragically--and mysteriously!--it has a way of doing
so.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>, in
short, fell into a perjury trap that no one had even set. Should we snap it
shut or release him?

            The best case that can be made for letting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> off the hook for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX>--besides the fact that everyone is sick to
death of it, which strictly speaking is not a legal argument--is that he was
caught in a perjury trap. Consensual sex between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> is no crime, lying
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about an</NUMEX> ancillary matter in a civil suit deposition is a crime that would
never normally be prosecuted ("Oh yes it would" <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">...</ENAMEX> "Oh no it wouldn't" ...
yadda, yadda, yadda), and so <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s one legally indefensible act was lying
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">grand jury</ENAMEX>. After <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX> of investigation, in other words,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s only good card is a crime he carefully arranged for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to commit
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">just three months ago</TIMEX>. And you don't crucify a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> for that.

            Or that's the argument. Good
enough? Maybe not. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> still lied under oath to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">grand jury</ENAMEX>. Perjury is a
serious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offense</ENAMEX>. Those who make and enforce the law have a special obligation
not to flout it. It's not about sex, it's about ... you know. So where does
that leave <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>?

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
