
   
   
      
         
            Is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Good</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>?

            
               GET
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INTERNATIONAL</ENAMEX> PAPERS" BY E-MAIL!
            

            
               For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> and
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> delivery of this column, plus "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX>),
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pundit Central</ENAMEX>" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>), and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment"</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>),
click here. And
if you missed the most recent installments of this column, here they are:
posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Oct. 6</TIMEX>, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, Oct.</TIMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>.
            

            Writing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jerusalem Post</ENAMEX>, Yossi
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben-Aharon</ENAMEX>, a former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director-general</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>,
proffered the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> case as an example of why <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Benjamin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX> should convene an emergency conference of world <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX> to adopt "an urgent plan to save <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diaspora Jewry</ENAMEX> from extinction."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> demonstrates the extent to which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Jewry</ENAMEX> has become
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">assimilated</ENAMEX>, he said. The fact that she landed a "much-sought-after job" in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> "show[s] the extent to which the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> [has]
become so well-connected, right up to the highest levels of society and
government."

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben-Aharon</ENAMEX> wrote that a report by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Jewish Congress</ENAMEX> showed "the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> is fast disappearing from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> demographic
map." According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WJC</ENAMEX>, he wrote, the present number of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5.5 million</NUMEX>--will be reduced by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two decades</TIMEX>. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jewish Agency</ENAMEX> and the organized <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> of world <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jewry</ENAMEX> must wake
up to the urgent need to take action in the face of the impending
disaster."

            With <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> poised for military action over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX> took a strongly anti-Western line on the issue.
But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">daily</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sevodnya</ENAMEX> also mocked <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Yeltsin</ENAMEX> for devoting
more time to it than to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s economic crisis. "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX> waited for a month
and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a half</NUMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> to explain the crisis and how the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> should fight
it," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, however, remained in a state of
lethargy." Then, "when he finally woke up," he immediately started making phone
calls to world <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> because this "gave him a chance to feel
himself a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> of a great power." On <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s pledge to veto any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resolution</ENAMEX> authorizing force against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sevodnya</ENAMEX> described
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s position as ambiguous "because [it] is both threatening the West and
begging it for money at the same time."

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Izvestiya</ENAMEX> said the use of force against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX> would revive the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold</ENAMEX>
War. Nezavisimaya
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gazeta</ENAMEX> said there is a possibility <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> will send <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Balkans</ENAMEX>
in extreme circumstances. "Back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 1994</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> threatened to bomb
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Bosnian Serbs</ENAMEX>, it was the appearance of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peacekeepers</ENAMEX> in the region
that prevented the attack," it explained. It added that, by constantly putting
pressure on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> side in the conflict--the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX>--the West was encouraging
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanian</ENAMEX> terrorism. "The general assumption that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> is bad and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanians</ENAMEX>
are good still dominates <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Western</ENAMEX> politics," it concluded.

            
In an editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times of London</ENAMEX> decried the
chaos afflicting international diplomacy over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>, "with meetings scheduled
and cancelled within <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX>, statements issued and promptly retracted, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">statesmen</ENAMEX>
announcing their arrival in capitals unprepared to greet them, and leaders
trying to keep telephone track of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Balkan</ENAMEX> imbroglio while locked into
campaigns and duties <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">thousands of miles</NUMEX> away." Attempts to base every decision
on consensus had created a multinational <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">muddle</ENAMEX>, "while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan Milosevic</ENAMEX>
laughs a little longer," it concluded.

            On
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s own crisis, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Komsomolskaya Pravda</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> was being sheltered from
reality by his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kremlin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisers</ENAMEX> who sent him reports making his reforms appear
successful and life in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> happier than it was. But it praised him for
having at least restored free speech to a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> that had been deprived of it
for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">centuries</TIMEX>. "No one in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX>'s time has ever been persecuted for making
anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> statements," it said.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Novye Izvestiya</ENAMEX> ran an interview <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Geoffrey Saks</ENAMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adviser</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>,
whom it quoted as saying that corruption and misappropriation of Western
credits have created a situation in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> to which no one sees a solution.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saks</ENAMEX> said that <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">between $50 billion and $100 billion</NUMEX> in Western aid was taken
out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and either deposited in Western <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> or used to buy
property abroad. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saks</ENAMEX> added that when he spoke to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX>
Department about this scandal, he was met only with silence, even though, in
private talks, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> admitted the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West</ENAMEX> had given money to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> not
for economic but for political purposes.

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Le Monde</ENAMEX> reported
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> on its front page that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> has ordered the establishment of a
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">100 square meter</NUMEX> vegetable garden in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the old quarter</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Le Marais</ENAMEX> as a memorial
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Princess</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>. It is designed to be "a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> of initiation to nature" for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said. The proposal angered neighborhood <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> and
provoked some acid comments in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>, which pointed out that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>
had no interest in gardening and that she couldn't even <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cook</ENAMEX>. But the London
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Evening Standard</ENAMEX> hopes the proposal will undermine a deeply
controversial plan supported by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> for a memorial garden to
her to be created in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kensington Gardens</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
