
   
   
      
         
            A <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wolfe</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clothing</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Wolfe</ENAMEX> has always been
explicit about what he thinks a novel should be. He published essays expounding
these views in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1973</TIMEX>, before he ever wrote a novel, then again in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>, after
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bonfire of the Vanities</ENAMEX> became a huge best seller. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American writers</ENAMEX>
should do what they used to do, he argued in "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Stalking the Billion</ENAMEX>-Footed
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beast</ENAMEX>," his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX> manifesto published in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harper</ENAMEX>'s . They should depict the
mad multiplicity of contemporary life. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolfe</ENAMEX> chastised his fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novelists</ENAMEX> for
abandoning the rich material at their doorstep in exchange for interiority,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">minutiae</ENAMEX>, and meta-fiction.

            There are
flaws in this argument, not the least of them <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolfe</ENAMEX>'s assumption that only
realistic narrative can portray the world persuasively. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Twentieth century</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> who have depicted large swaths of society in experimental
prose include <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Dos Passos</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Faulkner</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Pynchon</ENAMEX>. But I do
think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolfe</ENAMEX> has a point when he argues that reports of the death of the
traditional novel--the plot-driven epic--have been greatly exaggerated. As
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Bonfire</ENAMEX> demonstrated, the form retains great vitality and has the
potential to reach a vast, underserved <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>. But strangely, despite the
commercial success of that book, no other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> has responded to the call.
There is no <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School of Wolfe</ENAMEX> novel. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolfe</ENAMEX> remains a flourishing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-man literary
movement.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Wolfe</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> novel obeys all the strictures set down
in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Wolfe</ENAMEX>'s essays. It is, in fact, strikingly similar to his first
novel--in subject matter, structure, and theme. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protagonist</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Man in</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Full</TIMEX> is a white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">businessman</ENAMEX> who lives in sumptuous surroundings that
include a pretty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> whom he seems to need to be introduced to. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">The year</TIMEX> is
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX> not <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX> not <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlie Croker</ENAMEX> is a real
estate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">developer</ENAMEX> not an investment <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">banker</ENAMEX>. But like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sherman McCoy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Croker</ENAMEX> is a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Master</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Universe</ENAMEX> who has run into a heap o' trouble. Having erected a
megalomaniac monument to his own ego, a lavish see-through office <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tower</ENAMEX> in the
distant outskirts, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Croker</ENAMEX> finds that his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s assets are suddenly less
than its liabilities. Vultures circle the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX>, who is not inclined to
surrender. As in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Bonfire</ENAMEX> , a high society plot and a low society plot
chug toward each other. There is the same theme of legal error and even some of
the same jokes, such as a reference to the heavy metal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pus Casserole</ENAMEX>."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolfe</ENAMEX>'s style is still <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolfe</ENAMEX>'s style. Animal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Spirits</ENAMEX>! <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pizza Grenade</ENAMEX> ties! I
didn't tally up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">exclamation</NUMEX> points, but it must be ... <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Hundreds</NUMEX>! Heh-hegggggggghhhhhhhh!

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolfe</ENAMEX>'s
fictional <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">craft</ENAMEX> has improved. His major <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>--namely the failing honcho
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Croker</ENAMEX> and the gimlet-eyed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wes Jordan</ENAMEX>--are more human and less
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">caricature</ENAMEX>, though the minor ones, including all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, are still cartoons.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolfe</ENAMEX>'s take on what makes the world go around is still highly reductive.
Business is about virility, politics about manipulation, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>'s
sexual interest--something <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> have no control over. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>'s
understanding of psychology has developed a greater degree of nuance. The
description of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Croker</ENAMEX>'s withdrawal from his problems into illness and
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">depression</ENAMEX>, late in the book, is surprisingly tender--for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wolfe</ENAMEX>.

            
There are also scenes in the new book that
constitute journalism as good as any that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolfe</ENAMEX> as done. The description of
work inside a frozen foods <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">warehouse</ENAMEX>, where wheezing lugs destroy their health
hefting <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">80</NUMEX> pound ice bricks of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> sticks, is worthy of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Upton Sinclair</ENAMEX>'s
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jungle</ENAMEX> . The recounting of a brutal "workout" session, in which
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bankers</ENAMEX> try to break a defaulting debtor down psychologically, is brilliantly
drawn, as are the scenes set in a dehumanized <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oakland</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wolfe</ENAMEX>'s tour
from the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">suite</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX>, you search in vain for false notes.

            
Nonetheless, there's something off about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolfe</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novelist</ENAMEX> that's hard to put
a finger on. I was borne along very merrily, and in fact wanted to do little
else but read the novel until I was finished. But this book didn't affect me in
any lasting way, the way a novel by one of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wolfe</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th century</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroes</ENAMEX> can. For some reason, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Man in Full</ENAMEX> , like <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Bonfire</ENAMEX> , remains
sophisticated entertainment rather than literature. The problem may be writing
that proceeds from a theory. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolfe</ENAMEX> uses the novel as a vessel for his social
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reportage</ENAMEX>. At <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">moments</TIMEX> it seems the wrong container. He has a tendency to try to
cram too many tiny figures into an overcrowded canvas. For instance, his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">excursion</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> outside <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX> known as "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Chambodia</ENAMEX>" is shoehorned in. In
a few pages, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolfe</ENAMEX> lets us know that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Vietnamese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> live packed into
tiny <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartments</ENAMEX> and take odious jobs in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chicken</ENAMEX> processing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> that white
and black <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Atlantans</ENAMEX> both spurn. This is part of the teeming pluralism he wishes
to convey, but it feels superfluous.

            But the failure goes deeper. A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Man in Full</ENAMEX> follows
the example of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Dickens</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honoré de Balzac</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Émile Zola</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Theodore</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dreiser</ENAMEX> in its ambition to tell a big story, the kind that covers a lot of
geography and captures the flavor of the age. In this <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolfe</ENAMEX> succeeds ably,
infusing his tale with characteristic wit, verve, and narrative propulsion. But
the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">19 th</NUMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early 20 th century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">realists</ENAMEX> shared with each
other a quality <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolfe</ENAMEX> lacks: a social conscience. In a famous essay, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orwell</ENAMEX> wrote that what makes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dickens</ENAMEX> so attractive, despite his failures in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">characterization</ENAMEX> and a tendency toward sentimentality, is his decency. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Dickens</ENAMEX>
was decent in the way he wrote about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, and he recommended decency as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">universal</ENAMEX> salve.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolfe</ENAMEX> has
no such compassion. There are underdogs of a kind in his books--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCoy</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Bonfire</ENAMEX> and the good family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Conrad Hensley</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Man in Full</ENAMEX> .
But what horrifies the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> is that these sympathetic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figures</ENAMEX> should sink
into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s degraded lumpenproletariat . The lower orders in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wolfe</ENAMEX>'s
novels, such as those who populate the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">jail</ENAMEX> where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Conrad Hensley</ENAMEX> is imprisoned,
are barely above the level of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX>. The same goes for the ghetto-bred
college <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fareek Fanon</ENAMEX> (in unsubtle hommage to Frantz
Fanon, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectual</ENAMEX> who championed <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-</ENAMEX>colonial violence in the
1950s). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fanon</ENAMEX> is a primitive grotesque, a grunting monster.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dickens</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zola</ENAMEX> showed their contemporary
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> how social conditions led to the debasement of human beings. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolfe</ENAMEX> has
the causality running in the other direction. In his novels, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prisons</ENAMEX> and
ghettos reflect the low nature of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inhabitants</ENAMEX>. It is <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">beasts</ENAMEX> that make the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">jungle</ENAMEX>, not the other way around. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolfe</ENAMEX> does take us to the bombed-out block
where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fanon</ENAMEX> grew up, making such a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> plausible. But he gets way more
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">juice</ENAMEX> out of the brutality such a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> embodies than from exploring how he
got to be that way. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Woolfe</ENAMEX> brings very little indignation to bear on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">society</ENAMEX> that allows this to happen. Returning from his tour of hell, he tells
the rest of us that we should be shocked--not outraged. The mass of suffering
humanity is a kind of flea circus, more <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> farce than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
Tragedy .

            This coldness and lack of
moral vision bring <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wolfe</ENAMEX> much closer to the spirit of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evelyn Waugh</ENAMEX> than to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dickens</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Waugh's</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1930s</NUMEX> novels, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vile Bodies</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Black</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mischief</ENAMEX> , are wicked fun in the strict sense. They are hilarious, but
they're also slightly guilt-inducing, because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> is deeply nasty about
his fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolfe</ENAMEX> doesn't see himself as primarily a satirist. But like
Waugh, he makes his fun out of snobbery. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolfe</ENAMEX> mocks the obsession with money
and status, yet at the same time, his cleverest moments come from indulging in,
not just exposing, invidious distinctions and superficial judgments. The reader
is led to despise <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> because of his bad taste in neckties, but not
to hold racism and homophobia against another.

            I think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolfe</ENAMEX> is right about
the potential of this kind of novel, one that takes us through unexplored
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">precincts</ENAMEX> of our own society while spinning a good yarn. But society awaits a
popular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novelist</ENAMEX> who is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> in full--one with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolfe</ENAMEX>'s eye and a heart to
go with it.

         
      
   
