
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mother Tongue</ENAMEX>

            By Eavan
Boland

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday, Oct.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            To hear the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX> read "The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mother Tongue</ENAMEX>," click .

            The old pale ditch can
still be seen <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">less than half</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a mile</NUMEX> from my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>--

            its ancient barrier of mud
and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">brambleswhich mireth</ENAMEX> next unto <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irishmenis</ENAMEX> now a mere rise of <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">coarse grass</ENAMEX>,a
rowan <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX> and some thinned-out spruce,where a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> is playing at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">twilight</ENAMEX>.

            I stand in the shadows. I
find ithard to believe now that oncethis was a source of our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">division</ENAMEX>:

            Dug. Drained. Shored up
and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">leftto</ENAMEX> keep out and keep in. That herethe essence of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">colony</ENAMEX>'s defencewas
the substance of the quarrel with its purpose:

            Land. Ground. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">line</ENAMEX> drawn
in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rainand clay</ENAMEX> and the roots of wild broom--behind it the makings of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>,beyond it rumours of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>--by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dalkey</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kilternan</ENAMEX> and Balallythrough
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> ways of saying their names.

            A window is suddenly
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">yellow</ENAMEX>.A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> is calling a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>.She turns from her play and runs to her
name.Who came here under cover of darknessfrom <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Glenmalure</ENAMEX> and the Wicklow
hillsto the limits of this boundary? Who whisperedthe old names for love to
this earthand anger and ownership as it openedthe abyss of their future at
their feet?

            I was born on this side of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pale</ENAMEX>.I speak with the forked tongue of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">colony</ENAMEX>.But I stand in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the first dark</TIMEX>
and frost of a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dublin</ENAMEX> and imagine

            my pure
sound, my undivided speechtravelling to the edge of this silence.As if to find
me. And I listen: I hearwhat I am safe from. What I have lost.

         
      
   
