
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Movies
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holy Man</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buena Vista Pictures</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> are disappointed by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eddie Murphy</ENAMEX>'s turn as a spiritual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guru</ENAMEX> who is discovered by a TV <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX> and
ends up hawking gadgets on a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24 hour</TIMEX> cable shopping <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX>. The film "wants to
say something about the commodification of spirituality, but has no idea what"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rod Dreher</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Post</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treading</ENAMEX> ground previously trod by
Being There , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Network</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forrest Gump</ENAMEX> , the screenplay
doesn't give <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Murphy</ENAMEX> a chance to flex his comedic muscles, and the result is
weak satire. (Visit the official site.)

            
               
                  The
Mighty
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miramax Films</ENAMEX>). The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">handicapped-kid</ENAMEX> friendship story of
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX> (after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simon Birch</ENAMEX> ) hits the mark. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kieran Culkin</ENAMEX> and Elden
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Henson</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">outcasts</ENAMEX>--the former a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whip</ENAMEX>-smart bookworm with a
degenerative <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">bone disease</ENAMEX>, the latter a hulking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">giant</ENAMEX> who has been held back in
school <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> running. With <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Culkin on Henson</ENAMEX>'s shoulders, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pair</ENAMEX> is able
to outwit neighborhood bullies and to overcome personal obstacles. Although a
few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> find it too heavy with "only-in-the-movies claptrap" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Owen</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gleiberman, Entertainment Weekly</ENAMEX> ), most praise the film because "it
never slides down that slippery slope of sap that you keep expecting" (Jami
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bernard</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Daily News</ENAMEX> ). (Find out about the young-adult novel that is the basis for
this film.)

            

               
                  Slam
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trimark Pictures</ENAMEX>). After snagging the grand <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prize</ENAMEX> at
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Sundance</ENAMEX> and the best first film <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prize</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cannes</ENAMEX>, this fable of the redemptive
power of poetry wins more praise in its general release. Although <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>
detect shaky spots, they find the film "stirring, powerful, and thrilling," and
call <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veteran</ENAMEX> poetry-slam <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">champion</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saul Williams</ENAMEX>' performance as a drug
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealer/poet</ENAMEX> "eerily beautiful" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Morgenstern</ENAMEX>, the Wall Street
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andy Seiler</ENAMEX> disagrees: "The movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drowns</ENAMEX> in
self-indulgence and earnest speechifying." (Here is a page of links to slam
poetry sites.)

            
               
                  A
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Night</TIMEX> at the Roxbury
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paramount Pictures</ENAMEX>). As <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Saturday Night</ENAMEX>
Live skits-turned-movies go, this one "makes The 
               Blues
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brothers</ENAMEX> look like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kurosawa"</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Wlosczyna</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> ). A three
minute skit about two pathetically eager "delusional poseurs" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tamara Ikenberg</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baltimore Sun</ENAMEX> ) who'll do anything to get into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roxbury</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">nightclub</ENAMEX>,
is <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">now an hour and a half</TIMEX> of the same, which wears thin by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX>. Funny
cameos, though, by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Loni Anderson</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Grieco</ENAMEX> (who plays himself). (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Read</ENAMEX>
a parody of the movie's script here.)

            

               Dance
            

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Swan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Lake</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neil Simon Theatre</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Choreographer Matthew</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bourne</ENAMEX>'s re-engineered "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">gay Swan Lake</ENAMEX> " played for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six months</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>
(the longest continuous run of any ballet there) and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight weeks</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
and is now basking in critical acclaim on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX>. Gripping storytelling and
an ingenious use of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> in feathers are the most praised elements of the
production. Despite radical changes to the story line, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> note that both
the score and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ballet</ENAMEX>'s sense of magical fantasy remain virtually unchanged.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Simon</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> ), dissenting, calls the production
"choreographically impoverished" and advises <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bourne</ENAMEX> to "[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">g</ENAMEX>]o jump in a lake."
(Visit the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ballet</ENAMEX>'s Web
site.)

            

               Books
            

            

               
                  Work in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Progress</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Eisner</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Schwartz</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Random</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>). One word crops up in almost every review of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX>'s
"riches-to-riches autobiography" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ty Burr</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Entertainment Weekly</ENAMEX> ):
"bland." Even the swipes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eisner</ENAMEX> takes at archenemies <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeffrey Katzenberg</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Ovitz</ENAMEX> are mild. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> shocker in the book is the revelation of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eisner</ENAMEX>'s heart-and-soul belief that those who criticize <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> simply don't
understand it and that "the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s good is unquestionably,
inextricably intertwined with the larger social good" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Schickel</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> ). (For the biography of another "awkward, toothy,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">curious</ENAMEX>, and good-spirited <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Everyman</ENAMEX>" at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>, read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goofy</ENAMEX>'s official bio. And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Crispin Miller</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Ferguson</ENAMEX>
discuss the book in 
                  Slate
               's "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Book Club</ENAMEX>.")

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pure Drivel</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Martin</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hyperion</ENAMEX>). This "spankingly
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">inventive</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brett Kelly</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> ) collection of humorous essays (most
of which originally appeared in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> ) puts <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin</ENAMEX> back in the
comic pantheon after a recent series of disappointing films. The titles
alone--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mars Probe Finds Kittens</ENAMEX>" and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Schrödinger's Cat"</ENAMEX> (which covers
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sacajawea's Rain Bonnet" and "Wittgenstein's Banana"</ENAMEX>)--display <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin</ENAMEX>'s knack
for goofy parody. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> call the slim volume lighter than air but "giddy with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">imagination</ENAMEX>, exuberance, and originality" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maureen Corrigan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsday</ENAMEX> ).
(Find out more about the book on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.)

            
               Recent
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment</ENAMEX>" columns
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7:</TIMEX>

            

               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Antz</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- What Dreams</ENAMEX>
May Come ;

            

               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Happiness</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- I Married a</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Philip Roth</ENAMEX>;

            
               Television -- The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Secret Diary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Desmond Pfeiffer</ENAMEX> ;

            

               Art --"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Van Gogh</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Van Goghs</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Masterpieces</ENAMEX> From the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Van Gogh Museum</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Amsterdam</ENAMEX>."

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30:</TIMEX>

            

               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ronin</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Urban</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Legend</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Book -- <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">Cities</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Edgar Wideman</ENAMEX>;

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Opera</ENAMEX>--
               A Streetcar
Named <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Desire</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Music--
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Painted From</ENAMEX>
Memory , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elvis Costello</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burt Bacharach</ENAMEX>;

            

               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Felicity</ENAMEX> ;

            

               Art --"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">From Van Eyck to Bruegel: Early Netherlandish Painting in the</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metropolitan Museum of Art</ENAMEX>."

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">23:</TIMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Report</ENAMEX> -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>
Report ;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bag</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bones</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen King</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- Model
Behavior , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jay McInerney</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Birds</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lorrie Moore</ENAMEX>;

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Rush</ENAMEX>
Hour ;

            
               Movie -- Permanent
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Midnight</ENAMEX> ;

            

               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- A Soldier's Daughter Never Cries</ENAMEX> .

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">16:</TIMEX>

            

               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rounders</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- One True</ENAMEX>
Thing ;

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simon</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Birch</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- Touch of
Evil ;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anne</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Melissa Müller</ENAMEX>;

            
               Music -- Mechanical
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Animals</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marilyn Manson</ENAMEX>;

            

               Music -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Teatro</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willie Nelson</ENAMEX>.

            
               --Eliza
Truitt
            

         
      
   
