
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Address your e-mail to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. You must include your address and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX>
phone number (for confirmation only).
            

            
               No <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>
of the Web
            

            Re the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 8</TIMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>": <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX> did not put
anything on the Internet. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> did that. If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shuger</ENAMEX> believes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>
did a poor job of redacting the report before it was posted, he should say so.
But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> is blameless (on this score, at any rate).

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reed Washington</ENAMEX>

            
               Race to
the Finish
            

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judith Shulevitz</ENAMEX>'s
response to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ladenson</ENAMEX>'s letter of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 8</TIMEX>, she rightly points out that admission to an elite
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">university</ENAMEX> is often based on a set of subjective judgments. She goes on to list
such things as volunteer work, athletic or artistic ability, recommendations,
and so forth.

            But simply
listing a set of criteria is neither a justification for expanding them nor an
argument against striking a few. Including race in that set of criteria and
making it coequal with qualifications such as volunteer work or ability is a
concept that I, and many other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, find disturbing.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yon Lew Arvada</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Colo.</ENAMEX>

            
               My <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mouth</ENAMEX>
as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Raw Hamburger</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Paste Test":</ENAMEX>
I'll have to put the hex on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Colgate</ENAMEX> Total. I bought <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> large tubes after your
super review. After <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two days</TIMEX> of using the paste, my mouth turned into raw
hamburger. After the return to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Colgate Gel</ENAMEX>--because of its positive
characteristics when used with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sonicare</ENAMEX> cordless brush--my mouth was just
about back to normal. After <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three days</TIMEX> of using the gel, my mouth has returned
to its familiar self.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenworthy Madison</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wis.</ENAMEX>

            
               Paste for
Greenies
            

            I have always suspected the
majors were trying hard to cover the fact that a generic will do. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> things,
however, that you missed in "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paste Test"</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Colgate Total</ENAMEX> makes your tongue numb
(I've tested this with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>), and Mentadent/pump <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pastes</ENAMEX> in general are
hugely wasteful. They waste <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">paste</ENAMEX> inside their complex mechanisms, and
their packaging couldn't be less eco-friendly.

            I wish
this piece had included the idea that you will be using paste your whole life
and that that means a lot of tubes--and overly built pumps just for the
"aesthetic" value are a bad deal for the environment.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Benjamin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Keyser San Francisco</ENAMEX>

            
               Address
your e-mail to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. You must include your address and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX>
phone number (for confirmation only).
            

         
      
   
