
   
   
      
         
            A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Starr Is Boring</ENAMEX>

            Everyone wants to know how
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> is going to get out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX> mess. What's the exit strategy?
After watching <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Independent Counsel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">eight hours</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, I
propose an idea. Put <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> on every TV <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> and let him talk.
After <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five minutes</TIMEX>, when the entire <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> has fallen into a deep slumber, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> can drop the matter. When everyone wakes up, we can pretend it was all
just a nightmare.

            Both
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> seem weirdly hopeful <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Judiciary</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee</ENAMEX> meeting, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> and perhaps only major impeachment hearing.
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>, who are still enjoying their postelection gloat, know they have won
the war: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is safe, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX> is all but dead. They see <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> as their
chance to punish the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enemy</ENAMEX>, to humiliate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> for his prosecutorial aggression
and sexual obsession.

            Hard-core <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX>, who dominate the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> side
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> and who willfully refuse to learn anything from the election,
still suffer from the delusion that they can beat <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. They feel that
somehow, if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> explains it just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> more time, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> people
will come to their senses. During the lunch break, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Chabot</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX>,
actually tells <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> is important because "It's finally an
opportunity for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Starr</ENAMEX> to tell his side of the story." (So what was the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">453</NUMEX>
page report? The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7,000</NUMEX> pages of documents? The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six months</TIMEX> of leaks?) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chabot</ENAMEX>'s
spin is the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>'s only hope, that this time will be different.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>, they pray, may be <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oliver North</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX> who reverses
public opinion by sheer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> of personality.

            But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>
foils both sides.

            
The hearing has the kind of monstrous buzz that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX> hasn't seen since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX> testified in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Eight</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX> are here
to cover it live, so are <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a zillion</NUMEX> print <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Moore</ENAMEX> has come with
a camera <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX>. He has special access and lurks on the dais behind <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">committee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moore</ENAMEX> is ostentatiously underdressed, wearing a windbreaker
and a green baseball cap with a big letter S--for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>?)

            And the
hearing opens with the kind of vitriol everyone has anticipated. As soon as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Hyde</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ill.</ENAMEX>, bangs the gavel at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10:10 a.m.</TIMEX>, committee <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>
start carping that they are being unfairly silenced, that they and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> have not been given enough time to question <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sheila Jackson</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lee</ENAMEX>, a posturing <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Texan</ENAMEX>, says that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> are being "bound and gagged in the
courtroom" and compares the hearing to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Seven</ENAMEX> trial. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mel Watt</ENAMEX>,
D-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.C.</ENAMEX> calls the hearing a "railroading." <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Members</ENAMEX> start yelling "I will not
yield!" It is all very promising and becomes even more so when the ranking
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Conyers</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michigan</ENAMEX>, gives his opening statement. Staring
at the independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX>, who's seated below him at the witness table,
Conyers scolds "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth W. Starr</ENAMEX>" (as he repeatedly calls him) for writing "the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tawdry</ENAMEX>, salacious, and unnecessarily graphic" report and for "cross[ing] the
line into obsession."

            Then <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> begins his <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two hour</TIMEX> presentation, and he sucks
the air out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> like to say <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> is "dangerous." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boy</ENAMEX>,
they're right! <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> is a terror, a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> weapon of mass exhaustion. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s
strategy, and I'm sure it is intentional, is to seem so unremarkable, so
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">unthreatening</ENAMEX>, so uninteresting that his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> can't find anything to attack.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oliver North</ENAMEX> he's not.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two hour</TIMEX> performance--if you can call it that--consists of him reading a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">58</NUMEX>
page prepared statement in a monotone. He reads excruciatingly slowly. I
count his pace--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> words a minute. This ... is ... what ... it's ... like ...
to ... listen ... to ... someone ... talking ... at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">... 100</TIMEX> ... words ... a ...
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minute</TIMEX>. ... Now ... imagine ... listening ... to ... this ... for ... <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> ...
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX>.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s address is not only tortoise-paced,
it's also familiar, a rehash of everything we've read <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> times before--what his
duties are as independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX>, how the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> case came to him, why he
pursued it as he did, how the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> lied, etc. I imagine the network news
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX> pulling their hair out: We're covering this! Some pudding-faced
old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> reading a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two hour</TIMEX> statement at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX> rpm! Get me <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Regis</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathie</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX>!
            

            (There is
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> small diversion in the monologue: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Whenever Starr</ENAMEX> quotes from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s testimony, he drops his voice a register and makes it breathy. The
effect is creepy.)

            The attention of the committee <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> wanders. I begin to
count yawns: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard Coble</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.C.</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Inglis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">S.C.</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles</ENAMEX>
Canady, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fla.</ENAMEX> ... I lose count. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Wexler</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fla.</ENAMEX>, the photogenic
and aggressive <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">defender</ENAMEX>, does not succumb to this languor. He glares at
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> as if he's a particularly vicious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> molester.)

            During the
lunch break that follows <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s statement, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> are gleeful. "Did you see
that?" says <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zoe Lofgren</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX> "His own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> were falling asleep. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>
was putting his own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> to sleep." The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">principal</ENAMEX> and persuasive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic</ENAMEX>
spin: The only new thing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> said was that he has exonerated <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Filegate</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Travelgate</ENAMEX>.

            
But any hope that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> can capitalize on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s non-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North</ENAMEX> performance dissolves immediately after lunch, when
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">committee counsel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abbe Lowell</ENAMEX> questions <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>. It is like hammering
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lowell</ENAMEX> tries to get <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> to admit that he should have told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">attorney</ENAMEX>
general about his contacts with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paula Jones</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> and that he mistreated
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> by holding her for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ritz-Carlton</ENAMEX> and denying her a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Lowell</ENAMEX>
has been given an hour to quiz the independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> runs out the
clock on him. Lowell fires his questions. Each time, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> looks slightly
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pained</ENAMEX>, then says, "In fairness, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lowell</ENAMEX> ...," then wanders off on an
immensely long, barely responsive answer. Just when I think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> has finished,
I hear, "and, indeed, if I could just add that ..." (I notice another <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>
tic: He uses adverbs to drag everything out. He does not "dispute," he "utterly
disputes." Something is not "misleading," it is "grossly misleading.")

            The interrogation by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> that follows is equally
unproductive. (I am writing at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6:30 p.m.</TIMEX>, when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> has nearly
finished its questioning, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> have
not yet taken their turns.) Each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> gets <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five minutes</TIMEX>, which, after a windy
introduction, turns out to be time for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> questions. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> generally
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">congratulate Starr</ENAMEX> for his fair-mindedness and resilience in the face of
partisan attack, then toss him softballs about whether the rule of law should
apply to everyone equally. (His surprising answer: It should.)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>
pursue the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lowell</ENAMEX> strategy, trying to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bully</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> into revealing
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">embarrassments</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> wants to know what leaks his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> made, another
why he didn't stop <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Tripp</ENAMEX> from helping <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>. But even the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">toughest</ENAMEX> inquisitor--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barney Frank</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mass.</ENAMEX>--can't shake the affectless
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>, who ducks questions with the grace of, well, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. As the afternoon
wears on, the committee <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> empties.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank</ENAMEX>, as usual, has the keenest take. During
an <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX> break, he tells a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> is useless.
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hearing Ken Starr</ENAMEX> is a waste of time." No matter what happens here, Frank
continues, it won't make a difference to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX>'s outcome. Conservative
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> are so obsessed with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nailing</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> that they will never
surrender. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horse</ENAMEX> is dying, and the logical thing to do is shoot it. But
the right wing says 'No, no, we'll paint stripes on it and call it a zebra.'
They just won't accept defeat." And because they hold the committee <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">majority</ENAMEX>,
"They are not going to give up without voting out an article of
impeachment."

            Which brings me to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who deserves the most sympathy in all this: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Hyde</ENAMEX>, or "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry</ENAMEX>,"
as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank</ENAMEX> calls him. His <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> are pressuring <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hyde</ENAMEX> to do
something, anything, to make the scandal viable again. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last few days</TIMEX>
they have proposed subpoenaing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Huang</ENAMEX>, taking over the campaign finance
investigation, going after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathleen Willey</ENAMEX>, going after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathleen Willey</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hyde</ENAMEX> can't control them. Nor can he rein in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> who accuse
him of partisanship.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hyde</ENAMEX>'s
own reputation has been ruined by the news of his adultery, his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> is in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">shambles</ENAMEX>, there is no way out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX> mess, but what can he do? Still
"poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry"</ENAMEX> must sit up on the dais, ashen-faced, and preside over this sorry,
sorry <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> spectacle.

         
      
   
