
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Giving Peace a Chance</ENAMEX>?

            
               If you missed the most
recent installments of this column, here they are: posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 20</TIMEX>, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Nov. 17</TIMEX>.
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Le Monde</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> showed sudden
optimism <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> about a <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> peace settlement. In an editorial titled
"<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> Neorealism," it said that the hand-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over</NUMEX> of the little <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Bank</ENAMEX> town
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kasbatieh</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Friday</TIMEX> shows that "very slowly, in distrust, recrimination,
and mutual regret, by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin Netanyahu</ENAMEX> and also by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yasser</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arafat</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israelis</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX> are progressing toward peace."
Pointing out that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX> had battled against the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oslo</ENAMEX> accords and promised
his fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">countrymen</ENAMEX> that they wouldn't have to give up territory in exchange
for peace, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Le Monde</ENAMEX> said he has now come to recognize that territorial
concessions are necessary. "In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">his day</TIMEX>, another <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Likud</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Menachem Begin</ENAMEX>,
went down the same <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX>," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said. "He said that <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sinai</ENAMEX> belonged to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israelis</ENAMEX>. And to make peace with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX>, he gave it <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sinai</ENAMEX>, even charging a
certain <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ariel Sharon</ENAMEX>--now <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foreign minister</ENAMEX>--to expel the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">settlers</ENAMEX> who had
established themselves there. Are we permitted to <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">dream?</ENAMEX>"

            On the
continuing showdown with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>, the liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Independent of London</ENAMEX>
called for the lifting of sanctions because, "in the long run, free trade is
the surest way to undermine totalitarianism." In an editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> (once you're on the page, scroll down to read
the piece), the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Independent</ENAMEX> said it is now widely assumed that "the
object of Western policy in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> is the removal of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX>--a polite way
of saying killing him, because it is hard to see how he might be dislodged
otherwise." But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said that even if it is argued that the rule of law
would continue to be flouted as long as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX> was in power, "there can be no
consensus that the death penalty is called for."

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Libération</ENAMEX> published extracts from a conversation between its
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondent</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Galina Starovoitova</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Yeltsin</ENAMEX>'s former
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adviser</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three days</TIMEX> before her assassination in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Petersburg</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Friday</TIMEX>.
"The greatest threat today is the lack of a liberal anchorage in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>,"
she was quoted as saying. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are disoriented. There is a political
void." The conservative Le
Figaro of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> is haunted by "political terror" and described
Starovoitova as the latest victim of "a series of politico-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mafia</ENAMEX> murders."

            Despite the furor in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX>
over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>'s refusal to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">extradite</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abdullah Ocalan</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurdish</ENAMEX> rebel <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily</ENAMEX>
News said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> that "it would be wrong and even self-defeating to
make the entire <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> pay the price for the mistakes of a few
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">misinformed</ENAMEX> and misguided <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. ... We do not and should
not have a vendetta against the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. So let us stop this campaign of
antagonism towards <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> and start using our resources and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> to
convey our clear messages to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masses</ENAMEX>."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Financial Times</ENAMEX> pointed out in
an editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ocalan</ENAMEX> is being sought on charges of violence and
terrorism not only in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX> but also in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>. It proposed that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Germany</ENAMEX>
request his extradition from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> and put him on trial for the offenses of
which he is accused there. At the same time, it called on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> "to answer the genuine demands of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurdish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> for more
autonomy and more economic development." A military solution "is neither
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">workable</ENAMEX> nor stable," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said. "That should be the clear and repeated
message from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX>."

            
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Independent</ENAMEX> reported on its front page <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> leading <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> law
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> are being investigated on suspicion of laundering profits from drug
trafficking, gun running, and contract killings by international <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">racketeers</ENAMEX>,
including <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Colombian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">barons</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mafia</ENAMEX>. Saying the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> include
"household names," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> added that they are suspected of acting as fronts
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> who include "crime <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">syndicates</ENAMEX> in eastern <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gangs</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Colombian</ENAMEX> cartels." It quoted police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> as saying
that arrests are imminent.

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jerusalem Post</ENAMEX> said that,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> will "officially release a so-called dirty list, containing
the names of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than a dozen</NUMEX> international <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>, both public and
private, which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> alleges hold information on <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> and
other related activities, which they are refusing to publish." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bobby Brown</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adviser</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Diaspora</ENAMEX> affairs, will release the names
during the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Department</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> era restitution conference starting in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said, adding that the list will include the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vatican</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Czech Republic</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KGB</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MI-5</ENAMEX> espionage service.

            On the
sale in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vincent van Gogh</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Self-Portrait Without Beard</ENAMEX> for
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$71 million</NUMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Financial Times</ENAMEX> --noting that his <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Portrait of Dr.</ENAMEX>
Gachet , bought in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$82.5 million</NUMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">industrialist</ENAMEX> Ryoei
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saito</ENAMEX>, reportedly was sold off to satisfy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">creditors</ENAMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saito</ENAMEX>'s death--said
that "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Van Gogh</ENAMEX>, the artistic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX>, has been reduced to the status of mere
collateral." It concluded, "The price of artistic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX>, it seems, is often a
better guide to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of the banking market than the aesthetic spirit of
the age."

         
      
   
