
   
   
      
         

acknowledged that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> in possession of a good fortune should not upon
returning from his honeymoon let his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> work out at the gym with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seinfeld</ENAMEX>. This is the lesson learned by <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX> theater <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heir</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric</ENAMEX>
Nederlander, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">32</TIMEX>, when <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> after coming back to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> from a honeymoon in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>, his new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jessica Sklar</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">26</TIMEX>, met <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seinfeld</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">44</TIMEX>, at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reebok Sports</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Club</ENAMEX>. Before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newlyweds</ENAMEX> had time to unpack all their new <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">china</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Enquirer</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> had photo spreads of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sklar</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seinfeld</ENAMEX> around <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> in full lip lock. According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nederlander</ENAMEX>--who will now save a fortune on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">anniversary</TIMEX> gifts--contemplated an
alienation of affection suit against the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">comedian</ENAMEX> but finally decided to simply
file for divorce. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> also reveals why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seinfeld</ENAMEX> would behave so
perfidiously: He hadn't had "good sex" since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> when he broke up with
his young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shoshanna Lonstein</ENAMEX>.

            The tabs
also tout the "shocking" resemblance between the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> but are
uncharacteristically restrained in neglecting to mention that there is one (or,
more accurately, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>) crucial difference in the physiques of slender <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jessica</ENAMEX>
and bounteously well-endowed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shoshanna</ENAMEX>. Shoshanna, who became a tabloid
celebrity in her own right by dating <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seinfeld</ENAMEX> while she was still in high
school, has recently launched her own line of lingerie.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lingerie</ENAMEX>, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> , will be the focus of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s next career move: It reports that she would like to confer
with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">madam</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heidi Fleiss</ENAMEX>--who had her own lingerie <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>--when her
fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Monica College</ENAMEX> alumna gets out of jail. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> does not
reveal if <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX>'s merchandise will come pre-stained.

            There is,
not surprisingly, even more <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> news. According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> ,
during her affair with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> feared her more than they
did a possible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assassin</ENAMEX>. Citing grand jury testimony, the publication describes
how, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Christmas</TIMEX>, the "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> became frantic about the possibility
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX> turning up at a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> holiday reception hosted by the First
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lady</ENAMEX> and attended by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">some 400</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX>." An <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> social
office testified that an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>, upon discovering <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s name
on the guest list, rushed up to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX> and said, "We have to find her
before Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> sees her." It is presumed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> was successful as there
are no reports that either <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX> tried to dunk the other's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> in
the wassail bowl.

            
Of even greater concern to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX>
were the times the temperamental <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> spent alone with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Pape</ENAMEX> told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">grand jury</ENAMEX> of a
conversation he had with another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX>. "If she [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>] was going to do any
harm to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> ... I said she would do the--you know-- it would be
something along the lines of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lorena Bobbitt</ENAMEX>, if she was going to hurt him." Had
that happened, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MSNBC</ENAMEX> would have had to change the name of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The White House</ENAMEX> in
Crisis to The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Penis Is Missing</ENAMEX> .

            But even
that is not as shocking as the photos <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tabloids</ENAMEX> have run of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>
in exercise clothes. Since she was last seen in public, the former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">intern</ENAMEX> has ballooned to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">almost 180</NUMEX> pounds. She has joined a gym and has hired a
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$75</NUMEX> an hour personal <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trainer</ENAMEX> to help her peel off <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">55</NUMEX> pounds, reports the
Star . Now imagine how much more happiness and how much less heartache
there would be in the world if only <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Seinfeld</ENAMEX> liked full-figured gals, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>, not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jessica Sklar</ENAMEX>, had joined the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reebok Sports Club</ENAMEX>.

            As inverse images of the wages of fame, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Ally McBeal star Calista Flockhart</ENAMEX> make a perfect <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pair</ENAMEX>. Under pressure,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> has expanded. Meanwhile, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flockhart</ENAMEX> has shrunk. So shocking is her
appearance that the tabs, which luridly chronicle every celebrity chin waddle
and thigh dimple, are now expressing concern about her and other stick figure
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">actresses</ENAMEX>. According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">5 foot 6 inch</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX> is down to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">95</NUMEX>
pounds, having lost <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about 15 pounds</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past year</TIMEX>. She is so weak from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dieting</ENAMEX> and compulsive exercising that the show's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producers</ENAMEX> have cut back on
her screen time, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flockhart</ENAMEX> and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> deny
she has an eating disorder. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX> even called a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> radio station
to say that she enjoys gorging on junk food. Such denials are usually a prelude
to hospitalization, recovery, and a tearful interview with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oprah</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Barbara</ENAMEX>, or
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diane</ENAMEX>.

            The tabs
also report that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrity spouses</ENAMEX> couldn't quite wait until their dearly
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">beloved</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX> were fully cold before finding that they could learn to love
again. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A few months ago</TIMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">funeral</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tammy Wynette</ENAMEX>, her <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">husband George Richey</ENAMEX>--perhaps stealing some moves from the finale of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">James</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX> concert--had to be repeatedly held up by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> to keep from collapsing.
He even threatened to take the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> of his dead <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> home. Perhaps he could
have stashed her in the backseat of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Rolls Royce</ENAMEX>, which, according to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> , he has now given to his new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX>, a former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dallas Cowboys</ENAMEX>
cheerleader 30 years his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">junior</ENAMEX>. And <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Bono</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">widow</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sonny</ENAMEX>, started dating <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nine months</TIMEX> after his skiing accident death. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX>, who
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">won Sonny</ENAMEX>'s congressional seat, has been seeing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian Prout</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drummer</ENAMEX> for
country <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Diamond Rio</ENAMEX>, reports the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> . Although the congresswoman
says, "I feel like this weight has been lifted off of me," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bono</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> calls
the relationship "disgusting." But, according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> , there may be
more heartbreak in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">widow</ENAMEX>'s future. It reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prout</ENAMEX> is a "womanizer
with more notches on his bedpost than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Casanova</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> even says
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drummer</ENAMEX> is already romancing a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nashville</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">waitress</ENAMEX>.

            
And a book that is portraying the late <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Princess</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX> as neurotic, jealous, and out of control is causing new grief for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Prince</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lover</ENAMEX> Camilla <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parker Bowles</ENAMEX>. They have released a joint
statement denying any involvement with <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Charles: Victim or Villain</ENAMEX>? , the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> reports, but royal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">watchers</ENAMEX> say the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Penny Junor</ENAMEX>, would
not have won the cooperation of so many of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> without the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX>'s
tacit approval. The book charges that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX> was the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> to cheat (with her
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bodyguard</ENAMEX>), that she used to call <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parker Bowles</ENAMEX> and make death threats, and
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles</ENAMEX> was relieved when she died. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX> may yet get her revenge. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> relays a "startling report transmitted on the world-wide internet"
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX> has been cloned by a "mad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientist</ENAMEX>" and that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> will be born
by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the year</TIMEX> at a secret laboratory on an island off the coast of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>.

            The tabs
are getting fed up with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who have become rich and famous by telling
everyone else how to be better. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">All three</NUMEX> tabs have run stories about the nude
photos of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laura Schlessinger</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">51</TIMEX>, radio <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX> and moral <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arbiter</ENAMEX>, that have
appeared on the Internet. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> reports that at first Schlessinger
claimed the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than 20-year-old</TIMEX> photos were not of her. She subsequently
filed suit claiming that she owned the photos, and they were temporarily taken
off the Web site. The photos were released by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Ballance</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">80</TIMEX>, a former radio
talk show <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX> who says he and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schlessinger</ENAMEX> were once <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lovers</ENAMEX>, who, in his
memorable phrase, used to thrash around "like a couple of crazed weasels."

            And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> is at the forefront of an anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oprah</ENAMEX>
Winfrey backlash <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> with the story "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oprah Revolt</ENAMEX>! <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Fans</ENAMEX> charge: You're
too big for your britches!" Actually, part of the problem is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> liked
the talk show <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX> better when she was bigger britched, before she became the
Vogue cover <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX>. They are also sick of her constant preaching on
self-improvement, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX>. One "insider" at her production company
is quoted as saying, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oprah</ENAMEX>'s always been religious, but she's gone overboard
thinking she's been given a specific mission on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX>."

            If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oprah</ENAMEX>'s not safe, no one
is. To prove it, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> reports that the ghost of mild-mannered
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ozzie Nelson</ENAMEX> is haunting his former <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> home. He's a very friendly ghost.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> says female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> wake in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the middle of the night</TIMEX> when they
feel the late <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ozzie</ENAMEX> nuzzling their necks. Sounds like a premise for a
sitcom.

         
      
   
