
   
   
      
         
            No <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare Scare</ENAMEX>

            Who'd have thought seniors
would be clamoring to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, "Please don't take my HMO away"? Only a year
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ago</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> were being castigated for "herding the elderly into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMOs</ENAMEX>." But
now, as health maintenance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> are suddenly pulling out of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> markets, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">400,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elderly customers</ENAMEX> are scrambling to find insurance
coverage beyond <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the year</TIMEX> and demanding that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> do something
about it. News reports raise the specter of an HMO stampede to the door that
could unravel the entire <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6 million</NUMEX> member <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare HMO</ENAMEX> system.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMOs</ENAMEX> say it's all because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> pays too little. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> has
fired back, saying that if anything, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMOs</ENAMEX> are paid too much. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health Care</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Financing Administration</ENAMEX> has refused to renegotiate rates or to allow the HMOs
to drop benefits on established contracts. And <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>, including the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, are pounding the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMOs</ENAMEX> for "breaking their promises" of coverage for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elderly</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Dodd</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Conn.</ENAMEX>, has announced that he will introduce
legislation that will block the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMOs</ENAMEX> from dropping out for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six months</TIMEX>.

            
Health policy debates tend to be eye-glazing,
but there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> reasons why casual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">observers</ENAMEX> should care about what's going
on here.

            First, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> HMO
program is a critical test case for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clintonian</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Third Way</ENAMEX>" thinking. Under
policy changes passed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> has been transformed into an enormous
voucher system. It is the prototype of a still new and controversial idea:
Government should finance a generous safety net, but competing, private
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organizations</ENAMEX> should do the work. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> now allocates to each senior
in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> a fixed amount of money that will buy coverage from either a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">private HMO</ENAMEX> or the traditional government-run <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> program--thus fostering
competition. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">If HMOs</ENAMEX> refuse to participate, however, the whole reform plan is
dead.

            <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> savings are supposed to provide the major part of the much-heralded
deficit reduction projected for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next few years</TIMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$102 billion</NUMEX> out of a total
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$127 billion</NUMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998 through 2002</TIMEX>. And <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50 billion</NUMEX> of that is to come from
savings expected in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> HMO program. If the HMO program fails, it will
be an economic as well as a social disaster.

            All signs, however, suggest that the immediate problems in
the program have been exaggerated.

            
               More <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">HMOs</ENAMEX> are seeking to
enter Medicare markets than are seeking to withdraw. The pullouts affect
just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">400,000</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">6 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare HMO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>. Industry <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">observers</ENAMEX> and HMO
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> say that only a few more HMOs are expected to leave the program.

            
               Withdrawals are not
proof that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMO</ENAMEX> payments are too low, as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMOs</ENAMEX> claim. In fact, if next
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>'s payment rates were high enough to keep all the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">450</NUMEX> contracting HMOs
profitable, then <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> would clearly be paying too much. As <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Newhouse</ENAMEX> points out, the optimal rate of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">exit</ENAMEX> is unlikely to
be <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX>. Presumably, at least some of the plans are inefficient. We don't know
precisely what an optimal rate would be, but the anticipated withdrawal rate
among <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMOs</ENAMEX> (plans covering <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 7 percent</NUMEX> of enrollees) is probably not
unreasonable.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMO</ENAMEX> payments have, in
fact, been too high. The HMO pullouts seemed so unexpected because until
recently <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMOs</ENAMEX> were pushing to expand their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> business. The reason
was simple: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> was overpaying them. Before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>, under a
formula that even the HMO industry admits was "rather robust," <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMO</ENAMEX> payments
were derived from the traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> program, which had a much sicker
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> and costs that rose <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>. The overpayment was estimated
to be <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">8 percent</NUMEX>, so <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> put in a new formula that essentially
cut the increase for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2 percent</NUMEX>. Given the tightened payments and a
major downturn in HMO stocks, some marginal markets--especially rural
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">areas</ENAMEX>--started to look unprofitable. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMOs</ENAMEX> were allowed to drop them up to this
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">month</TIMEX>. So with the deadline looming, a bunch did.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Nearly 90 percent</NUMEX> of dropped enrollees are in areas where they can choose
the effects of the announced withdrawals will be limited.

            
To be sure, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who have to switch <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMOs</ENAMEX> may
have to change <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX>. And those who lose all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMO</ENAMEX> coverage may suffer
substantial financial loss. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard Medicare</ENAMEX> coverage pays <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 80 percent</NUMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> and hospital bills and nothing for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMOs</ENAMEX> pay all medical bills
except for a small copayment and generally provide generous drug coverage,
often at no extra cost--except giving up one's choice of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX>.
an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMO</ENAMEX> saves <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,200</NUMEX> per year--<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 10 percent</NUMEX> of average income--compared with
those with the standard coverage and some supplemental insurance. No wonder
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMOs</ENAMEX> sign up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50,000</NUMEX> new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every month</TIMEX>.

            What
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> is now suffering is not a calamity. It is the inevitable turbulence
and messiness of introducing choice and competition to a major social program.
In a voucher system, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">seniors</ENAMEX> have a choice of plans, but the plans have
choices, too. They aren't breaking any promises if they decide to take their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ball</ENAMEX> and go home. The benefits, however, may still be worth this downside.
After all, regulations failed to control <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>'s costs adequately. The hope
and the logic is that competing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMOs</ENAMEX> might have better success.

            
It would be a big mistake for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> to
respond to irate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">seniors</ENAMEX> by punishing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMOs</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dodd</ENAMEX>'s proposal to block the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pullouts</ENAMEX> is crazy. Forcing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMOs</ENAMEX> to stay in a failing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> cannot be good
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">seniors</ENAMEX> and would chill entry by others. Nor should <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> heed HMO
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyists</ENAMEX> and force <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> to renegotiate the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> contracts. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMOs</ENAMEX> knew the rules, and the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dropouts</ENAMEX> does not seem excessive.

            The real cause for concern
is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMOs</ENAMEX> may fail to control costs in the long term. Over <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of managed
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">care</ENAMEX> plans are now losing money, and a major shakeout is underway. After
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several years</TIMEX> of remarkable success, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">insurers</ENAMEX> are having serious trouble
controlling the costs generated by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> like me, and not just for the senior
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>. New <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>, diagnostics, and other technologies have accelerated
costs far beyond the pace of inflation. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Insurers</ENAMEX> are seeking double-digit
increases in premiums from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX>, who will then cut health benefits, wages,
or both. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> will face intense pressure to raise <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> HMO
payments in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">future years</TIMEX>. Suddenly, the current budget surplus looks
short-lived indeed.

            If <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMOs</ENAMEX>, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">regulators</ENAMEX> in
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">1980s</NUMEX>, fail to tame health costs, we will be left with an ugly choice. Do
we let the new technologies--with their promise of a longer and better
life--consume ever more of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s wealth and productivity? Or do we
ration them? More than anything, the current <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMO</ENAMEX> troubles are evidence that
this could be the major domestic policy debate of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the coming decade</TIMEX>.

         
      
   
