
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Splat</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spackle</ENAMEX>, Plop!

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Oct.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">31, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            The first
powerful experience I remember having while looking at art was in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jackson</ENAMEX>
Pollock <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum of Modern Art</ENAMEX>. I was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13 or so</NUMEX>, and we were on a
family visit to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>. Overwhelming everything else in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> was the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17</NUMEX>
foot long One: Number <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">31, 1950</TIMEX> , a painting that amazed and thrilled me
with its scale, its spontaneity, and the intensity it radiated. I had the same
feeling again when I saw <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lavender Mist: Number 1</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1950</TIMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Gallery</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> soon thereafter.

            But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pollock</ENAMEX> has left me cold
as an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adult</ENAMEX>, and often bored. His paintings looked hollow and often sloppy and
garish. Did I respond to him as an adolescent because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pollock</ENAMEX> was a misbehaved,
grandiose adolescent himself? Maybe we all just had a teen crush on Pollock the
art world delinquent. Or was it entombment in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museums</ENAMEX>, being surrounded by the
work of nonaction <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">painters</ENAMEX>, that muffled his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> and left him dead on the
wall? I have been awaiting a show that would settle the issue.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pollock</ENAMEX> retrospective
that opens at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum of Modern Art</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this weekend</TIMEX> ought to
resolve all such ambivalence. With <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 200</NUMEX> works--pretty much every
important painting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pollock</ENAMEX> did--it is a complete and authoritative presentation
of his life and work. Occupying the entire <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">floor</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX>, it
includes both a full-scale replica of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pollock's</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studio</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Springs</ENAMEX>, on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Long</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Island</ENAMEX>, and a continuous showing of the fascinating films that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hans Namuth</ENAMEX>, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German émigré</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">photographer</ENAMEX>, made of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pollock</ENAMEX> painting at the peak of his career.
The long catalog essay by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Modern</ENAMEX>'s chief <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">curator</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kirk Varnedoe</ENAMEX>, is a model
of its kind, covering the salient facts of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pollock</ENAMEX>'s biography, artistic
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">development</ENAMEX>, and the critical debate about him. As an exhibition, this is one
of the best I have ever seen. And it did make up my mind.

            In the early <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX>,
skepticism can't but prevail. From the time <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pollock</ENAMEX> arrived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1930</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the age of 18, until about 1946</TIMEX>, he was casting about for a style. He
loved the idea of being an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>, but his vast ambition wasn't coupled with
much, or even any, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">talent</ENAMEX>. Through the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX>, we see him find and
mimic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mentors</ENAMEX>, some living, some dead. He <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> fell under the sway of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thomas</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hart Benton</ENAMEX>, his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Art</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Students</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">League</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Albert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pinkham Ryder</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">essaying moonlight seascapes</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">moody</ENAMEX> swirls of Americana, such
as Going <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">West</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1934-38</TIMEX>). Then <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Pollock</ENAMEX> apprenticed himself to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> muralists, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Siqueiros</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orozco</ENAMEX>, as in Untitled
(<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Naked Man With Knife</ENAMEX>) (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1938-41</TIMEX>). Next he ate <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Picasso</ENAMEX>'s dust, as in
Stenographic Figure (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1942</TIMEX>), then <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miró's</ENAMEX>, as in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Untitled</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blue</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moby Dick</ENAMEX>]) (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1943</TIMEX>).

            By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1945</TIMEX>, when the ungifted
Pollock was still struggling with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">greats</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clement Greenberg</ENAMEX> was
already heralding him as the baby <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> art, noting that "he is not
afraid to look ugly." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenberg</ENAMEX> liked <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pollock</ENAMEX> because of the evidence he
provided for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenberg</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marxian</ENAMEX> view of art history as a series of developing
stages in which the picture <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> was destined to flatten, empty, and
disappear. Today <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenberg</ENAMEX> is much derided for his dogmatic views and imperial
pronouncements. But as far as I can tell, he was correct in every respect:
right that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pollock</ENAMEX> was ugly, right about where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Modernism</ENAMEX> was going,
and right that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pollock</ENAMEX> had genius trapped inside him. What is amazing is that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenberg</ENAMEX> could see how good <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pollock</ENAMEX> would become, given how bad he was.
Perhaps the most famous picture from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that period</TIMEX> is (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1943</TIMEX>). After <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13 years</TIMEX> of
practice, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pollock</ENAMEX> was void in color sense, draftsmanship, composition, and
handling of his materials. The painting is a kind of red <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">herring</ENAMEX>. With its
suggestive title, glyphs, and symbols, it is designed to make you think it
contains more than meets the eye.

            But in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1946</TIMEX> something
suddenly happened: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pollock</ENAMEX>'s nauseous swirls and lugubrious slatherings stepped
into a phone <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">booth</ENAMEX> and re-emerged as his mature "all-over" style. You see this
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> paintings known as the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sounds in the Grass</ENAMEX>" series, the best of
which is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shimmering Substance</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pollock</ENAMEX> has said goodbye to content and
seems to have found his self-confidence at last. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A year later</TIMEX>, he is flicking,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dripping</ENAMEX>, pouring, and splattering, creating medium-scale works of great beauty
(though still interspersed with fits of unappealing blotchiness). You don't
have to read the elaborate taxonomy of his technique in the catalog to
recognize that what sometimes appears as chaos is in fact the product of great
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> and finesse. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pollock</ENAMEX> came at the canvas with a range of tools--sticks,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">brushes</ENAMEX>, basters, and paint cans with holes--the effects of which he had
mastered. There is chance in his paintings, but it occurs within a well-defined
structure.

            How did <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pollock</ENAMEX> arrive so
suddenly? I think what happened is that he threw off the heavy influence of
others and stopped worrying about his lack of conventional technique. Instead,
he began to express himself in the way he could, basing his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">craft</ENAMEX> on his
abilities. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">The year 1947</TIMEX> yields a bounty of expressive work such as the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gorgeous</ENAMEX> , which has the quality of a musical nocturne, its orange, yellow,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">black</ENAMEX>, and white <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">filigrees</ENAMEX> spun on a thin surface of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">silver</ENAMEX> and unprimed
canvas. In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Full Fathom Five</ENAMEX>, the murk grows more evocative; the
enticing detail is a kind of small crossbow shape, in yellow and orange,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">glimpsed</ENAMEX> through the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">submarine</ENAMEX> tangle of a surface encrusted with nails,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">buttons</ENAMEX>, coins, and cigarette butts. In these paintings the feelings--mirth,
ecstasy, confusion, awe, whatever--seem intense and distinct.

            It stays that way over the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next few years</TIMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pollock</ENAMEX>'s scale expands toward the vast masterworks of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1950</TIMEX>.
The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> greatest of his monumental canvases, hung together in a single <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>,
have an almost overwhelming presence. Curiously, these paintings don't repay
prolonged viewing--or at least they didn't for me. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> follows the arcs and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">arabesques</ENAMEX> across the canvas, but they don't lead the eye anywhere. When you
try not to follow lines, you find you can't get any purchase on the whole. This
is the opposite of the experience you have looking at a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Rothko</ENAMEX>. You soak
in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rothko</ENAMEX> as in a warm tub. It's a meditative, spiritual experience. Pollock,
by comparison, is a splash of cold <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> on the face. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">power</ENAMEX> lies in being
confronted by his paintings, not in looking for meaning in them.

            For some reason, I wasn't
much moved by the old <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX>: Number <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">31, 1950</TIMEX> . But , a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">15 foot long</NUMEX>
monochrome work on loan from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Düsseldorf</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>, took my breath away. This is
the distilled essence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pollock</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX>, a mysterious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">calligraphy</ENAMEX> stripped of
the distraction of color or the accretion of layers of paint. In the
extraordinary photographs and films <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Namuth</ENAMEX> made of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pollock</ENAMEX> working in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1950</TIMEX>, you
can be mesmerized by his act of creation. The agonized expression on his face
looks like a kind of rapture. His dance around the canvas looks like its own
hidden language.

            What follows the incredible
spree of productivity that lasted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">from 1947-50</TIMEX> is a kind of brownout. In the
final <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> of the exhibition, you see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pollock</ENAMEX>, who was suffering from
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">depression</ENAMEX> and had relapsed into <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">alcoholism</ENAMEX>, struggling to regain a gift that
had vanished as swiftly as it had arrived. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">40</TIMEX>, he was pretty much washed up.
His career took the shape of a palindrome. looks like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Untitled</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1946</TIMEX>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Easter</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Totem</ENAMEX>(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1953</TIMEX>) collapses back to Totem
Lesson 1 (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1944</TIMEX>). Here <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pollock</ENAMEX>'s "camouflage palette," as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Varnedoe</ENAMEX> notes,
"gives way to carnival." The only really arresting work he did after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1950</TIMEX> is .
With its electric <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">brightness</ENAMEX>, this huge painting, which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pollock</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>
started for him, is stunning but sad, a big smile for the camera and perhaps a
kind of requiem for his earlier work. In his final painting, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Search</ENAMEX>
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1955</TIMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pollock</ENAMEX> seems to have drifted back even further, to the period before
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">talent</ENAMEX> began to emerge. In his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">final year</TIMEX> he binged, painted nothing, and
drove his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> into a <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX>.

            You can explain this flameout
with whatever theory appeals to you. In clinical terms, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pollock</ENAMEX> had a
productive manic phase, and he was overtaken by black <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the days</TIMEX> before
anti-depressants. In art historical terms, he flattened the picture <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX>,
emptied it, and then had nowhere to go. You can view him as the classic case of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doomed artist</ENAMEX>, his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX> and self-destruction bound up together. My own
admittedly romantic preference is to see his career as a quest for inspiration,
and to say <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pollock</ENAMEX> sought it long, found it briefly, and couldn't live without
it.

         
      
   
