
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">135</NUMEX>:

            By <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cohen</ENAMEX>

            
               "Are you
ready to make real noise<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>" This slogan is part of a new <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">multimillion-dollar</NUMEX>
campaign--to persuade whom to do what?
            

            by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> to
e-mail your answer (newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>).

            
               Responses
to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s question (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 134</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dewey Eats Truman":</ENAMEX>
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> are
invited to provide a postelection headline that, in a just universe, would run
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> in the media outlet of their choice.
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">D'Amato Wins; Sulfur</ENAMEX>
Fumes at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Victory Bash Fell Three</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beth Sherman</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Women's Wear</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Daily</TIMEX> : <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D'Amato Concedes</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vows Return to Runway</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jon Hotchkiss</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> : <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Midwest</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Autumn Colors Extravaganza</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brooke Saucier</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsstand/Time</ENAMEX> : <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al D'Amato Sprayed</ENAMEX> With <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Deadly Sarin Gas</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim</ENAMEX>
Carvell
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">All Good Candidates Lose</ENAMEX>;
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric Zicklin 'Too Busy</ENAMEX>' To Vote."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric Zicklin</ENAMEX>
            

            Click for more
responses.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
            

            "By the time you read this, I
will already be politically dead." This is the election message <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al D'Amato</ENAMEX>
could send just <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a few short hours</TIMEX> from now. (Or a few regular-size <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX>.) This
would be great for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> but tough on "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">News Quiz</ENAMEX>," already perilously low
on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">favorite targets</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina Brown</ENAMEX>--gone. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Strom Thurmond</ENAMEX>--could go like that.
(Imagine me snapping my fingers, but in an attractive Italian suit and a better
apartment.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gwen Verdon</ENAMEX>--that was a freak accident; I'm sick about it. The
trend is clear.

            Consider
cartoons: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom</ENAMEX> needs <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry</ENAMEX>, Bugs needs <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elmer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J. Edgar Hoover</ENAMEX> needs decent
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> exercising their political freedoms. Our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foes</ENAMEX> define us. Far more
quiz responses kicked at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">D'Amato</ENAMEX> than at anyone else. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Quiz</ENAMEX> encouraged
this piling on, but certainly some of it was heartfelt.) What will we do
without him? Sure, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudy Giuliani</ENAMEX> is drawn to national <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> like a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX> to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">flame</ENAMEX>, if the flame is a trash fire or maybe a pile of old tires. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sorry</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">moth</ENAMEX>.) But his fall will be swift and extremely amusing, yet brief. Whom will
we choose who more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">durably</ENAMEX> embodies coldhearted thugishness, a lack of vision,
and a deep contempt for our democratic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX>? Perhaps we need a retreat.
Can we meet <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this weekend</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bohemian Grove</ENAMEX>?

            
               One Angry
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Man Extra</ENAMEX>
            

            Actual highlights of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX>' video testimony <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> antitrust trial:

            I don't remember using those
words.

            I don't know.

            I don't remember sending
it.

            Well, how would I know
that?

            I have no idea what those
numbers are.

            I don't remember.

            I really don't know what that
means.

talking about when you say "ask."

            I don't know.

            I'm not sure.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Disclaimer</ENAMEX>: All submissions will become the property of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> and
will be published at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> 's discretion. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> may publish your
name on its site in connection with your submission.
            

         
      
   
