
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Foghorn Leghorn Meets an Owl</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">GREENVILLE</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">S.C.</ENAMEX>--It's way
too late for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South Carolina Senate</ENAMEX> race to be a fight for the political
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soul</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX>. (That soul is held under lock and key at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican Party</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX>.) But the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Carolina</ENAMEX> race still probably ranks as the most
important <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> contest of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>. It is important not because <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> must
hold the seat to prevent a filibuster-proof <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">majority</ENAMEX>, though they
must. It is important because it's absolutely, positively the last stand for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic Party</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Dixie</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> know they can't be the majority
party down here. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Carolina</ENAMEX> race tests whether they can be any kind of
party.

            If Sen.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fritz Hollings</ENAMEX> cannot hold his seat--if a powerful, intelligent,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pork-barreling</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">32 year</TIMEX> incumbent, supported by the full force and bankroll of
the national <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic Party</ENAMEX> and opposed by a little-known challenger, cannot
win--then the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic Party</ENAMEX> might as well fold and flee <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">North</ENAMEX>. So I have
come to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greenville</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX> the dogfight between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hollings</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">challenger</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Inglis</ENAMEX>. They are holding their <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> debate <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX> at
the local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">affiliate</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studio</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hollings</ENAMEX> barely won in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s
race promises to be just as tight--<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> polls have Inglis trailing by
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only three</NUMEX> points, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> polls by slightly more.

            The race is as nasty as it is close. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican Party</ENAMEX>
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hollings</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">campaign</ENAMEX> have blanketed the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s airwaves with marginally
true and thoroughly vicious attack ads. And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hollings</ENAMEX>, who is temperamentally
incapable of controlling his tongue, has already called Inglis "a goddamn
skunk," "a fraud," <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"a rascal</ENAMEX>," "an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opportunist</ENAMEX>," "a hypocrite," and--my
favorite--"oozing and goozing."

            You could
not invent <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> with more antithetical worldviews than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hollings</ENAMEX> and
Inglis: This is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Old New South</ENAMEX> vs. the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New New South</ENAMEX>, the New Deal vs. the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich Revolution</ENAMEX>, the good-timer vs. the choirboy.

            
At <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">76</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hollings</ENAMEX> remains the caricature he has
always been. When he enters the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studio</ENAMEX>, it is as though God has arrived. He
looks absurdly distinguished--though his magnificent white mane is starting to
thin. His Southern accent is so impenetrable that during his short-lived but
entertaining <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1984</TIMEX> presidential run, he was introduced by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Kennedy</ENAMEX> as "the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> non-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> speaking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hollings</ENAMEX> is arrogant,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rude</ENAMEX>, vituperative, and overbearing, but he is an utterly ingratiating
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX>. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early '60s</TIMEX>, while his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alabama</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX> were leading the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> to the brink of civil war over civil rights,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hollings</ENAMEX> guided <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Carolina</ENAMEX>--very slowly, it must be admitted--toward
peaceful integration. As a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX>, he has been an inveterate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">distributor</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pork</ENAMEX> and a fierce, successful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocate</ENAMEX> for the modernization of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Carolina</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hollings</ENAMEX> was an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New South</ENAMEX>, establishing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Carolina</ENAMEX>'s
network of technical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX> and avidly recruiting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> to its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">low-tax</ENAMEX>, anti-union confines.

            The
owlish, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">39-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Inglis</ENAMEX> has none of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hollings</ENAMEX>' presence. He has been
described, perfectly, as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> in your fourth-grade <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> who reminded the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> to collect the homework. Elected to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> with strong
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian Coalition</ENAMEX> support, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Inglis</ENAMEX> out-Gingriches the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gingrichites</ENAMEX>. He hates
government and politics as much as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hollings</ENAMEX> likes them. He is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Man</ENAMEX> of
Principles. He refuses <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">PAC</ENAMEX> money. He chooses to sleep in his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> office
rather than rent a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> (proving either his loyalty to the Palmetto
State or his cheapness). He's a term limits bore. He calls himself,
irritatingly, a "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Young Turk</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inglis</ENAMEX> is so principled, in fact, that he votes
against funding pork projects in his own district. In <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> famous case,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inglis</ENAMEX> helped kill federal funding for a needed <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">highway</ENAMEX>, requiring the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> to
build a toll <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> instead. He has not been forgiven.

            By any rational calculus, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Inglis trounces Hollings</ENAMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX>'s debate. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forum</ENAMEX> is being broadcast to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greenville</ENAMEX> and its environs,
which are among the fastest growing regions in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. The area is
prosperous, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX>, and economically conservative. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inglis</ENAMEX> represents this
district in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>, and he knows how to appeal to it. The fast-growing
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Upcountry</ENAMEX>," as it's called, is the new voting engine of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>: If
Greenvillians come out and vote, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inglis</ENAMEX> will almost certainly beat
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hollings</ENAMEX>.

            To this
conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inglis</ENAMEX> touts his anti-pork philosophy, insisting that he
won't "play by the old system of bringing home a little money and expecting
everyone to fall at my feet and call me Savior." He repeats his call for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to resign, an extremely popular position in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Carolina</ENAMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">castigates</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hollings</ENAMEX> for voting with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. He lectures on the need
to privatize <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> (he refers to the "miracle of compounding" with
the same reverence that most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christians</ENAMEX> reserve for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">loaves</ENAMEX> and fishes).

            
Inglis, knowing of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hollings</ENAMEX>' vitriol, proposed
a "Contract for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Courteous Campaign</ENAMEX>" that would have required <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> to
warn <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> in advance about <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">attacks</ENAMEX> and to minimize negative ads and race
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">baiting</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hollings</ENAMEX> rejected it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several weeks ago</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inglis</ENAMEX> gets fabulous mileage
out of this, doing a brilliant "more in sorrow than in anger" act that casts
him as too horrified even to repeat <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hollings</ENAMEX>' slurs. "Was it distinguished to
call me a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">'g</NUMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">d.</ENAMEX> skunk'? Was it courteous to say 'kiss my blank'? ...Was it
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">courteous</ENAMEX> to refer to black <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">South Carolinians</ENAMEX> in a way I can't describe<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>"
(Glossary: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">g.d.</ENAMEX>" = "goddamn"; "blank" = "fanny"; I have no idea what the last
refers to.)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hollings</ENAMEX>,
meanwhile, looks bored with the entire event. This is his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">sixth</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>
campaign, and he never liked retail politics to begin with. He's slightly
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">frailer</ENAMEX> and less focused than he used to be, and his answers wander away from
the studio <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>'s questions. His off-the-cuff style seems amateurish next
to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inglis</ENAMEX>' polished <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mini-essays</ENAMEX>. He often ignores the camera while he's
talking. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inglis</ENAMEX>, by contrast, all but jams his head into the lens.)

            But after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">45 minutes</TIMEX> of this, I begin to suspect that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hollings</ENAMEX> is being cannier than he lets on. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hollings</ENAMEX> is betting on old-time
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> politics, such as they still are in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Carolina</ENAMEX>. He is counting
on a huge black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">turnout</ENAMEX> and the last few yellow-dog <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>. He doesn't want
to engage <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inglis</ENAMEX> in some lofty debate about principles. The more he contrasts
himself with the cool, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">schoolmarmish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Inglis</ENAMEX>, the better. All <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hollings</ENAMEX> wants to
do is remind <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that he's their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fritz</ENAMEX> and that he got them that road they
needed.

            So
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hollings</ENAMEX> embraces <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inglis</ENAMEX>' charges that he's a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pork</ENAMEX>-barreler: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">He</ENAMEX> calls it pork.
This is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>." He has spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">32 years</TIMEX> wangling <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airports</ENAMEX> and
sewers for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Carolina</ENAMEX>, and he doesn't mind reminding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> about it.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inglis</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> derisively calls this <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hollings</ENAMEX>' "I got you ... I got you ...
I got you ... I got you ... I got you ..." speech. But it works. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Hollings</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">paints Inglis</ENAMEX>' obsession with principles as a handicap, mocking his refusal to
accept home-district <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">goodies</ENAMEX>: "What have you done for your district for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">six</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> other than whine and complain and holler 'pork'<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>"

            
When <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inglis</ENAMEX> vows to serve <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>
terms, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hollings</ENAMEX> crows about his experience. He says that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inglis</ENAMEX> would be "a
whisper" in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lame duck</ENAMEX> as soon as he took office. (There is
something bravely contrarian about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inglis</ENAMEX> campaigning in favor of term limits
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hollings</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Strom Thurmond</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South Carolina</ENAMEX> likes
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">re</ENAMEX>-electing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Between Hollings</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thurmond</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Carolina</ENAMEX> has, what,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8,000 years</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> seniority? Speaking of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thurmond</ENAMEX>, he plays a hilarious
role in this campaign. Both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> cite him as their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX>. To name just
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> example, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hollings</ENAMEX> uses <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thurmond</ENAMEX>'s silence on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> scandal to excuse
his own silence. Since when did the practices of confused, incompetent <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Strom</ENAMEX>
become the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guide</ENAMEX> for senatorial behavior?)

            Inglis
has more ideas, more energy, and--God knows--more principles, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Carolina</ENAMEX>'s young <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian conservatives</ENAMEX> are his for the next generation.
Still, all the older <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">South Carolinians</ENAMEX> I talked to at the debate and in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Greenville</ENAMEX>, without exception, plan to vote for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fritz</ENAMEX>. The loyalty strategy may
succeed for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hollings</ENAMEX>. It won't, of course, succeed for any other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX>. There are no <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> left in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX> who command the
kind of affection that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hollings</ENAMEX> does or who have compiled <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">his 50 year</TIMEX> record.
But <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Carolina</ENAMEX> and in the national <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> don't really care
how <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fritz</ENAMEX> wins. If he wins at all, that will be miracle enough.

            

               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tomorrow</TIMEX>: the bizarre <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Carolina</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX>'s race, which proves that for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic Party</ENAMEX>, there is indeed a fate worse than death.
            

         
      
   
