
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Movies
            

            

               
                  Beloved
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buena Vista Pictures</ENAMEX>). After <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX> of buildup, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>
are ambivalent about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oprah Winfrey</ENAMEX>'s adaptation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Toni Morrison</ENAMEX>'s novel:
"[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX>]he movie is undeniably a labor of devotion and intelligence, but, in the
end, a labor is just what it is" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Owen Gleiberman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Entertainment</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> ). The film gets a few outright raves, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oprah</ENAMEX>'s performance is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">universally</ENAMEX> lauded. "As for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Winfrey</ENAMEX>, one can only say, My God, what a blaze of
genius she is" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Hunter</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> ). But <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> praise
the film's intentions more than the film itself. Other complaints: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) At nearly
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three hours</TIMEX>, the running time is too long. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) The plot is hard to follow if you
haven't read the book. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) The film is too literal an interpretation of a book
whose very essence is obliqueness and indirection. (Find out more about the
film at the official site.)

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Bride</ENAMEX> of Chucky
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Universal Pictures</ENAMEX>). For the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> sequel to a
movie that wasn't great to begin with, this installment in the story of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">demonic</ENAMEX> doll is getting surprisingly good reviews. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Detractors</ENAMEX> are predictably
disgusted: "[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX>]he novelty of a bloody horror film built around a malevolent
doll carrying the soul of a serial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">killer</ENAMEX> has worn thin" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lawrence van Gelder</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ). But <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> say the addition of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer Tilly</ENAMEX> as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chucky</ENAMEX>'s human <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX> (who is later transformed into his doll-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX>)
ratchets up the star power and the fun. They also praise the film's "flair,"
"wit," and willingness to make fun of itself (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leonard Klady</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily</ENAMEX>
Variety ). (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Visit "Chucky's Toybox</ENAMEX>," an unofficial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> site that has film clips,
pictures, news, and a message board all about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chucky.</ENAMEX>)

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Practical Magic</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner Bros.</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Muddled</ENAMEX> and pointless is how
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> describe this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>-power witch movie. Despite two dazzling leading
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ladies</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nicole Kidman</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sandra Bullock</ENAMEX>), the film is said to be unsexy; and
though a comedy about <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> cursed with witchcraft who inadvertently
kill their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boyfriends</ENAMEX>, it is also said to be unfunny. Also annoying: the
obligatory "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dancing Around Like Idiots</ENAMEX>" scene (<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Mick LaSalle</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">San</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Francisco Chronicle</ENAMEX> ) and "estrogen-soaked soundtrack" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Wloszczyna</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> ). A few indulgent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> call it a "guilty pleasure" that is
"transcendentally silly" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Maslin</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ). (Visit the
official
site.)

            

               Theater
            

            

               
                  Corpus Christi
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Terrence McNally</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Manhattan Theater Club</ENAMEX>).
After getting the best possible <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PR</ENAMEX>--an angry religious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> demanding
censorship and a slew of editorials citing the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">First Amendment</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McNally</ENAMEX>'s
latter-day gay interpretation of the life of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> is universally panned.
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Corpus Christi</ENAMEX> has all the power of a slap across the face with a limp
lettuce leaf" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer Harper</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Times</ENAMEX> ). Contrary to
expectations, the play is neither lascivious nor particularly blasphemous. It
"positively exudes a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">puppy</ENAMEX>-like friendliness and eagerness to ingratiate"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald Lyons</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> ).(Learn
more about the protests against the play; read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Weisberg</ENAMEX>'s
review in 
                  Slate
               .)

            

               Music
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Live: 1966</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dylan</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia Records/Legacy</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> wax
poetic about the official release of the hitherto bootlegged "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royal Albert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hall"</ENAMEX> concert: "[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S</ENAMEX>]tunningly good. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX> creates waves of music that crash
onto the shore and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dylan</ENAMEX> is almost giddy as he rides them in" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Hinckley</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Daily News</ENAMEX> ). This pivotal concert <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridges</ENAMEX> the gap between
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dylan</ENAMEX>'s beloved acoustic phase and his controversial electric phase, and the
interplay between a defiant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dylan</ENAMEX> and the disapproving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> is said to fuel
the performance. (
                  Slate
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">'s Jacob Weisberg</ENAMEX> finds the album
"disappointing." Read his review/attack on the myth of bootlegs in general.)

            

               Book
            

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Poisonwood Bible</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara Kingsolver</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HarperFlamingo</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kingsolver</ENAMEX>'s
latest is hailed as a step forward in maturity and scope. The story of a white
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">missionary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Congo</ENAMEX>, the novel is praised for its attention to
detail, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">female</ENAMEX> voices, and critical take on colonialism. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minority</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX> find the political messages "heavy-handed" and say the novel is more
like a "starklylit morality play" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michiko Kakutani</ENAMEX>, the New York
Times ). (Listen to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kingsolver</ENAMEX> read an excerpt from this book.)

            
               Recent
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment</ENAMEX>" columns
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">14:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Man</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- The
Mighty ;

            

               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Slam</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- A <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Night</ENAMEX> at
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roxbury</ENAMEX> ;

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dance -- Swan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Lake</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neil Simon Theatre</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>);

            
               Book -- Work in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Progress</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Eisner</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Schwartz</ENAMEX>;

            

               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pure Drivel</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Martin</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7:</TIMEX>

            

               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Antz</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- What Dreams</ENAMEX>
May Come ;

            

               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Happiness</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- I Married a</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Philip Roth</ENAMEX>;

            
               Television -- The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Secret Diary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Desmond Pfeiffer</ENAMEX> ;

            

               Art --"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Van Gogh</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Van Goghs</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Masterpieces</ENAMEX> From the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Van Gogh Museum</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Amsterdam</ENAMEX>."

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30:</TIMEX>

            

               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ronin</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Urban</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Legend</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Book -- <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">Cities</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Edgar Wideman</ENAMEX>;

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Opera</ENAMEX> -- A Streetcar
Named <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Desire</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Music -- Painted
From Memory , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elvis Costello</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burt Bacharach</ENAMEX>;

            

               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Felicity</ENAMEX> ;

            

               Art --"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">From Van Eyck to Bruegel: Early Netherlandish Painting in the</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metropolitan Museum of Art</ENAMEX>."

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">23:</TIMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Report</ENAMEX> -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>
Report ;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bag</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bones</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen King</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- Model
Behavior , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jay McInerney</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Birds</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lorrie Moore</ENAMEX>;

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Rush</ENAMEX>
Hour ;

            
               Movie -- Permanent
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Midnight</ENAMEX> ;

            

               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- A Soldier's Daughter Never Cries</ENAMEX> .

            
               --Eliza
Truitt
            

         
      
   
