
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">136</NUMEX>:

            By <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cohen</ENAMEX>

            
               Fill in
the blank as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chase Untermeyer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">appointments secretary</ENAMEX>,
assesses the new <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> dynasty led by victorious <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeb</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">W.:</ENAMEX>
            

            
               "It's a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">competitive</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>. I don't think it's competitive with a hard edge to it, but
if you ever see the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">Bushes playing ________________</ENAMEX>, it can be pretty
frightening."
            

            by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> to
e-mail your answer (newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>).

            
               Responses
to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s question (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 135</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">What's the Catch Phrase?</ENAMEX>":
            

            
               "Are you ready to make
real noise<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>" This slogan is part of a new <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">multimillion-dollar</NUMEX> campaign--to
persuade whom to do what?
            

            "To persuade the mute to,
like, get over it."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Franzen</ENAMEX>
            

            "To persuade the new Mrs.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry King</ENAMEX> to moan during sex."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jon Hotchkiss</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Thomas</ENAMEX> had
a similar answer, with self-revelation worthy of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daphne Merkin</ENAMEX>.)

            "It's part of an internal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kellogg</ENAMEX>'s campaign to motivate shy <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Rice Crispies</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jon Schwarz</ENAMEX>
            

            "To persuade the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> to resume nuclear testing ... NOW!"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Brookes</ENAMEX>
            

            "To persuade <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> to
participate more heavily in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Purim</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman Oder</ENAMEX>
            

            Click for more
responses.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
            

            Real noise appeals to the
young and appalls the old. Babies bang wooden spoons on overturned saucepans;
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">grannies rock</ENAMEX> so silently you can hear the creak of floorboards and hip bones.
Rock 'n' roll is loud and young and rebellious; chamber music is soft and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">geriatric</ENAMEX> and bourgeois complacent. Movies, that youthful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">medium</ENAMEX>, are Dolby
loud; books are library quiet. Playgrounds are tumultuous, youthful, and
physical; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX> are hushed, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elderly</ENAMEX>, and spiritual. (Well, white <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX>;
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">black church</ENAMEX> is always shown as a scene of joyful noise. Such is our racial
ideology that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-Americans</ENAMEX> are always presented as loud and physical.)
Silence is passive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">acquiescence</ENAMEX>; noise is open rebellion. Except in the
relentlessly entertaining marketplace, where the television is always on, the
radio always plays, and good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> undergo a constant acoustic bombardment,
lest they have <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five minutes</TIMEX> to quietly think their own thoughts. It has been
widely observed that <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> is noisy, filled with the constant battering of
everybody's radio. And so like some <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">M.C. Escher</ENAMEX> bird-into-fish print, the
cultural meaning of noise is reversed. Noise is status quo; silence is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">subversive</ENAMEX>.

            So if
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">grannies</ENAMEX> are so touchy about noise, why are they always depicted as hard of
hearing?

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">All</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Volunteer Answer</ENAMEX>
            

            To persuade everyone to join
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX>.

            "It's still 'Be all that you
can be,' but we took the experience the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> can offer and packaged it in a
more contemporary fashion," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lt. Col.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Sullivan</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX>'s chief of
marketing and advertising.

            Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy</ENAMEX> failed
to reach their enlistment goals <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy</ENAMEX> since
the draft ended in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1973</TIMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.1 billion</NUMEX> defense bill passed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX>
included <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$113 million</NUMEX> to aid recruiting.

            A thriving economy and higher
military standards have shrunk the pool of potential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteers</ENAMEX>. "Most of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who walk into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> have something wrong with them," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Petty</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Officer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benny Granillo</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recruiter</ENAMEX>.

            There are
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.4 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on active duty in the uniformed services.

            
               Augmented
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rationalizations Extra</ENAMEX>
            

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> responds to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s disappointing returns. (Final
sentences added by "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">News Quiz</ENAMEX>.")

            "I think this was sort of
a status quo election. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slavery</ENAMEX> is still legal, right?"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> Majority
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Lott</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miss.</ENAMEX>
            

            "It's too early to be
disappointed. Now, imagine a humorous, self-deprecating remark about what I'll
do later in my hotel <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>, were I but secure enough in my sexuality to make
such a jibe."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Majority Leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Armey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
            

            "I'd say it's
disappointing. Whatever it is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Armey</ENAMEX> gets <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">up to</NUMEX> in his hotel
room."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Majority Whip</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don Nickles</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Okla.</ENAMEX>
            

            "You would think to do
something for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">70 years</TIMEX> would be a big deal, but not among
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX>. But enough about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Armey</ENAMEX>'s hotel <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> shenanigans; how
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Illinois Senate</ENAMEX> race!"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Speaker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX>,
R-Ga.
            

            "We've got to go after the
minority vote--the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-American</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX>, and every other minority.
And if any of them ever show up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX>, I'm going to, like, not hurt
them."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orrin Hatch</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX>
            

            "The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> demagogued,
and we failed to get our agenda out there. And by 'failed get our agenda out
there,' I of course allude to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Armey</ENAMEX>'s perverse but disappointing hotel
room antics."-- former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Quayle</ENAMEX>
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Disclaimer</ENAMEX>: All submissions will become the property of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> and
will be published at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> 's discretion. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> may publish your
name on its site in connection with your submission.
            

         
      
   
