
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sickbed Populism</ENAMEX>

            A mere <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six months ago</TIMEX>, Big
Tobacco stood astride the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> political scene, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colossus</ENAMEX> of evil. Every
public interest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> despised it. Every <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX> railed against
it. Its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> approval ratings trailed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Tripp</ENAMEX>'s. Its political
contributions were tainted. But then something funny happened on the way to the
ballot box: <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> found themselves a new boogeyman to replace the tobacco
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">barons</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dems</ENAMEX>' new "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">merchants</ENAMEX> of death": health maintenance organization
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bureaucrats</ENAMEX>.

            The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>
campaign's vilification of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMOs</ENAMEX> marks the culmination of a remarkable and
speedy collapse of the industry's image. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Just five years ago</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMOs</ENAMEX> were the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">golden</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> of the busted health-care industry, imposing the cost controls
and efficiencies everyone agreed the system needed. But during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this summer</TIMEX> and
fall, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> have had a field day telling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMO</ENAMEX> horror stories.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMO</ENAMEX> has become a synonym for heartlessness and windfall profit, and political
contributions by health <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">insurers</ENAMEX> are blood money.

            In the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Missouri</ENAMEX> senate race, for example, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> TV
ad declared that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">incumbent</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kit Bond</ENAMEX> would let "insurance company
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bureaucrats</ENAMEX> make your medical decisions" because he had accepted <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$200,000</NUMEX> from
the insurance industry. An ad tarred <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> gubernatorial
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Ryan</ENAMEX> for accepting contributions from "exactly those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMOs</ENAMEX> that
are charging us more while providing us less." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arizona</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Johnson</ENAMEX>
ran ads saying that incumbent <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane Hull</ENAMEX> "has taken <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">tens of</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">dollars</NUMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMOs</ENAMEX> and big insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> and then steadfastly
refused to impose any meaningful reforms on an industry that is clearly out of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX>." In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wisconsin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kentucky</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX>, and elsewhere, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> have anchored their campaigns to HMO reform and
depicted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> as shills for the health insurance industry. The issue is
the key to "almost every race I'm involved in," says <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pollster</ENAMEX>.

            As a
purely political matter, health insurance populism seems all upside for
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> always worry about health care, and they are especially
fretful about managed care. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMOs</ENAMEX> have new rules that they have not adjusted to
and don't much like, and the industry has its share of profiteering shysters.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMOs</ENAMEX> are still an experiment: <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> have not yet decided if we like having
for-profit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> controlling our medical care.

            
The pop culture, a leading political indicator,
is full of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMO</ENAMEX> bashing. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Audiences</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>'s movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">As Good as It</ENAMEX>
Gets burst into applause at the line--voiced by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> of a sick
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>--"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fucking HMO</ENAMEX> bastards! Pieces of shit!" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMO</ENAMEX> horror stories have spread
widely and rapidly: "drive-through" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> deliveries, the experimental
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">chemotherapy</ENAMEX> denied to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">accountant</ENAMEX> who proposed
permitting cataract <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> to have surgery on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">eye</ENAMEX> because you need
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">eye</ENAMEX> to see. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Consumers for Quality Care</ENAMEX>, an anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>, even picks
an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMO</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Casualty of the Day</ENAMEX>.")

            All this is fertile soil for
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>, after all, did just kill a
(relatively modest) HMO reform bill. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> are in the pockets of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMO</ENAMEX> and insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">industries</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Majority Leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Lott</ENAMEX>'s office
told health insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> to "get off your wallets." And they did,
forking over <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> this election cycle.) And <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>' proposed
reforms are not elaborate and not unreasonable: the right to sue your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMO</ENAMEX>, the
right to appeal denial of treatment, no gag rules for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX>, and easier
emergency <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> access. One survey showed that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">90 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> support
such changes, and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">85 percent</NUMEX> would favor a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> who supports them.

            
(<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMO</ENAMEX> bashing is also an unexpected windfall from the defeat of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX> health plan. Under the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> plan there would have been tacit
rationing, limits on service, and more rules about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> visits--exactly the
kind of bureaucratization and handcuffing of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> so deplore
in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMOs</ENAMEX>. Killing the plan has backfired on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>. Had <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> let
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s plan go forward, they would now be the ones campaigning against
bureaucratic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX> and telling nightmares about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton Care</ENAMEX>. Instead,
managed care went private, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> get to inveigh against it, and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> are absorbing all the blame.)

            Despite its political logic, this vilification of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMOs</ENAMEX> is a
dismaying manifestation of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> common illnesses of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> politics. The first
is Something-for-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nothingism</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> have seized the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMO</ENAMEX> issue this fall
because it is classic entitlement politics. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> are understandably
ambivalent about health insurance. When your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> gets sick, you naturally
despise the frugality that made your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMO</ENAMEX> so attractive when you subscribed.
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> want--no, expect --health care to be both infinite and cheap.
We should have everything, paid for by someone else who shall remain nameless.
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>, by pushing regulation without acknowledging its costs, are feeding
this impossible expectation. (Something-for-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nothingism</ENAMEX> is, of course, the
guiding philosophy of almost all politics. There is no reason health care
should be an exception.)

            A
principled <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> response to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic anti-HMO</ENAMEX> campaign--and a
response that a few <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> are actually making--is to say: "OK, if you
want to have the right to sue your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMO</ENAMEX>, you are going to have accept x
percent higher premiums and that's going to price y <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousand</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>
out of the health insurance market." But most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>, who are as willing
to pander as the next <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> (heck, more willing), are afraid to fight on the
merits. Instead, they are countering <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> boogeyman with another, claiming that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> should reject anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMO Dems</ENAMEX> because they are beholden to trial lawyers.
This is too bad, because a fight on the merits is exactly the way <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Americans</ENAMEX>
could make an informed decision about how much HMO regulation they want.

            
The anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMO</ENAMEX> strategy is also evidence of the
pernicious influence of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Anecdotal Politics</ENAMEX>. The benefits of managed care are
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">unremarkable</ENAMEX> and undramatic (lower premiums, more preventive care). But its
costs are visible and awful (denial of and delays in care). The result:
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> have terrible tales to tell, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> have nothing
to reply with.

            A <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry J. Kaiser</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Family Foundation</ENAMEX> survey found that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> in managed care plans are
basically content with their own care. But they are more worried about the
future than those in fee-for-service plans. Why? Largely because they have
heard so many alarming tales about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMOs</ENAMEX>. Never mind that no hard evidence
exists that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> health care has actually deteriorated under managed
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">care</ENAMEX>.

            This is why managed care is
a genuinely confusing issue: Should <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> believe the anecdotes, which
are real and horrifying, or should they accept the evidence that people
are mostly happy with their own insurance, happy to be paying less, and as
healthy as they have ever been? Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">'98</NUMEX> campaign offer an easy
answer to that question. The difficulty for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> is that neither answer is
completely right and neither is completely wrong.

         
      
   
