
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Courtship of Germany</ENAMEX>

            
               If you missed the most
recent installments of this column, here they are: posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, Oct.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30</TIMEX>, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Oct. 27</TIMEX>.
            

            As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerhard Schröder</ENAMEX> arrived
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> for his first foreign trip as <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chancellor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> were vying for the affection of the new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>'s largest and
most powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Welt am Sonntag</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blair</ENAMEX> claimed that
he wasn't "in any way threatening the relationship between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>,"
which has always been the cornerstone of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Union</ENAMEX>, but he
nevertheless made proposals that were in direct opposition to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>'s stated
national interests. Calling for a more dynamic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anglo</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partnership</ENAMEX> to
tackle <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>'s problems, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair</ENAMEX> wrote that he and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schröder</ENAMEX> wanted to discuss
the pace of enlarging <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> eastward, how to reform and restore confidence in
financial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX>, how to combat over-regulation in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, develop a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> defense identity, reform the common agricultural policy, and correct
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> budget imbalances.

            
Meanwhile, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Le Monde</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> carried a front-page article by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Luc Rosenzweig lamenting Schröder</ENAMEX>'s
apparently excessive Anglo-Saxon leanings. While welcoming the fact that he
paid his first postelection foreign visit (but before he took over as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chancellor</ENAMEX>) to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, the article noted that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schröder</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> wasn't any
better than that of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">predecessor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helmut Kohl</ENAMEX>. An article titled "The
Difficult <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Profession of Francophile</ENAMEX>" said that, in contrast to other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> "starts from the principle that 'francophilia is a natural and normal
thing for other peoples' " It asked, "Are we not the fatherland of the rights
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>? Haven't we in the past raised high the standard of political and social
emancipation for which the whole planet owes us recognition?"

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rosenzweig</ENAMEX> went on to point out that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> did little to
succor its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX>. While <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> was cutting back on its cultural exports, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Germany</ENAMEX>
under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kohl</ENAMEX> had created "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> chairs of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> studies in the most prestigious
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. ... The result: eminent <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">academics</ENAMEX>
have noted that, across the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Atlantic</ENAMEX>, they 'read' <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> more and more with
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">eye-glasses</ENAMEX>."

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> ran an
editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> noting that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schröder</ENAMEX> had spoken of "an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anglo</ENAMEX>-German-French
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'triangle'</ENAMEX>--a key element of which, it goes without saying in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>, is his
confidence that Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair</ENAMEX> will soon come down firmly on the side of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
entry into economic and monetary union." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , which is strongly
against <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> monetary integration, said that "the new <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">programme</ENAMEX> is too heavily stamped with the trademarks of traditional
tax-and-spend socialism to bear scrutiny as a modernising agenda. ... Herr
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schroeder</ENAMEX> may have won over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>'s inherently conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> with his
talk of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">'new centre</ENAMEX>,' but his election swings <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> firmly leftward." It
added, "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Far</ENAMEX> from strengthening the case for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> entry into the European
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monetary Union</ENAMEX>, it strongly reinforces the many good arguments for staying
out."

            
In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>, the conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jerusalem Post</ENAMEX> expressed the
hope <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> that the decision made at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wye Plantation</ENAMEX> talks to establish "a
strategic planning <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX>" between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> might
strengthen the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> commitment to protect <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>'s security against its
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> with nuclear capabilities. But it said that "if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein</ENAMEX>'s recent announcement that he is suspending <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> inspections
entirely--coupled with new evidence that he lied about not arming warheads with
the chemical <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapon VX</ENAMEX>--is not enough to spur <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US</ENAMEX> action, it is hard to imagine
that closer consultations with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> will do so either."

            In
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>, the conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Telegraph</ENAMEX> called for a tough line against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX>. Saying in
an editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> that "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX> means terror, confrontation
and war," that "[h]e is bent on building <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> into a dominant regional power
with the assistance of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> of mass destruction," and that the authority of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX> would be "in tatters if he is allowed to terminate Unscom
operations." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said that "[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">g</ENAMEX>]iving money to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resistance</ENAMEX> is
little more than a symbolic gesture. What is needed is the will to hit <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>
repeatedly from the air until <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX> backs down." It added, "He must now
believe he can defy the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UN</ENAMEX> with impunity. It is time that he was sharply
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">disabused</ENAMEX>."

            After a period since the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> anniversary of the death of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Princess</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>, during which the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> press more or less honored a public
appeal by her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Princes William</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry</ENAMEX>, that it respect her memory, it
is now open <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX> against her with the serialization of new books in the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tabloids</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mail</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> has been running extracts from a
biography of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prince Charles by Penny Junor</ENAMEX>, claiming that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX> had an affair
with her personal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodyguard</ENAMEX> early in the marriage and that she issued death
threats against her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mistress</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Camilla Parker Bowles</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunday Mirror</ENAMEX>, in the
serialization of a book by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>'s "close confidante" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simone Simmons</ENAMEX>, said this
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX> that she had mutilated her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> with a fork, wanted to run off to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Africa</ENAMEX> with a heart <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">surgeon</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hasnat Khan</ENAMEX>, and voted <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">250</NUMEX> times against the
monarchy during a televised debate about its future by pressing the redial
button on her mobile phone.

         
      
   
