
 
     		
 	
 		yeah are you there
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yes
 	
 	
 		okay do you know the question for today
 	
 	
 		uh yes it's about why there aren't more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are voting and participating in
 	
 	
 		and what is your feeling do you think this is
 		vital importance
 	
 	
 		oh absolutely
 	
 	
 		okay do you
 	
 	
 		um i think that uh
 		it's kind of discouraging to um i have been involved in some political campaigns and that kind of thing and it's really discouraging to be in a phone <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> and call <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and not
 		a lot of them are so ill informed they have no idea
 		you know even there's there's an election or
 		and these are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are registered
 	
 	
 		i
 		it  i have worked in some campaigns and it's the most discouraging thing in the world i'm originally from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX>
 		and up there if they miss <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> elections
 		then they have to reregister and i have often wondered if if maybe that would help the situation i don't know
 	
 	
 		well that's a thought
 	
 	
 		well can you come up with anything else that maybe
 		we could do to these people
 	
 	
 		hm  i don't know i i like that idea um
 		oh i had a though just a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> ago but it slipped my mind um
 	
 	
 		oh that's  it's
 	
 	
 		one thing that i that i think probably one of the reasons that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't vote more is because they don't know the candidates
 		and i think sometimes you know that's one thing that i have learned in working working in elections and things is you know sometimes even when you work for someone you don't really know what they're like
 		i know there's been a couple of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that we voted for and worked for and when they got in office it was just a disaster
 	
 	
 		well
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh and</ENAMEX> and i'm not sure how you go about really finding out what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are really like before you vote for them
 	
 	
 		i'm i'm i'm not sure the only thing is if they don't vote they have no right to complain
 	
 	
 		absolutely
 	
 	
 		it is um i don't know why we are so complacent
 		but i'm gonna vote each time right or wrong i'm gonna cast a ballot and then if i'm unhappy with it i have the right to express my opinion
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		so uh there was something else i was gonna
 		and i'm like you i've just lost a train of thought that i had but they have been more little more
 		effective in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX> with having this program that you vote or you lose it
 	
 	
 		now if you just lose if you just skip <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> election
 	
 	
 		no <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three</TIMEX> you have to  you have to skip three
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three</TIMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and um course those can be they can be
 		oh a long time apart but um
 	
 	
 		i think that's an excellent idea because then <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> really have to think about it
 	
 	
 		of course what do you think and this is not one of our questions but what do you think of this no excuse absentee balloting
 	
 	
 		no excuse i i'm not sure if i'm familiar with that or not
 	
 	
 		okay
 		i'm sure all over the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> now you have <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three weeks</TIMEX> to go for absentee balloting
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and you don't have to have be sick out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> or anything there there is no excuse anyone can go and vote
 	
 	
 		oh i think that's great uh
 	
 	
 		do you
 	
 	
 		actually you know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> has run for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> before and sometimes it's nice to be able to go ahead of time and vote because you know if you're gonna be tied up that day
 		uh campaigning or whatever it might be um that kind of just kind of takes that load off you know you can just go ahead and get that taken care of and
 	
 	
 		but that is an excuse and that would i could live with
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but this idea of anyone well i just i am so bitterly opposed to this if you're busy that has always been a legitimate excuse
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		if you are incapacitated ill health but to have the expense of
 		let's see they have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> at my polling place they can come from all over the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> and i don't know why we couldn't have duplicate voting on some of this
 	
 	
 		well hopefully once they have uh
 		you know once they've checked them off the list they they do have to check them off a list
 	
 	
 		yes i know
 	
 	
 		when they vote so hopefully they couldn't
 	
 	
 		but is there is every list checked as thoroughly as a you know we back in it when i lived
 		
 		
 	