
 
     		
 	
 		so what kind of music do you like
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i like um a wide variety like programmed into my radio my car radio i have any everything everything from like soul
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		to uh like some easy listening i have the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Edge</ENAMEX> on there
 	
 	
 		um-hum uh where do you live
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">um New Wave oh Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay i'm from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		where are you from
 		okay then you wouldn't know what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Edge</ENAMEX> is  it's kind of like new not punk or anything but just new age <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Wave</ENAMEX> or whatever how about you
 	
 	
 		right exactly
 		okay
 		um well i like a lot of folk music and jazz and different sorts of experimental music
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		like New Age
 	
 	
 		um yeah some stuff that you could call New Age let's see i like uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cherry Riley</ENAMEX> a lot
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		i don't know who that is
 	
 	
 		and okay uh let's see well who do you like from that category yeah say
 	
 	
 		from New Age well i was talking about like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Wave</ENAMEX> or uh-huh um-hum
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">uh New Wave</ENAMEX> all right okay well who do you like like that i mean
 	
 	
 		oh God i don't know anybody's name um  um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Murphy</ENAMEX> or um
 	
 	
 		okay
 		yeah i'm not i'm not that crazy about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauhaus</ENAMEX> um i liked <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joy Division</ENAMEX> a lot and
 	
 	
 		trying to think what else Simple Minds
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		um-hum you probably know a lot more about music than i do i just listen to it while i'm driving basically uh i don't even have a stereo at the moment
 	
 	
 		oh oh maybe right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh how horrible how  how can you live like that um
 	
 	
 		so uh-huh
 		um-hum it's pretty hard
 	
 	
 		right um let's see and
 	
 	
 		um
 		but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soul</ENAMEX> you know i like everybody um don't die but  i like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vanilla Ice</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MC Hammer</ENAMEX> and um um the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jacksons Michael</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 		okay
 		um-hum yes i think
 	
 	
 		Terrance
 	
 	
 		right least the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jacksons i</ENAMEX> can agree with you
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Terence</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent D'Arby</ENAMEX> uh
 	
 	
 		uh
 		um-hum yeah you like stuff like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prince</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		just everybody yeah i like him except for his latest song Cream i could live without
 	
 	
 		and
 		his what
 	
 	
 		his latest song Cream i could live without
 	
 	
 		okay uh let's see yeah i think i heard that
 	
 	
 		but like <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Purple Rain i</ENAMEX> liked
 	
 	
 		once i like what i've heard of the new album
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		his uh
 	
 	
 		i like his old stuff
 	
 	
 		uh like what
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">um Purple Rain</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i have that tape um
 	
 	
 		yeah well that's very good have you heard uh Dirty Mind
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		hum-um i don't think so
 	
 	
 		oh that's a that's a fantastic album it's even
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		earlier it's one of those where he's playing all the instruments and it's uh actually pretty brilliant a lot of it's uh like the dirty side of his stuff
 	
 	
 		hm
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but that's all right too
 	
 	
 		yeah he's always been kind of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pervert</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		which is weird because it's like on one hand he's so religious and then on the other hand he's such a big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pervert</ENAMEX> you know kind of ironic
 	
 	
 		right well
 		yeah well i think that kind of happens for
 		a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> i mean you could say the same sort of thing about
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elvis or Jerry Lee Lewis</ENAMEX> or something or well <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy Swaggert</ENAMEX> he's in  he's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singer</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um-hum um-hum that's true
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		they abuse their power
 	
 	
 		uh right uh and no it seems that a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christians</ENAMEX> seem to sort of walk the line between uh
 	
 	
 		hm
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		hm
 	
 	
 		you know total depravity and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know and religion and asceticism you know
 	
 	
 		hm
 		hm
 		how old are you
 	
 	
 		what
 	
 	
 		how old are you
 	
 	
 		i'm <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty uh uh six</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you use a lot of big vocabulary words i was just wondering
 	
 	
 		uh oh well
 		um
 	
 	
 		hm
 		what's your major
 	
 	
 		acoustics
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		i was thinking <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> or something
 	
 	
 		okay yeah no i'm in engineering basically
 	
 	
 		hm
 		hm
 	
 	
 		but i'm very interested in music anyway i play some stuff and i'm a radio <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DJ</ENAMEX> and blah blah blah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh neat
 		hm
 		how did you get into that
 	
 	
 		um
 		well just
 		i worked for a radio station as an undergraduate just the college radio station and had
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		where where'd you go to school
 	
 	
 		had to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Goshen College</ENAMEX> which is in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		hm
 		hm
 	
 	
 		and i found it
 		to be a very
 		good experience i mean besides having access to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of records i liked being able to control the airwaves you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so now i'm just working for the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campus</ENAMEX> radio station at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Penn State</ENAMEX> where i am
 	
 	
 		neat
 		neat
 		so no wonder you know so much about music
 	
 	
 		okay  oh well um let's see we're really supposed to talk about that then um
 	
 	
 		um-hum oh it really doesn't matter to tell you the truth
 		
 		
 	