
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		what is it about nursing homes
 	
 	
 		um well about nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> and and older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> has a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> that lives with his mother
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they're just really close here and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> has bad health too and so i go over sometimes in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> when he's at work and i um help with her and bathe her and feed her
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and um and i i it's hard to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">caretaker</ENAMEX> i really believe it's really difficult to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">caretaker</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty four hours a day</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh it's very difficult i know
 	
 	
 		uh it she has <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Alzheimer's</ENAMEX> and does not remember
 		uh a lot if anything and so she asks the same questions over and over again
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		which is not unrealistic you know unrealistic um and so you just have to try and be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> and answer them again or just answer another question
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeam
 	
 	
 		uh i i some <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nights</TIMEX> his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> calls me and says can your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and just bring the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and just come over and and visit grandma because she gets very disoriented
 	
 	
 		yeah how old is she
 	
 	
 		she's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ninety two</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh my see my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ninety two</NUMEX> and still uh he and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> still live at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and drive and
 	
 	
 		oh well i think that's wonderful
 	
 	
 		and do the whole thing but you know if something would uh whenever something happens to one of them then
 		i don't know what i'll do up there i i just know that too many horror stories about nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> and so
 	
 	
 		well
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah i was just <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gonna</ENAMEX> say
 	
 	
 		they're in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Missouri</ENAMEX> and i could i i know i know stories for sure that they just they they just well they can't take the proper care of them most of them
 	
 	
 		yeah um
 	
 	
 		and uh it's it's tragic that you know when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> live so long that they uh
 		don't have a place really don't have a place to go
 	
 	
 		yes uh i think it's wonderful these these places that aren't nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> necessarily but they can and reside there like little apartment <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">places</ENAMEX> in between places
 	
 	
 		so
 		right
 	
 	
 		and i like that idea if they can handle it themselves um
 	
 	
 		yeah there's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> very close to where my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> are but uh
 		i think it would be nice but my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>'s the type he wouldn't wanna spend the money on anything so uh i mean he's from that old depression <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">era</TIMEX> and uh you know it's oh it's just blissful that they're both able to do everything for themselves
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i would imagine that i'll uh if something happens i'll move <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of them or both you know in in with me
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so uh but i know a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have said that and then find out how tough it is and but i think you'd have to really they also wanted us to talk about you'd have to really check on the uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		nursing homes
 	
 	
 		on this this <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> but i just don't know how much you can see when you go for a i think you just have to drop in all uh unexpectedly a lot
 	
 	
 		visit
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> when they put <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurses</ENAMEX> home they never see them
 	
 	
 		they don't go and see them that's right that's right
 	
 	
 		they never go to see them i've talked to many uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> of places and say that nobody even maybe maybe <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know um i i think nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> are
 		our um some are good i have to say that but for the most part i truly believe that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> would be better if they were with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um-hum right
 		oh i do too
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		or if  if they could be real real nearby where they could see them everyday or so
 	
 	
 		right right
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> because i know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Governor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richards</ENAMEX> is really upset about what she's finding in the nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes homes</ENAMEX> uh
 		regulation in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> so maybe we'll get it improved
 	
 	
 		um-hum i hope so you know it's i think it's very difficult in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place to make that choice
 	
 	
 		so  anyway
 		right
 	
 	
 		to have them go there and then if you find out that they are not having good care you know i'm sure that it is just you know you'd pull them out of there so fast
 	
 	
 		oh it's tough i'm sure
 		oh
 		right it'd be devastating i'm sure so
 	
 	
 		and uh and yet if you didn't feel like you could be a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">caretaker</ENAMEX> i don't  it's a very very hard decision i think
 	
 	
 		it is a tough decision and it's one that needs a great deal of thought and prior probably
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		i think that's right and especially if you're not a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> that is like a medical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> maybe or something that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> needs medical treatment
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right
 	
 	
 		now i know a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of mine who had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> um she brought to her home
 		um to live there but he needed the medical treatment and she had a nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> come in like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times a week to to help him out
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and that might be a partial solution or something but um
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		i personally am for the trying it at home <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">caretaker</ENAMEX> part before i think i'd ever
 	
 	
 		i would hope we could do that and then go from there
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		well anyway
 	
 	
 		well  i i think we kind of are along the same lines
 	
 	
 		we've covered a little bit and uh it's good to hear from you and
 	
 	
 		good to hear from you have a lovely day
 	
 	
 		have a good have a good life
 		
 		
 	