
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh so what have you seen recently
 	
 	
 		well let's see
 		why don't you start i'm trying to remember
 	
 	
 		okay i've seen uh oh Necessary Roughness
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that was filmed in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Denton</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh have you seen that one
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		it's pretty good
 		i really enjoyed that one
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 		let's see
 		i just rented um we watched um
 		let's see
 	
 	
 		uh let's see i guess one of the last ones i saw that i really enjoyed was Ghost
 	
 	
 		yes wasn't that a good movie
 	
 	
 		that was great
 	
 	
 		i really liked that one
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but i like um
 		oh who's the lead in that Swayze
 		i think he's a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		Swayze yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patrick Swayze</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah we have a
 	
 	
 		and
 	
 	
 		personal acquaintance with
 	
 	
 		oh you do
 	
 	
 		his mother
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		she's a dance <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">instructor</ENAMEX> over here
 		not an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">instructor</ENAMEX> so much she choreographed a
 		some of his movies
 	
 	
 		oh really um would that would be wonderful
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patrick Swayze</ENAMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		uh
 		and uh he that one he has out recently that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Point Break</ENAMEX>
 		i haven't seen it but they said it's really good
 	
 	
 		yeah i haven't seen it
 	
 	
 		i haven't seen it
 		we rented um
 		oh what was that movie
 		about the rock <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> and i can't remember what it was now
 	
 	
 		huh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hey Gayle</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> and i can't remember now um
 	
 	
 		
 
 		what was one of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patrick Swayze</ENAMEX>'s last movies
 		getting a little help here
 	
 	
 		i can't remember what that one is um but uh
 		The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Doors</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		Point Break
 	
 	
 		oh yeah that's the one he's in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> and that's suppose to be great
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and then um but i've also rented <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Doors with um</ENAMEX> that story about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morrison</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh
 	
 	
 		i didn't see that or hear any of that
 	
 	
 		that is weird i mean i i couldn't understand it i guess it was real tough to understand
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well i let's see i just uh
 		feel obliged to make a comment that the uh i think the movies have too much violence in them these days
 	
 	
 		i do too i do too
 		um
 		they're unreal i mean it's it's almost too much and
 	
 	
 		and they wonder oh gee i wonder where all this crime is coming from
 	
 	
 		yeah and it's like no we're not provoking it no
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">huh-uh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and and it's even what what kills me even more is what we've allowed to go over the television
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know movies are one thing where there is some type of rating
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but TV is out of control as far as i'm concerned
 	
 	
 		yep
 		it seems that way
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		you know i pretty soon we're going to use every word in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> language on the television and everything else but
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah that's the truth
 		um one of the movies i'm i just moved here from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Dakota</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh Dances with Wolves</ENAMEX> was filmed out by where i
 	
 	
 		that's one of the just the one i was just fixing to say was Dances with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wolves</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah and that's where we lived yeah in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pierre</ENAMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		yeah you liked that i suppose that would be one i would expect you would like yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		but um my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father-in-law</ENAMEX> flies and he flew us over the like the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buffalo ranch</ENAMEX> and everything where they you know took them heat there is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">herd</ENAMEX> of buffalo
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		that they used for that and um
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		that was quite a long movie but it was good
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah it was that was uh
 	
 	
 		it really was
 	
 	
 		
 
 		interesting from the
 		historical standpoint
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah the the hardest part with that is that it was very you know good from a historical part of it but to you know for now there was a lot of um discrimination feelings coming back out
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know living up there with you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tribes</ENAMEX> and things like that it started to come back it started to surface again
 	
 	
 		yeah you heard about them going to rename or uh talking about renaming the
 	
 	
 		which was kind of a
 	
 	
 		the that <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> up there where the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Little Big Horn</ENAMEX> was fought
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah they were going to rename that to
 		oh now i can't remember
 	
 	
 		it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Custer</ENAMEX>'s
 	
 	
 		Custer yep and now they're going to rename it <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Little Big Horn</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and now
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		that's a good idea
 	
 	
 		yeah that whole thing kind of
 		did that
 		and then of course i always watch <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julia Roberts</ENAMEX>' movies
 	
 	
 		pardon
 	
 	
 		i always watch the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julia Roberts</ENAMEX>' movies
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julia Roberts</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pretty Woman</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		hum
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i think <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flatliners i</ENAMEX> really enjoyed
 	
 	
 		i don't think i see i see did i no my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> was watching that i saw little glimpses of it
 	
 	
 		see and i
 		that was really good that was that was weird
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know for to to see if you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s description of that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh that was where they uh
 		these
 		like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> were
 	
 	
 		yeah they were
 	
 	
 		trying to see if they could put them to death and then bring them back
 	
 	
 		right they were like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> medical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah right
 	
 	
 		and he they would put them into death for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">seconds</TIMEX> or whatever and they'd come back out and see how close they could get
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and when they'd come back out they'd bring their sins with them and they had to
 	
 	
 		oh i never did see that part i just saw the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> part
 	
 	
 		and they had to settle their sins because they brought them back with them it was really weird
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but it was
 		
 		
 	