
 
     		
 	
 		real excited when i heard this that's why i've been trying to call <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all day</TIMEX> because i keep getting these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX> like capital punishment so football i love this this is great well we're from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> so we're <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Bronco</ENAMEX> fans
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh yes
 	
 	
 		and um we just moved here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years ago</TIMEX> and they went to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Superbowl</ENAMEX> when we first moved here and they lost again that was pretty pitiful but they seem to be doing pretty good this year
 	
 	
 		well i was from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Illinois</ENAMEX> originally and i grew up a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bear</ENAMEX> fan
 		and uh then we moved here even when we knew we were being transferred here we became Cowboy fans
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and we had some wonderful wonderful <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> there under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Staubach</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		we kind of got spoiled
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		we expected it to continue forever i think they're doing pretty well <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> though
 	
 	
 		well they haven't they haven't have they just lost <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> game this year
 	
 	
 		i think <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> i know they lost yeah to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		two
 		yeah but they're not doing bad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are pretty surprised that they i mean they beat the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Giants</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah and wasn't that fun i went went to the balloon festival in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plano</ENAMEX> and carried my little portable radio with me and i must say i attracted a lot of attention <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> running up saying oh what's the score what's the score
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 		i bet  oh boy i bet all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> that got direct down there were just right on it
 	
 	
 		that's right and that's exactly what they said my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> dragged me away from the television
 	
 	
 		yep
 	
 	
 		and now then i wasn't i had forgotten or i probably wouldn't have been there
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah well i am i'm a big football <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> i never was my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> was a football <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> my whole life and he used to have the <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football pool</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> and all this stuff and i just hated it and i think i was just mad because he spent so much time watching <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sundays</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh so when i met my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> he was watching <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> and i figured out that i couldn't see him <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all weekend</TIMEX> i couldn't see him until like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> because <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Monday Night Football</ENAMEX> if i didn't like football so
 	
 	
 		that's exactly where both of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wives</ENAMEX> came from i think it was uh you know it's easier to join them than fight them
 	
 	
 		yep
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and if you wanna see them you might just as well enjoy <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> and i used to tease my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> sometimes and say my gosh you know  did you bet the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> or something <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> to get so excited about these games
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		uh-huh well i do i just i love it it's such i just think it's such a fun sport and uh i'm just hoping that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Broncos</ENAMEX> can get back on their feet we're not convinced that we're gonna be Cowboy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> yet
 		but uh  well i guess we'll first have to get to used to the idea that we're staying here  that's even harder but
 	
 	
 		well it takes a little brainwashing first
 		yeah are you uh transit usually i mean do you stay not in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> place too long
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		no we're just this is only the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> place we've lived we've only been married for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five and a half years</TIMEX> and uh we have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and he had a uh just got transferred here to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">E Systems</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well it'll take you a little while but you'll probably always have a soft spot in your heart though for for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Denver</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh
 		well i tell you this the weather here and there's no mountains or anything you know and when you go to a <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football game</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> it's
 		you know there's snow and it's an adventure  and here you know you just got to drive down to the to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stadium</ENAMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		oh i know
 		well if they close it in see we'll have the best of both worlds then as they're talking about doing but uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Reeves</ENAMEX> a pretty neat <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> anyway
 	
 	
 		yes
 		well he's from here
 	
 	
 		yeah that's right you know he was one of ours one of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> so we are never we never cheer against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Denver</ENAMEX> unless they're playing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cowboys</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so
 		yeah  that's what i hear
 		which is rare
 	
 	
 		yep
 	
 	
 		which is good yeah but uh i you know it's funny in in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Broncos</ENAMEX> went to the Superbowl <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times in the last i don't know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five or six years</TIMEX> whatever it's been um they have these songs on the radio they take modern popular songs and and
 		change them to fit uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Broncos</ENAMEX> and stuff and they had i was just thinking about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one the other day</TIMEX> uh if i saw a picture of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Elway</ENAMEX> in the in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cafeteria</ENAMEX> at school um but they did the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnny Angel</ENAMEX> they did <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnny Elway</ENAMEX> to that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnny Elway</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i'm uh i was trying to get my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> to sing that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> was just having a fit don't have him sing that song  but they they do a lot of fun things i think <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> is football's kind of a a sport that i think you kind of it's hard not to like it  do you know there's just
 	
 	
 		well there's so much about it to like you know it's so exciting and when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cowboys</ENAMEX> won the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Superbowl</ENAMEX> here course they put together some real cute songs and we all ran out and bought the records and now we feel like they're kind of a collector's item
 	
 	
 		it's exciting yeah
 		yeah yeah they probably i i wish i would've bought the tape when i was in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> because uh i i think about that a lot but you know when i <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> moved here was when they well no i guess it was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a year ago</TIMEX> they did this
 		this interstate seventy <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> song or or
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		whatever it was about <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central Expressway</ENAMEX> and getting it done in nineteen <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ninety five</NUMEX> and everything that was kind of a funny song but they sure do it seems to me like they really love their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cowboys</ENAMEX> here even when they were losing pitifully
 		you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> still support them we drive by some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">everyday</TIMEX> that have big signs we love the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cowboys</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	