
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		so the question the question had something to do with usage of personal computers um
 	
 	
 		yes we are we are talking about computers this morning
 	
 	
 		um i'm a firm <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">believer</ENAMEX> in in having lots of them i'm sitting at my desk now with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> machines in front of me
 	
 	
 		you have you have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> machines around you boy well you've uh you've got me beat i have a a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zenith</ENAMEX> here
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and at home i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commodore</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zenith</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> has an AT&T <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1200</TIMEX> i believe it is
 	
 	
 		good grief what do you do with all those
 	
 	
 		well actually on my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commodore</ENAMEX> i mainly study lottery numbers would you believe i have written some uh programs in basic
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		whereby i can select any number of uh drawings and from that extract the numbers that have appeared the most
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		i have another program in which i can look at the cyclical uh appearance of these numbers
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		to see if there's anything that's consistent on that
 		i have another number that allows me another program that allows me to
 		add all the numbers i want and then it generates a complete set of numbers so that all combinations are covered
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so this is what i do most of the time uh
 	
 	
 		that's what you do on your  at least one of your machines on your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commodore</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		on my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Commodore</ENAMEX> on my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Commodore um</ENAMEX>-hum  and of course i have uh
 		word processors and i write all my letters is is wonderful uh my uh thoughts in my head come in bursts of about a paragraph at a time and i get them all down and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yes
 	
 	
 		naturally on a computer if you make a mistake who cares you can go back and uh correct it very easily
 	
 	
 		yes yes
 	
 	
 		so that makes it very very nice i get all my thoughts down and go back and clean it up very very readily
 		so how about you <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Charles</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well i um i do an awful lot of
 		preparation of documents um uh and i i use
 		word processors and and fancier programs i mean you know graphics programs and simply make all of our slides um some of them i do on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX> some i do on an XT
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um now maybe we don't call these personal computers um
 		i started out with you know an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX> PC back in the
 		you know about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> after they came out
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and you know
 	
 	
 		so where where may i ask where you work sir
 	
 	
 		i i work for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i know you work for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> i just wondering are you a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAVC</ENAMEX> or what
 		what what section of it roughly
 	
 	
 		of in in in an obscure part of the defense department
 	
 	
 		oh uh-huh because see that's my type of work too i work at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Applied Research Lab</ENAMEX> here here on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campus</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		my my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">field</ENAMEX> is underwater acoustics and there's a lot of things we can do with computers into uh studying
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		how
 		uh things vary in the water you know and uh taking advantage of them and so forth so it's a very nice very nice <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">field</ENAMEX> and i i am retiring at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of this month end of December</TIMEX> excuse me
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		are are are you are you also a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> or or do you just research
 	
 	
 		yes
 		i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> i'm an associate professor but my i my i'm a full time researcher
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yes
 	
 	
 		and it's uh been a very very interesting career believe me
 	
 	
 		i can believe what are you gonna what are you gonna do when you stop i mean  take all your machines with you or
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well
 		well uh
 		the ones here in the laboratory obviously i'm they're gonna stay but i have similar machines at home i would consider uh uh doing some more consulting when i get home
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i have a very very busy extra life anyway i'm also a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">musician</ENAMEX> and i play in several symphony <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">orchestras</ENAMEX> and uh i run a concert <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yes
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so i have a lot of external uh interests
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		but i do want to get very deeply much more deeply into computer work because obviously the world is gonna be controlled run and operated by computers in the future there's no doubt about it because it is really taking over
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yes
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and the amount of work that we're doing and the depth of things that we are studying can basically only be handled by computers because uh it's so much involved
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it sounds as though you're probably more aware of that than i am because uh i don't get to use it in my <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> work as much as i would like to
 		here again let's say i'm starting to getting ready in preparation for retirement and uh so basically what i'm doing is
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		slowly getting rid of my things for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many many years</TIMEX> i had a full size acoustics uh
 		study <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">laboratory</ENAMEX> where where i could take recordings and and uh perform experiments with them and so forth and so that's gone now and so i'm sort of out of business
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> as i say i worked with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAVC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fellow</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Blazey</ENAMEX> was the fellow i worked with for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many many years</TIMEX> and he is now retired
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so it's been an interesting life and computers have come in towards the
 		latter end of that i wish we'd had computers in the very beginning it would have been
 		
 		
 	