
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well let's see we're supposed to talk about movies
 	
 	
 		yes uh have you seen any recently or
 	
 	
 		i don't uh i'm trying to  think i have not gone out to a movie we rent a few but i haven't rented rented <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> real lately so you name a few that you've seen see if i've seen them
 	
 	
 		um we just went out to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about couple weeks ago</TIMEX> it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Necessary Roughness</ENAMEX> the one that was filmed in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Denton</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i've not seen it i've not seen it but i've heard a little bit about it
 	
 	
 		yeah it it was pretty good but i i don't know if if you saw this and you weren't in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> or around <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> if you'd understand some of it
 	
 	
 		oh is that right
 	
 	
 		yes i don't know if it'd be good if you were outside of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> but
 	
 	
 		well i i was just reading about it though and it's uh it's been a sleeper hit it's already grossed like <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">forty million dollars</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		so it's it's actually becoming a pretty good hit across the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well that's good it it yeah that's good um let's see
 	
 	
 		so they are liking it
 		and uh
 		it's just i think just a silly entertaining movie movie from what the articles i've read about it which you know you go just to be entertained and and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are liking it for that
 	
 	
 		yeah that's what it is
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah and and that's good um that's pretty much what it was about it was just uh you know a a comedy you know just a a football <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> that was bad and come up you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh yeah</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh we just moved here from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Dakota</ENAMEX> and uh <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dances With Wolves</ENAMEX> was filmed up there when we were there um-hum and we saw that where they filmed they filmed it in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pierre South Dakota</ENAMEX> and that's where we went to see it
 	
 	
 		did you
 		right
 		oh oh you went out and watched them film
 	
 	
 		um yeah they the buffalo and all that on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ranch</ENAMEX> um my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father-in-law</ENAMEX> owns a plane and he um took us to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buffalo ranch</ENAMEX> and where they you know use the buffalo to film and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh took us out there and you never knew that there was so much land that was not developed you know until you go you know and see that yes but um
 	
 	
 		i bet that's true  a lot of wide open spaces out there
 		i've never been up that direction i'd like to
 	
 	
 		yeah it's nice
 	
 	
 		the main thing i think about is that it gets so cold in the winter up there
 	
 	
 		it is it's like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> now you know it's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between thirty</TIMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">forty</NUMEX> and we we've just moved here and we call <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> back there and they just can't believe that we're still wearing shorts and going out and
 	
 	
 		wow
 		and and will occasionally up until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thanksgiving</TIMEX> probably
 	
 	
 		is that when it starts changing
 	
 	
 		well we'll we'll have some cold <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> you know like uh in in uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX> you know we had some pretty cold <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nights</TIMEX> but uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh up until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thanksgiving</TIMEX> really uh well we usually get our <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">frost middle of November</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay yeah they've had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> already <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> freezes
 	
 	
 		somewhere
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so
 		and so and that was a really good movie and it lasted <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three hours</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		do you have the time
 		<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three hours</TIMEX> that's the only complaint i've heard about that it's so long
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		it's it's really long but i don't know it didn't feel like it was that long but after you got out and thought oh wow  it was longer but um <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Costner</ENAMEX> was really good in that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> passes fast huh
 		it's
 		oh i like him everything i've seen him in i've liked real well
 	
 	
 		oh i think he's great
 		um-hum he's you know done uh i can't remember now but the baseball show um
 	
 	
 		yeah uh <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Field of Dreams</ENAMEX> yeah that was good i saw that one
 	
 	
 		yes <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Field of Dreams</ENAMEX> and have you seen <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin Hood</ENAMEX> with him in it or
 	
 	
 		no i haven't
 	
 	
 		i haven't either and i've heard that's just great
 	
 	
 		i bet it is is uh i've not even i don't think i've even read i usually read the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> and i pretty well agree with their thinking on most movies
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh but i've i've don't believe i've read one about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin Hood</ENAMEX> yet it's already it's yeah it's released isn't it
 	
 	
 		um-hum yeah it's probably been out for you know like a month now yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah maybe that's why they'll get to it shortly
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but uh is it on uh video yet
 	
 	
 		um no huh-uh i don't think it's out on video yet i still think it's at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theaters</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but um
 	
 	
 		i need to get that <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Dances With Wolves i</ENAMEX> would sort of like it at first i thought uh i don't know you know
 	
 	
 		uh-huh well
 	
 	
 		i'm tired of having these <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indians</ENAMEX> everybody pushed down our throats how we've mistreated them so and all that
 	
 	
 		oh and see that's how we've you know we come out of it going yeah we come out of it going you know it's it's hard you know for us you know it was a good movie it interpreted what happened then but
 	
 	
 		i'm sick of all that
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it brought out a lot that isn't going on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> that they again felt that they were you know being so mistreated and and and yes and it was not what we mean now you know
 	
 	
 		right
 		uh pushing a little too far yeah yeah that's
 		that's the very reason i have not even rented it from the video i i and everyone that uh i've talked to has said yes you'll love it you'll love it and i'm sure i will
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh and i'm sure i'll see it before too long
 	
 	
 		because that's quite a deal you know being up in there in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Dakota</ENAMEX> where we have to pay the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> funds to them and keep the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tribes</ENAMEX> going and and you know it it hurts me because
 	
 	
 		i bet it is
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know i have to keep paying this but yet i don't feel that i did anything to them but you know we have to keep doing this and you know
 	
 	
 		that's true
 		that's true you know uh just because our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ancestors</ENAMEX> did certain things they did it i think as a matter of survival and not to be
 	
 	
 		right
 		and how they lived
 	
 	
 		brutish to other to some other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you know
 	
 	
 		right and and how they lived is very different from what we try to do now and and i feel that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		we're not working with territory or things like that now that we're overpowering somebody's <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">territory</ENAMEX> or something like that now but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yes
 	
 	
 		but um you know i've i've seen a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julia Roberts</ENAMEX> movies
 	
 	
 		i like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julia</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i do too
 	
 	
 		i like her i uh i'm trying to think what my favorite with her was uh oh what is it where
 		
 		
 	