
 
     		
 	
 		okay i'll just go with you first what kind of eating out do you enjoy
 	
 	
 		
 
 		okay  well i like dining out of course it means that i don't have to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cook</ENAMEX> but um i'm a divorced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> and you know when when we dine out
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we go to like medium priced <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> i don't i don't particularly i think it's sort of a waste of money to go real to a real high priced restaurant
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		do you go like home cooking like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Black-Eyed Pea</ENAMEX> and that kind of thing or cafeteria
 	
 	
 		um yeah um
 		not really we go  more for the um <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> and stuff like that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> stuff that i can't cook  yeah
 	
 	
 		me too
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> uh-huh uh we do too we do the same what are your favorite places
 	
 	
 		um well i like <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> food um uh there's a little place down on what is that <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Coit Road um</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese Pavilion</ENAMEX> or something that is really good and i like it and um i do i do like <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> buffets
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh yeah well we go we've gone to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">August Moon</ENAMEX> and we think that was real good but our favorite when you have a little more to spend is to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">May Dragon</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and those are excellent they're really a nice place you could take someone to eat it's not the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the rinky</TIMEX>-dink <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">decorations</ENAMEX> but it's a very elegant nice place to eat  we go
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		very very often we go out for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fajitas</ENAMEX> that's my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s just gotten stuck and we go to On the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Border</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and lots of places that have uh i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Costa Rosa</ENAMEX> and some of those and get <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fajitas</ENAMEX> and he'll just eat chips till we've got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three or four</NUMEX> baskets coming back
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last weekend</TIMEX> we went out for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> also and for some reason the cooler weather makes me tend to wanna go eat  lasagna and  garlic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX>  so we went to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">El Sorrento</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right uh-huh uh-huh have yeah have you ever um tried <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pappasito</ENAMEX>'s
 	
 	
 		and it was fun
 		you know what this is that's real funny you said that because we were coming back <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob</ENAMEX> pointed to it and he said i keep hearing good things about that place we're gonna have to go
 	
 	
 		oh it is delicious
 	
 	
 		that's what he said that in fact you're about the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last month</TIMEX> that said that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so i guess we'll have to do it he
 	
 	
 		it's you always stand in line when you go but it's worth the wait
 	
 	
 		that's what that's what it D <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Magazine</ENAMEX> said that it said there was always a line but that's probably i mean that's a good that's a good sign
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX>  and have you ever tried um the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Macaroni Grill</ENAMEX> up on
 	
 	
 		yes we did now my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> didn't like it because they just wanted to get plain old spaghetti
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		or lasagna and most of those things were a little more northern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and they like just the traditional they're not very
 	
 	
 		that they're they're the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spaghetti Warehouse</ENAMEX> type  right yeah yeah  my little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> likes uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spaghetti Warehouse</ENAMEX> real well  it's real entertaining for her
 	
 	
 		yes they are exactly  exactly the place of the seventies
 		um-hum yeah most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> do  what do you ever go for steak just a steak and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">potato</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salad</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX> that kind of thing
 	
 	
 		um
 		not really that's a steak something that i <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cook</ENAMEX> at home
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know that that you grill out and i really don't particularly um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well i'm i'm real curious to try this one that has such horrid commercials the uh that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Del Lincoln</ENAMEX> and
 		oh what is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>'s name they do those real corny commercials
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		it's um over there's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> over there in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Addison</ENAMEX>
 		i can't remember his name anyhow it's some
 	
 	
 		steak
 	
 	
 		yeah it's some famous steak place over in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Addison</ENAMEX> there's a there's a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> downtown
 		and they have these really corny radio commercials but their steak their steak is supposed to be wonderful so i had i had not tried that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> was saying that up north they have such nice <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> where you can go after a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">theater</ENAMEX> or after the movie
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it seems like i've been we we found those <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time and then they discontinued it was over in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Addison</ENAMEX> and then they um closed up  so most of these places are pretty much just uh theme <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> around here
 	
 	
 		hm
 		yes
 		right i think that's what goes you know really goes right now in the in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> area of course you know down
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		next to downtown up around <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McKinney</ENAMEX> and everything you know there's just a there's a different class
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well that's exactly true  that's right
 	
 	
 		of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> up there that i can't even touch
 	
 	
 		that's right yeah that's right
 	
 	
 		you know it'd probably take my whole paycheck just to go in and  have one meal up there but um
 	
 	
 		that's even  yeah that's right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		i had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> who was taken to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lawry</ENAMEX>'s downtown for prime rib and i haven't been we usually don't go for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beef</ENAMEX> really anymore we're we've gotten so used to doing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chicken</ENAMEX> and things at home that that's that's usually the way we'll go if we're not going lasagna
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right um-hum
 		um-hum yeah when when i go out it's it's normally to get um some specialty type of food besides you know because you chicken and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">steaks</ENAMEX> and everything i grill at home
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		i know well i understand
 	
 	
 		and and really it's they're a lot better than what i get in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX>  that's right  saves you a little bit money
 	
 	
 		that's right and save you some money too
 		well now what your what's your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>'s favorite place to eat
 	
 	
 		um
 		favorite place uh she has a lot <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taco Bell</ENAMEX>  yeah that's right
 	
 	
 		oh yeah  they're easy  yeah  well
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		mine enjoy that too they like to go pretty much where we like to go and they'll and then our favorite thing on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Fridays</TIMEX> we generally order <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pizza</ENAMEX> in so not <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pizza Inn</ENAMEX> but <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pizza</ENAMEX> to our house
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 		right uh-huh
 	
 	
 		so we've done that well um is there anything else you'd like to discuss about it i think we've i think it's come to a nice conclusion so i'll talk with you later thank you bye-bye
 	
 	
 		no not that i know of
 		uh-huh thank you bye-bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	