
 
     		
 	
 		uh all right <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carolyn</ENAMEX> do you are you reading the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> about the the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> summit
 	
 	
 		
 
 		uh some
 	
 	
 		yes i'm just a little bit too i think um i think i was worn out worn out from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> after the war
 	
 	
 		yeah i think it kind of uh it didn't really take over the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> page quite as much as it did i think during the war
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh
 		we definitely need something there with all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hostages</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah what that's i think uh i don't know in the short run it would be really nice to get the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hostages</ENAMEX> all back i think that's really uh
 	
 	
 		what all
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		really important i i i can't i guess we grew up in such a different world i could never even imagine taking hostages
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but i think they just have a whole different world than we do so i don't know but i don't know what do you think some of the long term repercussions might be
 	
 	
 		oh well you know i just see this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> situation with with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> and
 		everything there that's happened i think that that crisis has kind of slowed down and i see the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> as being you know the real hot spot of the future so to speak
 	
 	
 		um
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so i guess i view view it as being the prime importance as far as
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		trying to negotiate trying to
 		wind down some of the tensions and everything that are there
 	
 	
 		yeah i think um
 		i don't know i have uh i just have this this civil rights mentality i i guess you know should we or or you know should should we
 		uh those i wish those <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> could have the same type of freedoms or whatever that we do
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i guess that's what i i hope for them but some of them don't want those freedoms i think their their religious beliefs may um
 		may not you know they may not want it as a whole so i think that's something that has to be considered too but i think that's a that's really a long term
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		type thing i don't know the the it said think about long term repercussions and i was just thinking well peace is peace you know and that's really is the nicest thing
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		i guess the question in my mind somewhat and and it depends on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> you know i think some are more peaceful than others
 	
 	
 		um-hum yeah
 	
 	
 		if you look at um <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> for example and you know the recent thing with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UN</ENAMEX> going in there and the the
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		bomb development and all this kind of stuff you know uh gosh i think you know we should have
 		got him while we could
 	
 	
 		yeah yes i i think so i think um
 	
 	
 		or whatever
 		and i think there's a certain mentality to that that's in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> you know that's this constant fighting you know and
 	
 	
 		right i think i think they realized we would probably never push him out and uh i think the other probably all of the other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> said that we were sort of wimpy for not forcing him out because
 	
 	
 		yeah i think they they look at force as a way of
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you you know their their means to their ends
 	
 	
 		yeah yep
 	
 	
 		and um so i you know i don't know so much if these peace talks are gonna
 		i don't know how much they'll stay to them you know if even if we say that we're going to do stuff i don't know how they'll stick to that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i i think the the thing is though i i guess
 		the
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> that used to argue with us or not support any ideas ideas that that coincide with the the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> ideas or whatever used to probably receive money from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i guess that's all gone i think that's really uh probably what started the whole process  i
 	
 	
 		
 
 		uh-huh well that's probably a bonus on our part
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yes it is
 	
 	
 		i think i think that they're so they're so much more vulnerable now because they don't receive support
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> so i guess they're saying well you know we can eat <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> ways or we can get this aid free from these <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> ways we can either act like we're gonna be
 		pro communist or act like we're going to be pro uh
 		pro democracy and whatever gets us the most out of it that's what we'll act like we're going to do but we really won't change in the long run i think that's the way i sort of see them all working you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i tend to agree with you you know i think they have in mind what they want to do and i think
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		a lot of times their slogan is might makes right
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and you know it kind of the forceful
 		you know i don't know i i just don't think peace is
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">uppermost</ENAMEX> in their minds
 	
 	
 		yeah it's it's really funny as an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> and always being an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ally</ENAMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israelis</ENAMEX> i always find it very hard in my heart
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		to align to align with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israelis</ENAMEX> because they seem to be just as bad as the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arabs</ENAMEX>  you know but then again they have to live in that environment they have to be subjected to
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		all of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> bombings and terrorist attacks and whatever and they have to negotiate
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		almost everything and then you think to yourself well you know in your heart you don't want to be aligned with somebody that's mean and cruel to someone else
 		but if that's the environment that they have to live in and survive in then you have to sort of like i don't know logically
 		
 		
 	