
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay so you said that you live in Coppell
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so what is your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> like
 	
 	
 		it's a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedroom</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">two bath</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">duplex</ENAMEX>  brick
 	
 	
 		oh well that's neat
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> is it one that you're renting or buying oh
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		no we own it yeah well our side   uh-huh uh-huh
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah well that's kind of neat that you can even though it's a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">duplex</ENAMEX> you can still buy that's good do you have any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh yeah</ENAMEX>
 		no huh-uh do you
 	
 	
 		yes i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">home</ENAMEX> is really too small for us right now
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		ours is too we outgrew it when we moved in
 	
 	
 		yeah we moved from an <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> that was really small and at the time we just had a little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> that was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five months</TIMEX> old
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and we moved into this <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Garland</ENAMEX> it's in one of the older areas of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>  and one thing i really like is it has big <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> everywhere and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know lots of shade and squirrels and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">birds</ENAMEX> and real pretty but the the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> is real small it has <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">less than a thousand square feet</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 		yeah
 		oh wow
 	
 	
 		yeah it's real little
 	
 	
 		y'all are cramped
 	
 	
 		yeah and now i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> now my the one that was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five months old</TIMEX> is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven years old</TIMEX> and the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and i have another one that's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three and a half</NUMEX> and i have all these clothes and  toys and stuff that we're just trying to find places to put
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		wow
 		uh-huh how many <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedrooms</ENAMEX> is it
 	
 	
 		well they advertised it as a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedroom house</ENAMEX> because it has a a built on addition room you know but the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> that's built on doesn't have a closet
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		ah
 	
 	
 		so um the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that lived here before us did use it for a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedroom</ENAMEX> but we have always just put like our computer and extra toys and books and  you know it's kind of a catchall room
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but it sure is nice to have it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> come over to play they all go out there to play with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Barbies</ENAMEX> and that kind of stuff so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		how fun
 	
 	
 		yeah that works out good  and i'm thankful i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> because they're in bunk beds and so you know they can share a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> and uh make for more space that way
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		and how old's the youngest
 	
 	
 		she's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three and a half</NUMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so um and right now we have their clothes on uh like double racks you know in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">closet</ENAMEX> we made a higher and a lower and it works out fine but they're just about to get too tall  where the dresses are beginning to drag you know and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh we're going to have to figure out a new idea but we're we're kind of looking around and wanting to move into a bigger <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> and  uh hoping to be able to do that within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year or so</TIMEX> so that would be nice
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		that's what we'd like to do
 	
 	
 		yeah is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coppell</ENAMEX> a nice area to live
 	
 	
 		oh it's wonderful place to live and they i don't have any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> so i don't really know but they say that we have wonderful schools
 	
 	
 		well i think i've heard a lot uh about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Coppell</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> that they're real good and that's neat  do you  do you hope to have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> or are you not planning on having any or ah i see  well do you have any <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pets</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum um-hum um</ENAMEX>
 		nah i don't think so nah  oh of course those are my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh yeah  ah so do they stay inside or ah well that's neat
 	
 	
 		yeah they're inside dogs they're my babies
 	
 	
 		yeah  well what are the colors in your house
 	
 	
 		uh um kind of a mauve and gray
 	
 	
 		oh i bet that's pretty
 	
 	
 		um-hum and then the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen</ENAMEX>'s kind of a a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> pink and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> blue and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's all done in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cows</ENAMEX> i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cow nut</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh well that's neat i like <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cows</ENAMEX> too
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah well our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> was redone uh our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> is very old also it's like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty seven years old</TIMEX> yeah and it was redone before we moved in which i'm
 	
 	
 		so
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		wow
 	
 	
 		thankful for that but the it was redone at the time probably when earth tones were in you know everything is like
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		the carpet's kind of a tan and brown and has um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		paneling in the living room and lots of lots of tans and lots of browns but the good thing is you can bring out other colors from that you know so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		uh that's worked out good in the in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen</ENAMEX> they put real pretty blue and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">tan um wallpaper</ENAMEX> and had done it up with blues so that's nice that's
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh sounds pretty
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah we've enjoyed living here it's it's close to my uh oldest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>'s school and that makes it really handy too
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and she really likes her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> so and we're so close to shopping and just
 	
 	
 		well good
 		that's an important factor there
 	
 	
 		yeah what uh how about in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Coppell</ENAMEX> i've always imagined it kind of out away from everything
 	
 	
 		well you know now we have that new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mall</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lewisville</ENAMEX> and that's just like a mile or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> from our house
 	
 	
 		oh really
 		oh well that's nice
 	
 	
 		but when we first moved to Coppell it's what <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six years ago</TIMEX> we didn't even have a grocery store
 	
 	
 		oh wow
 	
 	
 		and now we have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coppell</ENAMEX>'s not really big enough to support <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four four</NUMEX> grocery <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 		yeah yeah but it does sound like it's definitely growing
 	
 	
 		so
 		oh much very much in fact it's about the size now i moved down here from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> what <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty three years ago</TIMEX> and to Lewisville
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh uh-huh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coppell</ENAMEX>'s now about the size that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewisville</ENAMEX> was when when i moved down here
 	
 	
 		oh i see  well when we first moved here we moved here from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lubbock</ENAMEX> and we almost moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lewisville</ENAMEX> that was our <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> choice yeah behind <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Garland</ENAMEX> we  at the time we thought we might buy a mobile home
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh really
 		
 		
 	