
 
     		
 	
 		what what do you feel is the the major change that's been going on
 	
 	
 		
 
 		that's a tough question we're now able to work <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">full eight hours a day</TIMEX> and still do our housework right
 	
 	
 		i think that has been the major change is that
 	
 	
 		don't ask me
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> feel they need to go out and do this they they no longer feel it's um   it's no big deal to to stay home and raise your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> anymore
 	
 	
 		well it has no credibility anymore
 	
 	
 		i know it and i i think i think that's really sad because i think there's going to be a generation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> that are going to grow up raised by somebody else
 	
 	
 		well i'm a school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> and i'm in charge of raising them so i can appreciate it
 	
 	
 		you don't well  i'm i'm still home with with my last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and i wouldn't trade change a minute of it for anything
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh good for you good for you
 	
 	
 		but i i can't i can't help but think that
 		eventually the pendulum's going to swing back the other way again
 	
 	
 		well you know it's interesting because when i heard the topic i was thinking uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this summer</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oprah</ENAMEX> had a TV show
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wives</ENAMEX> that refused to go to work and how their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husbands</ENAMEX> thought they were terrible
 		and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 		and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> said she wasn't pulling her own weight in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and that's frightening
 	
 	
 		oh yeah that's yeah it it's sad
 	
 	
 		and it's you know it was almost from the audience participation it was almost a
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">social</ENAMEX> issue
 		yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were siding with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> saying you've got to go to work if you have these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> you've got to support them
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and nobody would give her credit for being home and raising them
 	
 	
 		uh-huh yeah i i think too many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> feel they need to live a more extravagant life style than necessary
 	
 	
 		that's true
 	
 	
 		uh you know to i i don't think you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> don't benefit from the bigger <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and the fancier <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> and and and this type of thing i think that they would from the you know attention or whatever
 	
 	
 		that's true
 	
 	
 		uh but i i uh i
 		i don't know i i see it as a major problem and i think it's going to have to swing back the other way because i think we're going to have an awful lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> who are going to have major problems from all this
 	
 	
 		yeah well you know i as i said i teach <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		gosh i'm trying to think i don't know i have one woman
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> that i know is home
 		but she also has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		what what grade do you teach
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six seven</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six seven</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> i've got a child uh where do you live are you out
 	
 	
 		in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Richardson</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Richardson</ENAMEX> we're in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plano</ENAMEX> here and i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> in middle school and uh i know there aren't very many but she has a few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> that have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">moms</ENAMEX> who are still at home but do you see
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		um you know do you ever do you ever see problems you know that you feel you know that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are are left alone too much and
 	
 	
 		oh yes
 		yeah i've got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> um that stays with me everyday till <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five</TIMEX> because his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> doesn't come home until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven</TIMEX> and he doesn't wanna to be home from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three thirty to seven</TIMEX> by himself
 	
 	
 		he stays at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and the school allows that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well he stays with me and i have a tendency to work late i work till <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so he stays with me till <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five thirty</TIMEX> and then goes home
 		and you know i have lots of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> because they know i'm there late i'm a slow mover to say the least but um they'll come in and say can i stay with you because i don't wanna go home to an empty house
 	
 	
 		oh my
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and that's frightening because you know the when i said i i'm i'm raising them i am because we're talking about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boyfriends</ENAMEX> and we're talking about
 		what the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> said in class and you know what's right because there's no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> at home to do it
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> to talk to
 	
 	
 		and um
 		it makes a difference i've and just the social values
 	
 	
 		well i've  do you do you feel it will swing back the other way or do you feel there's just going to be a big push to uh you know for for more more and more day care type situations
 	
 	
 		i i don't know
 		i i have a feeling we're gonna go more and more i've got a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty one year</TIMEX> old
 		female and i've got <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty two year old</TIMEX> male
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children child children</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i listen to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> and she's going to work and she's going to buy her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and she's gonna get her <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and then she's gonna have her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 		and then when you know they go on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> salary will they be able to sustain what their lifestyle is
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they back to work and you know i agree with you i was raised in a generation we didn't need all those things
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and we live without them we did fine
 		
 		
 	