
 
     		
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the hardest things in finding child care is deciding to let go what do you think
 	
 	
 		
 
 		now what do you mean by letting go
 	
 	
 		well like going back to work and uh it seems like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> have a very difficult time especially <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> have a very difficult time in uh
 		finding someone well <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> off in going back to work they uh with the little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX> and then then finding someone that satisfies them
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right right well um gosh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are older now so i feel like that that my uh choices are are different <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> when i first
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yes
 	
 	
 		when i <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> went back to work uh you're right i i wanted to have somebody who came into the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and who performed you know certain functions and that closeness and i noticed that as the older they got
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know the less and less picky i got about that um uh that criteria
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh but you know now uh you know i wish there was somebody not so much to babysit the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> but tutor them in homework  really really so but
 	
 	
 		oh yeah and help help with the housework a little bit
 		the the best one i ever had was uh when i had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> and
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh</ENAMEX> was an infant and it was an older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> and she came to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and uh she had <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon meal cooked</TIMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and i came home and ate and everything
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh see that would've been wonderful
 	
 	
 		well of course it was extra special for us because he was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> and i had to work so uh that really helped
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh yeah yeah yeah those uh those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who can uh stay you know home and and take care of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and uh you know do that i think are really special people
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um so you just don't find that anymore um even now the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> cares though are so expensive
 	
 	
 		oh yes
 	
 	
 		that um i don't know how <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> afford them uh
 	
 	
 		i don't either well a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> have had to quit work because of that
 	
 	
 		right right
 	
 	
 		you get one or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> and could be fifty to seventy <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five dollars</NUMEX> a week
 	
 	
 		oh yeah i
 	
 	
 		and then you get <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> and it just multiplies
 	
 	
 		um-hum yeah i i think it's gone up to like a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">hundred dollars</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> and depending on on what age they are
 	
 	
 		oh
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh you know if you want quality day care to where they have uh not only just their meals taken care of those basic necessities but also uh their education too
 	
 	
 		that's true study time and uh if they watch television it's educational only or you know monitor that don't just turn them loose on it
 	
 	
 		um-hum because
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh yeah oh yeah so it's a i i think it's changed over the years
 		um but you know i found uh like i said they at least when my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> were growing up that uh it was harder especially <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> didn't have programs to where they would help you find babysitters yeah
 	
 	
 		oh no huh-uh
 		you found someone in the neighborhood if you were lucky yeah
 	
 	
 		um-hum  that's right that's right and  um-hum
 	
 	
 		it
 		have you had any experience with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who have chosen nannies
 	
 	
 		
 
 		no no but you know i've read um you know some stories uh about that and uh so now now i don't do you know of anybody
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well i'm i do the kind kind of work we
 		we do medical checkups on some who are going to be nannies and the criteria they're using are they want they they require them to have certain blood tests and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		as well as their educational requirements and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> nannies i've talked to who bring the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in are very very uh
 		oh enthusiastic about what they're doing with them and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um they present themselves well but that's as as close as i've come to them
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah no i had just you know read in a uh oh i don't know the the want columns um but i guess when i had thought about it since i've been a single <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> for so long that uh you know i wished i had the money for something like that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh yes
 	
 	
 		because of the special um
 		oh i don't know the um the special closeness that bond that's formed versus taking them to a day care where they just they're one of many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		yeah so that's a that's to me it's extra special
 	
 	
 		well the only i think the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> good thing about day care of course i'm in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandchildren</ENAMEX> age and one of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandchildren</ENAMEX> needed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> care because he needed to the other
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh other uh younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> he needed to learn to share
 	
 	
 		sure sure
 	
 	
 		he was uh his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> couldn't get <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">two feet</NUMEX> from him
 	
 	
 		right right
 	
 	
 		and uh they're hoping that that helps on that course that may be just the age
 	
 	
 		yeah it it could be age but you know i i can never regwet regret uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> going through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that day</TIMEX> care experience because they learned so many things uh such as responsibility independence
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh you know that sharing i mean there are a lot of good things i i know there's a lot of drawbacks to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> going back to to work
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but um i think there was so many positives that that i saw
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		um that i i really didn't have that much guilt about it
 	
 	
 		well good good course what really helps is when you know you have to right
 	
 	
 		yeah that made it real easy  but i i
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	