
 
     		
 	
 		well do you have any <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pets</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes i do i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grisly</ENAMEX> who's a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten year old</TIMEX> uh mixed breed between <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Golden Retriever Afghan Hound</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chow</ENAMEX> and i have a pair of box turtles
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh i used to have box <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">turtles um</ENAMEX> well <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> when i was growing up i
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i really liked them um
 	
 	
 		oh yeah i do too
 		Lucky and Spot that's their names and they live in an aquarium without <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> in my family <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> thinks he's a mother <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">turtle</ENAMEX> and always has his nose all around my <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">turtle</ENAMEX> box
 	
 	
 		oh
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so do you have any <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pets</ENAMEX> now
 	
 	
 		yes um we have one dog a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bichon Frise</ENAMEX> um
 		our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> bred <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">the dogs</ENAMEX> i had never heard of them
 	
 	
 		no i haven't either
 	
 	
 		they're um they're all white and they're small and um and fluffy they don't shed i guess they are distantly related to a poodle but
 		they're not very well known in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and they're not um high strung or over bred
 	
 	
 		oh and how big do they get
 	
 	
 		um
 		ours is uh on the small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">end</ENAMEX> and she's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about ten</NUMEX> pounds and they range from probably <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixteen</TIMEX> pounds
 	
 	
 		oh that's interesting
 	
 	
 		and they love <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> um
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and that was something we were looking for um
 		our our love is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Golden Retrievers</ENAMEX> and
 		that's what we had intended to get in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> but we had a small <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">yard</ENAMEX> and a pool and knowing how they love to dig and love the water um and we thought that was kind of a tough climate
 	
 	
 		yes the water yes
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so uh we ended up getting this and uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> would rather have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Golden Retriever</ENAMEX> though i think  now he wants a
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		a good size dog
 	
 	
 		uh-huh well we've got a good size <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> and we were considering getting a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">puppy</ENAMEX> a small <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> lap top dog
 		for him because he likes other <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> and for me because we used to have a miniature <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">Dachshund</ENAMEX> and i miss having a little one
 	
 	
 		oh
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know around the kind you have sounds very interesting though
 	
 	
 		what they really are um they're really sweet dogs we've uh we thought probably our neighborhood in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> had more of this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">breed</ENAMEX> than any other <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">place</ENAMEX> just because of um
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> that had them and and bred them they had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> litters of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">puppies</ENAMEX> and and a lot of them stayed in the neighborhood because um
 	
 	
 		oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		and how do you spell that breed
 	
 	
 		they
 		it's <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">B I C H O N F</ENAMEX> R I S E
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F R I S E</ENAMEX> and how do you pronounce that
 	
 	
 		Bichon Frise
 	
 	
 		okay
 		i'm writing it out phonetically
 	
 	
 		yeah they're uh
 		and they don't shed so they're they're good <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">allergies</ENAMEX> and they love <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i mean they're
 	
 	
 		yes
 		do they bark a lot
 	
 	
 		um no not really ours um
 		ours barks more than uh than
 		some because she spent a lot of time at our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> house we used to swap back and forth <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> that they have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> dogs they had a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cockapoo</ENAMEX> and and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Bichons</ENAMEX> um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and she didn't bark at all until she spent time there and and um
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		now it's funny she's she's a good watch <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> i mean if there's
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um she'll bark that way but she also talk a lot she
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		um
 		has a definite personality and so if we're leaving her she barks at us because she doesn't want to be left um
 	
 	
 		oh
 		does she ever mess in the house
 	
 	
 		no no and they're um they're very smart dogs the circuses in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> used to use them um for the acts they uh
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		oh they'll dance on their hind legs each
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh gee
 	
 	
 		um  but they're very easy to train and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		and about how much are they
 	
 	
 		well they range i'd noticed up here they're a lot more expensive it seemed to me from the ads in the paper they run <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">anywhere from two hundred</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">four hundred dollars</NUMEX> i think which i thought was a lot
 	
 	
 		and how about the and how about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well she's no longer breeding them but um because her dogs um
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">the second</NUMEX> one that she has was one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">puppies</ENAMEX> from the litter and uh the one male that she used had a tooth problem
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so she only bred that <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> once because it had the tooth problem and did them strictly as <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">um pets</ENAMEX> you know they weren't weren't show quality
 	
 	
 		oh yes
 		just pets
 		yes that's what we'd rather have is just a pet instead of we used to show <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saint Bernards</ENAMEX> when i was a little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> we did that every weekend
 	
 	
 		right
 		oh but yeah it takes a lot of time um
 	
 	
 		yes and it's very expensive
 	
 	
 		yeah um but she might have some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contacts</ENAMEX> here i know originally i know that
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> um
 		was from Plano
 	
 	
 		oh that's where i live
 	
 	
 		oh that's where i live too
 	
 	
 		yeah i'm at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coit</ENAMEX> and Legacy
 		
 		
 	