
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">hello</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">hello</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		hi my name's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gail</ENAMEX> i'm calling from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		hi
 		i'm <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sandy</ENAMEX> i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> too
 	
 	
 		oh what a deal
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hm</ENAMEX> took long enough to find you
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		yeah seems like they take forever any more but um so did you hear what the topic was did she tell you okay
 	
 	
 		yes
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		great well if you're ready then uh i'll just go ahead and start okay hold on
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		
 
 		okay well i guess we're supposed to talk about the changing roles of women
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		seems like um
 		to me everything is just
 		changing so much that it's almost like um
 		you can't keep up with things
 		any more and everything is uh there everyone's striving so much to make it equal between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> i personally i'm a stay home <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> and i like it the way it used to be
 	
 	
 		so am i
 	
 	
 		are you
 	
 	
 		i you know i think it's kind of coming back around to that don't you i mean that there's a lot more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that stay home now than before but
 		i guess more than anything i think maybe <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were just kind of wanting to have the choice of what they could do you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i don't know i mean i think sometimes some of the the women's lib though is kind of like they wanted it all you know and you can't have everything
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i don't i don't think that you can have i mean there's no way i could have a career and then be the kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> that i wanna be
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and to me that's more important
 	
 	
 		how how many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> do you have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> are they young or
 	
 	
 		two
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX> are <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two and nine months</TIMEX>
 		so um being being home is real i i just am fortunate because i don't know a real lot of moms that get to stay home
 		and uh i just it's just weird that i was just talking to somebody this morning who's who's a working uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> a working <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> and
 		you know these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretaries</ENAMEX> and these high power jobs and it just seems like um she she told me now her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> took her <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> steps at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> care
 		and uh i just think i i
 		i just don't agree with that i think it should be
 		that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> should get back to staying home and
 		and being family more family oriented than than not
 		you know it seems like everybody's always so busy with everything that they're doing that there's no time for this and that and the other and i hope it just doesn't get to where
 		you know there's more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> more and more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> going into the work force
 	
 	
 		well i agree i mean but i i hate for them to make <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> feel bad that have to work too saying you know you should stay home you know otherwise your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> aren't going to you know turn out or whatever because that's not fair to
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know like the single moms that have to work or if they wouldn't be able to make ends meet
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		not working or whatever i mean i think it's got to be a personal choice and
 		it's nice that that we could have the choice to stay home
 	
 	
 		yeah well i find that i whenever i have to whenever i'm in a group of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and we're discussing things like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">just over the weekend</TIMEX> i visited my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and some cousins i hadn't seen in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time</TIMEX> and everyone's all interested in what everybody's doing
 		and uh you know well i had my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> with me and i found that all i talked about was my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> which was fine with me but it's like you know here these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are they're going to school getting degrees making all this money and you know they kind of looked at me like i was
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		from the dark ages  you know like i because i didn't have really all that much to talk about uh where career and things like that were concerned
 		i mean you kind of feel little bit like an outcast for a while
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		in social situations sometimes
 		which is too bad because you know
 		i i feel like i don't obviously i don't get paid for my job but i should get paid at least double what my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> makes  working in an office for staying <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> that's what i figure i'm worth a lot as for what i do
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX>
 		but you know i don't know
 		he's kind of a um
 		at at least here i've noticed i'm not from here i'm from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX>
 		but i've really noticed that there are a lot of uh a lot more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are more comfortable at least with some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> being home and
 		at least in the circles i've traveled and in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> that i go to you know that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> don't treat you like you don't know anything generally
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		speaking
 	
 	
 		well and i think a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> are realizing this and offering more opportunities as far as like job sharing or you know even having a day care on site and that kind of stuff and i think that's really important
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		that that they do that and they realize there's a need for that and um
 		i don't know i found when i did do some work when my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> was young it was like contract work and it wasn't where i had to be there <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> but
 		i mean we're going to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> once a week so i don't know how you could have a full time job and ever have any vacation time to do anything besides go to the doctor
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah i can see where that would definitely hinder the problem
 		definitely
 		well
 		
 		
 	