
 
     		
 	
 		well how did you like that topic
 	
 	
 		uh i don't know i've got mixed feelings about the topic
 	
 	
 		do you i don't
 	
 	
 		no okay
 	
 	
 		no i'm pretty opinionated about that and many other things as you well know
 		i agree with it i think uh i think a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> should be able to test at any any employee anytime they see fit
 		i just i just don't think there's a place in our environment environment you know in the work
 	
 	
 		well
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">force</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> either
 	
 	
 		well i don't believe in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> but if you'll remember when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> had to take the TCAT
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		they were talking about drug testing us
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and we were laughing that we'd have to go to that examination to prove we could read and write with a specimen of urine
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and we found it belittling
 	
 	
 		you did uh-huh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		well i can sort of understand that uh but not being a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> as you are you know i i was not quite as sympathetic as you know as i probably would have been if if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kay</ENAMEX> were a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> or something
 	
 	
 		that's true
 	
 	
 		but uh
 	
 	
 		but then you know at the same token i'm not against because i look at airline pilots
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		bus drivers
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that really have other peoples' lives in their hands <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX> it's supposed to be a huge problem with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX> using <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's right that's right
 		that's that's right and i think it is a big problem with them using <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> from what you read you know but uh
 	
 	
 		and alcohol
 		and
 		you know in those areas i really you know do believe that maybe we should clean up our
 		you know house
 	
 	
 		yeah i think so too i i agree with it uh i know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kay</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> you know they started it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">couple of years ago</TIMEX>
 		and so many of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> even the professional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> they were so against them doing that you know and i thought jeez to me it's quite simple uh
 		you either need a job or you don't the the job is what provides all of your needs
 		and uh if they say hey you can't do this work i'd say hey i agree i don't i won't do that and i think most of them have agreed to that now although they didn't like it at first
 	
 	
 		yeah i think it's just like anything else a new concept you know as i had said if i have to go to a testing area with my urine specimen i was insulted
 	
 	
 		yeah it it it is i can see where you would think yeah that is belittling you know i'd probably feel the same way
 		if i had to do that
 	
 	
 		but at the same token in education we can't do drug <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug random drug</ENAMEX> testing on kids
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true
 	
 	
 		you know i mean their rights are protected
 	
 	
 		you bet oh gosh they would they would really raise a stink if that was to happen
 	
 	
 		what well but why if you're going to do <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> why not do the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		when we see them and they're you know under the influence
 	
 	
 		right yes i agree with that i i i wouldn't be opposed to it at all it's just our bleeding heart  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> that would
 		fight it tooth tooth and nail you know
 	
 	
 		that's true
 	
 	
 		but uh  well <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lynn</ENAMEX> i've enjoyed talking with you i don't know how long we're supposed to carry on a conversation do you
 	
 	
 		it's <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three minutes</TIMEX> and the clicker comes in when it's time to
 	
 	
 		oh well we'd better keep talking because i've not heard it have we have you heard it
 	
 	
 		yeah no
 	
 	
 		anyway  we both a  sort of agree on it don't we
 		about about random testing
 	
 	
 		yeah well do we agree or unless it's it's not me  you know here we go again i mean
 	
 	
 		well you see i yeah yeah if you agree
 	
 	
 		yeah you know i believe that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that have even though <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> have other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> lives in their hands and if they come in stoned or they come in drunk
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and there was an incident in my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s high school where a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> stayed drunk
 	
 	
 		is that right
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you just don't think of that happening with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and yet
 	
 	
 		i really don't i when i think of drug testing i'm thinking of the
 		uh you know outside of education
 	
 	
 		uh well no it you know we are as susceptible a society as anybody else
 	
 	
 		sure sure i know that but uh you don't think of that first hand normally
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		yeah well did you hear on the news where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> was up for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> molestation
 	
 	
 		isn't that
 	
 	
 		it was on the news tonight
 	
 	
 		isn't that mind boggling goodness it it is it's mind boggling and well you know i agree with you i know
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> are
 		just like everybody else same problems  the same uh good qualities as anybody else
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		then i think you know if it came push came to shove i'd probably be drug tested
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		you know because it does you know
 	
 	
 		you you think the benefit would be greater than the
 	
 	
 		yeah because you know as i say i'm sitting there fussing and fussing and yet i know of you know one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> who was an alcoholic
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> as well as you know i presume out
 	
 	
 		and that was in your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s high school isn't that amazing
 	
 	
 		um-hum and you know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> brought it to my attention i never was there to see it
 	
 	
 		if it if it's if it was true there i'm sure it's true with just about probably to some degree every <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> there is
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know because they represent a pretty good
 		uh
 	
 	
 		and that's not giving a good example to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no certainly not uh certainly not
 		they don't need that example but
 		
 		
 	