
 
     		
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		
 
 		why don't you go ahead and start
 	
 	
 		okay well we subscribe to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> magazine and to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>
 		and course i like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">People</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> because it's gossipy
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it's fast reading and uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> of course is uh you know more newsworthy and
 		and uh
 		it has more world affair type things of course
 		and then i will purchase a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Good Housekeeping</ENAMEX> occasionally especially around the holiday time because of recipes and ideas and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and things like that and uh do you subscribe to any magazines
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah i well i have in a while for a while i haven't gotten any because i just find that i'm not reading what i'm getting because uh
 		i have so much going on in my life that seems to be the last thing i pick up so i found that i was wasting my money as much as i enjoy them
 		uh when i do subscribe i i've gotten in the past the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parents</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> and uh  the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Housekeeping</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		uh-huh you probably have smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are grown
 	
 	
 		yes yeah
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh i'm letting their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> read on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandchildren</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right well i found that after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of years</TIMEX> of having a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parents</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> it was getting repetitious so i kind of canceled it anyway for that reason
 		uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Housekeeping</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> i do like because they like you say they have nice  uh recipes in them and ideas but uh lately they just been piling up on me so i figured it wasn't uh something i needed at this point in time
 	
 	
 		well do you think that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> subscribe to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> as much as they used to
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i don't know i i well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> would love to have more now he's the type who will get the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">uh Inc</ENAMEX> magazine and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Money</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> and all the financial type magazines
 	
 	
 		yes now my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> does that and you know and of course uh naturally <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> you know and or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sports Illustrated</ENAMEX> but i don't know i know i see <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> leafing through them at the store
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		uh-huh yes
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but you just don't hear <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> talk about them and i know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> when uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> were young and stuff
 		i just loved <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ladies' Home Journal McCall</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Good Housekeeping</ENAMEX> and i took them all and um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		then oh i don't know what in the seventies maybe late seventies they changed their format and i haven't
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i don't think there as good a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> as they used to be even <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Good Housekeeping i</ENAMEX> don't
 	
 	
 		well
 		yeah and and some of those that have what what i consider or what i get the idea that they're maybe the
 		the more pricier type <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> as far as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> they seem to be just so chocked full of of ads
 	
 	
 		oh they are my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> uh takes uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Town and Country and Vogue</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and she sends them to me and there's really nothing in them but advertisements for very expensive clothes very expensive jewelry
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		yes
 	
 	
 		things that the average middle class <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen</ENAMEX> is not going to be purchasing
 	
 	
 		right  yeah
 	
 	
 		you know and if i want to drool or if i want to see how the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> is living
 	
 	
 		yes yeah
 	
 	
 		you know then i can i look through them and i do i just what i do is i flip through them and and pitch them then you know they're not something i  you know take any length of time over
 	
 	
 		yes
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i have discovered that you know with my available time i would rather actually read a book than a magazine
 	
 	
 		yes i enjoy books a lot more that's true
 	
 	
 		yes and um so but
 	
 	
 		well yeah i have certainly stopped subscribing as much as i used to other than my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> have gotten you know they get tons of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> it seems they they're always getting something in the mail
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		and uh so between reading to them and uh reading the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> and then i have a book that i'm occasionally reading when i get a chance but i just don't get a chance for those
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> newsy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> the ones that are full of ads unless you just want to skim through while you're i i read them when i'm at a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> or you know waiting on something like that
 	
 	
 		yes yes i will read them in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> too as i said i i subscribe to uh to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> and to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and i will go through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> but usually not to cover to cover you know i'll glance through it i'll like reading uh
 		you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Passage of People</ENAMEX> or something you know and uh but i do like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> magazine it it reminds me of the old time movie <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> when i was young
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh uh-huh
 	
 	
 		and uh that's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and you know i really like that i enjoy that it's quick reading
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know it doesn't require a lot of thinking and sometimes after i've worked <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all day</TIMEX> and have things to do at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i just i want fluff  i don't want a lot of thinking
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		that's true that kind of is a good way to do it
 	
 	
 		it uh you know it's it's much more relaxing sometimes when i read <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Time magazine</ENAMEX> after i've read an article i'm real depressed over the situation of the world
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so well it seems like we both kind of agree on on the subject of magazines
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh so uh i think that probably i will end the call i've enjoyed
 	
 	
 		okay
 		
 		
 	