
 
     		
 	
 		do you have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		uh yes uh we have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX> uh one's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">freshman</ENAMEX> in college and one's a sophomore in high school and you
 	
 	
 		ah
 		i have one that's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">freshman</ENAMEX> in high school a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> who's a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">sixth</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grader</ENAMEX> in a middle school
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		and i spend most of my time carpooling  the story of my life
 	
 	
 		oh yes  yes uh
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are involved in sports my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX> played basketball for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six years</TIMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> plays football i my rule is that they can't play a sport the same time of the year
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		because there's just not enough of me to drive them around everywhere
 	
 	
 		
 
 		uh well uh
 		yeah we spend a lot spend a  did spend a lot of time uh it really helped when the uh older <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> was old enough to get his license and could uh
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		drive around by himself although that brought in a whole another set of problems  but uh  for yeah for one thing uh
 	
 	
 		i know i know the insurance
 	
 	
 		but yeah we uh we do but our <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> had had uh totally different interests so that there there was not much uh overlap
 		as such the the older one is not was not at all into uh sports for the most part  uh he participated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX> and and uh scouts were his <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> big things and uh
 	
 	
 		yes my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> is in both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX> and scouts too
 	
 	
 		and the younger younger <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> is uh
 		uh the sports <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and the whatever season it is he's he's playing <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">although football</ENAMEX>'s really his favorite yeah
 	
 	
 		oh gee
 	
 	
 		so uh yeah we spend a lot of time uh uh carpooling and uh you know and then trying to be uh at as much as possible with anything that they that they do but then uh
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		we also did do spend uh  time with them trying to trying to uh you know just family time uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we at a at a fairly young age we started teaching them to play games and card games and so forth and and uh
 		uh although we didn't uh do it as much or as often as uh i would have liked to i would like to do that as a as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and and some TV watching what about you
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		we found this <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Oriental</ENAMEX> tile game called mah-jongg
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah i've i've i've heard of that i've never actually never actually played it but
 	
 	
 		have you
 		well it's really fun um one of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> moved here from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Memphis</ENAMEX> and a lot of them played it and she started a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> going in the neighborhood and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> wanted to learn how to play it and it's more fun with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> people
 	
 	
 		yeah yep
 	
 	
 		and it's a game that none of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> know how to play and they both enjoy it so if they want to play they have to play with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> so uh we play that a lot with them
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh we like to go miniature golfing and to movies we have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> that lives outside of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> so we
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		go visit both sets of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX> and and take car trips so that and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> go camping
 	
 	
 		yeah so do we
 		okay
 	
 	
 		with scouts mostly my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> and and i hate camping so we go shopping so that just kind of works out real well and um i'm a writer
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		by profession and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> enjoys writing too so a lot of times she and i will travel to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> conferences together
 	
 	
 		oh now that's neat yeah no we never had anything like like that but that
 	
 	
 		yes
 		yeah so that gives us special time together too and she's on the yearbook <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> and things like that so i can help her with that and she gives me ideas for my writing too so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yep
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh well good well i you know in terms of in terms of any sorts of trends i
 		you know obviously obviously things are different from for for me than and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> than when i was growing up i i i grew up on a farm uh in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		you know the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> was around the the whole time and and what my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> did was was uh interseting you know obvious to me and i i helped out with it but
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh although i have brought my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> into  to see where i work it's not that easy and it's it's certainly not
 		at all common and they they just don't really have that same idea so that there's uh it's it's a whole different uh kind of thing there then then uh
 	
 	
 		right
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s taken us to work with him and we still don't know what he does so we just say he travels a lot so that kind of covers it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah yeah well that makes it hard though for in terms of you know family time with with him
 	
 	
 		yes
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah i've been lucky in that respect that i don't uh don't travel too much
 	
 	
 		he's been on temporary duties where he's been gone <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nine months</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		yes so those are the real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">killers</ENAMEX> if he's just gone he's gone <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three weeks right now</TIMEX> and that's that's mild compared to the big ones so we just you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yes
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i just do the carpooling and and handle whatever needs to be done and something major always needs to be done so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you just have to to handle it till he gets home
 		and hopefully he won't have too many surprises when he gets home
 	
 	
 		yeah right
 		
 
 		
 		
 	