
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh how do you feel about this topic
 	
 	
 		um i think it's just fine  but um i just worry about some things that show up as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> that aren't like i've heard poppy <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">seeds</ENAMEX> come up to be like opium i think they're in the same family
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and just little things like that that um
 		you might get in big trouble for and just because you ate a roll with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">poppy seeds</ENAMEX> on it you know
 	
 	
 		right i understand completely you know i i feel the same way
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know i i believe in drug testing
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know there's nothing wrong with that because something like that if you work in some some types of some type of situations that makes it um
 		makes you unmanageable or something like that that you could either hurt yourself or somebody else
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 		i might really agree with it you know if they tell you before you come into employment like when you're going to get hired
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know i don't see anything wrong with them telling you that you might have to go through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one and</TIMEX> and then
 		sometimes i have a hard time understanding the random
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		you know the i'll pick you out and i'll pick you out and i'll pick you out
 	
 	
 		well random
 	
 	
 		and you go through the drug test
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">random i</ENAMEX> heard was to make it fair so they wouldn't think you're just picking on somebody
 	
 	
 		what's that now
 	
 	
 		i've just heard that the random testing like drawing a name out of a hat or whatever is just so they can't be accused of you know picking on someone in particular that they're suspicious about you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah that's true
 	
 	
 		but um because i work at a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and they were thinking about doing that
 	
 	
 		that's true
 		were they
 	
 	
 		yeah but even though they were i mean who's to say it's random or not you know
 	
 	
 		right and who's to say if it's for sure
 	
 	
 		they could just
 		uh-huh they could be saying it's random and they could be not random
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		yeah where i
 	
 	
 		you can't prove prove that
 	
 	
 		yeah where i was hired they made us sign something saying that we could be um put through one at any time
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		and we were like okay
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but we did have to sign that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but um
 	
 	
 		well i just worry uh you know i don't care so much about well i mean they can they'll get fired whether they do their job or not you know if the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> affect their job that much but
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		um i just worry about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that have jobs that could hurt other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bus</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		stuff like that
 	
 	
 		or air traffic controllers
 	
 	
 		yeah exactly or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX> or
 	
 	
 		right or even somebody on a line you know that could run machinery or something like that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah that's how i feel too
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i don't know have you been in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time</TIMEX> or
 	
 	
 		um-hum about twelve years
 	
 	
 		about twelve years
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i just moved here and then <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Dakota</ENAMEX> is very seldom
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		that you see a drug test
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but
 	
 	
 		i think like
 		if you work in defense like i know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have had to have drug tests for that and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but then they have like a secret clearance
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but um then i know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that work at um
 		you know normal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		some do and some don't require <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> testing you know if it affected the work they might you know wonder but
 		it's not required
 	
 	
 		because i was really surprised because i i go into my major is in accounting
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i've looked at an accounting positions
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and definitely a  a position i've applied for has either come up
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		or you know they won't make you go through one
 	
 	
 		hum even to change position
 	
 	
 		which was a real surprise
 		what's that
 	
 	
 		to change positions
 	
 	
 		no to get a position i just moved here in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Dakota</ENAMEX> and i was real you know shocked to here how many that did
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know from where i'm from it's not
 		that popular or that much i think
 	
 	
 		hum so a lot more here i guess because it's a big big <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> or
 	
 	
 		yes
 		yeah you know like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> has got more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> than the whole state of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Dakota</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and we're closer to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes  that's very true
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and um you know i guess i never was awakened to it you know i knew it was out there but i knew you know i didn't know it was to a an extent
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh i'm glad it's there you know but um
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it was just something that i come across that i wasn't really you know used to
 		but you know i i feel fine with it you know that's not a problem
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		um-hum me neither
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and uh
 	
 	
 		but i'm there's some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that i think there's a cheerleader that's suing a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> for wanting to drug test her and i haven't heard if she's going to win or not but um like a high school
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		can high can a high school do that
 	
 	
 		but because
 		hum
 	
 	
 		can a high school do that
 	

 	
 		um i think because it she's in the extracurricular thing cheerleading
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they they said they could but um i think she's going to try and use like the constitution against them
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		saying it's an invasion of her privacy or something like that and  and i don't know she might win i'm not sure i haven't heard
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah i've never heard of a high school asking a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> to do that i guess
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		huh that is that in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> or
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh the high school that she's from
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um no i think it's out further west maybe <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> or something um-hum
 	
 	
 		oh really
 		huh
 	
 	
 		i thought see i teach so i thought you meant where i teach
 	
 	
 		oh you do teach
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Richardson</ENAMEX> in
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Richardson</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Admissions</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> at UTD
 	
 	
 		he's the what
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Admissions</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> for UTD
 	
 	
 		oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so i kind of know something about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richardson</ENAMEX> but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		how neat so he's um decides if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	