
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		oh okay well i am sorry to do this to you um i don't know if you  explained this is part of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">fund raiser</ENAMEX> for the church
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah i remember it it's just like what do i know about the metric system
 	
 	
 		yeah well i don't know anything so um you know we can just kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wing</ENAMEX> it but if you're ready i'll push <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and we can start and
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		lately their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> has been so full that they've been cutting us off after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about three to five minutes</TIMEX> so it it won't be anything like the
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		okay
 		
 
 		
 
 		i don't know why the last effort failed i i know that it's very hard to get <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to change
 		to do different things i think the metric system is so convenient because it's in multiples of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> um but it's just hard
 		to switch everything over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> managed to do it uh
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		i know the whole world has managed to be doing metric system and we're just left out in the middle of nothing and then having to do the conversions that uh the rest of the world doesn't have to do
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		which makes it more difficult in trading and and that type of thing
 		as far as going back and forth between the two
 	
 	
 		i don't know if they um tried before if there were any way that they could offer incentives to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> that switched uh
 		i don't even really know where to they would begin i mean certainly um it's already being taught in the schools
 	
 	
 		yeah the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> need to do more widespread um you touch it a little here and there and but you're never explained really explained to it all and
 		and actually even in the science classes though a lot of times um the metric system is used rather than
 		um
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> system
 	
 	
 		um-hum well it is a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a an</NUMEX> universal system now uh
 	
 	
 		that we use
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i uh
 		and some ways it's like the idea of the alternative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> calendar uh the way our calendar set up
 		goes back to uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the days</TIMEX> when we were primarily an agricultural <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> they needed the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> home to help with the farming and planting
 		again the rest of the world
 		it has it has already adopted has always had a uh what we call an alternative calendar with more breaks throughout <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> and a shorter <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer vacation</TIMEX> uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and and gradually as things try and uh and
 		using that as a parallel i know different <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">districts</ENAMEX> are trying <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> with you know one or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and then some <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">districts</ENAMEX> have converted uh
 		maybe there's some areas that they could start a conversion like maybe at the gas pumps that would be one way maybe they need to do it in stages
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		i think the most logical way is just to educate very severely or very uh
 		try very hard in the education system and starting with the young eventually eventually they grow old and they take a while to do it that way but um since it's just right now touched on the education system the more that it's used
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> and it's impressed upon the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> the more comfortable they'll feel with it um i don't feel very comfortable with the metric system even though i was exposed to it
 		um but if they did even so even more than they are now eventually um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it would gain popularity as they grow older and they could switch over more easily the more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> they have that's trained on the metric system rather than our system
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> and actually the metric system itself isn't so difficult it's the conversion that's difficult and um
 	
 	
 		right
 		exactly
 	
 	
 		that's what um i look at it from uh
 		trying to feed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> from old recipes and things having i i have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> and when they give me recipes it's hard because they do things in <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">grams</NUMEX> and um you know their whole measuring system is different and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 		i think that's been an area of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resistance</ENAMEX> but i think your idea of uh
 		starting through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and working with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> um certainly easier growing up with it it's easier to learn something when you are young than to relearn and uh
 	
 	
 		right but much easier so and i always had a hard time converting converting it's like why can't we just all do it the same what's the purpose of switching back and forth why are we different
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well i don't know why the effort failed before but i have a feeling that it may have been businesses it would be costly for them to convert over um especially some of the
 		manufacturing industries all the machines they have um to have to convert over to centimeters although several things uh
 		already are i know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> has tools for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> that he has to use
 		
 		
 	