
 
     		
 	
 		okay well what movie have you seen
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i think the last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> that we actually went to go see
 		well there's two i took my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> to see <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">101</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dalmatians</ENAMEX> of course they wanted to see it they had the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> book and they thought that was wonderful and they loved the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		it's one of my favorite even
 	
 	
 		so yes we went with some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> of ours and i was a little worried about my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> he's <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about two and a half</TIMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		he's going through a stage right now where he's kind of afraid of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> barking if he can hear them and can't see them
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and he did real good through the whole movie except the part where the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> are sending the message you know that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">the the puppies</ENAMEX> are missing and it shows the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> and you can hear all the barking but you can't see the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX>  yeah
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		a whole lot uh-huh kind of dark uh-huh
 	
 	
 		yeah so that kind of bothered him but after that he did fine
 	
 	
 		is it well how is he young
 	
 	
 		yeah he'll be <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah okay that makes sense
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>' very favorite and yours may be too young for it was Home Alone
 	
 	
 		i loved that movie
 	
 	
 		they uh well we do too but they just wanna rent that one that is their very favorite
 	
 	
 		probably gives them ideas of what they wanna do right
 	
 	
 		they think that is so cute
 		i guess so so i guess so i guess so we're not real big movie goers ourselves but we did try to go see <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a month ago</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">um  Dead Again</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		that black and white one and i was not real impressed with it in fact we kept sitting there all through the theater going now what what did that mean wait wait run that back and we couldn't run it back
 	
 	
 		wasn't that good
 	
 	
 		um-hum but we we just kept trying to figure it out until finally toward <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX> and we thought we were being very quiet this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> turned around and said could you all please save that for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later</TIMEX> and i'm sorry  so we're just not real big movie goers
 	
 	
 		oh no
 		well i like to watch the movies but it's gotten so expensive that we wait until they come out on video and we rent them
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well that's us too that's us too
 	
 	
 		and now we did go see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Home Alone</ENAMEX> at the dollar movie and that was just hilarious i died
 	
 	
 		yeah i thought that was cute too
 	
 	
 		and we we did also we went to see What About Bob <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one night</TIMEX> which is a funny funny movie with uh
 	
 	
 		well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s name is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob</ENAMEX> and he wants to see that
 	
 	
 		it's a funny movie
 	
 	
 		yeah he wanted to see that i thought the funny part in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Home Alone</ENAMEX> was uh that's good for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> is kind of coming up with how they can deal with problems on their own without panicking
 	
 	
 		that's true
 	
 	
 		and i thought they could learn a lot of lessons from that the little guy's so cute and he's terribly rich by now
 	
 	
 		i hope he stays cute  not spoiled you know you get to where
 	
 	
 		yeah me too
 		oh that's right
 	
 	
 		the money goes to their heads or goes to something you know they grow up too fast so
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		but uh there's a lot i wanna see you know what i try to do when they come out is just make a list of them that look good so that when they come out on video you know i'd like to see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Green</ENAMEX> Card i want to see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Awakenings</ENAMEX>  uh i'd like to see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Silence</ENAMEX> of the Lambs
 	
 	
 		that's right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh Awakening</ENAMEX> is supposed to be wonderful
 		yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Awakening</ENAMEX> is supposed to be wonderful my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> saw that and she said that was an excellent movie
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		and see i've had somebody tell me that Regarding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Henry</ENAMEX> you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harrison Ford</ENAMEX> movie is supposed to be really good i'd like to see that
 	
 	
 		yes yes
 		i think that's supposed to be good and i uh we have some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> who said that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Doctor</ENAMEX> was just wonderful um-hum
 	
 	
 		i've heard that's good yeah so i think there's a bunch of good movies coming out my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids wanna</ENAMEX> see <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rescuers</ENAMEX> Down Under
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so i'm going to have my VCR went on the blitz <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about two weeks ago</TIMEX> so i'm getting it fixed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">right now</TIMEX> because they have their little movies their little you know <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> movies they watch all the time and stuff and
 	
 	
 		oh dear
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well on uh back to your movie you saw that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten thousand</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh 101 Dalmatians um uh</ENAMEX> did you all ever think about purchasing that one when it comes out
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		do you know
 		i look at those like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cinderella</ENAMEX> came out was for sale and i don't buy them i now i will copy them and rent them and keep them at home but i just have a problem paying <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty five</TIMEX> dollars for a movie that i can go down and rent for a dollar
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well i understand that too i understand that too now they had
 	
 	
 		you know and they don't last that long
 	
 	
 		um-hum they had <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Home Alone</ENAMEX> offered for like i think with the rebate you could get it for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">nine dollars</NUMEX> and i thought well now that's that's close enough to being several you know you could rent it more than once <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than four</NUMEX> times and watch that
 	
 	
 		oh that's pretty decent
 		yeah yeah
 		that that makes it worth it uh but
 		a lot of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> movies it's just too expensive and i can rent them or i can make a copy you know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>'s in love with the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Little Mermaid</ENAMEX> and i have a copy that's just about worn out she's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		well i understand i understand i understand
 		oh yeah of course
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so she just thinks the great in fact she told me <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mom</ENAMEX> if we have a little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> and she has red hair we're naming her Aerial now i'm not pregnant mind you but this is she's planning ahead for me yeah  so
 	
 	
 		oh sweet  but that's in her plans  well it's hard it's hard to find a movie any more <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> that you can take your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		and even the ones that we rent at home the trouble with some of them i know we rented <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Adventures</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Babysitting</ENAMEX> thinking that would be so cute and it's a precious movie but the language in it is just for no reason
 	
 	
 		oh i saw
 	
 	
 		has to stick in
 	
 	
 		now see i remember thinking it's a wonderful movie but it's been so long since i watched it i don't remember the language it was bad well that's true
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well you watch it differently when your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> you know
 		and i was just sitting there going oh my goodness and i'm going to have to stop and explain and they go i know Mommy i know
 	
 	
 		oh and see my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> weren't in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> you're right i watched it without them
 	
 	
 		uh-huh yeah it's it's real different because you see things from a different different angle
 	
 	
 		huh
 		huh
 	
 	
 		uh we rented <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this summer</TIMEX> before we went on vacation we rented <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chevy Chase</ENAMEX> and that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Family Vacation</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		and those are just absolutely hilarious but you just really can't watch a lot of that we had to fast forward through a whole lot of it for them to see it
 	
 	
 		yes
 		yes  some of it just isn't a
 		
 		
 	