
 
     		
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carolyn</ENAMEX> i have a little <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schnauzer</ENAMEX> little miniature Schnauzer
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh
 	
 	
 		what do you have
 	
 	
 		well it's kind of a mixed breed that we got from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Humane Society</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh you know those make the best <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals uh pets best pets</ENAMEX>
 		my uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> has a uh oh it's a real mixture it's part uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Doberman</ENAMEX> and part <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Husky</ENAMEX>
 		yes and they gentlest <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> you ever met and they got him from the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Humane Society</ENAMEX> here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma City</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh my
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and she's just turned out to be a jewel
 		my my little <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schnauzer</ENAMEX> is is my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> she is so spoiled she's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year and a half old</TIMEX> now
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and being single
 		she's become very important in my life
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's so nice to have come home and find something or someone who's really so happy to see you
 	
 	
 		well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are the ones that wanted our pet and this one is probably the best one that we have had
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> as i say we got it from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Humane Society</ENAMEX> and uh we had lost a pet and we really went there looking for the one that we had lost it got out under the fence while we were on vacation and
 		we just looked all over for it and couldn't find it but uh when we walked in to the
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Humane Society</ENAMEX> this little <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> was uh in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> and would sit up and beg and just oh he was so cute and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> just fell in love with it we just couldn't leave without it
 		but it's um whoever had it before must have trained it real well
 		because it's just you know it's uh a good house dog
 		i've never had one that i could keep in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> before and tolerate it
 	
 	
 		sometimes i wish i had not gotten this one as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">puppy</ENAMEX>
 		because i work and i'm not home
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and unfortunately she's not as well trained as
 		as i would like her to be
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i realize it's my fault i'm not
 		doing a really great job as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">disciplinarian</ENAMEX>
 		but uh
 	
 	
 		it's hard to do that when you're not there constantly
 	
 	
 		it is it is she's you know
 		she's real good i can leave her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all day</TIMEX> in the bathroom
 		with her toys and her food and everything and and not one mess does she make and then we go outside
 	
 	
 		hm
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and she'll stay outside for oh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX> to an hour
 		come inside and use the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">restroom</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		i just want to kill her at those times
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		but she's a doll she's a love she really is
 	
 	
 		about the only time we have well i shouldn't say the only time but most of the time when we have problems with <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">restroom</ENAMEX> is in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night</TIMEX>
 		and uh she usually stays inside at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> we try to take her out right before we go to sleep
 		but uh sometimes it doesn't work
 	
 	
 		you know i i
 		we always had a pet when i was growing up oh always had a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> did not like <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX>
 		so we always had a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> and and then course when my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> were growing up we always had a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> and always said it's because
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> wanted the pet
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i find that i'm enjoying this one far more than i ever did when it was the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s dog
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		i uh in fact my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> gave me this this little <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">puppy</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		what a cute idea
 	
 	
 		yeah i think so
 	
 	
 		well we got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one year</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> and uh i had a baby <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next day</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh my goodness
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		so  that one wasn't really well trained
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX> huh
 		oh
 	
 	
 		oh i just didn't have time to take care of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> and train <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">puppy</ENAMEX> at the same time so
 		
 
 	
 	
 		that
 		that is really probably
 		bad timing
 	
 	
 		yeah i think it was it really was The older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> had wanted one though and you know we thought well that would be a fun time for them to have it you know get it at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> time it was a little <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Spitz</ENAMEX> with a little white
 	
 	
 		oh yes
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fluffy</ENAMEX> and you know looked like it came right from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">North Pole</ENAMEX>
 		and that was fun but um i I sure wasn't good at training it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		do you
 	
 	
 		i think you have to have time you know to to do those things
 	
 	
 		and patience and you have to
 		you really have to be just like your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 		when you set a rule you have to stand by it
 		and be consistent
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		and
 		
 		
 	