
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i'm ready okay
 	
 	
 		you have an opinion about civil stuff
 	
 	
 		
  
 		well you know when to me when you're talking about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">juries</ENAMEX> there's there's two types of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">juries</ENAMEX> you've got the civil <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">juries</ENAMEX> and then you've got the criminal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">juries</ENAMEX> now the criminal juries
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		my understanding of those where a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> has done some crime and you're trying to determine that they need to go to jail or not and then if he does for how long the civil <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> does it matter of
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you owe me some money or you think that i owe you some money and we can't get it resolved so we go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> and we're ask we're gonna ask that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> to uh make a decision as to who owes who and for how much
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		i'm sorry i have a problem with that
 	
 	
 		oh i do too
 	
 	
 		because <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of all  i'm a working <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> and i need to get paid for my day of work and if the our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">juries</ENAMEX> only pay us <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> dollars and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">fifty cents</NUMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a full day</TIMEX> of work
 		i think it's wrong that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have a dispute they had a little car wreck and maybe <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> owes the other guy <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five hundred dollars</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a thousand dollars</NUMEX> whatnot and they're going to call me away from work
 		for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">seven dollars</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">fifty cents</NUMEX> to make a decision as to who owes who and how much to me that is what we pay our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> to do
 	
 	
 		okay you're
 		you're you're self-employed so you're not
 	
 	
 		i am self-employed that's right
 	
 	
 		reimbursed by anyone
 	
 	
 		i'm not going to be reimbursed by no one
 	
 	
 		okay uh yeah that that's interesting point i i i'm not an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enthusiast</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">juries</ENAMEX> particularly
 		and i think especially in in civil cases i doubt doubt the effectiveness of it i hadn't thought about it from terms of the cost point of view to providing the jury
 		i think
 		we may be the only major <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> that still uses <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">juries</ENAMEX> in civil trials
 	
 	
 		you know that one i've never heard of but that you may be right i was i wish i'd you know i've i've never heard that before
 	
 	
 		i'm pretty sure <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> has has uh given up <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">juries</ENAMEX> in civil cases
 	
 	
 		but i mean isn't isn't that what we have the elected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> who supposedly is unbiased who can't aren't they supposed to have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> on their shoulders to make these decisions
 	
 	
 		well probably judges
 		would be the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you  decision about whether to use <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">juries</ENAMEX> or decision
 	
 	
 		no decision as to whether or not as far as civil's concerned
 	
 	
 		i mean i i i think
 		it would be better to have them have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> trained <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> deciding such things
 	
 	
 		true
 	
 	
 		um i don't know there's any Constitutional way to do that other than to change the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Constitution</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you're probably right but it that's still my as far as i'm concerned i just think it's wrong to use a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> for the civil matters now you can talk about criminal matters
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh i've got no problem with that one because you know here you're talking about uh
 		has a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> fit into society has he followed the rules of society
 		i've i've got no problem at all with using your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peers</ENAMEX> quote quote
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and helping to make decisions although we'd have problems as to who qualifies to be on that uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> and i think some of the the
 		manipulative rules that they use to say that all the rich and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">famous</ENAMEX> cannot be on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> but all the poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dregs</ENAMEX> can be you know it doesn't it doesn't make sense
 	
 	
 		
 
 		uh
 		no i don't think i guess different <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> have different rules on that
 	
 	
 		well it it it what amount to if you're if you're rich if you got money
 	
 	
 		i
 	
 	
 		and your really high on society somehow another you're going come up with a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of these excuse that the the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge gonna</ENAMEX> say yeah you're excused you don't have to be here
 		but if you are some poor old uh blue collar <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX> who you know uh just trying to eke out a living and uh i work from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight to five</NUMEX> and
 		you know for some reason he's not gonna find an excuse to get out
 		and so we typically find our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">juries</ENAMEX> made up of some of the dumbest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> rather than the smarter people
 	
 	
 		
 
 		this is because because of  not who initially comes in but who's selected out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX> uh okay certainly both sides
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		pick criteria by which
 		they wanna wanna judge <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">juries</ENAMEX> and and uh veto lots of those and i suspect
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		that uh well see  likely to get off that way although it it'll vary
 	
 	
 		true
 	
 	
 		um
 		i mean i guess traditionally <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">juries</ENAMEX> are supposed to do findings of fact as opposed to findings of law
 		and deciding
 	
 	
 		but then they but then they also have to make the decision as to how long that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> should serve
 	
 	
 		well that that varies by state and locality as to whether the
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">okay</ENAMEX> and and there most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">juries</ENAMEX> don't even know what the hell they even talking about
 	
 	
 		uh there is a little basis for comparison
 	
 	
 		and then when you get someone who says okay this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> should be convicted for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty years two years later</TIMEX> they're on probation
 		because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> doesn't know and in in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> i don't think you are allowed uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX>'s not allowed to be told how soon that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> would be off on probation
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only</NUMEX> thing that they can do is determine how long they should be put in jail
 		not knowing what the rest of the rule is which i think is unfair
 	
 	
 		well i guess i feel much more comfortable with with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> either
 		
 		
 	