
 
     		
 	
 		okay as far as uh universal health care um
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i guess i'm all for it i think it's time that we start looking at um
 		getting into that um health cost has continued to rise and i think uh there's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that to me it's the fundamental uh life life of a person um
 		it it doesn't matter if you have money or no money or all the money in the world um you would
 	
 	
 		you should still be
 	
 	
 		everybody should be able to have surgeries that will save their lives or things that will make their life more comfortable verses than just the rich <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that can afford to pay or to work for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> that have wonderful health benefits
 		um i think if uh they looked at it as a way of business helping out financially for universal health care and
 		uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> um helping out in some sort of way whether it be taxes or some how but uh the expenses right now for health care um are just unreal
 	
 	
 		well they really are even for even when you're not talking about surgery if you're just talking about basic care we've
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		we've got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and you know in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past month</TIMEX> they it just they pass things from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and it just can devastate your budget you know um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh sure
 		and your constantly exactly
 		yeah the only i i know that um uh i know a little bit about the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> uh universal health care and there's some
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pros</ENAMEX> and cons one of the things of course is everybody gets health care but uh sometimes health care
 		uh when you get into a universal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">system</ENAMEX> lacks in uh what would be considered uh
 		how can i say it um over like in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Poland</ENAMEX> uh where my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father-in-law</ENAMEX> lived for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> their their health care system is
 		um because no financial gains are available for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX>
 		uh they may just go into being a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> just clearly just to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> for the full reason but most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that go in to being a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physician</ENAMEX> here in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> do it for financial gain
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		they say well jeez if i get into this area of dermatology i don't have to do this i can do this and i can you know
 	
 	
 		can still make big bucks
 	
 	
 		yeah or plastic surgery or uh if i become a uh heart <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">specialist</ENAMEX> i'm gonna make this kind of money uh and there's
 		you know financial gains toward that and in a universal system i don't think there is a financial gain for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		do you think that the quality um it would would be as high
 	
 	
 		the quality i think goes down um-hum when you have a universal system um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		the only way they could do that is by having a real good quality check um and also offering some kind of because i think uh all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX> well anybody um
 		likes the ability ability to kind of uh get themselves financially uh situated uh i guess that's the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> concept is to come here and
 	
 	
 		right more motivation
 	
 	
 		yeah and i don't know if you can have that with a universal system maybe you know there's a way of working that out but
 		i know that in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Poland</ENAMEX> in particular the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> just go to do their job and that's it that's what they look at it as there's no
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and that's sad because if that's the case if if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> aren't going in to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> to help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> then maybe they shouldn't be in that area anyway but
 	
 	
 		right yeah
 	
 	
 		that might be one way of weeding out those that are greedy for the money and those that really want to help mankind
 	
 	
 		that's true yeah i uh
 	
 	
 		so
 		but i i think we have to head toward that way
 	
 	
 		well we're going to have to do something because there's just too many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> that are uninsured and and you know you cannot i mean it's just
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		i'm worried when i get older  you know and uh let's say for instance you uh
 	
 	
 		oh sure
 	
 	
 		get fired or or not fired but maybe laid off from your job you no longer have insurance
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		i mean and you're sixty some or uh fifty <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">some years old</TIMEX> you try try to find insurance
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		i mean you're you're uninsurable unless you want to pay <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five hundred six hundred dollars</NUMEX> a month and i know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are paying <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">two hundred three hundred dollars</NUMEX> a month for insurance
 	
 	
 		that's right
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and how they can do it i have no idea um i know working for small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> and health insurance um myself
 		um it would cost for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and this was back <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three four years ago</TIMEX> to put my entire <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> up and this was working for like a medcenter uh health plan
 		um it was like eighty dollars out of my paycheck so
 	
 	
 		yeah well ours  ours is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three hundred</NUMEX> for our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and i mean we that is we pay that instead of a car payment you know i mean i'm driving a piece of junk you know
 	
 	
 		see yeah
 		well we do the same i mean it's i think uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are changing their viewpoints of you know it's getting harder and harder to survive
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and uh and that's why uh if they don't go to a universal system something's going to happen we're gonna have uh
 	
 	
 		see
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh larger amount of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> dying
 		
 		
 	