
 
     		
 	
 		uh the the only work i do outside the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> is i am an <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Avon</ENAMEX> representative
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		and i sell <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stanley</ENAMEX> products
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		so i i don't really i don't really dress up a whole lot do you work outside
 	
 	
 		she can
 		well i i work um i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CPA</ENAMEX> and i do contract work
 	
 	
 		oh uh-huh
 	
 	
 		and so and i work with another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CPA</ENAMEX> who just started his own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">practice</ENAMEX> and i work with him <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple days a week</TIMEX> and so when i go to his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> or to other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> then i'll dress up
 	
 	
 		oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but otherwise it's great being at home in jeans or shorts or whatever so that that makes it pretty nice it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's kind of weird because before i used to work you know full time and and uh it seemed like i was wearing a suit <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> just about
 	
 	
 		well you'd have to dress
 		differently when you're working <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> i think yeah
 	
 	
 		right right and so it's uh some of my suits i haven't put on for quite a while  so it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX> it's kind of a nice to relax a little bit yeah
 	
 	
 		it's it's very nice i
 	
 	
 		yeah well my my dress up i live out in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> also so what i wear depends on the weather
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		sure
 	
 	
 		uh so i really i know a lot of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Avon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> are portrayed as being very dressed up but i mostly dress
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i try to dress nice but for convenience because when the weather's bad when i go into the home i take off my shoes
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		which i try to wear something easy to take off you know and put on and i don't too often take off my coat even so
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh i really don't have to dress up like you you would like if you're in an office or something
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah well i imagine that where you live uh you're in warm clothing quite a bit of the year
 	
 	
 		uh well not actually because we really only have maybe <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three four months</TIMEX> of i'd say warm weather
 	
 	
 		not really
 		oh is that right
 	
 	
 		yeah and the rest is uh gets into the cooler weather
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh-huh course they keep saying the weather's gonna change or we're gonna have more <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> type weather up here so i don't know but for now
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> so y'all are waiting for that
 	
 	
 		um-hum but even for now we have a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">snow</ENAMEX> in the wintertime and uh cold weather and that type of thing now my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> works all the time so she dresses
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it i think you know you have to spend more money on your clothing and that because you do have to have the appearance a good appearance to do a good job
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 	
 	
 		where you work
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well down here it's sunny most of the time and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		usually warm i mean we've had a few cool <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this month</TIMEX> but not anything i'm sure compared to what you've had so far so i mean <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are still wearing shorts and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh usually around <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Halloween</TIMEX> it starts getting cooler so you start you know breaking out a coat
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right yeah
 	
 	
 		at that time but that that lasts you know for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few months</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		did you find you wore uh slacks when you were working full time or did you did did they wear more dresses and skirts
 	
 	
 		no
 		no never wore slacks it was
 	
 	
 		no slacks
 	
 	
 		i think it was one of those things where it's not like someone came out and said you can't wear them it was one of those understood things that you just you know either wore you know a dress or
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		uh-huh not even a dressy slack a dressy suit slack suit even if it's all
 	
 	
 		not no not not with what i did um most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> didn't sometimes like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretaries</ENAMEX> might
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but even then you didn't see them wearing slacks too much and i really you know there's some nice pantsuits out and and i wouldn't have minded minded you know wearing those especially when it gets pretty cold
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		hm
 		um-hum um-hum i know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> mostly i don't think she ever wears slacks slacks to work but i didn't know if the trend changes you know if uh
 	
 	
 		but um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		you know i think it's one of those things where it's not viewed upon as being professional i guess they expect <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> to be in skirts  or dresses
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		uh-huh look more like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> huh  uh-huh uh-huh
 	
 	
 		yeah  that's right  and it's the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> that make the rules
 	
 	
 		uh well then you you you know why they make them then  that way
 	
 	
 		
 
 		but no we usually you know skirt and skirt and blouse or suit or dress is is what you see down here so it's nice with me working at home because i can wear pants
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		no one no one can see me unless i'm you know gonna
 	
 	
 		yeah but yet you need to keep up an appearance for your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> too though at home but that's i i believe
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah but i'm not gonna put a skirt on just for him
 	
 	
 		oh you don't think you will huh  well you'll be excused because considering everything  huh uh-huh
 	
 	
 		yeah i think that the main issue at home is being comfortable in your clothing
 	
 	
 		yeah but i i look at homemaking as a job also uh being a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homemaker</ENAMEX> and i i think sometimes we lose sight of that
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh by the fact that we don't sometimes watch our dress
 		
 		
 	