
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay the topic of the conversation is national health insurance and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pros</ENAMEX> and cons and do i do we think that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> should finance it what is your opinion
 	
 	
 		i say yes
 	
 	
 		you say yes
 	
 	
 		yes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> and there are in her subdivision there are fifty percent <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadians</ENAMEX> who won't give up their <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizenship</ENAMEX> because of the health insurance
 	
 	
 		i have heard someone else uh say that uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX> health insurance is absolutely excellent
 	
 	
 		it's wonderful
 	
 	
 		and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the ways that they're financing it is they have an exorbitant tax on their cigarettes
 	
 	
 		oh  well
 	
 	
 		this is
 		evidently evidently this is one of the ways that they're paying for the program plus discouraging the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to quit smoking so they don't have to pay out as many uh benefits on like <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">lung cancer</ENAMEX> and things like this
 	
 	
 		well even if that's so you know really when you look at it they have full coverage they have HMO which you know after you get used to it it's not too bad
 		and uh everything is covered
 	
 	
 		yeah if
 	
 	
 		and we have so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> that we spend well in my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> alone we spent <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">four thousand dollars</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX> on medical bills
 	
 	
 		oh my word <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lynn</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		insurance didn't cover <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a penny</NUMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		that's horrible
 	
 	
 		yes it is horrible
 	
 	
 		well we're fortunate in that we so far knock on wood most of us have been relatively real healthy so we don't have a lot of medical bills
 	
 	
 		yeah but if
 		uh if you're healthy it's fine but i had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah but what worries me is the fact that
 		i don't like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> telling me who i can see and who i can't see
 	
 	
 		yeah but you know <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Richardson School District</ENAMEX> has the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMO</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">ninety percent</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> you would choose are on that list
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		are they
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		well i know that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg uh James</ENAMEX> had it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McCullum</ENAMEX> is
 	
 	
 		i beg your pardon
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McCullum</ENAMEX> is
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah i know that when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James</ENAMEX> was with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Continental Steel</ENAMEX>
 		McCullum was part of that and and that's good but i also heard for instance like uh
 		a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> was on it through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Instruments</ENAMEX> and she was on that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kaiser Permanent</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they had screwed up her appointment and when she went in she had to take whichever <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> was available
 		and they she would have had to wait like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two months</TIMEX> to get the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> she wanted
 	
 	
 		well but that's
 	
 	
 		but then again i guess you can even do that in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">McCullum</ENAMEX>'s
 	
 	
 		that's a screw up in an appointment you know i'm thinking going back to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the days</TIMEX> when i was pregnant
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX>
 		and one was my favorite personality wise
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but when i delivered <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronnie</ENAMEX> he was not on call the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> delivered him
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well that's true and that still goes on
 	
 	
 		you know and that and you know if um i go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Townsend</ENAMEX> he's got a new partner
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i go to both of them now
 		you know i have no choice
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know because when i want to go if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doctor Howe</ENAMEX> or whatever his name is is on duty i go to him
 	
 	
 		
  
 		well you know it uh
 		how do you think we're going to pay for it
 		more and more taxes
 	
 	
 		well no we need to cut some of our spendings
 		cut some of the fat off the top
 		and whittle it down to the rest of us
 	
 	
 		i know that it's getting to the point that the insurance doesn't pay that much on catastrophic illnesses
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		they don't pay anything on uh implants or transplants
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		and you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are needing these and the average <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> can't afford you know a heart or a kidney
 		on just their own
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		but you known <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronnie</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX>
 		went to a program and went to a social worker
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and at the same token there is something because he can get his <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pills</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">two dollars</NUMEX> when i'm paying fifteen on my medical insurance
 	
 	
 		good grief
 	
 	
 		and he can get free medical care but he has to go to the city <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> instead of seeing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so again you know we went through it <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronnie</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX> and we talked about it and said you know is it worth it yeah you know he pays <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">forty five dollars</NUMEX> a month for his prescriptions where he could pay <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">six dollars</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		hum
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so there are programs you know if you get on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX> or one of those
 	
 	
 		that's very true
 		well i know they have the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX> you know for those that have trouble and i know that like we have the uh prescription cards which that's helped bunches
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and wonder if the insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> are fighting the national health or wonder if they're wanting it
 	
 	
 		that's what i read
 	
 	
 		that they are wanting
 		
 		
 	