
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mark</ENAMEX> where where do you live
 	
 	
 		uh i live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Richardson</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh do you okay i'm in Plano
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		okay uh what kind of music do you like
 	
 	
 		um uh rock and roll
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rock</ENAMEX> and roll
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		me too
 		that's pretty much
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		what i listen to
 	
 	
 		i'm i'm <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty one</TIMEX> so i'm in the the new kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rock</ENAMEX> and roll stuff
 	
 	
 		oh you're twenty one okay i'm <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty three</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes
 		okay
 	
 	
 		so not much difference
 		yeah i was a music minor in college
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		um i i took a uh recording engineering <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> out in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Irving</ENAMEX> with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phil York</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so i know how to run a sound <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> and everything like that
 	
 	
 		well that's neat
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		that's neat
 		have you ever recorded anything or
 	
 	
 		oh i did a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">band</ENAMEX> project for the class itself and then i haven't been able to get anything with it since
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i have some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> with bands and they don't even bother to ask me
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		that's when you find out who your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> are i guess
 	
 	
 		yeah you do
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		oh that would that is neat i like that i've always wanted to be in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">band</ENAMEX> but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		we just moved here in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX> and
 		i haven't been able to get settled that much yet but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i i i played piano for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about sixteen years</TIMEX> so
 	
 	
 		yeah my i uh i think i took for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about four years</TIMEX> when i was younger and i don't remember how old i was
 	
 	
 		really did you like it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah i had fun with it
 		as as long as it wasn't too dull and boring
 	
 	
 		like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX> had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Little Lamb</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah the simpler stuff was a little more boring but
 	
 	
 		yeah i had i taught for a while and
 		and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> just
 		they just didn't you know after they got to a certain point they gave up
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know and and they tell you if you can't keep it interesting then
 	
 	
 		i think that's what
 		i think that's what happened to me
 	
 	
 		yeah they're they're you know it's just kind of stuff because after you go to a certain point there's you don't feel like there's much more you can do
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but
 	
 	
 		basically all that's left is to stick the music in front of them and let them play
 	
 	
 		right because they'll do the rest on their own
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		because they know the notes now it's just they have to do it themselves but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> took piano for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirteen years</TIMEX> when she was younger yeah she still plays once in a while
 	
 	
 		really
 		i bet she's good
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		she does the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mozart Mozart</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chopin</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beethoven</ENAMEX> stuff she sits down and plays all that the hard stuff that i never got around to
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		yeah uh
 		we had to give concerts and all that in college
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		with our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">majors</ENAMEX> so
 		well it's it's tough  not bad
 	
 	
 		yeah now i now i play guitar
 	
 	
 		you do um bass guitar or
 	
 	
 		yes
 		electric uh rhythm
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">electric</ENAMEX>
 		oh okay yeah i would that's one thing i never learned to play and i wish i would have is guitar
 	
 	
 		i i've never had formal lessons i just would sit down and listen to the music and figure it out how to play it
 	
 	
 		really
 		that's great
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i wish i had an ear like that because i can sight read
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but i can't ear any i can't hear or i can't
 		you know listen to something and play it
 	
 	
 		yeah uh the the only other problem i have with it is that i've never learned how to learn the the notes for guitar
 	
 	
 		that's real tough for me
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		in other words where the fingers would go for the different notes and everything
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so when if i ever have a conversation with somebody else that plays guitar they start naming off notes and i go whoa you lost me stop
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh just sing it to me
 	
 	
 		i and so i can't read tabulates or anything else like that that go along with it so i just have to listen to the music and
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		you know pick it out
 	
 	
 		well that that's good though because then you can hear something and play it instead of waiting for the music and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah that would be good and that's even better for bands even i think
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		to be able to do that
 		yeah that's neat
 	
 	
 		makes makes it easier whenever somebody is trying to teach you a song you just go show me where it goes and i'll do it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		rather than them going play an A play an E play a B
 	
 	
 		yeah that that is good i like that
 		so like um what bands do you listen to
 	
 	
 		oh i i listen to the the more heavier rock uh <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Kiss White Snake Scorpions</ENAMEX> stuff like that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
  
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">um i like Kiss</ENAMEX> but they haven't been out too long i mean they haven't done anything recently
 	
 	
 		well they so the rest of them came out let's see
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about two years ago</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		they
 	
 	
 		and that was the one they came out without the makeup and they haven't been with makeup for quite a while have they
 	
 	
 		right uh they took off their makeup back their it's my favorite group that's why i know a lot about them um they took off their makeup in eighty i believe it was
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		in eighty
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah that was something  you know
 	
 	
 		they had they had <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five or six</NUMEX> albums since they took off their makeup but
 	
 	
 		yeah i i have the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and i can't remember what the name is now but they put all the um
 		it was one of their um best hits
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh Smashes</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thrashes</ENAMEX> and Hits yeah
 	
 	
 		yes
 		that's it and i just love that tape that is great
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but now they're trying to convert me because i just moved here from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Dakota</ENAMEX> and uh they're trying to convert me to Country and i am just not  i Country person
 	
 	
 		fight them
 		fight them all the way
 	
 	
 		yeah i'm just not a Country Western person
 	
 	
 		yeah i'm i'm not either uh my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> listens to it and it just it drives me up a wall
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah i'm that's one thing i'd you would think in a in a <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Midwest</ENAMEX> that you would but i
 		i never grew up that way so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 		
 	