
 
     		
 	
 		okay well uh what what do you all do for camping
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well we don't do so much now but when uh i i was uh a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> we went regular old <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camping tents</ENAMEX> and and everything like that and then with our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> we did uh we had a pop-up tent camper
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and we used that to go camping
 	
 	
 		where do you go
 	
 	
 		we uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> we lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX> and we went to uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lake Ardmore</ENAMEX> i mean <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lake Murray</ENAMEX> all the time but when we did it with our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> we lived in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tennessee</ENAMEX> and we went up into the Smokeys
 	
 	
 		oh uh-huh
 		oh
 	
 	
 		which was just absolutely fantastic
 	
 	
 		oh i bet it was around <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Gatlinburg</ENAMEX> or somewhere out in there
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX> and along the uh
 	
 	
 		ooh
 	
 	
 		there's a ridge that goes down from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tennessee</ENAMEX> through uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgia</ENAMEX> and into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alabama</ENAMEX> and uh i think it was called the
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh White Cloud</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White Mountain</ENAMEX> and went up on it
 	
 	
 		well now did you all sleep in sleeping bags and did it get real cold at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> or
 	
 	
 		it got real cold but the uh camper had uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		beds in it you know when we had that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and uh so we just you know we had our bedding we didn't have to go with sleeping bags but the  when i was a
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">teenager</ENAMEX> and growing up that was sleeping bags and joining blankets and sleeping on ledges or you know ground and uh that got kind of rough sometimes
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well we only did that once now since we've been married we just go um we go real often to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> to the mountains but we'll stay in cabins
 	
 	
 		oh do you
 		oh uh-huh
 	
 	
 		and you know we call it going camping but we're really not  but the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time that i did go camping when i was about i guess <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixteen</TIMEX> or seventeen with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> we drove
 		to uh up by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cosa Cosa Springs Colorado</ENAMEX> and went <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about seventeen miles</NUMEX> back in the back where you couldn't even get a forest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ranger</ENAMEX> if you tried and to the the tent for a week
 	
 	
 		oh uh-huh
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> it was so cold you thought you'd never feel your feet again and the smell and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> were just <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">five feet</NUMEX> above you you know they were just right there and it was the most
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh just beautiful
 	
 	
 		bonding most wonderful time we enjoyed it but about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the fourth day</TIMEX> i thought if i don't get a hot tub and shave my legs i'm gonna die  and i had
 	
 	
 		yes  yes i understand that
 	
 	
 		i i i got enough of it right then so when we can go to a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cabin</ENAMEX> as long as we've got running water  i'm a little bit better off
 	
 	
 		but
 		yeah my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and i he he says his idea <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> of roughing it is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regency Hyatt</ENAMEX> and i i agree with him our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are are grown but i know that we liked it when our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teenagers</ENAMEX> because we got away from the TV
 	
 	
 		i understand i agree with him too
 		well that's true um-hum
 	
 	
 		and the phone and we got just strictly by ourselves we uh some of the time we would not allow them to take <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> along so that it was just the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> of us and you know and we could you know get back in touch with each other
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well that that's  and they can't believe that they could survive it and then once they're there they they think it's kind of cool
 	
 	
 		oh i know i know oh they just you know they just thoroughly enjoy it you know or enjoyed it
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah and we hiked we would hike <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all day</TIMEX> and  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> did the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">uh pork</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beans</ENAMEX> and you know the slice slice the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">potatoes</ENAMEX> and fry them outside and all of the little stuff that we just were so amazed she knew how to do you know couldn't believe
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yes yes
 		yes like i know that you know breakfast we would you know we'd have these big breakfast cooked over this little <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coleman</ENAMEX> stove and
 	
 	
 		oh yeah with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacon</ENAMEX> oh yeah
 	
 	
 		yes and would just absolutely taste wonderful
 	
 	
 		and and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daddy</ENAMEX> would always try to prove he could catch <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> for breakfast so we usually had a bite apiece  one one
 	
 	
 		yes  or one yes yes but i know that we you know as a teenager growing up and going to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lake Murray</ENAMEX>
 		there would be oh maybe <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty twenty five</TIMEX> of us because it would be all of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> you know and all my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousins</ENAMEX> and it
 	
 	
 		oh my goodness
 		well now is that hot camping is that where you're you're hot like on a beach i mean is that
 	
 	
 		oh no no we were in the we were in the woods you know
 	
 	
 		because a lot of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> will
 		well a lot of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> in east <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> will go to east <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> and i'm thinking how could you stand it you know just
 	
 	
 		well we didn't notice it back then but that was back before air-conditioning was so prevalent you know prevalent and all
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah yeah that's true we did a lot
 	
 	
 		and uh you know and it it always rained on us i don't care what <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekend</TIMEX> we went and when it was it always rained on us
 	
 	
 		
 
 		but i like that and see especially in the tent every <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX> it would rain and you'd get your book and just kind of cuddle up and i thought that was fun
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		cuddle up um-hum well i don't know i remember <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time uh some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousins</ENAMEX> were in a tent and it was married <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousins</ENAMEX> and they they had the tent and this you know  frog strangler that we used to call him came through and
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		they were had put their tent over kind of i don't know what it wasn't a creek bed it was like kind of like a little
 		little uh gully or trench or something and the water rushed down and they said they looked down and there went <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bud</ENAMEX>'s boots you know there went several things floating down this <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> you know we just used to have balls you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh no oh no
 		golly
 	
 	
 		it was it was more fun you know and as i said it just rained every time and then my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> had a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cabin</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Lake Tenkiller</ENAMEX> and we went up there but it was never quite the same thing you know
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well
 		yeah well i yeah i understand that too because some of the places we in fact the the more urban we get with the television and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cabin</ENAMEX> and the whole bit it loses it's flavor
 	
 	
 		yes yes it does it really does um
 	
 	
 		so  well i've i've gotten in the mood to go now  yeah
 	
 	
 		yes yeah even i would kind of like to go and i know if i go home and say oh let's go camping my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> says you're crazy  i enjoyed talking to you too thank you bye-bye
 	
 	
 		i you're crazy  well listen i enjoyed talking with you
 		okay have <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a good day</TIMEX> bye-bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	