
 
     		
 	
 		do you see anything wrong with public school systems
 	
 	
 		well yes i do um i think i'm concerned about the large number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> that
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> is expected to to deal with in some quality way i think maybe we've given our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> a almost impossible job
 	
 	
 		i agree
 	
 	
 		do you do you have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in the public school system
 	
 	
 		yes and i taught for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fourteen years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		is that right
 	
 	
 		before we moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> and the the one thing i see is changing is
 		i was held accountable so much i had to document and create a paper chase for all of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> and instead of spending my time coming up with creative learning <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX> and things like that i was filling out all these forms for all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you you were a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bookkeeper</ENAMEX>  oh
 	
 	
 		everything had to be documented and i had file cabinets that weren't filled with neat stuff for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> it was filled with documentation
 	
 	
 		oh no well um i'm i have <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX> toward a teaching degree and am trying to get headed back and and i'm just really in a dilemma if that's what you know i'd love
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		to work with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and to teach them but i'm really having questions if if i can deal with that system and and have a good conscience about you know what i do i don't think
 	
 	
 		me too
 	
 	
 		i don't think it's the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> i think it's the system but um
 	
 	
 		i think so too
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		they're so worried about lawsuits and the scores that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> get on tests now
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> competency you know and it's not like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> can just get in there and do her best she's always worried whose looking over her shoulder and
 	
 	
 		what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gonna</ENAMEX> say something some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX>'s going to overreact to that's
 	
 	
 		that's right
 		i know
 	
 	
 		that's true  well it's it's hard on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> too i think you know because the um the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> are overworked and just like a mommy that's overworked you're not at your best you know um and
 	
 	
 		that's right
 		do you have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in the system
 	
 	
 		i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> i have uh in the system one is in <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">ninth</NUMEX> grade and one is in <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">seventh</NUMEX> grade and them um i'm home schooling my kindergartner this year
 	
 	
 		ah
 	
 	
 		we um  live in a district that has open <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">classrooms</ENAMEX> and i wasn't particularly comfortable with that for her
 	
 	
 		yep are you in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plano</ENAMEX> yep i am too and i have one in <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">ninth</NUMEX> grade at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clark</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hendrick</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> and he my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ninth</ENAMEX> my uh <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">sixth</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grader</ENAMEX> came from an open <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">classroom</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Matthews</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes you too
 	
 	
 		and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the very first year</TIMEX> i taught back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seventy three</TIMEX> we had open <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">classroom</ENAMEX> and it didn't work then and when we moved down here i was just appalled that they were still doing it here
 	
 	
 		oh
 		still at it
 		well the explanation i was was given about you know they they seemed to admit that it wasn't working but they didn't have the money to restructure but looks to me that it wouldn't take
 		really that much money to at least come up with i mean some kind of partitions you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">partitions</ENAMEX> or just to face the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> different directions or to do something
 	
 	
 		just yeah
 	
 	
 		i know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> had to eat in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">classroom</ENAMEX> because there was no <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cafeteria</ENAMEX> at his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> so he spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all day</TIMEX> in this one large open area
 	
 	
 		oh goodness
 		oh
 	
 	
 		so i didn't really care for that it seems like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michigan</ENAMEX> were much better than they are down here
 	
 	
 		were they
 	
 	
 		that was our last tour up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michigan</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well we were from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North um Carolina</ENAMEX> and of course <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North North Carolina</ENAMEX> has a terrible reputation as far as education i think they rank <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about forty ninth</TIMEX> but our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> got a very good education there they were in the magnet school program
 	
 	
 		oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and a lot of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classes</ENAMEX> from the time they were about <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> grade they they changed classes several times during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> which has its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pros</ENAMEX> and cons but a lot of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classes</ENAMEX> there were only <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in their classes
 	
 	
 		oh wow
 	
 	
 		and it was wonderful so you know i'm coming to to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plano</ENAMEX> thinking well gosh it's going to be really great it's ranked so much better
 	
 	
 		yes
 		yes that's right we heard wonderful things about it till we actually got in the system
 	
 	
 		isn't that interesting i i i don't understand how they get this this reputation unless it's just that they spend a lot of money i don't know
 	
 	
 		probably so on publicity and letting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">realtors</ENAMEX> know and key <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> how wonderful the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> are
 	
 	
 		i guess so well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> is at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Clark</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> too so uh we're yes
 	
 	
 		so
 		as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">freshman</ENAMEX> yep
 	
 	
 		and uh he's pleased with his classes um i i don't guess i've been in the high school long enough to to know
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 		
 
 	
 	
 		what to expect really you know how to judge it uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> seems to be having a good time she was absent with strep throat <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last three days</TIMEX> and i ran over and picked up her report card and she did very good so
 	
 	
 		well that's good
 	
 	
 		and she seems to be studying and has just about the right amount of homework i would expect
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">freshman</ENAMEX> to have she's not bogged down but yet she has some <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">every night</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		well <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric</ENAMEX> seems to have quite a few <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nights</TIMEX> where he doesn't have any so that's interesting but he his grades i haven't seen them yet but supposedly they're good so
 	
 	
 		yes you always hear how good now my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>'s at junior high and says that his grades are going to be wonderful but who knows what he's going to bring home so i don't
 	
 	
 		that's right
 		
 		
 	