
 
     		
 	
 		well i almost forgot the topic i was waiting so long for uh for it to find somebody
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		it was it's on your favorite TV shows and why
 	
 	
 		right well so what is your favorite TV show
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh Major Dad</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh you like that one
 	
 	
 		i i love it i think it promotes good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> values and it's funny
 	
 	
 		um-hum  i've i've never really watched that one you know it's funny how you can just get in a mode where you only watch certain shows
 	
 	
 		that's right yeah uh
 	
 	
 		and uh you know there's so there's only a few that i that i like to watch routinely
 	
 	
 		what kind do you like to watch
 	
 	
 		probably my favorite is um
 		oh well i i like shows like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Growing Pains</ENAMEX> and uh what's the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> now they moved from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> so i don't get to watch it very much
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wonder Years</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wonder Years</ENAMEX> yeah that's my favorite uh
 	
 	
 		i like both of those real much also i i think basically they promote same thing they promote family values
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wonder Years</ENAMEX> i i guess that is supposed to be put out at a time when i was growing up or whatever i guess i can really really relate to it and uh it's just a real cute show
 		uh i i guess i like the shows that really have a a real sense of uh  i don't know honesty or sort of a purity value i guess
 	
 	
 		i do too i i don't like it uh lot of the shows that that i've liked in the past like uh oh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Golden Girls</ENAMEX> and some of them tend to get so risque and when you have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh yeah</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh watching it that sometimes really starts to bother me and uh
 	
 	
 		right right
 	
 	
 		that's one of the reasons i mean  if you want to go all time favorite show probably one of them was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Little House</ENAMEX> on the Prairie
 	
 	
 		uh-huh yeah my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> really likes that show
 	
 	
 		yeah which i just i always i always felt was wonderful uh and so many of them nowadays like i said i think are just um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh they they go after
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		well  like i said the risque stuff just i guess they think that's what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> want to watch
 	
 	
 		yeah well there was but there's a sense of honesty i guess purity in the show like one of my favorite shows used to be Happy <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Days</TIMEX> but uh
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richie</ENAMEX> always used to be so you know just so honest and pure i guess and when he left the show you know that it seemed to be missing that part of it and i never did like it after that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so i i don't know i i say see the same thing in like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wonder Years</ENAMEX> and a lot of the shows that i like to watch there always seems to be that kind of value in there somewhere
 	
 	
 		yeah i i agree uh do you like the sports programming
 	
 	
 		yeah uh-huh
 	
 	
 		um i i enjoy those also almost as as much to a certain extent i'm our whole <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> is baseball <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> and uh we enjoy that and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		so you're gonna watch a game tonight
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		oh yeah they're
 	
 	
 		so do you do you have a favorite for the series or anything
 	
 	
 		uh
 		probably the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pirates</ENAMEX>
 		but only because of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Bushel</ENAMEX> i guess  otherwise i really don't care that much but uh you know i'm i'm
 	
 	
 		oh uh-huh
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		annoyed that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rangers</ENAMEX> got rid of him and uh i'd
 		like to see him do well laugh all the way to the bank i guess
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah he's a nice <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>  i i take it you live in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> area do you live in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> area
 	
 	
 		with as much
 		pardon
 		uh live in live in Plano
 	
 	
 		uh-huh yeah i live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Garland</ENAMEX> and yeah i i like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Bushel</ENAMEX> but i don't really like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pirates</ENAMEX> i'm a big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saint Louis Cardinals</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> so uh i'm kind of i'm kind of pulling for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Braves</ENAMEX> over all they you know they
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they've come from so far down  i really would like to see them do well
 	
 	
 		well yeah yeah it's uh
 		it's what i keep hoping the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rangers</ENAMEX> are going to do
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one one year</TIMEX> then maybe they'll make it i don't know
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		so  but uh yeah i'd like sports programming quite a bit but
 		uh i guess my my favorite shows are the and you know the getting back to a point that you made that's really true we are watching <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Roseanne</ENAMEX> i guess <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">couple of weeks ago</TIMEX> and
 		her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> was talking about birth control you know and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> was kind of walking in during that time and  you know she's only <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven years old</TIMEX> so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well it's so many of them now um  you know it it just seems like they feel like they have to stick that stuff in and and uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know i'm  you know i'm i'm an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adult</ENAMEX> and i have adult tastes now but i don't need that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		uh i i like things that uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> are wholesome i guess
 	
 	
 		yeah well that that seems to be more our values too like like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wonder Years</ENAMEX> i i mean
 		uh it's kind of risque stuff for maybe for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teenagers</ENAMEX> you know or and and you can kind of relate to it you know i don't know that's i enjoy that a lot
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yes yes
 	
 	
 		but uh you know i i i agree with you the and it's funny because the shows
 		like a lot of them that used to be considered risque like <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Three's Company</ENAMEX> and stuff i think they they maintained <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would watch them because there was that uh
 		you know there was really the period that was going on there i mean he really wasn't messing around with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> but everybody perceived him that way and stuff
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but as soon as you know he went to move in with another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> the show just died
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and it's it's interesting that that a lot of the shows are that way
 		
 		
 	