
 
     		
 	
 		okay i don't  do you have a opinion on that on the USR
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well  the  i think i'm i'm skeptical about the whole thing uh and a little still a little bit worried about them because of the history the history of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russia</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they're in a in a state of flux right now changing uh you uh changing a great deal primarily because of the economic distress
 	
 	
 		sure
 		um-hum sure
 	
 	
 		and even in that situation uh the it seems like to me from what i've read in in the history of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> and and you know different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX>
 		uh there has always been a <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">paranoia</ENAMEX> they've always suspected everybody and and that's why they put you know that's why they put a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and that's why they put a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to death
 	
 	
 		sure
 		sure that happens
 	
 	
 		yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stalin Staling</ENAMEX> was a was a classical example i guess of that <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">paranoia</ENAMEX> because he he probably killed more <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX> than uh you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> killed anybody else
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		sure i guess in particular my viewpoint is that they financially cannot
 		go into a war uh they are desperate at this point in time to keep their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> together but i could not foresee them  severing what they have with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US</ENAMEX>
 		um because they need us at this current time because of their financial situation um from what i've been hearing is the USSR uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USSR</ENAMEX> has been uh almost bankrupt
 		for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and it's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are desperate and there might be a revolution within the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>  but i don't think the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> would get involved with it because uh there's too close of ties to where
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i think they understand that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gorbachev</ENAMEX> is trying to make a change and that we cannot run
 		them like we run the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> and that they have to make their own independent decision so i guess i really have no fear at all of the USSR verses uh you get these small little uh places like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> and all of that that
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		might be something that i'd be more concerned about with nuclear weapons versus a a small
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> or the big <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> of USSR i i i have no feelings that they would ever start a war with us because to them it would
 		totally  you know it would totally destroy their whole <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> because our technology is far advanced from what theirs is at this current time
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so i mean sure they have weapons to kill us over and over and over but
 		to them that would be a suicide and they and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are not suicidal type of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> but if you get the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iraqis</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX> which will do it for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> for the pleasure of
 		you know doing whatever uh for their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> they'll do it uh
 	
 	
 		yeah you're uh i think you're right there's a little more craziness down there
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i think are not that much different from us you know i think they're that it would be the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> that i'd i'd uh mistrust
 	
 	
 		sure sure
 		um-hum  sure i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> that's frustrated she's on a a stool that she can get up on but it if she can't get down on it it's like get me down <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">right now</TIMEX>  but anyway it was really good talking to you and you have a good weekend
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 		you to thank you bye-bye
 	
 	
 		uh-huh thank you bye now
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	