
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		my name's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Dell</ENAMEX> and i live in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas Texas</ENAMEX> area where there's a lot of pollution
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">okay</ENAMEX> and i'm up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wisconsin</ENAMEX> uh my name is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Terry</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh uh-huh
 	
 	
 		and uh in the small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> we don't but uh we're not that far from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> where there's <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">tons</NUMEX> of pollution
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		okay i'll go ahead and start recording that
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay um just in particular here in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Twin Cities</ENAMEX> we have a lot of big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> and um i'm sure there's a lot of pollution we uh before moving to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wisconsin</ENAMEX> lived across from where they were um
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		gravel pits and also where they were making <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tar</ENAMEX> and so we would occasionally if the wind was blowing the right direction would get the smell of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tar</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		ooh
 	
 	
 		it would uh smell the continuous you knew that you were also breathing that into your lungs so and it was like <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">miles</NUMEX> away but just the idea of having that
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		come across the way it did in the wind kind of made you know that there was a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pollution</ENAMEX> and that was just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporation</ENAMEX> that was doing the pollution of that but
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		also um where we also lived too it was very close to a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">highway</ENAMEX> so we got a lot of fumes from uh trucks
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> and you would literally see the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pollution</ENAMEX> on your furniture i mean it was on your tables you would dust <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> and it was dirty um
 	
 	
 		oh gosh
 	
 	
 		type of uh dust i mean it wasn't the typical dust that you get way out in the country
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 		i live in a small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">um town</ENAMEX> now quite a ways from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Twin Cities</ENAMEX> about <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an hour</TIMEX> away and i may dust once a week and that's all it needs versus <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> when i lived in the city
 	
 	
 		huh i'd never thought about that being a cause i have to dust a lot as well
 	
 	
 		so
 		oh yeah it it comes right on through through the screens the only way that you could
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		actually live in the in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> is to close your windows and have an air cleaner system right in your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> that would take the air from the outside and clean the air before it would get into the house
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		my goodness
 	
 	
 		and so it was quite a dirty city um if if you were well protected by <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> which catch a lot of the pollution
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		then you're fine but most of the time in the city you have lots of high rises you have lots of other things that are not
 		catching the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pollution</ENAMEX> and it's just going for miles and miles and miles and it's landing somewhere with the wind but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		that's kind of the way <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> is we're so flat and open and i live in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">suburb</ENAMEX> that doesn't have much vegetation <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> it was all <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cotton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">fields</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		sure
 		sure
 	
 	
 		we don't have that advantage and ours i think is primarily <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> where we don't carpool like we should
 	
 	
 		yes yes
 	
 	
 		an <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airport</ENAMEX> i work in a building i'm nineteen <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">floors</ENAMEX> up and i look out toward <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DFW International</ENAMEX> and there's just an awful brown haze all the time
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i can imagine it's even worse for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> living over near the airport
 	
 	
 		oh sure sure yeah it's i mean our air quality um
 		in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Twin Cities</ENAMEX> is a lot better than what we've heard about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> and maybe in
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the other areas but um they were always talking about the air quality of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> is this you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ozone</ENAMEX> or whatever and it's kind of scary because the air is something we take for granted
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		and many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are too busy getting to work not thinking about okay i could have carpooled with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> even
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> was uh talking to some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> at work now he's uh <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">fifteen miles</NUMEX> away from work but he was talking wouldn't it be nice to carpool and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> says well it's too close it wouldn't pay and so
 	
 	
 		um-hum want to meet my own schedule those are the arguments we hear
 	
 	
 		yeah and
 		exactly exactly and so my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> says well that's fine you know it would save quite a bit on the wear and tear on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> and you know the gas
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and no everybody has their preference to drive by themselves or if they do they
 		they drive with one little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buddy</ENAMEX> uh at least it's with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> but most of the time <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are saying forget it i don't want to carpool it's too much of a hassle it's too much involvement but yet
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		but we're paying for it
 	
 	
 		yes we are and i think of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> and i'm sure you think of your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and you kind of say to yourself
 		what kind of future will they have when they think back and say well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> did have the choice to kind of make a difference and  i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are trying
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but they have to change attitudes
 	
 	
 		and it seems to me that it's already so evident with our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> having a lot more respiratory infections than we had growing up
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		sure
 	
 	
 		you can really see it i i had a chance to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bolivia</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple years ago</TIMEX> and of course there's no industry
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		very little trash they they don't even have that much that they burn because they consume everything down to the thread and it amazed me i i just had totally forgotten how blessed
 	
 	
 		sure
 		sure
 		well they
 		
 
 		
 		
 	