
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay i guess our topic is um advice about going to college do you have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> of your own
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh no i don't have any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> but i'm still going to college uh-huh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NC State</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh are you what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> are you going to
 		oh are you enjoying it
 	
 	
 		um well it's a lot of work
 	
 	
 		are you working on your um
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Bachelor</ENAMEX>'s uh-huh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bachelor</ENAMEX>'s degree and what field of study are you in
 	
 	
 		um it's actually in computer science and i have a special interest in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Voice IO</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh well that's neat are you from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no i'm actually from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Amarillo Texas</ENAMEX> originally
 	
 	
 		oh are you really oh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well what took you to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um the service
 	
 	
 		oh i see
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		well that was one of the things i was thinking about in school um when i went to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Tech</ENAMEX> out in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lubbock</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh i had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">roommate</ENAMEX> went to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tech</ENAMEX> also but she was from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Mexico</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and she had to pay out of state tuition  and i think that would have uh played a real big part in my decision
 	
 	
 		ooh
 		it would have played a major part in mine
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah because um she was paying of course back then it was so much cheaper than it is now it was like <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">four dollars</NUMEX> a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">semester</TIMEX> hour
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so i was going to  school for you know just <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a few hundred dollars</NUMEX> a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">semester</TIMEX> and she was paying <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">forty dollars</NUMEX> an hour  so she's paying <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> times as much because she was out of state
 	
 	
 		golly
 		yeah luckily i've paid in state tuition the whole time
 	
 	
 		oh that's good
 		yeah so i think  that would be one thing i would definitely consider  try to find a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> within the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> that um i liked well enough to attend
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> thing is some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX> only offer the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liberal Arts</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh whereas like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> they offer engineering courses
 	
 	
 		right yeah
 	
 	
 		so depending on what your major is or medical you might want to atteck somewhere um attend somewhere like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tech</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah right
 	
 	
 		and um aside from the uh well some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> may even give you financial aid where <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">another one</NUMEX> won't
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah that's true that was something else i had was i had government aid of course but uh it was wonderful because i got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of those grants that you don't have to repay
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		and yeah it was so nice it paid most of my tuition and um a lot of the book costs and that kind of thing so  yeah i really
 	
 	
 		hm
 		wow that's great was it a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pell</ENAMEX> grant
 	
 	
 		i'm sorry what did you say
 	
 	
 		what kind of grant was it
 	
 	
 		well it was called a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BEOG</ENAMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Basic Equal Opportunity Grant</ENAMEX> and it was from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and it was based at first it was based on my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>' income  my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and really didn't make enough money to
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		send any of us to school and so uh because based on the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and the amount of money uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> brought in i got a small grant but then after that i was on my own working and you know trying to go to school on my own
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so then i got a real big grant because the amount of money i was making really didn't compare
 	
 	
 		wow
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so it was kind of nice i don't know if those are still available or not but
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh i'm not quite there's there's a lot of different <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> who uh who do give grants but uh
 		i'm not exactly sure which ones they are and how how much that they you know they generally run
 	
 	
 		yeah  yeah  well this was great it was just based on you know how much your tuition  costs and everything and generally it paid everything so i went to school <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about three years</TIMEX> of my <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> for almost nothing so that was
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		golly that's great
 	
 	
 		yeah it was really nice
 	
 	
 		oh another thing i've got a i've got a degree from another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> and uh something that might play a part is the size of the college
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh lots the smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> can give you a lot uh a lot more specialized instruction and attention than the larger <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> in the larger <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> you get caught up in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bureaucracy</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they just give you a  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assistants</ENAMEX> you know instead of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholar</ENAMEX> you get a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TA</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		and uh you don't get near the uh quality of education  and as well the uh smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> often times don't cost as much
 	
 	
 		hm i didn't know that
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well  i guess the only comparison i had ever heard was between um
 		a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> college because i  thought about attending <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Abilene</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> instead of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Tech</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and of course the price was just astronomical compared to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tech</ENAMEX> um the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> was so much more expensive
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		but i guess some of the other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX> smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX> might might be a lot different
 	
 	
 		um
 		oh i at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> i think it's just a waste of somebody's money to go there
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		it's really a shame because of you know the instruction um i'd rather go to any other college you know in the state and i would definitely get my money's worth uh much better than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah huh
 	
 	
 		it's kind of unfortunate because they've they've just grown so big that they just don't care about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> anymore
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah you're just a number
 	
 	
 		yeah they're they're bent on uh seeing how much land how much more land they can get and how much uh how much of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campus</ENAMEX> they can build up
 	
 	
 		um
 		right
 	
 	
 		and uh yeah it's really a bad situation here
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 		oh that's a shame
 		well i i felt a little cheated at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tech</ENAMEX> also once i got into my i um major ed in
 		
 		
 	