
 
     		
 	
 		so what do you think about it
 	
 	
 		well i found it interesting that they started off with a problems of immigration in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> and then went back and said well if there is a problem what should we do about it
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah i guess that's so
 	
 	
 		do you feel there's a problem with immigration in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 		uh i think there are some problems but they're not really big ones i think that
 		um
 		in general the whole immigration policy isn't quite as open as it should be
 		that it's really pretty hard for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> to get in here like even if they're educated and will be a good asset to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>
 		it's often hard for them to get in and get on the track towards citizenship unless they marry a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen</ENAMEX> or something like that
 	
 	
 		okay that's interesting i was i was wondering what your response would be i'm a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> generation <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay uh where did you come from
 	
 	
 		so i'm from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrant parents</ENAMEX>  or an immigrant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> anyway
 	
 	
 		okay okay so where did your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> come from
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">uh Poland</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		and that was you know prior to <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War</ENAMEX> Two
 	
 	
 		and
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but it's interesting that
 		you know
 		with the topic  i think i agree with you there needs to be more of an open policy
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and you know we have to remember the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> came here and were our labor you know for the railroad <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Transatlantic Railroad</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		yep
 	
 	
 		our <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> came and you know built the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX> and
 		did labor
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but what do you think are you from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> or
 	
 	
 		i'm from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX> okay well that'll be interesting
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right and um a lot of
 	
 	
 		because we have just had a naturalization act where the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexicans</ENAMEX> that were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> i'm from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and have become <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> now
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		what do you think about that
 	
 	
 		um i think that's all right
 		i um
 		at least on the surface it sounds like a good thing do you have an opinion about it
 	
 	
 		well i agree with it wholeheartedly the only thing is i've got to share with you and my background is from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so when you were giving your answer i was thinking
 		is this a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Texan</ENAMEX> i'm talking to  because <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Texan</ENAMEX> philosophy is a little different
 	
 	
 		no okay
 		right
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well a lot of the experience that i have with this problem has to do with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother-in-law</ENAMEX> who's <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> and immigrated from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> and um
 		you know he
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> got a green card is and is in good standing in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> and in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> but only because he was always pretty nice to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> government
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and all that and he was always on pretty good terms with them
 	
 	
 		yeah well we
 	
 	
 		but um their
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> just had a baby and they're trying to get permission for his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> to come to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> to like help care for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> and that sort of thing
 		and it's turned out to be sort of a horrible problem
 		it's just very difficult to
 		get a a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who doesn't have a lot of assets or whatever out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> even temporarily to visit here
 	
 	
 		oh well then you have first in the experience on immigration
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		well that is interesting
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah well i well i wonder you know even with those that were involved with <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tiananmen Square</ENAMEX>
 		you know did we really protect them
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah that's and i think that's pretty crazy because
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i mean those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> who were in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> when that was happening
 		are
 		almost certainly going to be in trouble if they go back
 		and
 		besides that they're the best and brightest of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> so it's certainly in our best selfish interest to keep them here if we can
 	
 	
 		that is true
 		that is true
 	
 	
 		yep
 	
 	
 		well what do you think about we have in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> a large <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Vietnamese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that has been brought in
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		what do you think about that
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		and these are not the brightest i mean we
 	
 	
 		see these are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX> you mean okay
 	
 	
 		we're talking boat people
 	
 	
 		right okay
 	
 	
 		we have a lot of boat <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right well um
 		i don't have any problem with that um
 	
 	
 		you're a true liberal heart-to-heart good for you  i was ready for a fight on this one
 	
 	
 		yeah i guess so  uh-huh right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no i agree because um interesting my when my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> was in high school
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the custodians was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vietnamese</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and with his limited English they found out through you know that  she was in student <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">council</ENAMEX> and they found out that he was a medical doctor
 		
 		
 	