
 
     		
 	
 		um i don't i
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i am only <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty eight</TIMEX> and i haven't had much experience with nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> i don't i have never visited any  i don't think i've ever even been in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> have you
 	
 	
 		um actually i have um
 		i've i've been in them
 		but um just visiting and
 		um we used to go when we're like in in our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teenagers</ENAMEX> we'd go on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sundays</TIMEX> and visit you know the older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> but um i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elderly grandmother</ENAMEX> that lives with us
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and she's lived with us for like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX> so i kind of know how it is to have to decide if you wanna put somebody in a rest <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> or
 		um  like we i mean we've had those discussions you know about should we put her in or because she's pretty senile and
 	
 	
 		and it takes it takes a lot of care like <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty four hours</TIMEX> a day someone has to be well like there's someone in my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fiance</ENAMEX>'s family his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> too and they're
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		it's really
 	
 	
 		that his her
 		son his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncle</ENAMEX> whatever you know anyway  he he has he recently retired and so he's the one who she moved in with when she had a stroke and and all the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		um are working or whatever they're all my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX>'s age and uh so he's got you know his retirement though is really <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty four hours</TIMEX> a day they have a
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		day care  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two days a week</TIMEX> they call it senior citizen day care but she goes to the senior citizen center
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		so she he gets a break <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two days a week</TIMEX> but it's only for like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three hours</TIMEX> at a time
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and you know just you see a lot of things like you you know was always a great golfer and wanted to play <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">golf</ENAMEX> when he retired and you know that a lot of the things he thought he would do when he retired he's not able to do now
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but he refuses to consider any other
 		i i don't know yeah and is that how your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> feel or
 	
 	
 		to put her in a rest home
 		um  well see it's more of my grandma that feels that way she says that when her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> died that he said
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncle</ENAMEX> had said that he would never have put her in a rest home
 		so it's kind of
 		uh i don't know  i don't think my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> would but she is getting pretty bad like she has to
 		have like a little toilet right by her bed it's and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> has to take care of her pretty much so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it gets
 		i don't know it's it's a hard decision but i don't think i would do it to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> personally
 	
 	
 		i know at this i know i feel like i would never do that with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> either you know but i i really feel bad for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i see that not very i'm not really really experienced but like i said just have that one
 		family and that's really so bad for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who his whole life is different now and than he thought it would be but
 	
 	
 		when he retired
 	
 	
 		yeah and he's got you know <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> and and uh he's the one because he's the one that doesn't going to work <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">everyday</TIMEX> and that she moved in with when she needed to move in with someone and
 	
 	
 		yeah and it's worked out good for us just because my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncle</ENAMEX> and my and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> switch off like we have her for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three months</TIMEX> and then he has her for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three months</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		i can't say much oh well that's great that's a good idea we ought to
 	
 	
 		so that that works out good
 	
 	
 		yeah and maybe when the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> retire or whatever i don't know what they're gonna do it's really not my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> it's my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fiance</ENAMEX>'s so i don't
 		i can't say much but i always feel like i would never put my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> in either and i wonder i'm gonna be the only
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		sibling that isn't gonna have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> so if my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> do need to live with someone it'll probably be with me because all my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> will be having <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teenagers</ENAMEX> around and everything to care for
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		you know and i'm i that's fine with me  my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fiancee</ENAMEX> i both figure that's what's we're gonna end up with both of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> or whoever if it you know what i mean we feel like it's our responsibility and i feel like i would never put them in a home
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i wonder how much you know if one of us is gonna have to quit work someday or retire early or something you think about it and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's really i don't know this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> kind of takes the worst care of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elderly</ENAMEX> of any other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		you think i i
 		i'm not really familiar with how other countries
 	
 	
 		it's really more of a um like a respect issue
 		and that the older the older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> that i've been to seem to really have a lot more respect for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elderly people</ENAMEX> and and they really seen as wise and and in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> nobody really
 	
 	
 		they're seen as senile
 	
 	
 		yeah nobody really pays attention and they oh the old timer made with the old way and nobody respects the traditions and you know it's
 		i i'm not saying that i do either but  you know it's just funny and and we really don't have any they don't have social security and everything really isn't that much for
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elderly people</ENAMEX> to live on you know even if they're in good health it's incredible they don't have any they don't get special treatment and maybe they should you know because we're all gonna get old someday
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		i know
 	
 	
 		so it's a  it's kind of depressing topic though how old are you
 	
 	
 		um i'm <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		so it is yeah and it must be rough for you too to see your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah it's it really is but and she
 		she drives us crazy
 		
 		
 	