
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		anyway
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		so i'm
 		so like what did you eat the last time you went to a dinner party
 	
 	
 		well the last time i went to a dinner party was down at the lake and uh golly it was a dish uh from uh down in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Panama</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		wow
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		i think the name of it was Paetha
 		and uh it was a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">delicious meal</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		what was it what was the dish
 	
 	
 		well the dish was composed was composed of uh steak and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chicken</ENAMEX> and shrimp all cut up you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> into uh bite size portions and it had <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rice</ENAMEX> in it and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tomatoes</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vegetables</ENAMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">onions</ENAMEX> and green peppers and what you do is prepare this uh in a a large uh oh it looks like a large uh uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">garbage</ENAMEX> can uh uh lid you know only turned upside down
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh this particular particular this particular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> that cooked this uh cooked it over a burner propane burner course down in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Panama</ENAMEX> they cook it right out right over right over an open flame
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and
 	
 	
 		it's it's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paella</ENAMEX> is what it is because i've i've had that before
 	
 	
 		yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paella</ENAMEX> how'd you know oh oh you have i'll be darned
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i've <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> who are <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cuban</ENAMEX> who well they're <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cuban</ENAMEX> and uh i was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miami</ENAMEX> one time and they fixed that dish and they used squid in it it it had all kinds of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meats</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		yeah well it
 		right and they omitted the squid and there's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> other item too that they omitted i can't i can't recall what that was but uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh we don't no we don't like squid it's too rubbery
 	
 	
 		it's sort of like the a version
 		it's sort of like a version of gumbo it's sort of like <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin American</ENAMEX> gumbo or something
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		but all this was cooked together they did serve <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread buttered uh bread</ENAMEX> and uh and uh it was delicious
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we had that in fact uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> of this last week
 	
 	
 		wow
 	
 	
 		down at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caney City</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
  
 		where's that
 	
 	
 		oh it's <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about sixty miles</NUMEX> this side of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tyler</ENAMEX> and uh
 		and uh oh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about a hundred</NUMEX> uh let's see <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about seventy five miles</NUMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> in between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tyler</ENAMEX> and us
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh like near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canton</ENAMEX> or
 	
 	
 		yeah is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canton</ENAMEX> is north uh uh north of us
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		what's the name of that lake down there
 		oh yes
 		yeah it's on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Cedar Creek</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh okay well i know where that is
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		we have a lake <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> down there and jointly owned with another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> here in the neighborhood
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so we're always having parties and this particular time we had uh what we call our uh our our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> here in uh in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Richardson</ENAMEX> the uh what we're in we gather together and go out and eat at some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> or something of that nature
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		or go to some event
 	
 	
 		well i'm having <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this weekend</TIMEX>
 		i'm from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South Alabama</ENAMEX> originally
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">south</ENAMEX> huh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Alabama</ENAMEX> way down there uh close to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mobile</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		what town
 		Mobile uh-huh
 	
 	
 		yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Foley</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and anyway so what what i one thing i like to do is i like to cook real <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southern</ENAMEX> food
 		and so my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> um you know whenever i cook they usually like for me to really like cook <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southern</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> so <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this weekend</TIMEX> we're i'm doing like fried chicken i'm going to fry <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chicken</ENAMEX> and have turnip <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">greens</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and like a blackeyed <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pea salad</ENAMEX> and uh uh corn <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX> so i mean
 	
 	
 		turnip <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">greens</ENAMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">greens</ENAMEX> too
 	
 	
 		yeah actually just the with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">greens</ENAMEX> not much of the turnips
 		i don't like the turnip parts
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but
 		so i mean it's kind of you know weird because you think all your yuppie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> wouldn't necessarily want to eat like that but they do
 	
 	
 		do you like highly seasoned uh highly season it
 	
 	
 		the turnip <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">greens</ENAMEX> oh sometimes like with pepper <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sauce</ENAMEX> you mean
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah i like to eat those green peppers just uh uh whole you know with turnip <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">greens</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well i'm i
 		yeah
 		i i like seasoned <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> but i can it can get too much pretty quickly for me i i think but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well did you go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Auburn</ENAMEX> down there just off the subject
 	
 	
 		
  
 		yes
 	
 	
 		well good did you know a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spivey</ENAMEX> down there
 	
 	
 		i did
 		a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spivey</ENAMEX> in Auburn
 	
 	
 		yeah that went to Auburn
 	
 	
 		no we had <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> whose names were Spivey uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aubrey</ENAMEX> Spivey
 	
 	
 		uh what
 		no
 	
 	
 		they were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> of ours my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> live now live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Auburn</ENAMEX> my whole <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> everyone lives in Auburn
 	
 	
 		no
 		Auburn
 		i have a niece and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nephew</ENAMEX> that graduated from uh from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Auburn</ENAMEX> and he played <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Auburn</ENAMEX> broke his leg in the uh in the bowl down there at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">El Paso</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh goodness
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun Bowl</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		in their uh
 		in in oh that was a number of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> he's probably oh probably pretty close to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">forty</NUMEX> now
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well that's where i went to that's where i'm from
 	
 	
 		i'll be darned
 	
 	
 		but anyway
 	
 	
 		so uh you really uh like to entertain your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> uh and
 		
 		
 	