
 
     		
 	
 		well this is a subject that you never think you'll be assigned to speak <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about  one</NUMEX> that kind of comes up when you've lost it
 	
 	
 		
 
 		no
 	
 	
 		the other  other subjects  um as i was sitting there i thought the weather's been perfect i don't know much to say about it it's uh
 		it's you know for the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">balloon festival</ENAMEX> here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plano</ENAMEX> it was just gorgeous and are you it couldn't have been better i mean it didn't foul one launch and that's kind of unusual
 	
 	
 		i'm from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plano</ENAMEX> also
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		and it's kind of cold in the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">mornings so</TIMEX> you dress up warm but by  and that's the only thing wrong i can find with it  but
 	
 	
 		right
 		i just got back from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dayton</ENAMEX> i spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX> with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> are changing color there so that as soon as we got out of the cloud cover of course it wasn't sunny like it is here it was real gray
 	
 	
 		oh how fun
 		i miss that yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but as soon as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> got through the clouds and i saw all those trees it just really made me
 		realize how much i miss the fall  i don't complain weatherwise though because it was also <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty five</TIMEX> degrees there <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> and the high was only fifty and it was supposed to drop and get sleet in the afternoon
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 		ooh
 	
 	
 		so it was nice to get off the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> where it was in the seventies
 	
 	
 		i guess you have to take some things and leave some things
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		so yeah i'm from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> area and the you know we have tons of canyons where the leaves change and they're gorgeous you could spend <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every weekend</TIMEX> of the  fall going to a different area
 	
 	
 		yes
 		we did that when we lived up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michigan</ENAMEX> we went up to the upper peninsula and they actually printed out maps of routes you could take so you would get maximum leaf exposure
 	
 	
 		hm wow
 	
 	
 		and then on leaf <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekends</TIMEX> it was which is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this time of the year</TIMEX> it's bumper to bumper traffic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> it's whoever was driving could never have a prayer of looking at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">leaves</ENAMEX> because they had to keep watching the road
 	
 	
 		no it's kind of hazardous for driving that's for sure but i can't complain it  i don't know if i've been spoiled i've been thinking it's getting cold sooner than normal we've only lived here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple years</TIMEX> but
 	
 	
 		yes
 		i think it is and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> said that in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX> there was just an article on at the TV news  that they are <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three weeks ahead</TIMEX> of schedule
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		as far as the coldness of the temperatures and uh the first frost everything just happened <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three weeks early this year</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		we'll have to see how it goes  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple weeks ago</TIMEX> we were cooler than normal but then we were back to being warmer than normal <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week or last week</TIMEX> so
 	
 	
 		just so we don't have one of those famous ice storms in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the spring</TIMEX> i
 	
 	
 		i don't have to live through many any of those really a bad i mean nothing comparable i guess to what you've had before
 	
 	
 		well i've only been here just a short time too so i haven't been through any of those either so i have in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michigan</ENAMEX> but in in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michigan</ENAMEX> you can get <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">twelve inches</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">snow</ENAMEX> and life goes on
 	
 	
 		
 
 		you're right
 	
 	
 		so as i understand it here if there's anything they'll call off <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and and close businesses
 	
 	
 		well they get <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX> and no one can drive on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX> i mean we used to think they were pansies but then when you decided what <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX> was
 	
 	
 		right
 		right the real definition of ice
 	
 	
 		so  well i think we've discussed it good enough <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>  so it was it was good talking to you maybe we'll get to next time thanks <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karen</ENAMEX> bye bye
 	
 	
 		i think so it was nice talking with you okay okay bye
 		
 		
 	