
 
     		
 	
 		okay what kind of pet do you have <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gail</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well i don't i have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>  i have little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> both of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are under <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two so</NUMEX> right now we don't have pets but we've had lots of them in the past
 	
 	
 		oh you have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 		have you uh what have you had
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well we had a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> before we moved here uh and we couldn't bring her with us we came from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> and we've had hamsters and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">birds</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		oh well you're going to have lots of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pets</ENAMEX> with your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> growing up  well we had a a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schnauzer</ENAMEX> that we lost <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this summer</TIMEX> and he was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fourteen years old</TIMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">cats</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we've had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schnauzers</ENAMEX> and before that we had all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dachshunds</ENAMEX> and i think my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> wants another <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dachshund</ENAMEX> and we're trying to debate because our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are grown and and uh
 		i don't know whether we really want to be tied down to a pet you know another <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> and we do have a very loving <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> that's you know kind of our baby
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh and we like <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pets</ENAMEX> we like them around we have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandchildren</ENAMEX> that run through and they think we should have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> and
 		that's because they have a <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Great Dane</ENAMEX>  which is huge
 	
 	
 		um yes
 		definitely well
 		we you know if it um if it were just more peaceful you know with the little ones we would definitely have a pet i just think it's nice have around we had a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> though that had kittens so any pet that i get from now on will definitely be spayed or neutered
 	
 	
 		oh yes yes
 	
 	
 		because uh i did that experience was awful
 	
 	
 		yes i have never wanted a that's why we've never gotten a female you know in anything and uh uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and our male cat you know we had uh neutered right away and course it he doesn't know it and he's still out partying
 	
 	
 		
 
 		um
 	
 	
 		but um you know i do think that maybe we'll get a female next time and just had her have her spayed you know
 		and uh
 	
 	
 		well a lot of times <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> when you buy them from like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">SPCA</ENAMEX> or
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		and the humane <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">societies</ENAMEX> or whatever their adoption includes their spaying
 	
 	
 		yes yes which i think is a good thing it just breaks my heart to see these poor little old <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> wandering the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> looking starved and you know
 	
 	
 		so
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">hum-um um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it uh plus uh you know the safety factor and stuff well we enjoy having <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pets</ENAMEX> we uh
 		you know i think they're a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> and and when my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> lived with us uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> was really hers and and he was kind of wild our our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> found her and brought her to us and uh
 		that <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> walked in and walked right up to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> and jumped up and curled up in her lap and she was the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> at first that you know could really hold him you know because he was really skittish but it was like he knew
 	
 	
 		oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know and he'd sleep with her and so he was a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> to her you know and and just love her and he's <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX> are usually so independent but this one you know he comes up and he crawls up next to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> now you know uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		he's you know  right before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> died we have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">queen</ENAMEX> size bed and the dog would sleep on my side and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> would sleep on my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s side you know  and when everybody turned we all <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> of us turned in a row
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 		uh-hum
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> that's one thing he hated was our <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> used to sleep with us our <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> wasn't interested in even coming in our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> but our <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> would sleep with us and he hated that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		did he
 	
 	
 		um-hum he just thought that they belong and when he'd she'd walk on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couch</ENAMEX> along the back behind his head he hated that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so i guess it's probably probably if we get another animal it probably wouldn't be a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> even though i love <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX> i think it would probably be a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> and it would definitely be an outdoor animal
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh um-</ENAMEX>hum i think that's one of the reasons our because as i said our our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schnauzer</ENAMEX> was old
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and so he was becoming incontinent and so then i would generally have messes in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and i think that's one of the things that both of us are not wanting to start over with you know
 	
 	
 		um-hum oh yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh and it was new carpeting and you know it just just really you know upset me no end and uh
 	
 	
 		um-hum oh that would <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg</ENAMEX>'s um my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX> have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> and
 		they just it needs to be put to sleep but it's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">grandpa</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> and he he is really getting too old to take care of it but the dog messes all over the carpet and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> is just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nine months</TIMEX> old
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and so then she crawls on the carpet oh the smell i mean it's just really awful and that's that's one real drawback but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know i guess you'll do just about anything for your pet if you love them enough
 	
 	
 		yes you will you will you know we were trying to decide uh
 		you know about putting him to sleep he was just you know he was getting so old and had that other problems too and and fortunately the decision was just taken away from us which made it a whole lot easier
 		you know and and again going through that because our our <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> are almost like our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> in some ways you know and and you grieve just as much over them when they go
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know as you would a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> and and you know our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> and and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandkids</ENAMEX> all say
 		get a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> get a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> you know and i'm saying be quiet be quiet and and i can tell my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> you know deep down he you know he really
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	