
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay um where do you work
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i work at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NCNB</ENAMEX> i'm a lawyer
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		um so you probably wear the suits <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		i wear a suit
 	
 	
 		yeah i was i bet um i work at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JC Penney</ENAMEX> finance
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		and i wear suits um sometimes you know the dress a nice dress or a nice pant outfit
 	
 	
 		oh you can wear pants
 	
 	
 		yes as long as we have the nylons and that and heels on
 	
 	
 		wow
 	
 	
 		so that's kind of nice
 	
 	
 		i've worn them in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the winter</TIMEX> when it's like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> degrees and you know no one's going to look
 	
 	
 		uh-huh well that's see i just moved here from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Dakota</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and now that's a change in wearing clothing
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		but uh they just got uh they're down to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> degrees now
 	
 	
 		already
 	
 	
 		yeah and they've gotten snow and the whole bit so when i was there i would wear everything you know
 	
 	
 		i didn't own a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX> coat to wear to work until um
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years ago</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		i mean my whole i what do i graduated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty three</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i have not bought one until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years ago</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		because you just don't need it
 	
 	
 		huh-uh you know when i i moved here and it's it's just great i call back there and it's just you know it's wonderful to be able to wear no coat you know and just a dress and and go to work
 	
 	
 		when did you get here
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX> first
 	
 	
 		oh so you got the summer
 	
 	
 		yeah and it wasn't too bad um because there they can have both extremes
 		so we can
 	
 	
 		yeah i guess they that uh
 	
 	
 		it can get really hot
 	
 	
 		it it did not get hot here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this summer</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's what i was told
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		that it was pretty mild  but that's when i moved and i left all my <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX> clothes with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nebraska</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		don't don't send for them
 	
 	
 		
 
 		okay i i just brought a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> and it's like they're still sitting in the closet
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah i oh i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> of them  and all the essentials essentials
 	
 	
 		you have more <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than one</NUMEX> oh God
 		um
 	
 	
 		but
 		yeah all you know we just have to wear the nice clothes and the and which i was really surprised that i wouldn't have to be in the suit
 	
 	
 		no we have a lot of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> even are believe it or not uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> are not that bad and we don't meet with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> you know we work for the
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		for the um  oh you know we work with the banking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so we don't have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> come in and look at us and we wear fun stuff too like um oh shorter skirts and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh you know a lot of dresses
 	
 	
 		yeah i i'd say it's it's uh probably eighty percent dresses
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh once in a while we wear the pants
 		but not too often
 	
 	
 		i just wear
 		i just wear an old suit when i don't feel like you know
 		i feel like i don't have any imagination <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> i'll get this starched shirt out and put a suit on
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		i know this matches i'm not going to have to think about this
 	
 	
 		yes but uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		it's the truth
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		well you'll get
 	
 	
 		but i just started the job <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few months ago</TIMEX> they just opened up um the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> that i'm working at
 		and since we are located you know they located it in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		are you in Plano
 	
 	
 		yeah i live in Plano
 		but they have it down on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hillcrest</ENAMEX> and uh LBJ
 	
 	
 		ooh
 		that's up on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hillcrest</ENAMEX> and LBJ
 	
 	
 		oh the uh okay yeah
 	
 	
 		but yeah that's um well i'm i'm more used to downtown
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		so um
 		i
 		i never lived <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">North</ENAMEX> of
 	
 	
 		yeah i haven't i haven't gone into downtown too much
 	
 	
 		well you don't need to
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		believe me you don't need to
 	
 	
 		yeah i just
 	
 	
 		lots of street people
 	
 	
 		yeah my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> works down there in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> uh book or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> is
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School Book Depository</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes and uh he it's tough
 	
 	
 		yeah there are lots of bums on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> and
 		uh
 		if you go i went to work <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX> early and i had to i parked in a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fourteen</NUMEX> dollar parking <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">garage</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh you're kidding
 	
 	
 		well uh you know i i mean i got there at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">four o'clock in the morning</TIMEX> and
 	
 	
 		oh wow
 	
 	
 		and uh i'm not going to walk you you know walk anywhere downtown at that time of the day
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		hum
 	
 	
 		and so you <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park park</ENAMEX> where you can go directly in on the tunnel
 	
 	
 		into the building
 		wow
 		yeah i haven't you know i i just haven't gone down there so you know it's pretty you
 		it's like where i'm from here
 		you know in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Dakota</ENAMEX> it wasn't a real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population population</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> has as many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> as we did in our whole state
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so it's uh
 		a little different but i really like it here so
 	
 	
 		i'm glad i'm a native so i always like to hear that
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah i really enjoy it i you know we we both graduated my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and i both graduated from college
 		and decided to move here
 	
 	
 		just like decided to move here
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		golly
 	
 	
 		he'd like to get his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Master</ENAMEX>'s at UTD
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		and he liked that school so we come here for him to start that and and he has a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> you know degree so for him to use that we had to get somewhere where that was useful
 	
 	
 		yeah except down here it's a dime a day well
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		not really if he's if he's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anglo</ENAMEX> yeah an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anglo</ENAMEX> who speaks <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	