
 
     		
 	
 		do you or your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> work for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> or
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i'm a contract person at <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> in fact involved with uh data switchboard
 	
 	
 		oh are you
 		oh i see well that's neat uh-huh
 	
 	
 		and uh do you work for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI uh</ENAMEX>-huh
 	
 	
 		so i've worked for them for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several years</TIMEX> like twelve now i guess
 	
 	
 		oh you sound very young like just out of college
 	
 	
 		well i try to i try to think of myself as young but uh well have you seen any movies recently
 	
 	
 		uh i'm trying to think we saw uh <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dances With Wolves</ENAMEX> and uh have you seen that one
 	
 	
 		oh did you
 		no i haven't i have i have a hard time with movies that are real long i don't know
 	
 	
 		that was excellent
 		well surprisingly enough i do too i get tired of sitting there and so does my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> but we both just thoroughly you know enjoyed it just really liked it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		well i've heard a lot of good things about it
 	
 	
 		and uh i'm trying to think we went to see a uh
 		a real funny one i can't think now what the name of it was i've gone blank
 	
 	
 		was it
 		uh we my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and i went and saw a couple of funny ones we saw the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Naked Gun Two and a Half</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh we have not seen that we want to see that one
 	
 	
 		yeah that was that was pretty funny and then we saw
 		what was the spoof on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Top Gun</ENAMEX>
 		it's
 	
 	
 		oh i haven't seen that one
 	
 	
 		oh i can't think of what it was called  we saw that too that i was pretty disappointed in that one  yeah but uh so you know through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> we have small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> so we don't get to see too many but we've seen i guess <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two or three</NUMEX> movies <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this past summer</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		were you
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> doesn't enjoy the shows as much going to them he likes to rent them and so we watch a lot of them you know at home as they come out and uh yes yes
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right have you seen Ghost yet
 		i really i enjoyed that movie
 	
 	
 		did you now i i was real disappointed i'm a real big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Patrick Swayze</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> and uh i was really disappointed in it it was one i don't think it was as funny as what i was anticipating anticipating and i guess i was expecting it to be kind of funny
 	
 	
 		really
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh yeah now yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh and it wasn't you know at all it was it was more of a love story and uh so i was really disappointed in that because i like him real well we just got through watching one with uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> is it <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Claude Van Damme</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Van Damme</ENAMEX> yeah i think
 	
 	
 		yeah and uh enjoyed it i can't think of what the name of it was but it was a uh of course one of the typical you know kicking fighting lots of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> and guts and all that type move and and we enjoyed that and uh
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the uh
 		uh the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jodie Foster</ENAMEX> did you see it yes wasn't that excellent
 	
 	
 		oh Silence of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lambs</ENAMEX> yes i did yeah i really enjoyed that a lot
 	
 	
 		yeah that was one that that stayed with me you know for a month i just i kept thinking about it you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah well it's amazing but really i mean when you stop and think about it uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony Perkins</ENAMEX> didn't have that big a role in the movie and yet it was his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> that was so intriguing
 	
 	
 		no
 		oh it was excellent and and of course he's such a uh very good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> anyway and i think he made the movie
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah i do too i really do you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jodie Foster</ENAMEX> was good too but i think i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony Perkins</ENAMEX> was the one that that really made the movie i agree with you
 	
 	
 		you know
 		is it <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony Perkins</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anthony Hopkins Hopkins</ENAMEX> uh-huh i know i know it uh well i'm not a real big <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jodie</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Foster fan</ENAMEX> but i thought she was good in that
 	
 	
 		oh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hopkins</ENAMEX> i'm sorry <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hopkins</ENAMEX> yeah i always get those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> mixed up
 		well i i agree well i haven't been i'm i saw her in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Accused</ENAMEX> and i thought that was a pretty good movie i thought she
 	
 	
 		no now i didn't see that one
 	
 	
 		that was that was a pretty uh interesting movie and uh but you know i i did i really liked the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Silence of the Lambs</ENAMEX> that was really intriguing and it it didn't scare me all that much you know and i i don't like to go to movies to be scared that's not why i go
 	
 	
 		no no i like a good suspenseful story and that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> very definitely kept you on the edge of the seats in fact i want to uh rent it when it comes out for my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> to see because he didn't he won't go see that no i went with uh our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so
 		right and that one was
 		oh he didn't see it oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh so you know saw it with her and uh enjoyed it my all time favorite is <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Weekend At Bernie</ENAMEX>'s did you see it
 	
 	
 		um
 		oh really yeah i've seen it
 	
 	
 		oh i've seen it you know we saw it at the movies and then we've rented it several times and we just love it in fact we have a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten year</TIMEX> old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandson</ENAMEX> that he and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and i we just sit there and cackle you know and just get hysterical
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		uh-huh yeah i've seen that it's pretty it's pretty cute i guess you know as far as comedies go probably my favorite is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Young Frankenstein</ENAMEX> i don't know i love that movie
 	
 	
 		uh yes yes my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> liked that
 	
 	
 		yeah so
 	
 	
 		uh he's a big <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gene Wilder</ENAMEX> fan
 	
 	
 		yeah well <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gene Wilder</ENAMEX> doesn't do that much for me but i'm a big uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mel Brooks</ENAMEX> fan all his movies i really really enjoy
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh uh</ENAMEX>-huh he has a new one out and uh-huh uh i have seen it advertised i don't know what the name of it is
 	
 	
 		he does
 		oh is that the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> with that's he's starring in oh yeah that came out like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early in the summer</TIMEX> or something i think yeah i haven't seen that one either it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yes yes
 		and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> wants to see that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and uh did you see that one that he made <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> about the uh
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sheriff</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blazing Saddles</ENAMEX> yeah uh-huh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blazing Saddles</ENAMEX> oh that's my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s all time favorite i think
 	
 	
 		oh uh-huh i like i like that one too but i thought <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Young Frankenstein</ENAMEX> was better yeah that that was just you know had all kinds of things throughout the whole movie i just really enjoyed it
 	
 	
 		did you
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and uh um i'm trying to think because we saw another one that we thought was really good <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early this summer</TIMEX> that was a suspenseful movie
 		i'm trying to remember what it was
 		because it you know it's
 		
 		
 	