
 
     		
 	
 		okay for as far as um i would think the probably the uh worst substance that's probably um or started to say the uh what causes the most air pollution is probably the car
 	
 	
 		
 
 		probably so
 	
 	
 		and uh whether or not um they'll ever get into like huge transit <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">systems</ENAMEX> into big <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would all travel on a high speed uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">train</ENAMEX>  or or something like that or park
 	
 	
 		yeah it'll be hard to get <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to give up their mobility
 	
 	
 		yeah that's exactly it and that's what we're finding um here where we're at in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minneapolis</ENAMEX> area is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't want to carpool that there are
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">inconveniences</ENAMEX> to that or maybe you don't like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> you have to you would want to carpool with that kind of thing so it's it's kind of a thing where uh i think the majority of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> do not carpool
 	
 	
 		i think so too i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> and very few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> carpool uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that i know don't want to because uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		they never know for sure what time they're going to leave their job they never know when they want to run out and do an errand at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX> you know they just feel they need their car
 	
 	
 		exactly
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> or if somebody gets sick yeah or if somebody gets sick and it's not the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> and they want to go home and that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s got the car then they're they're stuck you're definitely right so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		um-hum that's right and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't want to give it up but now i think we've made great strides in changing a lot of that by going to the unleaded <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gasoline</ENAMEX> and and
 	
 	
 		yes
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		sure  oops sure that happens quite a bit
 	
 	
 		to change the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> itself but uh you know i i don't guess we can get away from it <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred</NUMEX> percent but yeah
 	
 	
 		yes yeah that's very true um other than that uh i don't know oh okay oh okay we'll try to be real quick here the other thing then is because i don't know how long they want us to talk it
 	
 	
 		well my other line is ringing but we're going to ignore it  i'm sorry for these beeps
 		oh a close to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five minutes</TIMEX> i believe and you're in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minneapolis</ENAMEX> well is the pollution really bad up there
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five minutes</TIMEX> oh okay <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minneapolis</ENAMEX> area
 		uh actually no we have uh quite a bit uh the only problem that we have and that's all over the whole world is ozone and of course <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">hay</ENAMEX> fever season you get more <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pollutants</ENAMEX> such as those but those are natural
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um but there is starting to in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minneapolis</ENAMEX> itself because of so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">highway</ENAMEX> there is becoming a problem of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pollution</ENAMEX> and they just put in a strict
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		law that as of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> when you get your license tabs you have to have your <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> inspected to see if it's releasing any uh lead
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		into the air the air or other <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pollutants</ENAMEX> and if that's the case then you have to get your car fixed at least you can't
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		that's the way it has gotten here we have just had that law i think about a year maybe <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year and a half</TIMEX> here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		sure yeah
 	
 	
 		but uh i think it's a good idea because a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> still want to drive the older <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> which you can't blame them for that and uh but if they are polluting the air they need do need to have them fixed
 	
 	
 		yeah it's not a bad idea
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		sure sure
 		exactly
 	
 	
 		and you know there's a big move especially in the industrial part in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> right now of controlling the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CFCs</ENAMEX> that the big manufacturing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> are producing into the air they're having to change the type of products they use
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		sure
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh they can't use like i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> that's in the air conditioning heating business
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they have to pay a penalty for every ounce or pound of this certain type of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Freon</ENAMEX> that they use in the air conditioning systems systems
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		therefore the individual every time they have a service call if they have an old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> that's still using this <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">twenty two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Freon</ENAMEX> or whatever it is it costs them <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times as much to get it fixed
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		sure
 	
 	
 		and uh if you have a new high efficiency system that uses the new type of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freons</ENAMEX> that do not release as many <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CFCs</ENAMEX> into the atmosphere it doesn't cost as much
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so eventually <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are gonna have to go to newer systems you know but
 	
 	
 		sure uh the other thing when you're talking about freon with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> uh air conditioning i'm sure over there it's it's a necessity versus something up here we can live without it but it's uncomfortable
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> recharged our freon because it was needed to be done and one of the cans released entire amount of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">freon</ENAMEX> into the uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		hm
 	
 	
 		into the air because he opened it and i don't know if there was something wrong with it or it his directions weren't quite fully instructed onto that and i was thinking how many other people
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		it's probably happened to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> um-hum
 	
 	
 		oh sure because if you take it into a service <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX> they want to charge you <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">forty dollars</NUMEX> just for uh freon which only costs you <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about three dollars</NUMEX> so i have this feeling that freon probably will increase in price
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because it is something that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> will have to take into consideration and say hey that's that's right there i think it's like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">four dollars</NUMEX> a a can
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and it takes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about four to five</NUMEX> cans to fill up a air conditioning <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and i i thought about that and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> even was kind of woozy after that because i'm sure he breathed it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">inhaled</ENAMEX> so much of it um-hum
 	
 	
 		but uh you think about that all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are using <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">freon</ENAMEX> and things like that and
 	
 	
 		yeah well of course in the uh i'd think you probably noticed in the discount <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> and places in the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hair sprays</ENAMEX> we're not seeing <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">as many aerosol</NUMEX> cans down here nearly everything is in the pump <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">squirt</ENAMEX> you
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		exactly
 		pump yeah
 		
 		
 	