
 
     		
 	
 		now we're ready do you have a personal computer
 	
 	
 		
 
 		we have one
 	
 	
 		you do in your home
 	
 	
 		yes yes ma'am
 	
 	
 		i do not have one in my home i use <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all day</TIMEX> at work but i don't have one at home
 	
 	
 		what
 	
 	
 		do you find you use it a lot
 	
 	
 		do you wish you
 		i don't use it as much as my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> do my actually my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and i are taking a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> at our local junior college
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Microcomputers Microcomputers 101</ENAMEX> and we're just
 		touching on database spreadsheets and word processing and just kind of you know different kinds of storage and we're just kind of touching on
 		a basic  computers
 	
 	
 		um-hum um-hum what kind do you have
 	
 	
 		
 
 		we have an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX> compatible it's <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Gateway</ENAMEX> brand
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that we bought mainly for our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> to
 		have educational programs
 	
 	
 		um-hum well that sounds interesting
 	
 	
 		yeah what kind of a computer do you use at work
 	
 	
 		i
 		i have a a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PS 1 IBM</ENAMEX> type
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and i use it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all day</TIMEX> at work and i put all my personal stuff on it at work
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so i really don't haven't had a need for one at home but probably if i didn't have access to one all the time at work i'd want <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> at home
 	
 	
 		right i worked on my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airline</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apollo Focal Point</ENAMEX> computer for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about four years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it which was different
 	
 	
 		yeah what is that tracing tracking the flights and things
 	
 	
 		but i missed
 		right right how long are we supposed to talk on this
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		they tell us when we're through
 	
 	
 		oh okay okay this is
 	
 	
 		they come in and tell us have you just started doing this
 	
 	
 		this is my very first time yes
 	
 	
 		oh really they'll come in and tell us that the switchboard is full now and it's time for you to wind up in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next thirty</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">seconds</TIMEX> or something like that
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		it's not more than <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five minutes</TIMEX>  but i'm going to ignore that that's a call on my other line so i'm just gonna ignore it but
 	
 	
 		uh oh
 		oh okay oh okay that i have that too
 	
 	
 		it's kind of a hassle when you have this but other times
 	
 	
 		i
 	
 	
 		it
 	
 	
 		where where do you work
 	
 	
 		i work at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Instruments</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh you do oh well of course of course that's why you  why you're making these calls right
 	
 	
 		yes
 		i sure do
 		well no i'm doing this at home i'm already home for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the day</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh i see well this is a pretty good deal
 	
 	
 		i  do it uh you know i can't do it at work i i'm i work in the legal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> so i'm pretty busy
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i use my PC there mostly for creating legal documents we use <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WordPerfect Lotus</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh-huh oh you do know Lotus huh oh that's great that's something we want to learn
 	
 	
 		um
 		yeah it's really i love Lotus i think that's about my favorite
 	
 	
 		oh
 		i've heard that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that finally learn how to use it really like it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's great
 	
 	
 		it really is and i know there's still <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred</NUMEX> things i don't know how to do on it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh you know you learn something every time you use it
 	
 	
 		i have a question on this this thing that i'm this survey or whatever you know this i volunteered for
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		do i start calling in myself or do i wait for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to call me
 	
 	
 		you can did they give you a number to call
 	
 	
 		right an <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight hundred</NUMEX> number
 	
 	
 		you can start calling in whenever it's convenient for you but you can only make one call a day
 	
 	
 		oh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> a day
 	
 	
 		yeah if you've talked to someone like you're talking to me now and i place the call this counts as your call
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		so you cannot make a call now until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh i see okay so then do you get the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> bucks or do i
 	
 	
 		no we both do
 	
 	
 		oh we both do well that's a heck of a deal
 	
 	
 		didn't they ask you for your ID number when you answered okay so you both do from what i understand
 	
 	
 		right i had to put that in well that's a pretty good deal so why why are we doing this
 	
 	
 		it's for research
 	
 	
 		actually i'm doing this for somebody else but you know for a fund-raiser
 	
 	
 		it's a research type project on uh voice activated electronics you know to uh it's uh well they call it the speech <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lab</ENAMEX> that is setting this thing up
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh
 		it's almost like that
 		like a voice command computer type thing oh
 	
 	
 		um-hum um-hum they're doing research for a lot of big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> from what i understand on this now i don't know
 	
 	
 		well that's wonderful
 	
 	
 		i don't know everything about it but they uh try to get as many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> as they possibly can to contribute to this and that way they can check voice patterns
 	
 	
 		i see different kinds of voices and
 	
 	
 		um-hum and get the computer where it recognizes voices
 	
 	
 		things
 		wonderful see that's why i it's interesting because you have i i'm going to say you have an accent
 	
 	
 		well i probably do since i've
 	
 	
 		and i and i think that i don't i mean to you but you know
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well i've been born i was born and raised in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> have lived here forever so i probably do
 	
 	
 		and you're in what city
 	
 	
 		i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Richardson</ENAMEX> it's right outside of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay my sister one of my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> lives in Plano
 	
 	
 		uh-huh well <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richardson</ENAMEX>'s right between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> and Plano
 	
 	
 		is that right outside of
 		how about that i probably went through <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richardson</ENAMEX> then
 	
 	
 		you probably did
 	
 	
 		and then i have a sister that lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um-hum well what are you doing way in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but there both
 		well we're actually all from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nebraska</ENAMEX> they just are recently moved there my brother-in-law is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of admissions at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Texas</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um-hum well that's interesting
 	
 	
 		yeah and then my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> works at the air force base
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> so i imagine they use personal computers
 	
 	
 		actually yes they both have personal computers
 	
 	
 		do they do their correspondence on it
 	
 	
 		uh i think they just send <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> letters on it as far as i mostly my <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> uses hers for
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s games
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	