
 
     		
 	
 		do you have a pet
 	
 	
 		yes we have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> too many at the moment um
 	
 	
 		what all do you have
 	
 	
 		well we have a um a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> as a golden <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lab</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">um cat</ENAMEX> and they're both driving us crazy actually they're uh
 	
 	
 		huh
 		lot of work
 	
 	
 		just a just a lot of work and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> seem to be in so many activities that
 		the reason for having the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pets</ENAMEX> were you know for them and they don't seem to have the time to to care for them so  we're at a frustration point with our pets how about you
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		i know how that it is because until like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few days ago</TIMEX> i had a little <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miniature Pinscher</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and um my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> finally took him to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miami</ENAMEX> where they are
 	
 	
 		what
 	
 	
 		and um it was kind of a pain because i was taking these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classes</ENAMEX> after work so i couldn't leave my <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> locked up you know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all day</TIMEX> and then <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">all night</TIMEX> so i'm glad they took him
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		because  otherwise i would have a big mess in my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> when i'd come home you know
 	
 	
 		that's for sure they're they're a big responsibility they're really fun for especially for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>  if they have the time to enjoy them but
 	
 	
 		so
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		boy uh it's a lot of work it seems
 	
 	
 		um-hum but i'm i'm single so it would keep me company
 	
 	
 		that's true
 	
 	
 		you know there's something you to come home to and happy to see you
 	
 	
 		well i i enjoy <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX> if my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s out of town i enjoy having the dog just for you know he'll he'll bark if anyone comes around or
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		protection
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that sort of thing so it is a comfort from that standpoint
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		do the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> get along or
 	
 	
 		yeah they do they um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they get along fine but the  <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> doesn't get along with anyone in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> she
 		every time you walk by she grabs attacks your leg and just hangs on and we've had <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX> before we've never had one like this so i i don't know what the deal is with this <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		huh
 		did you find it or did you buy it or huh
 	
 	
 		no it was a gift  someone gave it to us  for my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>'s birthday so um
 	
 	
 		
 
 		hm
 	
 	
 		and we you know we had been looking for one so  we were hoping to get one but this this one is
 		kind of  been a problem we live across the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> from a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vet</ENAMEX> and he just can't quite figure it out either so
 	
 	
 		hm
 		um-hum it is kind of strange i wonder where they got the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">the cat</ENAMEX> from
 	
 	
 		it was um from uh um <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wills Point</ENAMEX> i don't know if you're familiar with
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">huh-uh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the town  you know just outside <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> and knew somebody that lived in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> so we're wondering if maybe if they were kind of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> outside <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">breed</ENAMEX> you know um
 	
 	
 		huh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		maybe they're just a little too wild or something
 	
 	
 		um-hum because that's what i was wondering if you found it or not because it sounded pretty wild
 	
 	
 		yeah well
 	
 	
 		huh that's interesting
 	
 	
 		but um
 	
 	
 		does your  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> hunt with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> or anything or
 	
 	
 		no no he's not a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hunter</ENAMEX> he he's always liked having big dogs but um  doesn't work real well in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> with small yard
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		when we um when we get got the dog we lived out in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and she could just run and that was fine that that worked real well
 	
 	
 		yep
 		oh how neat
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but now that we're  in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> it's kind of hard yeah
 	
 	
 		hm
 		how long have you been living where you live
 	
 	
 		um we've moved here in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		so just not quite a year  um you said you're going to school
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		um-hum yep i i'm just at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Albany Easy Learning Center</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		work
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 		i'm just taking education and psychology <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courses</ENAMEX> i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> and i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bachelor</ENAMEX>'s in psychology so i'm just trying to brush up on stuff  to be a better teacher
 	
 	
 		oh good
 		yeah
 		oh well that's good well i i bet your your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> do you have <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pets</ENAMEX> in your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">classroom</ENAMEX> or you don't
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">hum-um nope</ENAMEX> downstairs they have a gerbil and a
 	
 	
 		a what
 	
 	
 		fish i think like a gerbil and a fish but in our particular classroom we don't have anything we have plants
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		seems like our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> have mostly
 		had um <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guinea pigs</ENAMEX> and that sort of thing in their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">classrooms</ENAMEX> and that's kind of neat you know um the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">class</ENAMEX> gets to take turns taking it home and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		hm
 	
 	
 		and that so a little visiting pet you can you can uh have the fun of it without the total responsibility
 	
 	
 		um-hum yep
 	
 	
 		but that's worked well
 	
 	
 		can just mess up it's cage  you don't have to worry about your whole apartment
 	
 	
 		right
 		really
 	
 	
 		yep
 		um have you been trying to call in lately and it's been the same topic
 	
 	
 		no um let's see i'm trying to think the last time i called in was probably  um
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		few <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days ago</TIMEX> it was cooking or something
 	
 	
 		it was what
 	
 	
 		cooking yeah
 	
 	
 		really because i've been calling in lately and this is uh my last call that i have to make i think
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and um <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every single day</TIMEX> for probably <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a week</TIMEX> it was gun control
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		gun control and i was just about to freak out you know because i already talked with someone about gun control
 	
 	
 		
 
 		get tired of gun control huh
 	
 	
 		uh-huh you only can talk so much about gun control so hm
 	
 	
 		this is true yeah
 		well um-hum well do we go until they cut us off or
 		
 		
 	