
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay
 		i don't have a budget my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and i i should make that clear i've been married <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty three years</TIMEX> and we've never had and we don't follow budgets but i've got the greatest system going  i just don't handle any money
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and i told her when we got married that i am going to earn so much money and she can spend it on what she wants but if she ever spends more than i earn she's got to go to work she's never gone to work yet so
 	
 	
 		smart woman
 	
 	
 		so it worked
 		
 
 		so it's so you know it's really great
 		so i you know to answer their question i we don't we don't have a budget
 	
 	
 		yeah we don't we don't uh  we didn't when we <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> got married uh i've been married <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only about four years</TIMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> always wanted to write something down and keep track and i said look <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mary  i</ENAMEX> said you you get money we should save a little bit
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh whatever else you know play it by ear go spend on whatever you spend it on and if at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the month</TIMEX>
 		our checking account is no good then we got to sit down and and decide what we're going to stop spending it on but until that happens let's not worry about it
 	
 	
 		yep
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> and since then we've both been done pretty well regarding uh raises and stuff at our jobs and and our rent has stayed relatively low
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and now we haven't had that problem yet and then my we we just had our <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two months</TIMEX> ago
 		and then i said well we'll see what happens then because she she had to take some time off work and she probably will even quit her job now and maybe do some part time work
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but we still haven't had a problem paying the rent so i don't know what the i guess i'm blessed in the sense that i have a good enough job that i don't have to worry about that
 	
 	
 		yeah you live right in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah i live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX> i work out in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Queens</ENAMEX> oh which is also part of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> there's just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> boroughs
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> so your rent is quite expensive as compared to what we're accustomed to back here probably
 	
 	
 		yeah except for i have a a rent um stabilized apartment <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">um</ENAMEX> so the rent is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only seven hundred</NUMEX> and fifty dollars a month which for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> is extremely inexpensive in a very good neighborhood
 	
 	
 		oh i see
 		oh yeah yeah
 		well that's great  no i can you know again i can see the reason for them i have  i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> grown <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and
 		one my youngest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> is
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken</ENAMEX> they both have very very good jobs they live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> they have absolutely no problem they have no need for it  and my eldest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> he very definitely has to live by a budget because he just cannot control control his finances
 		but i don't you know i cannot see this  which i have a very close <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister-in-law</ENAMEX> that  everything she does at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the beginning of the month</TIMEX> or every payday she sits sits down and fills envelopes  and i've i find that
 		that's a tedious bore i mean if we had to live like that i'm not so sure i'd want to continue working
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but for them it works so i mean whatever  uh our system works for us we we have a policy my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and i both that we don't
 		everything we have is ours as far as money we don't holdout holdout on each other or anything else and never really had a problem  but i do believe in
 		uh retirement investment programs very much so
 		uh nowadays you sound like you're fairly young so i you know i keep telling my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> for God's sakes get involved in it because when they retire they should have a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">half dollars</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah i i i i agree the same i mean you know i i see too many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elderly people</ENAMEX> with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> uh is a social <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX> and she works with the elderly
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh you know in in your i don't know how how much older you're i'm <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> and
 	
 	
 		i'm fifty <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> so
 	
 	
 		yeah uh you're generation has gotten pretty lucky regarding or at least in this area regarding real estate you know they went and bought a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fourteen thousand</NUMEX> dollars and then they they were <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixty years old</TIMEX> and retired
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and sold that same <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two hundred</NUMEX> fifty <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">thousand dollars</NUMEX> and
 		you know moved down to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> or did whatever they had to do but they had all this capital um i don't know if the real estate market's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gonna</ENAMEX> say the same for one thing i'm <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> i'm an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> and uh i don't own a house
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		which i think is unusual because all the my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> owned <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> when we were growing up and now i grew up in suburbia as opposed to in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> but still
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um but someday i'd like to own a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and and i i've certainly um make it a point that that i will put some money away um
 		uh maybe a little less now while my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> isn't working so that someday we can have a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and we can that would be our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX> and in addition to that i have
 		at work they have you know uh investment plans where you can avoid having to go through um paying taxes but your entire
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right oh those things are great i boy i encourage those  yeah you're you don't own a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and i'm fifty <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> and i just built my <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> home
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		really
 	
 	
 		so i just took on another mortgage don't ask me why i really don't but it's tax
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> you have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> homes now or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> okay
 	
 	
 		i've had no i've had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> no not all at the same time
 		but this is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> one i've owned and this one i built but  i'm looking at this as an investment so i hope real estate keeps climbing and it's a brand new area so it should
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah  i mean at this point in this area i mean it's it's absolutely ludicrous my
 		my uh just the main you know just the taxes and upkeep of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> would cost me more than i'm paying in rent now obviously i get the
 	
 	
 		right
 		
 		
 	