
 
     		
 	
 		okay let's talk about schooling
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah uh what what what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contacts</ENAMEX> do you have with uh public school system
 	
 	
 		okay well i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> and he just went into middle <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> early  and i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> and she's in uh grade school
 		and then i have a little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> who goes to uh they have something just before kindergarten and it's called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Early Childhood</ENAMEX> and i have a young a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> in that
 	
 	
 		oh okay um-hum
 	
 	
 		so i i have a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in in the school system down here
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and um i think we have excellent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> here i am really uh like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> like the way the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> work with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>
 		uh i've not been so um
 		happy with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>  themselves i guess like my <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> were in the same grade <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> before he moved up to middle school and it was just packed
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i mean it was a a fire hazard if we had any kind of assembly there with parents
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and it was just a real problem uh so we had to do a bond issue and and um
 		vote to take money and either have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> bussed to different <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> if that's what the preferred to do
 		or to uh work on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> work for another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> to be built
 		which is a good idea but in the meantime the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> still has lots and lots of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> in it
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		so um i think one thing is that would maybe we don't have enough <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and secondly when we have enough schools
 		sometimes we can't get the the support for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> that we need to pay them to keep good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well i think that's i think that's uh true i i've got a a little different uh contact but i've i've got a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> that graduated from high school <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> and another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> that's a
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		a sophomore <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> and uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> teaches kindergarten here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Richardson</ENAMEX>  ah but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh great
 	
 	
 		in general i i think that the you know one of the reasons that we we uh
 		the choice to live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Richardson</ENAMEX> when we when we came here was the was the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and i think that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plano</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richardson</ENAMEX> in terms of the uh
 		uh things seriously wrong with the public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> are are not nearly to the extent that that
 	
 	
 		we see through the out the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> name
 	
 	
 		and right right and i think and i think part of that is that is the the uh your big part of that is just uh the demographics the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> in those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> are are
 		typically uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that very much value the education and support the the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school systems</ENAMEX> and and uh
 	
 	
 		um-hum i think that's right
 	
 	
 		although there is still some still some problems but uh
 		i i you know i when when i was when i was going to school and i grew up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> and and we in my family <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> was certainly valued but if there was ever any sort of a uh
 		if ever if i was ever in trouble in school i was also in trouble at home and and even more so and i think that that part of it is is not
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		exactly with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> but with the with the uh
 		the culture that doesn't doesn't value the education and doesn't value the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and doesn't support uh
 	
 	
 		the home yeah
 		uh i think that's right
 	
 	
 		what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> are are trying to do
 	
 	
 		it is so hard with a family system um either divorced or or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">just one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> or just
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true
 	
 	
 		uh like and then if both of them have to work even that is a a hard situation
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> uh to to have a supportive system around them to make school work for them
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i think it's really important that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> work with the school um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i think what you said is is really a pinpoint though that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> and the family life really adds or detracts from what's happening in the school
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so um well what about your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> is she she happy at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> or  she's just ready
 	
 	
 		well uh she she works very hard as a kindergarten <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> she she has she has <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two half day</TIMEX> classes so she has uh
 	
 	
 		oh i bet she does
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know  on the order of twice as many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> as as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> in the higher grades and uh uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right right
 	
 	
 		but her her background is in is in uh
 		child development and and uh so forth and so kindergarten is as high as she as she wants to teach and she's she's teaching rather than something else because that that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		that's the jobs that are available and that the schedule matches uh you know with our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and things like that so
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		yeah uh and but uh the
 		
 		
 	