
 
     		
 	
 		well i don't know if there's gonna be a solutions to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US</ENAMEX> budget
 	
 	
 		well i know it's in pretty disastrous shape for sure
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's only getting worse exponentially it seems um
 	
 	
 		yes exactly
 		there's uh maybe some short term things that they can do and it hurts everybody's pocket of course but um i know that state
 		has uh cutback uh raises for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> to help uh
 		the uh state financial or whatever you might want to say to get better in a better condition that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh which state is that
 	
 	
 		uh state of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so there's the potential that perhaps
 		you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US</ENAMEX> budget might wanna take a look at it's uh federal
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> or and take a look at saying well let's freeze
 		wages i mean everybody's doing it so it isn't like uh private business has had to do it so it might have to be something that they might consider doing as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shirt</ENAMEX> that's got to be very short term
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 		right
 	
 	
 		and and the only other <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">avenue</ENAMEX> that i can think of is um looking at where they're spending the money and not so much as
 		saying  well we're spending too much in that area as perhaps looking at what is costing them the moneys uh
 	
 	
 		yep
 	
 	
 		for for instance i think you probably remember the military getting caught um with toilet seats that cost them <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">four hundred five hundred dollars</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and it was just i mean you can go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kmart</ENAMEX> and buy them for uh <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">eight dollars</NUMEX> or i think <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">six dollars</NUMEX> or whatever for toilet seats so
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yep
 		yeah definitely i think that there's probably a lot of
 	
 	
 		so it gives you an idea that
 	
 	
 		waste in defense and in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> funded research in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place
 	
 	
 		sure sure so
 	
 	
 		i mean there was
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">um people</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stanford</ENAMEX> who
 		were soaking the government you know using <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">millions of dollars</NUMEX> of research money to um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> to buy beach <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> or whatever it was
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i think that that may be more widespread
 	
 	
 		than we think sure
 	
 	
 		than well than we'd like to think but  but then
 	
 	
 		sure
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know it's something that's hard to enforce too i'm sure
 	
 	
 		um-hum it sure is the you know as far as i think there was something with the government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> that went on conferences for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two days</TIMEX> and actually
 		uh the conferences were nothing but uh you know they're getting paid for this and it was something more than just the conferences they were using it as eating out um when you think about people
 		uh taking vacations these big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> taking descendants in congress the rest of them taking these vacations and using the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX>' money for that and it's a real big crunch
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh of course when they get caught then they're you know they're guilty of course but uh during that time i'm sure there's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are um spending money that does not belong to them
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well that's right the i think that oh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> talk a lot about waste but i'm not sure that that's really that much of the
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		problem i mean when you look at
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		something like the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gulf War</ENAMEX> it cost us God knows
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		how much you know at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a million dollars</NUMEX> a pop for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Patriot</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		exactly and i i don't think uh it's ended up being i mean it gave <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> jobs
 	
 	
 		and
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but i think it also cost um quite a bit as far as because after they're done with the war a lot of things were no longer put to use i mean it was kind of like okay we'll do this during this point and time but after that that's
 		you know um they didn't wanna do it anymore
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so a lot of things that they're saying that they're no longer gonna be doing for
 		next wars that are coming up that they did for this one in getting rid of a lot of things so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i don't know  okay well it was good talking to you and have a good <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 		okay all right you too bye-bye
 	
 	
 		uh-huh thanks bye now
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	