
 
     		
 	
 		well i've been real um thinking i'd love to buy a new car right now if i could afford it but we have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">right now</TIMEX> and we're still paying on but i would love to have one of these new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">minivans</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i've got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> little ones and i think that would be just the perfect <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> car
 	
 	
 		i right now my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> is terminally ill so i am really looking at uh facing the purchase of a car
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and uh what i would like to have is so totally impractical for me that i won't do it  uh well i would like for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time in my life to have a convertible
 	
 	
 		well what is it
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and uh you know i don't even like the wind blowing on me so i don't know why i think i want <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> but i do
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh i will probably stay with a foreign make i've had real good luck with them
 	
 	
 		yeah we have um
 		we have we went out to buy an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> so we bought um a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chevy Nova</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about three years ago</TIMEX> and then we opened up the the hood and it said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toyota</ENAMEX>
 		made in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> right across the front of all the engine parts
 	
 	
 		is that right
 	
 	
 		um-hum <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toyota</ENAMEX> uh well the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chevy Nova</ENAMEX> is the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toyota</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Camry uh</ENAMEX> at that time
 		was the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> so they just put different names on them depending on who they're being shipped to i thought that was pretty insensitive
 	
 	
 		oh well i didn't realize it i knew that one of the
 		that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nissan</ENAMEX> which is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toyota</ENAMEX> had uh joined with
 		had a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> over here and and i didn't know if it was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Motors</ENAMEX> or who
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but i i never thought of
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i don't know uh you think of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chevrolet</ENAMEX> and the good old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um-hum um-hum that's why we were so surprised to see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toyota</ENAMEX> written i mean imprinted on the engine it was real interesting
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		but uh i with so many options now available you know where where <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> are concerned it just seems like there is
 		there's almost too much of a choice anymore you know that there's
 		so many different options and so many different prices and who has this cash back and whatever i think that if i were
 		really serious about looking for another car i would take into consideration the price naturally but um
 		you know i would really want something that i would want for that much money for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> or twelve or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">fifteen thousand dollars</NUMEX> or whatever
 	
 	
 		uh well yeah and that's minimum
 	
 	
 		oh yeah definitely
 	
 	
 		it you know it's it's a major purchase now what we used to pay for homes
 		is now what a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> can cost
 	
 	
 		i cannot imagine that you know somebody i heard a commercial or something about a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixty</TIMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">thousand dollars</NUMEX> car
 		about oh oh it would how exciting it is to make that kind of a purchase and i thought i don't think i'd find that exciting i'd be wondering you know here i am buying this expensive of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> isn't worth that much money
 	
 	
 		
 
 		if they held their value that would be one thing but when you consider that when you drive them off of the show lot they're immediately <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">two thousand dollars</NUMEX> depreciated
 	
 	
 		that's true
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and you know that
 		i don't know that i'll go with i've bought a new car the last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> that i've bought and i don't know that i'll buy a brand new one again
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah well we got a pretty we bought our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chevrolet</ENAMEX> brand new and then we bought a used <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>   just a minute i'll change your diaper  the we bought our our next <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> used
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and uh we had better luck with our used <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and i like it more it cost us less money and we got more features and air-conditioning and whatever on it then we did on our brand new one for
 		twice as much money
 	
 	
 		well i'm i'm seriously considering going that route instead of a brand new car

 	
 	
 		if you can find one that's reliable uh you know reliable if you can get someone that you trust to buy one from or you know make sure that you can have it checked out well enough
 	
 	
 		well some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you know some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have to have a new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh i wouldn't
 	
 	
 		or it you know at the most every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> and they don't drive them that much
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		especially your foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>
 		yeah like a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Honda</ENAMEX> or uh a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toyota</ENAMEX> fifty <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousand</NUMEX> is just getting broken in for them
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and if i can find one or a repossession
 	
 	
 		that's we bought one like that
 	
 	
 		and with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> being in such financial you know problems now that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you can find the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> willing to sell you a car
 	
 	
 		uh-huh we bought <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> that way and had we bought it real reasonably and it was in real nice condition so because apparently whatever the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> get
 		
 		
 	