
 
     		
 	
 		okay i've got a you know i have a real good method of
 		starting to get the budget balanced again and that's get <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> rid of the half the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> payroll
 	
 	
 		i think that would probably  uh be very possible and and and we really wouldn't feel it in our services
 	
 	
 		
 
 		not all i you know i don't know if you've ever been to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes i have
 	
 	
 		uh you you've seen that which was on there and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> and in light of these uh hearings we've all been sitting through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last two weeks</TIMEX> we have very definitely decided that every <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> there is just overstaffed
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		they really don't have enough to keep them busy and keep their noses at in their own business and what they're doing and the other thing is uh
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		besides that i think uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> things that very definitely need looking at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> is foreign aid
 		i have a real problem with all the foreign aid that is going to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> that really have no use for us  i find that a total waste and part of the defense budget
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh again being just a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voter voter</ENAMEX> and a taxpayer
 		you know working through our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">congressman</ENAMEX> i don't think there's too much that i'm gonna be able to do about it but
 		i believe in taking an active part in politics so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well i <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one one</NUMEX> thing that really bothers me beyond beyond cutting what they spend is that just really aggravates me when the big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> do not end up paying taxes and the um
 		regular normal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX> are you know paying such a large proportion of of our personal income and then  the uh corporate
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah industries just don't seem to not pay proportionally
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		i think that that would would help a lot i guess in a way it would trickle down to us in the prices of things but
 		i don't know it's just hard to  hard to take um you know see so much of our paycheck go out and then realize that they have all the loopholes that they can use
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh seems like some rather large chunks of money could come from from that direction
 	
 	
 		yeah they don't they don't seem to well
 	
 	
 		but
 	
 	
 		i really think the biggest problem and then the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Taft Rudman Act</ENAMEX> is supposed to help that the biggest part is they have no accountability for what they're doing
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i mean this nonsense that's coming through now about uh uh lowering
 		payments on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> and a few other things that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> has in mind in order to to boost the economy because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have no more money is it's it it's ridiculous
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		if they don't have that money now bringing in less is not gonna help the problem as far as the government
 	
 	
 		not not gonna help
 		it's never never helped my my personal situation i i can't say it would help theirs either
 	
 	
 		
 
 		no
 		yeah and thank God we don't operate our budget the way they operate theirs or we'd all be in in dire trouble
 	
 	
 		we're we're being serious
 	
 	
 		but that's uh
 		yeah i don't know what we're gonna be able to do about it but i guess it's been around so long that
 		it's sort of like our mortgages i don't ever expect to pay mine off before i die so i guess why should the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> try
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		isn't that's the way they're thinking <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> anyway
 	
 	
 		it seems seems to be i you know i it really does bother me when i think about  you know leaving our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> with with this sort of uh
 		a national problem that we can't seem to find an an answer to it i i don't know
 	
 	
 		i i don't think it ever will really i maybe if they ever get to the point the biggest
 		you know the biggest outlaid expense has always been either wars or defense
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		really if they were to take <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of what they spend on that and put it on some economic
 		you know intergovernmental intergovernmental or inter-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> type programs that i wouldn't really mind i
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i believe in paying my share and i don't mind uh paying for some of these fringe benefits that  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are entitled to but i just i just
 		sometimes feel like i'm being used  but uh  again i don't think we'll be able to do anything about it so
 	
 	
 		well that that's quite possible i guess we have to have to keep plugging away a little bit or it'll just totally get even more out of control but i  i don't know
 	
 	
 		yeah bite the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bullet</ENAMEX> it sounds like you have a baby there
 	
 	
 		yeah i i do she's a we're not feeling too well over here so that  yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh really
 		oh that's a shame she's not the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> going to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> huh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		no no she's  i don't think i could part with her
 	
 	
 		oh
 		okay okay <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		we've probably been on long enough they didn't cut us off but i think that'll probably do it so it was nice talking to you
 	
 	
 		okay well thanks bye bye
 	
 	
 		okeydoke bye-bye
 		
 
 		
 		
 	