
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well uh and that's an idea that's been around for kicked around for a long time i don't know that it's ever been
 		seriously considered uh as far as close to passing uh any legislation or anything like that but
 		i believe <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> does that don't they for their
 	
 	
 		uh yes i think so uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the
 		well everybody has to do  has to do something or maybe maybe theirs is in fact <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one year</TIMEX> of military service for everyone but uh
 	
 	
 		yeah i don't know
 		yeah i believe that's right
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		and uh  and i don't know that that's really what we're talking about uh
 	
 	
 		no i don't think it's it's necessary no i think of that it it it couldn't be military <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> is not that much but
 		military used to do it but the idea that uh
 		there are things that that do need to be done that could be done and then uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> would benefit from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one year</TIMEX> from from everybody and even out the the
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah for for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> in high school it could be in the summertime
 	
 	
 		requirement
 		well now that's a thought yeah
 	
 	
 		uh
 		you know um
 		it it could even be done while they're doing another job while they're doing you know a job to make money
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but uh  it's uh you know such a grassroots idea that it it i think the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> would have to be involved in it and and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would have to be convinced that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know i i think the the basic message is that giving is better than receiving
 	
 	
 		yeah right
 	
 	
 		and that's not the kind of society we have right now
 	
 	
 		oh yeah i'm afraid you're right there but uh
 		but uh
 		anything like this it came up whether it it
 		quickly would be
 		significant industry in in figuring out how to get around it where
 	
 	
 		yeah there are lots and lots of volunteer programs and um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who didn't wanna
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but most of those are
 		at least at least it it's my opinion that most of those involve uh adults
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> who have the time to give and and uh you know the desire
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		to to give
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it's not uh
 		you know it's not uh maybe the maybe it could uh younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> feel like it's not open to them i don't know
 		but but it should be if it's not
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		uh i suspect that the yeah that that that that's not the thing that they that they don't feel it's open to them it's just that they
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> are more self-centered if you will and not not considering voluntary preference
 	
 	
 		yeah it is kind of an introspective time of life but some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> some high <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>  have actually started a program of like a visitation program to
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh
 		you know areas economically uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		say less advantaged areas and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they they promote service
 		on the part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> to to uh some of those people
 		so at least that's a step in the right direction i guess
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		at uh
 		now i didn't
 		
 
 		i don't know it did
 		i i think you're right that that that's not the not the way that the society <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> is going and i i
 		think we need to  we need to try to figure out some way to to turn that around that everybody
 	
 	
 		yeah it's really it's really unfortunate because  when you do
 		i do volunteer work for  the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Lung Association</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		and i have have done uh gone to work for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Heart</ENAMEX> and just recently for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leukemia Society</ENAMEX>
 		and there's there's no question that doing you know doing that kind of service you get a lot more out of it than uh than the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> involved
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh it's it's really a gift to yourself and and that's i think that's a really a really important lesson to learn
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and and and maybe that's why we have so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in society who are not uh not really happy
 		you know
 	
 	
 		or that could be
 	
 	
 		because if  if you concentrate all of your energies and efforts on yourself you're just kind of down the tube you know
 	
 	
 		yeah right
 	
 	
 		uh  really is better to give then to receive
 	
 	
 		yeah i agree i
 		agree with that and uh
 		and i'd i'd
 		i don't know what  what what has what has set it off or what but it it it certainly seems to me that that uh
 		uh
 		things in in the last <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty thirty years</TIMEX> uh things things have have definitely gone towards uh
 		very much the concentration on self and and and loss of loss of perspective in terms
 		
 		
 	