
 
     		
 	
 		what do you like to watch on television <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maureen</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well  i guess a lot of the uh something that's kind of more of a comedy  we do have uh cable and we have premium <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBO</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Showtime</ENAMEX> and such and
 		i guess a lot of times when i <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> turn the TV on i i normally go to those because i pay for them i'm like i guess i want to see if there's anything i really want to see there so i don't end up watching the um
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">prime</ENAMEX> time on some of the standard channels as much i i tend to go to my premium channels first
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh uh</ENAMEX>-huh well we have cable but we only have <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cinemax</ENAMEX> and uh i think our favorite <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> is uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> and we start out with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Evening Shade</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Major Dad</ENAMEX> and i think that's the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one night</TIMEX> that we really try to watch television you know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s always got it on i'm not always sitting down at it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		yeah
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>'s pretty good with <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Murphy Brown and Designing Women</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes yes yes i just i love that all those that <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">that two hours</TIMEX> and uh now tonight i just finished up with that <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Woman Called</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackie</ENAMEX> did you watch did you watch it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		we had watched it uh i guess <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> but we didn't get to watch it tonight
 	
 	
 		yeah it was it was pretty good it uh sometimes i like a dramatization and i like uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX> when they have their uh  uh mystery movies and things their made for TV movies
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh i like those and we very seldom watch any uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public Television</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX> thirteen do you watch it much
 	
 	
 		the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">only night</TIMEX> we tend to watch some of that is on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nights</TIMEX> starting fairly late like i'm talking <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ten o'clock</TIMEX> and maybe till <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">midnight</TIMEX> they have some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> comedy
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		that we've we've really liked a there's a variety some of them is uh <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Black Adder or Good Neighbors</ENAMEX> or Yes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> and Are You Being Served they they rotate those around
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and um we like that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> comedy <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> comedy is very fast you really have to listen but
 	
 	
 		yes it is now we haven't watched any of those
 	
 	
 		they're real good but they do come on kind of late but we really do enjoy those sometimes we get to watching some stuff on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Discovery Channel</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes now we have watched some things on that
 	
 	
 		and i'm amazed sometimes what i see on there  but i'm very intrigued i <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time i was watching a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX> and i thought gee i i don't believe i'm watching this
 	
 	
 		yeah we had uh i don't know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> loves to uh
 		that male syndrome of flicking that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX> thing you know and he's flipping around there and
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and he went by and he said whoops and he  backed up and you know there's this surgery going on as we're eating our dinner  you know and and i'm saying let's move right on
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 		yeah right right
 	
 	
 		but our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandchildren</ENAMEX> like that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Discovery Channel</ENAMEX> if they're over here because lots of times they will have things on <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">uh animals</ENAMEX> and they just thoroughly
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know enjoy that in fact i think they were watching something on uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">whales</ENAMEX> or killer <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sharks sharks</ENAMEX> one or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other  couple of weeks ago</TIMEX> over here and uh so we have watched that and uh  otherwise  of course my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s into the football
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and you know i will watch that some if i'm reading or doing something else you know with him and uh but other
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah i'm not into watching sports now my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> likes to watch football

 		he's not really into <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">uh baseball</ENAMEX> or basketball too much but uh football soon as it's fall then he likes to watch <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> and then of course <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cowboys</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes
 		
 
 		yes and sometimes now we're getting it that uh the other football where they play it
 		inside and you know i'm hollering this is a you know this is too much
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saturdays</ENAMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sundays</TIMEX> this is fine but do we have to carry this on into <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the spring</TIMEX>  you know all of that and uh but he will uh he'll flip around i think <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the other night</TIMEX> we had on uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		um
 	
 	
 		uh it was a it was car races some kind of car races where they were bumping over hills and flying into the air and coming down i don't know what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX> he found that on
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		and uh but he will turn that on especially for if again if our uh oldest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandson</ENAMEX> is over here he's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> and uh they'll find something like that and just absolutely sit glued to it i you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i keep telling him it's the same mentality there you know something's wrong  and uh but uh and we very seldom watch television on a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> because we're not home
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and uh so and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sundays</TIMEX> uh we usually have all of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are over on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> so you know we don't get into that except that sometimes we'll get into the home videos
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		do you ever watch that
 	
 	
 		yeah the you mean talking about the funny home videos and stuff yeah those are pretty good  yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah um-hum
 		that are sometimes so dumb
 	
 	
 		but true to life i mean some of the those
 	
 	
 		but very true to life i mean i've seen our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> in several of those situations
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	