
 
     		
 	
 		hi i'm wondering what what camping means to you
 	
 	
 		hi
 		when i think of camping i think of of bugs  and sleeping bags and and tents uh like along the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Appalachian Trail</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh very good that's sort of the same thing that that i do i don't think of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">um trailers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">campers</ENAMEX> and all this stuff
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		um do you do much camping
 	
 	
 		i have never been camping
 	
 	
 		oh you've never been camping oh gee
 	
 	
 		no do you do much
 	
 	
 		well um yes and no and the uh i haven't done much recently but um up until
 		gee maybe <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five or six years ago</TIMEX> i did a lot of it  and you know i've sorry
 	
 	
 		really uh
 		where you live now or uh did you camp up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> or
 	
 	
 		no um i used to live abroad and so i i camped a lot in um the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> and i was able to camp right in ruins which was always very exciting
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 		oh i bet
 	
 	
 		and a bit exotic  for those who love bugs but
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> and then when i used to come back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> we'd often go up um to the lake <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and and do camping there
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh okay well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousin uh husband</ENAMEX> and and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncle</ENAMEX> especially uh grew up camping together and uh they they just love it
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and they're planning a trip uh into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>
 		this i guess in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a year</TIMEX> and they're going to spend <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a week</TIMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a half</NUMEX> camping up there
 	
 	
 		and you're not going
 	
 	
 		no this is this is a a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s trip so
 	
 	
 		oh that's too bad
 	
 	
 		so they're really looking forward to that
 	
 	
 		oh gee
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		i guess it makes a difference i grew up camping being in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Girl Scouts</ENAMEX> and things like that so
 	
 	
 		and see i was i was never exposed to it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so it's i i feel like i'm a little bit too uh much of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city city</ENAMEX> mouse to try doing it
 	
 	
 		oh that's too bad i think the you know there's certainly a lot of aspects you would like but maybe not the you you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>'s trip but some other you know a nice tent on the the shore of a lake and
 	
 	
 		what's the best part about it to to you the the quiet the getting away
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">right the</TIMEX> and the the no telephone the gee <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whiz</ENAMEX> you go to bed when it gets dark and you get up when it gets light
 	
 	
 		
 
 		man
 	
 	
 		yeah and um i guess just just the change from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX> race
 	
 	
 		
 
 		now do you usually like do you usually go and there's lots of other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> around or is it pretty much much isolated
 	
 	
 		no it's uh it's pretty isolated um and to me i like that i guess too although there are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i mean you know it's really hard to get away
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and i guess when when we did sites in in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> of course it was with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> in order to make it safe
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		but i mean we'd go in different parts of the ruins and and things like that but we didn't even have tents there  we just sort of put out the sleeping roll
 	
 	
 		oh good grief
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		that that does sound neat but i don't think i i've got a quite enough nerve to do that
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s gone uh for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several days</TIMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Appalachian Trail</ENAMEX> before and he said that you can a lot of times you can go for you know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a good day</TIMEX> before you'll see or meet anybody else on the trail
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		so it's not for the faint of heart i don't think
 	
 	
 		right actually i just joined um the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Appalachian Trail Walking Club</ENAMEX> or whatever they call it what uh and i'm very eager to to start uh i love to walk
 	
 	
 		oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and um i'm going to start with day trips though because i don't know the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">territory</ENAMEX> and all and i'm not sure um my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> is not eager to go and  you know i think that that that might be a little eerie at first going alone
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i think it would be yeah  well that sounds really neat
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh but you know i'm gonna try  well gee <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whiz</ENAMEX> i hope you get into camping some day just slowly
 	
 	
 		well
 		i don't know uh we talk about sometimes going up to Chincoteague
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh i maybe like you said start out slow and and kind of get used to it and find out that it maybe it's not as bad as i i fear it might be
 	
 	
 		right i think that you know  i guess <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time recently we went up to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maine</ENAMEX> and had planned to camp
 		and you know the only site left when we got there was in the middle of a field and i said gee <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whiz</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty</TIMEX> dollars we can go down the road and get a a motel which we did and so that you know if the setting was right and that it's it's great but if it's just
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 		
 	