
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay  well uh some of the books i've read lately have to do with crafty type things where i've
 		where i've um learned things that i'm going to do for my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they were really uh helpful
 		because i didn't know how to do this one stitching
 		and so that was very helpful to me as far as books otherwise
 		um i like to read <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s books
 		and things like that what about you
 	
 	
 		oh goodness well i was an <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> major so i like to read period
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		uh lately i've been on the whole very practical
 		and uh i'm trying uh to to uh furnish a home
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		so i've been
 		looking at i'm not sure reading is the word but looking at books on uh antiques and paintings and uh interior decoration hints
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh lots of books on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> and and and gardens because we started a garden
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and things things like that and so i've been doing very little reading except i i did finally dip into a couple of biographies
 		um all of sort of literary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figures</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this century</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> it's interesting that you said that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and i had uh took a book out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> about gardening too and started a garden a fall garden
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		um with
 	
 	
 		good for you i haven't gotten around to that
 	
 	
 		oh  yeah and our our uh cantaloupes and and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">um peppers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tomatoes</ENAMEX> are on right now
 		so it's been really fun and and we learned that you know um some of the gardening skills we had were before but some of them we learned from a book
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so that was helpful to us now i've read <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> books
 		uh that were uh nonfiction lately and uh
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		i
 		well one was nonfiction and one was fiction
 		and the fiction one uh was about a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> in uh during the time of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adolf Hitler</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		and he grew up and lived through a concentration camp
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		and that was not enjoyment  that that was too realistic and really um mind
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		a real eye opener  uh and i guess it's good to read those things too
 		uh but i didn't enjoy it necessarily
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh the other one was quite enjoyable it was uh about a
 		a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generations</ENAMEX> down her what happened to her family through the years
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		so that one was good i think all of uh well even if they're not enjoyable they bring you uh a some kind of of learning
 		so even if it's the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> that they're from or anything like that
 		so i
 		i i like to read the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s books i think that's the most animated and imaginative so i like those a lot
 	
 	
 		uh what are your favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s books
 	
 	
 		oh there are a couple of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Newbery Award winners uh A Wrinkle in Time</ENAMEX> is one  and i don't know if you've ever read that but but um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		no
 	
 	
 		oh there's one about an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> and i can't think of that
 		Island of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blue Dolphins</ENAMEX> is another
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		and that's a good one
 		now some of the ones that have just received the awards <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> i haven't read and i would like to read those
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh it's funny because i've read some from like nineteen <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">twenty three and nineteen forty five</NUMEX> and things like that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i didn't enjoy those as much and i don't know if it's just because they didn't come from my <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">era</TIMEX> or what but uh
 	
 	
 		that's interesting i i i well i mean you can't be an <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> major major unless you like reading things from the past
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so i've read a a great deal of old things i tend to go go back i don't have any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so i don't read the new ones but i occasionally if no one's looking
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		dip into something like <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Winnie the Pooh</ENAMEX> or
 	
 	
 		uh-huh no even that's good
 	
 	
 		or uh uh the the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grimm</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Fairy Tales</ENAMEX> or something like that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um just because it's sheer magic
 	
 	
 		yeah uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and i uh i started a thing where i read a book with them before they went
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		to bed at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> and there was one called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Pig Princess</ENAMEX>
 		and it was a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a princess</NUMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long long time ago</TIMEX> and she came through a a spell kind of thing and ended up in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pig um sty</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that she came to were just
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		farm <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and she didn't understand them and they didn't understand her but it came together in this book and it was really a lot of fun
 	
 	
 		yes
 		yes i think that uh we we
 		
 		
 	