
 
     		
 	
 		okay where do you enjoy dining out
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh i generally go to the quickie places just because they're cheap
 	
 	
 		yes do you have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh we have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> but most of them are gone now so there there might be but we were taking you know uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four five</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> out
 	
 	
 		ah
 		yes that makes a difference doesn't it uh-huh what area of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> do you live in
 	
 	
 		yes
 		i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes i am too
 	
 	
 		and we lived we lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX> prior to this oh
 	
 	
 		so
 		i did too  i'm from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dayton</ENAMEX> area
 	
 	
 		uh we were up near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cleveland</ENAMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		ah
 	
 	
 		but i look for service even at the quickie places type things uh i don't like to go to the drive-thrus because sometimes they get your order wrong and then you're stuck and it's a pain to have to
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		stand there and see what it is before you leave so i really don't like the drive-thrus that much i i like to go and eat there
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		but i would say service uh atmosphere and whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> is good on on going out i like <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">steaks</ENAMEX>  so we try to hit those places when we can
 	
 	
 		when we travel we look for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wendy's</ENAMEX> because we have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and i like getting the salads or the lighter <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meals</ENAMEX> and then that way they can get their <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">burgers</ENAMEX> and fries and we can have a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salad</ENAMEX> bar
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so sometimes we drive for <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a couple hundred miles</NUMEX> until we find a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wendy's</ENAMEX> because it's all either <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald's</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dairy Queens</ENAMEX>  but
 	
 	
 		
 
 		uh  yeah and in in in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> unless it's a large <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> i guess <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dairy Queen</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wal-Mart</ENAMEX> are their main  that's what you find right
 	
 	
 		right that's right
 		i know
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> likes um <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dairy Queens</ENAMEX> he likes their <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk</ENAMEX> shakes and their <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">chili cheese dogs</ENAMEX> i guess so he's a fan of of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dairy Queen</ENAMEX> and and we'll go even in town here at times just as a a change although
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i'm not that excited about it it we've eaten we eat out so much it's gotten so i don't like to really eat any place but yet i hate to cook <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> at home
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		so that might be why i look for inexpensive places just because we're eating out probably <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nights</TIMEX> a week maybe or we eat junk food at home
 	
 	
 		um
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> now that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so what are some of your your favorite inexpensive places
 	
 	
 		oh we'll go to them all we sort of take turns and and we uh i'm sort of favor the ones if i have a coupon we can go there and if not we can't
 		because it's cheaper so mine is monetarily i guess strongly monetarily
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		based uh we'll go get <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pizza</ENAMEX> and uh at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Little Caesar</ENAMEX>'s although the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> prefer <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Domino</ENAMEX>'s
 	
 	
 		oh we are Little Caesar <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> here that's where we always go
 	
 	
 		right
 		but it's just a lot cheaper than than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Domino</ENAMEX>'s so that's
 		we go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandy</ENAMEX>'s quite a bit i would say
 	
 	
 		yes we like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandy</ENAMEX>'s too
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald's</ENAMEX> uh we've sort of been off of that for a while and no particular reason and i i maybe we avoided <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wendy's</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last few years</TIMEX> because our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> worked there and she never wanted us show up there
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		so i don't uh we don't go
 		there that much
 	
 	

 		where do you go if you like to have a nice meal out or a big meal
 	
 	
 		a nice meal oh
 	
 	
 		where you go for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">steaks</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's usually when we're out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> and i'll order steak or steak and lobster combined
 	
 	
 		ah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so that it's really not in town
 	
 	
 		ah you ever been to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX>'s on Beltline
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		that's where we go to get <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">steaks</ENAMEX> they have a teriyaki steak there and when we have something to celebrate we head to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX>'s they don't take reservations and you wind up waiting about an hour
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> is good and they've got a nice patio area that you can wait and get something to drink unless you get there at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five o'clock</TIMEX> then you can go right through
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but they have real good signature salads there and nice <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">steaks</ENAMEX> so
 		that's our nice place to go we don't usually take the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> when we go there
 	
 	
 		don't well we don't go out that much i guess well i guess we do go out without <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> we're usually picking things up quickly though and just we just don't
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		dwell on food too much and uh with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> traveling he can get all he needs  for that during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX> going to those places so it it doesn't really matter to him he'd probably just like to stay home
 	
 	
 		right
 		that's right
 		yeah that's the way with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> he's gone during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX> and likes to eat at home on the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekends</TIMEX> and i've been eating at home <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all week</TIMEX> long with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and would like to go out somewhere
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		so we have a conflict of interests on the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekends</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		well i think our i i never have liked to cook <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> but i think it all began eating out when we had uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> in in different uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> it was mainly baseball <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> would coach
 	
 	
 		right
 		yes
 	
 	
 		so we were never home at the same time and i'm not one that's going to fix you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meal</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two o'clock in the afternoon</TIMEX> so they can eat it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all day</TIMEX> whenever they're there if they're not there in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">between five and six well</NUMEX> then i guess we don't eat <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> or you go you know you fend for yourself you go somewhere else
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 		yep
 	
 	
 		so that you know that really snowballed when we got down here when i started to sub make money i went oh well i'll just sub to
 		
 		
 	