
 
     		
 	
 		well the types of vacations that i usually take i usually come back more tired after my vacation then i do
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 	
 	
 		you know before i take it um i need to definitely take a vacation where all all i do is rest and i i guess to do that i'd probably have to take it at home
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		but um the vacation spots that i like to go to are places like the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bahamas</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> i enjoy the beach
 	
 	
 		okay  i am after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">our last summer</TIMEX>'s vacation i am antibeach  uh-huh we went to uh <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Cape</ENAMEX> Hatteras
 	
 	
 		antibeach
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well we we were out visiting <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> then we went down to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cape Hatteras</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few days</TIMEX> and uh uh the the waves were huge i've never quite seen waves like this one  and uh i was standing in water not more than
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		in just barely above my ankles and uh you know when the waves go in the waves go out they kind of all of a sudden you're in sand above your ankles and i was standing there talking to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> and this really big wave came and totally threw me and one
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">foot</ENAMEX> did not come out of the sand and it tore the ligaments in my knee so i'm never going to another beach again  i'm a more
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		you might be like i am i enjoy i enjoy going to the beach and to beach areas but i really don't like to get into <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> the water the ocean i prefer a swimming pool
 	
 	
 		well i I love to go and play around at least i always did but although actually my i like the mountains i uh i don't really like hot weather that's my biggest gripe about living here and i basically
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		don't wanna go to a hot place on vacation  um i my dream vacation is Alaska
 	
 	
 		right i can understand that
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> that would be nice
 	
 	
 		this is just someplace i've always wanted to go and someday i hope we can afford to just take a humdinger of a vacation up there
 	
 	
 		uh-huh i know i've taken several vacations to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> and i used to live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> oh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sometime ago</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of years</TIMEX> and i really enjoyed that
 	
 	
 		um-hum yeah i'd i'd like that uh i haven't been to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yellowstone</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long long time</TIMEX> and i would uh we've been talking about going there <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next summer</TIMEX>  uh i don't know we'll have to to
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah  i've never been up to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yellowstone</ENAMEX> area so
 	
 	
 		it's been a long time but you know it seems when your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> is is different places
 		a lot of trips involved going to visit
 	
 	
 		that's right that's right you got that
 	
 	
 		oh i'm we usually go up to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wisconsin</ENAMEX> at least once a year because this is where my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and i are both from and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> live up there feeling lost and alone because we moved down here and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we've got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of our our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> lives out on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Coast</ENAMEX> and so we have to you know go to those
 	
 	
 		well you have you have a lot of vacation areas you can go to then right
 	
 	
 		well i know but i'm tired of them i wanna go someplace different  up there uh my my idea i guess of the ideal vacation would be to begin with uh money be no object
 	
 	
 		that's right
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know so just absolutely you know <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> class fly where i want to rent a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> if i want to
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh you know just really the nicest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> and stuff like that and and not worry if somebody says well let's take this little side trip you know and not have to sit there and figure out um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know can we we fit that in there or now that uh that that's what i um
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes that's what i would like to do i have no interest for example in taking a cruise to me why anybody wanna ride around on a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few days</TIMEX> is  mind boggling
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		it would be sort of confining i feel like it would be confining
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know i would rather much rather get on a plane and get there and then enjoy myself
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah i just uh that that does absolutely nothing for me
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh i don't know i can say that i think my my favorite spots are still to go to go where there's <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">mountains</ENAMEX> and and lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> and and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">wildlife</ENAMEX> to view and and uh
 		i like that kind of stuff i could just sit there <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all day</TIMEX> and look at the scenery
 	
 	
 		yes i i agree i can i can do that too and um you know i think if i had if i had the money i would probably go to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 	
 	
 		because of you know i think that they have they have it all over there in just a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a few tiny two two miles</NUMEX> you know there's <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">mountains</ENAMEX> and there's beaches and  it's all right there so
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah uh i i guess i've never really thought about it that way
 		our uh  we have our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> who's almost thirteen but she's uh a very picky <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">eater</ENAMEX> and our our standard excuse for not going someplace like that is
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know gee <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holly</ENAMEX> would starve to death if we you know we took her to another <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		oh
 		right
 	
 	
 		but i i would like if you know it was anywhere in the world to go i guess even though it's hot i would like to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	