
 
     		
 	
 		do you have any <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pets</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats two dogs</ENAMEX> a snake and a bunny
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">holy Nellie</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's enough to keep anybody busy with <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pets</ENAMEX> how about you
 	
 	
 		i oh i guess we have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> miniature Dachshund
 	
 	
 		um i think i'm envious
 	
 	
 		oh i don't think i could cope with that many how do how do you uh avoid having your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> smell
 	
 	
 		well my <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX> are indoor outdoor <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX> and
 		i don't know i hadn't really thought about it  one thing is to keep everything clean i mean you have to keep cages like for the rabbit you have to keep it cleaned and you have to keep litter boxes scooped
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but most of my <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX> go outside so there's not that much there i only have one who stays inside
 	
 	
 		um  do you let your rabbit run around loose
 	
 	
 		oh no it's in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cage lot</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> do but i've never been able to quite handle that with a rabbit
 	
 	
 		okay i i knew somebody who said they were easy to uh litter box train but she had trouble with it chewing on wood
 	
 	
 		no i've never i've never even tried it to be honest with you
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		it's really my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>'s rabbit
 	
 	
 		oh how what kind of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> do you have
 	
 	
 		um i have i have one that's kind of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Golden Retriever</ENAMEX> mutt
 		that means a mix  and then my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> just got an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> Eskimo
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		uh do they get along
 	
 	
 		and oh yeah oh yeah all my <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> and even the rabbit and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX> everybody in my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> gets along except the snake he kind of keeps to himself
 	
 	
 		see we our dog hates every other <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animal</ENAMEX>  and our we have a couple <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> that are are grown and on their own and every once in a while they will come home for a visit with an animal
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and our our dog just about has a stroke
 	
 	
 		well he's probably older and he's used to being the only <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> and it's hard for him just like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> it's hard for them to give up their
 	
 	
 		well
 	
 	
 		their place as the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> and kind of share the attention but almost all of my <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> are used to not being the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and so they're kind of used to being part of a group
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well we we kind of joke that that our our <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about eight years old</TIMEX> and but one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> was between jobs for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of weeks</TIMEX> and was here with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Golden Retriever</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh when he left you know we swear the our <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX>'s muzzle turned white
 		and then uh our our other son
 		is in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy</ENAMEX> and was being relocated to go to school down at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">College Station</ENAMEX> so he was here for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple days</TIMEX> in between waiting for his household goods and stuff and with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">beagle puppy</ENAMEX>
 		and we swear after she left the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> got gray on the front <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">two feet</NUMEX> you know
 	
 	
 		maybe he's just getting old
 	
 	
 		i don't know but it seems a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a</NUMEX> a visit from uh one of his <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cousins uh</ENAMEX> tends to uh really really affect how he is
 	
 	
 		turns him gray  one of the things they mentioned was why do you think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have pets
 	
 	
 		well i think they're i think they're good company i have been trying for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> to convince my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> who lives alone
 		that she would like a a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> she loves it when she comes here and our dog sits on her lap you know and she'll just sit there and pet him and pet him and i'll say you need an <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animal</ENAMEX> he would
 	
 	
 		i think so too i really think that they are wonderful therapy they're they're just companionship i'm
 	
 	
 		and
 		yes um-hum
 	
 	
 		obviously i'm a i'm a real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">believer</ENAMEX> in them
 	
 	
 		well and i i think they're good for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> in that they can teach the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> responsibility
 		you know if if you if you have a a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> who wants an <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animal</ENAMEX> badly enough and agrees to take care of it i mean it's a responsibility cleaning up after it and
 	
 	
 		yes i think so too
 	
 	
 		um you feeding it making sure it has water and uh you know just just all that kind of stuff that's that's good also uh
 	
 	
 		feeding it
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		but we just have a we we in the past we've had <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Great Danes</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		ooh that's a big dog
 	
 	
 		which were probably the best <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pets</ENAMEX> we've ever had
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		yeah oh they were well the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> one we had was wonderful she just finally died of old age but she was just so the the greatest house pet and uh we were asked when she was probably about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years old</TIMEX> when our our youngest one was born
 		and she would totally ignore this baby i mean the dog could be laying there sleeping and somebody could carry this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> into the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> and the dog would just kind of
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sniff</ENAMEX> and walk walk out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>  and would have absolutely nothing to do with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> until uh she got old enough to sit in the high chair and throw <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> over
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		yet and then all of a sudden the dog decided she was okay but yeah but then  my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> decided it would might be nice to have a lap <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> for a change
 	
 	
 		um here's a source
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		now he just really likes having a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> that curls up in his lap when he watches TV and sits in his recliner and falls asleep
 	
 	
 		
 
 		sure
 		that's neat that's neat
 	
 	
 		uh what what
 		
 		
 	