
 
     		
 	
 		how would you go about organizing a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> reunion
 	
 	
 		well  i from i grew up in the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Deep South like</ENAMEX> south <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alabama</ENAMEX> so whenever i think of family reunions my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> like got together almost every week
 	
 	
 		oh gee
 	
 	
 		and there'd be like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> so <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> talk about you know big family reunions and i i think like i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> who just went to like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wyoming</ENAMEX> to some big ranch you know where like there were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four hundred</NUMEX> people
 	
 	
 		oh my
 	
 	
 		for for their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> reunion and i  so i mean how i would go about doing it is i would just call all my  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because i since i came from my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> has uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX>
 		so i can both of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> had big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>
 		and we always were we always got together just always
 		now it's different because i live here and i've you know when i go home i try to see the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> as much of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> as i can but it's real different and i grew up in a real not  i think not normal setting
 	
 	
 		yes
 		with all of you living so close together
 	
 	
 		right i mean <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> dinner was at my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX>'s and you know like i said there'd be <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX>  you know a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and everyone would just bring things and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> would cook and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cook</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cook</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		it
 	
 	
 		well i come from a very small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and we planned a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> reunion <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this spring</TIMEX> um where we are from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>'s from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX> and we met in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> of us went on a cruise and then went to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> together
 		so that's all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> so planning our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> reunion reunion was very easy
 	
 	
 		yeah i guess so and  sounds like it was fun
 	
 	
 		yeah it was we had a wonderful time
 		
 		
 	