
   
   
      
         
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 23</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Aug. 23</TIMEX>)
            

            The
cover editorial blames the world's economic problems on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX>. They waste too much time on minutiae and too many of them have
abandoned grand free-market principles for statism. An article notes a
promising new medical procedure: "downsizing" failing hearts and lungs by
trimming tissue. The smaller organs work better. Also, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> says
graphite rackets (power over technique) and charmless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> are ruining
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">tennis</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 8 & 15</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 22</TIMEX>)
            

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX> to end all <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX> s. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX>-page cover package
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">celebrates "Zionism</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX>." An immense essay by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Editor</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Peretz</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">traces Zionism</ENAMEX>'s triumphant history, beginning with the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1897</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Basel</ENAMEX> conference.
Among his several conclusions: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zionism</ENAMEX> succeeded because it favored pragmatism
and modernity over ideology and nostalgia. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Seventeen</NUMEX> other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> contribute
short essays. The main themes: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> is a model democracy; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX>
treatment of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arabs</ENAMEX> is incomparably better than <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> treatment of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israelis</ENAMEX> or
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> treatment of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arabs</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zionism</ENAMEX> signifies "the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> preference for power
over self-pity." (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Ludicrous</ENAMEX> note: a back-page <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vodka</ENAMEX> promotion, one of many
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Zionist</ENAMEX>-themed ads, proclaiming "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Absolut L'Chaim</ENAMEX>.")

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times Magazine</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 24</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 21</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
story tracks the promising early performance of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wisconsin</ENAMEX>'s welfare reforms.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s new mandatory work policies, while more expensive than welfare
checks, have pushed more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> into the job market and fewer into poverty than
had been expected. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> doubt that the new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> will keep their jobs in a
recession. An article profiles best-selling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guru Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Weil</ENAMEX>, who's trying
to persuade the mainstream medical establishment to accept alternative health
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">care</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Doctors</ENAMEX> are dubious. An article notes the resurgence in the Western
Hemisphere of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX>-bearing <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mosquitoes</ENAMEX>. Their near-disappearance in the '60s
reduced disease immunity, and entomologists now warn that new epidemics of
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">malaria</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">dengue fever</ENAMEX>, and encephalitis are likely. Alarming statistic:
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mosquitoes</ENAMEX> will kill, by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">W.H.O.</ENAMEX> tally, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">roughly 1</NUMEX> in every <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> currently
alive on this planet."

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harper</ENAMEX>'s , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 1997</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 21</TIMEX>)
            

            A
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-story cover package damns and praises higher education. An essay by a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Virginia</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> says that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> seek only
ironic entertainment in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">classroom</ENAMEX>. Raised on the cool medium of television,
undergrads are skeptical about passionate ideas, doubtful of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX>, and
intellectually timid. Even worse news: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bottom-line</ENAMEX>-obsessed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX> won't
challenge this complacency because they can't afford to offend their paying
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>. The other piece glorifies an experimental humanities <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> for
low-income, undereducated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> contends that philosophy, art, and
literature are empowering, because they teach the disenfranchised how to
challenge the elite without violence. Evidence: The once-hopeless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> have
gone on to college or better jobs.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 25</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 19</TIMEX>)
            

            A cover
story explains a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">movement</ENAMEX> within the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catholic Church</ENAMEX> to elevate the status of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX> to "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Co-Redeemer</ENAMEX>." She's "not just another pretty face"--and she could make
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holy Trinity</ENAMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holy Quartet</ENAMEX>. A report highlights the potential effects of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UPS</ENAMEX> strike on the economy. An article exposes <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>'s worsening traffic
congestion. And a story speculates that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Reserve</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Greenspan</ENAMEX>
may finally be subscribing to the view that the economy has whupped
inflation.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 25</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 19</TIMEX>)
            

            The
sensationalistic cover--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Death of Privacy"</ENAMEX>--belies a more nuanced treatment of
privacy in the information age. The solution isn't to keep them from knowing
everything about you, but to allow you to know everything about them. An
exposé details phone scams that bilk the elderly out of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$40</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">billion</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>. And an upbeat story claims that, in the wake of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>'s welfare bill,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX> are mobilizing against poverty.

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 25 & Sept. 1</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 19</TIMEX>)
            

            A double
issue about love. The highlight: the life story of the brilliant, weird <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alfred</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kinsey</ENAMEX> (of report fame). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gay</ENAMEX>, masochistic, and happily married, Kinsey
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">presided</ENAMEX>, gurulike, over a utopian, sexually experimental <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>.
(Revolting detail: He masturbated by sticking pipe <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cleaners</ENAMEX> into his urethra
and tying rope around his scrotum. He filmed this.) A piece depicts royal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mistress Camilla Parker Bowles</ENAMEX> as a smart, funny <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">charmer</ENAMEX> who knows how to get
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prince Charles</ENAMEX> to relax. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>? A dim bulb.) An essay says the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
is too consumed by sex scandals: Sexual privacy would be preferable. Also, love
letters by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> famous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> (including <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dylan Thomas</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simone de Beauvoir</ENAMEX>)
prove that romantic clichés are universal. And an article says that prenuptial
agreements are more popular than ever.

            

               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 25 & Sept. 1</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 19</TIMEX>)
            

            Yet
another thumb-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sucker</ENAMEX> about the right-wing crisis, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the fourth this year</TIMEX>. "Is
There a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Worldwide Conservative Crack-Up?</ENAMEX>" includes contributions from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">28</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>, including <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Bauer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Brock</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Gelernter</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grover Norquist</ENAMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Q. Wilson</ENAMEX>. The consensus: No crack-up. Conservative ideas have
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">triumphed</ENAMEX>, and left-wing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> are being elected only because they have
stolen right-wing ideology. The other main theme: <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Conservatives</ENAMEX> must practice a
principled, moral politics, and not pander to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> does.
Dissenting views: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contributors</ENAMEX> propose a muscular, pro-government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Teddy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roosevelt</ENAMEX> conservatism. And the lone <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pollster</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanley Greenberg</ENAMEX>, says
that center-left <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> are winning because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> are
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">extremist kooks</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
