
   
   
      
         
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 4</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Oct. 4</TIMEX>)
            

            A
cover editorial says <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the millennium</TIMEX> bug is overhyped.
Fixing computers to recognize "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">00</ENAMEX>" as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>, not <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1900</TIMEX>, is a pain, but will cost
only <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$300 billion</NUMEX> worldwide. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cassandras</ENAMEX> had estimated a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3.6 trillion</NUMEX> bill. A
story argues that manned space travel has been largely useless because
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> have treated space as an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adventure</ENAMEX>, not a business. Space tourism
may be a future commercial market. Also, an essay claims that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Booker</ENAMEX>
Prize for fiction is out of touch with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Amis</ENAMEX>
go unrecognized; lesser lights make the short-list.

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 20</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, Oct. 3</TIMEX>)
            

            A cover
story rejects the notion that globalization will pacify <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>. Evidence from
history: <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> believed trade ties to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> would prevent a
conflict--then <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War I</ENAMEX> broke out. An article accuses the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Smithsonian</ENAMEX> of
sacrificing intellectual integrity to appease <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>: Curators tone down
controversial exhibits when they offend <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> or industry groups. An essay
calls <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX>' new fantasy house a symbol of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby boomers</ENAMEX>' obsession with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX>. The high-tech <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> creates "a technological cocoon that anticipates
your every need and protects you not only from danger, but from serendipity as
well."

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times Magazine</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 5</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, Oct. 2</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
story proclaims <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruth Bader Ginsburg</ENAMEX> a good choice for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> Chief
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Rehnquist</ENAMEX> retires. Unlike <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activist liberal judges</ENAMEX> such as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Brennan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ginsburg</ENAMEX> practices restraint and caution--good leadership
qualities for a divided <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>. An essay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> legal, over-the-counter
syringe sales at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pharmacies</ENAMEX>. Currently, needle-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchange</ENAMEX> clinics damage
neighborhoods by serving as magnets for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">addicts</ENAMEX>. Also, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">playwright</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric Bogosian</ENAMEX>
interviews comedian <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chris Rock</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bogosian</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rock</ENAMEX>'s race-laden humor "makes us
laugh not only because of perfect writing, skewed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX> and rock-steady
timing but also because of pain."

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 6</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Sept. 30</TIMEX>)
            

            It's
Promise <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Keepers week</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's cover story questions the intent of the movement's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Founder</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill McCartney</ENAMEX>, former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Colorado</ENAMEX> football <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX>, slips
pro-life and anti-gay messages into his rhetoric about responsibility and
forgiveness. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOW</ENAMEX> doesn't like the way <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Promise Keepers</ENAMEX> urges <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> to "reclaim"
their "role" as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>. ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Stodghill</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News & World Report</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marci McDonald</ENAMEX> debate <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Promise Keepers</ENAMEX>
here.) Speaking of masculinity, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> article notes the nail-polish-for-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> trend. Best name for
a male-marketed color: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Testosterone</ENAMEX>. Also in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> , a piece explores the massive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha Stewart</ENAMEX>, who
has just launched a new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">venture</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kmart</ENAMEX>. When compared to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Jefferson</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stewart</ENAMEX> replies, "I'm reaching more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. ... He had a job to do, and so do
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">I.</ENAMEX>"

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News & World Report</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 6</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Sept. 30</TIMEX>)
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX> ' inside
piece on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Promise Keepers</ENAMEX> says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wives</ENAMEX> generally welcome
their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husbands</ENAMEX>' newfound religiosity and devotion to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>. Only rarely do
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Promise Keeper</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> become domineering; mostly they become more attentive. (In
case you missed the link above, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News & World Report</ENAMEX> 's Marci
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Stodghill</ENAMEX> debate <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Promise Keepers</ENAMEX> here.)

            On the
cover, the magazine <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">seconds</TIMEX> the popular wisdom that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">El</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Niño</ENAMEX> will be the "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">century</TIMEX>'s biggest weather event." What will happen?
Californian hurricanes, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> drought, destruction of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pacific</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> and
seabird <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX>, floods in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South America</ENAMEX>, etc. (For more weather hype, see
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Assessment</ENAMEX>" of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El Niño.</ENAMEX>)

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 6</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Sept. 30</TIMEX>)
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's cover story on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dylan</ENAMEX> claims that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">songwriter</ENAMEX>'s new
album equals his best work. A story on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> hearings (which were filled with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX>' stories of "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Kafkaesque torments"</ENAMEX>) concludes that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> wields too
much power with too little accountability. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> article predicts
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marv Albert</ENAMEX> will not return to broadcasting: Adulterers like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Gifford</ENAMEX> are
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">forgiven</ENAMEX>, kinkmeisters like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albert</ENAMEX> are not.

            

               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 6</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Sept. 30</TIMEX>)
            

            The
Standard traces the history of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Promise Keepers</ENAMEX> in a long article.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> really does seek male spiritual renewal, not, as its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> claim,
political power or male supremacy. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> is commended for its ability to
tap spirituality without degenerating into self-centered <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>'s-movement
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">histrionics</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Founder</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill McCartney</ENAMEX> is much praised, too. The cover story, "Has
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred Thompson Blown It</ENAMEX>?," concludes that he probably has. The campaign-finance
hearings have been too muddled and bipartisan to be compelling. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thompson</ENAMEX>'s poor
performance has infuriated conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX>, especially <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Lott</ENAMEX>, and
may have crippled his presidential ambitions. An article <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">disses</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Turner</ENAMEX>'s
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1-billion</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> gift: It's not really worth <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 billion</NUMEX>, it won't go to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX>, and he's only doing it to win the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nobel Peace Prize</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 6</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Sept. 30</TIMEX>)
            

            A book
issue. A story says that publishing really is in crisis. Sales are flat,
profits are meager, advances are too generous, and returns are too frequent.
Astounding fact: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">35 percent</NUMEX> of books were returned to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">publishers</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cynthia Ozick</ENAMEX> deplores the corruption and sentimentalization of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anne Frank</ENAMEX>'s diary. Her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">collaborators</ENAMEX> carefully edited
the diary to make it an uplifting, universal story, omitting her references to
sex, religion, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> anti-Semitism. What was lost? The sense of evil. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX>'s autobiography contributes a funny, fond memoir about
preparing the book. Examples of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>'s forgetfulness and inattention are
frequent.

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nation</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 13</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Sept. 30</TIMEX>)
            

            A
column suggests that the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Freedom From Religious Persecution Act</ENAMEX>,
which would cut foreign aid and impose limited trade sanctions on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> that
persecute on the basis of religion, could force the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> to punish
some notable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">allies</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern Ireland</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> (where
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scientology</ENAMEX> is under the gun). (See <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cross-Purposes</ENAMEX>" for
another take on the act.) A story says <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Portland</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ore.</ENAMEX>, provides a new model for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">urban</ENAMEX> planning. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Urban Growth Boundary</ENAMEX> eliminates <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>-style
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sprawl</ENAMEX>. An editorial marvels that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Turner</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1-billion</NUMEX> gift to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX>
represents only his earnings since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX>. Extreme concentration of wealth is
making billionaires more powerful than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX>.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Review</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 13</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Sept. 30</TIMEX>)
            

            On the
cover: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NR</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founder</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William F. Buckley Jr.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lovingly</ENAMEX> illustrated,
gazing serenely into the distance. Inside: A long excerpt from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buckley</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nearer</ENAMEX>, My God: An Autobiography of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Faith</ENAMEX> . Sample passage (from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buckley</ENAMEX>'s description of his childhood): "We were superintended by ... three
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurses</ENAMEX>; fed and looked after by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cook</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">butler</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> maids;
trained and entertained in equestrian sport by a groom and an assistant, making
use of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Father</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> horses; instructed in piano by a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX>
who came and stayed with us <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three days of every week</TIMEX>, giving us each a lesson
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> pianos in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>. ..."

            

               --Compiled by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seth Stevenson</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> .
            

         
      
   
