
   
   
      
         
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 22</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Feb. 22</TIMEX>)
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deng</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Xiaoping</ENAMEX>'s death leads the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> . The cover story credits him with "wealth-creation on a scale unparalleled
in modern history," but concludes that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s prosperity depends on
establishing democratic freedom and the rule of law. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> also warns
that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s economic reforms might stall if it doesn't dismantle its
inefficient state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enterprises</ENAMEX>, something <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deng</ENAMEX> was unwilling to do. An article hints that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> is moving toward--believe it or
not--political and economic stability. Also, a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">26</NUMEX>-page survey of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>
determines that its economy is growing too slowly.

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times Magazine</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 23</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, Feb. 21</TIMEX>)
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>
Crazy" disparages the anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> conspiracy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">theorists</ENAMEX>--on the Internet, in
the fringe press, and on talk radio--who believe that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vince Foster</ENAMEX> was
murdered, that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cronies</ENAMEX> dealt <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>, and that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> ordered hit jobs.
An article describes the horrific child abduction-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">molestation</NUMEX>-murder case in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgium</ENAMEX>, and predicts that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> might fall on account of it. A
profile of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Necmettin Erbakan</ENAMEX> can't decide whether his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Islamism</ENAMEX> will radicalize <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX> (à la <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>) or clean up its corrupt <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>.
Also, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> issues its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">semiannual</TIMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Women's Fashions of the Times</ENAMEX>." As in
recent editions, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fashions"</ENAMEX> depicts no models, only "real" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>. Most of the
real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> seem to be professional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dancers</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 10</TIMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly Standard</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 24</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, Feb. 21</TIMEX>)
            

            Both pick <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deng</ENAMEX>'s
death for their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> cover packages (what timing!) and take a hard line toward
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Middle Kingdom</ENAMEX>, warning that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> must discipline <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> now or
face a "rogue <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">superpower</ENAMEX>" later. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX> , published <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>
after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deng</ENAMEX>'s death, denounces his legacy in an editorial: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">In Deng</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, the
politics of communism was joined to the economics of fascism." Echoing a recent
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nation</ENAMEX> story, a TNR piece describes how former <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>
(notably <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Kissinger</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander Haig</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brent Scowcroft</ENAMEX>) shill for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> doing business in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>. A long piece describes <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s suppression
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>, and another argues that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> is, contrary to popular belief, a
small and difficult market for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> goods.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> ,
published <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few days</TIMEX> before <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deng</ENAMEX>'s death, covers similar territory. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helms</ENAMEX> opposes granting <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> permanent <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">MFN</ENAMEX> status, calling it a reward for bad
behavior. Several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> condemn <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s policy of "constructive engagement"
as appeasement: They favor economic sanctions instead. An article says the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> must not sacrifice its democratic ideals "in order to sell a few
more <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Macs</ENAMEX>." And <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">legislator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Lee</ENAMEX> deplores <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s plan to
wipe out the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">colony</ENAMEX>'s democratic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>.

            Also in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jefferson</ENAMEX>-mania continues: A long book review
celebrates the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> as a "great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">democrat</ENAMEX>," albeit a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slave</ENAMEX>-owning
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 24</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Feb. 18</TIMEX>)
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Echoes of the Holocaust</ENAMEX>" on
the cover details how <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Swiss</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> have stonewalled attempts by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> to retrieve
ancestral money. A sidebar recounts <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Switzerland</ENAMEX>'s awful <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX> history:
It turned away <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> and served as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>'s money <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">launderer</ENAMEX>, but has
denied responsibility for its actions. An article pegged to the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> current
volcano movies says that the world's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">550</NUMEX> active volcanoes threaten <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500 million</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> (including everyone at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX>!). Also, an article on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">averted American Airlines</ENAMEX> strike: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> cautions that walkouts are
possible at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAir</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northwest</ENAMEX>, too.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's cover story, "<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Mammogram War</ENAMEX>," agrees with the National
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institutes of Health</ENAMEX> advisory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX>'s findings: Mammograms don't really protect
younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Breast guru Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Love</ENAMEX> contributes an
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX>, saying <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> must develop a breast-cancer blood test. Also,
more <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madeleine Albright</ENAMEX> hoopla, this time about her <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> ancestry: A
long article contends that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> secrets usually do more harm than good ("lies
beget other lies"). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albright</ENAMEX> is interviewed: She says she is proud of her
family history, but vehemently denies having known about it. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">For Slate</ENAMEX>'s take,
see "Did She
Know?") <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> speculates about whether <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fund-raiser</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Huang</ENAMEX> was a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spy</ENAMEX>. "A classic technique is to use <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nationals</ENAMEX>
who have made their fortunes abroad--and thus gained access to the ruling
establishments of capitalist <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>."

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News & World Report</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 24</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Feb. 18</TIMEX>)
            

            The
cover story warns of the growing power of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> drug <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gangs</ENAMEX>,
which now control <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">70 percent</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX> trade, and whose intimidating
tactics and bribes have all but paralyzed the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. A sidebar claims that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">gangs</ENAMEX> are buying off <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> border <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guards</ENAMEX>,
paying them <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">as much as $1 million</NUMEX> to ignore a single drug shipment. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
News profiles <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Lott</ENAMEX>: Like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Magazine</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> , it finds him ambitious and extremely willing to compromise.
Also, a photo essay on ultimate fighting, the popular, savage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spectator</ENAMEX>
sport.

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 24 and March 3</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Feb. 18</TIMEX>)
            

            The
special issue on "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Crime and Punishment</ENAMEX>" contains more of the former than the
latter. An article on the roots of violence argues that nearly all violent
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have brain damage--often caused by childhood abuse--that makes them
incapable of controlling their rage, and reprises liberal ideas about crime's
environmental causes. An article <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lionizes</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Maple</ENAMEX>, the eccentric <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cop</ENAMEX> who
devised <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>'s crime-tracking program. He is credited with much of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s crime drop. A story explores a new phenomenon of urban <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">juries</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Black</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women jurors</ENAMEX> are causing mistrials by refusing to convict black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> despite
overwhelming evidence of guilt. As for "punishment," a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">convict</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>
describes the deterioration of prison conditions.

            

               --Compiled by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Plotz</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> .
            

         
      
   
