
   
   
      
         
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 9</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Aug. 9</TIMEX>)
            

            The
cover editorial takes a dim view of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s giddy stock
market. In order to justify <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s stratospheric share prices, profits and
productivity must grow at improbably high rates for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">an impossibly long time</TIMEX>.
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">For Slate</ENAMEX>'s similarly pessimistic take, see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX>'s "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stock Market</ENAMEX>
Chicken-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Counting Orgy</ENAMEX>.") A related article notes that the skyrocketing stock market is
a worldwide phenomenon: Equity markets are booming in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX>, too,
thanks to low interest rates. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> celebrates the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th</ENAMEX> birthday of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">aspirin</ENAMEX>, the world's first synthetic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> and
still one of the best. Latest bit of good news: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aspirin</ENAMEX> now seems to prevent
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">bowel cancer</ENAMEX>, in addition to relieving pain, quelling inflammation, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">preventing strokes</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">heart attacks</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 25</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 8</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
story deplores the overdiagnosis of learning disabilities: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LD</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> say
that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">as many as 50 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> are learning-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">disabled</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> say that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> claim impairment to extract special treatment from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> (extra
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tutoring</ENAMEX>, extra time on tests, etc.). The disabilities include such dubious
afflictions as "dysgraphia"--that is, bad handwriting. A piece argues that
black <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> espouse paranoid myths (that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> sells crack in the inner
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>, for example) because it's easier for them to believe that white <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>
is trying to destroy them than to believe that white <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> doesn't care about
them. The "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">TRB"</ENAMEX> column suggests that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Weld</ENAMEX> could revive the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican</ENAMEX>
Party and position himself as a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contender</ENAMEX> by fighting Jesse
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helms</ENAMEX> over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weld</ENAMEX>'s nomination as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ambassador</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">For Slate</ENAMEX>'s less
flattering view of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weld</ENAMEX>, see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franklin Foer</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Assessment</ENAMEX>."
Also check out the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Frame Game</ENAMEX>" on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weld</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helms</ENAMEX>.)

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity Fair</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 1997</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 8</TIMEX>)
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VF</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">traces Andrew Cunanan</ENAMEX>'s bloody trail from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minneapolis</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>
to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miami</ENAMEX>. He favored hard-core <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">S&M</ENAMEX>, belonged to a fraternity of rich,
mostly closeted gay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Gamma Mu</ENAMEX>, dealt <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> to support his lavish
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">lifestyle</ENAMEX>, and lied to everyone about everything. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harold Ickes</ENAMEX> profile says
the ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffer</ENAMEX> is cruel, bullying, and smart. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> may have tossed
him aside, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ickes</ENAMEX> is retaliating by cooperating with campaign-finance
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX>. Also, a pair of articles on celebrity marriage. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> piece mocks
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry King</ENAMEX> for marrying too often, depicting him as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">needy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lonely</ENAMEX>, and
desperate for attention. The other claims that the marriage of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudy Giuliani</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX>/TV <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donna Hanover</ENAMEX> is a façade: The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> has
been conducting an affair with his communications <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the past three</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hanover</ENAMEX> will separate from him after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this fall</TIMEX>'s election. The story
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">chastises New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> for ignoring the story, saying they fear alienating
the vindictive <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times Magazine</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 10</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 7</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
story reports on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert McNamara</ENAMEX>'s visit with his old <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">North Vietnamese</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counterparts</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McNamara</ENAMEX> accepts some blame for the war; the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Vietnamese</ENAMEX> don't. A
story recounts how a long-shunned medical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researcher</ENAMEX> is finally winning
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">acceptance</ENAMEX> for his unconventional theories on <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">heart disease</ENAMEX>, and suggests that
new ideas in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX> are often slighted when they don't stand to make money
for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>. A piece profiles <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX>'s real-estate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">barons</ENAMEX>. They're
being challenged by a new, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">faceless</ENAMEX> breed of property <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>, but they're
not worried.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 11</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 5</TIMEX>)
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> hypes as
"exclusive" a new bimbo eruption. A former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bernard</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nussbaum</ENAMEX> tells the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> that, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>, another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathleen E. Willey</ENAMEX>, told her that she had been groped and kissed by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> have subpoenaed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX> to establish <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
"pattern of behavior."

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> offers its
eighth medical cover story of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX>. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hidden Causes of Heart Attacks</ENAMEX>"
identifies a new villain, the amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid homocysteine</ENAMEX>, which damages "arterial
walls if it reaches high concentrations in the blood stream." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX>
advises a prevention regimen of multivitamins, especially vitamins <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">B-6</ENAMEX> and
B-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX>. ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> published a piece on homocysteine <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>.) Other risk
factors for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">heart disease</ENAMEX> include low birth weight and infections like
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">gingivitis</ENAMEX>.

            Forget about saving the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">whales</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> reports that the overfishing of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sharks</ENAMEX> for fins (an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">delicacy</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cartilage</ENAMEX> (mistakenly thought to prevent <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>) has brought
several species to low population levels.

            Both
magazines analyze the budget deal. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> notes that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">budget</ENAMEX> would have balanced itself quicker if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> had done nothing new.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News & World Report</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 11</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 5</TIMEX>)
            

            The
cover
story offers a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">News You Can Use</ENAMEX> analysis of the budget deal's tax cuts: You
benefit if you are middle class and have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>, or are rich and own stock. A
report details how a new coal-mining technique, which decapitates
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mountains</ENAMEX>, has scarred <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Virginia</ENAMEX>'s scenery, destroyed property, and created
floods. An earnest analysis of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in the military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> use
the techniques that helped integrate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> into the services.

            

               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 11</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 5</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
story <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lauds</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Helms</ENAMEX> as (next to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>) "the most important <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservative</ENAMEX> of
the last <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25 years</TIMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helms</ENAMEX> is "misunderstood," "an able and resourceful
executive," "the easiest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>," and "a kindly, courtly gentleman
who loves <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>." "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helms</ENAMEX>'s gutsiest decision has been to confront the homosexual
movement." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">For Slate</ENAMEX>'s take, see "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Old</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carolinians</ENAMEX>.") An editorial criticizes the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> for
threatening to withhold federal aid from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Texas</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of California</ENAMEX>, both of which have enacted race-blind admissions
policies. And an article opposes the use of statistical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sampling</ENAMEX> for the next
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">census</ENAMEX>, arguing that the samplers will favor <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 11</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 5</TIMEX>)
            

            A long
profile of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> refusenik-turned-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Natan Sharansky</ENAMEX>
examines the struggle of moving from sainthood to practical politics. An
editorial argues that the balanced-budget compromise is not a compromise, since
both sides granted each other all the spending and tax cuts they wanted, and
hence will not balance the budget. An article profiles <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Doerr</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Silicon</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Valley</ENAMEX> venture <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">capitalist</ENAMEX> in search of the next big technological
revolution.

         
      
   
