
   
   
      
         
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 12</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, July 12</TIMEX>)
            

            An
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX>-page survey concludes that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> is an appalling mess. The economy has
shrunk for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight consecutive years</TIMEX>, and the vast majority of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX> are
struggling. The good news (sort of): <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX> are too demoralized to start a
violent revolution. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> anoints a populist economic reformer
named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Nemstov</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s great political hope. The cover editorial and story say the rise of multi-party democracy in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> will
stabilize the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> politically but may slow free-market reforms. A piece
applauds the phaseout of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s agricultural price supports, while warning
that newly liberated <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX> seem to be taking too many risks: If
<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">crops</ENAMEX> fail, there could be a wave of farm failures.

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 28</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, July 11</TIMEX>)
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Cohen</ENAMEX> may be thoughtful and bright, argues the cover story,
but he's timid about using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">America</ENAMEX>'s military might (in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX>, especially) and
unwilling to make hard decisions about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> budget cuts. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNR</ENAMEX> 's late
hit on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Reich</ENAMEX>'s self-serving memoir points out how powerless cabinet
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretaries</ENAMEX> are. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">For Slate</ENAMEX>'s take, see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Rauch</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Reich</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quote Doctor</ENAMEX>.") An article asks why <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASA</ENAMEX> sends <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">astronauts</ENAMEX> to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">rickety Russian</ENAMEX> space <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Mir</ENAMEX>: It's incredibly dangerous, generates no
worthwhile scientific data, and costs <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100 million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>.

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times Magazine</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 13</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, July 11</TIMEX>)
            

            A
TV-insider cover story recounts the tribulations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC Entertainment President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Tarses</ENAMEX>, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> to head a network entertainment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">division</ENAMEX>. Tarses,
who revitalized <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX> with shows like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Friends</ENAMEX> , was supposed to do the same
for struggling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>. She hasn't, and is on the verge of losing her job. Her
failure is blamed on immaturity. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> profiles hot young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX>
Smolin: His "evolutionary" theory posits that black holes give birth to
alternate universes, and that our universe itself was created in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">black hole</ENAMEX>
of another universe. If true, the theory could unify relativity and quantum
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mechanics</ENAMEX>. Also, a photo essay about aging prison <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inmates</ENAMEX>.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity Fair</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 1997</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, July 10</TIMEX>)
            

            A long
story on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Kennedy</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> rehashes their familiar troubles (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">divorce</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX>'s babysitter affair, etc.). It concludes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ethel Kennedy</ENAMEX>
indulged her brood, and that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kennedy</ENAMEX> probably did not sleep with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">babysitter</ENAMEX> until she was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX>, a legal age. A piece predicts that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bancroft</ENAMEX>
family, which controls <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dow Jones</ENAMEX>, may oust <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Kann</ENAMEX> because of the
miserable performance of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s stock. The article depicts <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kann</ENAMEX> as an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ineffectual pushover</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karen House</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>-turned-Dow Jones
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">exec.</ENAMEX>, as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monster</ENAMEX> who terrorizes her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> underlings. A
story says that legal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">publisher</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Brill</ENAMEX> will launch a glossy, hard-hitting
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">media</ENAMEX>-criticism <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Content</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mel Gibson</ENAMEX> is on the cover: The
puff inside implies, unpersuasively, that he has a deep, dark soul.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 14</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, July 8</TIMEX>)
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Nearly</NUMEX> identical issues.
Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mars</ENAMEX> cover stories dwell on the can-do practicality of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASA</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineers</ENAMEX>:
Pathfinder was built and launched for a fraction of the cost and in a fraction
of the time required for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mars</ENAMEX> missions. The stories applaud the
upcoming flurry of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mars</ENAMEX> expeditions (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> launches in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight years</TIMEX>), with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> concluding that they will undoubtedly determine whether <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mars</ENAMEX>
ever hosted life. Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> preview the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> fund-raising hearings that
start <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>, predicting much partisan bickering and few revelations. In
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> , a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fund-raiser</ENAMEX> proposes a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX>-step campaign-finance
reform. Most notable step: immediate electronic reporting of all contributions.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> compete to publish the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gushiest</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Stewart</ENAMEX> obituary
( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> headline: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Wonderful Fella</ENAMEX>"; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> headline: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The All</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Hero</ENAMEX>").

            Also in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , a funny story about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spice Girls</ENAMEX> imitators. The all-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> band
has spawned <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spicy Girls</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Nice 'n' Spicey</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spiced Girls</ENAMEX>, among other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">copycats</ENAMEX>. And an article says that <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">boxing</ENAMEX>'s reputation is so bad that not even
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Tyson</ENAMEX> debacle could make it much worse.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News & World Report</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 14</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, July 8</TIMEX>)
            

            The
cover story exalts <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laura Schlessinger</ENAMEX>, the radio
therapist/world-class noodge, for her moral absolutism. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laura</ENAMEX>'s immense
popularity (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">listeners</ENAMEX>) indicates a sea change in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s public
morality: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The me-</ENAMEX>first era is over," and self-sacrifice and personal
responsibility are in (at least for other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laura</ENAMEX> herself comes off
as a somewhat cruel, mostly good-hearted, totally overbearing nag. A long
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> investigates "attachment disorder," a psychological malady that
affects neglected east <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> toddlers adopted by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>. Outwardly
normal, the afflicted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are anti-social monsters: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> adoptive mother
has been charged with murdering her uncontrollable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>. A piece tinged with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schadenfreude</ENAMEX> says that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Starbucks</ENAMEX> may be
growing too fast. It's opening a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every other day</TIMEX>, but has been accused of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">predatory</ENAMEX> practices and mistreatment of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pickers</ENAMEX>, and may have
oversaturated markets such as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 14</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, July 8</TIMEX>)
            

            A long
story explores the sad, paranoid world of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Tyson</ENAMEX> and recounts the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holyfield</ENAMEX>
fight in all its ludicrousness. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tyson</ENAMEX> is depicted as selfish, anxious, and
thoroughly confused by the world around him. Highlights: the description of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tyson</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entourage</ENAMEX> (ex-cons and sleazeballs) and a visit with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Muhammad Ali</ENAMEX>, who
declares that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tyson</ENAMEX> "don't have it." An essay argues that immigration is not
the great economic boon its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> claim, because virtually all economic
benefits go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> themselves, not to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">native</ENAMEX>-born <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Immigration</ENAMEX> also threatens to divide <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX>: one
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">multicultural</ENAMEX> and young, the other white, older, and resentful. A writer
catalogs the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> phyla of screen <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX>, which include "the small, gray,
hairless, chinless, big-eyed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">waif</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">à la Close Encounters and</ENAMEX> "the
comic-relief plush toy" such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Alf</ENAMEX>. Also, a moderately scatological piece
celebrates the idea of disgust.

            

               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 14</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, July 8</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
story credits the economic boom to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Greenspan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">capitalists</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Milken</ENAMEX> (his junk bonds enabled undercapitalized but bold <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> to take
over and streamline stodgy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>). Deregulation, globalization, and
productivity increases make it likely that the good times will last, but world
events may not cooperate. An article mocks "cosmic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">capitalists</ENAMEX>," the geeky
techno-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entrepreneurs</ENAMEX> who wear shorts, repeat the word "vision" like a mantra,
and prognosticate madly about the world's information-rich <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Edenic</ENAMEX> future. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">editorial</ENAMEX> deplores the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>'s anti-assisted-suicide decision for being
insufficiently anti-assisted suicide.

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nation</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 21</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, July 8</TIMEX>)
            

            
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nation</ENAMEX> 's
liberalism clashes with its libertarianism: The cover package wonders if the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First Amendment</ENAMEX> needs to be revised to limit commercial speech (campaign
contributions, cigarette ads, etc.). <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Ten</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> opine, and there's no
consensus. The civil <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">libertarians</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Floyd Abrams</ENAMEX>) warn of a slippery slope: If
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Philip Morris</ENAMEX>' commercial speech is constrained, limitations on the New York
Times ' commercial speech are likely to follow. Others argue that
noncommercial speech must be given special protection by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. Also,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore Vidal</ENAMEX> condemns the anti-sex <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">moralism</ENAMEX> of the Wall Street
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> , concluding that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> has degenerated into a theocracy.

         
      
   
