
   
   
      
         
            

            

               
                  New 
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 31</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 14</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
story smacks supply-side economics <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guru</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jude Wanniski</ENAMEX> for his grandiosity,
tax-cut monomania, and all-around loopiness. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wanniski</ENAMEX>'s flirtations with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Louis</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farrakhan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lyndon LaRouche</ENAMEX> have made him a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pariah</ENAMEX> among the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">conservatives</ENAMEX>
who used to worship him. An article rejects the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CW</ENAMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> will
strike down the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Communications Decency Act</ENAMEX>. The reason: New filtering software
makes it possible to restrict access to Internet porn without excessively
limiting free speech. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNR</ENAMEX> joins the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chorus</ENAMEX> in favor of needle <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchange</ENAMEX>,
saying that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s opposition to it has doomed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">addicts</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX> infection. Also, a review demolishes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathryn Harrison</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">memoir</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Kiss</ENAMEX> , which recounts her affair with her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>: It's "trash
with a capital 'T.' ... Just because she wrote it does not mean she had to
publish it."

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> , 
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 15</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 14</TIMEX>)
            

            A
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Euro</ENAMEX>-issue. The cover editorial touts <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin-Clinton</ENAMEX> summit
as a historic opportunity: If <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> can agree to a limited
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">partnership</ENAMEX>, it will secure the long-term peace of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>. Also, plenty of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EU</ENAMEX>
news: A long article counts the benefits of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>'s common market, while
another piece describes how eager <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Poland</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hungary</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Czech</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> are to join it. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> declares that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Health Service</ENAMEX> needs an overhaul: It's underfunded, and
its service is "third-rate."

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times Magazine</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 16</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 13</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
story asks why <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Pataki</ENAMEX> has been a more effective <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX> than most
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">New Yorkers</ENAMEX> expected. Its answer: He's bullied and prodded the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legislature</ENAMEX> to
cut taxes and spending. In the process, he's become more popular than his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mentor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al D'Amato</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> visits the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southern</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Baptists</ENAMEX> who are
trying to convert <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>: He is appalled by their aggressiveness. Also, an essay
on why modernist literature is so tedious (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry James</ENAMEX> is singled out: "Does
anyone like to read him?").

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 17</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 11</TIMEX>)
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's cover story tries to explain "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">How Colleges Are Gouging U.</ENAMEX>"
Tuition has risen twice as fast as inflation, says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> , mostly because
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> are willing to pay, but also because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX> hoard their
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">endowments</ENAMEX> and pay their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professors</ENAMEX> too much. An article hypes the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hale-Bopp</ENAMEX> comet, which will be visible
for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next month</TIMEX>, as "the best celestial show in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX>." Also, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>
claims that for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past year</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> has been seeking "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Jacques</ENAMEX>," a possible accomplice to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Timothy McVeigh</ENAMEX>
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma City</ENAMEX> bombing.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Black Like Who?</ENAMEX>" explores the "new generation gap" among
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">African-Americans</ENAMEX>. The pop psychology: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Middle-aged</ENAMEX> and elderly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX>, having
witnessed the gains of the civil-rights movement, believe in the system. But
young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> are marginalized and angry. Gangsta rap is blamed for feeding the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>' rage. In a sidebar interview, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Cosby</ENAMEX> lambastes trashy black TV shows
and movies. Also, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> tells the weird story of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Stuchiner</ENAMEX>, a
high-level <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Immigration & Naturalization Service</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> alleged to have sold
passports to illegal <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX>. And an article accuses the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy</ENAMEX> of
abusing its female combat <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX>: Their fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX> and commanding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX>
gave them the silent treatment instead of helping them.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News & World Report</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 17</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 11</TIMEX>)
            

            "The
Quality of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mercy</ENAMEX>" indicts <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> for not prescribing effective painkillers
to the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">34 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> who suffer from chronic pain. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Opioids</ENAMEX>" (such as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">morphine</ENAMEX> and codeine) are fantastic pain <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relievers</ENAMEX> and almost never addictive.
But <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> are afraid to prescribe high doses for fear of lawsuits and
licensing investigations. A sidebar profiles a pain <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> who lost his license for
prescribing lots of opioids. An article says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense Department</ENAMEX> could save <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$30 billion</NUMEX> a year
by hiring private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contractors</ENAMEX> to run <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PXs</ENAMEX>, process paychecks, operate day-care
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">centers</ENAMEX>, etc. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cyber Vice Squad</ENAMEX>" notes the growing popularity of
Internet "filtering" software, which allows <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> to block
access to naughty sites.

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 17</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 11</TIMEX>)
            

            A fashion
package. An article observes "coolhunters," the hipster <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultants</ENAMEX> who are
hired by clueless clothing and shoe <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> to find the next big thing.
An article wonders whether <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">couture</ENAMEX> will accept hot young <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designers</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander McQueen</ENAMEX>. Also, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> profiles
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">eccentric British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J.G. Ballard</ENAMEX>: His cult novel Crash , about sex
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> accidents, has just been filmed.

            

               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 17</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 11</TIMEX>)
            

            An
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mocks</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX>'s writings as "gibberish"--a froth of loony New Age
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">slogans</ENAMEX>, weird lists, and incomprehensible diagrams. The editorial, which is
pegged to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Fitzsimmons</ENAMEX> controversy, slams <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> for ignoring the
truth about partial-birth abortion: Even a cursory investigation would have
shown that the procedure is much more common than its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defenders</ENAMEX> claimed. (For
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s take, see "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abortion Apostate</ENAMEX>.") Professional ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communists</ENAMEX> are on the cover:
Book <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX> lavishly praise <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whittaker Chambers</ENAMEX> (subject of a new biography)
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Horowitz</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> of a new autobiography).

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nation</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 24</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 11</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
story, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Bad Air</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Day</ENAMEX>," investigates industry lobbying to prevent stricter clean-air
standards. It accuses industry of fudging data to minimize the dangers of air
pollution, blames <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> for kowtowing to corporate demands, and fingers
former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Boyden Gray</ENAMEX> as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">polluters</ENAMEX>' heavy on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol Hill</ENAMEX>. A long article describes the service <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX>' fight to organize in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX>: It has been more successful than the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX> had expected.

            

               --Compiled by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Plotz</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> .
            

         
      
   
