
   
   
      
         
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 21</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, June 21</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
editorial and article endorse--tentatively--assisted suicide. The
magazine fears that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> might eighty-six incompetent or impoverished
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>, but is optimistic that good laws and strict enforcement can prevent
such abuses. An article and editorial pegged to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G-7</ENAMEX> caution that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> economy isn't as healthy as <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> believe: Productivity does seem to
be increasing, but imminent inflation, a low savings rate, and an aging
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> may kill the boom. A piece on the fragmentation of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> feminism
mocks old-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> "difference <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">feminists</ENAMEX>" and cheers the sassy, libertarian "pod
feminists" who are now in vogue.

            

               
                  New 
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 7</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, June 20</TIMEX>)
            

            More on
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> evil. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX>'s persecution of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christians</ENAMEX> deserves to be an important
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> policy issue, says the cover story. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> kill and jail <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christians</ENAMEX>
and destroy <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shrines</ENAMEX>. The piece credits <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian conservatives</ENAMEX>
(especially <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Bauer</ENAMEX>) and neoconservatives for raising the issue. A book
review lionizes <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dissident</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wei Jingsheng</ENAMEX>, whose letters from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> were
just published. An article calls new <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tansu Ciller</ENAMEX>
"pathologically duplicitous," <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"craven</ENAMEX>," and phenomenally corrupt. Also, a story
explains why the much-touted emergency flood-relief bill is political
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">grandstanding</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> purposely underfunds the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Emergency Management</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agency</ENAMEX>. Then, when disasters happen, it gives extra cash and takes credit for
providing "emergency relief."

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times Magazine</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 22</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, June 19</TIMEX>)
            

            More on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX>. The ambivalent cover story wonders whether the military
can survive without a hypermacho, violent male culture. Conclusion: It probably
can, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> will take a long time to adjust. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> may be
slow to accept the idea of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> dying in combat, as well. (For the
evolutionary angle on a sexually integrated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX>, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Earthling</ENAMEX>.")
The piece also finds that most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women soldiers</ENAMEX> lack the blood-and-guts instincts
needed in combat. An article contends that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> can painlessly
resolve its entitlement crisis by admitting more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> and using a huge
tax credit to promote childbearing. Also, the magazine profiles first-term Rep.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carolyn McCarthy</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Long Island Railroad</ENAMEX>-massacre <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">widow</ENAMEX> elected to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>
as a gun-control <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocate</ENAMEX>. She's almost as saintly as her image, though she's
increasingly torn between her principles and political expediency.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 23</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, June 17</TIMEX>)
            

            The newsweeklies go tabloid.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's cover story celebrates the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">50 th</NUMEX> anniversary of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roswell</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.M.</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">UFO</ENAMEX>" crash--a k a "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Incident</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> describes the
crash landing in vivid detail (right down to an alien giving <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> aid to a
wounded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleague</ENAMEX>), then concedes that the downed <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">spacecraft</ENAMEX> was undoubtedly a
military <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">balloon</ENAMEX>. Requisite alarming data: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thirty-four</ENAMEX> percent of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Americans</ENAMEX>
believe <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX> have visited <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Roswell festivities</ENAMEX> may draw <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100,000</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's cover story chronicles--with more than a little
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schadenfreude</ENAMEX> --the decline of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> dynasty. Evidence: the
disintegration of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Kennedy</ENAMEX>'s marriage and the alleged affair between
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kennedy</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-ager</ENAMEX>. The "protective aura" that once insulated the
family has vanished. A sidebar notes the political dynasties taking shape in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cuomo</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jackson</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> has plenty
of celebrity-murder news. In an interview, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.J. Simpson</ENAMEX> gripes about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brown</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goldman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> and says he's trying hard to survive on <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25,000</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX>. A
story on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">JonBenet Ramsey</ENAMEX> case says her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> are not the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suspects</ENAMEX>.
Biggest revelation: Contrary to press reports, it's possible that someone
entered the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> from outside. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ramseys</ENAMEX> left their front door unlocked, and
melting <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">snow</ENAMEX> could have obscured footprints. (For a backgrounder, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Gist</ENAMEX>.") The
magazine interviews <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">billionaire buddies</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Ballmer</ENAMEX>.
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ballmer</ENAMEX>, a college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classmate</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX>', is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s business <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX>.) They
say that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Netscape</ENAMEX> and the network computer threaten <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s prosperity.

            

               Time profiles <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ward Connerly</ENAMEX>, the black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">businessman</ENAMEX> (and rising
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX>) who's leading the fight against affirmative action in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News & World Report</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 23</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, June 17</TIMEX>)
            

            A
cover story advises <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> to exploit the best job market in
history by milking their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> for higher pay, flex time, continuing
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">education</ENAMEX>, shorter <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX>, gym memberships, etc. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Computer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX>, not
surprisingly, have the most leverage.) An article explains why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s much-ballyhooed race initiative is
so insubstantial: The poll-driven <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> was too scared of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voter</ENAMEX> backlash to
risk endorsing affirmative action or criticizing police racism. Also, a
piece warns that the booming <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">egg</ENAMEX>-donation business is an ethical
minefield: Does the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">egg</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donor</ENAMEX> have any claim on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>? Should the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> be
told that it has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX>? Should human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eggs</ENAMEX> be bought and sold?

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 23 & 30</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, June 17</TIMEX>)
            

            The
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> fiction double issue exalts <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>. (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX> marks the
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">50 th</NUMEX> anniversary of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> independence.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salman Rushdie</ENAMEX> explains
why it's good that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indians</ENAMEX> write in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>. He also contributes a short story,
as does <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruth Prawer Jhabvala</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amitav Ghosh</ENAMEX> recounts the forgotten history of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Army</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> who deserted the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British Army</ENAMEX>
during <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX> to fight for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX>. An <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX>/author
describes the impossibility of practicing medicine in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>--too much squalor,
too few supplies, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25,000</NUMEX> cases of rabies <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Updike</ENAMEX> is the latest
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reviewer</ENAMEX> to write a rave for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arundhati Roy</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The God of Small</ENAMEX>
Things .

            

               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 23</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, June 17</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
story on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Teddy Roosevelt</ENAMEX> exhorts <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> to emulate his
"nationalist-individualist" ideology. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roosevelt</ENAMEX> believed in the power of
government to accomplish grand tasks (e.g., build the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Panama Canal</ENAMEX>), but he had
no patience for the nanny <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. Today, such a "limited but energetic"
government could rebuild public trust. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Criminologist John DiIulio</ENAMEX> claims that
inner-city "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">super-preachers</ENAMEX>" are the best hope for saving troubled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> from
crime: Churchgoing seems to prevent backsliding by recovering drug <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">addicts</ENAMEX> and
former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX>. Also, another editorial opposing <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">MFN</ENAMEX> status for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity Fair</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 1997</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, June 14</TIMEX>)
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fair</ENAMEX> indicates that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>'s campaign-fund-raising hearings could be
the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '90s</TIMEX> if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred Thompson</ENAMEX> can forge a bipartisan
consensus for a deep investigation. But so far, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> aren't
cooperating and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> have been ham-handed. (Full disclosure: the
piece is co-authored by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Weisberg</ENAMEX>.) Yet another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VF</ENAMEX> article
about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rupert Murdoch</ENAMEX>: It handicaps the race to succeed him.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Twenty-five-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lachlan</ENAMEX>, who ranks highest in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Corp.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire</ENAMEX>,
is the favorite. But older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elisabeth</ENAMEX> is tough and smart, and younger
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">son James</ENAMEX> is the boldest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thinker</ENAMEX>. The cover story gushes about gay divorcée
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>: She's freer, happier, and more devoted to charity than she was as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Princess</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wales</ENAMEX>. And she still wears great clothes.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wired</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 1997</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, June 12</TIMEX>)
            

            Highly
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Panglossian</ENAMEX>. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Long Boom</ENAMEX>" projects <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25 years</TIMEX> of global economic
prosperity. Thanks to free markets and (of course) high technology,
productivity will increase, environmental degradation will decrease, genetic
diseases will be eradicated, and a worldwide, multicultural civilization will
flourish. Possible <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">obstacles</ENAMEX>: a plague, an ecological crisis, a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> war.
The piece includes a "world history" chart for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years 1980-2020</TIMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Immigrants</ENAMEX>
drive revival of family" in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2014-16</TIMEX>. "<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">First</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designer kid</ENAMEX>" in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2020</TIMEX>.

         
      
   
