
   
   
      
         
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 12</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, April 12</TIMEX>)
            

            The
cover story and editorial conclude, albeit unenthusiastically, that morality and
human rights have a place in foreign policy. Outside pressure often civilizes
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">undemocratic</ENAMEX>, inhumane <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> (i.e., <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Africa</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX>). But
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> is uncertain whether <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Western</ENAMEX> pressure can persuade <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>
to mend its ways. A gloomy
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> details the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">obstacles</ENAMEX> that will face <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Zairian</ENAMEX> rebel <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laurent</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kabila</ENAMEX> after he deposes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mobutu</ENAMEX>: opposition to his <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tutsi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> by other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tribes</ENAMEX>, a roaming <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Rwandan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> marooned in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Zaire</ENAMEX>, and endemic corruption. A
piece on biological weapons cautions that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> still has them;
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) they are easy to hide; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) they are phenomenally dangerous.

            

               
                  New 
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 28</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, April 11</TIMEX>)
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> hesitate to dump <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX> because his potential successors
would be worse, argues the cover story, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Men Who Would Be Newt</ENAMEX>." Each of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heirs</ENAMEX> apparent is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dissected</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Armey</ENAMEX> is too dull, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom DeLay</ENAMEX> is too volatile, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Boehner</ENAMEX> is
too treacherous. All are too conservative. An article about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary-designate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexis Herman</ENAMEX> labels her the "least-qualified--and certainly most
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">scandal-plagued</ENAMEX>" of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominees</ENAMEX>. But she will cruise to
confirmation because <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> prefer an ineffective labor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> to a
fighter like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Reich</ENAMEX>. An article lambastes medical ethicists for being ill-trained. The most
damaging claim: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMOs</ENAMEX> hire <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ethicists</ENAMEX> who then justify the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMOs</ENAMEX>' decisions to
deny expensive treatment. Also, a piece claims that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX> is not really a
holy <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Islam</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX> claim it only to score political points off
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity Fair</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 1997</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, April 11</TIMEX>)
            

            This
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">month</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">billionaire</ENAMEX> profile is Sir <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Goldsmith</ENAMEX>, the corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">raider</ENAMEX> turned
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX>. Violently opposed to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Union</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goldsmith</ENAMEX> is spending <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$30</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX> to underwrite his anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EU Referendum Party</ENAMEX> in the upcoming <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
election. Much is made of his peculiar <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>: He keeps a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ex-wife</ENAMEX>, and
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mistress</ENAMEX>. An article on crime <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novelist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patricia Cornwell</ENAMEX> finds her obsessive,
vengeful, and paranoid, and confirms that she had a lesbian affair with an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> (who was nearly murdered by her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>). An appreciation of art critic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Hughes</ENAMEX> says he observes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">America</ENAMEX> better than anyone since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">de Tocqueville</ENAMEX>.
Also, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity Fair</ENAMEX> hypes its own: A long excerpt from a biography of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Claire Booth Luce</ENAMEX> focuses on her stint as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VF</ENAMEX> 's managing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>. (The
magazine was "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Condé Nast's</ENAMEX> prize gift to the haut monde .")

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times Magazine</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 13</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, April 10</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
story chronicles a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">46-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>'s heart transplant, from her diagnosis to
the "harvesting" of her new heart to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX> itself. (The highlight is a
photo of the old and new hearts sitting side by side in metal basins.) The
piece notes that the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10-year</TIMEX> survival rate for heart transplants is an
astonishing <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">60 percent</NUMEX>, orders of magnitude higher than it was in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '70s</TIMEX>. A
baseball <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> expounds his theory about what makes a great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cunning</ENAMEX>,
intensity, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ego</ENAMEX> are useful, and almost all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> perform best in their
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">few years</TIMEX> with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> profiles former anti-apartheid
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">activist Mamphela Ramphele</ENAMEX>, who now heads the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Cape</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Town</ENAMEX>: She has
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">won admirers</ENAMEX> (and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX>) by insisting that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX> not adjust its
standards to favor black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>. Also, the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">semiannual</TIMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Home Design</ENAMEX>"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">supplement</ENAMEX> insists that simplicity--incredibly expensive simplicity, that
is--is chic.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 14</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, April 8</TIMEX>)
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> scoops
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellen DeGeneres</ENAMEX>. Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> report that her sitcom
character comes out in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 30</TIMEX> episode of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellen</ENAMEX> , but only
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's cover package reveals that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeGeneres</ENAMEX> herself is lesbian.
("<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Now</ENAMEX> I feel comfortable with myself and I don't have to be fearful about
damaging my career if it gets out," she says.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> agree that: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) her
TV coming out is a milestone because it's the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time a show will have a
lead gay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">advertisers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> won't strongly object; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellen</ENAMEX> is still a mediocre show.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heaven</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Gate</ENAMEX> survivor
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Ford</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rio DiAngelo</ENAMEX> takes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's cover and reveals more weird
details about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cult</ENAMEX>. Among them: For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several months</TIMEX> members consumed nothing
but a concoction of lemonade, cayenne, and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">maple syrup</ENAMEX>; they communicated with
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cult leader</ENAMEX> only in writing; they were not allowed to have their own
thoughts. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX>, who still considers himself a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX>, refers frequently to his
own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> as his "<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicle</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> tracks down other former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cult members</ENAMEX>, who state that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> considered
suicide <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">as long ago as 1994</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> has put up a new Heaven's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gate</ENAMEX>
Web page containing messages from the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Away Team"</ENAMEX> (the suicides). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>
doesn't give the Web
address, though.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> warns that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Antarctica</ENAMEX> may be warming. If its marine <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice sheet</ENAMEX> floats free, worldwide ocean
levels could rise <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">20 feet</NUMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Backlash Against HMOs</ENAMEX>" describes how <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> are banding together to fight restrictive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMO</ENAMEX> rules.

            Also in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , a commemoration of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackie Robinson</ENAMEX> regrets that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> have
forgotten his non-sports legacy as a civil-rights <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> and role model. And a
peculiar bit of newsmagazine amity: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's art <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> profiles and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">praises Time</ENAMEX> 's art <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Hughes</ENAMEX>, who is narrating a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> series
on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> art.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News & World Report</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 14</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, April 8</TIMEX>)
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
News is famous for ranking <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s best <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This week</TIMEX>, it tells you
how to get into them. The cover
story chronicles the admissions process at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Pennsylvania</ENAMEX>,
then offers tips: High grades and low test scores are better than low grades
and high test scores; hard classes and extracurriculars impress admissions
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX>; being an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alum</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> does not guarantee admission. Also, an article illustrates the influence that political donations can
buy. Among the examples: TV <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">broadcasters</ENAMEX>, who donate lavishly to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, were
given <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$300 billion</NUMEX> worth of new licenses for nothing. Credit-card <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>,
also big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX>, blocked legislation that would lower late fees. A story claims that the illegal-immigrant-smuggling business is
booming: <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asians</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Central Americans</ENAMEX> pay <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">as much as $28,000</NUMEX> for passage to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 14</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, April 8</TIMEX>)
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guanxi</ENAMEX>" describes how a pair of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> fund-raisers parlayed political
connections into personal gain. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nora</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eugene Lum</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hawaiian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX>, raised
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">tons</NUMEX> of money from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asian-Americans</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic Party</ENAMEX>, befriended <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> bigwigs, used these political ties to buy an <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX> gas
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, and earned a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$9 million</NUMEX> profit on the deal without lifting a finger.
The conclusion: All this was sleazy but probably legal. A warm profile of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">playwright Wendy Wasserstein</ENAMEX>, whose new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX> play opens <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this month</TIMEX>, depicts
her as an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">establishment figure</ENAMEX> who still thinks of herself as an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">outsider</ENAMEX>.
Also, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> complains about how much time he must spend helping out at his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>' private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>.

            

               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 14</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, April 8</TIMEX>)
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crack</ENAMEX>-up
at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX>," the cover editorial, argues that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney General</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Reno</ENAMEX> is an
ineffectual pawn of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> and that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Immigration and Naturalization</ENAMEX>
Service and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> are rogue <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>. An article asserts that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> has
failed to prosecute <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who have been caught distributing child
pornography on the Internet. A long feature blames <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yasser Arafat</ENAMEX> for the
failure of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> peace process, contending that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> has got
nothing in return for granting <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> autonomy.

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nation</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 21</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, April 8</TIMEX>)
            

            The
cover story says that
gay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> must build a new culture that is not founded on sex: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gay</ENAMEX> community
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">centers</ENAMEX>, gay <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX>, and gay marriage would be its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">anchors</ENAMEX>. An article mourns the anniversary of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1996 Telecommunications Act</ENAMEX>.
The act has benefited media <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">conglomerates</ENAMEX> and reduced competition, and the
forthcoming implementation of digital TV will help the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">conglomerates</ENAMEX> even
more.

            

               --Compiled by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Plotz</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> .
            

         
      
   
