
   
   
      
         
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 31</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, May 31</TIMEX>)
            

            The
cover editorial and article confront the problem of "the disappearing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayer</ENAMEX>." Tax
revenues will fall worldwide because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> can move to avoid levies, and
because electronic commerce is virtually impossible to tax. The remedy: Raise
taxes on consumption and property, which are easy to track, while cutting
corporate and income taxes. An <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX>-page survey pegged to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EEC</ENAMEX>'s
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">40 th</NUMEX> anniversary claims that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Union</ENAMEX> is suffering from a
"mid-life crisis." <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Citizens</ENAMEX> have lost confidence in it. Instead of pressing
forward as planned with currency union, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> should take a respite
until popular trust returns. An alarming article warns that
antibiotic-resistant <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacteria</ENAMEX> have arrived. Unfortunately, drug <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> are
not developing new antibiotics to fight the drug-resistant bugs, so they may
spread unchecked.

            

               
                  New 
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 16</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 30</TIMEX>)
            

            The
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>-story cover package, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Africa Is Dying</ENAMEX>," is as gloomy as its headline. Among
the lowlights: An article contends that the much-touted new <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Uganda</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yoweri Museveni</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rwanda</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Kagame</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Congo</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Laurent Kabila</ENAMEX>) are as
tyrannical as their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">predecessors</ENAMEX>. A long review of a book about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nigeria</ENAMEX>'s
decline concludes that that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">west African</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>, like the rest of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">continent</ENAMEX>, has nothing to offer the modern world: Its labor is unnecessary, its
commodities are expensive, and its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is monstrous. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Louis Gates</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jr.</ENAMEX> describes returning to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Africa</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25 years</TIMEX> after his first visit: He is stunned
by the squalor. Also, a piece on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> decision warns that the
continuing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> investigations are undermining the integrity of the
executive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">branch</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times Magazine</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 1</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 30</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
story is a week in the life of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muscovites</ENAMEX>--a real-estate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mogul</ENAMEX>, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Playboy Playmate</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baker</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pianist</ENAMEX>, and a pensioner. The point: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX>
is the most exciting <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> in the world, "brasher than <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, faster than
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tokyo</ENAMEX>." Typical scenes: The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baker</ENAMEX> is visited by his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mob</ENAMEX> "protection"; the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mogul</ENAMEX>
spends <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2,000</NUMEX> for lunch; the pensioner scavenges bottles to make ends meet.
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trapped"</ENAMEX> finds the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitewater</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX> engaged in an
impossible task: Unable to indict the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">first lady</ENAMEX>, he'll find
it difficult to close the investigation. The case demonstrates the shortfalls
of the independent-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> statute. Also, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> complains that all computers
look the same, and that all are ugly: He proposes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> alternative designs,
including the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Trellis</ENAMEX>" and the "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Odeon</ENAMEX>."

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News & World Report</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 2</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 28</TIMEX>)
            

            Computer doomsaying from
both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's cover story, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Day the World Crashes</ENAMEX>,"
predicts disaster on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 1, 2000</TIMEX>, when computer clocks will fail to recognize
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year 2000</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Programmers</ENAMEX> are furiously debugging old software, so we're
likely to avoid catastrophic shutdowns of electrical grids, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX>, air-traffic
computers, medical equipment, and the like. Even so, the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Millennium Bug</ENAMEX>" may
cause <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5 percent</NUMEX> (!) of all <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> to go under and cost the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> economy
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$600 billion</NUMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX> , a long book
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">excerpt</ENAMEX> warns that Internet security is dangerously lax. It recounts the
misdeeds of "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phantomd</ENAMEX>," a teen-age "cracker" who infiltrated computers at
nuclear-weapons <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">labs</ENAMEX>, military <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bases</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dams</ENAMEX>, and major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX>
before he was caught. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX> berates computer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> for picking
obvious, easily cracked passwords and chastises system <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">administrators</ENAMEX> for
ignoring basic security precautions.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX> ' cover
story, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Road Rage</ENAMEX>," raises alarms about aggressive driving--incidents are
up <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">51 percent</NUMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>. The causes: worse traffic; pugnacious immigrant
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX>; and sport-utility <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicles</ENAMEX>, which make <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX> feel impervious.
( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's short article about aggressive driving is also titled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Road</ENAMEX>
Rage.")

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's article on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lt.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kelly Flinn</ENAMEX> does not excuse the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX>
pilot, but emphasizes that her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">superior officers</ENAMEX> treated her clumsily, and that
her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lover</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Zigo</ENAMEX> was "a cad." A piece commemorating the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th</ENAMEX>
anniversary of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Marshall Plan</ENAMEX> notes that while it was a noble idea, it also
had a political purpose: to prevent <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> domination of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 2</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 28</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
package depicts <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kelly Flinn</ENAMEX>'s case as an irreconcilable "conflict between <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
codes of conduct," military and romantic. Flinn was wrong to have committed
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">adultery</ENAMEX> and lied, but she deserves sympathy, says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flinn</ENAMEX> says she
still believes in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX>. A book excerpt chronicles the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX>'s
history of mistreating female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX>. Female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recruits</ENAMEX> have been routinely
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">raped</ENAMEX>, humiliated, and harassed, but they rarely complain, because the military
punishes few male <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offenders</ENAMEX>. An article contrasts dueling <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> leaders
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tung Chee-Hwa</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Lee</ENAMEX>. The conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tung</ENAMEX> agrees with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hong</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kong</ENAMEX> needs order; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX> believes it needs freedom. Both are stubborn. A piece on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> entertainment <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Tarses</ENAMEX> warns that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX>'s slumping ratings
may cost the glamorous Tarses her job.

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 2</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 28</TIMEX>)
            

            Two
pieces by dead <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>. "A Visit to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Camelot</ENAMEX>," by the late literary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trilling</ENAMEX>, describes a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1962</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> dinner for <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nobel Prize winners</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">James</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baldwin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Frost</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Dos Passos</ENAMEX>, and other <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">literary lions</ENAMEX> attended. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackie</ENAMEX> glittered. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trilling</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lionel</ENAMEX>, talked to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackie</ENAMEX> about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D.H.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lawrence</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vassar</ENAMEX>. The 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> also publishes a long-lost
short story by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nathanael West</ENAMEX>. Also, an article explores <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>'s immensely
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">complicated Salinas</ENAMEX> family scandals. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Raul Salinas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> of former <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carlos</ENAMEX>, has been accused of murder. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soothsayer</ENAMEX> who
"discovered" the skeleton of the murdered <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Raul</ENAMEX>'s estate actually planted
the bones. And the current <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ernesto Zedillo</ENAMEX>, may have
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">orchestrated Raul</ENAMEX>'s indictment in order to save his failing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. (The
whole story is much more <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Byzantine</ENAMEX> than this.)

            

               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 2</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 28</TIMEX>)
            

            An
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> scoffs at "stress": It's a bogus disease that white-collar <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> use
as an excuse to skip work. The "stress management" industry is a "racket." The
cover story, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Narcissus</ENAMEX>," criticizes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">academics</ENAMEX> for first-person
scholarship. Instead of pursuing traditional objectivity, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professors</ENAMEX> now
incorporate their own experiences into their work. It's yet another sign that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">academy</ENAMEX> has gone soft, grumps the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Danish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> who left her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">baby</ENAMEX> unattended in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> prompts an indictment of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Denmark</ENAMEX>. It is not the
child paradise the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> has portrayed it to be: Child pornography is rampant,
and adolescent suicide is epidemic.

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nation</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 9</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 28</TIMEX>)
            

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">left-wing</ENAMEX> magazine challenges its own. The cover story condemns left-wing opposition to biology. Many
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">social</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX>, notably <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">anthropologists</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foolishly</ENAMEX> claim that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX> are
shaped only by culture, not by genes. These "secular creationists" wrongly
ignore scientific evidence. An article warns that a <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> war may be
imminent. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> is increasingly belligerent, while <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> no longer trust
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mediator</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rev.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Jackson Jr.</ENAMEX> writes a column
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">imploring Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">champion</ENAMEX> civil rights and affirmative action.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Esquire</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 1997</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 23</TIMEX>)
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Historian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Johnson</ENAMEX> contends that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is the "most disreputable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> ever."
The profusion of scandals--from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitewater</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> files to
campaign finance--proves that he lacks any moral <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fiber</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> stakes out the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cornish</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.H.</ENAMEX>, home of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J.D. Salinger</ENAMEX> ("the last private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>") and
meditates on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer-hermit</ENAMEX>'s career. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salinger</ENAMEX> drives by, but doesn't speak.
A profile of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MCA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edgar Bronfman Jr.</ENAMEX> suggests that he's too nice for
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>. His purchase of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MCA</ENAMEX> was financially disastrous: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DuPont</ENAMEX> Corp.
shares that he sold to buy the entertainment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">conglomerate</ENAMEX> have since gained
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$9 billion</NUMEX> in value.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlantic</ENAMEX> 
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monthly</TIMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 1997</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 20</TIMEX>)
            

            
Traditional public-health measures such as widespread testing and notification
of the infected would slow the spread of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX>, argues the cover essay. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gay</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX> have resisted such measures as stigmatizing. An article debunks
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">environmentalists</ENAMEX>' belief that we consume too much: Raw <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">materials</ENAMEX>, energy, and
food are more plentiful than ever. But we should worry that our materialism is
making us lose our reverence for nature. A short piece says there is a "child
famine" in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Great Plains</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Dakota</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Dakota</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kansas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nebraska</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wyoming</ENAMEX> are not producing enough <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> to sustain their small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
