
   
   
      
         
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 20</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Sept. 20</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover editorial and a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">48</NUMEX>-page survey of the world economy
reject the conventional wisdom that the era of big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is over. The
share of government spending in the gross domestic product of industrial
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> has risen steadily throughout <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the century</TIMEX>, up to the current <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">46</NUMEX>
percent. Exceptions: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Singapore</ENAMEX>, which got rich with small
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bureaucracies</ENAMEX>. A story on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Weld</ENAMEX>'s blocked nomination blames not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Helms</ENAMEX>
("now in his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX> rumbustious term") but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> itself. Archaic rules let
one passionate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX> win out over reasoned argument. Also, an article says
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s new military cuts are in troop size, not spending. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, like most of
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Asia</ENAMEX>, seeks high-tech weaponry.

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 6</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, Sept. 19</TIMEX>)
            

            One
reason <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kelly</ENAMEX> was fired is that his "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">TRB</ENAMEX>"
columns were too tough on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>. But <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TRB</ENAMEX>, headlined "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Impeach</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>," is not as harsh as it seems. It argues that an independent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> lets
both sides hide behind legal technicalities. Impeachment hearings would never
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">oust Gore</ENAMEX>, but they would reveal the truth. The cover story on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Sweeney</ENAMEX>
advises the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFL-CIO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> to be more militant. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sweeney</ENAMEX> is too often
relevant, labor must take risks and build its membership (current growth rate:
less than <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2 percent</NUMEX> per year). Also, an article says <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">right-wingers</ENAMEX> are becoming
socially conscious, establishing conservative-minded mutual funds and
boycotting products. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Cheerios</ENAMEX> are out: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Mills</ENAMEX> gives to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Planned</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parenthood</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times Magazine</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 21</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, Sept. 18</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
story on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harold Ickes</ENAMEX> compares the former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX> to his FDR-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide father</ENAMEX>.
Each <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ickes</ENAMEX> kept absurdly copious notes, and was doggedly loyal to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX>.
Despite the fact that he was dismissed and abandoned by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, and despite
the fact that he turned his notes over to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thompson</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX>, the younger
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ickes</ENAMEX> maintains "unshakable" faith in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. An article on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oliver Stone</ENAMEX> says
he has eschewed political diatribe in his forthcoming film U-Turn and
his planned sequel to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mission</ENAMEX>: Impossible . Instead, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stone</ENAMEX> seeks
mainstream clout. Also, a story refutes the notion that learning-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">disabled kids</ENAMEX>
get too much attention. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Schools</ENAMEX> that are looking for places to save money are
tossing most LD-diagnosed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> into regular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classes</ENAMEX>, where they are not
assigned the rote drills they need if they are to learn how to read.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 22</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Sept. 16</TIMEX>)
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> devotes the cover package to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mother Teresa</ENAMEX>, asking when she
will be sainted. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Canonization</ENAMEX> can take <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than 100 years</TIMEX>.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pope</ENAMEX> may
waive several necessary steps, but Mother <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Teresa</ENAMEX> must still be credited with a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">posthumously</ENAMEX> performed miracle. (She'd better get cracking.) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's
cover story credits <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">America Online</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Case</ENAMEX> with
simplifying the Internet for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> and notes that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX>'s acquisition of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CompuServe</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subscribers</ENAMEX> tightens its domination of the online market. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Di</ENAMEX>
news continues as both mags chronicle the life and final <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">drunken hours</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Di</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">driver Henri Paul</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> has more details, even listing his brand of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">liquor</ENAMEX>,
Ricard pastis.) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> looks at how <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> deal with death: "A child
who has lost a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> feels helpless, even if he's a future <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">King of England</ENAMEX>;
abandoned, even in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palace</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> wailing at the gates." And
Time discounts the warnings of anti-nuke <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX> who claim
that the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">72 pounds</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">plutonium</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASA</ENAMEX>'s soon-to-be-launched <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Saturn explorer</ENAMEX>
poses a health hazard. The radioactive <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fuel</ENAMEX> is safely encased, and will not
pollute the atmosphere if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">spacecraft</ENAMEX> explodes. ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Nation</ENAMEX>
disagrees; see below.)

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News & World Report</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 22</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Sept. 16</TIMEX>)
            

            The
cover
story credits <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Julia Child with</ENAMEX> "invent[ing] modern life." How? The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrity chef</ENAMEX> launched the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">gourmet-food</ENAMEX> craze, made <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> cooking
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">respectable</ENAMEX>, empowered <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">housewives</ENAMEX>, and legitimized public television. And she's
a lot of fun, too. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> visits <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Little Rock</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central High School</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">40 years</TIMEX> after
integration and finds a new kind of segregation: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> take honors
classes, black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> take regular classes. The reason: White <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> press
their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> onto the honors track, black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> don't. An article heralds the rise of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">worm</ENAMEX> industry ("vermiculture"):
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Worms</ENAMEX> are a cheap, environmentally sound way of turning garbage into
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fertilizer</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 22</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Sept. 16</TIMEX>)
            

            Sex
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Pistols manager</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malcolm McLaren</ENAMEX> chronicles his wild '70s life, focusing on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sid</ENAMEX>
Vicious' <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1978</TIMEX> arrest for his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX>'s murder. Among many highlights:
McLaren fences sound equipment stolen by the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Sex Pistols</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Bowie</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">house; McLaren</ENAMEX> rejects <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Kunstler</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vicious</ENAMEX>' defense <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> because he
listens to "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dylan</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joan Baez</ENAMEX>--possibly even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joni Mitchell</ENAMEX>"; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McLaren</ENAMEX> tries
to sanitize <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vicious</ENAMEX>' image by finding him a "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">librarian</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX>. An article
on the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">insanity</ENAMEX> defense recounts the miserable story of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward Allen</ENAMEX>, the child
of a wealthy <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> who's now on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX>'s death row for murdering
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen</ENAMEX>, who defended himself, tried to prove he was insane, but the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> didn't buy it. A piece describes--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only half</NUMEX> in jest--"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Relics</ENAMEX>."
Among them: "the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pearl choker</ENAMEX>," "the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elvis</ENAMEX> dress," and "the cardigan with
running reindeer." Unlike other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">saints</ENAMEX>' emblems, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>'s relics can be bought
in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX>. Also, The 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> breaks with tradition by
publishing photographs of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contributors</ENAMEX>.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity Fair</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 1997</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Sept. 16</TIMEX>)
            

            An
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">JonBenet Ramsey</ENAMEX> case presents evidence that strongly suggests
her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> killed her. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">district attorney's office</ENAMEX> has botched the case
by cooperating with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX>, so it's unlikely that charges will
ever be filed. The "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">New Establishment 1997</ENAMEX>" ranks "the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> most powerful players
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Information Age</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rupert Murdoch</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Only two</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> are listed, at No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">47</NUMEX> and No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">48</NUMEX>.) On the cover: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicole Kidman</ENAMEX>. She's
cagey about her new movie, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanley Kubrick</ENAMEX>'s mysterious Eyes Wide
Shut .

            

               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 22</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Sept. 16</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
editorial and article <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rip</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>. The editorial calls him a sleazeball based
on the fund-raising evidence. The article says that while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> doesn't seem
rattled by the allegations, he should be. Even his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">allies</ENAMEX> are anxious. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> accuses the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Way</ENAMEX> of political correctness (a capital
crime!): The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">charity</ENAMEX> has shifted funding from dull-but-worthy projects like CPR
training to programs that are supposed to support "ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX>." Also,
an article <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">savages</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX> for not doing her duty. She wanted money, popularity,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pleasure</ENAMEX>, and leisure, but not the obligations that came with her title.

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nation</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 29</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Sept. 16</TIMEX>)
            

            An
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudy Giuliani</ENAMEX> is not as good as he seems. Crime may be down, but
public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> are as lousy as ever, and the unemployment rate is one of the
highest in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> editorials oppose <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASA</ENAMEX>'s plutonium-laden mission to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saturn</ENAMEX> (see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> , above). An explosion of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">spacecraft</ENAMEX> within the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Earth</ENAMEX>'s atmosphere would spread toxic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">particles</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">endangering millions</NUMEX>. An essay
by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mother Teresa</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">basher</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Hitchens</ENAMEX> likens the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nun</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Princess</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Di</ENAMEX>:
Both used the poor and sick as "accessories" in "the service and the pursuit of
the rich and powerful."

            

               --Compiled by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seth Stevenson</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> .
            

         
      
   
