
   
   
      
         
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 19</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, July 19</TIMEX>)
            

            An
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> makes the case that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX>'s secular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX> has gone too far in its
struggle against the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Islamist Welfare Party</ENAMEX>. It recommends that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX> replace
the rigid modernism of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ataturk</ENAMEX> with a synthesis of democracy and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> values.
The cover editorial argues that economically and politically stable <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southeast</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX> must take an active role to shore up troubled <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> such as
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambodia</ENAMEX>. And a piece probes the claims of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> historical revisionists, who
have drawn controversy by challenging the moral basis of their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s early
history.

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times Magazine</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 20</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, July 17</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
story tracks the progress of medical marijuana in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, made legal by a
state referendum passed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last November</TIMEX>. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Californians</ENAMEX> have softened their
views on pot because they now view it as a beneficial <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX>, not as a wicked
street <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX>. This sea change has infuriated the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, which battled the
referendum. A profile of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Collins</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maine</ENAMEX>, like a recent <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arizona</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX>, lavishes attention on a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> who bucks her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> to support campaign-finance reform. A piece about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Africa</ENAMEX>
reports that many of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> have integrated since the end of
apartheid, but that they still harbor white racism. And a serious look at
making <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">airplanes</ENAMEX> safer proposes, among other ideas, a scheme in which drill
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sergeants</ENAMEX> would bark out preflight safety instructions.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 21</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, July 15</TIMEX>)
            

            Blond bombshells on the
outside, fluff inside. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> puts folk-rocker <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jewel</ENAMEX> on its cover for a
story on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women musicians</ENAMEX>. The piece praises the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>-only <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lilith Fair</ENAMEX> festival
(dubbed "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Galapalooza</ENAMEX>") for its sensitive yet sexy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">coffeehouse</ENAMEX> music. The
sidebar on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jewel</ENAMEX> marvels at her unpretentiousness, the result of a rugged
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Alaskan</ENAMEX> childhood. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's story about the cigar vogue is decorated,
inexplicably, by a cover shot of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MTV/NBC/ Playboy</ENAMEX> icon <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jenny McCarthy</ENAMEX>.
The article denounces cigars as expensive, repulsive, and unhealthy. (Though
not as dangerous as cigarettes, they still raise the risk of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stroke</ENAMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">heart attack</ENAMEX>.)

            
               Time credits <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>'s
young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>--the "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAFTA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX>"--for the ruling party's defeat in last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>'s elections. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">under-30s</TIMEX> despise <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>'s corrupt, one-party <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>,
but they are not as skeptical about capitalism as the leftist <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> they
voted for. Also, a pair of articles on juvenile crime: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> criticizes the
recent trend to charge <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> and confine them with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adult prisoners</ENAMEX>,
saying that such <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Draconian</ENAMEX> treatment hardens rather than reforms young
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX>. The other piece describes a vicious murder in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Flint</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mich.</ENAMEX>, of a
white teen by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gang</ENAMEX> of black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, a crime that has inflamed that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s
racial tensions.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> rehashes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mars</ENAMEX> cover story with a long feature about
the ingenuity and spiritedness of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX>. Also, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Che</ENAMEX> chic: A story notes
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Che Guevara</ENAMEX> is cool again, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30 years</TIMEX> after his death.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News & World Report</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 21</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, July 15</TIMEX>)
            

            The
impassioned cover story warns that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s national <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX> are being
ruined by overcrowding, underfunding, invasion by exotic <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> and animal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">species</ENAMEX>, and commercial development. The solution? Lots more federal funding
for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Park Service</ENAMEX> and stricter regulations for development on park
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">perimeters</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yellowstone</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Great Smoky Mountains</ENAMEX> are singled out as
especially endangered <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX>. An article about the bankruptcy of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Montgomery Ward</ENAMEX> notes that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> times as much retail space per <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>
and perhaps twice as much as it needs. A long piece
alleges that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan Milosevic</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cronies</ENAMEX> have plundered
their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, pocketing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> from state-owned <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> and
foreign-currency reserves.

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 21</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, July 15</TIMEX>)
            

            An
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> chronicles the so-far-unsuccessful battle by a gay auto <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX> to force
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler</ENAMEX> to adopt anti-gay-discrimination policies. His double burden:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Management</ENAMEX> doesn't want to address the issue, and many of his fellow factory
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> are violently homophobic (literally). A <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Galápagos travelogue</ENAMEX>/essay says
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Darwin</ENAMEX>'s curiosity and enthusiasm enabled him to make sense of the
peculiar islands' ecology. It also credits him with "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">de-sanctif</ENAMEX>[ying]" nature
writing. Also, a book review makes the case that cosmetic surgery can be
art.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity Fair</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 1997</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, July 10</TIMEX>)
            

            A long
story on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Kennedy</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> rehashes their familiar troubles (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">divorce</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX>'s babysitter affair, etc.). It concludes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ethel Kennedy</ENAMEX>
indulged her brood, and that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kennedy</ENAMEX> probably did not sleep with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">babysitter</ENAMEX> until she was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX>, a legal age. A piece predicts that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bancroft</ENAMEX>
family, which controls <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dow Jones</ENAMEX>, may oust <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Kann</ENAMEX> because of the
miserable performance of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s stock. The article depicts <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kann</ENAMEX> as an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ineffectual pushover</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karen House</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>-turned-Dow Jones
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">exec.</ENAMEX>, as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monster</ENAMEX> who terrorizes her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> underlings. A
story says that legal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">publisher</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Brill</ENAMEX> will launch a glossy, hard-hitting
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">media</ENAMEX>-criticism <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Content</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mel Gibson</ENAMEX> is on the cover: The
puff inside implies, unpersuasively, that he has a deep, dark soul.

         
      
   
