
   
   
      
         
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Esquire</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 1997</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 23</TIMEX>)
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Historian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Johnson</ENAMEX> contends that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is the "most disreputable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> ever."
The profusion of scandals--from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitewater</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> files to
campaign finance--proves that he lacks any moral <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fiber</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> stakes out the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cornish</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.H.</ENAMEX>, home of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J.D. Salinger</ENAMEX> ("the last private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>") and
meditates on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer-hermit</ENAMEX>'s career. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salinger</ENAMEX> drives by, but doesn't speak.
A profile of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MCA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edgar Bronfman Jr.</ENAMEX> suggests that he's too nice for
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>. His purchase of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MCA</ENAMEX> was financially disastrous: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DuPont</ENAMEX> Corp.
shares that he sold to buy the entertainment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">conglomerate</ENAMEX> have since gained
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$9 billion</NUMEX> in value.

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 9</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 23</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
story, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peddling Poppy</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mocks</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX> revivalism. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> is now the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>-most-popular modern <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> (after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX>), thanks in part to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">relentless PR</ENAMEX> by him, his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, and former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX>. The article <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">derides</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s
much publicized parachute jump. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Eight</NUMEX> professional skydivers assisted him: "I'd
let a 6-year-old do that [jump]," says <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. A profile of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gingrich</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buddy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grover</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norquist Jr.</ENAMEX> accuses him of selling out his conservative principles: He now
lobbies for slimy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dictators</ENAMEX>.

            

               
                  New 
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">York</ENAMEX> 
                  Times 
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Magazine</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 25</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 22</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
story lauds <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ariz.</ENAMEX>, for his effort to "restore honor" to
politics. The war <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX>/campaign-finance <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reformer</ENAMEX> is an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">idealist</ENAMEX> who has not
been corrupted by power. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> should be absolved for his role in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keating</ENAMEX>
scandal, the article argues: He did nothing improper to help <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keating</ENAMEX>. An
essay bemoans the rise of ghostwritten celebrity books, which dominate
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">best-seller</ENAMEX> lists. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Publishers</ENAMEX> no longer even pretend that the writing
matters--the only imperative is that the books sell. An article follows a
Haitian-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cop</ENAMEX> as he trains <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Haitian</ENAMEX> police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX>. The bleak prognosis:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Haitians</ENAMEX> don't trust cops, and the new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> have done little so far to
remedy this.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 26</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 20</TIMEX>)
            

            Yet another health cover
from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> : "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Scary Spread of Asthma</ENAMEX>." The incidence of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">asthma</ENAMEX> is
up <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">61 percent</NUMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early '80s</TIMEX>. The culprit is indoor air, which is filled
with dust <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mites</ENAMEX>, cigarette smoke, cockroach remains, and pet <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dander</ENAMEX>.
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Surprisingly</ENAMEX>, outdoor air pollution is not to blame: It's better for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> to
play outside than inside.) The good news: New <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> and treatments make it easy
to live with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">asthma</ENAMEX>. A happy feature chronicles a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wisconsin</ENAMEX> welfare <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s
search for work: She finds and keeps a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10</NUMEX>-an-hour job at a chemical <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">warehouse</ENAMEX>.
A story on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mt. Everest</ENAMEX> warns that even more climbers will probably die there
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>.

            Summer frivolity in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> . The cover: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">What's Cool This Summer</ENAMEX>." The highlights:
wakeboarding, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vince Vaughn</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Mexico</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Roswell</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgia</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O'Keeffe</ENAMEX>), roller coasters. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garry Kasparov</ENAMEX> writes an article requesting a
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>-game, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX>-take-all rematch with <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Deep Blue</ENAMEX>. He agrees that the computer
played brilliantly, especially in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Game 2</ENAMEX>, but says that he was thrown off by
the "hostile atmosphere" created by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX>. A short item suggests that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Security Council</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sandy Berger</ENAMEX> could replace <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Erskine Bowles</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief of staff</ENAMEX>.

            Both
magazines belittle <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Timothy McVeigh</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Jones</ENAMEX>, saying that his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cross</ENAMEX>-examination of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecution witnesses</ENAMEX> has been confused and
ineffective.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News & World Report</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 26</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 20</TIMEX>)
            

            The
cover story celebrates the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> economy. It makes several familiar
arguments: High-tech industry is driving <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the boom</TIMEX>; organized labor's decline
and pressure from foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX> are keeping wages and inflation in check;
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">unskilled workers</ENAMEX> still face tough times. A related
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> says that the sustained growth has flummoxed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Greenspan et al.</ENAMEX> have discovered that their old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">models</ENAMEX> no longer apply, and
they don't know what numbers to trust. A piece concludes that immigration both benefits and harms
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>: Low-skilled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> drive down wages, but high-skilled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX>
increase productivity. Also, the boom in guilt
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">museums: Slavery</ENAMEX>, tenements, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> internment <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camps</ENAMEX>, and radiation
experiments are all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX> of new ones.

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 26</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 20</TIMEX>)
            

            V.S.
Naipaul visits <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX> and finds it still haunted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> war. The men
who survived the war are disillusioned, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Islamic revolution</ENAMEX> has lost
much of its fire. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Naipaul</ENAMEX> warns that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> may succumb to "nihilism."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore Vidal</ENAMEX> writes a long appreciation of his old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clare Booth Luce</ENAMEX>,
portraying her as a tough broad. The opening comment by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don DeLillo</ENAMEX> pays
tribute to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dissident</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wei Jingsheng</ENAMEX>. Also, an article <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slams</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Regnery</ENAMEX>, the
right-wing publishing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> that's made a fortune with anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> books: The
once-distinguished conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX> now passes off salacious rumor and cruel
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">innuendo</ENAMEX> as fact.

            

               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 26</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 20</TIMEX>)
            

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> 's cover article, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Be Afraid</ENAMEX>," contends that <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Deep Blue</ENAMEX> is the
first evidence of a silicon-based life form with free will. The computer
demonstrated a subtle complexity of thought that even its human programmers
could not comprehend. Why be afraid of the silicon brain? It lacks emotion and,
hence, compassion. (For more on the match, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s special edition of
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Week/The</ENAMEX>
Spin.") A piece on cloning argues that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> wouldn't use cloned
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> for nefarious purposes and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) in vitro fertilization already violates
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nature</ENAMEX>'s laws as much as cloning would. It does propose limiting cloning to
married <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couples</ENAMEX>. Also, a conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economist</ENAMEX> makes the case for inheritance
taxes.

            

               
                  National 
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Review</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 2</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 20</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
profile paints <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Minority Leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Gephardt</ENAMEX> as a political
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">opportunist</ENAMEX>. He began his career as a socially and economically conservative
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX>, but transformed himself into a pro-choice, protectionist, mommy-state
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">liberal</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Morris</ENAMEX> writes an article praising the budget deal. A piece by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick Santorum</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pa.</ENAMEX>, complains that religious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">charities</ENAMEX> are corrupted by
federal-government funds.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlantic</ENAMEX> 
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monthly</TIMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 1997</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 20</TIMEX>)
            

            
Traditional public-health measures such as widespread testing and notification
of the infected would slow the spread of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX>, argues the cover essay. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gay</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX> have resisted such measures as stigmatizing. An article debunks
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">environmentalists</ENAMEX>' belief that we consume too much: Raw <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">materials</ENAMEX>, energy, and
food are more plentiful than ever. But we should worry that our materialism is
making us lose our reverence for nature. A short piece says there is a "child
famine" in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Great Plains</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Dakota</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Dakota</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kansas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nebraska</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wyoming</ENAMEX> are not producing enough <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> to sustain their small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
