
   
   
      
         
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 19</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, April 19</TIMEX>)
            

            The
cover editorial welcomes the idea of a tobacco settlement because
it would protect <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and compensate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> without crippling a legitimate
business. Anti-smoking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> are much chastised for their zealotry. A
related article contends that a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$300 billion</NUMEX> settlement could
improve tobacco <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>' finances by cutting legal fees and
eliminating future liability. A piece
notes the growth of the private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">police</ENAMEX> industry: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Security</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guards</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rent-a-cops</ENAMEX> now outnumber police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3-to-1</NUMEX>. A review of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> books about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> suggests that its best days
may be ahead.

            

               
                  New 
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 5</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, April 18</TIMEX>)
            

            An
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> denounces the recent TV-spectrum giveaway. The federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> could
have raised <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$70 billion</NUMEX> from auctioning the frequencies, but the TV
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">broadcasters</ENAMEX> lobbied their way to a freebie. The massive cover book review
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">praises Justice Antonin Scalia</ENAMEX> for changing the course of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
jurisprudence from "common-law constitutionalism" to "originalism," then blasts
him for betraying his own principles: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scalia</ENAMEX> has abandoned neutrality and now
decides cases based on his own political views. Also, a piece discusses the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">aging of America</ENAMEX>'s prison <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>. Geriatric cons cost <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times as much
as young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">extra</NUMEX> medical expenses, mostly), and their recidivism rates
are incredibly low. Even so, prison <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> rarely parole the older
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inmates</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times Magazine</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 20</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, April 17</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
story argues that work has become like <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> has become like work.
Thanks largely to total quality <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> now feel appreciated and
relaxed at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>. They find home (that is, child care) exhausting. The
upshot: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Workers</ENAMEX> don't care much about parental leave and flex time. "Everybody
Else's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">College Education</ENAMEX>" challenges the prevailing notion that higher
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">education</ENAMEX> is expensive and elitist: In fact, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">80 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> attend
public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX>, and their tuition averages <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">less than $3,000</NUMEX> per year. Also, a
photo essay by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sebastiao Salgado</ENAMEX> depicts <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX>'s landless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peasants</ENAMEX>.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 21</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, April 15</TIMEX>)
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> publishes its
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> roster of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25</TIMEX> "most influential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>."
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> --what a coincidence!--lists "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Next</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Century</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's culture-heavy lineup includes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tiger Woods</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosie</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O'Donnell</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Babyface</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edmonds</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don Imus</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Reznor</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dilbert</ENAMEX> (of the
comic strip). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madeleine Albright</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Colin Powell</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Rubin</ENAMEX> also make it,
and the most inspired pick is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Enquirer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Coz</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's list, which is not the cover story, offers bite-sized
profiles of young and middle-aged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">comers</ENAMEX>, from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dancer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Savion Glover</ENAMEX> to former
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">honcho</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Gorelick</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Case</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> lists overlap: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woods</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Louis</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates Jr.</ENAMEX>, Web <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entrepreneur</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kim Polese</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">X</NUMEX>-Files <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">creator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Carter</ENAMEX>
rate a mention on both.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's cover
story on fat argues that being fit is more important than being thin. Fat
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who exercise regularly are healthier than thin <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who don't. Not all
fat is equal: A paunch is more dangerous than chubby hips and thighs. A
positive profile of presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX> says that he is a
likely contender for the presidency in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>, but only if he succeeds in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reforming Texas</ENAMEX>' taxes.

            Also in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> , "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Joy of Text</ENAMEX>" claims that more <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> are reading books,
thanks to book <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clubs</ENAMEX>, books on tape, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oprah Winfrey</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publishers</ENAMEX>' profits
are falling. And an article describes the peculiar <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Liberation Army</ENAMEX>,
which seeks to overthrow the fundamentalist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>. Based in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>,
the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30,000</NUMEX> member <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> includes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women soldiers</ENAMEX>; <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">70 percent</NUMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commander</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, too.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News & World Report</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 21</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, April 15</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
story, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Born Bad?</ENAMEX>," argues against genetic determinism. Genes are
important, but a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>'s environment largely determines how those genes are
expressed: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nature</ENAMEX> and nurture can't be separated. The article warns that belief
in genetic determinism could lead to a revived, dangerous eugenics movement.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX> notes the surging popularity of anti-government <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">militias</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Watchdogs</ENAMEX> identify <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">858</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">380</NUMEX> of
them armed) and estimate membership at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50,000</NUMEX>. Militia tactics include clogging
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> with liens, refusing to pay taxes, and "seceding" from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>. Also, a piece charts the decline of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Homestead High</ENAMEX>
School, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alma mater</ENAMEX> of computer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whizzes</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Jobs</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Wozniak</ENAMEX>: Thanks
largely to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>'s education cuts, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s once-magnificent public
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> are slipping.

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 21</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, April 15</TIMEX>)
            

            

               The 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> excerpts former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Reich</ENAMEX>'s
insider memoir, Locked in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX> recalls the minimum-wage
fight, bemoans the influence of Wall Street on the federal budget, and
fantasizes a conversation with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Greenspan</ENAMEX> that ends with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX>
calling him a "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Bolshevik</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dwarf</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wang Shuo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s most popular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novelist</ENAMEX>, is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">profiled</ENAMEX>: The satirist just relocated to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chinese</ENAMEX>
government banned his works. A funny essay on sex books finds them too
cheerful, too open-minded, and too popular.

            

               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 21</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, April 15</TIMEX>)
            

            The
editorial advises <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> not to renew <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">MFN</ENAMEX> status. Clintonian
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">conciliation</ENAMEX> does not impress the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX>, but economic punishment will. The
cover story tars <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">superlawyer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Ben-Veniste</ENAMEX> for alleged
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">misbehavior</ENAMEX> during the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitewater</ENAMEX> investigation. It claims that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early 1996</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben-Veniste</ENAMEX>, then <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitewater Committee</ENAMEX>, blocked
inquiries about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Webster Hubbell</ENAMEX>'s hiring by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lippo Group</ENAMEX>. The problem?
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben-Veniste</ENAMEX> now represents <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Truman Arnold</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">businessman</ENAMEX> who also hired <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hubbell</ENAMEX>.
Also, an essay criticizes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">libertarians</ENAMEX> for their unwillingness to censure bad
behavior such as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> use.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Esquire</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 1997</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, April 15</TIMEX>)
            

            The
anti-anti-divorce backlash continues. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Two weeks</TIMEX> after the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX> 's
pro-divorce cover story, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Esquire</ENAMEX> offers "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Divorce Is Good for You</ENAMEX>." The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> on the verge of divorce, describes how separation has rescued him
from a loveless, oppressive marriage and supplied him with freedom. Divorce is
"not the right thing, perhaps, but the necessary thing." His "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ex-Wife-to-Be</ENAMEX>"
contributes an opposing view: She writes that she's lonelier and more regretful
than she ever imagined she could be. Also, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> joins a blackjack ring that
wins <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">millions of dollars</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vegas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">casinos</ENAMEX>. He reveals some of their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">card</ENAMEX>-counting and team-betting tricks. And a lovey-dovey profile of
conservative media <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">diva</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arianna Huffington</ENAMEX>.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity Fair</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 1997</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, April 11</TIMEX>)
            

            This
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">month</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">billionaire</ENAMEX> profile is Sir <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Goldsmith</ENAMEX>, the corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">raider</ENAMEX> turned
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX>. Violently opposed to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Union</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goldsmith</ENAMEX> is spending <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$30</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX> to underwrite his anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EU Referendum Party</ENAMEX> in the upcoming <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
election. Much is made of his peculiar <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>: He keeps a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ex-wife</ENAMEX>, and
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mistress</ENAMEX>. An article on crime <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novelist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patricia Cornwell</ENAMEX> finds her obsessive,
vengeful, and paranoid, and confirms that she had a lesbian affair with an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> (who was nearly murdered by her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>). An appreciation of art critic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Hughes</ENAMEX> says he observes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">America</ENAMEX> better than anyone since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">de Tocqueville</ENAMEX>.
Also, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity Fair</ENAMEX> hypes its own: A long excerpt from a biography of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Claire Booth Luce</ENAMEX> focuses on her stint as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VF</ENAMEX> 's managing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>. (The
magazine was "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Condé Nast's</ENAMEX> prize gift to the haut monde .")

            

               --Compiled by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Plotz</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> .
            

         
      
   
