
   
   
      
         
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 26</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, April 26</TIMEX>)
            

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> election issue. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> endorses the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tories</ENAMEX>--tepidly--in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX>'s British election. The cover editorial, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labour</ENAMEX>
Doesn't Deserve It," says that while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>'s ideas are "no longer
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">disastrous</ENAMEX>," they're not as sensible as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX>' free-market
policies. An editorial and article say that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next month</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> election could determine the
future of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX>. The re-election of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacques Chirac</ENAMEX> would
probably guarantee <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>'s participation in currency <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Socialist</ENAMEX>
victory would put it in doubt. A story about the new Sino-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> "strategic
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">partnership</ENAMEX>" concludes that it's nothing to worry about. For the moment, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> are united by their unease about the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> will
quickly learn that it has more to fear from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> expansionism than from
Western capitalism.

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 12</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, April 25</TIMEX>)
            

            A long
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> doubts whether online <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> can attract the loyal "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX>" of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> used to have. It compares the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Webzine Salon</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">legendary San Francisco</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herb Caen</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX> can't replicate the
"emphatically local" sense of place that made <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caen</ENAMEX> so popular. The cover book
review pans <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman Mailer</ENAMEX>'s autobiography of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Gospel According to</ENAMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Son</ENAMEX> ) as an unimaginative imitation of the real <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gospels</ENAMEX>. Also, a piece
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about</TIMEX> Mauritanian slavery, a truly peculiar <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slaves</ENAMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">northwest</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> are frequently richer than their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masters</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times Magazine</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 27</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, April 24</TIMEX>)
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Learning</ENAMEX>
Poverty Firsthand" profiles welfare <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholar</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathryn Edin</ENAMEX>, who claims that
all welfare <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> cheat, but only because they have to. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Welfare</ENAMEX> and
food-stamp benefits are not nearly enough to pay for essentials, so welfare
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">moms</ENAMEX> need outside income to survive. The other striking fact: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Women</ENAMEX> who work at
menial jobs are poorer than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> on welfare. The cover story reprints an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchange</ENAMEX> of letters between a desperate <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German Jew</ENAMEX> and an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX> who
tried to save him from the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX>. A sportswriter plays a pickup basketball
game with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oscar Robertson</ENAMEX>, who has lost a step but not his competitive spirit.
Also, a column about "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Slaves 'R' Us</ENAMEX>," a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recruits</ENAMEX> submissive men
to clean the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartments</ENAMEX> of dominant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>. (It's even weirder than it
sounds.)

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News & World Report</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 28</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, April 22</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover stories are pegged
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Colin Powell</ENAMEX>'s volunteer summit. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> says the "future of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> may be riding" on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Powell</ENAMEX>'s campaign to save at-risk <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>, but doubts
whether the general can persuade <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> to make long-term commitments to
philanthropy. In a short column, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX> exhorts all <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> to help
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">needier</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX> argues that most of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">93 million</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteers</ENAMEX> aren't doing much good. (For example: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Singing</ENAMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> choir
counts as "volunteering"; so does making <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cookies</ENAMEX> for a school bake sale.) Only
a tiny fraction of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteers</ENAMEX> assist needy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">seniors</ENAMEX>, and most
community-service <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> are badly mismanaged. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sidebar</ENAMEX> proposes transforming <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AmeriCorps</ENAMEX> into a vast national
scholarship program like the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">GI Bill</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> excerpts a
forthcoming biography of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tiger Woods</ENAMEX>. The passage recounts <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woods</ENAMEX>' <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> trip to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Masters</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>: He played <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX> holes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each day</TIMEX>, then spent <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the evening</TIMEX>
studying for his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stanford</ENAMEX> history exam.

            In
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX> , a puff
piece congratulates <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GM</ENAMEX> on its makeover: The troubled <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">maker</ENAMEX> is
introducing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX> new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">models</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>, hoping to stop its market-share slide. A
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kentucky Derby</ENAMEX> article explains why <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">racehorses</ENAMEX> aren't getting
faster: Unlike <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horses</ENAMEX> are such superb <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">athletes</ENAMEX> that training doesn't
help them.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 28</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, April 22</TIMEX>)
            

            "What's Wrong at the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">FBI?</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rehashes</ENAMEX> familiar complaints
about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>: The crime <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lab</ENAMEX> is a mess; <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louis Freeh</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bully</ENAMEX>; and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bureau</ENAMEX> flubbed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aldrich Ames</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruby Ridge</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Jewell</ENAMEX> cases.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Several weeks</TIMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> presents the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s case
against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Timothy McVeigh</ENAMEX>. The circumstantial evidence and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fortier</ENAMEX>'s testimony are devastating, but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> bungling might sabotage the
prosecution. A profile of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British Labor Party</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blair</ENAMEX> asserts that his politics are <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintonian</ENAMEX>, but
his forthright, honest manner is not. Also, echoing a recent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX>
cover story, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> says that strong opiates such as morphine are a godsend for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in chronic pain.

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 28 and May 5</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, April 22</TIMEX>)
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>! The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> celebrates with an exhausting double issue about
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Europe</ENAMEX>. An article says <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> cooking has stagnated because <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chefs</ENAMEX> avoid
the multiethnic fusion cuisine that dominates <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">San</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francisco</ENAMEX>. A story probes the psychology of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Switzerland</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Swiss</ENAMEX> are finally
facing the truth about their <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX> misdeeds, and their icy
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">self-righteousness</ENAMEX> is slowly melting. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Louis Gates Jr.</ENAMEX> argues that black
pop culture (especially Jungle music) now dominates <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> pop culture.
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> have finally found an <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>, rather than <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">West Indian</ENAMEX>,
identity. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> who used to live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Germany</ENAMEX> reads his secret police
file and confronts a "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>" who informed on him: She says she had to do it.
And several articles doubt whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Union</ENAMEX> will ever unify
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Europe</ENAMEX>.

            

               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> 
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 28</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, April 22</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
story condemns the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s commercial foreign policy, accusing
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> of valuing profit above ideology or strategy. The result: We
now happily do business with monstrous regimes in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Burma</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sudan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>. The editorial says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Colin Powell</ENAMEX>'s volunteer summit is an "incoherent"
event that will only reinforce the (wrong) idea that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> should
interfere with every aspect of private life. An article makes fun of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellen</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DeGeneres</ENAMEX>' TV/real-life coming out: It is a "cynical marketing ploy."

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nation</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 5</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, April 22</TIMEX>)
            

            A
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>-pack of campaign-finance stories. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> articles make the case for public financing of
elections--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> could either raise private money or accept public funds.
Ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Hamburg</ENAMEX> describes his campaign fund-raising experiences, revealing
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">congressmen</ENAMEX> solicit contributions from their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> all the time and
frequently do favors for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contributors</ENAMEX> (surely not!). A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> goes undercover as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">PAC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyist</ENAMEX>, and finds that
congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffers</ENAMEX> are incredibly considerate.

            

               
                  National 
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Review</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 5</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, April 22</TIMEX>)
            

            The
anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">anti-China</ENAMEX> backlash begins. Countering <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX> of editorializing by the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX> , "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">How Not to Handle China</ENAMEX>"
counsels moderation toward <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX>. "If you insist on treating another country
as an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemy</ENAMEX>, it is likely to become one." <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> has no worldwide ambitions, is
not a regional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bully</ENAMEX>, trails the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX> militarily, and isn't
so terrible on human rights. A related article advises the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> to maintain its military
strength, improve <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">East Asian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alliances</ENAMEX>, and build a missile defense for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX>.
An editorial suggests that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney General</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Reno</ENAMEX> be impeached for not
appointing an independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> to investigate campaign fund raising.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlantic</ENAMEX> 
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monthly</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harper</ENAMEX>'s , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 1997</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, April 22</TIMEX>)
            

            Here's a coincidence: In the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlantic</ENAMEX> , a black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> tells <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> to abandon race consciousness. In
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harper</ENAMEX>'s , a white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> tells <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> to abandon race consciousness. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlantic</ENAMEX> cover story argues that racial pride is irrational because it
values genes rather than actions. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harper</ENAMEX>'s ' "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Toward an End of Blackness</ENAMEX>"
says that black <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>' struggle for freedom and equality is the great
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX> story. Race consciousness casts black <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">outsiders</ENAMEX> whereas
they are quintessential <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>.

            Also in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Atlantic</ENAMEX> :
An article condemns the devolution of power to state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX>, arguing that
it won't save money or improve services. And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cynthia Ozick</ENAMEX> contributes a short
story.

            Also in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harper</ENAMEX>'s : A
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX> of technoscholars discusses the metaphysical significance of the showdown
between world chess <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">champion</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Kasparov</ENAMEX> and a supercomputer.

            

               --Compiled by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Plotz</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> .
            

         
      
   
