
   
   
      
         
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 16</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Aug. 16</TIMEX>)
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>'s
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">50 th</NUMEX> birthday is celebrated, ambivalently, as the cover package praises the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s democracy and condemns
its history of socialism. Recent economic liberalization has started to improve
living standards, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> urge the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> to privatize and
deregulate faster. A piece commends <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madeleine Albright</ENAMEX> for her "splendid
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bluntness</ENAMEX>" and her belief that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> must act as the world's moral
(and actual) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policeman</ENAMEX>. But even she may not be able to force peace on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX>. Also, an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> obsession: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> advises <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>
to legalize <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>, at least marijuana and ecstasy (MDMA). A related article
describes, lovingly, the many medical benefits of pot smoking.

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 1</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 15</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
story marvels at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lanny Davis</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> who does spin control for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> campaign-finance investigation. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX> for
scandal," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX> brilliantly defused the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thompson</ENAMEX> hearings by convincing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX>' testimony was old news. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heil Harvard</ENAMEX>" describes
how <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austria</ENAMEX>'s far-right <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>, the repellent <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jorg Haider</ENAMEX>, is polishing his
reputation by attending <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX> conferences and schmoozing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>. Haider, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> reminds us, praised the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SS</ENAMEX> and has proposed
expelling all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foreigners</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austria</ENAMEX>. A biography of efficiency
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">expert Frederick Winslow Taylor</ENAMEX> is reviewed. The conclusion: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Taylor</ENAMEX> was a
terrible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, and he should be blamed for the dehumanization of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
workplace.

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times</ENAMEX> Magazin e , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 17</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 15</TIMEX>)
            

            An
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> calls <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> primary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> the best in the world. Why? <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Kids</ENAMEX>
cooperate on everything, are encouraged to think creatively, and learn
responsibility from chores. (They clean the school <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> because there are
no janitors.) The bad news: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>'s high-pressure, exam-oriented secondary
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> undo the primary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>' good work. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> interviews <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boeing</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Philip Condit</ENAMEX>, who defends the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s safety record, its acquisition of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonnell Douglas</ENAMEX>, and its pro-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> policy. Most astonishing moment: Condit
likens the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodney King</ENAMEX> beating to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tiananmen Square</ENAMEX> massacre. The cover
story profiles celebrity <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chef</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Bouley</ENAMEX>, who's trying to launch a nationwide
gourmet-food <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire</ENAMEX>, complete with <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">overnight</TIMEX> delivery of flash-frozen,
vacuum-packed, four-star meals.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 18</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 12</TIMEX>)
            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple-Microsoft</ENAMEX> deal
takes both covers. The shared conclusion is that the agreement is a win-win:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple</ENAMEX> buys some needed time, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> locks up the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Macintosh</ENAMEX> applications
market and wards off antitrust <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's behind-the-scenes package follows <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Jobs</ENAMEX> through the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX> leading up to the fateful speech. Funniest moment: When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> asks <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jobs</ENAMEX>
what he should wear during the announcement, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jobs</ENAMEX> answers, a white shirt.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> publishes a short interview with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jobs</ENAMEX>, who says that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple</ENAMEX> will
concentrate on the education and "creative content" markets. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX>
also argues that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple</ENAMEX> will fail to hire a strong <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> because nobody wants to
work in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jobs</ENAMEX>' shadow.

            Both newsweeklies celebrate
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> congratulates <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> for its remarkable comeback,
applauding its falling crime rate, cleanliness, swinging nightlife, and
entrepreneurial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">City Boosters</ENAMEX>" pays tribute to big-city <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayors</ENAMEX> who've
privatized services, challenged employee <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX>, and supported school vouchers.
Singled out for praise: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Goldsmith</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Norquist</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milwaukee</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed Rendell</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael White</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cleveland</ENAMEX>.

            A pair of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> articles commemorates the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">20 th</NUMEX> anniversary of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elvis</ENAMEX>'
death. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> recalls the earliest <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> of his career, when he toured the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX> in
a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cadillac</ENAMEX>. The other remembers his twilight in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX>, where female fans
mobbed the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">auditorium</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">every night</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> predicts the biggest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">El Niño</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the century</TIMEX>. A warm <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pacific Ocean</ENAMEX>
will wreak havoc in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South America</ENAMEX>, cause drought in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX>, and bring a
nice, mild <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News & World Report</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 18 & 25</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 12</TIMEX>)
            

            A double
issue probes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX> unsolved mysteries of science. Among them: How old is the
universe? How do ice
ages occur? Why do we sleep? Why does anesthesia work? (Best guesses: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12 billion years</TIMEX>; absorption of
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">carbon dioxide</ENAMEX> by grasses lowers temperatures; to process memories; not the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">foggiest</ENAMEX> idea.) <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">A sidebar</NUMEX> examines a handful of less pressing scientific puzzles,
such as why <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs bark</ENAMEX>. An article chronicles a bizarre <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Egyptian</ENAMEX> espionage trial: An <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mechanic</ENAMEX> is charged with giving lingerie dipped in invisible ink to an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Egyptian</ENAMEX>. The trial has exposed <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Egyptian paranoia</ENAMEX> about <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> sex <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spies</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">inflamed</ENAMEX> already tense relations between the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 18</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 12</TIMEX>)
            

            A long
story describes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Cohen</ENAMEX>'s attempts to impose civilian
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">authority on Pentagon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> who don't trust him. Top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brass</ENAMEX> loathe the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
administration for trying to gut their "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">warrior</ENAMEX>" culture. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cohen</ENAMEX> has faced down
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generals</ENAMEX> who bucked his authority, but hasn't won (and will never win, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> predicts) the full confidence of high-ranking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX>. The magazine
prints the final entries in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William S. Burroughs</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journal</ENAMEX>. Best line: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">That</ENAMEX>
vile salamander <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX>, squeaker of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>, is slobbering about a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">drug-free America</ENAMEX> by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year 2001</TIMEX>. What a dreary prospect!" A piece chronicles
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Football League</ENAMEX>'s effort to regain the fans it has lost to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Basketball Association</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NFL</ENAMEX>'s bright idea: Hire an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MTV</ENAMEX> executive
to craft a snazzy marketing campaign.

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nation</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 25 & Sept. 1</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 12</TIMEX>)
            

            The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>
installment in its "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Entertainment State</ENAMEX>" series dissects the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
music industry. As in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> and publishing issues, the centerpiece of
the music edition is a chart of corporate conglomeration: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time-Warner</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sony</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EMI</ENAMEX>, etc.) dominate the music industry. Articles criticize
music <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> for ignoring black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX>, praise the embryonic feminism of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spice Girls</ENAMEX>, rejoice in the failure of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">U2</TIMEX>'s latest tour, and commend the
few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">musicians</ENAMEX> (notably <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ani DiFranco</ENAMEX>) who have rejected major-label control.

            

               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 18</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 12</TIMEX>)
            

            Summer
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">camps</ENAMEX> have gone soft, concludes the cover story. Back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the good old days</TIMEX>,
roughhousing, risk-taking, fighting, noogies, and wedgies were encouraged, and
helped make <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> courageous. Regrettably, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">'90s</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">campers</ENAMEX> are protected from all
risk. A piece mocks the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX>'s diversity training program for its squishy,
idiotic, white-male-bashing uselessness. The editorial cheers <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Helms</ENAMEX>'
attack on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Weld</ENAMEX>'s nomination, then urges <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Majority Leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lott</ENAMEX> to "squash [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weld</ENAMEX>] like a bug."

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Review</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 1</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 12</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
story claims that an obscure <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">businessman</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maurice Strong</ENAMEX> is the
ringleader of a "creeping <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> power grab." Strong currently serves as an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adviser</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary-general</ENAMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adviser</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Bank</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>,
and presided over the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">1992 Earth Summit</ENAMEX> as its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary-general</ENAMEX>. He's also
supervising <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> reforms and environmental regulations that will cripple <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
sovereignty, warns the article. Also, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rupert Murdoch</ENAMEX> writes an essay decrying
the triumph of "neosocialism." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Regulators</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bureaucrats</ENAMEX>, and a "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">New Class</ENAMEX>" of
mandarins are using their authority to erode individual liberty. Evidence
cited: "Why can't I get my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox TV</ENAMEX> news <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> onto more <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> cable systems
and compete?"

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity Fair</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 1997</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 8</TIMEX>)
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VF</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">traces Andrew Cunanan</ENAMEX>'s bloody trail from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minneapolis</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>
to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miami</ENAMEX>. He favored hard-core <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">S&M</ENAMEX>, belonged to a fraternity of rich,
mostly closeted gay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Gamma Mu</ENAMEX>, dealt <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> to support his lavish
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">lifestyle</ENAMEX>, and lied to everyone about everything. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harold Ickes</ENAMEX> profile says
the ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffer</ENAMEX> is cruel, bullying, and smart. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> may have tossed
him aside, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ickes</ENAMEX> is retaliating by cooperating with campaign-finance
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX>. Also, a pair of articles on celebrity marriage. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> piece mocks
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry King</ENAMEX> for marrying too often, depicting him as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">needy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lonely</ENAMEX>, and
desperate for attention. The other claims that the marriage of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudy Giuliani</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX>/TV <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donna Hanover</ENAMEX> is a façade: The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> has
been conducting an affair with his communications <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the past three</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hanover</ENAMEX> will separate from him after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this fall</TIMEX>'s election. The story
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">chastises New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> for ignoring the story, saying they fear alienating
the vindictive <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
