
   
   
      
         
            

            

               
                  New 
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mar.</ENAMEX> 3
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, Feb. 14</TIMEX>)
            

            The
cover story criticizes <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> prevention
program, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drug Abuse Resistance Education</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> behind <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DARE</ENAMEX>, TNR
says, suppress studies showing that it doesn't work and harass <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">academics</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> who criticize it. An editorial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slams</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s budget for papering over the
entitlement crisis with "rosy scenarios." An article asserts that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> are supporting the budget in
exchange for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s acquiescence to a capital-gains tax cut. The "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">TRB"</ENAMEX> column calls for the appointment of an independent counsel
to investigate the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> fund-raising scandal. And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Brustein</ENAMEX>
continues his brawl with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">August Wilson</ENAMEX> over race and theater.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 15</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, Feb. 14</TIMEX>)
            

            The
cover story and an editorial predict trouble for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helmut Kohl</ENAMEX>,
who's presiding over a weakening <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> economy. An article suggests that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> economy's troubles might
contributes an article about why <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> should expand into <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Eastern Europe</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Coats</ENAMEX>' idea of a tax credit for anti-poverty <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">charities</ENAMEX> wins the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>'s
praise. And a long article summarizes research on circadian
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rhythms</ENAMEX>. Most interesting fact: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">City</ENAMEX>-dwelling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">males</ENAMEX> lose the ability to adapt
to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seasons</TIMEX>. They don't sleep longer in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX> than they do in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX>, but they
should.

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times Magazine</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 16</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, Feb. 13</TIMEX>)
            

            The
smuggling of exotic and endangered <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX> takes the cover. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Madagascar</ENAMEX> and
elsewhere, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">snakes</ENAMEX>, primates, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">turtles</ENAMEX> are being destroyed by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">locals</ENAMEX>. The First World is blamed: A <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">turtle</ENAMEX> worth <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">30 cents</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Madagascar</ENAMEX> can
fetch <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10,000</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. Also, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garry Wills</ENAMEX> says
multiculturalism, not conservatism, is fueling the revival of classical
literature. "The ancient texts have become eerily modern in what they have to
say about power relationships between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, gay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and war, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">superiors</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subordinates</ENAMEX>." And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> visits <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vanessa Redgrave</ENAMEX>,
who is more self-righteous and obsessive than ever about her causes. She's keen
on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX>, not <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX>.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 17</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Feb. 11</TIMEX>)
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.J.</ENAMEX> cover goes inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brown/Goldman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX>, revealing
evidence that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">plaintiffs</ENAMEX> didn't use, including a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX> who saw <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.J.</ENAMEX>
demonstrate how to kill someone with a knife. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred Goldman</ENAMEX> says he doesn't care
about the money, only about the vindication. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's cover considers
"The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.J. Legacy</ENAMEX>," predicting that he will keep custody of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> but lose
his appeal of the civil decision. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> says that the
case did not divide <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX>; it merely revealed a breach that already
existed.

            Revisiting the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Luther</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King Jr.</ENAMEX> assassination, both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> doubt <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Earl Ray</ENAMEX>'s
latest reiteration of his "I was a patsy in a government conspiracy"
theory.

            Also in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> , a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madeleine Albright</ENAMEX> profile, which reaches the same
conclusions as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's cover story <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albright</ENAMEX> is media-savvy
and hardheaded, though not a grand visionary.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> sings the praises of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michelle Kwan</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s next great
figure-skating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">queen</ENAMEX>." And an article tries to explain why the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Euro</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>'s
unified currency) matters.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News & World Report</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 17</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Feb. 11</TIMEX>)
            

            The
cover story excerpts <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Confessions of a Spy</ENAMEX> , a new book
about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aldrich Ames</ENAMEX>, calling the convicted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spy</ENAMEX> the "most destructive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traitor</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> history." The piece claims that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ames</ENAMEX> exposed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> assets" to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KGB</ENAMEX>--more than twice as many as had been reported. He also crippled <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of
covert operations, including a wiretap on a private communication line in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KGB</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX>. Also, an article demystifies love (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">just</NUMEX> in time for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Valentine</TIMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Day</ENAMEX>), explaining that a chemical called oxytocin, triggered by breast-feeding,
makes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> love their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mates</ENAMEX>. (To learn more about familial love
genes, see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Wright</ENAMEX>'s recent article in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>.)

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 17</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Feb. 11</TIMEX>)
            

            A long
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitewater</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">specialist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Stewart</ENAMEX> examines <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan McDougal</ENAMEX>'s
refusal to cooperate with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>'s investigation. She says she won't
testify because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> is engaged in a political witch hunt; the piece
speculates that she may be trying to hide an affair she had with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>.
A story describes the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Indian</ENAMEX> island of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Montserrat</ENAMEX>, where a long-dormant
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">volcano</ENAMEX> is threatening to erupt. If it does, it will probably bury the island
(and the few <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousand</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inhabitants</ENAMEX> who remain) in lava and ash. Also, an article
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">praises House Budget Committee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Kasich</ENAMEX> as one of few <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>
brave enough to offend big business for the sake of a balanced budget.

            

               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 17</TIMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Review</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 24</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Feb. 11</TIMEX>)
            

            The conservative magazines
savage the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Bar Association</ENAMEX> as a tool of big-government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Nearly</NUMEX> identical articles condemn the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABA</ENAMEX>'s recent endorsement of a
death-penalty moratorium and denounce the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABA</ENAMEX>'s judicial rating system for its
left-wing bias. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> 's cover story, "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Truth</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Flynt</ENAMEX>,"
echoes similar pieces in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Nation</ENAMEX> by
arguing that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flynt</ENAMEX> is much scummier than his movie persona. The piece does
reveal a few sickening new details, notably a tape recording in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flynt</ENAMEX>
allegedly admits telling his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> to strip so he could look at
her naked. Also, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> article defends <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marine</ENAMEX> hazing rituals as
"macho bullshit" integral to military culture.

            Also in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Review</ENAMEX> , an article praising <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> privatization.
And a long adulatory essay about <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Austrian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Friedrich Hayek</ENAMEX>, Ludwig
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">von Mises</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carl Menger</ENAMEX>.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity Fair</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 1997</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, Feb. 7</TIMEX>)
            

            A profile
lionizes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tycoon</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Jewish Congress</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edgar Bronfman Sr.</ENAMEX> for his
campaign to recover <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>' savings from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Swiss</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bronfman</ENAMEX>, whom
some consider the "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pope</ENAMEX>," is portrayed as a relentless crusader who
single-handedly "unhinged" <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Switzerland</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity Fair</ENAMEX> investigates the
truly weird saga of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madalyn Murray O'Hair</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s most notorious atheist.
After <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30 years</TIMEX> as a troublemaker, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bully</ENAMEX>, and media hound, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O'Hair</ENAMEX> vanished in
late <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> along with her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> and granddaughter. <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">About $700,000</NUMEX> of her
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">foundation</ENAMEX>'s money, stashed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Zealand</ENAMEX>, also seems to have disappeared. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> claims <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O'Hair</ENAMEX> is lying low in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Zealand</ENAMEX>; others think she's dead; God
has no comment. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VF</ENAMEX> pays tribute (for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX> pages<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>!) to "swinging" <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>,
which has recaptured <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">its 1960s</TIMEX> hipness: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oasis</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blur</ENAMEX> are much admired; so is
fashion enfant terrible <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander McQueen</ENAMEX>. Also, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> is panned:
"familiar names like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Queenan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katha Pollitt</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wendy Kaminer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louis Menand</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Berman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicholas Lemann</ENAMEX>--all-purpose <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oxygen</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">depleters</ENAMEX> who wash up
everywhere." (<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Articles</ENAMEX> by all these oxygen depleters are available in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Compost</ENAMEX>.")

            

               --Compiled by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Plotz</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> .
            

         
      
   
