
   
   
      
         
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 30</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Aug. 30</TIMEX>)
            

            The
lead editorial embraces evolutionary biology's new insights
into human behavior, but warns against eugenics. A companion piece elucidates <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of these new insights:
Bodily symmetry largely determines physical attractiveness, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX> may use
smell to assess the quality of a potential sex <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX>'s immune system. An
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> predicts that the "kretek," an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> clove cigarette that controls
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">90 percent</NUMEX> of that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s market, may challenge <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco</ENAMEX>'s worldwide
dominance. Also, a story wonders why the weight-loss industry isn't booming.
Problems: It lacks a safe, effective <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX>, and is challenged by the
"fat-lash"--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">proponents</ENAMEX> of "big is beautiful." (For more on getting down the
pounds, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s "Medical
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Examiner</ENAMEX>.")

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times Magazine</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 31</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 28</TIMEX>)
            

            The
"successful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bureaucrat</ENAMEX>" issue profiles <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudy Crew</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chancellor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Schools</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yuri Luzhkov</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX>. The cover story says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crew</ENAMEX> is
promoting higher standards citywide, rather than focusing on a few flagship
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>. His efforts have not boosted test scores as much as had been promised,
but modest improvements and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Crew</ENAMEX>'s political clout make him the beleaguered
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">system</ENAMEX>'s most impressive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX>. The article on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luzhkov</ENAMEX> echoes the
now-familiar line that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX> is great (see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> summary, below).
The eccentric <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> ignores corruption, but effectively micromanages <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX>'s
building boom. Notable statistic: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prime</ENAMEX> office space costs more in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX> than
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>. Also, can rapper <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marky Mark</ENAMEX> become film <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Wahlberg</ENAMEX>?
He's the latest of many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">musicians</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Will Smith</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Courtney Love ...</ENAMEX>) to make the
leap to movies.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 1</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 26</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
story on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">billionaire financier</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Soros</ENAMEX> says that his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">philanthropy</ENAMEX> provokes
as much controversy as gratitude. Having given <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $1 billion</NUMEX> in aid to
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Eastern Europe</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Soros</ENAMEX> is now spending <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">tens of millions of dollars</NUMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> to promote medical marijuana, rights for legal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX>, alternatives
to incarceration, and better care for the dying. These donations are intended
to rectify <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> government inaction. Notable statistic: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Soros</ENAMEX>' <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> aid to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hungary</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Belarus</ENAMEX> tops <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> aid to those <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>. A story
argues that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>'s recent police brutality belies general reform in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s police <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">departments</ENAMEX>. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> now give cops clear anti-brutality
messages and better training on the use of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX>. An article by a baby boomer
contends that modern <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-agers</ENAMEX> have nothing left to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebel</ENAMEX> against, save
rebellion.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 1</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 26</TIMEX>)
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">ninth</NUMEX> health cover of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> warns that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">E. coli food</ENAMEX>
contamination is more common than is reported and won't be eradicated with
simple <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beef</ENAMEX> recalls like the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hudson Foods</ENAMEX>. New, tougher food-inspection
standards will help, but "no one predicts a day in which all <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> will be
perfectly free of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX>." A companion piece <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> destroying food
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacteria</ENAMEX> with low-level radiation. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Activist groups</ENAMEX> are dubious. A story says
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mob</ENAMEX> exerts too much control over that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s finance
industry, hindering <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>'s ability to compete in the global market. An article
on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX> concedes that it has high crime rates, but asserts that a growing
middle <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> and booming night life are revitalizing the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News & World Report</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 1</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 26</TIMEX>)
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Princeton</ENAMEX> tie for <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> in the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">11 th</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Best</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Colleges</ENAMEX>" rankings. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Duke</ENAMEX> cracks the Ivy monopoly by sharing <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> place
with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Virginia</ENAMEX> is the top public school (but <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX> st
overall), and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Swarthmore</ENAMEX> repeats as best liberal-arts <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX>. One
accompanying article says that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> who apply for early admission have
a better chance of being accepted. Another reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">fraternities</ENAMEX> and sororities are cracking down
on drinking, and promoting studying: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Panhellenic Conference</ENAMEX> has
declared <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>--this is not a joke--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Year of the Scholar</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX> '
bad <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beef</ENAMEX> article is a revolting description of what really goes
into cattle <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">feed</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chicken manure</ENAMEX>, grease, cement dust, newsprint, and human
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sewage</ENAMEX>, among other things. The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">feed</ENAMEX> is safe when treated properly, but many
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX> aren't careful, raising the risk of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beef</ENAMEX> contamination. And a piece
chastises the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Red Cross</ENAMEX> for dumping <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">3 million pints</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> of perfectly safe
blood donated by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with hemochromatosis. Those with the disease must
donate <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> regularly to rid their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> of excess iron, but blood <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> refuse
to use the plasma even though it would solve blood-supply shortages.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harper</ENAMEX>'s , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 1997</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 21</TIMEX>)
            

            A
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-story cover package damns and praises higher education. An essay by a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Virginia</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> says that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> seek only
ironic entertainment in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">classroom</ENAMEX>. Raised on the cool medium of television,
undergrads are skeptical about passionate ideas, doubtful of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX>, and
intellectually timid. Even worse news: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bottom-line</ENAMEX>-obsessed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX> won't
challenge this complacency because they can't afford to offend their paying
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>. The other piece glorifies an experimental humanities <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> for
low-income, undereducated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> contends that philosophy, art, and
literature are empowering, because they teach the disenfranchised how to
challenge the elite without violence. Evidence: The once-hopeless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> have
gone on to college or better jobs.

         
      
   
