
   
   
      
         
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity Fair</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 1997</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Oct. 11</TIMEX>)
            

            On the
cover and inside: portraits of "the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">65</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> who shape and rule the world
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>." Making the list: The Bills (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helmut Kohl</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Louis</ENAMEX>
Farrakhan, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fidel Castro</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Greenspan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Soros</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alberto Fujimori</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Colin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Powell</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nike</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phil Knight</ENAMEX>, among others. An article profiles
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cyberprophet Esther Dyson</ENAMEX>, whose technology <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newsletter</ENAMEX> is a must-read in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Silicon Valley</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dyson</ENAMEX>'s extreme eccentricities (despite great wealth, she's
lived in the same <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-bedroom walk-up for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25 years</TIMEX>--and it doesn't have a
telephone) bolster her reputation as a visionary. Also, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity Fair</ENAMEX>
excerpts a novel about a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> covering the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.J.</ENAMEX> case for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fair</ENAMEX> . The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dominick Dunne</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> who covered the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.J.</ENAMEX> case
for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity Fair</ENAMEX> . An article details how <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kennedy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biographer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seymour Hersh</ENAMEX>
got duped by forgers offering bogus JFK-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marilyn Monroe</ENAMEX> correspondence.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 11</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Oct. 11</TIMEX>)
            

            A cover
editorial calls for the ouster of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin Netanyahu</ENAMEX>.
Recent ill-timed blunders (including the failed attempt to assassinate a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hamas</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>) have derailed the peace process. (See <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Gist" on Mossad</ENAMEX> for more about the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX> that botched the assassination.) A report from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Promise Keepers</ENAMEX> rally
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> agrees with everyone else that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> isn't as scary as
previously imagined. (See <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Promise Keepers 1</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOW</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0</NUMEX>.") An essay says <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumer advocate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralph Nader</ENAMEX> will have a tough time
battling his newest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foe</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nader</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> of his own success. "[He]
has helped make <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> government intrusive; and that intrusiveness has made
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> wary of seeing government limit the freedom of successes like
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>."

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 27</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, Oct. 10</TIMEX>)
            

            A cover
story profiles <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Weyrich</ENAMEX>, right-wing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founder</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Empowerment</ENAMEX>
Television. A conservative "utopianist," <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Weyrich</ENAMEX> demands that fellow
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> absolutely obey the party line. This all-or-nothing attitude
cripples the right wing. An article says the pendulum is swinging back in
sexual-harassment cases: It's the accused, not the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">accusers</ENAMEX>, who are now
winning million-dollar judgments. Also, a story says the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Promise Keepers</ENAMEX>
exemplify the right's new strategy: Out-emote <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times Magazine</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 12</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, Oct. 9</TIMEX>)
            

            A cover
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> follows a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">squad</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Point</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cadets</ENAMEX> through the revamped basic
training they receive before their <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">semester</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Tradition-bound alums</ENAMEX> hate
the program's new softness (more gender equality, less hazing), while the
administration notes that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>'s female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cadets</ENAMEX> can do more push-ups than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1962</TIMEX>'s
male <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cadets</ENAMEX> could. A story studies slavery in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mauritania</ENAMEX>, which continues
despite official emancipation. After <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">500 years</TIMEX> under <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masters</ENAMEX>, many black
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mauritanians</ENAMEX> think like this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>: "God created me to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slave</ENAMEX> ... just as
he created a camel to be a camel." Also, an essay criticizes the double
standard for adultery: "When <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> cheat, they're <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pigs</ENAMEX>. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> do it, they're
striking a blow for sexual freedom."

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 13</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Oct. 7</TIMEX>)
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's trend-spotting
lead is "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">America's Fascination with Buddhism</ENAMEX>" (a k a: an
excuse to put <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brad Pitt</ENAMEX> on the cover). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pitt</ENAMEX>'s new film, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Seven Years</TIMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tibet</ENAMEX> , and droves of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Buddhist</ENAMEX> celebs (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Gere</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina Turner</ENAMEX>, Beastie
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Boy Adam Yauch</ENAMEX> ...) are bringing hipness to the religion and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tibetan</ENAMEX> cause.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Buddhism</ENAMEX> angle: It predicts protests by famous Tibetophiles
when <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang Zemin</ENAMEX> visits the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this month</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's cover on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> misdeeds repeats now-familiar accusations about
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>'s unchecked power.

            A
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> story says young male <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">elephants</ENAMEX> are murdering rhinos in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Africa</ENAMEX>. Why the violence? No male-elephant role models. (No kidding.) Another
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> article says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Soul Food</ENAMEX> 's success might rouse
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> to pay heed to black <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s box-office potential. Also in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , transcripts of newly released tapes from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LBJ</ENAMEX>'s archives.
Complaining to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Connally</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1964</TIMEX>: "Every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> in my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cabinet</ENAMEX>'s a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kennedy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>.
... I haven't been able to change 'em, and I don't have the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX> if I
could change 'em. They didn't go to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">San Marcos Teacher</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">College</ENAMEX>
[<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alma mater</ENAMEX>]. ... It's just agony. ... I don't really know how to
handle it all." (To hear excerpts from the newly released tapes, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">LBJ Sounds Off</ENAMEX>.")

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 13</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Oct. 7</TIMEX>)
            

            

               The 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> excerpts <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Plimpton</ENAMEX>'s forthcoming biography
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Truman Capote</ENAMEX> to tell the story behind <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Capote</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">In Cold Blood</ENAMEX> , the
"factional" account of a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1959</TIMEX> murder in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kansas</ENAMEX>, which appeared in the magazine
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1965</TIMEX>. Interesting details: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Capote</ENAMEX> met <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kansas</ENAMEX> cops wearing nothing but a lacy
pink negligee; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Capote</ENAMEX> identified with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">murderer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Perry Smith</ENAMEX>; female writer
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harper Lee</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">To Kill a Mockingbird</ENAMEX> ) acted as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Capote</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodyguard</ENAMEX> during
his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kansas</ENAMEX> visits. A column by former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Reich</ENAMEX> argues that
large campaign contributions corrupt <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> not by influencing them to
change votes, but by immersing them in the world of rich <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. An essay
describes how difficult, time-consuming, and sad it is to take care of aging
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News & World Report</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 13</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Oct. 7</TIMEX>)
            

            A
cover
package rates the best <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American HMOs</ENAMEX>. On top: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Group Health Cooperative of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Central Wisconsin</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New England</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard Community Health Plan</ENAMEX>. An
accompanying piece says consumer awareness is improving <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMOs</ENAMEX>. A story assesses the costly new push for smaller public-school
classes. Smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classes</ENAMEX> alone won't improve education, but they work wonders
when led by good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX>. Also, an article examines the booming business of naming <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX>.
Pitfalls abound: "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enron</ENAMEX>" originally chose "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Enteron</ENAMEX>," the medical term for the
excretory <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">canal</ENAMEX>. (To see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s take on the name game, read "You Name
It.")
            

            

               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 13</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Oct. 7</TIMEX>)
            

            A cover
story tracks <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Forbes</ENAMEX>' self-reinvention. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX>' new pro-life stand will
draw the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">right</ENAMEX> to his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> campaign. An article mourns the
deterioration of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Episcopal Church</ENAMEX>. Increasing moral lassitude (read: gay
rights) alienates the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX>'s base. Also, an editorial calls the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> hearings
the "biggest <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> victory in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>," arguing that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> must continue to
find hot-button issues.

            

               --Compiled by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seth Stevenson</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> .
            

         
      
   
