
   
   
      
         
            

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 24</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 7</TIMEX>)
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Great Equivocator</ENAMEX>" bashes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director-nominee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony Lake</ENAMEX>
as too wishy-washy to head the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>: He was soft toward the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviets</ENAMEX> during
the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX>, he's soft toward the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> now, and he's scared of using force
to achieve foreign-policy goals. The editorial asserts that welfare reform is already a success, since
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFDC</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Aid to Families With Dependent Children</ENAMEX>) caseloads are falling
everywhere. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">For Slate</ENAMEX>'s take, see "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Best</ENAMEX>
Policy.") Also, the fund-raising scandal: A parody makes fun of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> as a "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DNC Luxury Hotel</ENAMEX>."

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 8</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 7</TIMEX>)
            

            The
cover story and editorial on "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Future of Warfare</ENAMEX>" predict that satellites,
unmanned <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX>, and computers will replace <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> says
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> will dominate the high-tech arms industry, but that its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rivals</ENAMEX> will counter with biological weapons and terrorism. A long feature frets
about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s weakness : It's plagued by poverty, inequality, pollution,
etc. Also, a gloomy article on the welfare bill: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Training AFDC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> to work
will be extraordinarily expensive and, in many cases, futile. (For another
view, see the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX> , above, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Best</ENAMEX>
Policy.")

            

               
                  New 
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">York</ENAMEX> 
                  Times 
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Magazine</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 9</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 6</TIMEX>)
            

            "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Age</ENAMEX>
Boom" package celebrates life after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">65</TIMEX>. The lead article gloats that senior
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> live longer, more vigorously, and more comfortably <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> than ever
before. An <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economist</ENAMEX> argues that we shouldn't worry about rising medical costs,
since the money buys good health and happiness. An advertising executive
predicts that <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Madison Avenue</ENAMEX> will finally start pitching products to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">seniors</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> is touted as a wonderful retirement <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX>: You can walk
everywhere, there's plenty of culture, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> are excellent. Also,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elderly</ENAMEX> celebs talk about how great it is to get old.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rolling Stone</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 20</TIMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 10</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 5</TIMEX>)
            

            Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> profile
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard Stern</ENAMEX>, whose biopic, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Private Parts</ENAMEX> , opens <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this month</TIMEX>. Rolling
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stone</ENAMEX> 's cover story traces <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stern</ENAMEX>'s history from mediocre rock <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DJ</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX> of
shock <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jocks</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> puzzles over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stern</ENAMEX>'s psyche: His program is
pure id--vile, cruel, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">crude</ENAMEX>--yet he remains a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faithful husband</ENAMEX> and devoted
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>.

            Also in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yorker</ENAMEX> , an admiring profile of business-news <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tycoon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Bloomberg</ENAMEX>
suggests that he has the brains and financial muscle to cripple <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dow Jones</ENAMEX>. A
long piece on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> describes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>'s struggle to survive the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mao</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deng</ENAMEX>
eras, while the opening "Comment" says that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> involvement in the
campaign-finance scandal could sour <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sino</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> relations.

            Also in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rolling Stone</ENAMEX> : global warming. A piece argues that rising carbon-dioxide
levels are almost certainly causing the weird weather of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1990s</TIMEX>, and that
they will cause unimaginable devastation if the world does not slash
fossil-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fuel</ENAMEX> consumption soon.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 10</TIMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 10</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 4</TIMEX>)
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>'s and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's cover stories describe the
cloning process, predicting that the technology will be used on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven years</TIMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> ) or in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to 10 years
( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> ). Neither is terribly keen on the idea, but both agree that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">human</ENAMEX> clones would be normal. On the business side, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> is bearish on
biotech stocks, while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> is bullish. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's cloning package
also includes a short story and a cartoon.

            Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> jump on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln Bedroom</ENAMEX>
story, emphasizing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s intimate involvement in fund raising. A
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> column by former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adviser</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX> calls
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> fund raising "unpleasant but necessary": The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> needed
money to prevent a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> primary challenge and to overcome the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>'s
traditional fund-raising advantage.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>'s profile of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Lott</ENAMEX> reaches the same conclusion
as numerous earlier profiles of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">majority leader</ENAMEX>: Like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lott</ENAMEX>
is a compromiser.

            Also in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , an article about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Helfgott</ENAMEX>, subject of the movie
Shine : It says he is a wretched <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pianist</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News & World Report</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 10</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 4</TIMEX>)
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
News ranks graduate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>. There are few surprises. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale</ENAMEX> is tops
for law, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stanford</ENAMEX> for business, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MIT</ENAMEX> for engineering,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia</ENAMEX> for education, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYU</ENAMEX> for film. The requisite <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">campaign-finance</NUMEX> article
notes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, who has been an avid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fund-raiser</ENAMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">his days</TIMEX> as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX>, loves consorting with rich <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. Former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adviser</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gergen</ENAMEX> turns on his old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX>, writing that his "calculated exploitation of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s highest office" displays a "stunning crassness." A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Q&A</ENAMEX> about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dolly</ENAMEX> concludes that a cloned human would
have its own soul. Also, a piece investigates how <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> logging <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> are
despoiling rainforests in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South America</ENAMEX>.

            

               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 10</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 4</TIMEX>)
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Editor</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Kristol</ENAMEX> recycles the advice he dispensed to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> in a cover
piece <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">just two months ago</TIMEX>. The "cowering," "brain dead" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> must revive
itself by opposing partial-birth abortions, fighting affirmative action,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">blocking Clinton</ENAMEX>'s appointment of liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX>, and getting tough on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>.
An article on the fund-raising scandal suggests that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> is
terrified at the prospect of more <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ickes</ENAMEX> documents, more <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> revelations, and
the possible cooperation of key <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Huang</ENAMEX>. Also, a piece condemns
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> history textbooks, which "read like one long <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>'s brief in the
case of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oppressed People</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Males</ENAMEX> ."

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nation</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 17</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 4</TIMEX>)
            

            The
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>-story cover package, titled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"The Crushing Power</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Publishing</ENAMEX>," follows
the theme of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Entertainment State</ENAMEX>" special issue. The
lead story bemoans the
rise of gigantic publishing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX>, the demise of independent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bookstores</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">unholy</ENAMEX> marriage of publishing and television, and the abysmal quality of
contemporary books: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today</ENAMEX>'s worst ... is much worse than the trash of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">yesteryear</ENAMEX>." A fold-out chart depicts how a few <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">conglomerates</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Corp.</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hearst</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Viacom</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Advance</ENAMEX>, etc.) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> the publishing industry. A piece
argues that sentences in books are getting shorter, indicating a "dumbing-down"
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>. (It's true. I'm sure.) Also, an article claims that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Independent Counsel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>, who serves
on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABA Journal</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX>, gave the legal magazine
suggestions about how to cover <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitewater</ENAMEX>.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harper</ENAMEX>'s , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 1997</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, Feb. 28</TIMEX>)
            

            An
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> deplores modern <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">libraries</ENAMEX> for buying too many expensive, hard-to-use
computers and too few books: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Unique</ENAMEX>, anomalous, unconventional knowledge" is
being lost. (And the worst part: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Libraries</ENAMEX> aren't even silent anymore!) Another
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> calls the rebuilding after the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Berkeley Hills</ENAMEX> fire an
"architectural disaster." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grotesque</ENAMEX>, overdesigned <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mansions</ENAMEX> have risen where
beautiful, modest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> once stood. Also, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> spends a sunless <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenland</ENAMEX>: She drinks a lot.

            

               --Compiled by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Plotz</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> .
            

         
      
   
