
   
   
      
         
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 2</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Aug. 2</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
editorial calls for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> to rethink their
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX> policies when moderate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Muhammad Khatami</ENAMEX> assumes the presidency <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Khatami</ENAMEX> has been a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> of the West ever since he was removed as culture
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX> for being too permissive. A related story raises questions about an energy deal between
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkmenistan</ENAMEX>, since natural gas will be piped through <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>. And, an
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> on the double bombing in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX> says the explosion "could prove a
mortal blow" to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. Just <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one hour</TIMEX> before the
attack, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisers</ENAMEX> were mocking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> for their inability to
curb terrorism.

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times Magazine</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 3</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, July 31</TIMEX>)
            

            It's
trendy to be young and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Poland</ENAMEX>, says the cover story. With the end of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">communism</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> is witnessing a revival of the religion. But tension
with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catholic Church</ENAMEX> and a history of anti-Semitism still haunt the small
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">community</ENAMEX>. An article looks at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the remaining '60s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">communes</ENAMEX>, which has
survived by making hammocks. No longer a refuge for idealistic and transient
twentysomethings, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> "campus" is now home to middle-aged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who move in for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">up to a decade</TIMEX>. Also, a profile of disgraced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boxer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones Jr.</ENAMEX> details his struggle to distance himself from a controlling father
and to restore his reputation.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 4</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, July 29</TIMEX>)
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> covers on the rich.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> explains how stock options created the new billionaires. But
the article warns that the laws of financial gravity have not been repealed and
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">super-wealthy</ENAMEX> must eventually return to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">earth</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mormons</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inc.</ENAMEX>" cover story details the riches of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> founded by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Smith</ENAMEX>: It
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s biggest cattle operation) at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$30 billion</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church</ENAMEX> membership is
approaching <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">10 million</NUMEX> and is growing faster than most other religions'.

            Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> chronicle the
final <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> of suspected serial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">killer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Cunanan</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> offers a
brief psychological profile. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> offers a piece by a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cunanan</ENAMEX> friend
who says he was "a hard <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> to read."

            A package
of stories in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> examines <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50 years</TIMEX> after independence. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s economy and culture are booming. For the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time, the standard of
living for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s poor (although not the very poor) is rising. A piece in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> asks if the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX>'s softer boot camps ill prepare soldiers
for war.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News & World Report</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 4</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, July 29</TIMEX>)
            

            The
cover story finds the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">day-care</ENAMEX> industry woefully under-regulated
and under-supervised. Laced with horror stories of toddlers dying while in day
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">care</ENAMEX>, the piece blames <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyists</ENAMEX> who have blocked government oversight. Also, a
piece on the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.5 billion</NUMEX> hair-replacement industry explains that
you don't buy new <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hair</ENAMEX>, you rent it. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Consumers</ENAMEX> of hair ointments, "systems,"
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">surgeries</ENAMEX> must continue to pay to maintain their new growth. An article reports on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>' increasing dependence on gambling
taxes.

            

               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 4</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, July 29</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
story describes how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s "attack machine" of private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>, and spin <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> deflects the various <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> scandals
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Travelgate, Paula Jones</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Troopergate</ENAMEX>, etc.). The machine defends the president
by attacking the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attackers</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>. Currently, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> are taking aim
at independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> debunks "whole-math," which
is the rage in some elementary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school curricula</ENAMEX>. Whole-math focuses less on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">arithmetic</ENAMEX> and more on "real-world concerns." Also, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> more post-mortems on
the botched <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> coup.

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 4</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, July 29</TIMEX>)
            

            Two
articles on coups. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Continental Shift</ENAMEX>" examines the recent <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Congo</ENAMEX> revolution:
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alliance</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly a dozen</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> that helped topple <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mobutu Sese</ENAMEX>
Seko may permanently realign the region's politics. The Letter from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
looks at the failed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> coup from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Speaker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX>'s perspective,
predicting that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> will follow his support base and shift from
conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">revolutionary</ENAMEX> to moderate. Also, an article on an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alabama</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s beauty pageant: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Contestants</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> believe that beauty will
catapult their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> from the working <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nation</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 11-18</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, July 29</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
story uses <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX> data released after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freedom of Information</ENAMEX>
Act requests to portray the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> as sloppy and ineffective. The bureau
concentrates its energies on convicting <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealers</ENAMEX> and bank
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">robbers</ENAMEX> (who should be chased by local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX>), but mostly ignores
white-collar crime. Despite its poor track record, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> has expanded its
power.

         
      
   
