
   
   
      
         
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 15</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Sept. 13</TIMEX>)
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> devotes nearly
its entire issue to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Princess</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Di</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> sees that issue, and raises
with a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>, separate, advertisement-free "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Commemorative Issue</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joyce Carol</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oates</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Amis</ENAMEX> eulogize in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's regular issue
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">trumps</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy Reagan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katharine Graham</ENAMEX>. Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> provide detailed
accounts of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night</TIMEX> of the accident, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX> of mourning, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">funeral</ENAMEX>;
and both conclude that the future of the monarchy hinges on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Di</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> calls for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prince Charles</ENAMEX> to step aside in favor of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William</ENAMEX>. It
also advises <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles</ENAMEX>' paramour, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Camilla Parker Bowles</ENAMEX>, to avoid publicity until
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX> fuss subsides. Also, both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mags</ENAMEX> do the required soul-searching about
the paparazzi , concluding that the public's appetite for celebrity
photos will overcome its revulsion for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">photographers</ENAMEX>' methods.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Commemorative Issue</ENAMEX> also features essays and countless
pictures. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Di</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosa Monckton</ENAMEX> chastises the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> for their exploitation of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Di</ENAMEX> in a piece exploiting her own relationship with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Di</ENAMEX>, complete with private
photos of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">princess</ENAMEX>.

            Mother
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Teresa</ENAMEX>'s death is shunted to the back of each regular issue. The obits are, not
surprisingly, reverential. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time 's</ENAMEX> is longer.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 13</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Sept. 13</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
editorial and article on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s economic future recommend wholesale
privatization. Foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> cheer party <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang Zemin</ENAMEX>'s slow moves
toward capitalism, but <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s looming bank crisis requires far more rapid
reform. A piece says that the ozone layer is healing thanks to CFC bans. But
there's cause for worry: <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Ozone</ENAMEX> depletion is no longer a trendy political cause,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CFC</ENAMEX> smuggling is rampant in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>. A story on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX>'s purchase of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CompuServe</ENAMEX>
observes that online services increasingly resemble television <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX>: Their
core business is information and entertainment, not modems and servers.

            

               
                  New 
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 29</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, Sept. 12</TIMEX>)
            

            New
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Lane</ENAMEX> replaces <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kelly</ENAMEX>, who was ousted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Editor</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Peretz</ENAMEX> writes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lane</ENAMEX> "represents continuity with the best
traditions of this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journal</ENAMEX>: political independence, intellectual seriousness,
good writing and decency toward those with whom <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> disagrees." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lane</ENAMEX> also
contributes a cover story about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s ineffectual Haiti
policy. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> has failed to improve living conditions or uphold the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">authority</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">René Preval</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">De</ENAMEX> facto <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jean-Bertrand Aristide</ENAMEX> has
proven nearly as authoritarian as former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dictator</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Papa Doc" Duvalier</ENAMEX>. An
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> argues that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> should oppose the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Endowment for the Arts</ENAMEX>
on the grounds that art does not need federal subsidies. Also, why <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Princess</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Di</ENAMEX>
was like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>: The public cared more about her empathy than about
her actions.

            

               
                  New 
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">York</ENAMEX> 
                  Times 
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Magazine</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 14</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, Sept. 11</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jibril Rajoub</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palestinian Authority</ENAMEX>'s secret <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israelis</ENAMEX> distrust him because he was in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLO</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hamas</ENAMEX>, while <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX> despise him for cooperating with their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemy</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israelis</ENAMEX>. An article refutes the accepted wisdom that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Klaus Fuchs</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David</ENAMEX>
Greenglass leaked the first atomic secrets to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviets</ENAMEX>. (Later, however,
they did turn over secrets to the other side.) A recently released <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Soviet</ENAMEX>
document implicates <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Theodore Hall</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicist</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambridge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hall</ENAMEX> is
unapologetic about his spying, but the lack of living <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> makes
prosecution impossible.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News & World Report</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 15</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Sept. 9</TIMEX>)
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
News , which missed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>'s death <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> because of its early deadline,
makes up for it with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX> cover package <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>. "Who's to
Blame for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Death?</ENAMEX>" spreads the guilt among the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX>, the security
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">guard, Dodi Fayed</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">photographers</ENAMEX>, the rest of the royal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>,
and the adoring public. An essay explains why young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> identified with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>. (Why? They
want to be princesses, too. They also know what it's like to fall in love with
a jerk.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Editor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Fallows</ENAMEX> returns briefly to his favorite role of media
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX>. His conclusion: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Journalists</ENAMEX> can't help hurting the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> they cover,
but they should be less careless and cruel. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mother Teresa</ENAMEX> article is adulatory. And a piece
describes how <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> are increasingly snooping through <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>' e-mail,
voice mail, and credit records. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Employers</ENAMEX> say they need to protect themselves
against lawsuits and on-the-job misbehavior.

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 15</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Sept. 9</TIMEX>)
            

            The
celebrity-obsessed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> publishes a special <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX> issue, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three days</TIMEX> before
its regular publication date of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>. The all-star edition features elegiac
pieces from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clive James</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simon Schama</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salman Rushdie</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Di</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">acquaintance</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina Brown</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX> also did TV commentary for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX> at the
funeral). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX> warmly remember their <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">moments</TIMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">princess</ENAMEX>.
Rushdie offers a "semiotic" analysis of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Di</ENAMEX>'s life and death, suggesting that
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> should abandon its fascination with monarchy. Schama traces the history
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> alienated by the crown: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anne Boleyn</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aquitaine</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Princess Caroline</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brunswick</ENAMEX> (who?). A profile of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novelist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don DeLillo</ENAMEX> is
pegged to his forthcoming novel, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Underworld</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Trevor</ENAMEX> contributes
a short story.

            

               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 15</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Sept. 9</TIMEX>)
            

            No <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>
news. The cover story both mocks and admires "latte <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX>," progressive,
wealthy, organic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burlington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vt.</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ithaca</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.Y.</ENAMEX> What's to
praise? The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hippies</ENAMEX> who populate latte <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX> have finally embraced capitalism,
and they are using private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enterprise</ENAMEX> to build livable, prosperous <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>. An
accompanying article makes fun of several '60s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">do-gooders</ENAMEX> who've been arrested
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent weeks</TIMEX> for crimes of greed. The predictions of auto-safety experts
that fatalities would rise <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">30 percent</NUMEX> if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> lifted the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">55-mile</NUMEX>-per<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">-hour</TIMEX>
speed limit have not come true, a piece reports. Fatalities have not increased,
but the mainstream <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> have ignored this good news.

            

               --Compiled by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seth Stevenson</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> .
            

         
      
   
