
   
   
      
         
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 27</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Sept. 27</TIMEX>)
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX>
backlash. An article credits former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police chief</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Bratton</ENAMEX> and Wall
Street for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>'s comeback. Notable stat: The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s welfare rolls are
longer now than in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Dinkins</ENAMEX>' <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX>. The cover editorial criticizes <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>'s proposed "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> bail-out
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX>." Intended to counter economic shakiness in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Far East</ENAMEX>, it would
damage the world's monetary markets by weakening the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Monetary</ENAMEX>
Fund. Also, a story examines the extreme incidence of lesbianism in
Diaprepes 
               abbreviatus beetles. A theory: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">lesbian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pair</ENAMEX> poses as a male, thereby discouraging smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">males</ENAMEX> who are
unwilling to fight for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mate</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 13</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Sept. 27</TIMEX>)
            

            An
excerpt from <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Stephan and Abigail Thernstrom's America</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Black</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
cites polls to reject the conventional wisdom that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> remain bitterly
divided over race: "In fact, we are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>, with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX> much
less unequal and, by many measures, much less hostile than in the past." "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TRB</ENAMEX>"
calls the ban on land <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mines</ENAMEX> the "politics of sentiment" and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> clearing
old <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mines</ENAMEX> from now-peaceful <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> instead of prohibiting them from war
zones like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DMZ</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Korea</ENAMEX>. An article lambastes recent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic Party</ENAMEX>
overtures to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Weld</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> ignore <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weld</ENAMEX>'s fiscally <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> views, but
embrace precisely the socially progressive streak in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weld</ENAMEX> (gay rights,
affirmative action) that <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">middle America</ENAMEX> hates in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times Magazine</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 28</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, Sept. 25</TIMEX>)
            

            A special
issue offers <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a dozen</NUMEX> articles about technology and modern culture. Among the
highlights: An article deplores the way computers disconnect <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> from the
physical world. (We spend too much time hunched over keyboards thinking, not
enough experiencing the real world.) Another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">story</ENAMEX> rejects the popular notion
that technology discourages socializing. (In fact, Internet chat <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> and
newsgroups are excellent places for social interaction.) Yet another argues
that recent software upgrades are actually downgrades. (They add useless
features that confuse <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> and waste time.) And an essay praises hyperfiction
for blurring the role of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX>. (To minimize confusion in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s
hypertext environment: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> = me, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> = you.)

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 29</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Sept. 23</TIMEX>)
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's cover story praises <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Turner</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 billion</NUMEX> gift to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX> are more hands-on than their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">predecessors</ENAMEX>,
an accompanying article says. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's cover story explains how popular serotonin-boosting drugs
(such as diet <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pills Redux</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">fen-phen</ENAMEX>) work, and how they can be health risks
(high serotonin levels damage heart valves). (See <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s take
on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">fen-phen</ENAMEX>.) A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sidebar</ENAMEX> blames the "uncritical media" for promoting
the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> "in the war against fat." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hmm</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">One year ago this week</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>
ran a cover story praising <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Redux.</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Di</ENAMEX>'s death improves
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prince Charles</ENAMEX>' image, transforming him from unfaithful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> to grieving
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>. Time hails the colorized <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s best
newspaper and also raves about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dylan</ENAMEX>'s new album, terming it "alchemic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">magic</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang Zemin</ENAMEX> bolstered his
political power by ousting <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Politburo</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rivals</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communist Party</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, but his dictatorial style won't mesh with his push for a modern
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">economy</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News & World Report</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 29</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Sept. 23</TIMEX>)
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
News tells the now-familiar story of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>'s resurrection, proposing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Apple</ENAMEX> as
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX> for other downtrodden <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>. Reducing crime was the crucial first
step: It sparked a return of industry, tourism, and permanent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX>. (The
stock market boom and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yankees</ENAMEX> championship helped too.) An article says that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX> is losing confidence: After the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gulf War the Air Force</ENAMEX> felt it was the most important of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX>, but
cuts in funding and troop strength, as well as a move toward unmanned <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX>,
have shaken it. Also, a story predicts that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> will allow <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sell</ENAMEX> atomic power <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> face a shrinking domestic
market, and claim (dubiously) that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> won't make military use of the
technology.

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 29</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Sept. 23</TIMEX>)
            

            A story
says clues to the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1918 Spanish</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">flu</ENAMEX> epidemic may lie in the cells of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">corpses</ENAMEX> preserved by permafrost on a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Norwegian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Scientists</ENAMEX> want to
determine the cause of the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">flu's potency</ENAMEX> (it killed more <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> than World
Wars <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">I and II</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Korea</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> combined) and prevent future epidemics. An
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> argues that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Princess</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Di</ENAMEX> hoopla finally brought <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> emotional
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sensibilities</ENAMEX> (i.e., hysteria) to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>. Also, a piece marvels at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Getty</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center</ENAMEX>, the soon-to-open <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">L.A.</ENAMEX> art <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX>: Thanks to its deep pockets, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Getty</ENAMEX>
has built a first-rate collection without having to market itself as other
museums do.

            

               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 29</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Sept. 23</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
story revisits a favorite Standard topic: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s abysmal human-rights
record. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Laogai Archipelago</ENAMEX>" describes <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s massive, awful penal system,
which imprisons between <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6 million and 8 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and favors such
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">barbarous</ENAMEX> practices as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slave</ENAMEX> labor, torture, and organ-harvesting from executed
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">convicts</ENAMEX>. Anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laogai crusader Harry Wu</ENAMEX> is much praised. The editorial
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ridicules Al Gore</ENAMEX>'s campaign against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> hunger, using government statistics
to point out that there is virtually no one in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> who doesn't get enough
to eat.

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nation</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 6</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Sept. 23</TIMEX>)
            

            A
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>-story cover package on the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Politics of Travel</ENAMEX>" complains that mass
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tourism Disneyfies</ENAMEX> authentic culture and promotes economic colonialism.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tourism</ENAMEX>, it reports, is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>-largest industry in the world, after <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX>.
The funniest piece: A <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nation</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> takes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Review</ENAMEX> 's
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alaska</ENAMEX> cruise, hobnobbing with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Buckley</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milton Friedman</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">hundreds</NUMEX>
of wealthy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">right-wingers</ENAMEX>. He is baffled to find that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> are
incredibly nice. Other highlight: A visit to the "most poisonous place on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">earth</ENAMEX>," a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nevada</ENAMEX> nuclear-test site. A bus takes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX> craters
and blasted "test" <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX>.

            

               --Compiled by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seth Stevenson</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> .
            

         
      
   
