
   
   
      
         
            

             

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 3</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, May 3</TIMEX>)
            

            Much news
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> election. The cover
editorial asserts that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blair</ENAMEX>'s victory is a repudiation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tories</ENAMEX>,
not a victory for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor</ENAMEX> policies. It advises <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair</ENAMEX> to appoint a strong <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX>,
slow economic growth with higher interest rates, and strike boldly on
government reform, but worries that the new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX> is more concerned
with symbols than with policy. An <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> poll
concludes that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Britons</ENAMEX> are extremely skeptical of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Currency</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union</ENAMEX>. An article says that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor</ENAMEX> landslide does not signify the
death of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conservative Party</ENAMEX>: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Just five years ago</TIMEX>, after all, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> were
administering last rites to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Voters</ENAMEX> may hate <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tory</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>, but they
like <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tory</ENAMEX> policies. And a story
argues that bustling, open-minded <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Shanghai</ENAMEX>, rather than stodgy, authoritarian
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX>, is the future of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>.

            

               
                  New 
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 19</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 2</TIMEX>)
            

            "Gaming
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Poor</ENAMEX>" condemns state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lotteries</ENAMEX>. They sucker the poor with false
advertising, do a lousy job at raising revenue (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">only 34 cents</NUMEX> of every dollar
spent on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lotteries</ENAMEX> goes to state treasuries), and are magnets for corruption. A
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">review of Boutros Boutros-Ghali</ENAMEX>'s new memoir berates the former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary-general</ENAMEX> for his arrogance and condescension. The editorial calls the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> attack on federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> "intellectually incoherent and
constitutionally subversive," maintaining that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominees</ENAMEX> opposed by
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> are actually <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">moderates</ENAMEX> who advocate judicial restraint--exactly the
kind of jurists <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> should support.

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times Magazine</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 4</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 1</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
story endorses the state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legislature</ENAMEX>'s plan to scrap <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rent-control</ENAMEX> law. A story studies a block in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower East Side</ENAMEX> and concludes
that rent control reduces the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartments</ENAMEX>, encourages landlord
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">neglect</ENAMEX>, disproportionately benefits upper-middle-class <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">renters</ENAMEX>, and dissuades
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">developers</ENAMEX> from building new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartments</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economists</ENAMEX> agree. A story advises
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> not to take health warnings too seriously. The media exaggerate the
risks and benefits of research findings, and it's only in rare cases (notably
cigarette smoking) that science discovers clear evidence that changing behavior
can improve health. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chanel</ENAMEX> Under the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chador</ENAMEX>" examines <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>'s growing
"<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> feminist" movement: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Women</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elite</ENAMEX> are battling quietly to secure
a modicum of gender equity--the right to divorce, take maternity leave, win
custody of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, play sports, etc. Surprising fact: The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iranian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parliament</ENAMEX>
has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women members</ENAMEX>.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 5</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, April 29</TIMEX>)
            

            Brain issues. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's
cover story attributes all addictions--from <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">alcoholism</ENAMEX> to
drug addiction to binge eating--to the neurotransmitter dopamine. The addicting
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">substances</ENAMEX> are said to raise dopamine levels in the brain, inducing euphoria.
The upshot: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Addiction</ENAMEX> is a disease, not a moral failing. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's "The
Brain's <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Last Stand</ENAMEX>" ponders the significance of chess <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">champion</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garry Kasparov</ENAMEX>'s
rematch with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Deep Blue</ENAMEX>. The computer, now much faster and smarter, may
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">triumph</ENAMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX> shouldn't fret. A victory by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Deep Blue</ENAMEX> would indicate its
superior computational skills, but not a capacity for conscious thought.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , which loves fad therapies, hypes "natural <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Prozac</ENAMEX>." An herb
called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saint Johnswort</ENAMEX> seems to alleviate mild <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">depression</ENAMEX> with no nasty side
effects.

            Also, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tiger Woods</ENAMEX> moment
continues, as both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> use the golfer to celebrate multiracialism. They note that interracial
marriage is increasing, and express the hope that multiracial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> will bridge
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s racial divides.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> claims that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hong</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kong</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">businessman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ambrous Tung Young</ENAMEX> bailed out the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Republican National</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994 and 1996</TIMEX> by sending it <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $2 million</NUMEX> through a
complicated series of loans.

            Also in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , a piece pegged to the movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Volcano</ENAMEX> says that volcanoes
threaten <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> worldwide, but not the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News & World Report</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 5</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, April 29</TIMEX>)
            

            On the
cover, a long excerpt from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Billy Graham</ENAMEX>'s forthcoming autobiography,
Just As I Am , chronicles the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">preacher</ENAMEX>'s relationships with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">presidents</ENAMEX>. He admits that he "might have exaggerated <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>'s spirituality" in
his own mind; says he prayed with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX> the eve of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gulf War</ENAMEX> and with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy Reagan</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> after her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> was shot; and describes chastising <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> for consulting an astrologer: "I urged her to seek guidance from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lord</ENAMEX> instead." An article pegged to the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Volunteer Summit</ENAMEX> contends that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> don't need much help: They read better, take fewer <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>, score better on
tests, and have fewer health problems than their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> did. A story
says personal-computer sales are slow because PCs are too hard to use and
customer service is nonexistent.

            

               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 5</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, April 29</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
story, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Little Man, What Now?</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tweaks</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Reich</ENAMEX> for his sanctimonious,
bitter memoir. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX>'s liberal vision--a leaner but more activist
government--was abandoned by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> who promised to implement it,
leaving <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX> frustrated and powerless. An article urges the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> to
start acting like the majority <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>, principally by uniting around a tax cut.
The editorial endorses a tobacco settlement as a way to reduce both <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">smoking</ENAMEX> and
"specious" lawsuits.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mother Jones</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 1997</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, April 29</TIMEX>)
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mother Jones</ENAMEX> catalogs
the top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">400</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contributors</ENAMEX> of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995-96</TIMEX> election
cycle. Topping the list is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bernard Schwartz</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> of the defense contractor
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Loral</ENAMEX>, who gave a total of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$661,000</NUMEX> to both parties. Other high rollers
include: publishing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tycoon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dirk Ziff</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 6</ENAMEX>), who gave <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$436,000</NUMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>
and slept in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Bedroom;</ENAMEX> oil <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baron</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Koch</ENAMEX> (No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>), who gave
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$339,000</NUMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Libertarians</ENAMEX> to advance his anti-regulation agenda;
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gail Zappa</ENAMEX> (No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">widow</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank</ENAMEX>, who gave <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$292,650</NUMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>; and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jobs</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 126</ENAMEX>), who gave <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$150,000</NUMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>. A sidebar raps <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fund-raiser</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Terry McAuliffe</ENAMEX> for his
aggressive tactics. Also, a surprisingly favorable article about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian Coalition</ENAMEX>'s campaign to recruit blacks
and help rebuild burned black <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX>: This seems to be a truly sincere effort
to atone for a history of white <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> racism.

            

               --Compiled by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Plotz</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> .
            

         
      
   
