
   
   
      
         
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 1</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, March 1</TIMEX>)
            

            The
cover editorial--headlined, of course, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hello, Dolly</ENAMEX>"--rejects
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">alarmist The Boys</ENAMEX> From <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX> theories about cloning, declaring that
"careful application of biotechnology" can be enormously beneficial: "The fact
that new technologies feel scary or strange should not be enough to rule them
out." A related article praises the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">utility</ENAMEX> of genetically engineered
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX>, and notes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> have been using them for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">almost 20 years</TIMEX>.
Also, a story concludes that <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Asia</ENAMEX>'s economies are in excellent
shape, despite recent drops in their growth rates. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Economist</ENAMEX>
interviews <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> about foreign policy: He says the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
"can't afford to isolate <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>."

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 17</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, Feb. 28</TIMEX>)
            

            "The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madness</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Speaker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt" chronicles Gingrich</ENAMEX>'s decline:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">revolutionaries</ENAMEX>" are abandoning him; his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisers</ENAMEX> are
recriminating over who's to blame for his collapse; and potential successors
are jockeying for position. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX>'s own mood swings prompt <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> anonymous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">congressman</ENAMEX> to quip that "a good dose of antidepressants might help, if he
isn't on them already." A pair of articles catalog <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>'s drug
corruption--especially its crooked drug <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">czar</ENAMEX>--and scold the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
administration for ignoring it. Also, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNR</ENAMEX> publishes an appreciation of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX>' union <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albert Shanker</ENAMEX>, whose advertorials appeared in the
magazine for a quarter-century.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harper</ENAMEX>'s , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 1997</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, Feb. 28</TIMEX>)
            

            An
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> deplores modern <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">libraries</ENAMEX> for buying too many expensive, hard-to-use
computers and too few books: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Unique</ENAMEX>, anomalous, unconventional knowledge" is
being lost. (And the worst part: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Libraries</ENAMEX> aren't even silent anymore!) Another
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> calls the rebuilding after the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Berkeley Hills</ENAMEX> fire an
"architectural disaster." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grotesque</ENAMEX>, overdesigned <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mansions</ENAMEX> have risen where
beautiful, modest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> once stood. Also, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> spends a sunless <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenland</ENAMEX>: She drinks a lot.

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times Magazine</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 2</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, Feb. 27</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
story tours <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX> and finds it a dangerous, but salvageable, mess. On the one
hand, anarchy engulfs <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sudan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Zaire</ENAMEX>, and other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX>, and this chaos helps
spread <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">nasty diseases</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">malaria</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cholera</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX>, etc.) around the world. On the
other hand, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> who are--by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> standards--democratic, uncorrupt, and
competent have taken over former military <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dictatorships</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Uganda</ENAMEX>. A bit
of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Western</ENAMEX> investment could stabilize these promising <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>. Also, an
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> writes about getting fired and becoming a carpenter. And the
Sophisticated <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Traveler</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">supplement journeys</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tibet</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Memphis</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">San</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diego</ENAMEX>, among other locales.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 3</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Feb. 25</TIMEX>)
            

            A "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Special Report</ENAMEX>" tag
adorns both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">newsweeklies</ENAMEX>' cover stories on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deng Xiaoping</ENAMEX>. Similar obituaries and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">whither China?</ENAMEX>" pieces paint <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deng</ENAMEX> as a hard-nosed
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pragmatist</ENAMEX> and marvel at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s economic growth, but caution that the country
is still beset by poverty, corruption, pollution, etc. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's bigger
package offers a book excerpt from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sinophile Henry Kissinger</ENAMEX> on the history of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> relations that lionizes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deng</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mao Tse-tung</ENAMEX> (and, of course,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kissinger</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Patten</ENAMEX> advises the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> government
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">colony</ENAMEX>'s prosperity stems from its freedom. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> also
depicts new <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head of state</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang Zemin</ENAMEX> as a law-and-order <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">moralist</ENAMEX> who
is much less comfortable with capitalism's excesses than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deng</ENAMEX> was. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>
says that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang</ENAMEX> will probably face a challenge to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authority</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next fall</TIMEX>'s party
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnny Depp</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> of the new
movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Donnie Brasco</ENAMEX> , is much praised by both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX>: He eschews
conventional roles, yet still scores at the box office.

            Also in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> , an article claims that the stock market is not
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">overvalued</ENAMEX>, because the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> economy is in glorious shape. And a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX>-page
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Global Business Report</ENAMEX>" profiles a dozen <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">titans</ENAMEX> of
capitalism (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andy Grove</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hans Tietmeyer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ned Johnson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">et al.</ENAMEX>).

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News & World Report</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 3</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Feb. 25</TIMEX>)
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Space</ENAMEX>
Jam" surveys the burgeoning satellite industry. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,000-plus</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">communications</ENAMEX> satellites that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Motorola</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Teledesic</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Craig McCaw</ENAMEX>), and others are launching will drive down the cost of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">telecommunications</ENAMEX> and make television, telephone, and Internet service
affordable to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">billions</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in undeveloped <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX>. The package of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deng</ENAMEX>
stories echoes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CW</ENAMEX> that he liberated <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s economy while imprisoning
democracy. Also, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX> notes that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">60 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
pregnancies are unplanned, then slams <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> for downplaying effective
contraceptives such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Depo-Provera, Norplant</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IUDs</ENAMEX>.

            

               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 3</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Feb. 25</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
story calls for "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Return to National Greatness</ENAMEX>." After blaming <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> for
destroying the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>' expansive optimism and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> for
weakening <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>' faith in national <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, the article says that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> can revive its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spirit</ENAMEX> with a grand national mission. It's vague on what
that mission would be: "It almost doesn't matter what great task government
sets for itself, as long as it does some tangible thing with energy and
effectiveness." Also, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Bork</ENAMEX>, rehashing an argument from his current book,
explains why the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> should be amended to restrict judicial power. And
an editorial about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX> claims that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> is
"essentially dishonest in a way even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Nixon</ENAMEX>'s never was. ... Can
anyone doubt that if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> had <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oval Office</ENAMEX> tapes, he would expect <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bruce</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lindsey</ENAMEX> to burn them?"

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nation</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 10</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Feb. 25</TIMEX>)
            

            The
cover story proposes
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFL-CIO</ENAMEX> fund (to the tune of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$300 million</NUMEX>) a national progressive
newspaper--a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factory</ENAMEX>-floor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counterpart</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> . The
paper would report the real news about economic inequality, farm <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>, and
health care, zealously investigate corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX>, and open its editorial
pages to the likes of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cornel West</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Molly Ivins</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Kuttner</ENAMEX>. Also, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Rubin</ENAMEX> backlash. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Two weeks ago</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX> praised the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> for his social liberalism. Now <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Nation</ENAMEX> lambastes
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rubin</ENAMEX> as a conservative who favors bank deregulation that will hurt the
poor.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Review</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 10</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Feb. 25</TIMEX>)
            

            An
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> gloats that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> has not returned to its
old liberal ways. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s major policy (balancing the budget) and key
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">advisers</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Erskine Bowles</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rahm Emanuel</ENAMEX>) are conservative. His education
initiatives are dismissed as "micro-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberal</ENAMEX>." The cover story rips <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orrin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hatch</ENAMEX> for his alleged left-wing tendencies and says he's too closely aligned
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Kennedy</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hatch</ENAMEX>, who is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate Judiciary Committee</ENAMEX>, is
berated especially for going easy on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activist</ENAMEX>" judicial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominees</ENAMEX>.
Also, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Review</ENAMEX> continues its coverage of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bob</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dornan-Loretta Sanchez</ENAMEX> election controversy: An article suggests that there is
enough evidence of fraud (voting by illegal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX>, double voting) to merit new
balloting.

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 24 and March 3</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Feb. 18</TIMEX>)
            

            The
special issue on "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Crime and Punishment</ENAMEX>" contains more of the former than the
latter. An article on the roots of violence argues that nearly all violent
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have brain damage--often caused by childhood abuse--that makes them
incapable of controlling their rage, and reprises liberal ideas about crime's
environmental causes. An article <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lionizes</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Maple</ENAMEX>, the eccentric <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cop</ENAMEX> who
devised <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>'s crime-tracking program. He is credited with much of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s crime drop. A story explores a new phenomenon of urban <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">juries</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Black</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women jurors</ENAMEX> are causing mistrials by refusing to convict black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> despite
overwhelming evidence of guilt. As for "punishment," a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">convict</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>
describes the deterioration of prison conditions.

            

               --Compiled by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Plotz</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> .
            

         
      
   
