
   
   
      
         
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 29</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, March 29</TIMEX>)
            

            A <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX>-page
survey hails <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Silicon Valley</ENAMEX> as the model for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21 st century</TIMEX>
capitalism. Its high-tech <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> display admirable flexibility, reward
merit, welcome new ideas, and abhor government regulation. Interesting detail:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Silicon Valley</ENAMEX>'s GDP is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$65 billion</NUMEX>, equal to that of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chile</ENAMEX>. The cover
story compares various international education test scores and concludes
that teaching methods--not funding, class size, or culture--determine student
performance. The story also favors national and international education
standards: They give <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> targets to shoot for. An editorial and article
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">advise Netanyahu</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peres</ENAMEX> to form a coalition <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. Only a unified
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> can make real peace with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX>.

            

               
                  New 
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 14</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, March 29</TIMEX>)
            

            The
cover, given over to a long review of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> books about divorce, deplores the
growing popularity of the anti-divorce movement. Among the review's claims:
Divorce harms <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> less than "divorcephobes" claim; divorce rates rose in the
'60s because of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s economic independence, not because of selfish '60s
values; and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, where marriage has always been for love, is
naturally more divorce-prone than <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX> are. (See also <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dialogue</ENAMEX>" on divorce.) An article ridicules the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Recovery Channel</ENAMEX> ridicules the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Recovery</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Channel</ENAMEX>, a start-up cable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">venture</ENAMEX> that will feature drug <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">addicts</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alcoholics</ENAMEX>,
and overeaters <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24 hours a day</TIMEX>. It is "the logical terminus for a culture in
love with its own dysfunction." Also, a story criticizes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Boyden Gray</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gray</ENAMEX>, who has
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">berated Clinton</ENAMEX>'s fund-raising techniques, is himself a massive soft-money
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donor</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyist</ENAMEX> who exploits his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">insider</ENAMEX> ties.

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times Magazine</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 30</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 27</TIMEX>)
            

            
Free-speech <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Floyd Abrams</ENAMEX> denounces the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s
indifference to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">First Amendment</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has pushed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communications</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Decency Act</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">V-</ENAMEX>chip because he cares more about being "family friendly"
than about protecting free speech. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">For Slate</ENAMEX>'s take, see "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>
Turns <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yellow</ENAMEX>.") The cover story chronicles the making of a documentary film
about teen-age domestic violence: It takes the filmmakers to task for
exploiting their naive, vulnerable subjects. Also, an article about the
collapse of the go-go <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> art purchases of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '80s</TIMEX>: Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buyers</ENAMEX> have gone
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bankrupt</ENAMEX>, and their paintings have vanished into <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> bank <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">vaults</ENAMEX>.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News & World Report</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 31</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 25</TIMEX>)
            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Easter</ENAMEX> spirit is
contagious: A <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week after</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's heaven cover story, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX> counter with their own religious covers. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Mystery of Prayer</ENAMEX>" reports that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">87 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> believe God
answers their entreaties. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Theologians</ENAMEX> agree that prayer reinforces faith even
when God doesn't intercede. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX> offers a credulous cover story on near-death experiences (NDEs). <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">A third</NUMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who almost die report experiencing a spiritual vision. Skeptical doctors
assert that such NDEs are purely physiological (naval <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX> exposed to extreme
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gravity</ENAMEX> also have visions of bright lights and a God figure). A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sidebar</ENAMEX> argues that black holes and quarks are evidence of God's
"grand design" for the universe.

            Also in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , a
column on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Helsinki</ENAMEX> summit concludes that it was successful but barely
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">newsworthy</ENAMEX>, since <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> is so weak.

            Also in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX> , the defense
strategy in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma City</ENAMEX> trial: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McVeigh</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> will raise questions
about crime-lab incompetence, coerced government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX>, and the mysterious
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John Doe No. 2</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 31</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 25</TIMEX>)
            

            
               The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> wonders if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX> ' new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Fallows</ENAMEX>, can
rescue the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> from its current irrelevance. The answer: probably not.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fallows</ENAMEX> is depicted as too righteous for his own good, lacking the
"stop-the-presses adrenaline" needed for a successful newsmagazine. A long
profile of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Kennedy</ENAMEX> credits him with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> victory: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kennedy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">persuaded Clinton</ENAMEX> to emphasize liberal causes (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>, minimum wage) that
reassured his <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> base. The article finds <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Kennedy revitalized</ENAMEX>. And
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> argues that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> is struggling because it makes too
many super-expensive movies.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 31</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 25</TIMEX>)
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Airline</ENAMEX>
safety is on the cover. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> excerpts a new book by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Schiavo</ENAMEX>, the
former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspector general</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Transportation</ENAMEX> who had warned
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ValuJet</ENAMEX> was unsafe before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>'s crash. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schiavo</ENAMEX> tells horror stories:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> safety inspections are perfunctory, counterfeit parts are epidemic,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">air-traffic-control</ENAMEX> computers are outdated, and airport security is lax. She
advises <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> to avoid old <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX> and start-up <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airlines</ENAMEX>, and to sit near
emergency exits. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">The week</TIMEX>'s fund-raising scandal angle: To avoid oversight, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Committee</ENAMEX> instructed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX> to funnel contributions through
state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>. Also, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Doctors</ENAMEX> don't know what <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicines</ENAMEX> (and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dosages</ENAMEX>) to prescribe.

            

               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> 
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 31</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 25</TIMEX>)
            

            Echoing a
recent <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX> cover story, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Melts"</ENAMEX> argues that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> is on
his way out. His recent retreat from a tax cut and his embrace of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Jackson</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">infuriate conservatives</ENAMEX>: A back-bench challenge might be imminent. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter King</ENAMEX> writes a sidebar slamming <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> as the "most powerful
liberal in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> politics" for his opposition to tax cuts and his support of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Endowment for the Arts</ENAMEX>. Also, the Standard editorializes
against needle <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchange</ENAMEX>, saying there isn't sufficient evidence that it stops
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> transmission. "Government should not make itself a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">technician</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">heroin</ENAMEX> addiction."

            

               
                  The 
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nation</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 7</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 25</TIMEX>)
            

            
               The
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nation chronicles "A</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Year</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Corporate Crime</ENAMEX>." The list includes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADM</ENAMEX>'s price fixing, a
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billion-dollar</NUMEX> rip-off by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudential</ENAMEX>, defense<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">-contractor</ENAMEX> fraud, stock fraud,
and discrimination (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mitsubishi</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texaco</ENAMEX>). The point: Corporations are not good
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>. An article denounces the conservative claim that death-penalty
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">defendants</ENAMEX> are adequately represented. Most vivid detail: The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> for one
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> murder <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defendant</ENAMEX> slept through most of the trial. Also, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> (and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Nation stockholder</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paul</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newman</ENAMEX> writes an editorial mocking <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Helms</ENAMEX>.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harper</ENAMEX>'s , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 1997</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 20</TIMEX>)
            

            An
immensely long article condemns the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drug Enforcement Administration</ENAMEX>'s war on
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">poppy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">growers</ENAMEX>. Though <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poppies</ENAMEX> have legitimate commercial use (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">poppy-</ENAMEX>seed
bagels, for instance), the feds are paranoid that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gardeners</ENAMEX> will harvest them
for opium. The author grows his own opium <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poppies</ENAMEX>, and wonders if he's going to
be prosecuted. Also, a creepy explanation for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rwanda</ENAMEX> genocide: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judgment</ENAMEX>
Day" asserts that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rwandans</ENAMEX> are incredibly law-abiding, so when the government
ordered them to kill <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tutsis</ENAMEX>, they obeyed without a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> thought. The writer
visits <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rwanda</ENAMEX>'s awful <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prisons</ENAMEX>, where <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">92,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> await trial.

            

               --Compiled by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Plotz</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> .
            

         
      
   
