
   
   
      
         
            

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 17</TIMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 3</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 31</TIMEX>)
            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX> 's
cover story takes a skeptical look at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>'s
medical-marijuana initiative. Touring <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>'s "marijuana <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clubs</ENAMEX>" and head
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> notes the similarities between the medical-marijuana culture
and the recreational-marijuana culture: Many "medical" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> are stoners with
sham illnesses. The piece concludes that the medical-marijuana movement is a
back door to legalization. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> agrees that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Californian</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arizonan</ENAMEX> initiatives are far too squishy, but emphasizes that pot has some
medical benefits--particularly in increasing the appetite. In a sidebar, drug
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">czar Barry McCaffrey</ENAMEX> writes that more research is needed before medicinal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">marijuana</ENAMEX> can be legalized.

            Also in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNR</ENAMEX> , an article criticizes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> for his naive, outdated views
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and the Internet. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Net</ENAMEX> is no longer the vast electronic library
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> imagines; now it is a relentlessly commercial marketing tool,
hardly suitable for <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">classrooms</ENAMEX>. A story debunks the alleged links between
racism and black <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">illness</ENAMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> published a similar story more
than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two months ago</TIMEX>). And <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNR</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Peretz</ENAMEX>, who is famous for his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">paeans to Al Gore</ENAMEX>, tops himself, calling the veep "a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> rooted in the oldest idea
of our civilization."

            Also in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katharine Graham</ENAMEX> suck-up continues. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , which
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Graham</ENAMEX> owns, excerpts her autobiography at length, covering her major
episodes--<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s suicide, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Black</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White Ball</ENAMEX>.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 1</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 31</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
editorial, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Why Government Should Not Be Salesmen</ENAMEX>," opposes export
boosterism, calling it bad economics. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> sell a product overseas,
they almost inevitably subsidize the domestic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">producer</ENAMEX>; this subsidy subtracts
from the national economy. A long, related story lists the ways that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> hype exports (exchange-rate manipulation, subsidized <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">R&D</ENAMEX>, trade
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">missions</ENAMEX>, etc.), and bemoans their proliferation. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Economist</ENAMEX>
especially condemns the tactics of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Commerce Department</ENAMEX>. Also, an
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> criticizes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX>'s sloth, and says that computer simulations and
small early-stage clinical trials could speed the drug-approval process. And a
story tells how <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> expansion is irritating <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yeltsin & Co.</ENAMEX> may
retaliate by improving ties with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Korea</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times Magazine</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 2</TIMEX>
               
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 30</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
story on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Lott</ENAMEX> doubts that he can control the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>. The
majority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>, while conservative, cares more about passing bills than about
ideology. This willingness to accommodate will alienate the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ultraconservative</ENAMEX> "firebrands," who seek war against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>
over the balanced budget, abortion, and flag-burning. A sidebar profiles <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX>
such firebrands, including <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phil Gramm</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Brownback</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick Santorum</ENAMEX>. Also,
an article describes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>' experience of home schooling. Its
(unsurprising) conclusion: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Home</ENAMEX>-schooled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> probably learn more than
school-schooled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>, but they risk isolation and social discomfort.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 3</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 28</TIMEX>)
            

            Cute baby
on the cover. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fertile Minds"</ENAMEX> is sure to reinforce parental anxiety. Babies form
permanent synaptic connections very early, so <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> who are not properly
stimulated during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">their first year</TIMEX> can be scarred forever. A related article concludes that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> must
spend more money on early-childhood development to ensure that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX> are
sufficiently stimulated. Also, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> interviews <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Keating</ENAMEX>, whose <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S&L</ENAMEX> conviction (in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lance Ito</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>) was just overturned by a federal appeals <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keating</ENAMEX>, who still owes <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5.2 billion</NUMEX> in civil penalties, is largely
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">unrepentant</ENAMEX>. Speaking of civil penalties and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.J.</ENAMEX>, an article finds that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simpson</ENAMEX> has protected himself well:
Even if he loses the civil suit, he'll keep his <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2.5 million</NUMEX> retirement <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">fund</ENAMEX>,
his regular pension checks, and most of his future earnings.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News & World Report</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 3</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 28</TIMEX>)
            

            The
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> mutual-fund guide offers bad, if unsurprising, news: The market can't
sustain its irrational high. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX> ' advice: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dump</ENAMEX> index funds and buy
specialty funds. Real-estate funds and financial-stock funds are
good bets. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> picks the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">250 best</TIMEX>
funds "for the long haul" and ranks the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> biggest stock funds (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanguard</ENAMEX>
Index had <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the best three-year</TIMEX> performance). Also, a package of
stories contrasts the inauguration's pomp with the urban decay of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 3</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 28</TIMEX>)
            

            A profile
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Major</ENAMEX> depicts him as colorless and competent. Even though <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> is
prospering, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Major</ENAMEX> will lose the next election because he can't resolve the
question--or rather "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Question"</ENAMEX>--of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>. Most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tories</ENAMEX> loathe the European
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Major</ENAMEX> has alienated them with his ambivalence toward it. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Louis</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates Jr.</ENAMEX> contrasts highbrow black <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">theater</ENAMEX> with the "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chitlin Circuit</ENAMEX>." The
circuit's <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">crude</ENAMEX> plays make "Good Times look like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Strindberg</ENAMEX>," but they
make money and draw huge black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audiences</ENAMEX> (highbrow black <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">theater</ENAMEX> does neither).
An article details how the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> "marketed the prestige and glamour of
the presidency" to collect contributions: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Terry McAuliffe</ENAMEX> concocted the
dollars-for-access scheme, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> eagerly cooperated. Also, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Updike</ENAMEX>
writes a self-indulgent essay about his books: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Somewhere</ENAMEX> in their several
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX> pondered, proofread, printed words I must have done my best, sung my
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">song</ENAMEX>, had my say."

            

               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 3</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 28</TIMEX>)
            

            "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Road</ENAMEX>
from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hebron</ENAMEX>" applauds <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin Netanyahu</ENAMEX> for the recent peace agreement. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">accord</ENAMEX> may finally compel the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX> to live up to their part of the
bargain. It has also averted a potential <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> civil war. An article blasts
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> for standing by while <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> demolishes democracy and free
speech in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>. Also, yet another editorial praises the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">California Civil</ENAMEX>
Rights Initiative. And a story makes fun of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s inaugural address:
"Nothing big ever came from someone so small."

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harper</ENAMEX>'s , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 1997</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Jan. 25</TIMEX>)
            

            A long
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> investigates <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Executive Outcomes</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">South African</ENAMEX> mercenaries
hired to keep order in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sierra Leone</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> is ambivalent. On the one hand,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EO</ENAMEX> has pacified the land and ended a bloody civil war. On the other, it works
for greedy diamond <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX>, supports a brutal military <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX>, and employs
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Africa</ENAMEX>'s most vicious ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX>. The article predicts that private
armies such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EO</ENAMEX> will become increasingly common. Also, an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">essayist</ENAMEX> deplores
his own investments in global <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mutual funds</ENAMEX>: His money helps repressive
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> and exploitative foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> (But you can't beat the profits,
he admits). And a funny critique of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DSM</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">IV</ENAMEX>, the standard manual of mental
disorders: The manual classifies everything--from bad handwriting to snobbery
to clumsiness--as a mental illness.

            

               --Compiled by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Plotz</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> .
            

         
      
   
