
   
   
      
         
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 14</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, June 14</TIMEX>)
            

            Last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX> declared that <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX> is "dying." <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This week</TIMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> says that it is "emerging." The cheerful cover story and
editorial observe that economies are growing across <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">sub-Saharan Africa</ENAMEX>, commend
the tough fiscal and free-market policies of new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>, and urge the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> to lift tariffs on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> exports. There's a bit of bad
news, too. An essay by development-economics <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guru</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeffrey Sachs</ENAMEX> rates the
importance of geography and climate to economic growth: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tropical</ENAMEX> regions (e.g.,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Africa</ENAMEX>) are enormously handicapped by their high rates of infectious disease
and their low soil fertility. An <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX>-page survey predicts the globalization of
the defense industry. Only international megacontractors such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boeing</ENAMEX> have
the economies of scale necessary to build expensive high-tech <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX>. It also
notes that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s defense industry is more primitive than recent publicity
suggests.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity Fair</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 1997</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, June 14</TIMEX>)
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fair</ENAMEX> indicates that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>'s campaign-fund-raising hearings could be
the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '90s</TIMEX> if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred Thompson</ENAMEX> can forge a bipartisan
consensus for a deep investigation. But so far, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> aren't
cooperating and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> have been ham-handed. (Full disclosure: the
piece is co-authored by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Weisberg</ENAMEX>.) Yet another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VF</ENAMEX> article
about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rupert Murdoch</ENAMEX>: It handicaps the race to succeed him.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Twenty-five-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lachlan</ENAMEX>, who ranks highest in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Corp.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire</ENAMEX>,
is the favorite. But older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elisabeth</ENAMEX> is tough and smart, and younger
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">son James</ENAMEX> is the boldest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thinker</ENAMEX>. The cover story gushes about gay divorcée
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>: She's freer, happier, and more devoted to charity than she was as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Princess</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wales</ENAMEX>. And she still wears great clothes.

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 30</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, June 13</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
story lauds <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half a dozen</NUMEX> big-city <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayors</ENAMEX> as the potential saviors of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
politics. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudolph Giuliani</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Riordan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Daley</ENAMEX>, and other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayors</ENAMEX> are championing efficient <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and free
enterprise while opposing identity politics and income redistribution. These
"new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Progressives</ENAMEX>," who are simultaneously liberal and conservative,
could inspire a new centrist political <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">coalition</ENAMEX>. The "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">TRB"</ENAMEX> column parodies the truth-stretching <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Reich</ENAMEX>, imagining
him as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter Mitty</ENAMEX>. (See <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Reich</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quote Doctor</ENAMEX>.") A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> travels to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baghdad</ENAMEX> and finds Iraqis despairing:
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Food</ENAMEX> and jobs are scarce, travel is impossible, and internal security is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">overbearing</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times Magazine</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 15</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, June 12</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
story credits <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> with improving their response to medical errors.
Instead of finding scapegoats, they now encourage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurses</ENAMEX> to admit
mistakes (no punishment attached) in order to prevent future ones. Problem:
Malpractice <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> profit when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> confess error. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> profiles
the high-achieving <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emanuel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX>: presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adviser</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rahm</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX>
Ari, and medical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ethicist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zeke</ENAMEX>. A competitive, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectual upbringing</ENAMEX> made
them obnoxious, passionate, smart, and fabulously successful. Also, a pair of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> articles. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> deplores "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Microspeak</ENAMEX>," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s hideous,
responsibility-avoiding euphemisms: A bug, for example, is a "known issue." The
other story suggests that the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MSNBC</ENAMEX> may represent a sea change
in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> politics. Their anti-government, anti-politics libertarianism could
be the ideology of the future. Too bad no one's watching them.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wired</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 1997</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, June 12</TIMEX>)
            

            Highly
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Panglossian</ENAMEX>. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Long Boom</ENAMEX>" projects <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25 years</TIMEX> of global economic
prosperity. Thanks to free markets and (of course) high technology,
productivity will increase, environmental degradation will decrease, genetic
diseases will be eradicated, and a worldwide, multicultural civilization will
flourish. Possible <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">obstacles</ENAMEX>: a plague, an ecological crisis, a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> war.
The piece includes a "world history" chart for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years 1980-2020</TIMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Immigrants</ENAMEX>
drive revival of family" in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2014-16</TIMEX>. "<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">First</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designer kid</ENAMEX>" in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2020</TIMEX>.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 16</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, June 10</TIMEX>)
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> publish identical cover headlines--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Should He Die?</ENAMEX>"--and nearly identical stories about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Timothy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McVeigh</ENAMEX>. Both say that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> is eager for revenge and note that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McVeigh</ENAMEX> is
the ideal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> for execution--remorseless, intelligent, well defended,
white. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bud Welch</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> of an <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma City</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX>, writes columns in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> about why he opposes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McVeigh</ENAMEX>'s
execution. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> argues that the death penalty doesn't seem to deter crime,
doesn't comfort <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>, and is racially skewed. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> also has a
creepy photo feature about prison death <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">chambers</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's package of
stories on the military-and-adultery mess praises <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cohen</ENAMEX>'s effort to end the witch hunt, but faults him for defending <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ralston</ENAMEX> and not a lower-ranking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kelly Flinn</ENAMEX>--<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s poster girl
for the issue--writes a piece condemning this double standard: Why was she
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ostracized</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ralston</ENAMEX> helped? The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> profiles <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anson Chan</ENAMEX>, the
much-admired <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>'s civil service. She is the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">colony</ENAMEX>'s "canary in
a coal <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX>": If the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> stifle her, it will be a sure sign that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>
is in trouble.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">derides</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Gray</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Men Are From Mars</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Women</ENAMEX> Are From <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Venus</ENAMEX> , as an egomaniacal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">huckster</ENAMEX> who's making millions
selling banalities to vulnerable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couples</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News & World Report</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 16</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, June 10</TIMEX>)
            

            The death
penalty/<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McVeigh</ENAMEX> cover story also concludes that executions don't solace
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>. A piece accuses the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Japan External Trade Organization</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>-based
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> government <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>, of snooping on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JETRO</ENAMEX> is supposed to promote <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> exports to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>, but actually helps <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Japanese</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> acquire advanced <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> technology. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX> profiles a respected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">geologist</ENAMEX> whose computer models "prove" that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Biblical Flood</ENAMEX> occurred.

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 16</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, June 10</TIMEX>)
            

            

               The 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> chronicles the bitter fight over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kennewick Man</ENAMEX>, a
skeleton with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caucasoid</ENAMEX> features discovered recently in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. The
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9,000-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">skeleton</ENAMEX> is evidence that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Europeans</ENAMEX> arrived in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
before <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Native Americans</ENAMEX>, who migrated from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Native Americans</ENAMEX> insist that
the skeleton be reburied. The federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> has seized the bones and
forbidden further scientific examination. An article discusses the popular idea
of letting inner-city <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX> operate government welfare programs. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>
are keen on this, but the church-state questions are tricky. If the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX>
proselytize, they may violate the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">First Amendment</ENAMEX>. If they don't proselytize,
they may be ineffective.

            

               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 16</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, June 10</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
story worries that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Kasich</ENAMEX> is the future of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican Party</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Budget Committee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> is an eager beaver and a wonderful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX>, but he's
too narcissistic, too populist, and too willing to compromise with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>.
Also, the backlash against the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX> backlash. Contrary to a recent
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Magazine</ENAMEX> story, the independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> is not to
blame for the sluggish pace of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitewater</ENAMEX> investigation: Stonewalling by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">allies</ENAMEX> have impeded the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">probe</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nation</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 23</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, June 10</TIMEX>)
            

            Computer
databases make too much data available too easily, so the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> must
intervene to protect Internet privacy, argues the cover
story. A piece defends <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> rent control. (For more on rent
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX>, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s "Such a
Deal" and the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dialogue</ENAMEX>" it sparked.) Press reports wrongly suggest that
most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">beneficiaries</ENAMEX> of rent control are rich. In fact, it is mostly
working-class <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> who will be driven out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> if the controls are
lifted.

         
      
   
