
   
   
      
         
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 7</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, June 7</TIMEX>)
            

            The
cover story observes that public opinions in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Germany</ENAMEX>
are moving against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Monetary Union</ENAMEX>--in different directions. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">French</ENAMEX>
have backed a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> that favors loose interpretation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maastricht Treaty</ENAMEX>
criteria, while the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Germans</ENAMEX> have cheered for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bundesbank</ENAMEX>'s strict financial
bookkeeping. Nevertheless, the article predicts that an inclusive euro will be
launched on schedule, through fudging the original criteria. The editorial laments that the treaty's "misguided" fiscal targets
have harmed the "great opportunity that the single currency might have been"
and argues that they should be revised immediately. A killjoy article on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McVeigh</ENAMEX> trial says it doesn't really vindicate the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> judicial system,
because the proceedings were biased and conspiracy theories were not aired. An
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">admiring</ENAMEX> article on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>'s new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ehud Barak</ENAMEX>, speculates that
the besieged <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Likud</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is headed for more trouble and may turn to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barak</ENAMEX>
for support.

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 23</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, June 6</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
story by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Rauch</ENAMEX> warns that workplace-harassment law is destroying the
First <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Amendment</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Courts</ENAMEX> have equated discriminatory speech with discriminatory
action, causing lawsuit-shy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> to enforce "speech codes." Proposal:
Apply <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">First Amendment</ENAMEX> protection to workplace speech, even though there will be
some unrestrained bigotry. The editorial celebrates the "obtuse and suicidal"
choice of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">electorate</ENAMEX>, particularly because it will kill hope for a
common <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> currency. An article argues that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Timothy McVeigh</ENAMEX>'s view of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Constitution</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> may <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> and overthrow a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> that has exceeded its
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">authority</ENAMEX>--is consistent with the vision of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Founding Fathers</ENAMEX> (but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX>
forged a "new <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX>" based on "nationhood, equality and democracy"). And
an article explains how the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX> has adopted a radical-feminist view of
rape in order to survive in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '90s</TIMEX>.

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times Magazine</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 8</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, June 6</TIMEX>)
            

            A special
issue on "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">How the World Sees Us</ENAMEX>" asserts that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> has reached a
new level of cultural domination and asks whether the world is enjoying it.
Foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> respond. In the featured essay, a German
political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analyst</ENAMEX> announces the end of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX> anti-Americanism: <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Europeans</ENAMEX> who
used to hate obnoxious <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> (because of forced allegiance) now want to
imitate them (because they are relentlessly innovative). Some other responses:
A <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nigerian</ENAMEX> denounces "the shameless glorification of self-exposure," a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">French</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nanny</ENAMEX> complains that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are spoiled, and a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> observes that
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> are obsessed with their teeth (hence the cover). An accompanying
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">column</ENAMEX> frets that we are embarrassing ourselves by dumping the worst of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> culture ("<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rambo</ENAMEX>-esque violence and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>-esque sentimentality") on
foreign markets that enjoy having negative <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> stereotypes confirmed.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 9</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, June 3</TIMEX>)
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> makes
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's cover. The gist: The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">insurers</ENAMEX> want
him to settle the case, because no matter what the outcome, pretrial discovery
would be humiliating. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> contributor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX> urges
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to seek a fast trial and clear the air for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> campaign.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's feature argues that settling is trickier than it sounds: Can
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> acknowledge <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>' claim and not admit to any wrongdoing?

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's trend cover
story concludes that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Generation Xers</ENAMEX> are not slackers: They're
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">materialistic</ENAMEX>, ambitious, and entrepreneurial. The piece is accompanied by the
requisite sidebars about a go-getting movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>, a fabulously successful
cosmetics <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX>, and a hip young environmental <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activist</ENAMEX>.

            Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> write
skeptically about the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Torah codes</ENAMEX>" phenomenon, which claims that the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX>
contains encrypted messages prophesying events. (See <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cracking God</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Code</ENAMEX>.")

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> alleges that an <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">associate</ENAMEX> who owns a toxic-waste-disposal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> received a lucrative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Energy</ENAMEX> contract after making large
donations to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> campaign. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Golden Arches</ENAMEX> slump: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald's</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> is flagging, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> says, because <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> increasingly
favor tasty <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> over fast food. Also, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> publishes a special issue
devoted to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Visions</ENAMEX> , the TV show and book by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>'s
longtime <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">art critic</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Hughes</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News & World Report</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 9</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, June 3</TIMEX>)
            

            The
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> retirement guide offers the usual advice: Buy better mutual funds and
pay attention to your <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">401</TIMEX>(k). <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> piece declares that anyone can become a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">millionaire</ENAMEX> by investing
more, spending less, and buying used <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>. A long
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> describes a massive, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40-years</NUMEX>-in-the-making study of aging. Among
its findings: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> don't get crankier as they get older, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least half</NUMEX>
of senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> have no heart problems at all, and senility is not
inevitable. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX> ' Paula
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> scoop: Her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> have stashed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> copies of her affidavit about
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s "distinguishing characteristics" in hiding places around the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>.
A story notes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biologists</ENAMEX> have discovered <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of new mammal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past few years</TIMEX>, including a new <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">whale</ENAMEX> and a "giant barking
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">deer</ENAMEX>."

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 9</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, June 3</TIMEX>)
            

            The
magazine profiles <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nolanda Hill</ENAMEX>, who was business <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX>, best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> and, as
she reveals, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mistress</ENAMEX> of late <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commerce</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Brown</ENAMEX>. A brash <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Texan</ENAMEX> who
made a fortune buying TV <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX> is under federal investigation for her
business deals with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX>. Funniest tidbit: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX> loathed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
touchy-<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">feely Cabinet retreats</ENAMEX>, calling them "moongazing." An article rips
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrity doctor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Love</ENAMEX> for misleading <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> about estrogen and grossly
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">distorting</ENAMEX> (or misunderstanding) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Centers for Disease Control</ENAMEX> statistics. Love
advises middle-aged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> not to take estrogen, saying it raises breast-cancer
risk. In fact, estrogen therapy vastly reduces the risk of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">heart disease</ENAMEX> and
bone disabilities, while increasing that of cancer only minimally. Also, The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> publishes from the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">45-year</TIMEX> correspondence between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore Vidal</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louis Auchincloss</ENAMEX>.

            

               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 9</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, June 3</TIMEX>)
            

            Another
"what's wrong with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">conservatives</ENAMEX>" cover package blames the conservative
collapse in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> on the clever but vacuous
politics of the left. But not to worry: The left's victories are rear-guard
actions. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Conservatives</ENAMEX> are winning the intellectual war. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Editor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Kristol</ENAMEX>
bemoans the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Clintonization</ENAMEX>" of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Lott</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>, who have
replaced their old firmness with vague, pandering rhetoric. A piece criticizes
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">feminists</ENAMEX> for valorizing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilot Lt.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kelly Flinn</ENAMEX> and ignoring jilted
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">wife Gayla Zigo</ENAMEX>. Also, at long last, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> pans <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosie O'Donnell</ENAMEX> as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sycophant</ENAMEX> (in public) and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bully</ENAMEX> (in private).

         
      
   
