
   
   
      
         
            

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 21</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, April 4</TIMEX>)
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>
retains an unhealthy attachment to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mao</ENAMEX>, argues the cover story. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Helmsman</ENAMEX> is still widely revered; his crimes have been forgotten; and his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">muscular</ENAMEX>, anti-Western brand of nationalism is making a comeback. Also, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX>'s dilemma: Echoing a recent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> article, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNR</ENAMEX> claims
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> hasn't paid his <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$300,000</NUMEX> ethics fine because he fears his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>
might leave him if he uses their savings to clear the debt. If, on the other
hand, he pays the fine with campaign funds, the political backlash would almost
certainly cost him the speakership. In Heaven's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gate</ENAMEX> news, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> writes
sympathetically about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cult</ENAMEX>'s theology: "What is a cult but a collection of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">believers</ENAMEX>, like the early <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christians</ENAMEX>, who have not yet achieved dominant
status?" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">For Slate</ENAMEX>'s similar take, see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter Kirn</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Heaven Can't</ENAMEX>
Wait.")

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 5</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, April 4</TIMEX>)
            

            The
cover editorial regrets the collapse of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Republican revolution</ENAMEX>.
Fearful of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voter</ENAMEX> backlash, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> has become "a sad collection of drifters,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bickerers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> manqués ." With the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> going soft, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> will
retreat from necessary deficit-reduction and entitlement reform. A related
story says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX> was right to postpone tax cuts and does not
deserve the blame that's being heaped upon him.

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times Magazine</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 6</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, April 3</TIMEX>)
            

            The
opening feature in a special issue devoted to "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Store</ENAMEX>" asserts that the
retail <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> is thriving because shopping has become an event: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Places like</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Niketown</ENAMEX> and Borders have turned the humble <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> into an "entertainment
complex." A story bemoans the success of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gap</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pottery Barn</ENAMEX>, saying they
have afflicted the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> with an excess of bland good taste. A piece
describes how an outlet <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mall</ENAMEX> has transformed the sleepy <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manchester</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vt.</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founders</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Neiman-Marcus</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IKEA</ENAMEX>, and Virgin are interviewed. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Seven</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">contributors</ENAMEX> write short sketches about their favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX>.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News & World Report</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, April 1</TIMEX>)
            

            The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> newsmagazines
reconstruct the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Heaven's Gate</ENAMEX> suicide, trace the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cult</ENAMEX>'s history, and link it to
burgeoning New Age spiritualism. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's meaty package explains
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heaven</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Gate</ENAMEX>'s daft cosmology and catalogs <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s other doomsday sects.
(The weirdest is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Brotherhood</ENAMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oregon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cult</ENAMEX> that eats garbage.)
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> also hints that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX> Heaven's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>--the "ground
crew"--may be traveling through the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Southwest</ENAMEX>, waiting for a signal from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">spaceship</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> excerpts its own <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1979</TIMEX> article about cult leaders
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marshall Applewhite</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bonnie Lu Nettles</ENAMEX> (then "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bo</ENAMEX>" and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Peep"</ENAMEX>). A <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
News column describes the attractions of cults, and compares the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heaven</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Gate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">suicides</ENAMEX> to early <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">martyrs</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> agree that the Internet was an ineffective <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cult</ENAMEX>-recruiting tool,
and certainly not the cause of the suicides.

            Also, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> reports
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> fails to collect <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$150 billion</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> in owed taxes, largely
because its ancient computer system is too crude to catch frauds.

            Also in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , a
story (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Hillary Power</ENAMEX>") hooked to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">first lady</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX> trip claims that she
is making <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s rights a centerpiece of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> foreign policy.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
News examines the growing popularity of illegal
sports betting, which now tops <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$90 billion</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> (compared with <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2.5</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">billion</ENAMEX> in legal sports wagering). Cops have all but stopped enforcing
anti-gambling laws, while the rise of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Caribbean</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">casinos</ENAMEX> and Internet gambling
has made <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bookmaking</ENAMEX> easier than ever. An article investigates the exploitation of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, who are

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 7</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, April 1</TIMEX>)
            

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catholic Church</ENAMEX> must own up to its <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> guilt, argues "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Silence</ENAMEX>." While
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pope John Paul II</ENAMEX> has forged ties with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>, he refuses to acknowledge Pius
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">XII</ENAMEX>'s cooperation with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazis</ENAMEX>. The article blames the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX>'s nonapology on
the doctrine of papal infallibility, which shackles the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> to its sordid
past. Also, a story chronicles the discovery of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rock</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Next Big Thing</ENAMEX>, a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guitar</ENAMEX> phenom named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben Kweller</ENAMEX>. A story about the development of
HDTV contends that, contrary to laissez-faire dogma, government regulation can
help private industry make better products.

            

               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> 
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 7</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, April 1</TIMEX>)
            

            After a
brief hiatus, the Standard returns to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> bashing. The editorial
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">condemns Gore</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> trip for its "idiotic good cheer," and asserts that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> is "getting rolled by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX>" on human rights, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX>. An article says that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>, including <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Reps.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Armey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill</ENAMEX>
Paxon, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Kasich</ENAMEX>, might oppose renewing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">MFN</ENAMEX> status when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>
votes on it in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX>. The cover story, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Liar Liar</ENAMEX>," lists <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s evasions and
untruths about campaign fund raising. Among them: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> promise to ban
soft money; his claim that other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidents</ENAMEX> have used the same fund-raising
tactics; and his assertion that there was no quid pro quo for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX>.

            

               
                  The 
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nation</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 14</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, April 1</TIMEX>)
            

            
               The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nation</ENAMEX> inaugurates a series that will outline a set of "first principles"
for progressives. Judging by the opening article ("<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Progressive Compact"</ENAMEX>),
these principles will combine liberalism and communitarianism: "a right to a
job that pays a living wage--and an obligation to work ... a right to bargain
collectively--and an obligation to cooperate in the creation of more productive
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">workplaces</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul</ENAMEX>
Wellstone, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minn.</ENAMEX>, announces his nationwide crusade against poverty:
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> needs more funding for <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Head Start</ENAMEX>, health care, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WIC</ENAMEX>, and higher
wages for poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>, he writes. Also, a story
describes how the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">subcommittee</ENAMEX> on economic growth gave special access to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyists</ENAMEX> who contributed to the campaign of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McIntosh</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ind.</ENAMEX>

            

               
                  Rolling 
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stone</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 17</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, April 1</TIMEX>)
            

            The
magazine profiles <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bert Kreischer</ENAMEX>, the No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> partyer at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Florida State</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s
No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> party <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>. The article depicts debauchery of every kind, all involving
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> or both. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Editor/publisher</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jann Wenner</ENAMEX> co-writes an editorial
denouncing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> drug policy as "cruel, wrong, and unwinnable."

            

               --Compiled by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Plotz</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> .
            

         
      
   
