
   
   
      
         
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 28</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, June 28</TIMEX>)
            

            An
optimistic cover editorial says that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> may take over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>,
rather than vice versa. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> has inspired capitalism in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>--60 percent
of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> investment is routed through it--so perhaps it can inspire political
freedom there too. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> could serve as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s political "laboratory,"
proving that free elections and the rule of law are not destabilizing. A
related article speculates that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> is safe from
excessive <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> meddling: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> doesn't want to alienate <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX> or the
international <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tung Chee-hwa</ENAMEX> is making sound, relatively liberal
decisions. A story on the world environmental summit says that developed
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nations</ENAMEX> are breaking their promises to curtail <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">emissions</ENAMEX> of greenhouse <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gases</ENAMEX>.
And they can't agree on how to do better. A piece on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX> says there is a
teensy, tiny bit of hope that new economic laws will help unify the three
feuding ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 14 & 21</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, June 27</TIMEX>)
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNR</ENAMEX> finds a new angle on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>. The cover article, "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> Is in
Worse <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Trouble Than You Think</ENAMEX>," warns that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">colony</ENAMEX>'s "triad" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gangsters</ENAMEX> have
forged an alliance with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> will let the triads extort,
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">smuggle drugs</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX>, pander, and counterfeit. The triads, in turn, will
maintain order in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> and may act as the de facto secret <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX>. Several
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tycoons</ENAMEX> with ties to the triads and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> are investigated. Also, philosopher
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amartya Sen</ENAMEX> argues that the idea of "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> values"--collective identity,
absence of individual rights--is bunkum. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX>'s authoritarians are wrong:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freedom</ENAMEX>, tolerance, and respect for individual rights are integral to the
Confucian, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Buddhist</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hindu</ENAMEX> traditions.

            

               
                  New 
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">York</ENAMEX> 
                  Times 
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Magazine</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 29</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, June 26</TIMEX>)
            

            The diary
of a breast-cancer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> takes the cover. The piece's main themes: the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>'s fear that she won't be able to have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">anxiety</ENAMEX> about the
appearance of her breast, and gratitude toward her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and her cancer
support <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX>. After a lumpectomy and radiation, she has an excellent
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">prognosis</ENAMEX>. A story sings the praises of the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services Corp.</ENAMEX>,
describing how one of its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> has served a poor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Appalachian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> devotedly
for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25 years</TIMEX>. The message: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conservatives</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> should think twice before
defunding the program. A piece chronicles the struggles of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Firefly</ENAMEX>, a tiny
Internet startup: Its "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX>" software, an artificial-intelligence program that
helps <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> choose and buy online, may be the Net's next killer
application, but only if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> or another software <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">giant</ENAMEX> doesn't create a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">knockoff</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>. Also, an elderly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">widow</ENAMEX> writes about rekindling a sexual affair
with her first <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lover</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> she slept with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50 years ago</TIMEX>.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 30</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, June 24</TIMEX>)
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> runs its
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">seventh</NUMEX> health cover story of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX>. "How to <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Live to 100</ENAMEX>" advises exercise,
low-fat <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>, and perseverance. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Centenarians</ENAMEX>, it notes, are the fastest growing
segment of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>. A "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Longevity Test</ENAMEX>" lets you calculate your life
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">expectancy</ENAMEX> (e.g., add <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> if you're a happily married <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, and subtract
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> if you don't exercise), while a sidebar explains the many benefits and
few risks of estrogen therapy.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> puts the
cigarette deal on the cover. It describes the negotiations (extremely civil) and
the agreement. Anti-tobacco <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> fear that the industry will find a way to
evade regulation. Industry <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> fear they have given too much away. Cigarette
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">historian Richard Kluger</ENAMEX> praises the deal, saying that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> regulation of nicotine
content is a huge defeat for the industry. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's cigarette story
cautions that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> may spike the agreement: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Liberals</ENAMEX> think it's too soft on
the industry, while <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> think it's too harsh.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX>-page special report on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> reaches the same
conclusions as all the other special reports on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">colony</ENAMEX>'s
residents are optimistic; corruption and crime will seep in from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>; no one
knows whether <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> will quash political freedom. Accompanying articles
describe <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> is decrepit, polluted, and filled with
idle, state-owned <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factories</ENAMEX>; one is experimenting with private farming and
local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">democracy</ENAMEX>; one is bustling with capitalism. Also in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> , the
movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> pans <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> blockbusters for their similarly idiotic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">plots</ENAMEX>, brutality, and witlessness.

            Also in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , a package of articles cheers the capture of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pol Pot</ENAMEX>--"the last
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monster</ENAMEX> of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 th century</TIMEX>"--but notes that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambodia</ENAMEX> is still
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">corrupt</ENAMEX>, lawless, and scarred by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pol Pot</ENAMEX>'s genocide.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News & World Report</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 30</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, June 24</TIMEX>)
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Extreme</ENAMEX>"
sports are on the cover. Kayaking, sky diving, radical skiing, street lugeing, etc.,
are booming. The pop-psychology explanation: The elimination of risk in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX>
life has made <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> hungry for danger and excitement. Dramatic photos of
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice climbers</ENAMEX>, BASE <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jumpers</ENAMEX>, and sky-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">surfers</ENAMEX> accompany the article. A piece describes the moronic things <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX> do in national <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX>:
hike the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grand Canyon</ENAMEX> in high heels, run at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">midday</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Death Valley</ENAMEX>, dip their
hands in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F</ENAMEX> geothermic <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pools</ENAMEX>. An article says that both the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> tax plans favor
the rich too much, but that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> plan is much worse.

            

               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 30</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, June 24</TIMEX>)
            

            Another
cover package on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> crackup--the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this month</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the
cover pieces predicts that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX> will be ousted as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX> by the end
of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>: His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lieutenants</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Armey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Delay</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Boehner</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paxon</ENAMEX>) are abandoning him because he has betrayed them repeatedly. An article
contends that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s behavior toward <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> proves the failure of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
"constructive engagement" policy, which holds that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> will become more
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">democratic</ENAMEX> as it becomes more capitalistic: By gutting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joint Declaration</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> proves that it will never allow democracy to flourish, even if it
lets capitalism flourish. Also, the Standard apologizes to Deepak Chopra
for a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> cover story that called him a "huckster." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> retracts a
charge of plagiarism and an allegation that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chopra</ENAMEX> hired a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prostitute</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nation</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 7</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, June 24</TIMEX>)
            

            An
ambivalent cover story cheers <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Gephardt</ENAMEX>'s new commitment to old-time
liberal populism, but frets that he's a political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chameleon</ENAMEX> who has adopted
this cause for political reasons (i.e., the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> presidential campaign). It
also criticizes him for being a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">follower</ENAMEX>. An article warns that the growing
power of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Orthodox Jews</ENAMEX> will weaken <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American Jews</ENAMEX>' staunch support of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Orthodox Israeli Jews</ENAMEX> are alienating <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American Jews</ENAMEX> by refusing to recognize
them as <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
