
   
   
      
         
            

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times Magazine</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 8</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 6</TIMEX>)
            

            A
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-story package, headlined on the cover as "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">What Have the Ellwoods Done to</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>?" profiles health-policy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Ellwood</ENAMEX> and his son,
welfare-policy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Ellwood</ENAMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mugged by Reality</ENAMEX>" describes how Ellwood
fils , who popularized the idea of welfare time limits, saw his idea
"hijacked and brutalized" by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> story recounts the
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">disillusionment of Ellwood pere</ENAMEX> : Once <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s leading <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">champion</ENAMEX> of
managed care, he's increasingly horrified by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMOs</ENAMEX>' indifference to quality.
Also, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer wanders</ENAMEX> with the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">travelers</ENAMEX>"--<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>'s white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homeless</ENAMEX> street
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">punks</ENAMEX>--and finds them more pathetic than rebellious. And, an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">essayist</ENAMEX> argues
that the Internet is "a monument to idleness and wasted time," then explains
why that's good.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 9</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 3</TIMEX>)
            

            Here's a
surprise: The cover story about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> is almost pro-dope.
Targeting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby-boomer parents</ENAMEX> who smoked pot when they were young, the article
concedes that marijuana is less harmful than <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> then cops out by concluding that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> should not use a "dulling"
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX>: "The young don't need to have their pain dulled. They need to learn from
it." An accompanying article describes a rich <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> high
school where pot is epidemic and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> are confused; one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> moved into her
own <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> "after her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> forbade her to smoke marijuana at home." Also,
a long article examines how funeral-home <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chains</ENAMEX> are buying
up family mortuaries and gouging <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>. And a peculiar, rambling excerpt
from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pope</ENAMEX>'s forthcoming autobiography.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 9</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 3</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
story lionizes golfer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tiger Woods</ENAMEX>. Less a profile than a how-to guide for
raising a responsible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child prodigy</ENAMEX>, the article gives much credit to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woods</ENAMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>, who made him finish his homework before he could play <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">golf</ENAMEX>. A sidebar
considers <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prodigy flameouts</ENAMEX>, such as could-have-been <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NFL</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">superstar</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Todd</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marinovich</ENAMEX> and drug <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">casualty</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer Capriati</ENAMEX>. A story blames <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>
mess on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Ovitz</ENAMEX>. A related piece reports on the greedy Western firms
that--unlike <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>--have caved in to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s authoritarian demands. And
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> pokes fun at "post-sensitive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">males</ENAMEX>" (see: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Swingers</ENAMEX> ).
They're more desperate than macho.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News & World Report</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 9</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 3</TIMEX>)
            

            A
muckraking cover story investigates how the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> disposes of
surplus <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> (the short answer: badly). The article--a collaboration with
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">60 Minutes</ENAMEX> --finds that arms <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealers</ENAMEX> can easily purchase surplus bombs,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">encryption</ENAMEX> systems, attack <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">helicopters</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">stealth</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">fighter</ENAMEX> parts, etc., that
should have been destroyed. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> is the most eager <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customer</ENAMEX>, buying surplus
material through <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>-based scrap-metal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealers</ENAMEX>. The issue's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>
investment <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guide</ENAMEX> does not quite predict a bear market, but does suggest
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> "redeploy" out of stocks (in other words, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sell</ENAMEX>!"). Also,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX> notices the "little-noticed" white urban underclass. They're
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">disaffected</ENAMEX>, too.

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 16</TIMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly Standard</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 9</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 3</TIMEX>)
            

            So they do agree on
something, publishing nearly identical editorials about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> policy.
Both blast the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> for coddling <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> and ignoring its grotesque
human-rights violations. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> 's headline is "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kowtowing</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNR 's</ENAMEX> is "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sell Out</ENAMEX>."

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNR</ENAMEX> 's cover story wonders why the media ignored the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> scandals
during the campaign, and reaches familiar conclusions: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> pressure
silenced criticism; <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberal</ENAMEX>; press coverage is driven by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>; and so on. An article argues that "corporate welfare" is a lot
harder to find (and eliminate) than it seems. And "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">TRB</ENAMEX>" ridicules <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary of state candidates</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Holbrooke</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Mitchell</ENAMEX> as "archetypes of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Washington Male"</ENAMEX>--self-important,
humorless, and not as smart as they think.

            Also in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> : <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the holiday</TIMEX> book supplement. An article about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Claire Bloom</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Philip Roth</ENAMEX> celebrates literary revenge. A review criticizes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Samuel</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Huntington</ENAMEX> for not appreciating democracy. Another criticizes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Max Weber</ENAMEX> for not
understanding democracy.

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 9</TIMEX>
               
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 3</TIMEX>)
            

            An
adulatory feature about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woody Allen</ENAMEX> marvels at his hard work and resilience,
gives his side of the Soon-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yi</ENAMEX> story (her "presence is a reminder of life's
bounty"), and hypes his "radiant" new movie, Everyone Says I Love You .
His hapless schlub persona is revealed to be mere persona: He's actually full
of confidence. A dispatch from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.J.</ENAMEX> civil trial reports the defense
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX>' strategy to prove that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicole</ENAMEX> was obsessed with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.J.</ENAMEX>, not vice
versa. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">For Slate</ENAMEX>'s take, see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Shearer</ENAMEX>'s latest "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dispatch</ENAMEX>.") Also, an appreciation of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">planets: Thanks to the Mars</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rock</ENAMEX>, they're the hottest field in astronomy. And a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John Updike</ENAMEX> short
story.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 30</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 3</TIMEX>)
            

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> worries that a backlash against economic and political
reform is in the making in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Latin America</ENAMEX>. The technocratic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> that
replaced <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dictatorships</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central America</ENAMEX> have reduced inflation,
increased trade, and lowered deficits, but they have yet to deliver tangible
benefits to average <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>. Also, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> inaugurates a series that
will examine <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> (other than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>) that dominate high-tech industries.
The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> story considers chip-maker <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intel</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> predicts that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intel</ENAMEX> will continue to be profitable, but advises that it take more risks.

            
               --Compiled by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plotz</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> .
            

         
      
   
