
   
   
      
         
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 8</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Feb. 8</TIMEX>)
            

            The
cover story deplores the "outrageous" sums spent on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
elections, which are more expensive than any <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s but <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>'s. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> should consider campaign-spending caps and give the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Election</ENAMEX>
Commission teeth to enforce campaign laws, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> writes. The
accompanying editorial scoffs at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">First Amendment</ENAMEX> claim that
campaign spending is speech ("ridiculous") and suggests that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
ban political television ads. Also, several <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russia</ENAMEX> articles. One
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">applauds Al Gore</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chernomyrdin</ENAMEX>'s frequent, unpublicized
summits, which have resulted in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">150</NUMEX> small agreements on critical issues such as
nuclear-weapons disposal. Another says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander Lebed</ENAMEX> would win a new
presidential election if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> died (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lebed</ENAMEX> is still keeping <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">thugs</ENAMEX>, warns the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>). And an article claims that while <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> is more
socially and residentially integrated than the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minorities</ENAMEX> have
fewer economic opportunities there.

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 24</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, Feb. 7</TIMEX>)
            

            Last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">month</TIMEX>, the Standard wondered whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> belong in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX>. Now
it's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNR</ENAMEX> 's turn. The cover story, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sex and the Soldier</ENAMEX>," is less polemical than the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> 's article, but agrees that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> are too weak for many military
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">jobs</ENAMEX>, and that pregnancy disrupts training and deployment. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNR</ENAMEX> also
argues that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX> is overdoing gender integration in order to placate
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilian politicians</ENAMEX> (namely: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Schroeder</ENAMEX>). An article claims that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
"sandbagged" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Jackson</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995 and 1996</TIMEX> to prevent a primary challenge: The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> courted black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayors</ENAMEX>, refused a budget deal with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>, and
steered funding to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Jackson Jr.</ENAMEX>'s congressional campaign in order to
forestall a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson Sr.</ENAMEX> presidential run. Also, a story argues that the
much-touted <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Religious Freedom Restoration Act</ENAMEX> is unconstitutional (its
excellent headline: "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Anti</ENAMEX>-antidisestablishmentarianism").

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity Fair</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 1997</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, Feb. 7</TIMEX>)
            

            A profile
lionizes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tycoon</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Jewish Congress</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edgar Bronfman Sr.</ENAMEX> for his
campaign to recover <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>' savings from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Swiss</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bronfman</ENAMEX>, whom
some consider the "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pope</ENAMEX>," is portrayed as a relentless crusader who
single-handedly "unhinged" <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Switzerland</ENAMEX>. Like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> (see below), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fair</ENAMEX> investigates the truly weird saga of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madalyn Murray O'Hair</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s
most notorious atheist. After <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30 years</TIMEX> as a troublemaker, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bully</ENAMEX>, and media
hound, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O'Hair</ENAMEX> vanished in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late 1995</TIMEX> along with her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> and granddaughter. About
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$700,000</NUMEX> of her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundation</ENAMEX>'s money, stashed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Zealand</ENAMEX>, also seems to have
disappeared. The author claims <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O'Hair</ENAMEX> is lying low in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Zealand</ENAMEX>; others think
she's dead; God has no comment. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VF</ENAMEX> pays tribute (for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX> pages<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>!) to
"swinging" <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>, which has recaptured <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">its 1960s</TIMEX> hipness: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oasis</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blur</ENAMEX> are
much admired; so is fashion enfant terrible <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander McQueen</ENAMEX>. Also,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> is panned: "familiar names like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Queenan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katha Pollitt</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wendy</ENAMEX>
Kaminer, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louis Menand</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Berman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicholas Lemann</ENAMEX>--all-purpose oxygen
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">depleters</ENAMEX> who wash up everywhere." (<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Articles</ENAMEX> by all these oxygen depleters are
available in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Compost</ENAMEX>.")

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times Magazine</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 9</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, Feb. 6</TIMEX>)
            

            Why has
crime plummeted in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>? The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-story cover package credits the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX>. A profile of a rookie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cop</ENAMEX> says police work is improving because street
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> have been given more responsibility. It warns that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX>'s
proposed pay freeze could destroy the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYPD</ENAMEX>'s new esprit de corps. A sidebar
attributes the decline to "quality-of-life" policing and a crime-tracking
program called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">COMPSTAT</ENAMEX>. An article celebrates the return to favor of jazz
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pianist Keith Jarrett</ENAMEX>, whose sharp tongue is nearly as famous as his music (he
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">disses Wynton Marsalis</ENAMEX> as a "talented high-school trumpet <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX>"). And a
bizarre photo essay depicts a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> who have worn matching outfits
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last 17 years</TIMEX>.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 10</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Feb. 4</TIMEX>)
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> has more <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX>
Wars hype on the cover. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Force</ENAMEX> Is Back" rehashes recent articles in The

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , concluding that the movie is mythic and
wholesome but made <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> care more about special effects than about acting.
Only new tidbit: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> locates the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">almost</NUMEX>-forgotten <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Hamill</ENAMEX> (Luke
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Skywalker</ENAMEX>), who now stars in CD-ROM games. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> also chronicles the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madalyn Murray O'Hair</ENAMEX> saga (see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity Fair</ENAMEX> above).
And an article on the upcoming trial of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Timothy McVeigh</ENAMEX> says the defense will
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">emphasize FBI</ENAMEX>-lab incompetence and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX>' confusion over <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John Doe No. 2</ENAMEX>
(who the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> now says does not exist).

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's cover profile of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madeleine Albright</ENAMEX>
admires her charm, toughness, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PR</ENAMEX> skills. Its lone criticism: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albright</ENAMEX> has
no grand <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kissingerian</ENAMEX> vision. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> says that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albright</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX>-history
background will help her set <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX> policy, since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21 st -century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">East</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX> will resemble <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th -century Europe</ENAMEX>: rich, expanding, and
fractious. Also, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> describes the vicious debate about whether
there was life on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mars</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pro-life</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> (many at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASA</ENAMEX>) are ignoring
extensive evidence that casts doubt on their claims. And a gruesome story about
sexual molestation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Welsh</ENAMEX> reform <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News & World Report</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 10</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Feb. 4</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
story, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Business of Pornography</ENAMEX>," salutes the hard-working
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entrepreneurs</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> sex industry, who gross <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$8 billion</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>--more
than <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> does at the domestic box office. There are no salacious photos,
but amazing statistics abound: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producers</ENAMEX> churn out <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">150</NUMEX> new porn videos a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actresses</ENAMEX> earn <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$300</NUMEX> per sex scene and try to shoot <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a day</TIMEX>; an <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$8,000</NUMEX>
movie can net <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $200,000</NUMEX>. The article concludes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">porn</ENAMEX>'s popularity
would diminish if it were less illicit. Also, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harlem</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Next</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Renaissance</ENAMEX>" predicts an economic comeback for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> neighborhood:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Retailers</ENAMEX>, who have saturated the suburbs, are rushing to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Harlem</ENAMEX>, which is huge
(<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">520,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>), underserved, and surprisingly prosperous.

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 10</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Feb. 4</TIMEX>)
            

            Federal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Appeals Court</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> (and former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Diary</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alex Kozinski</ENAMEX> writes about how it feels to
deny a death-penalty appeal. A story examines the anti-government protests in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Serbia</ENAMEX>. While <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protestors</ENAMEX> do seek democracy, they are wildly nationalistic and
refuse to acknowledge <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Serbia</ENAMEX>'s responsibility for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX>'s destruction. An
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> chronicles the funny conflict between archaeologists and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Agers</ENAMEX> over
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sphinx</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Pyramids</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">New Agers</ENAMEX> want access to the monuments to test
their woolly theories about <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Atlantis</ENAMEX>, secret passageways, and undiscovered
ancient civilizations. The archaeologists despise the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Agers</ENAMEX>, but need their
money to fund research and preservation.

            

               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 10</TIMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Nation</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 17</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Feb. 4</TIMEX>)
            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">right-wing</ENAMEX> and left-wing
weeklies both criticize appeasement of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> 's target
is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>, while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Nation</ENAMEX> 's target is big
business. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> editorial urges the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> not to ratify an
extradition treaty with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nation</ENAMEX> article exposes how <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> are lobbying for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boeing</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AT&T</ENAMEX>, the Big Three
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">automakers</ENAMEX>, and other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">megacompanies</ENAMEX> have hired <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PR</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyists</ENAMEX> to
burnish <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s image on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol Hill</ENAMEX>, mostly in hopes of winning it permanent
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MFN</ENAMEX> status.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> cover
profile <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">anoints</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>) as a presidential prospect for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>. Why?
The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> has championed favorite conservative issues--welfare reform
and tort reform, to name <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>--and he's pushing a huge tax cut. He's also more
charismatic than his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>. Also, an article endorses the reigning view that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Lott</ENAMEX> is a compromiser, not an ideologue.

            
               The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nation</ENAMEX> , meanwhile, tries to save public education. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Eight</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> propose their remedies,
which include smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>, charter <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>, literacy programs, and--of
course--more money. Also, a story on how abortion is fracturing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">African</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Congress</ENAMEX>.

            

               --Compiled by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Plotz</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> .
            

         
      
   
