
   
   
      
         
            

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 10</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, May 10</TIMEX>)
            

            The
cover story and lead
editorial predict the automobile industry's collapse. Overcapacity will
benefit <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> as prices fall, but the world economy will shake as auto
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">makers</ENAMEX> go broke. Another editorial argues that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> should repeal laws
prohibiting foreign ownership of broadcast <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>. The reason: The Internet
has already made electronic media international. A <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> election <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">post-mortem</ENAMEX> predicts a bloody internecine fight over the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tory</ENAMEX>
Party's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 26</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 9</TIMEX>)
            

            "The
Selling <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">of Dr. Death</ENAMEX>" details how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Kevorkian</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">publicist</ENAMEX> have
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">masked Kevorkian</ENAMEX>'s most horrific exploits. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kevorkian</ENAMEX> has helped numerous people
without physical illness commit suicide, but compliant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> haven't
reported this. Singled out for blame is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> , whose
Kevorkian <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> also writes op-eds praising the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>. A piece says that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ralph</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reed</ENAMEX> picked the right time to ditch the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian Coalition</ENAMEX>: An FEC
investigation, falling membership, and disillusionment with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reed</ENAMEX>'s pragmatism
are undermining its power. The editorial deplores the balanced-budget agreement
for not cutting entitlements. It "postpones [the] day of reckoning."

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity Fair</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 1997</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 9</TIMEX>)
            

            Software
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">upstart Oracle</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Ellison</ENAMEX> is profiled. He comes across as a
superannuated adolescent: hypermacho, sexist, and desperate for attention (but
brilliant). His quest to defeat <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> (see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> below) is portrayed
as an unhealthy obsession. A long article chronicles the turmoil at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC News</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Westin</ENAMEX> has been anointed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roone Arledge</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">successor</ENAMEX> as head of the news
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">division</ENAMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arledge</ENAMEX> seems reluctant to cede his power. The legendary <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arledge</ENAMEX>
is depicted as detached, lazy, and old. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arnold Schwarzenegger</ENAMEX> is on the cover.
Why? Because he's turning <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX>.

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times Magazine</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 11</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 8</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> recounts <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vaclav Havel</ENAMEX>'s many troubles, but concludes that he is still
the world's "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX> of democracy." In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past two years</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Czech</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> has
been widowed, lost a lung to <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">illness</ENAMEX>, married an unpopular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX>, engaged in
a nasty real-estate feud with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>, and watched rival <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>
demolish his vision of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Czech</ENAMEX> society. Even so, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Czechs</ENAMEX> still revere <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Havel</ENAMEX> as
their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">philosopher-king</ENAMEX>. A story describes how <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX>'s left-wing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> still demonize <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>: This civic opposition dooms any chance
of real peace between the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX>. Also, a spooky photo of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TWA</ENAMEX> Flight 800's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">reconstructed</ENAMEX> remains, which have been pieced together in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> airplane
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hangar</ENAMEX>.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News & World Report</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 12</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 6</TIMEX>)
            

            Guilt-inducing cover stories
accuse <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> of shortchanging their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> by working too hard. (Both
stories are pegged to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arlie Hochschild</ENAMEX>'s new book, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Time Bind: When Work</ENAMEX>
Becomes <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Home and Home Becomes Work</ENAMEX> , which argues that home and work have
changed places: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Home</ENAMEX> is now stressful; work is now relaxing. See <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s
review.) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Myth of Quality Time</ENAMEX>" says that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> need more
sustained, structured attention than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workaholic parents</ENAMEX> give them. It notes
that few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> take advantage of "family friendly" corporate policies.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX> ' "Lies
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Parents</ENAMEX> Tell <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Themselves About Why They Work</ENAMEX>" is harsher, berating parents
for sacrificing their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> to their jobs. It argues that most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> don't
need <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> incomes, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that day</TIMEX> care is a lousy substitute for parental care.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Parents</ENAMEX>, especially <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fathers</ENAMEX>, ignore family friendly policies because they don't
want to hurt their careers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> credits <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tony</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blair</ENAMEX>'s election victory to a tightly run campaign, self-destructing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tories</ENAMEX>,
and an endorsement by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rupert Murdoch</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3.9 million</NUMEX> circulation <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tabloid</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX> . An article on the elimination of affirmative action at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Texas Law School</ENAMEX> notes that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 3 percent</NUMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s
admitted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> are black and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic</ENAMEX>, down from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">more than 12 percent</NUMEX> last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> previews the
summer blockbusters: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Lost World , Men in Black</ENAMEX> , and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hercules</ENAMEX> should do well; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Titanic</ENAMEX> may sink.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
News reveals that, since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Waco</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> has been cooperating with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">militia</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> to defuse confrontations with anti-government <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>
and militia <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> worked together during the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Republic of Texas</ENAMEX> and Freemen
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">standoffs</ENAMEX>.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 12</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 6</TIMEX>)
            

            The
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> consecutive medical cover. The profile of hirsute New Age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physician</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Weil</ENAMEX>
criticizes his anecdotal approach to bee-venom therapy, acupuncture, and the
like, but concludes that most of his recommendations--low-fat diet, exercise,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vitamins</ENAMEX>--are medically sound. The article recounts <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weil</ENAMEX>'s checkered history:
As a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX> undergraduate, he exposed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Timothy Leary</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSD</ENAMEX> experiments, but he
later did research concluding that marijuana is harmless. A story says that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Zairian</ENAMEX> rebel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Laurent Kabila</ENAMEX> may be a new
kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>: Like his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mentor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Ugandan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yoweri Museveni</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kabila</ENAMEX> seems to favor order and free markets (though not democracy). An
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oracle</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Ellison</ENAMEX> (a "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ninja warrior"</ENAMEX>)
claims that he represents the strongest challenge to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>. If his alliance
with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun Microsystems</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Netscape</ENAMEX> produces a cheap, simple network computer
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NC</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> could be in trouble.

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 12</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 6</TIMEX>)
            

            A long
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> predicts that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX>-installed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tung Chee</ENAMEX>-hwa will
model the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">colony</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Singapore</ENAMEX>: a commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire</ENAMEX> without political freedom.
It points out that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> record is hardly spotless: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>
suppressed democracy there until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '80s</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nathan Myhrvold</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> provocateur," is profiled. A paleontologist, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chef</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicist</ENAMEX>, and
software <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">programmer</ENAMEX> (not to mention <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Myhrvold</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX>'
"favorite geek," the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who sets <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s research priorities. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> asks, but does not answer, why <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Myhrvold</ENAMEX> almost overlooked
the importance of the Internet. An article marvels at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
administration's ennui: The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>-term <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> has no agenda, and entire
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">departments</ENAMEX> (notably the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX>) seem to be paralyzed.

            

               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 12</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 6</TIMEX>)
            

            The "No
Deal" cover package condemns the budget agreement because it raises spending on
domestic programs. The editorial urges <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> to "rebel"
against the deal. An article condemns the budget as soft on defense: It cuts
military spending to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 3 percent</NUMEX> of gross domestic product, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only half</NUMEX> its
<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX> level. A piece argues that the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Communications Decency Act</ENAMEX> should be
upheld even though it's an ineffective mess. The reason? It sends the right
message: that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> should be protected from "the spirit-destroying
coarseness of this culture." An article mocks the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Volunteerism Summit</ENAMEX> as an
event designed to make <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrities</ENAMEX> feel good about
themselves.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mother Jones</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 1997</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, April 29</TIMEX>)
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mother Jones</ENAMEX> catalogs
the top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">400</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contributors</ENAMEX> of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995-96</TIMEX> election
cycle. Topping the list is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bernard Schwartz</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> of the defense contractor
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Loral</ENAMEX>, who gave a total of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$661,000</NUMEX> to both parties. Other high rollers
include: publishing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tycoon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dirk Ziff</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 6</ENAMEX>), who gave <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$436,000</NUMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>
and slept in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Bedroom;</ENAMEX> oil <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baron</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Koch</ENAMEX> (No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>), who gave
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$339,000</NUMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Libertarians</ENAMEX> to advance his anti-regulation agenda;
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gail Zappa</ENAMEX> (No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">widow</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank</ENAMEX>, who gave <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$292,650</NUMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>; and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jobs</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 126</ENAMEX>), who gave <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$150,000</NUMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>. A sidebar raps <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fund-raiser</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Terry McAuliffe</ENAMEX> for his
aggressive tactics. Also, a surprisingly favorable article about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian Coalition</ENAMEX>'s campaign to recruit blacks
and help rebuild burned black <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX>: This seems to be a truly sincere effort
to atone for a history of white <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> racism.

            

               --Compiled by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Plotz</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> .
            

         
      
   
