
   
   
      
         
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 22</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, March 22</TIMEX>)
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hollywood</ENAMEX>
is in trouble, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oscar</ENAMEX><TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-week</TIMEX> cover
story. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Studios</ENAMEX> ought to reap huge profits, but don't because they overpay
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> and produce too many expensive films. (The average <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studio</ENAMEX> movie costs <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$60</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX> to make and market.) The good news for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>, according to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> : <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foreign</ENAMEX> movie <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">producers</ENAMEX> are even less business-savvy. An
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article on Zaire</ENAMEX> advises rebel <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laurent Kabila</ENAMEX> not to compromise with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mobutu Sese Seko</ENAMEX>, because any delay in toppling the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> will
damage the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> even more. (For a backgrounder on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Zaire</ENAMEX>, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Gist</ENAMEX>.") A
package of stories on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> election blames <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Major</ENAMEX>'s troubles on his
personal weakness, not his policies. Also, a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX>-page survey on management
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">consulting</ENAMEX> finds the industry vigorous, profitable, and a bit too
secretive.

            

               
                  New 
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 7</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 21</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
package takes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> to task, noting that congressional fund raising is as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">slimy</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> fund raising. Among the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outrages</ENAMEX> cited: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legislators</ENAMEX>
selling bills and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyists</ENAMEX> writing bills. Another article rips <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> for
its sluggish implementation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Congressional Accountability Act</ENAMEX>, the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>
law that was supposed to apply labor and civil-rights laws to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>.
Also, the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">TRB"</ENAMEX> column offers this campaign-finance scoop: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> will soon
ask the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Election Commission</ENAMEX> to pass regulations restricting "soft
money," accomplishing by executive action what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> refuse to do
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">legislatively</ENAMEX>. And a piece says that, despite the establishment of the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">billion</NUMEX> gold fund, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Swiss</ENAMEX> aren't at all sorry for their atrocious behavior
during <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War</ENAMEX> II.

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times Magazine</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 23</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 20</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
story compares <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nelson Mandela</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George Washington</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mandela</ENAMEX> suppresses his
emotions in favor of the common good, and this serene rationalism has allowed
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Africa</ENAMEX> to escape violence and recrimination. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Elders</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Ice</TIMEX>" observes the
twilight careers of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Rangers</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wayne Gretzky</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Messier</ENAMEX>: The
"greatest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> ever" and the "most-driven <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> ever" are past their prime,
but still know how to win. Also, the technology <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> dismisses Internet
"push"--in which content is delivered to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> rather than fetched
by them--as a silly, doomed trend. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">For Slate</ENAMEX>'s take, see "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Push Me</ENAMEX>, Pull
You.")

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harper</ENAMEX>'s , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 1997</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 20</TIMEX>)
            

            An
immensely long article condemns the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drug Enforcement Administration</ENAMEX>'s war on
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">poppy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">growers</ENAMEX>. Though <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poppies</ENAMEX> have legitimate commercial use (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">poppy-</ENAMEX>seed
bagels, for instance), the feds are paranoid that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gardeners</ENAMEX> will harvest them
for opium. The author grows his own opium <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poppies</ENAMEX>, and wonders if he's going to
be prosecuted. Also, a creepy explanation for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rwanda</ENAMEX> genocide: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judgment</ENAMEX>
Day" asserts that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rwandans</ENAMEX> are incredibly law-abiding, so when the government
ordered them to kill <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tutsis</ENAMEX>, they obeyed without a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> thought. The writer
visits <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rwanda</ENAMEX>'s awful <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prisons</ENAMEX>, where <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">92,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> await trial.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 24</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 18</TIMEX>)
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> looks to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">heavens</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> looks for heaven. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's cover package, "The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great Comet</ENAMEX>," celebrates <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hale-Bopp</ENAMEX>. A long article speculates about how ancient
Egyptians, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sumerians</ENAMEX> greeted the comet on its last visit in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2213</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B.C.</ENAMEX> (It was undoubtedly an important omen--of what, no one knows.) A related
story tells the when-and-where of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">comet</ENAMEX>'s flyby.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's cover asks,
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Does Heaven Exist?</ENAMEX>" Until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this century</TIMEX>, Christianity was
obsessed with describing heaven, but now "heaven is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AWOL</ENAMEX>." Most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clerics</ENAMEX> have stopped talking about it, because it's too controversial and too
hard to reconcile with modern science.

            Both
magazines cover the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Biggie Smalls</ENAMEX> murder and assert that gangsta rap has gone
too far. Also in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> : A profile of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Zairian</ENAMEX> rebel <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kabila</ENAMEX> predicts that he'll
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">topple Mobutu</ENAMEX>, but notes that he's only succeeding because <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Uganda</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rwanda</ENAMEX>
are helping him. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> presents the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s case against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Timothy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McVeigh</ENAMEX>, concluding that "it would have to be a very stubborn <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">juror</ENAMEX> indeed to
hold out in the face of the evidence."

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 24</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 18</TIMEX>)
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Unarmed</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warriors"</ENAMEX> describes the travails of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Committee</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Red</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cross</ENAMEX>. The traditional rules of war don't apply in places like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rwanda</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bosnia</ENAMEX>, where the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Red Cross</ENAMEX> can't persuade <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> to fight humanely. A
harrowing trip with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Red Cross</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX> is described. A long
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX>, pegged to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Godfather</ENAMEX> 's <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">25 th</NUMEX> anniversary, recounts
its filming in intricate detail. Also, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> proposes a grand unified theory
of stardom: Celebrityhood always lasts <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Letterman</ENAMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992-95</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1983-86</TIMEX>; etc.).

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News & World Report</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly Standard</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 24</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 18</TIMEX>)
            

            Race makes the covers.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX> ' cover
package, hooked to the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">50 th</NUMEX> anniversary of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackie Robinson</ENAMEX>'s
major-league debut, argues that sports are bad for black <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>. While only
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10,000</NUMEX> high-school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">athletes</ENAMEX> will ever play professionally, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">66 percent</NUMEX> of
black teen-age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> believe they could be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pros</ENAMEX>, and the resulting overemphasis
on sports has diverted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> from educational achievement. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX>
deplores black and white obsession with "white racism," arguing that it turns
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> into permanent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>. A related article savages the black newsmagazine
Emerge for its paranoid, anti-white style. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>'s popularity
among black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> is an alarming indication of how alienated the black
middle <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> is from mainstream white <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>.

            Also in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX> , a story asserts that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Polish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> is too rigid and too
technologically backward to integrate successfully into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity Fair</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 1997</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 18</TIMEX>)
            

            The
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> issue is endless (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">386</NUMEX> pages). An article about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Turner</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane Fonda</ENAMEX>'s marriage asserts that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fonda</ENAMEX> always dissolves herself in her male
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX>, whether he's a radical like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Hayden</ENAMEX> or a plutocrat like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Turner</ENAMEX>. A
movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> blames the decline of movie criticism on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pauline Kael</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">disciples</ENAMEX>
(among those implicated, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Edelstein</ENAMEX>). Also, much <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>
history: articles on the feud between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gossips</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louella Parsons</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hedda Hopper</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roman Polanski</ENAMEX>'s statutory rape of a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>, and the
shady activities of the now deceased <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fixer</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mob lawyer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sidney Korshak</ENAMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Ten</NUMEX> budding starlets adorn the cover. Zillions of celebrity photographs by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Annie Liebovitz</ENAMEX> are inside.

            

               --Compiled by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Plotz</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> .
            

         
      
   
