
 
     		
 	
 		golfer
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well yes i am as matter of fact not a good one but i am a golfer
 	
 	
 		well
 		well that's about the way i am i don't consider myself a good one but i do enjoy it
 	
 	
 		i uh haven't been out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all year</TIMEX> i didn't get out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> but uh i enjoy both watching it and playing it
 	
 	
 		i usually play a couple of times a month sometimes more but lately it's been just about that
 		but i do enjoy i think the one of the things i enjoy the most is the beauty of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">golf courses</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes and the the peacefulness
 	
 	
 		um-hum you can get out there
 	
 	
 		and the little critters that are around
 	
 	
 		yeah that's really neat you can just get out there and lose yourself in it and forget everything else in the world except what you're seeing out there
 	
 	
 		
 
 		that's right and it's such a personal challenge
 	
 	
 		um-hum yeah it really is
 	
 	
 		more than competitiveness against someone else it's it's a competitiveness against yourself
 	
 	
 		and you know it's so frustrating i keep wondering sometimes why do i do this because it's so frustrating you think you do pretty good <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> and you're doing a whole lot better you know and then all of a sudden you go back out and it's just terrible
 	
 	
 		well you'll
 	
 	
 		you can't do anything right you know
 	
 	
 		or you'll hear <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> and think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> i've got my game together i've had a par and a birdie and a bogey and then you quadruple bogey
 	
 	
 		boy i'm improving
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh and</ENAMEX> and you think my goodness why did i think i was doing better
 	
 	
 		being down there do you uh get to see like the colonial or any of those
 	
 	
 		i don't i guess i could i've never been to a <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">golf</ENAMEX> to a major golf tournament i uh watch them on TV a lot
 	
 	
 		oh
 		you really should go at least once you know we've had uh the PGA up here uh and and in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tulsa</ENAMEX> and i've been to both of them and it's
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it is so much fun to see these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> you see on TV to and to hear that ball go whizzing by
 	
 	
 		really
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i mean it's it's like a bullet going by
 	
 	
 		i'll bet
 		um
 	
 	
 		and you know to to see their concentration and yet to see them how friendly they are when they're they walk by you you know and and how good they are to their spectators
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well i've only been playing like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about three years</TIMEX> now my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s played for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty five</TIMEX> but i just took it up <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about three years ago</TIMEX> and uh
 		we play in a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX>'s scramble tournaments we belong to a country <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX> a little ways outside of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 		and we have developed a tremendous number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couples</ENAMEX> do this and you know it's fun to go on vacations and things and go to golf courses
 	
 	
 		both
 		yes
 		yes it is and i
 	
 	
 		you can meet some really neat people
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scrambles</ENAMEX> are fun
 	
 	
 		um-hum they really are i just love them
 	
 	
 		i belong to the country <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">club</ENAMEX> there in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El Reno</ENAMEX> when i lived there and it you know it it's fun because it's so uncompetitive
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you really on those you really go out for fun
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		and you know you won't you know you're stroke is just one of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one or two or three or four</TIMEX> you know that's going to make any difference and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		that's right and you can just do your own thing and be relaxed and enjoy it
 	
 	
 		that's right i used to when i worked at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kerr McGee</ENAMEX> i used to play in their tournaments
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		and uh now that was very competitive
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		and i enjoyed it tremendously
 		but uh i i'm more i think i get more enjoyment just <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple friends</ENAMEX> going out and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and if if it takes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of us <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> shots to get up to the green so be it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know we just think well the next time's got to be better
 	
 	
 		yeah i have never played in any tournament except just a scramble they have a lot of them there at the club you know they have A B C D type tournaments and then they
 		they have the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX> championships and everything with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s slots as well but i don't know i've just never really gotten into that now my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> i mean they love the real competitiveness of playing for money you know
 	
 	
 		oh yes every hole
 	
 	
 		uh-huh but i i'm not good enough for that
 	
 	
 		does your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX> have a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>'s association
 	
 	
 		yes they do i don't do much with it since uh most of theirs they have a traveling league
 		and uh most of their meetings and all are during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX> and i don't don't get to play except on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX>
 		i work during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX> all time
 	
 	
 		it's hard to be a weekend golfer and improve your game
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		someday when i i get where i live closer to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX> and partially retired maybe i'll uh be able to play a little more
 		but
 	
 	
 		it uh it's it's a it's a good game i uh
 		i wish i had more time to play and i felt you know had more energy to play it too
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	