
 
     		
 	
 		ah so <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beverly</ENAMEX> what do you think about drug testing
 	
 	
 		i think in some professions it's uh essential things like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX> and things that involve the safety of other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> particularly
 	
 	
 		yeah we've we got a lot of mistakes here uh in no <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland Baltimore</ENAMEX> area because of um
 		train conductors uh on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> i think we've had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> terrible accidents here recently and also on um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		just like i bet you within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five days</TIMEX> a truck  where the uh a dump truck where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX> was uh high on marijuana i guess he smoked marijuana for lunch and uh
 		drove his truck up the back of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> small <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tunnel</ENAMEX> that goes underneath the uh a river that leads into the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chesapeake Bay</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh my goodness
 	
 	
 		and it would that would tried up traffic for a long time everybody died the fire was terrible it was awful
 		so i yeah i think you're right i i think i if if if it's if you're in a field but then you know who would test all <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they  that's that is a problem and every time before they get into a vehicle
 	
 	
 		you know
 		right yeah i think i think at looking at <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">athletes</ENAMEX> being drug tested
 	
 	
 		i mean
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i don't know even i think the random drug testing i don't know in my own mind if it has reduced the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">athletes</ENAMEX> from taking <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> because they're still being caught does that make sense um
 	
 	
 		right
 		yes  it may make a difference for some of them
 	
 	
 		yeah and then uh i think
 	
 	
 		because they don't want to lose that lucrative uh career
 	
 	
 		yeah i i i think in the long run i think it's it would be good i think in the short run they think because so many of those tested have gotten away with it you know the the test hasn't come down hard on anyone i don't i don't know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 		um-hum however here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> uh we had a a player <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roy Tarpley</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mavericks</ENAMEX> team
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and he had been suspended a couple of times because of drug testing and was to the point he is on probation
 		it's to the point that if he was caught another time that he would lose his contract and they wouldn't have to pay him and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mavericks</ENAMEX> wanted to get rid of him but they couldn't afford to replace him and still pay his contract
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and uh just recently he was uh
 		missing from practice and whenever he missed like that usually he had some kind of problem and so a mandatory drug test was done was positive so they were able to get rid of him and not have to pay his contract
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		get rid of him
 		right yeah but
 	
 	
 		and so in his case he lost his whole career he's been in the paper in jail and it's just been awful and  talk about a terrible role model
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right i i think that that that's a terrible thing you know  it's really funny though um i guess my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> was hit by a a drunk <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX> who was also high um when i was probably eighteen my senior year in high school
 	
 	
 		um
 		oh my goodness
 	
 	
 		and um  though he's alive <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> and everything worked out fine it it it happened <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about two</NUMEX> blocks from the high school and
 		a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> came and got me and i was there and i could smell the dope and i could see the beer cans from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> that hit him
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and nothing ever happened and from from that point on i became so anti-drunk driving you know now i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> should be allowed to drink i think that's an adult responsibility whatever
 	
 	
 		oh that's terrible
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i really uh i'm so anti-drunk driving and and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> have uh long lasting effects and i i guess when i younger i was um  probably a little more liberal on the subject
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		i think most of us are
 	
 	
 		yeah and but as i've as as as soon as that happened i guess when i was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eighteen years old</TIMEX> if you'd have asked me i'd have thought it was fine but it by the time i was nineteen my opinion had totally changed yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yes if you know someone for example we have uh some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> whose son was driving <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> from work was hit <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> on by a drunk <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX> the drunk and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> were killed
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bobby</ENAMEX> missed his whole junior year of high school
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		he went through surgery after surgery and for a long time they didn't even know whether he'd be normal again and he as far as his athletics athletics he's lost all of that
 	
 	
 		hm traction and all that terrible stuff
 		right
 	
 	
 		he uh has been tutored and he'll catch up in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and everything but he's still not back where he was he may never have all those motor skills back
 	
 	
 		right yeah i don't think somebody
 		yeah you don't you don't you don't have the right to interfere in somebody else's life i can't even say you know i wouldn't even say ruin somebody's life you don't have the right to interfere in somebody's life
 	
 	
 		no
 		another thing that we saw here recently one of some of our high school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> were out goofing around in a park area that a a train <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">track</ENAMEX> ran through
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> who had been drinking decided for some stupid reason to try to play with the train
 		well he missed the train missed him but uh a big mirror type thing sticking out like a metal thing sticking out hit him in the head
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		he was in a coma for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four months</TIMEX> he's out of the coma now and eventually they think he will come back
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but you don't know that and but he's lost he was an outstanding <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> player
 	
 	
 		right
 		
 		
 	