
 
     		
 	
 		well what do you know about <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin American</ENAMEX> policies
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well
 		i think they're kind of ambivalent really uh
 		i i just have a feeling that we've kind of talked out of both sides of mouths down there like we do in some other situations you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we're we don't know half the time we don't know who to support
 	
 	
 		are you uh relating this uh to the uh affair we've got going on in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Haiti</ENAMEX> right now
 	
 	
 		that and you know uh maybe it's maybe it's tough for a big powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> to deal with with uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> like that that depend on us so much without you know just telling them running their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> for them but
 	
 	
 		right
 		that that's just it
 	
 	
 		it's got to be tough but i mean uh uh i'm you sure you still have to you know let them know how you feel
 	
 	
 		right i guess my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> uh
 		you know no matter which no matter which side we take we're gonna have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> and we're gonna have
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> antisupporters i guess for lack of better term
 		and uh
 		like you said they're such small countries
 		that we're bound to upset somebody but we seem to be lacking the ability to take a stance
 	
 	
 		yeah it it worries me that uh the economy of so many <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> in in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South America</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central America</ENAMEX>
 		depend on something that that damages <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like the you know like <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh
 		you know of course i i'm sure we have some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX> down there who would wouldn't care what happened to us but
 	
 	
 		that's true
 	
 	
 		but that is that's a tough deal  and it i don't think that maybe i'm maybe it's you know i'm just reflecting how i feel about it but i have a feeling that we that we really don't understand basically the the
 		the competing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">factions</ENAMEX> in a lot of those <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> and i mean they've been hammering tongs for the last you know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten centuries</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		and it's still going on and uh
 		we we dabble in it just enough to make both sides angry at us i think sometimes
 	
 	
 		that that's about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lump</ENAMEX> sum of it well um i was speaking with a a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> from uh uh i believe she was from
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Honduras</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guatemala</ENAMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">somewhere</NUMEX> in there no she was from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El Salvador</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		she was from a relatively wealthy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and when uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Contras</ENAMEX> came into power
 		of course with uh
 		oh gosh darn it what's his face he's in in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">jail</ENAMEX> now <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marcos</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		uh no he's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marcos</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philippines</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah um
 		well i'm blank  i can see his face i mean how could you forget his face
 	
 	
 		well you know who i'm talking about
 		yeah i i know it uh anyway when he came into power he basically just took everybody's property you know just assigned it to himself
 	
 	
 		yeah kind of nationalized it
 	
 	
 		right right and uh
 	
 	
 		for himself
 	
 	
 		so she's been a real strong supporter of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Sandinistas</ENAMEX> and has been trying to back the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> in that respect and i in that respect i have to agree that
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i think we're taking the right stance uh because they were a democracy
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		turned uh
 	
 	
 		dictator yeah
 	
 	
 		you know right basically a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dictator</ENAMEX> fascist
 	
 	
 		and it seems like those <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> are so easily susceptible to that kind of thing it just
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		you know unstable
 	
 	
 		well what do you think of uh this uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> free trade agreement we're working on with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well i think it's long overdue uh i just you know there's so much difference in in the economies of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> i i'm not you know i have a problem uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		with whether it's gonna work or not you know
 		there's uh
 		it seems like there's
 		and i this may be unfair to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> but it seems like there's a lack of honesty in  in
 		in in foreign policy a lot of the times
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">uh Mexico</ENAMEX>
 		they're i i know they're trying they're really trying the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is trying and a lot of the larger <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> are trying to
 		oh
 		make themselves Americanized i guess
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		which is great because that's what they basically need to do the big problem with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
 		is we
 		have our basic <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> schedule you know and we don't have the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Siesta</ENAMEX> and there's the cultural differences is what
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		is what's kind of it's what's really hurting uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> because they've had their way of life and we've had our way of life and uh
 	
 	
 		i think there's their version of the good old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> network going  that uh
 		you know has a lot
 		
 		
 	