
 
     		
 	
 		i um think that's one of the greatest concerns that uh is in our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> today is the crime problem
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		what do you think
 	
 	
 		oh yeah well yeah there's a host a lot of things that center around that crime area uh you know from
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		from just uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> trying to make a living on the wrong side of the law to those who are just trying to uh keep their drug habit up and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so i think that it encompasses a whole lot of the concerns
 	
 	
 		i know in the large <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> uh um we think that we have more crime but
 		we have a place out in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and uh we've had more  more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> break into our place in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> than we have in town
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		and so i don't know that it's confined just to the large cities
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh we found that
 		the crime rate in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> increased when they had let loose some uh early parolees
 		and uh that concerned me because i was hoping letting the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> out of prison early on for good behavior would work but i about decided it didn't
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but um
 	
 	
 		yeah i i just don't know what kind of criteria they have used for most of those early parole leases releases so uh
 	
 	
 		i think sometimes it it depends on what space they need
 	
 	
 		that's right i think you're right
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i'm sure it has a lot to do with it
 	
 	
 		do you think that that has as much to do with the rising crime rate as uh the uh beginning of the of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gangs</ENAMEX> and things
 	
 	
 		well i think um
 		certainly that might have something to do with it but i also think that
 		the standards of uh what we consider normal are is drastically changing each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> at least if not faster by because of the movies that are out there
 	
 	
 		oh yes
 	
 	
 		and what all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are exposed to and also the grown-ups out there that we're just constantly watching and
 		what we would of normally you know used to consider awful is almost a normal kind of thing on TV now and
 	
 	
 		i see what you mean
 	
 	
 		yeah and i so i think that it's uh and also i think uh
 		the way our lives our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> are are uh being raised that with a lot more single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> or a lot more full-time working <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> that uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		there are a lot more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strangers</ENAMEX> out there taking care of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and i i mean <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strangers</ENAMEX> in the sense of not the close family knit types that they used to have
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and um i felt so i think there's a lot more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> growing up confused and feeling not really considering uh you know necessarily as wanted or loved as they might have felt
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh</ENAMEX> had the family been a little closer-knit
 	
 	
 		um-hum or maybe don't feel as responsible to anyone for their actions
 	
 	
 		that's that's right that's a good good way to say uh to say it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well do you think that uh with the recession that everyone says is coming along and more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> don't find work and have to stay home and the economy goes down do you think that would help
 		um deter the crime raise and and increase raising of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well i think it would be a long term change i don't think that we will see it too soon i think it'll
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		not change i don't think it will slow down for quite some time just because there's you know it's gonna take that pendulum a long time to swing back the other way
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well i see an awful lot of working <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> who very very involved in their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's true
 	
 	
 		and um
 		i don't know i know it's hard especially to monitor television if you're not around
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh
 	
 	
 		oh yeah i think there are definitely are ways that both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> can work and have recent you know responsible and and you know very loving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> growing up and staying that way
 		but i think it takes the effort and extra time and effort out of those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> and not too many not as many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are doing that as they should because we're used to having an easy get it when you want it society and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh you know uh the easy way out is considered more appropriate sometimes than than the working hard methods that  used to be
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> who's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">principal</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and she said that a lot of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> that she calls they just flat don't wanna be bothered
 	
 	
 		so
 		right i think we're all tired and having too many pressures and i just occurred when you mentioned principal it occurred to me when i was teaching how
 		um it was becoming quite disturbing realizing how many crack <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX> were there were becoming you know out there in the educational area and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and the things that we'll be dealing with just on the educational <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">front</ENAMEX> that
 		um are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that will <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> that will eventually grow to be older possible crime <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">makers</ENAMEX> themselves because they started out in life with having so many you know uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	