
 
     		
 	
 		okay you want to tell me first how you feel about
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well um i i just think the way that things are going that um that it would be good for young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to go ahead and have um dedicate themselves to at least something
 	
 	
 		the proposal
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i know like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mormon</ENAMEX> religion you know they require <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> of service uh missionary service uh right the boys
 	
 	
 		the boys
 		not the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> just the boys
 	
 	
 		yeah and um so but i think it would be good if for all young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you know to be able to to do something like that um so that um you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i i i don't know i just feel it would be good for them to do that
 	
 	
 		um-hum i i thought it would be good too but i did not think it would be good that they all do something like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace Corps</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		because not all young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would have uh what it takes to go like that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because i think it takes a certain <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> to to be able to do something like that but there's a lot of other public service things that could be done
 	
 	
 		oh sure
 		oh yeah and and even in even in our home <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX> there's a lot of um public service things that they could do
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh you know drug rehabilitation and and alcohol and and just uh helping old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and um
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh you know helping cripple just helping somebody else and i think that art of giving is something that um we don't have very much any more
 	
 	
 		yes
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah i think it would be  when they say this proposal is this something that they're just suggesting or are they actually why why why did they call it a proposal that
 	
 	
 		oh i i think they just gave it a title but it's it's not something that's um in legislation or in works um uh yeah no no it's not it's just a just a topic but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		that's what i wondered what
 		it'd be a good character builder
 	
 	
 		i i think so too i think so too um because there's so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">um kids</ENAMEX> who have uh you know so much money and so much free time and uh nothing to do um and and nothing to give their time to
 	
 	
 		huh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um they don't even have a direction to give their their time to so i think it would be really good for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to um to be able to give their time in in uh some kind of public service uh even in our government
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know as uh aids to uh you know <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> uh people
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so um yeah it would be uh it'd be really good i think
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are um
 		have received sentences in jail they have uh some of them are going out and doing uh they have to go out and do public service activities which to me is is good
 	
 	
 		uh-huh right
 		oh yeah oh yeah i agree with you yeah this is something that um like you say it's it's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> building um you know learning how to to give to others and being less selfish and um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
  
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well i think sometimes it gives you a better picture of what some of the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> live like you know what what some of the other parts of the world are like or even other parts of the neighborhood uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum yeah</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> how they live or
 	
 	
 		oh i agree with you i agree with you and and i think uh young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are so um uh focused just on themselves and their activities and whose going out with whom <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">et</ENAMEX> cetera that uh
 	
 	
 		you know
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know to get a taste of what the real world is actually about uh you know doing that that public service would be great yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah because that's one thing that's hard with young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you you can't tell them how things are they have to see for themselves and
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		now of course this might be after they've gone through their teen <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> i don't know what their thought is on what age that this should be done
 	
 	
 		oh yeah i would think so like right after um high school you know even even if it was like the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the the their um that summer</TIMEX> right after high school you know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three months</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		um-hum of course they've already gone through the period of time where they need more direction
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know they their teenage <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and that they really sometimes need
 		a little better direction to go
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and something course now <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace Corps</ENAMEX> that couldn't be done of course until they were done with school
 	
 	
 		right right
 	
 	
 		in such
 	
 	
 		you know something that was that was outside of uh outside of school
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah but yeah you know right right after you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduate</ENAMEX> from uh high school because a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are just um
 		uh well gee <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whiz</ENAMEX> what do i do now if if they're not focused on going to college and uh you know having that that uh gung ho plan uh that's you know setting their life goals
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		kind of an in between time
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		um-hum yeah so to me see that would be the the uh the greatest time for um you know uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teenagers</ENAMEX> to to do that would be right after they graduated from high school
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but as for it being required  you know we're we're just not we're not based on on on that uh type of a system um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">huh-uh</ENAMEX>
 		no and and like i said not now all young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> should be able to do something but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		not all certainly would be geared to even the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">the Mormon boys</ENAMEX> that go out not all of them go i mean it's disaster if they don't go but  but some of them are not they're just not made to do that type of thing
 	
 	
 		right
 		oh right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they just aren't able to do it
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah so um yeah it'd be good but like i said it requiring it would be uh
 	
 	
 		but
 		
 		
 	