
 
     		
 	
 		yeah i had this topic uh the last time i called i believe
 	
 	
 		
 
 		my goodness that's unusual
 	
 	
 		well do you have any uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> or are you in college
 	
 	
 		mine uh <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">well mine</ENAMEX> are grown and uh of course uh i've already been through this with them
 	
 	
 		i see well
 	
 	
 		and i guess i'll have to help with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandchildren</ENAMEX> one of these days i hope
 	
 	
 		certainly and where did your uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> go to college
 	
 	
 		well <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> went to A and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> went to um  uh oh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen F Austin</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> went to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Texas</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> went to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Texas</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well that's great
 	
 	
 		and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of them ended up at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">El Centro</ENAMEX> in one of the uh specialized programs and another is putting herself through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">right now</TIMEX> back at UTD
 	
 	
 		i see
 		well that's great i'm the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of admissions at UTD
 	
 	
 		oh well good well i'm glad you let her in
 	
 	
 		well what advice did you give them when they were choosing their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX> it looks like they uh you have a variety there
 	
 	
 		well the main thing was uh what is it you want to study  and uh where is the best place to get what you need and
 	
 	
 		well
 	
 	
 		how far is it from home i had to put in and and then course we also had to include how much is it gonna cost
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well you're going right down my list uh the first thing that i always talk to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> about is the academic program because if we don't have what you're looking for it isn't gonna do you any good no matter how bad you wanna come here
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		that's true that's true
 	
 	
 		and uh cost is always uh usually next on the list especially for the parents and uh financial assistance and scholarships
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and usually then we talk a little bit about uh the size of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and uh different types of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> and activities that they can get involved in and of course distance from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> and size of classes and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um it sounds like uh from your experience you know how to go right down the list with them
 	
 	
 		well you have to be practical because uh i know um our our <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> went uh to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen F Austin</ENAMEX>
 		and uh her <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">allergies</ENAMEX> acted up in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Piney Woods</ENAMEX> and it was too far from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> and she got lonesome and that didn't work out for her so i guess i learned on that one
 	
 	
 		yeah you you know it's interesting especially when uh uh my experience uh has always been at a public university
 		and uh a lot of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> in that home <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> uh sometimes shun the idea of staying and going to school across the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> so to speak
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh it always seems like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at the beginning of the year</TIMEX> they're talking about well i'm going to this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> and i'm getting out of here and i'm going way over there
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and a lot of times when it gets right down to the practical aspect of it they end up staying pretty darn close to home because they can save money as far as housing and uh laundry
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		laundry and food i think <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> has a lot to do with it too
 	
 	
 		you bet  it sure does
 	
 	
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> doing the laundry  especially with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> it don't seem the laundry isn't that quite that important because they seem to know how to handle that better but the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> it's that laundry that throws them there for a while
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		even when they know how to use the washing machine
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well there's a little barrier around the washing machine and the dryer and uh for some reason <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> just can't get around that barrier
 	
 	
 		oh
 		well we'll have to give them the pass key i guess do you have uh uh more than the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> to plan for
 	
 	
 		uh i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> that's a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">seventh</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grader</ENAMEX> and then i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> that's a sophomore at uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shepton High School</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		and so it's uh it's been interesting watching them uh sign up for appropriate course work and things and they're they're on the college bound <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">track</ENAMEX> at least
 	
 	
 		um-hum well
 		that's good do you find that uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> is going in a different direction than the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> as far as what his uh um needs are and the type of college he wants
 	
 	
 		well uh they certainly have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> different personalities but uh in terms of needs the older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> is interested in the medical field
 	
 	
 		well yeah
 		good
 	
 	
 		and uh at this particular point you know taking appropriate course work but really nothing uh that's in out of the ordinary
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> has indicated that uh she wants to get a degree in uh
 		business um and then go on to become <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>  sure  you bet and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		okay i'll vote for her if she has good track record hope i'm around to do so
 	
 	
 		well i uh you know we're we we try to be conscious of uh of the uh equal uh equal rights and uh
 		
 		
 	