
 
     		
 	
 		okay who do you like
 	
 	
 		okay  what kind do i like i like just about any kind except <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and western
 	
 	
 		yeah that same with me same with me
 	
 	
 		it it's course <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and western even i've gotten a little bit used to because it's not like it used to be
 	
 	
 		uh-huh like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clint Black</ENAMEX> he's pretty good and who's the other big guy
 	
 	
 		well in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX> we say <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garth Brooks</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garth Brooks</ENAMEX> yeah that yeah that's the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> i was thinking of was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garth Brooks</ENAMEX> yeah fact i think both of them have performed here
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenny Rogers</ENAMEX> he's kind of country western verge you know on the verge of country western
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">course Garth Brooks</ENAMEX> lives about uh you know his his home <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> is about uh <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">fifteen minutes</TIMEX> away
 	
 	
 		oh wonderful
 	
 	
 		so he is he's a home boy
 	
 	
 		well then of course you like him that's great so well i have teenage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and so you know i'm hear the the rock music not the hard rock but the you know
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Bolton</ENAMEX> type stuff he he's my personal favorite
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> is uh <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty eight so</TIMEX> but he he's real unusual in that uh he likes a little bit of every kind he likes jazz
 	
 	
 		oh that's good
 	
 	
 		and uh blues and and course the rock
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i i can't say he's real crazy about elevator music as he calls it
 	
 	
 		no no what i don't i don't think actually we don't listen to any elevator music at my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> but i've got <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teenagers</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teenagers</ENAMEX> are all gone i can listen to any music i want to
 	
 	
 		yeah that's good i actually when i'm <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">home</ENAMEX> alone which isn't too often but
 		uh our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> radio station has wonderful classical music
 		it's just very wonderful soothing and you know uh a lot of symphonies and i just i love that that's probably my all time favorite
 	
 	
 		you know uh i i teach
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		and we can have music in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">classroom</ENAMEX> but it you know it can't be the rock or anything like that and i i find that the classical music is very good for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> too
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		it doesn't disturb them and yet it it's it stimulates them and and
 	
 	
 		right
 		relax yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh
 	
 	
 		what do you teach what grade
 	
 	
 		well it's <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">ninth</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> through twelve
 	
 	
 		good for you
 	
 	
 		and  well it's uh business technology
 	
 	
 		a certain subject
 		good for you
 	
 	
 		but uh
 	
 	
 		i was just sitting here while she was trying to find a
 		a another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">caller</ENAMEX> uh i was reading my  my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and i are taking a computer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> at our junior college
 	
 	
 		oh boy
 	
 	
 		yeah it's pretty good it's just a real basic class but we're learning a lot and we have a home computer so  it's it's very interesting
 	
 	
 		uh yeah i'd learn it too uh
 		back to i guess we'd better get back to music though  i uh
 	
 	
 		yeah the subject of music
 	
 	
 		do you play any instruments
 	
 	
 		i play i play piano i took lessons for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirteen years</TIMEX> and right now my <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nine year old</TIMEX> is taking piano
 		and i just got a whole mess of music i i play the volunteered to play the piano at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> program for the whole grade school which is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> through <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">six</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		ooh you took on a good job
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five hundred</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>  i did it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> and and um i sub i just sub at the school i don't wanna work full time so i just sub at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and that's kind of my volunteer thing so that it's it's really neat and
 		my older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> plays the saxophone my next <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> plays the drums and my <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> just started baritone <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> and my little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> will start <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> horn <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX> so
 	
 	
 		oh well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> played the sax and drums my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> the piano organ and French horn
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> horn is absolutely wonderful instrument it's just my favorite course that's what i played and so
 		i'm pushing that on my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> because i wanna play in our city <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">band</ENAMEX> not the symphony we just the city <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">band</ENAMEX> once we get the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> horn and i get a little bit more time right now i'm busy chasing my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 		yes sounds like you've got a houseful
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i do i do i love it but we have a a marvelous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">band instructor</ENAMEX> and and he just he's wonderful we have  <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">couple of hundred</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> in the band our junior high <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX> is just wonderful
 		he lot of and then their concert <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX> and then he has a jazz band that my older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> was in and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> will be in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX> that's i mean they can play college level music in junior high he's that good of an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">instructor</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> just love him
 	
 	
 		oh that's a
 		oh that's wonderful i i have totally totally a tin ear
 	
 	
 		so it's really good it is wonderful
 		oh do you
 	
 	
 		and i love music i cannot carry a tune in a basket
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i know what i like and but i you know and i love to listen to it and i love to sing
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> when i was little and they were little and i was rocking them singing to them they'd say
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	