
 
     		
 	
 		all right um well uh let's see i'm <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		how old are you <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lisa</ENAMEX>
 		okay that i'm older
 	
 	
 		yeah how old are you
 		older
 	
 	
 		older than you are
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		okay we are supposed to talk about places we like to go so i'm gonna and where are you from where are you calling from
 	
 	
 		i'm calling from uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Provo Utah</ENAMEX> but i'm from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plano Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh you are from Plano my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plano</ENAMEX> yes her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> is the new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Admissions</ENAMEX> at uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Texas</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh really
 		oh wow my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> used to work at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UTD</ENAMEX> also
 	
 	
 		yeah so i
 		anyway so where's your favorite place to go
 	
 	
 		um
 		generally we just go on family vacations to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX> live there that's generally our usual <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer vacation</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		
  
 		where in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tempe</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay i've never been to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tempe</ENAMEX> that's where i'd like to go
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		what do you like about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tempe</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um mainly just being with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> is it we just hang out and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX> have a pool so we go swimming and um
 	
 	
 		pretty hot isn't it in the summer
 	
 	
 		yeah but we keep cool just by going swimming and it's fun to be with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousins</ENAMEX> they're up there also my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousins</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		that's good uh-huh
 		have been to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no have you
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ha</ENAMEX> yes in fact i just got some reservations i'm going to go for uh almost <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">almost two weeks this winter</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh my goodness
 	
 	
 		yes it's the longest well actually i lived there so i was there longer but <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks</TIMEX> is the longest vacation i'll have ever taken there so i'm kind of looking forward to that with
 	
 	
 		wow
 		around <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> time
 	
 	
 		uh no in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> we're going to go in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> after my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s birthdays and get all that business out of the way
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 		wow
 	
 	
 		yeah so i think i would like to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX> i mean i was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Phoenix</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January last January</TIMEX> but it was rainy and icky
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		it was the coldest it's been there ever in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX> i think it's very cold
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hm</ENAMEX> so do you travel a lot or
 	
 	
 		but i would like to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tempe</ENAMEX> do we travel a lot uh some yeah well i've been a i was a travel agent
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		i mean i have been up until just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few months ago</TIMEX> but i'm thinking of going back to work
 	
 	
 		huh so you know a lot of good vacation spots huh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i low i know a lot of good places to go but you definitely need to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's your favorite
 	
 	
 		very definite
 		yes it is my favorite my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> hasn't been to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> yet and i'd like to take him there
 		and but he's traveled all over the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and i haven't like i haven't been down south i'd like to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Orleans</ENAMEX> have you been there
 	
 	
 		i haven't where where do you live
 	
 	
 		we i live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yakima Washington</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		wow
 	
 	
 		so it's cold and rainy <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> it's yucky
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		but we've had some pretty nice weather we played tennis outdoors until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> so that's a pretty good deal so do you go to school in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Provo Utah</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		hm
 		i do
 	
 	
 		do you use <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">NuSkin</ENAMEX> skin care they're located in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Provo</ENAMEX> do you i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">NuSkin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> person
 	
 	
 		yep
 		i work for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NuSkin</ENAMEX>  yeah
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		yeah i sell <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NuSkin</ENAMEX> too i i am my only been best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customer</ENAMEX> not only in best but i'm my best customer
 	
 	
 		oh my goodness
 	
 	
 		since we're not supposed supposed to talk about this though is there anything more intensive for the eye area than the eye cream
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">great</ENAMEX>
 		uh i don't probably maybe the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rejuvenating cream</ENAMEX> is the only
 	
 	
 		do you know
 		i have that too
 	
 	
 		other thing i would use
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i'm <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">forty two</NUMEX> i need something i need more
 	
 	
 		than the intensive eye
 	
 	
 		yeah i didn't know if there was anything else and i use the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Celltrex</ENAMEX> but anyway well yes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">NuSkin</ENAMEX> is wonderful
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		good yeah
 	
 	
 		i think it's a wonderful product do you use it
 	
 	
 		i do yeah we get free products <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every month</TIMEX> so
 	
 	
 		oh my gosh that's great
 	
 	
 		like right now i'm getting about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixty</TIMEX> bucks a month
 	
 	
 		yeah oh yeah
 	
 	
 		free <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">products</ENAMEX> so i've worked there about a year
 	
 	
 		that's good are they good to work for
 	
 	
 		
  
 		yes they're wonderful to work for
 	
 	
 		that's great
 	
 	
 		yep
 	
 	
 		anyway so we're supposed to be talking about places to go and you have not been to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> do you go to school
 	
 	
 		uh-huh i do
 	
 	
 		do you ski
 	
 	
 		i ski yes i've
 	
 	
 		ski you probably ski very well in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no i don't  actually since i grew up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> i've only been here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about two years</TIMEX> and have gone skiing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about three</NUMEX> times well well <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> times <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each season</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 		why did you move to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> you're going oh you are going to school at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BYU</ENAMEX> is that where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BYU</ENAMEX> is okay i know some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that went to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BYU</ENAMEX> that's great pretty good
 	
 	
 		yeah i  uh-huh yep
 		so
 		i do like to ski  yeah i i said i do like to ski
 	
 	
 		pretty pretty down there huh
 		so where have you skied
 	
 	
 		and it's it's kind of nice being up here just because it's all like a vacation in itself when you get to go if you like that kind of thing
 	
 	
 		sure
 		sure so you're a sophomore or junior
 	
 	
 		i am actually a junior beginning of my junior year
 	
 	
 		you're a junior
 		good for you what are you studying
 	
 	
 		so nursing
 	
 	
 		good for you you sound like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> that has it together i would just encourage you to do a little traveling though before you get married because when you get married you won't have the money or the time
 	
 	
 		nursing so
 		
 
 		you think
 		
 
 		i know
 	
 	
 		so just you know don't don't be in any hurry
 	
 	
 		i'm not i'm not
 	
 	
 		you really should go to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> i went to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six weeks</TIMEX> after i graduated from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> and that was just i i mean i could have had that or a down payment on a new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and i took the trip
 	
 	
 		and it was great
 	
 	
 		and um i traveled with a group of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixteen</TIMEX> other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> actually they there was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> other graduating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">seniors</ENAMEX> besides myself and we just had a ball we stayed at
 	
 	
 		how long did you get to stay there
 	
 	
 		uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six weeks</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh real ly
 	
 	
 		yeah it was wonderful so you should think about doing something like that
 	
 	
 		uh-huh i just had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> that got back from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> and she was there like all <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter semester</TIMEX>
 		
 		
 	