
 
     		
 	
 		well <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robin</ENAMEX> um i do have a PC in my home
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		um-hum i don't have at home but i used one at work and i play on there but i do i do some of my own stuff on there too so
 	
 	
 		use <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> at work
 		yeah
 		what do you use it for as far as your own work
 	
 	
 		
 
 		um oh games mostly um data base like address lists and recipes and just
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh sort of the stuff that i like to keep track of mostly most of what i do is shareware games and and copies of stuff that i've gotten from other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i use <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lotus</ENAMEX> a lot just because i like using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lotus</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		do your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> ever get to use it at work
 	
 	
 		
 
 		uh no because they're <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> so they're not quite old enough to use those yet i tell them mommy's playing on the computer so
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> huh
 		yeah not there yet yeah
 		
 
 	
 	
 		they know what i'm doing
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well
 	
 	
 		but at work i use it mostly for
 		i most of what i do is in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lotus</ENAMEX> i've we've got a couple of word processing but  i'd rather use Lotus  i know it better
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		know it better than that yeah
 		i think everyone knows it better than most the custom word processor
 	
 	
 		uh yeah uh well we've got <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">WordStar 2000</TIMEX> we just got <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">WordPerfect</ENAMEX> and i  haven't gotten around to learning WordPerfect yet so
 	
 	
 		yeah well i use WordPerfect at work exclusively pretty much exclusively
 	
 	
 		yeah it's i like well i work for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RTC</ENAMEX> so we that's what everything they send us is in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">WordPerfect</ENAMEX> so we kind of had to get <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WordPerfect</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		uh
 		have to use it yeah
 		well i have one at home that  my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are twelve <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> and three
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		so they use it uh quite a bit for games and uh the twelve <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year old</TIMEX> uses it you know for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> uses the word word processing for school quite a bit really
 	
 	
 		i'll bet
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well good yeah that's that's one thing i'm hoping by the time mine get up there that we will be able to have one at home
 	
 	
 		and and uh
 		yeah now we also uh course of i use it for uh
 		i have a some check
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">balancing</ENAMEX> and budgeting software that i use have for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several years</TIMEX> now every all my checkbook's been on the computer for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh
 		yeah that's since i work for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RTC</ENAMEX> we used to uh i used to be the loan teller for a failed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">savings and loan</ENAMEX>  and a couple of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> would use the automated check writing
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		huh
 		would they really
 	
 	
 		programs yeah and it was i it was always interesting to see them it was like oh okay  i recognize these who would be i i guess that would be a pretty good feature to use on that
 	
 	
 		here they go
 		yeah yeah
 		well i've used it also for tax for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about the past four years</TIMEX> i guess and it's makes it real nice
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		that would be good
 	
 	
 		and um
 		i guess that's mainly been it other than you know like like yeah we use it for games quite a bit
 	
 	
 		yeah i'm kind of hooked on Tetris
 	
 	
 		yeah  i don't have <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tetris</ENAMEX> but boy i'm glad to probably a good thing i don't
 	
 	
 		well the shareware version i got has got like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> different versions of Tetris
 	
 	
 		you got a shareware version huh what's it
 	
 	
 		um-hum it was like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> dollars i've i like that it's it's pretty cool
 	
 	
 		do you know what it's called i mean does have a
 	
 	
 		um it's called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nyet N Y E T</ENAMEX> which is what is it
 	
 	
 		in
 		hm
 	
 	
 		oh
 		something about
 		it's not not called Tetris you know it's like uh-huh
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and the other version's called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ain't</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		ain't because it ain't Tetris
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah well the the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> letters i don't even remember what they stand for but it's it's a little
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i mean what think of what that thing's called but it's it's a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> word phrase that means no it's not Tetris  it's really not  but it's it's fun i like that and plus there's a a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> at work that he and i trade
 	
 	
 		hm
 		oh okay
 		right
 		oh boy
 	
 	
 		different games like he's like well you know what do you have and i'll give you this  and we trade well he's given me <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Jeopardy and Monopoly and Wheel of Fortune</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		all right you got some good ones then
 	
 	
 		oh yeah the only problem is the computer i like to play them on that's got the color monitor also i can't turn the sound off
 	
 	
 		oh you can't turn the sound off yeah
 	
 	
 		so i haven't figured out how to turn the sound off yet it's like oh because i i haven't really been into computers for except for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about the last five years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		at before then it was like get that computer out of here i don't want it around here leave me alone
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i i've gotten to where i took a basic programming course out at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Richland</ENAMEX> and i really i enjoyed that and i got little bit further into programming  and i worked with a couple of our programming <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> down at uh Frito-Lay
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and i thoroughly enjoyed that now it's like give me computer and consequently i am the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> that everybody comes to at work it's
 	
 	
 		huh
 		how about that
 		isn't that amazing
 	
 	
 		oh it's it really is it's like hm amazing how this turned around  she used to hate it now she loves it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		but  i like it
 	
 	
 		well well that's good
 	
 	
 		it's fun
 	
 	
 		well do you suppose we've talked long enough
 	
 	
 		oh i guess we have that sounds pretty good
 	
 	
 		all right
 		well i think we've done our duty here anyway
 	
 	
 		yeah i think so
 	
 	
 		all right good to talk to you bye-bye
 	
 	
 		thanks a lot <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vic</ENAMEX> bye-bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	