
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		all right so we started recording already
 	
 	
 		uh i guess i don't know it's the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time i've made a phone call on it
 	
 	
 		oh so you pressed one okay so i guess we're supposed to start talking uh  what kind of books do you read
 	
 	
 		right
 		
 
 		i read uh a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven King Dean R Koontz</ENAMEX> uh some <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danielle</ENAMEX> Steel my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aunt</ENAMEX> got me hooked on those
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		um-hum so it's mostly all novels  okay
 	
 	
 		so i
 		yeah they're all novels
 		i'll read some of classic too
 	
 	
 		oh like what
 	
 	
 		um
 		well i like <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Grapes Of Wrath</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steinbeck</ENAMEX> an i like um
 	
 	
 		uh yeah i like that i like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steinbeck</ENAMEX> a lot
 	
 	
 		a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Rose For Emily</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Faulkner</ENAMEX> that's one of my favorite
 	
 	
 		i have never read a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Faulkner</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh and this  this is more of a play or something that it that it was from that that i saw and i read the book from that
 	
 	
 		oh cool
 	
 	
 		and by the way my name's Bill i'm from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i'm <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doug</ENAMEX>  i'm from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 		um i let's see  what kind of books do you like to read
 	
 	
 		um well a bunch of
 		stuff i guess um  fair number of novels but mostly shorter ones and like i don't really
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 	
 	
 		like the you know <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six hundred</NUMEX> page long <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen King</ENAMEX> novels and all that  right
 	
 	
 		i really have to be in the mood i i read <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> like maybe once a year of those
 	
 	
 		um-hum no like i like say uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Broudigan</ENAMEX> a lot um okay he's um
 	
 	
 		i've never read anything by him
 	
 	
 		he's dead now but he was really a pretty amazing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> he wrote books that were like pretty short and
 		pretty easy to read you know like written at a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> grade level or whatever but they were still very heavy and philosophical also very funny like he wrote <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trout Fishing</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		okay
 	
 	
 		so that's anyway and um i read a lot of nonfiction books too um let's see
 	
 	
 		i like to read read a lot of nonfiction history when <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Civil War</ENAMEX> era and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and that kind of thing i i found that real interesting i'm reading The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lion</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Wind</ENAMEX> right now and that was on TV it was uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		now what's that
 	
 	
 		sometime  during <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Teddy Roosevelt</ENAMEX>'s time
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and um
 		about about <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> that got kidnapped in um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Morocco</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh this is when they were having their revolution or whatever and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Teddy Roosevelt</ENAMEX> sent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> over and  really portrays him as a kind of a crazy man
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 		surprised me i had no idea that he was like that
 	
 	
 		um-hum what how crazy
 	
 	
 		well just like some some uh one quote that he had was that he thought the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s emblem was stupid because it was an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">eagle</ENAMEX> and it should be a grizzly bear because he liked the to
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		to to hunt grizzly and stuff like that
 	
 	
 		i see
 	
 	
 		so it was it was i saw the movie and that's what uh made me want to read the book  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Candice Bergen</ENAMEX> was in the movie i'm a real big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> of hers so
 	
 	
 		um-hum  yeah cool see i also read a lot of books about music
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		because i'm interested in that and fair number of stuff about science and also philosophy things
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		what
 	
 	
 		i like i like to read some of the philosophy stuff stuff stuff
 	
 	
 		um-hum like
 		let's see
 		and even like reading some new age things things that i don't quite believe in like here on my shelf i have a book called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Journeys Out of the Body</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah i think that i'm fascinated by that yeah i'm fascinated by that
 	
 	
 		it's all about how to have out of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> experiences and all of that um-hum  yep
 	
 	
 		that and and uh even stuff about not like ghost stories but real encounters with ghosts and supposedly haunted <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> i like  i'm kind of a doubting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX> and i like to read stuff like that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		some of it really freaks me out
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		um-hum  you're right definitely
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		and i like to read um
 		i like to read some self help books like
 		um i read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dianetics</ENAMEX> once once i got past all the gibberish on it and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh</ENAMEX> did you like it
 	
 	
 		it was okay it it it it took me a while to really get into it it didn't help me that much  but uh i think once you're set in your ways you're set in your ways
 	
 	
 		um-hum i see
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um then i one interesting real interesting book i read recently was when i was looking for a job i read <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">How to Get the Job That You Wanted</ENAMEX> and it it had real good tips in it and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i got the job that i wanted by applying the the methods that
 		that they
 		
 		
 	