
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">hello</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		hi my name is uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donna Donahue</ENAMEX> and i live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plano Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		hi
 		
 
 		hi my name is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lowell</ENAMEX> and i live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Raleigh North Carolina</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh okay um do you wanna start or would should i start
 	
 	
 		go right ahead
 	
 	
 		okay um i would say that our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">home</ENAMEX> is a very typical home for the area that we live in
 		we have um <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and um they attend the public school here and are very active in a lot of the sports <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">soccer and baseball</ENAMEX> and
 		well my little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> goes to tap dance and my little one goes to preschool and um
 		i'm
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> just do a lot of running around it seems like a lot of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> kind of have a similar type
 		i don't know life um what about you
 	
 	
 		i'm i'm single and i i live in a town <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Raleigh</ENAMEX> and it's pretty typical of the other town <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> in the area there we we have a lot of town <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> here
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		okay
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		as well as single family <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> and at the time that i bought this one it was just a a much better
 		arrangement for me personally i'm not home a lot i travel a great deal with my job and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so it was easier to have a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> that didn't exactly that somebody else looks out for the maintenance
 	
 	
 		was sort of maintenance free yeah
 		oh yeah well um that that sounds that sounds pretty good because i know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> takes an awful lot of time on the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekends</TIMEX> not so much now but to um maintain the lawn and the edging and the flower beds and
 		it's a lot of work owning a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> with a little bit of property attached to it it's
 	
 	
 		it certainly is
 	
 	
 		sometimes i think um it would be nice to have a town <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> with not having all that responsibility
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well if you ever get one be sure the walls are good and thick because if they're not you can hear i that's the main thing when i was shopping for one i wanna make sure i couldn't
 		it i couldn't here my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> and it was so i bought one that's more like living in a once you're inside you don't know you're in a town home
 	
 	
 		right
 		oh that sounds lovely
 	
 	
 		it is they're kind of built on a catty-cornered instead of right side by side so you don't actually hear anybody next door to you
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		um-hum so in in your area then there's probably a lot of um career type <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that have those type <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> and uh-huh and um
 	
 	
 		yes definitely
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">area</ENAMEX> that we're settled in is um definitely young young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> with with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> they're still doing um a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> in the neighborhood
 		so the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that move here seem to move from all over the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> which we're from um the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Northeast</ENAMEX> and um
 		seems like a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> just don't also also don't have any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> around so it um also gives you a common bond when you don't have a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> visiting your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> and you know um but um
 		that's i
 	
 	
 		well we also in this area seem to have a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">retirees</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who don't wanna the heat of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> but don't want the heat of the northeast the cold of the northeast so they settle sort of in between
 	
 	
 		right right
 		um-hum now it's um is it very very wooded around where you are there lots of pretty <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> and yeah
 	
 	
 		yes as a matter of fact this is a uh
 		this particular <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> that i live in is very wooded
 	
 	
 		oh how pretty
 	
 	
 		it is nice it
 	
 	
 		i do miss that um around here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plano</ENAMEX> there are very few <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> and it's pretty flat and and kind of barren and
 		that's the only thing that we don't like about living in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> is we miss all the beautiful <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> and the fall and and um
 		uh  the landscape is much different here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> than it is you know in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North um</ENAMEX> or even where you are
 	
 	
 		uh we definitely have a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> here
 	
 	
 		a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">leaves</ENAMEX> to rake up too i bet
 	
 	
 		yes but fortunately the home <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">owner</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">association</ENAMEX> does all that yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 		does that well see that's another plus
 	
 	
 		yes i don't have to worry about that and this is the time of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> we're starting the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">leaves</ENAMEX> are all falling now
 	
 	
 		that's right that's right they are i'm gonna get the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> to get outside with the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbor kids</ENAMEX> and and do the little bit of raking that needs to be done we just have a few <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> in the front and a few in the back but
 		not not much just just a little kind of just in more of a makes a little bit of a mess for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few weeks</TIMEX> then if you didn't do anything about it then they'd probably the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">leaves</ENAMEX> would just blow away so it's not too bad
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		okay do we have to speak for a certain amount of time okay okay well it was really nice speaking to you
 	
 	
 		no i don't think so
 		it was good to speak with you too
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">okay</ENAMEX> and have a happy <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thanksgiving</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		thank you you too bye bye
 	
 	
 		bye bye
 		
 		
 	