
 
     		
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		what's your favorite TV show
 	
 	
 		oh you know i used to like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saint Elsewhere</ENAMEX> that's one of my old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">favorite um</ENAMEX> and that's i'm being beeped so i'll just ignore it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> and now
 		i  i did like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thirty Something</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yes  my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> says <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">90210</NUMEX> we like that one
 	
 	
 		yeah that's one of my favorites
 	
 	
 		good and how old are you
 	
 	
 		i'm <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty eight</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh so you're little bit younger than i am but yeah i think it my seventeen <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year old my fourteen year</TIMEX> old my other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> like it i'm over <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">forty</NUMEX> and i like it i think it's wonderful
 	
 	
 		yeah it's a good show i like uh <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Murphy Brown and Designing Women too</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah now see i we are so busy with all of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are in sports and i hardly ever watch TV but that's one that that we watch and then <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nights</TIMEX> we watch uh <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Life Goes On</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah i like that that's a that's a good show too
 	
 	
 		very good did you see the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes it was a  uh uh i did miss that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> no i didn't that's a good episode
 	
 	
 		the it that one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Becca</ENAMEX> likes he has <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 		yeah the the new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> on there did
 	
 	
 		right right all the way to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX> what time is it there
 	
 	
 		uh it is <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty minutes</TIMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh my gosh
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty minutes</TIMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> here
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three hours</TIMEX> difference
 	
 	
 		yeah yep okay what else do you like
 	
 	
 		um
 		uh see i like a lot of different shows let's see <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">um i like Murder She Wrote</ENAMEX> and that that
 	
 	
 		oh see i never i'd never watched that ever in my entire life
 	
 	
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matlock</ENAMEX>'s another good one i watch
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 		then during daytimes <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">i like i like All My Children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		a small bowl will be plenty
 		oh that's <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX> that's the only one i watch whenever i  oh a small bowl would be better why because it's pretty fattening
 		i'm talking to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> um
 		um
 	
 	
 		All <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">My Children i've</ENAMEX> watched that for about twelve years
 	
 	
 		yeah i've i'm sure i watched it for more than that probably <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty</TIMEX> some i used to uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Hospital</ENAMEX> when i was a teenager doesn't
 	
 	
 		i quit watching <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Hospital</ENAMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leslie</ENAMEX> got killed
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and so that was a long time ago i used to watch it  when in high school and college and and when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laura</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> got killed that she was my favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> on there i
 	
 	
 		right
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i just  i read the reason she got she they they killed her off was because they couldn't settle the contract and i said well if they're gonna do that to her i won't watch it and
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh that's great well i do like <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">All My Children</ENAMEX> and i and i like it you know i don't know i just i like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on it i guess you know
 	
 	
 		i i i i like it i just wish they'd bring some of the old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> back
 	
 	
 		yeah well <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tad</ENAMEX>'s gonna come back i bet do you think
 	
 	
 		yeah i'm i'm sure he will
 	
 	
 		he'll be he'll come back show up at the just the right moment
 	
 	
 		i kind of wish that uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nina</ENAMEX> would come back because she because the story you you know just for a brief visit or whatever because it never has been resolved with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Palmer</ENAMEX> remarrying and and everything
 	
 	
 		oh
 		yeah like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daisy</ENAMEX> pops in once in a while and
 		i forgot about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nina</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cliff</ENAMEX> right
 	
 	
 		yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cliff on The Young and the Restless</ENAMEX> now
 	
 	
 		oh he is so he's out for good
 	
 	
 		yeah he's out for good
 	
 	
 		did they marry
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nina Cliff</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's how they left the show but not in real life
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		now she's married to some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> and she's happily married and that's the reason she left the show i guess she wanted a private life
 	
 	
 		oh okay oh see i i i watch it maybe twice <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX> so i don't watch it everyday like i did when i had babies
 	
 	
 		oh well i'll i i'll watch
 	
 	
 		because i play lots of <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">tennis</ENAMEX> and i'm gone a lot so i don't get to watch
 	
 	
 		i watch it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> religiously i'd videotape it when i have to miss it  yeah
 	
 	
 		oh no kidding i used to be i used to be like that
 	
 	
 		i'm that way about a lot of different shows i'm that way about <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Murphy Brown Designing Women</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		now isn't <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Designing Women</ENAMEX> don't they have a new chick on there instead of the instead of what's her name
 	
 	
 		uh yeah there's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> on there there's um  uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jan Hooks</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Saturday Night Live</ENAMEX> i don't know if you know her or not and then
 	
 	
 		huh-uh that's the show i like
 	
 	
 		and then um
 		uh the blonde headed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> that used to be on Newhart
 	
 	
 		oh yeah oh
 	
 	
 		i i don't like her on it i never have liked her so
 	
 	
 		well i i just know which one she is i don't you know
 	
 	
 		she she's taken the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Suzanne</ENAMEX>'s part and then  uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jan Hooks</ENAMEX> has taken <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlene</ENAMEX>'s part there's
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlene</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Delta Burke</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh Charlene</ENAMEX> was  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jean</ENAMEX> Smart the blonde headed
 	
 	
 		oh okay well see i never watch that one either  i really don't watch a whole lot of TV just
 		you know on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>  <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Life Goes On</ENAMEX> comes on about the time that we eat dinner and my whole <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>'s home because i don't allow the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> out on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> you know because they got to go to bed and go to school <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next day</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and so we we sit around and eat popcorn and oh we then we watch <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Funniest Home Videos</ENAMEX> those are always pretty cute
 	
 	
 		well that <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Murder She Wrote</ENAMEX> comes on opposite of that and so i  that
 	
 	
 		oh so you got watch that one instead of
 	
 	
 		yeah i i i pick <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nights</TIMEX> uh pretty much so on on TV that i watch different <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX> but <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beverly Hills</ENAMEX> 90210 i i watch it religiously
 	
 	
 		sure
 		yeah we like that real well we like that
 	
 	
 		it will be sure to watch it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> because somebody's getting killed on it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		i know they <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> already know who it is i don't know who it is though
 	
 	
 		who is it ask them
 	
 	
 		let me ask <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nicole  Nicole</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	