
 
     		
 	
 		well <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlie</ENAMEX> what do you think should we spend more on <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> research or stay the same
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well i don't i don't think we're uh spending enough so i i think we should i that i should i think we should spend more
 	
 	
 		why do you think we don't spend enough
 	
 	
 		uh
 		let's see
 		um you know to tell you the truth i i couldn't tell you exactly i couldn't tell you what we're spending but from what i from what i hear um
 		from most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> uh you know just reading about <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> advocacy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> and oh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like that uh there have been a couple of deaths um lately uh like one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> that was on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> committee
 		um that we're not i it just doesn't seem like we're taking the disease as as seriously as we need to
 		uh lot of lot of talk about it but we're doesn't i don't know what do you think
 	
 	
 		well i agree with you i think we have a lot of talk but not dollars and you know we we situation  our situation where
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		we're faced with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that
 		you know choose a lifestyle that may cause <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX>  but then at the same token there are a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>
 		who didn't choose a lifestyle
 		but there was not help for them
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and i think one of the things we can do as far as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> goes is just to dispel some of the myths
 		you know drinking from a water fountain will give you <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		using a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">restroom</ENAMEX> will give you <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but at the same token i feel like <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">heart disease cancer</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">multiple sclerosis</ENAMEX>
 		where do we put those in perspective to <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well i wonder what i don't know what the statistics are but i think uh
 		it's uh the numbers of of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> infected do you know any have any idea what they are what they're estimating now
 	
 	
 		
 
 		no i don't and you know i'm like you i do not know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well i you know what it
 	
 	
 		what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is spending on <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah what what i think is that is that somehow in in our most a lot of our minds it's still a disease that affects primarily <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homosexuals</ENAMEX> and intravenous drug users
 		but what we're finding is that that that it's
 		it's um also it's affecting a lot more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> than that that that there's a lot more um uh
 	
 	
 		yes
 		
 
 	
 	
 		heterosexual transmission of the disease than than we probably thought
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		so
 		and you know i mean as long it's as long as it's um limited to those
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> select you know <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> kind of narrow areas <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homosexuals</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">intravenous drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> it it it's probably gonna get unfortunately sad to say a lot more lip service than it will actually actually dollars
 		and uh it might be that  as it spreads among the general <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> more that that uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		you know and and in all these stories about these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> who had transfusions and these
 		oh there's been a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple housewives</ENAMEX> lately that were you know national news that they had had transfusions transfusions uh transfusions and they you know and they're they're they died you know and left behind <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> and oh
 		oh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yep
 	
 	
 		well i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> and we have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> that died from <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh you you all did in your uh in your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> school district or something
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well not my school district but it was in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> and it was because of a transfusion and i think that got a lot more publicity because again it wasn't a minority group
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and you know we're looking at a situation that hopefully can be controlled
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i know yeah i don't know kind of kind of scary actually
 	
 	
 		it is frightening you know because it could be you or i and then what what would we do we'd want help
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		what are what are you gonna do if you're in an auto accident and uh you had need a blood transfusion are you gonna have confidence in the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> supply
 		i don't i don't i don't know that i would
 	
 	
 		that's true
 	
 	
 		or will
 	
 	
 		yeah well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> had a blood transfusion <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about four years ago</TIMEX> and i i was scared to even mention to her
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		that there was an emergency situation we couldn't give she couldn't give her blood we couldn't go down to give her our <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> for her
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and you know there's always the possibility
 	
 	
 		yeah and and i think as long as it's uh as long as it's still <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are thinking that it's mostly even <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that that it's almost like because they're choosing to practice those lifestyles that they're choosing you know that's their choice
 		that they ran that risk i mean i you know that's probably i hate to say that that sounds cruel
 	
 	
 		no but the i agree with you
 	
 	
 		uh that sounds <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cold cold</ENAMEX> and cruel but that's probably
 		as long as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> perceive of it being that way i i mean that probably explains the lack of um lack of concrete money and being spent
 	
 	
 		yeah and i think it's you know
 	
 	
 		yep
 		
 		
 	