
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		um tell me something about your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">camping</ENAMEX> experiences <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carolyn</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well um i have gone to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> camp a few times as a you know a chaperon or a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> whatever and uh i enjoy camping i
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		we have we have a tent and we've gone even with our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> a few times out camping and have a camp stove um
 		i guess our our my biggest memory is when we froze to death we just didn't take enough blankets and
 	
 	
 		
 
 		where where do you go camping at around here
 	
 	
 		whatever
 		uh we went camping at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">uh Lake Bonham</ENAMEX> which is is pretty close here um we went fairly early uh in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the season</TIMEX> for this area which is probably <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		is when we went and and it got really cold at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>
 		and of course we were close enough that we could go back and get
 		some <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more</NUMEX> blankets and things in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX> but
 	
 	
 		sure
 		uh what uh what activities do you do when you're camping
 	
 	
 		oh we take little nature hikes and
 		and uh we take along games that we can play with the with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and
 		it's that kind of stuff usually try to have a
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh occasionally a camp fire at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> you know and roast the marshmallows and what all
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well that sounds like fun i uh i grew up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Dakota</ENAMEX> up in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Black Hills</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and so we used to go camping my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> would take uh there's there was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> of us <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> we'd he'd take us you know we'd all go camping my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> and and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and
 		and it was always fun uh because
 		what i always remember is my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> would let us pick our camp spot and uh he'd always tell us you know okay look for you know a nice flat little area where we can pitch our tents and
 		it always had to be somewhere near a a river so we could go fishing and hopefully we'd catch our supper but we never did
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		but it was it was always fun we'd always <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> was always prepared and she'd bring along something you know something because  tradition had it we would never catch anything so we always had
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		something along to eat but then we'd roast <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">marshmallows</ENAMEX> roast <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">marshmallows</ENAMEX> and it it was always an enjoyable experience uh
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about nineteen eighty two</NUMEX> i moved from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rapid City</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Black Hills</ENAMEX> across the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> to to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aberdeen</ENAMEX> and uh there's no hills it's flat and then i was in high school and uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends couple</ENAMEX> of my high school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and i we'd go camping out by
 		a river of course and and go fishing but by then of course i was able to catch uh catch some things but it was it was always fun it was a different experience camping in the hills versus camping just by a river
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know in the hills we we would
 		do like you did your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> did you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> did would take the nature hikes and you know and look for <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> and we always you know in the hills you could see quite a few different animals
 		but go ahead
 	
 	
 		well
 		we we used to live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> and uh course there's lots of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">mountains</ENAMEX> around there to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> in and and streams and stuff that's that's a great place to go camping and the hiking is just really great
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		you know hike up those mountains is just really fantastic
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		now is there anything uh are there any mountains or big rocks a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> could hike around this area
 	
 	
 		i'm not acquainted with any you know i there's woods and things out in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Texas Tyler</ENAMEX> area you know there's a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tyler State</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Park</ENAMEX> that's uh really a nice camping area
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		but it it's just a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> it's not i don't know of any place in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> that has uh really big
 		you know what i call mountains
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		i
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Rocky Mountains</ENAMEX> are so much uh bigger than anything that they they've got down here that
 	
 	
 		
 
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> is the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tyler</ENAMEX> is it been a pretty commercialized i suppose
 	
 	
 		no it's not well it's not too bad they have um screened in
 		areas you know they're not really cabins i wouldn't say i guess they could call them that but they're they're more just a screened in
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> camping area or whatever they're they're not bad
 	
 	
 		okay
 		help help keep the the pests out i suppose
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		well that sounds
 		i don't know if that can rate camping but you know it sure beats driving <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a thousand miles</NUMEX> to
 		
 
 		to find a mountain i guess
 	
 	
 		yeah that's right i i take it you haven't done a whole lot of camping in this area
 	
 	
 		no we just moved down in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">in June</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh i see well you're still uh getting you're just trying to get over the culture shock still
 	
 	
 		yeah i'm still trying to find my way around i tell if i can get on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central</ENAMEX> from anywhere i'm happy
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah well really the ideal times to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> in this area are <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early spring</TIMEX> and and in the fall
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		uh it just gets so hot in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> you can hardly i mean there's there's a lot
 		
 		
 	