
 
     		
 	
 		let me ask you do you think the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> is a still a threat to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		do you know i don't know what to think i i
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> i am i want to believe that it's an honest effort i want to believe that that they really are trying to change that that maybe they are headed for a more democratic society and i i want to believe it's all okay
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but then there's that side of me that says  yeah but they've put on faces before
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and never to this extent though you know so so it's like there is a struggle within me going do do i be open minded and give them the benefit of the doubt which is kind of my basic personality you know i i trust <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i'll do that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		or do i keep on going well we'll wait and see
 	
 	
 		well i think there's a
 		a struggle within the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> um
 		i think  the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are are just fed up and i think it's showing in all the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">republics</ENAMEX> trying to gain their independence
 		and i think uh  that's making <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gorbachev</ENAMEX> and others realize that
 		hey maybe this <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist</ENAMEX> thing isn't working
 	
 	
 		yeah that it's not just <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> uh or western society telling you it it's it doesn't work
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know  they've always said you know the the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were united we believe this and maybe they're seeing that no no hey we don't believe this you know
 	
 	
 		that's right i think
 	
 	
 		but it's still you know i guess i keep that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> part of me that's like well
 		i don't know i want to trust them and i it's like i can't and maybe it's because you know we've had our own propaganda over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> i don't know
 	
 	
 		well that that could be you know what i we always we think of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KGB</ENAMEX> and we think such bad things you know but i wouldn't doubt if the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> think <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> and they think such bad things you know
 	
 	
 		and they probably do the same things
 	
 	
 		exactly exactly they do
 	
 	
 		you think the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> doesn't spy i'm sure they do
 	
 	
 		oh yeah they do you know
 	
 	
 		now the difference is we don't i don't i don't think we take <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and kill them just because they don't believe what we believe you know i think to that extent we don't go as far but i'm sure they lie
 		you know
 	
 	
 		oh yeah oh absolutely that's part of that propaganda thing and i think if we can get away from that or if we can keep that out of our minds  ah excuse me i've got a cold today
 	
 	
 		so
 		that's all right i hope you get better
 	
 	
 		thank you um
 		i think if we can get that propaganda thing because i'm sure both <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> are seeing seeing it you know thinking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KGB</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> and all that but uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		just on an economic point of view if the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> doesn't do something fast they're they ain't gonna be able to feed their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this this winter</TIMEX> you know but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah that's true
 	
 	
 		but on the other hand i'm kind of getting fed up with uh our own <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and presidency ah always  concerning themselves
 		with other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX>' problems when we have so many at home yet
 	
 	
 		and i'm not against them being concerned but i feel like we ought to be spending maybe the same time and effort and and energy into trying to solve our own or resolve our own
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know i mean you know any any <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> that wants to be democratic i'm all for helping them you know because i i understand that you know you're looking at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> as the biggest and longest supporter of that type of government
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but at the same time  i agree i don't think we can do it and and just you know turn our backs or or be ignorant per se to the things that are happening here
 	
 	
 		that's right
 		you know we've got uh
 		we've got quite a few domestic problems that uh
 		that i feel we ought to be concentrating more on i think the problem is and on the international scope
 		maybe the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> feels that uh
 		you know for long term relations with all these <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> it's important and well we'll always we'll always have the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and you know we need to solve these international problems but um
 		i've think i heard in the news about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> sometime that uh
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> ended up canceling one of his international trips so he could spend more time on them on a
 		domestic issue because the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>'s kind of getting fed up with it
 	
 	
 		yeah we we we believe in what he's doing abroad but but like you said there's issues here too
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and  but i i am encouraged by what's happening in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> i'm encouraged by what's happened in you know the the iron curtain <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> you know in in that block and
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and i think it's moved in the right direction i now i think sometimes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> expect it to happen <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">overnight</TIMEX> you know it's not going to it didn't happen here <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">overnight</TIMEX> and it didn't happen here without a struggle
 	
 	
 		yep no
 		that's right that's right
 	
 	
 		you know
 		and i i think sometimes we forget that
 		but i i i'd i have to say yes i'm you know i'm encouraged by the way it's going
 		uh
 	
 	
 		well i think uh
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		i think in the long
 		
 		
 	