
 
     		
 	
 		uh you keep up with current events
 	
 	
 		um somewhat yeah not not as well as i would like to probably but that's the way it goes
 	
 	
 		somewhat
 		is that right
 		yeah where where abouts in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		what
 	
 	
 		where in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">um State College</ENAMEX> i go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Penn State</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh do you well great
 	
 	
 		yep
 	
 	
 		how's uh well no we're not supposed to talk about that we're supposed to talk about current events  well i'm a current event junkie so i
 	
 	
 		right exactly uh
 	
 	
 		i watch i try to watch the news and i read the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> and i like to read <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time magazine People</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> keep up what's going on in the world
 	
 	
 		i see well what particularly are you interested in
 	
 	
 		but
 		well i just pretty uh a little you know about everything and not and then again not everything but you know i like to know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		pretty well what's happening so political things don't interest me a great deal except i do like to stay informed enough to
 		feel like i halfway vote intelligently you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh
 		other than that uh i just you know just the events that happen around the world interest me and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and stay in touch with it know feel like i know what's going on now i have to say <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all three</NUMEX> of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> none of them are too interested in current events
 	
 	
 		i see
 	
 	
 		but i always have been
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i stay up with it but uh how do you how do you uh stay aware of most of the current events uh newspaper
 	
 	
 		um uh well some of both i
 	
 	
 		TV news or what
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		read i read the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> sometimes and i watch <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> and that sort of thing occasionally and  i
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well that's yeah that's good because
 	
 	
 		read magazines and such
 	
 	
 		uh-huh well you stay up with it pretty well then
 	
 	
 		well yeah i mean not not that badly anyway so i am i am interested in what's going on
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh yeah</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i'm particularly interested in certain things of course like all the news about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Haiti</ENAMEX> recently because i've been down there
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh yes uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh you've been there well you would be interested in it then
 	
 	
 		and yeah
 		right exactly
 	
 	
 		yeah uh i i follow it you know i don't just read everything about but i i'm always aware of what's going on like that
 	
 	
 		yep
 	
 	
 		and uh because it is it's interesting
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh i i don't know i feel sorry for those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> down there they've just been so
 		terribly mistreated for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">so many many years</TIMEX> you know i mean through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Papa Doc</ENAMEX> i mean he was a terrible tyrant
 	
 	
 		that's true they've never really had a good leader
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it i think it's been better since he died but it's still been bad
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but uh
 		even that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">priest</ENAMEX> that was in control there for a while that they overthrew uh i i've read some things about him that he was he wasn't too good himself
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah he was pretty pretty much a he didn't mind having <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> bumped off for
 		certain things you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh
 	
 	
 		i see
 	
 	
 		that's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one one</NUMEX> of the reasons <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> wasn't so you know didn't do more than they did at the time
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because they weren't all that excited about him although he's probably better than a lot of them but  uh but then again who know you know they're so super so used to it i guess it's the only thing that works
 	
 	
 		yeah so what do you think about the quality of news coverage in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		and not that
 		i think it's pretty darned good i think we're lucky to have as good a coverage as we have
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i really do now i uh they sometimes they jump on it and and and go a little to the extreme the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> does but
 		uh but that's kind of understandable because you know it of course if you watch it more than more than once a day i mean it's the same thing over and over and over and over and i listen to the radio watch
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		so i you hear it so much you get a little tired of it but then again so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you got to understand only catch it once a day maybe
 	
 	
 		yep
 	
 	
 		but i think the quality of our uh our news is just uh i don't believe it could be better
 	
 	
 		um-hum yeah well you know i think it probably could be  it always could be better but i'd agree that it's pretty good
 	
 	
 		i really don't
 		i don't think so
 		i don't think our news could be better
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		i i mean i mean what else could they do to make it better
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		i don't see anything that they could do
 	
 	
 		yeah it well i think that
 		um
 		i don't know
 	
 	
 		well you always wanna think everything can be improved upon i i really i understand what you're saying
 	
 	
 		the uh
 		right right i think that
 	
 	
 		but by trial and error over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> i think they got it about as good as they gonna get it
 	
 	
 		well that may be so yeah uh i think that i'm not always satisfied with how dig they deep into things how deep they dig into the things and such
 	
 	
 		uh nothing is perfect but
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well that's uh that's true i understand what you're saying and then again
 		i understand why they can't dig too much deeper that's why we have <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> you know <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> has the time since that's all they do is news to dig deeper
 	
 	
 		right
 		um-hum right
 		
 		
 	