
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay uh
 		what what is it what does camping mean to you and and
 		what camping have you done
 	
 	
 		oh we've done a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">camping</ENAMEX> actually that's one of our favorite pastimes um  to us camping is is a combination of tent camping as well as environmental camping
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> and i think that really what it means to me is being outdoors in a sort of a wilderness environment and being able to enjoy nature
 		what does it mean to you
 	
 	
 		well what uh uh what what do you mean by environmental camping
 	
 	
 		um there are a number of environmental cabins near where we live that uh offer some sort of dwelling some sort of um security from the elements but there's no electricity no heat no water
 	
 	
 		oh
 		okay
 		but yeah that's neat i'm not not
 		not had that available uh anywhere that i've lived at well uh first
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Park System</ENAMEX> i think is probably what supports a lot of those they're they're state as opposed to county facilities
 	
 	
 		what what <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> is that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> okay i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> and uh uh
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		but most of the camping that we've done we we spent uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">New England</ENAMEX> uh and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and i did a lot of tent camping before uh our first
 	
 	
 		oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> was born uh there in in uh state <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX> in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">New England</ENAMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		here here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> there are are state <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX> where they have uh uh
 	
 	
 		what
 	
 	
 		shelters they're called uh they're wood frame on a concrete slab but screened in
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		kinds of of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shelters</ENAMEX> and uh but they have uh electricity and uh <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> at those cabins and there there's  cabins
 	
 	
 		i see
 		actually in the cabins so it's like uh a a sink
 	
 	
 		well that's the no the uh there's uh
 		one outlet and a light in the cabin uh an overhead one overhead bulb and then just outside the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cabin</ENAMEX> there's a uh
 		faucet uh coming up out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pipe</ENAMEX> coming up out of the ground so that there's access to water like that uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		in in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> what are the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp parks</ENAMEX> like if you go tent camping are you near a real wooded area or does it tend to be more um plains
 	
 	
 		well uh
 		no it's it's the the ones that i'm familiar with are are basically
 		uh basically wooded areas uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> has an awful lot of uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> made lakes
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh uh tend to be uh wooded areas around those lakes i'm in i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> northeast uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		uh-huh what a difference from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">New England</ENAMEX> though i bet
 	
 	
 		yes yes oh yeah yes yes there there you could uh you know depending on what kind of camping you wanted why uh you go an hour in a different direction here you go
 		<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three hours</TIMEX> in any direction and it's still about the same so uh that's a difference but we also
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh uh-huh uh</ENAMEX>-huh well what's it like camping with your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> when he was young
 	
 	
 		well well we didn't we took a break from camping uh for with the the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> until they uh they got into uh scouts basically and uh and then our biggest one we we rented a uh pop up tent trailer
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several years ago</TIMEX> and went up to uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Black Hills</ENAMEX> and back down through the uh uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> uh <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Rocky Mountain National uh Park</ENAMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		oh wow
 		that's a pretty area
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Colorado</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Springs</ENAMEX> area and so forth <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pikes Peak</ENAMEX> and that was a that was a lot of fun
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		i bet it was for them too it's been an experience uh with our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> who's turning <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of days</TIMEX> because she was probably <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six months old</TIMEX> the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time and we had kind of missed camping
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		well i the last time we'd camped before she was born i think i was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight months</TIMEX> pregnant because we like stretched to the very end  and that was a little rough in a tent but uh she's actually done very well and has enjoyed it a lot even even as a little
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh yeah</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> so it's been kind of fun uh trying to adjust our routine and and doing it with with her as she grows up
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah and
 	
 	
 		i'm sure it'll be a lot different when she has a chance to really participate more
 	
 	
 		right right at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">at at at</TIMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> she's old enough to walk but not too far i would guess and and
 	
 	
 		which is what your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> have done
 		right and she's fairly cautious so we're not too concerned about her running into the poison ivy or whatever
 	
 	
 		yeah well  right right but you also don't do a lot of of hiking associated with the camping i i presume yeah yeah well that that sounds good sounds good
 	
 	
 		exactly
 		uh staying close to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp ground</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh
 	
 	
 		well it sounds like you've um continued it no matter where you've been and how your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>'s grown so  that's my aspiration as well
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah and   uh uh and and uh
 		although it it after a while it gets uh with teenage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> at this point well one's uh in college but uh uh
 	
 	
 		oh wow cool
 	
 	
 		uh it it turns different in that uh the problem becomes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of getting getting time when they're available and don't have other activities uh
 	
 	
 		right right well i guess it
 		
 		
 	