
 
     		
 	
 		well what i believe is one of the major problems uh things that is wrong with our public school system is that um we do not have enough
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		discipline and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> do not let the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> discipline the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> the way that they need to be disciplined right now
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh uh</ENAMEX>-huh i agree with that
 	
 	
 		
 
 		uh when i went to school i know i was scared to death
 	
 	
 		you were
 	
 	
 		about being disciplined and the discipline that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> receives now in going to school it's just totally different
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know you just you did not see i did not see anybody in my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">classrooms</ENAMEX> when i was going to school act up the way that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> do <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> in the classroom
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah yeah from what i understand they act up pretty bad
 	
 	
 		yeah  that's right that's right
 	
 	
 		what uh grade is your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> in
 	
 	
 		my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>'s in the um <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> grade and um there's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">classroom</ENAMEX> that just totally disrupt
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">classroom</ENAMEX> where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> cannot teach and when i went to school that just wasn't put up with
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh no huh-uh they always had paddle in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">our school</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh-huh well they they they just don't do that anymore the the school system's afraid of getting sued and um
 	
 	
 		i know
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		all sorts of lawsuits i'm sure because of things like that and i also believe we don't
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		even though i feel like i pay a good share towards the school system that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> are still underpaid and we still don't have enough money towards putting toward public schools
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and um i think that if we had enough money and paid the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> a little bit more that maybe that can solve some of our
 		problems
 	
 	
 		yeah wasn't that what part of the lottery's gonna go for if we approve it uh-huh uh-huh
 	
 	
 		yes  supposedly that's what it's suppose to go for and you know we'll just have to wait and see whether that's proved or not you know i don't know your feelings toward that i guess we shouldn't get into that but um  and what else um
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i think in some ways that they need to be more careful of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> that they hire
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i have heard stories um from other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> that i know of when their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are in high school that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> are out there giving <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> and selling drugs
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		no really ooh
 	
 	
 		oh yeah oh i've i've heard some horrible horrible stories about high school high school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> and you know to be more be more careful of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> that we place in our schools
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		um-hum hm
 	
 	
 		um that's basically about all that i know that may be wrong with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school systems</ENAMEX> i think with what they have to work with i think they're doing a pretty good job right now
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh i do too i think they're doing real good job
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		but then what do i know i don't have any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>  no none at all
 	
 	
 		you don't have any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in school you don't have any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>  yeah okay so this is probably a real hard subject for you
 	
 	
 		oh yeah  so
 	
 	
 		yeah  okay well i guess um we can discontinue our call now it was a joy in talking with you
 	
 	
 		okay well it's good talking to you too we'll see you bye-bye
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">okay</ENAMEX> thanks bye-bye
 		
 		
 	