
 
     		
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh</ENAMEX> did you hear i guess you heard the subject right
 	
 	
 		
 
 		uh right magazines
 	
 	
 		right well i tell you i'm about a magazine junkie so this is right up my alley
 	
 	
 		oh good okay well go ahead and start and pick one
 	
 	
 		okay well see i subscribe to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Consumer Report Texas Monthly D Time</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s now getting Hotrod
 		and then i pick up <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Money</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> and then a couple of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s you know if when i stroll through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">supermarket</ENAMEX>  and uh i don't know i just love <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX>  for some reason
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		i even like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">People</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> but i hate to buy it because you can read it in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty minutes</TIMEX> and then you feel like you wasted your money you know   oh
 	
 	
 		well let's see i subscribe to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Appetite uh Vogue Bazaar</ENAMEX> and um a home decorating <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> that's all i can think of
 	
 	
 		oh
 		i bet your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> looks nice and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX> is decorated the way it was seventeen <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		oh i'm afraid i'm afraid i'm not a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> by the looks of this <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> i need to get a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> in here to help me out  but i do like to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cook</ENAMEX> or i used to seems like
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		you know the busier you get the that kind of lose you lose out on that some
 	
 	
 		it is it's difficult well let's see you you have one in particular that oh i subscribed to at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time and haven't for some time but i think is really interesting is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Consumer Reports</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right yeah we do subscribe to that it is interesting and you really get some surprises in there too and if if you would read it religiously you would save a lot of money
 	
 	
 		do you go ahead
 		well do you actually act on any of the uh tips that they give you
 	
 	
 		oh yes i i we really do uh go out and look for some of the brands you know and then then we'll lose the copies or  some'll get thrown away and we'll get sloppy you know
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		but uh uh many many times we have acted on it yeah because sometimes the cheaper brand is is better than a leading one you know
 	
 	
 		it's one i probably ought to resubscribe to you know particularly if you're getting ready to buy some kind of a major product
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but it's interesting even with the everyday you know like the shampoos and all um they had one i recall not too many <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> that they were talking about the various brands of shampoos and how uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh yeah i remember that
 	
 	
 		yeah and the most expensive ones were not the ones that they recommended
 	
 	
 		i know they've done that before on uh mascara and different kinds of makeup too well you know i was at a a wedding reception once and there was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> there that was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chemist</ENAMEX> for one of the oh who is that uh famous makeup <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Kay</ENAMEX> i think it was
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and she said well the truth of the matter was there was just only a handful of basic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">products</ENAMEX> you could make <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cosmetics</ENAMEX> out of anyway so they were nearly all pretty similar
 	
 	
 		i kind of have heard that too but you know how much do you want to pay uh for the brand to feel glamorous or whatever uh-huh exactly
 	
 	
 		right
 		for the packaging
 		so uh and that always stood out in my mind and i really buy a lot of cheap uh lipsticks and i think they're just as pretty and they last as long as the real expensive ones
 	
 	
 		well i only do <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maybelline</ENAMEX> mascara because i think it's the best i guess they're gonna kill us if we talk about our <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cosmetics</ENAMEX> instead of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> but
 	
 	
 		right yeah that's what i have
 		oh that's right i forgot i wonder who has to listen to all this garbage
 	
 	
 		i don't know it's got to be a boring job
 	
 	
 		i know this is only my <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> call i just kept forgetting about it and then my phone wasn't working and i'd get a call <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every now and then</TIMEX> and i'd put my PIN number in and they'd say this is incorrect then then somebody suggested it was the phone sure enough we had a new phone
 		and so now i had to switch phones so i'm just trying to make some calls and catch up how many have you made
 	
 	
 		
 
 		ah i was in the project oh maybe <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six or eight months ago</TIMEX> ah and then oh i made maybe <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">five six seven</NUMEX> and then they had some problems on the system and i just kind of got out of it and this is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> since they brought it back up again that i have done
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right uh
 	
 	
 		but um from what i understand they get <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from all over the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> but i i
 	
 	
 		yeah my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> was on it last time well we didn't know it was only supposed to be my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> so anytime anybody called we punched in number and talked well that got to and she talked to somebody several times from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 		i've never gotten anyone outside the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> area
 	
 	
 		well me either i i was uh in fact i haven't gotten anyone over here i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arlington</ENAMEX> i usually get <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garland</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mesquite</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> but it's kind of interesting isn't it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yes it is
 	
 	
 		i know i wonder if it's really gonna help them
 	
 	
 		well it helps us with our <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five dollars</NUMEX> a call
 	
 	
 		oh i know did you get a present or money last time
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		we we got a what what was it my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> works for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> so we couldn't get the money we had to choose something but it was neat we got a camera and he got a real nice attache case which he needed anyway
 	
 	
 		well that's fun
 	
 	
 		right do y'all work for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> or you just heard about it
 	
 	
 		no just a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of mine ah introduced me to it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh okay i'm gonna get us back on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> so we can okay now i'm gonna ask you your opinion of the the perfume tear strip in magazines when you get those
 	
 	
 		oh right right
 		well i like them i've heard <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are allergic to them or something
 	
 	
 		i do too i think they're great
 		well if you do nothing else with them i tear them out of the books and put them in my lingerie drawers or something
 	
 	
 		i just read about that in the paper <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX> and uh i need to do that that's a great idea  no i like them a lot and uh i've bought you know
 	
 	
 		sure
 		
 		
 	