
 
     		
 	
 		feel about this
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well i've i've seen all kinds of carnage and i'm very much in favor of laws to restrict the access to <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i am too
 	
 	
 		um i you know i cannot understand the the argument on the other side
 	
 	
 		yeah i i hear the argument of um you don't have anything to protect yourself with and
 		and all this that i just i don't know
 		i don't know there's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> at work you know that's trying to get a gun for his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> because she works in a divorce
 		type position and she's scared that somebody might turn on her sometime and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i'm like why do <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> need <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> in their desk at work i just don't understand that
 	
 	
 		i don't understand either now there probably there probably are cases of  certain occupations certain actually certain <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> in certain occupations who would
 	
 	
 		but
 		right
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		for whom that may be legitimate uh
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but there whole <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> where <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> are banned uh i think in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United Kingdom</ENAMEX> and then in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		where the homicide rates are far far lower than the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> i don't see how it possibly
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		makes sense for us to have all these <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> lying about
 	
 	
 		oh i don't either and you can go to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> and pick out which one you want and just you know it's it's weird to have something like that you know i've never been a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hunter</ENAMEX> or been around anything like that that
 		um there have been <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> or anything like that and to see those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> having you know like you see on the news these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> like are you in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> or
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		no i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> okay well we just had an accident accident here that um a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fifteen year old</TIMEX> got into a fight uh you know like you always do in school high school you know you always had little fights with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		well he had a fight with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> and his older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> who's eighteen came to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and shot the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		and killed him and i'm like what in the world are these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and then they confiscated <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">twenty three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> from that high school out of lockers
 		and it's like i just can't understand why these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> have guns
 	
 	
 		that's amazing that's amazing yeah
 	
 	
 		it's just awful
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah well it happens a lot around here too um in fact maybe even worse in terms of frequency
 	
 	
 		to see something like that
 		does it
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh drive by shootings in high <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> are you know
 	
 	
 		yeah we had quite a few drive by shootings recently with buses
 		of um you know that
 		public transportation <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">buses</ENAMEX> and like i think <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were killed during that when they were having just <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> were driving by and shooting out the windows
 	
 	
 		yes
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh and then we had that killing you know in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Killeen</ENAMEX>
 		i don't know if you heard about that
 	
 	
 		yes i uh everybody heard about that
 	
 	
 		yeah i think so and that happened and that was something else and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		so i'm i'm i think on the scale at the one end you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		i'd i'd be close to the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight nine</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> area
 	
 	
 		wait wait i thought i i <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight nine ten</NUMEX> was no restrictions
 	
 	
 		oh i thought <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> was the best oh i'm sorry
 	
 	
 		whatever whatever we're down at the same end whatever end that is
 	
 	
 		heavy duty restrictions  that's i feel in favor for because you just can't be handing these things out to anybody
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and and you're getting them sold to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and then they're getting into the wrong hands
 	
 	
 		yeah would you somehow get them away from those who already have them
 	
 	
 		what's that
 	
 	
 		would you somehow disarm those who are already armed
 	
 	
 		um
 		yes
 	
 	
 		how would you do that
 	
 	
 		um  do you you know do they don't they have records of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who own the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">um guns</ENAMEX> that were bought isn't there
 	
 	
 		in many cases not uh because many cases they're
 	
 	
 		yeah i know it
 	
 	
 		they're stolen um
 	
 	
 		right underground type
 	
 	
 		i i have no idea what the statistics are on that but um
 	
 	
 		underground type uh selling of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah i don't know how you know it's gonna it's gonna have to happen sometime but it right now there hasn't been a way
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah i don't i don't
 		know this for a absolute fact but i have the suspicion that the gun industry that manufactures
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		these things and also those who <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealers</ENAMEX> who sell them are a major force behind the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NRA</ENAMEX> and all these campaigns that that stir <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> up and try to get them to uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		to uh not ban them
 	
 	
 		yeah to to to right to oppose them
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		it  because they have an economic reason over and above whatever their their private preferences are
 	
 	
 		oh sure
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah it it's a tough thing
 	
 	
 		until the thing has to be won on an economic ground too
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		so there has to be some way to compensate those who lose and um
 	
 	
 		so that they don't keep you know saying don't ban so um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right
 	
 	
 		yeah it's it's tough i don't know what they're gonna do and
 		you know i there's got to be a way to get them out of the hands of and plus for them to when they do have them to
 		you know they keep them in these areas where their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> can get to them and and hurt so you know and they're young enough they don't even know what they're playing with they're playing with something they saw on TV
 	
 	
 		if
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh you know it's it's not safe at all
 		for um
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> in the home even because they don't keep them under lock and key anyway they keep them in their top drawer or
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and then they say well if we unload them then how are we gonna have time to load them
 		
 		
 	