
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh well i i i guess it's a subject i haven't thought too much about uh i don't know if there's so much wrong with the public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> uh as much as we're expecting too much out of them
 	
 	
 		uh that might be a lot to do with it i know a lot of it here in my <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> i'm from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mississippi</ENAMEX> i'm not sure where you're from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota</ENAMEX> okay well a lot of it in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mississippi</ENAMEX> here is got to do with funding
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Minnesota Wisconsin</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		problems with our education system a lot of it's due money and they're trying to spend money where we don't have it and there's a lot of things we need that we just can't afford
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah well it's it it is getting very expensive to run <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> so they got computers now that you got to train on there's just so much uh more
 	
 	
 		well it is
 		right
 	
 	
 		and less money to do it with
 	
 	
 		that's true and a lot of it lot of it has to do with uh salaries too speaking of money because if you can't pay the right <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you know they're not going to be able to do they're not not gonna get the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that can do a good job
 	
 	
 		all right yeah
 		yeah yeah i i i guess that in uh
 		talking on lot of the things as far as the discipline in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> i i think they're
 		expecting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> to discipline the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and uh i think it should go right back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> if you don't train your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> right then
 	
 	
 		right i feel the same
 		right i feel the same way a lot's got to do with how the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> were raised at home
 	
 	
 		right yeah
 	
 	
 		and then when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> get to school they try to take away a lot of things that they can do to discipline the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> i mean they've so severely severely severely limited
 		what disciplinary action you can do
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		i i know when i uh was going to school it it wasn't uncommon for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> to strike a student that was misbehaving i mean they do that now and they could probably lose their job
 	
 	
 		exactly right
 		lose their job and and big lawsuit and all that
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		i feel that's got a lot to do with it <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> aren't as afraid of misbehaving as they used to be
 	
 	
 		right right
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh</ENAMEX> seems uh a be a subject that i i don't have much to say on
 	
 	
 		really we've we've talked some about it in my <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> because we've have a lot of uh problems well our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> that just got thrown out of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> was trying to be real big on education but he wasn't
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and a lot of his problems had to do with money mostly i know a lot a lot of if you have more money it's just logical that you can provide a better school system
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and unfortunately there's not many places to get that money
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		then if you don't have
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		qualified <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> in the different subject areas i know one of my physics <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professors</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> has has addressed this that
 		most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> at the um elementary and high school level aren't <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> they're <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> and they may not know a lot about what they're teaching
 		where as they may have just had a teaching major
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		and then had some social studies <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courses</ENAMEX> and they're trying to teach social studies and they don't know a lot about that
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		where maybe a physics <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> he my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> was a physics <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> and he said a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> teaching physics <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> have no background in physics at the high school level
 		so therefore they're teaching from a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX>'s point of view and not from a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicist</ENAMEX> point of view and that causes a lot of trouble
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah
 		i don't know  maybe they should sit back and and kind of uh
 		decide on where the money's best spent i know
 		in lot of cases uh different <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">districts</ENAMEX> like to have nice fancy schools
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and maybe they should be a little more uh
 		uh concerned with paying the right <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to teach and and be uh satisfied with maybe a little older school
 	
 	
 		exactly because i mean here in uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">county</ENAMEX> where i went to high school
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the the four</TIMEX> high <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> in my <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">county</ENAMEX> one of the high <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> was blown away by a tornado
 		so when they rebuilt that school they had a a top of the line high tech <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> there and the other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> were built back in maybe the fifties or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early sixties</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then when uh evaluation <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committees</ENAMEX> came through they praised the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> that had been rebuilt while they were down grading all these other ones telling them what they need to do to fix up this building and this and this and this
 		and so it it kind of would make you think that we'd all be better off if all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> were blown away by tornadoes and we had to rebuild them
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		well i i i know uh where i came from uh we didn't have a very
 		uh rich <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> and uh
 		high <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> that i went to was
 		uh very old and um as far as uh i know it's still there they've expanded expanded on it but they've never build a new one and it's probably fifty <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixty years old</TIMEX> or or better
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		i don't foresee them uh building a new one for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time</TIMEX> because they can't afford it
 	
 	
 		exactly that's
 		
 		
 	