
 
     		
 	
 		okay what uh what do you mean by camping
 	
 	
 		
 
 		uh well i work i work out at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scarborough Fair</ENAMEX> down <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Waxahachie</ENAMEX> and i'd i'd camp out there during the uh the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the open season</TIMEX> that we're open down there so i've got my tent and my all that stuff going and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		tent sleeping bag and i i just leave it all down there over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX> or during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX> while i'm gone and and come back and crawl in and everything's
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right where i left it i don't have to set it up once a week or anything like that but it's a lot easier
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> so like camping to you means tent camping and sleeping bag and to some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people camping</ENAMEX>'s going out you know in a motor home
 	
 	
 		yeah that's  that's that's those the the the wimps way out to rough it  but uh
 	
 	
 		oh no camping camping to me is
 		you you know like the question said there's different types of camping and going out in a tent and not being around any sort of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities shower facilities</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bathroom facilities</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		uh i don't like to get that extreme
 	
 	
 		i don't i don't really particularly care for that you know i don't mind staying in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tents</ENAMEX> with sleeping bags and everything but i like you know a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bathroom</ENAMEX> near or shower near
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah that's that's what's nice about working out at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scarborough</ENAMEX> and the uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> have a uh a a separate shower thing that we all are go use and everything so don't have to bother with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Port</ENAMEX>-a-Pots or anything like that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right you know when when i was younger i would go up into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> and you know and we'd go up and we'd hike up into the mountains and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> with tents you know and we wouldn't have anything and now that i've gotten a little older
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		a little like some of the finer things in life  yeah i  i was in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boy Scouts</ENAMEX> when i was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> and so i i've done  dealt with all that fun stuff
 	
 	
 		right  like
 		right i don't like to go camping now and stay in a tent without one of the big thick air mattresses to sleep on because  ground's a little bit
 	
 	
 		yeah i i
 		i i keep a uh one of those uh those banana <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lounge</ENAMEX> chairs that have the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> parts that fold on it
 	
 	
 		um-hum right
 	
 	
 		i unfold one of those and throw my sleeping bag on it and if i have to crawl in i crawl in if not i just lay on top of it you know depending on how cold it is whatever  and i i i never touch the floor
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right i i've tried those too  only part of those is that that they're really not wide enough for your <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX> to have any place to hang down you know
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah yeah uh i can get comfortable anywhere  but uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like to use the uh the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coleman</ENAMEX> uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cook stoves</ENAMEX> and stuff no uh uh real fire real fire got to have a fire pit
 	
 	
 		um-hum right
 		no
 		yeah i i don't either you know some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> even bring charcoal with them  and um
 	
 	
 		yeah charcoal charcoal is nice if the ground is sopping wet otherwise  grab a dead tree
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah that's that's what i like to use and they just kind of look at me and go well why are you gonna go to that trouble we have this <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coleman</ENAMEX> stove here
 	
 	
 		because i want i want my <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> to taste like i just cooked it over a you know a fire pit not over
 	
 	
 		i just look at them and go
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		propane
 	
 	
 		that's like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that bring instant <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX> with them too and heat up their <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> and i go what's wrong with the coffee pot you
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		what's wrong with the good old <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX> pot throw the grounds in heat the water up
 	
 	
 		yeah  that's right well i enjoyed talking with you
 	
 	
 		okay thank you
 	
 	
 		thank you bye-bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	