
 
     		
 	
 		what <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> are you
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well pretty pretty familiar with we moved here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about six months ago</TIMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year ago</TIMEX> so i'm pretty familiar with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mavericks</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		most familiar with
 		yeah where'd you move from
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well yeah the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Mavericks uh</ENAMEX> have done fairly well in the past but doesn't look like they're going to do too good this year
 	
 	
 		nope not doesn't look like
 	
 	
 		maybe maybe they'll surprise us though reckon
 	
 	
 		yeah that would be a big surprise
 	
 	
 		it would be a big surprise
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah do you do you follow basketball
 	
 	
 		oh i kind of follow it a little bit i'm not a great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> of it but uh you know i read a little bit about it and follow it on the radio and everything
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but i was glad to see them get rid of that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> Tarpley although by far the best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> they've ever had i guess
 	
 	
 		Tarpley
 		
 
 		yeah i think he i think he he was i i think it went on went on too long  you want to get her out of here
 	
 	
 		yeah it did it did and and they had to do they had to get rid of him
 		but i couldn't believe they'd given him a contract like they had where that they couldn't get rid of him
 	
 	
 		yeah well they already he already had uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> strikes against him when they gave him that contract
 	
 	
 		yeah uh
 		i guess they felt like that was enough that
 		you know
 		uh if that you know if if they had to get out of it they could and they wouldn't want out of it unless he did something wrong
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		if he did that well that'd cancel the contract i guess
 	
 	
 		no that's true that's right if you get the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> strike they can break the contract and if doesn't you want to pay him that much money because he's that good
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yes that's right he'd be worth it yeah he'd be worth it
 	
 	
 		yeah that makes sense
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh</ENAMEX> did you uh see the score of their <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> game against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Antonio</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but there's gonna
 		oh they got blasted didn't they
 	
 	
 		yeah they lost by uh <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">forty</NUMEX> or fifty points <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">hundred</TIMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		that was unbelievable i i'd i hadn't seen that score i just heard somebody talking about they'd gotten beaten real bad
 	
 	
 		yep
 	
 	
 		and uh but i think they did better last night though didn't they
 	
 	
 		yeah they lost in overtime by a point or two
 	
 	
 		yeah so that was a good game i guess
 	
 	
 		yep
 	
 	
 		i i really don't follow them that closely there although there was a good article <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> in the in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunday Magazine</ENAMEX> about uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brad Davis</ENAMEX> did you read that
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh yeah
 		nope nope what did it say
 	
 	
 		course uh
 		well it just uh this is going to be his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> but it just you know he just been it's amazing that he's one of the original Mavericks you know still playing
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 		hm yeah i don't think i was aware of that he was an original Maverick huh
 	
 	
 		he is the only original Maverick yeah  he started out with them when they started
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and has made just to make the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> since then so and you know you don't you don't make the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> if you're not any good
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yep
 	
 	
 		so he's done well <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six hundred thousand</NUMEX> a year
 	
 	
 		is that right that's what he makes
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and he's worth it i guess
 	
 	
 		well how do you think they'll finish this year
 	
 	
 		i mean
 		huh
 	
 	
 		not too good i imagine what do you think
 	
 	
 		no i don't see how that nah they won't even
 	
 	
 		they don't they won't
 	
 	
 		they won't even come close to the play-offs  i don't think
 	
 	
 		hm i don't think so they're now they're aiming trying they're wishfully hoping i mean they've lowered their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> from play-off to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">maybe five hundred</NUMEX> which and that's probably a pretty big stretch
 	
 	
 		they what
 		yeah yeah
 		that's a big stretch probably yeah and uh but boy they you know they've had some darn good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> in the past
 	
 	
 		yep
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i guess that's why it's so hard to swallow you know right off the bat they started doing well
 		but
 	
 	
 		yep how do they you kind of wonder how they let themselves get to where they have such an old team
 	
 	
 		yeah it makes you they've had some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX> problems over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> uh
 		Motta was probably the best they've ever had or ever will have but he i don't know he just he was such a hot head
 		that he just quit <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> once he made up his mind to do something like that he gone he don't change his mind
 		but he was by far i think the best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX> they ever had
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but he couldn't get along with
 	
 	
 		with who
 	
 	
 		i i mean Aguirre
 	
 	
 		oh Aguirre
 	
 	
 		yeah Aguirre
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh he he had a hot temper
 	
 	
 		yeah i haven't followed them too close until uh we moved we moved here i you know i remember seeing them in the play-offs <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of years ago</TIMEX> i guess
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah probably yeah <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at least two years ago</TIMEX> or longer
 	
 	
 		it yeah
 	
 	
 		but they did they used to have some darned good <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh
 		i've always been a and i don't follow basketball that closely but i've always been a a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Celtics</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> because i love i love to watch <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Bird</ENAMEX> play
 	
 	
 		uh-huh  yeah i like watching the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Celtics</ENAMEX> play they're uh they play uh have played a good brand of basketball it's real teamwork oriented
 	
 	
 		always you can always count on them playing a good brand of basketball
 		and of course so you can the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lakers</ENAMEX> so can you depend on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lakers</ENAMEX> for doing that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i don't know i just always liked old
 		old <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Bird</ENAMEX> he just can do things that
 		i don't think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX> are supposed to be able to do with a basketball you know him and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Magic Johnson</ENAMEX> and old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jordan</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but we'll have to keep our fingers crossed i guess for the old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mavericks</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah it'll take at least that
 	
 	
 		well and they got a they got a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> i mean he's willing to spend the bucks to get what they need so i think it's just a just a matter of time till they it may take them a couple of years
 	
 	
 		well i imagine it will they're down to i mean like their top there's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> of their starting <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five</TIMEX> are like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> over you know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty three thirty</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh yeah</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so you're talking you're talking about pretty well having to rebuild from scratch
 	
 	
 		and that that's
 		yeah that's just too old for a <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yep
 	
 	
 		man old old <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Johnson</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	