
 
     		
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jay</ENAMEX> um my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are are both in college um
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and i'd played i played a fairly active part in helping them decide where to go on the other hand they really decided themselves um what what kind of experience did you have
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well i uh
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> went in in state and has graduated and then uh that was um
 		you know that was her choice pretty much where she wanted to go and i have uh one out of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> out of state both in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Missouri</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and um i teach uh in a college and so i had they had heard me talk about it and for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i didn't think it really made too much difference where they went for their undergraduate
 		uh
 		so that was pretty much uh
 	
 	
 		hm
 		i see well i maybe maybe i'm wrong but i think it makes a big difference in terms of finding a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> that is sort of right for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> in terms of
 		his or her happiness and and and the appropriate support environment and things like that
 	
 	
 		oh they if they if they're content there but i mean as far as the education and as far as looking at the degree at the end that uh to it's very little difference is paid to it where you get that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bachelor</ENAMEX>'s
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh if it's a halfway decent school they should be happy naturally and if they can get uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> out of let's see
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> got a full total uh scholarships and so there's uh there's plenty of scholarships out there and so <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> should be advised to
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		to look for those and um
 	
 	
 		did did you play a a strong role in helping them pick <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> or did you just sort of say listen to your uh guidance <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counselors</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		uh
 		well they uh i went we went around my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> was a graduated from a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jesuit</ENAMEX> high school and so he he was pretty much looking for a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jesuit</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX> and so there were you know that was limited to
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> different places and um so he's in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saint Louis U</ENAMEX> and i
 		guess i played a role in that i i just sort of uh let them um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know they'd all been uh pretty uh  efficient as far as studies and and uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so i didn't have that much to do they just uh they just knew they wanted to go to college and and i you know helped them uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh get there as far as uh traveling with them to look at different places we did do that and i would suggest a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> always goes and looks at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> before they sign up
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		yeah i think think that's a great idea i mean that
 	
 	
 		some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't do it and then they get there and
 		hate it or or whatever so
 	
 	
 		right it's it it seems expensive at the time you're doing it but but the compared to the the total decision it's nothing
 	
 	
 		if it's possible
 		right
 		
 
 		i think in the short run it is expensive in the long run it's very uh reasonable if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> that's been in in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Missouri</ENAMEX> uh for a
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> now she's coming home at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the semester</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so uh you know she's already <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty one</TIMEX> she started late so that's you know strictly up to her and uh she'll finish down here um um finish <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> down here and then decide what she's gonna do next year
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it'll save me a lot of money because i'm not going to have to pay out of state tuition but again that's her decision
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right
 	
 	
 		so uh but i have so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> in my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classes</ENAMEX> that have dropped out and come back and they're much better <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty five twenty six maybe twenty eight</TIMEX>
 		so you know i don't i never have pushed them i just say that education is important you should do it
 		uh but uh they have to do the work
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so uh
 	
 	
 		you know well back back to this visiting thing i mean i found that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> had no conception of what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> was really like <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">um</ENAMEX> and and that the process of going around to a few <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> with them really helped them understand
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and being able to go with them to some at least some of them  you know it had gave me a chance to explain things to them in terms uh in reference to what we had seen
 	
 	
 		oh i think so
 		and also i'm opposed to the to the size does they've just gotten so huge and so my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> first looked at a place that was <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">forty thousand</NUMEX> see that's just too many
 	
 	
 		good grief
 	
 	
 		ended up going to where i used to go and that was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty five hundred</TIMEX> when i went there it's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty one thousand now</TIMEX> it's too big
 	
 	
 		good grief what is what is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">twenty one thousand</NUMEX> what what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> is that
 	
 	
 		so uh
 		pardon it's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southwest Missouri State University</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and um it was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty five hundred</TIMEX> when i went there forty <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> and uh
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> is in a school <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about seven thousand</NUMEX> and that's that's not bad i teach in a school <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about eight thousand</NUMEX> and that's that's even a little large but it's much better than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">twenty one thousand</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yes
 	
 	
 		but they do have to visit and and if if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> can point out all the different places to look for for scholarships and then
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh those rating uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> and all those things are doing the ratings now and everything i don't
 		think it hurts to look at them i don't put that much stock in them but probably fine just to compare
 	
 	
 		yes
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		helps helps to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least</NUMEX> set up range of things to look at
 	
 	
 		right and uh if they you know uh they need to
 		
 		
 	