
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		is that right
 	
 	
 		right now what was your name again
 	
 	
 		okay well well my name's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry</ENAMEX> where do you golf at
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry</ENAMEX> okay
 		well i don't uh much well actually hardly at all i um the only times that i've actually golfed is we we were uh going to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> reunion up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maine</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX>
 		and a bunch of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>-in-laws and whatever else would go out and play like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">couple</NUMEX> times during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX> that we were all there um
 		i've done that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about three or four</NUMEX> times i guess
 	
 	
 		i see so you're from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maine</ENAMEX> originally then
 	
 	
 		no i'm from uh uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but we've got my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>'s from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maine</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well i'm originally from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nebraska</ENAMEX> and really didn't play much golf there until i moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Dakota</ENAMEX> and we lived on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">golf course</ENAMEX> and i took up uh golf at that time and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		really enjoyed it and uh then when we moved to Plano
 		i really haven't had uh we've lived here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> now and i really haven't uh golfed a lot but those times that i have been out i went to the uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">uh Plano Municipal Golf Course</ENAMEX> and then i've golfed uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">couple</NUMEX> times uh at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chase Oaks</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and that's very challenging at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chase Oaks</ENAMEX> uh lot of water
 	
 	
 		what's it cost to to play at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">at now</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh if i go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Municipal Course</ENAMEX> it's uh maybe <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty five</TIMEX> dollars for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighteen</NUMEX> holes and uh seems to me that when i was at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chase Oaks</ENAMEX> uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well of course i took my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> with me so we were close to you know fifty dollars or so
 	
 	
 		it's pretty expensive isn't it
 	
 	
 		it really is
 	
 	
 		yeah real expensive actually
 	
 	
 		but uh i enjoy it probably uh it depends on which day i go uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		as to which part is most challenging
 	
 	
 		um-hum what do you shoot what do you shoot when you were playing
 	
 	
 		oh probably uh for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> um i i i've felt pretty good with maybe a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">forty one forty two around</NUMEX> in there
 	
 	
 		well that's not bad at all i that would make you about eighty or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty two</NUMEX> for for eighteen
 	
 	
 		that'd be a that'd be a darn good game for me yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah but that's pretty that's pretty good shooting
 	
 	
 		yeah i'm i'm happy with that
 	
 	
 		yeah well what do you what do you uh what do you find attractive about playing <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">golf</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well i think what i find attractive is when i can go out uh with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and uh on a nice day just to be out uh and stay
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry</ENAMEX>  hold on a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>  <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Jerry</ENAMEX> she's about to get my cord
 	
 	
 		uh oh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">baby</ENAMEX> we got a loose connection on this phone
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh just uh i i guess the thing that i like most about it is getting away from work and uh a although uh if i am jogging or working out or playing <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">golf</ENAMEX> or whatever it's a
 		a time to get away from things but yet sometimes things become more a little more clearer that way too
 	
 	
 		yeah well i i liked uh we i probably played maybe <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five or six times</TIMEX> but we did that
 		and uh but what i liked about it was i could i could uh i liked being outside
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> and of course the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">golf courses</ENAMEX> uh are are beautiful the one that we played at in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maine</ENAMEX> was real pretty and you could be with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and yet ooh ooh uh so you had nice you had company and stuff but then significant portions of the time you were off
 		in an area of the course by yourself too which uh it was kind of um  the best of both
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		both worlds actually
 	
 	
 		yeah that's nice i'm uh you know it it bothers me when uh especially in this particular area there are so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that play <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">golf</ENAMEX> that you tend to uh
 		you have a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> there and feel hurried and i don't i don't like to feel rushed when i'm playing <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">golf</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		what's uh what's what do you do best on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">golf course</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but
 		oh you know it it really varies from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX> to day uh if i'm if i'm on i uh really can hit uh hit my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX> pretty well
 	
 	
 		is that right
 	
 	
 		and uh that's that's a new experience for me because for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a year to two years</TIMEX> uh i couldn't hit my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX> i had such a hook
 		that uh i would just use a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> iron all the time and i could hit my <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">three iron</NUMEX> just about as far as anybody else could hit a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX> so i used that but then i took a few lessons and really uh worked on it and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh you took lessons
 	
 	
 		uh yeah we had a golf pro uh and i took maybe <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two or three</NUMEX> lessons basically uh and uh had a golf pro and and uh it was like maybe <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty five</TIMEX> dollars for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a half an hour</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh he really helped a lot
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		do you own your own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clubs</ENAMEX> i guess you probably do don't you
 	
 	
 		yep yeah i uh uh got a pair of used <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clubs</ENAMEX> for a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas present one year</TIMEX> and uh so before that i'd been using uh
 	
 	
 		is that right
 	
 	
 		my little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>'s uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s set  and i thought boy <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first day</TIMEX> i got those uh new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clubs</ENAMEX> i'd go out and uh really uh knock them dead and uh it takes a while to get used to a new set of clubs
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		hum
 		my uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> plays a lot like every weekend
 		up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		is he pretty good golfer
 	
 	
 		well you know yeah he shoots well he shoots eighties you know which which i think that's pretty good you know
 	
 	
 		good
 		we uh probably my the most exciting experience i had playing <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">golf</ENAMEX> was over in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX> we took a vacation and uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> and i went out brother-in-law went out and uh
 	
 	
 		uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		played in uh
 		
 		
 	