
 
     		
 	
 		kind of options do you have in your work
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> as far as other than salary like the fringe benefits um  we get of course insurance paid  we get our sick leave and and holidays paid
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		that's nice
 	
 	
 		uh earn vacation and uh of course the work place is is uh very
 		uh it's a very nice area to work in
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um how about you
 	
 	
 		well we don't get much
 	
 	
 		you don't
 	
 	
 		no we don't um we have to pay for our own insurance
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and we you know we do get the vacation but we don't get sick pay until we've been there a year
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then um i think it starts after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four days</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		if you've been gone <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> consecutive <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> then you get <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> of sick pay
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		um it's real tough
 	
 	
 		the
 	
 	
 		for benefits
 	
 	
 		the sick leave is according according to the status the way you're employed it has something to with the the way you earn your sick leave and uh you don't automatically get it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		depends on your status
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh but uh really can't complain course the cost of uh living keeps going up salaries remain about the same and your medical benefits go up also
 	
 	
 		that's the truth
 		uh-huh if you can get some good medical benefits it makes a big difference
 	
 	
 		it it surely does especially if you have a family
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		i don't but i know when you have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and you don't
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it can get to be quite expensive
 	
 	
 		yeah i don't have any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> but i do have my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> gets um insurance paid through his company
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but it's still cheaper for me to pay for mine through my job than it is to get onto his
 	
 	
 		is that right
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		gee i i didn't realize that
 	
 	
 		so
 		until he's been there a little longer then maybe i can you know get into that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but a little better but um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right now
 	
 	
 		well do you think then salary is the most important
 	
 	
 		no i really don't i really think that benefits
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		um help out a lot
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know with the positions um
 		uh benefits you know like you said are are almost better you know that's a lot of pay
 	
 	
 		that's true
 	
 	
 		if you thought if you think about health because i think my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and i went to um get health insurance from an outside <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> once
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it would cost just me alone <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">two hundred dollars</NUMEX> a month
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		to get basic health insurance and if you think about that on top of your pay it makes a big difference
 	
 	
 		i know that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> recently retired well not recently maybe <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last six eight years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh they had to uh buy a policy until
 		something kicked in at a certain age and they were paying an enormous amount of money per month
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		it is unbelievable
 	
 	
 		in order to maintain it really is
 	
 	
 		and then my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> have that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blue Blue Cross Blue Shield</ENAMEX> and i think that goes up <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every month</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		that is just something else
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because they're you know at the retirement age and
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and that's something too that's just unbelievable
 	
 	
 		i know some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> when you do retire you're able to carry forward your retire your insurance benefits
 	
 	
 		oh well that would be great
 	
 	
 		wouldn't that be wonderful
 	
 	
 		that would be nice  yes it would
 	
 	
 		
 
 		but uh i don't know i don't know what else would there be besides your insurance and your <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">holiday</TIMEX> paid and
 	
 	
 		yeah my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> gets uh life insurance dental insurance and um
 		life and dental and and health
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and then he also gets legal help legal aid
 	
 	
 		oh uh-huh
 	
 	
 		and he also gets like he's entered into a credit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		oh yeah we have that
 	
 	
 		and and all that that kind of helps out
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> now that's true now we've started the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">EA</ENAMEX> where you can um if you have like a mental health problem
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		a drug problem or what have you
 		uh mentally they they will provide services for that now too and that's wonderful uh
 	
 	
 		well that's nice
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> where she works has the HMO
 	
 	
 		oh yes uh-huh
 	
 	
 		which is something that's
 		you know it's nice but you know it's great because you pay <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five dollars</NUMEX> and you go
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and and your <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five dollars</NUMEX> but if it's not an emergency you wait <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three months</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		is that right well
 	
 	
 		to get in
 		um-hum that is um
 		trying to think which one that is but i'm not it's a real popular one
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hum</ENAMEX> is it like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cigna</ENAMEX> or
 	
 	
 		but um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kaiser Kaiser</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kaiser</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		well we have that option at at work uh to choose that or to stay with our our company
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> has desired to administer the insurance program
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh you can either go with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMO</ENAMEX> or stay with with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aetna</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah i i'm going with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aetna</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's what i'm i'm staying with
 	
 	
 		well i'm just going to stay with the um you know i can go to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> i think i pay <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two hundred</NUMEX> and fifty dollar deductible and that's it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but yeah because she you know was trying to get into like an eye <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> or something like that and if it's not an emergency you wait for quite a while to get in
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well see now your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">eye doctor</ENAMEX>'s paid for through the HMO
 	
 	
 		yes yes
 	
 	
 		ours isn't
 		well i don't know about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMO</ENAMEX> but through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aetna</ENAMEX> it is not covered no
 	
 	
 		it's not yeah my isn't either but through the HMO it is
 	
 	
 		oh that's interesting
 	
 	
 		and i think eyes and and about every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> you could about
 		
 		
 	