
 
     		
 	
 		okay have you faced uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		elderly care yet uh nursing home care for any of your parents
 	
 	
 		unfortunately yes uh in fact tonight i had a dinner with uh my <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> and our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wives</ENAMEX> and we were talking uh we had a review with the nursing home <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s in a nursing home
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh we had a review <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> and a few things we had to do that
 		are part of it that you don't really like like uh making decisions on living wills and extended care that type of thing so yes i'm very familiar with it and it's not something that is uh
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		you know i never thought i'd have to go
 		through this kind of an experience but i guess we all do
 	
 	
 		i think sooner or later uh
 		both my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> we had to end up putting in nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> and they were to the point that they only lived both of them <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about six weeks</TIMEX> once they got in
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		and uh-huh and it's absolutely i believe that was one of the hardest things i ever did
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		in my life i that it just you know it's absolutely devastating
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		what have you found in dealing with the nursing homes
 	
 	
 		well they're not every all the horror stories you hear about them i think are true uh
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		we've we you know we've looked around and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> has looked at extensively at all the ones in the area  and the one she is in now um
 		there's a lot of drawbacks a lot of things we don't like but again it's no different than everyone
 		and you know the cost of it <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">three three thousand dollars</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX> when you think about it for what you're paying a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> for
 	
 	
 		hm um-hum
 	
 	
 		almost the same well even not as much care
 	
 	
 		yes
 		yes
 	
 	
 		it's not that expensive really
 	
 	
 		no uh
 		there was a little bit of difference in in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> between my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother-in-law</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh theirs both ran oh i think my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother-in-law</ENAMEX>'s was like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fifteen hundred</NUMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two thousand</NUMEX> then this has been <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years ago</TIMEX> and uh uh one of the things that you know i had discovered is that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		if they knew that i came in there at all different hours
 		they got much better care
 		than if when i started out with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother-in-law</ENAMEX> because she was in there first
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i would go certain <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> and they knew and if i'd pop in unexpectedly i discovered you know they did a little bit they did better
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		you know uh-huh and you know a couple of times with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother-in-law</ENAMEX> i would catch something not being taken care of and you know would have to raise so i got to where i knew then when my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> was in
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that you know not to go the same time all the time
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and they would and when i was looking for the nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> another thing that i learned uh
 		we had my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> all set to go into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and for some reason i just went back and on my own went around the different floors
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i saw areas that they had not shown me and they did not come across as well
 	
 	
 		well i'll be darned
 	
 	
 		as you know what they had originally shown me so uh
 		we did not put her in that one we put her in another one that i i went <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a couple</NUMEX> times when they weren't expecting me and saw and you know was much uh better pleased
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		with the situation
 	
 	
 		yeah you you know this is the whole point you've got you've got to shop them
 	
 	
 		yes you do
 	
 	
 		i know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> that's mainly <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Alzheimer's</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and um
 		we're convinced that she probably would be better off in a geriatric
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh the fact that these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are  they're up and around but they're they're it's reminds me too much of
 		an asylum type situation situation and it's very very
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		does your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> have <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Alzheimer's</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		she well who knows they call it uh dementia
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh we don't know i mean she does not know us anymore
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and whether it's <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Alzheimer's</ENAMEX> or what it is nobody really knows but it's basically the same and her health is not that bad
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		although she has gone down downhill drastically since this this this last well she had been in a retirement <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> and somewhere in so we're in the back of her mind she had it that she would live with her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> well
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		she we we just did not have the capabilities to to take care of her
 		and uh but she she has gone down steadily since she has been in and she's been in the nursing home now for  oh i would say about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three months</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		um-hum did she know that she was going to a nursing home did she know that she was going to a nursing home
 	
 	
 		and
 		i'm sorry
 		she no as far as she knew she was going to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and that she could she could handle a hospital and we says you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> if you you know if you get a you get better you've got to have the care the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> insisted on it you know if you get better that you could come out
 		
 		
 	