
 
     		
 	
 		um we our subject is golf
 	
 	
 		
 
 		and that's a good subject that i like to talk about
 	
 	
 		well good because i thought my goodness i'm i'm a definitely a beginner at golf
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh are you do you play
 	
 	
 		um i took lessons a couple of not <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last spring</TIMEX> but <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">spring</TIMEX> before last and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i really enjoyed it and i had taken <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> and i never could see that what i was doing was
 		causing that little ball to do anything and so um but when went i took <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this time</TIMEX> you know it actually went up in the air and
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and i i mean i could see that what i was doing made a difference and so um my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and i uh took together he had played some
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		already and then we started playing some and and we played in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> a few times and then i teach and i don't have time to during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the school year</TIMEX> much but um
 	
 	
 		oh that's the way to do it yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right well you got <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekends</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		well it just seems like it just is all a it really does and then uh and in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the spring</TIMEX> we've we've been lucky enough to go to several of those tournaments around here the uh
 	
 	
 		it takes a lot of time yeah it does
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Las Colinas</ENAMEX> and uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Byron Byron Nelson</ENAMEX> and i've loved watching so i'm i'm definitely a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spectator</ENAMEX> for not so much on TV but you know for live
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well i even i enjoy it on TV uh it once you get into it a little more you'll enjoy it on TV also
 	
 	
 		well now you know actually i have occasionally occasionally watched a little of it and i never did ever before i took these lessons my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> uh plays golf and he's oh he loves to watch it on TV so i guess if you play a lot you
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yes the more you get into it you you'll really enjoy it on TV too i think or or everybody i know that does
 	
 	
 		right well how about well well what about you
 	
 	
 		yeah i play all the time well not all the time but i try to get in at least
 		we play where there's a little course go down <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Texas</ENAMEX> and we go down there a lot in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mount Vernon</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		where is that
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh
 	
 	
 		that is that very far
 	
 	
 		no it's <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a hundred miles</NUMEX> i'm originally from there and we go down <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nearly every weekend</TIMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> live there so we have a place to stay and uh it's it's just so much fun when you got a regular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buddies</ENAMEX> you play with
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		sure
 	
 	
 		so that's what i do and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> took it up <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about two or three years ago</TIMEX> and she's she's enjoyed it a lot but it's hard to get the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> to play you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> it is
 	
 	
 		and uh so she doesn't really get to play you know enough enough not nearly enough although what she does she and i'll play sometimes you know and and she enjoys it but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		and she enjoys playing with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> but heck most of the time they're not all playing you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and course i've got a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> that i play with
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so it makes it a little bit difficult there but we enjoy it it's a lot of fun and uh one of the best parts about it once she took it up was when we'd go on a little
 		trip somewhere not long trips or anything but just little trips you know well it was always real good to  to take our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clubs</ENAMEX> and she could we could play golf
 	
 	
 		oh i know i think that's that's great
 	
 	
 		whereas before i probably wouldn't even get to play you know and now she enjoys playing with me and and we you know it it just makes the trips more enjoyable for me
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		sure
 	
 	
 		so uh
 	
 	
 		so uh how long have you been playing
 	
 	
 		oh i've been playing probably <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years</TIMEX> or longer i didn't start it nearly as young as i should have i think i was about
 	
 	
 		oh wow
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty</TIMEX> uh i don't know i guess i've been playing longer than that since i'm fifty i've probably been playing uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty five years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well um that i mean that's what they all say is that you know that's one of those things that you just can't start young enough
 	
 	
 		yeah uh-huh well you most  well you think you'd be better if you started early i'm not so sure that's true i see
 	
 	
 		especially i guess if you you start early and you just get get good lessons and you do it right i guess and
 	
 	
 		yeah some some people
 		that helps but then some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are just good at it and some are not
 	
 	
 		i i guess so it really is interesting
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> now now you're gonna improve and it helps to take lessons and and play a lot you're going definitely gonna get better but i'm talking about the difference from being a
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		uh mid nineties to low uh high i mean a low nineties to a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid</TIMEX> eighties <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shooter</ENAMEX> which that's what i am to being a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> that shoots in the low seventies
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh my well you're doing real well
 	
 	
 		that doesn't sound like a lot of difference but believe me it's a lot of difference
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		it really is
 	
 	
 		well um uh did and so do you play around here some
 	
 	
 		i used to play around here all the time but i don't any more since we just i just play down there now
 	
 	
 		uh-huh where would you play here
 	
 	
 		uh my favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courses</ENAMEX> around here are uh <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fire Wheel</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh i i like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chase Oaks</ENAMEX> real well but it's kind of expensive
 	
 	
 		oh so is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fire Wheel</ENAMEX> not as expensive
 	
 	
 		no it's a it's a municipal course <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garland</ENAMEX> owns it
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garland</ENAMEX> owns and that's how
 	
 	
 		oh well i i  course have you ever played at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plano</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plano</ENAMEX>'s a good course i've played there oh gosh ever since it's been there many many times
 	
 	
 		well well is it competitive well we've played that's where we've played mostly we've played at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chase Oaks</ENAMEX> too but um
 	
 	
 		it's an excellent <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">golf course</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chase Oaks</ENAMEX> is difficult you really need to be a good golfer to play <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chase Oaks</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh horrors i mean we just lose <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">jillions</NUMEX> of balls and
 	
 	
 		yeah if you're not a really good golfer don't waste your time at at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chase Oaks</ENAMEX> yeah it's too
 	
 	
 		that's discouraging isn't it
 		
 		
 	