
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		hi this is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donna Donahue</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hi Donna</ENAMEX> ready to get started
 	
 	
 		hi ah yeah i think so
 	
 	
 		okay  sort of an interesting topic since i just got back from lunch here
 	
 	
 		oh okay well what did you have for lunch
 	
 	
 		oh it was uh it was i'm an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX> and we went to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Officers</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Club</ENAMEX> for a little <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> food today
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh well that's interesting okay so our topic is is food today is that okay
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah yeah if you're having a dinner party what what would you serve
 	
 	
 		okay  uh do you want me to go first
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		okay if i was having a dinner party  i would probably um  have some um some uh um
 		some fruit to start with with some <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">apples</ENAMEX> sliced up and maybe some cheddar <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cheese</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">crackers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">grapes</ENAMEX> and um probably serve maybe some <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX> and maybe have some ah
 		ah salsa and chips around and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">peanuts</ENAMEX> and then i would have
 		um let's see i usually have like a little theme when i have a dinner party so um i would have maybe um say if it was like <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> or something um maybe um  on the barbecue we'd put um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		cubes of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">lamb</ENAMEX> or i guess <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">lamb</ENAMEX> used for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> and um like a shish kebab and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">um mushrooms</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tomatoes</ENAMEX> and onions and then we'd have um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		like a big <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> tossed salad kind of like a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Caesar salad</ENAMEX> and um let's see what else um maybe some rolls and um i guess some um some <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rice</ENAMEX> or something like that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		jeez well well when's the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> here
 	
 	
 		how's that sound
 		yeah  um yeah that would take some planning  but
 	
 	
 		i don't know being a being the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bachelor</ENAMEX> here that i am i i don't think i i'd be
 		nah nah it i mean it it's not a question of capability here to do something like that it's just there's there's no motivation
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		you know i wanna i wanna throw some charcoal on the grill and and throw a steak on there and some baked <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">potatoes</ENAMEX> and stuff like that but um
 	
 	
 		oh that sounds good too but i have um i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> so um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		when we have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> over i have my oldest kind of babysit for the little two younger ones upstairs and um usually we just have very plain kind of you know interesting not very interesting <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meals pizza</ENAMEX> and that also
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		once in a while when we do something like that it's kind of fun but it's not a not a regular thing
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um now we supposed to talk for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about five minutes</TIMEX> is that it okay
 	
 	
 		yeah it
 		yeah that's what they they're shooting for here
 	
 	
 		okay um let's see now what okay so you would have a barbecue wouldn't
 	
 	
 		well i live on a i live on a lake here and uh so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it it during the summertime it's real nice to be able to entertain outdoors like that's a little more ah casual thing but in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX> in the wintertime it's not bad too because then i've got a
 	
 	
 		oh sure
 	
 	
 		you know fireplace and a nice nice <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and all that so it's uh uh really good place to do entertaining like that i just haven't uh really tried a whole lot but uh
 	
 	
 		uh-huh oh that sounds wonderful
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i don't know let's see i have had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">well one</NUMEX> time i did have a dinner party i served a uh  uh
 		had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gang</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> over and kind of made a fried chicken thing and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">biscuits</ENAMEX> and kind of southern uh southern <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> even though i'm up here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> so i
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh oh you're in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> right now oh i'm i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> i didn't know this was all from all over the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> oh i see and i'm from originally from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Long Island</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh yeah yeah it is it
 		oh no kidding
 	
 	
 		yes and now where are you in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		upstate <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Griffins uh Griffins Air Force Base</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh upstate oh okay oh okay is that where you you're originally from around there
 	
 	
 		well i was born in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Buffalo</ENAMEX> and uh been all over the place
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 		oh wow that's interesting okay let's see um well i like to have um sometimes when i have a dinner party i'll have um everybody bring something
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and that's real interesting because then you get different um different kinds of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">foods</ENAMEX> and new recipes and um
 		ah sometimes somebody will bring something that you really like and get recipe from them and whatever
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and we just getting interested in in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> because here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> they have lots of really good <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> and um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		sure
 	
 	
 		we're we're just getting into the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fajitas</ENAMEX> and all that stuff that you could do you know what a fajita is yeah okay
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah i've been down to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> a few times and uh had uh the pleasure of their good <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> cuisine down there
 	
 	
 		yes they have some <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">delicious delicious things</ENAMEX> and i um sometimes make uh chicken <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">burritos</ENAMEX> that just take chicken breasts and you boil them maybe like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> chicken breasts and you boil them till they're cooked
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		maybe like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX> and then you debone them and and kind of shred them up if the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX>'s gotten cooled and you take um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">salt</ENAMEX> little bit maybe <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> tablespoons of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">butter</ENAMEX> and a frying in a big frying pan and chop up some onion and put in oregano and salt
 		
 		
 	