
 
     		
 	
 		well i don't know what to do about the federal budget um there certainly been ideas surfaced uh recently um matter of fact repeatedly by many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and i sort of wonder what your what thoughts you had on that area
 	
 	
 		
 
 		what the uh the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> one is we need <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in there that that understand uh numbers and the numbers that are being thrown around when when we're talking in <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">trillions of dollars</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh  which is an astronomical sum and and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are talking these numbers  have no concept of what that number means
 		um
 	
 	
 		now are you are you talking about the elected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> or are you talking about others um-hum
 	
 	
 		the elected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> yes um-hum
 		our our our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> and and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that that deal everyday and and what's going to be done with those monies
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> and don't really understand what that is or how a budget even works
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh we need to elect <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are more
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX>  or
 	
 	
 		i'm not sure how you would achieve how would you achieve that i mean if
 	
 	
 		well  let's let's make them have a degree in economy uh or economics
 	
 	
 		uh so you would trust the decision making  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you you
 		well
 	
 	
 		sometimes called the dismal science
 	
 	
 		yeah but but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people people</ENAMEX> that that know the value of a dollar that understand the value of a dollar
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yes
 	
 	
 		um  when in in in the
 		the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyists</ENAMEX> needs to be eliminated
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> um
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		they don't make pragmatic decisions they make a decision based on constituency constituency
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		instead of a decision based on what they really believe
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um you know the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the  or</TIMEX> or they tack on these uh pork bellies and and do things that that are good for their area to pass something that is that is not good for the country
 	
 	
 		right so so you would favor a law which said there could not be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyists</ENAMEX> i mean right now <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyists</ENAMEX> require to register you'd just say
 	
 	
 		oh i definitely i definitely would yeah get rid of them
 	
 	
 		love that make them all no causes that you think the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyists</ENAMEX> would be good for
 	
 	
 		totally uh
 		i i think that any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> or anything that wants to contribute to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">fund</ENAMEX> should be able to do that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and be registered with what they ever contribute contribute but they should not have a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one-on-one</NUMEX> relationship with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> making the decisions that affect them
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that that's a conflict of interest as far as i'm concerned
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		when you're talking again uh billions and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">trillions of dollars</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh you're you're you're jeopardizing the future of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> uh for today
 		and that
 	
 	
 		so uh you talk about jeopardizing the future would you be against any deficit spending
 	
 	
 		i i think to bring it in line
 		you're going to have to have a generation that's going to really bite the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bullet</ENAMEX> to bring it in line you can't ease into it it took <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> to build up the momentum that's there now
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh i i i forget the figures on the interest rate but it's something like uh <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">hundreds of thousands of dollars</NUMEX> a second
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		in interest part of the problem is we don't loan from ourselves we we buy from intimate international banking that's why we have interest
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and and i i really i really feel that that that is part of the problem
 		that we we've let things get so out of control that that we don't wanna put the brakes on them
 	
 	
 		but what what practical steps could one could one take um
 	
 	
 		by by having a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a</NUMEX> a budget that is is feasible that is reasonable
 	
 	
 		well but everybody will say that he is for that
 	
 	
 		oh of course yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh and and</ENAMEX> and how will you make that actually happen
 	
 	
 		and then add on to it
 		you take the gross national income
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and you say our budget is <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">X</NUMEX> number of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">percent</NUMEX> of this gross national income one thing we could do is give a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> percent income tax
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		across the board everyone no matter what pays a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> percent income tax
 	
 	
 		yep
 		sounds like a good idea
 		nothing escapes right no no deductions nothing just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> percent
 	
 	
 		uh
 		that's right
 		right no deductions you pay a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> percent income tax that's what you pay if you make <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">forty million dollars</NUMEX> uh then you're going to pay <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">four million</NUMEX> if if you make <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">forty dollars</NUMEX> you're going to pay <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">four dollars</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		yep
 		right
 	
 	
 		and and that's it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">yep</ENAMEX> so that that's it that's i mean i i agree with that that's a good idea idea and is it your expectation that that would raise the total revenues collected or or lower them or what
 	
 	
 		and
 		i don't know that it  that it would or wouldn't
 		
 		
 	