
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		go ahead
 	
 	
 		um i haven't given this a a lot of thought i'm
 		uh
 		i'd that's a whole pleased with the practice practice that is they i uh i don't you would favor invasions of privacy on the other hand
 		i'd say arguable that that that uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who's jobs are critical to to public safety should have to meet special standards uh i haven't given this matter enough thought
 	
 	
 		do you work for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no uh uh i'm in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> area i work for NIST
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh okay oh all right well see we have the testing already here we've had it for oh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about five years</TIMEX> it used to just be for new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and now it's for all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> they uh randomly select <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX> numbers and uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> that they select you is when you have to go and and be tested so we're familiar with it
 	
 	
 		and now
 		and how do <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> feel about it
 	
 	
 		uh we have a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">um people</ENAMEX> upset about it at the beginning some not all
 		but what was happening at <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> is that they found certain parts of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> there was a lot of drug abuse um
 		mainly the areas where where they were doing a lot of um manufacturing type things and what they ended up doing is um kind of like doing a little bit of an undercover agent
 		to watch what was happening and we had <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> using on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">premises</ENAMEX> and actually selling and dealing you know on the premises
 	
 	
 		well okay that's that's a very different issue
 	
 	
 		well yeah it it was you know combination of of uh both activities and uh and using too so they developed this uh drug policy so that
 		uh to eliminate there's some parts of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that we do uh government contracts and i think some of those require the drug testing but now <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> thought well we'll just do it for all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>
 		that um not just because of safety issues but because we want a totally drug free safe environment for all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to work in and that we shouldn't have um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> within <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">our</TIMEX> you know <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> and such
 		i haven't personally ever been tested but i don't have a problem with it
 	
 	
 		and
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> does the testing cover <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> as well as illegal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no but one thing that to to me was um going on stretching it a little too far was that they also check um if you're taking somebody else's prescription drug
 		you know it happens a lot of times like some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> gets the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">flu</ENAMEX> or whatever and you know then they give it to everybody else in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and don't always go back to the you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> and get another prescription
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		well according to what they do at <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> if you take a prescription drug it has to be in your name
 		it you know it can't be in your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouse</ENAMEX>'s name so they will look i mean the testing will look for i guess any kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> and you have to tell them what you're taking a prescription for
 	
 	
 		so they ask you to declare beforehand what prescription drugs you are taking
 	
 	
 		right yes yes when you get tested you're supposed to tell them you know everything that that might be there
 		and then if they ever um question you or something you may have to show proof that you do have a prescription in your name
 	
 	
 		okay well well i mean it's i would guess that in fact they don't test for for they don't routinely test for very many prescription drugs but that i but they don't tell you in advance uh so
 	
 	
 		well what they were be testing for are the ones that would have like you know barbiturates or codeine things like that in them
 	
 	
 		the ones that would constitute controlled <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">substances</ENAMEX> or something anyway
 	
 	
 		right right i guess that's what is they wouldn't be looking for penicillin and antibiotics antibiotics and stuff they'd be looking for the yeah controlled things barbiturates amphetamines
 	
 	
 		so what they're asking you to tell them is all the prescription drugs you're taking which are controlled substances
 	
 	
 		right
 		right you pretty much you know put down what you remember even if it is was just Contact or something like that
 		but afterwards uh maybe if you had a controlled substance  well you you probably put down you know you had <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Drixoral</ENAMEX> or Contact if you would remember that you did it
 	
 	
 		is Contact a
 		what
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">okay</ENAMEX> is Contact a
 	
 	
 		no i'm just saying you probably probably put down on the sheet anything you have taken but if they had a controlled substance maybe they would ask you then to show that you had that prescription in your name
 	
 	
 		substance okay
 		okay
 	
 	
 		i know i had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> contract employee through manpower was not a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> but was it contract <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> and they test them too even if you are not a real uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TIer</ENAMEX> if you are a contract <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX> here they test you too
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and he had taken some kind of um oh you know uh just he had some kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">flu</ENAMEX> or something he got a real bad migraine and he took his mother's
 		
 		
 	