
 
     		
 	
 		well let me just start by asking what you think of this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> affair we've got going on
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i think that it's time that we concentrate more on what's going on within our own borders than what's going on in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Middle East</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i have to agree with you there i uh i think that uh for once we should we shouldn't even be at at these <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mideast</ENAMEX> talks because with the exception of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hostages</ENAMEX> we really don't have
 		to much of a uh a real interest we shouldn't have too much of a real interest in deciding who's land it is just let these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> fight it out
 	
 	
 		i agree
 	
 	
 		you know we've got so many domestic problems and and what does it cost to keep these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> over there you know
 	
 	
 		absolutely
 	
 	
 		oh so how about the uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> what do you think's gonna happen there the break ups
 	
 	
 		i think that's great i'm i'm glad to see that but i again i don't want to see
 		us pour a whole lot of economic aid into the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> without
 		a uh well uh not a whole lot under any circumstances because i i don't know i'm a i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">believer</ENAMEX> in the old adage that if somebody earns something it's worth more to them than if you give it to them and so i'm i'm not
 		much in favor of it but i'm glad to see us advising them that doesn't seem to cost a whole lot of money so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		that's right that's right
 	
 	
 		but i'm ready to have a uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> elected that at least has some sort of a domestic agenda even if it doesn't work
 		at least he is somebody who who is working on that problem and i i haven't seen that in the last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> so
 		they don't seem to have a clue
 	
 	
 		well let's see  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> obviously wasn't too concerned with the domestic side of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">of</NUMEX> of uh his political affairs uh and i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s kind of followed suit um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">international</ENAMEX> is important but i mean we've got a budget deficit that just won't go away unless it gets seriously addressed
 		uh you know and then there's the homeless issue and and there really is a lot we could be doing stateside without uh
 		hurting our international aspects or straining any international relations i think and we wouldn't have to spend the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">billions</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billions of dollars</NUMEX> each year that we're spending
 	
 	
 		oh i agree i just i i think we got once we started economic aid over seas we have really
 		set ourselves up to be
 		sort of the  the world <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> and as far as aid is concerned and i think there's a a limit and we've passed it a long time ago
 	
 	
 		right
 		i agree we've been writing off way too many bad debts uh country bad debts
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		that's another thing i don't understand is is is things like selling technology and uh even military <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hardware</ENAMEX> to foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> and then forgiving their debt
 	
 	
 		exactly
 	
 	
 		that doesn't to me that just doesn't make any sense as as much in debt as we are
 	
 	
 		i know it
 	
 	
 		i just i i don't know i think it's definitely time for a change but i don't see anybody i don't understand too why we have to have <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> and it's it's either one way or the other there's
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		it seems seems to be we're turning into a black and white society you either do it this way or you do it that way and there's no in between
 	
 	
 		that's right you're either liberal or you're conservative
 	
 	
 		and that just uh it obviously isn't working
 	
 	
 		well i think uh
 		it it wouldn't hurt and i know the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Independent Party</ENAMEX>'s been trying for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> to get a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a</NUMEX> a real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> in in the uh in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> but uh you're right there's just too many
 		issues that come up that uh our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> and our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">congressmen</ENAMEX> vote on simply because it's a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> issue or it's a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> issue and if they would vote with their conscience and with what their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">constituents</ENAMEX> feel
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		i think uh we might have a a lot better a lot more efficient running <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and and a lot better laws passed
 	
 	
 		oh i agree with you well of course you know we have the national embarrassment in our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">state</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jessie Helms</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and uh as soon as as we can get of course it seems to me that every time he opens his mouth he he just lines up <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> against him so
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		it's not too it's not too often that you see him swaying too many opinions he's uh usually on the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">the ninety eight</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> side he's the one of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> that votes
 	
 	
 		he's one he's one of the two huh
 	
 	
 		yeah he's
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		very ineffective i think
 	
 	
 		well let's see uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senators</ENAMEX> are in for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six years</TIMEX> right and uh when did you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> vote him into office
 	
 	
 		right
 		oh unfortunately nineteen ninety
 	
 	
 		oh you're stuck
 	
 	
 		yeah we're stuck with him for a
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		a little while longer but uh unfortunately for him but maybe fortunately for us his health is not great so i
 		i hate
 		
 		
 	