
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		all right are we paying too much in taxes and are we getting what we pay for
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		what's your opinion
 	
 	
 		well it's kind of a broad subject uh i i think there are some areas where we where we uh pretty well
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		you know get our money's worth but i i i also think there are a lot of areas
 		especially in uh big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> federal government uh where we're we're short changed
 		uh lot of money spent for
 		uh
 		things that are not used and i don't know i was i was in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX> and out of it there were  there was equipment at every base i was ever on that was just going to waste it was just sitting and rusting and
 		you know it
 	
 	
 		okay i i tend to agree with you when it comes to government spending there are so many studies done that don't mean anything
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but we'll spend <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds of thousands</NUMEX> if not <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">millions of dollars</NUMEX> on
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and it's nice to know something doesn't work or something doesn't exist but
 		it could be put to more practical use
 	
 	
 		yeah and i i think that uh  it's a a tone of our times that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> are into themselves more than they are into you know doing something worthwhile for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> they represent which which is really unfortunate
 	
 	
 		that is true i agree with you in that area
 		um i have a tendency to i'm in from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> and i read you know how our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> voted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each week</TIMEX> in the paper
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and it's you know it's interesting how
 		the votes vary and what they ran on in platform
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		don't necessarily come true in their voting in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> whatever
 	
 	
 		and don't really respond to uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who write them and call them and uh you know unless they're in the limelight and under pressure
 		so
 		yeah i think we get short changed on that
 	
 	
 		right that's very true what state what state do you live in
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay what do you think about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin Hood</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		now that
 		well
 		i work for school district and uh it's it has hurt us a lot
 		um there has to be some way i think to equalize education opportunities
 		but um at you know our uh we we tend to think i think this especially big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> tends to think that the solution to everything is to throw money at it
 		and i don't you know that's just not true i don't think the
 		you know i don't think money is gonna take the place of intelligence or uh problem solving skills uh i think there
 		there are too many things that money can't  uh that can't that money can't buy that that are important as far as education is concerned
 	
 	
 		that's true what school district do you work for
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Richardson</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay i work for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plano</ENAMEX>  so we're comparable as a matter of fact i just paid my <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richardson</ENAMEX> taxes because i live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Richardson</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		oh great okay
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		supplemented the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin Hoods</ENAMEX> very thoroughly i think
 	
 	
 		yeah i think we've uh
 	
 	
 		our taxes went up tremendously
 	
 	
 		we yeah we've got it on the line don't we
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		and it's not gonna get any better don't i mean you know it just keeps going up and up and up
 		uh i used to live in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plano</ENAMEX> school district and uh
 		there was a an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> that uh finally communicated the message to i think to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plano</ENAMEX> that you know we didn't want our taxes raised
 	
 	
 		yes i remember that was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about four five years ago</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		but this you know this uh
 		i think living in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Richardson</ENAMEX> we're kind of spoiled because i think we get  we come closer to getting our money's worth as far as the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> is concerned
 		i think then probably any city any <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> in the country
 	
 	
 		yes well did you read in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> where they increased the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">administrators</ENAMEX>' pay by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty three</TIMEX> percent
 	
 	
 		is that incredible
 	
 	
 		after they laid off all those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's a that's the biggest mess i've ever heard of you know
 		how can you how can you justify raising anybody's salary if you you know if you have to lay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> off
 	
 	
 		right but you know i'm not gonna complain because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Plano</ENAMEX> got we all got a pay raise this year
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you all got a pay raise <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> am i correct
 	
 	
 		yeah well yeah the i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> did uh did and i don't know about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">administrators</ENAMEX> i i'm semiretired and i was i was an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">administrator</ENAMEX>
 		so i i you know i don't get a raise anymore i just
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		uh i work part time and just get uh  you know my pay doesn't change
 	
 	
 		are you on the early retirement
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		oh are you enjoying it
 	
 	
 		yes very much uh course i still i still work <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> part time jobs so it's not really total retirement
 	
 	
 		hm
 		
 
 		well it's interesting you know because when you look at what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richardson</ENAMEX> has done with the early retirement you
 		
 		
 	