
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i've uh
 		oh uh
 		are you there all right okay  um
 	
 	
 		yes sir i'm right here
 	
 	
 		i'm in an area where um we can uh enjoy it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> round so i've actually been uh uh been out within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past couple of weeks</TIMEX>
 		i'm mainly freshwater fisherman how about yourself
 	
 	
 		well actually i've done both kinds uh i'm originally from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh lived uh near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia Beach</ENAMEX> where we could uh surf <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cast</ENAMEX> and uh catch a lot of things in the ocean there
 	
 	
 		do you ever
 		did you ever do the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">James River</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i don't believe i have fished the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">James River</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		there's a possibility but that was so long ago i moved here to to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State College</ENAMEX> uh in nineteen fifty <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> and that has pretty well limited my fishing to fresh water
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and we have a lot of uh beautiful fresh <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> streams that come through this this area i'm in an area called <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Center County</ENAMEX> which is in the very center of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i've  i've been in that area and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">trout</ENAMEX> fishing's supposed to be legendary
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">trout</ENAMEX> fishing is really uh beautiful as i say the the streams are oh <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">eight ten fifteen feet</NUMEX> wide and so forth and uh
 		you you stand on the edge and you you cast out and you you work uh from your feet most of the time and then there are there are a few lakes of course close by
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> for brookies
 		what do you like brookies or uh rainbows or
 	
 	
 		well tell you the truth i'm i'm not uh not picky i wherever the area whatever the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">specialist</ENAMEX> in that area i uh i enjoy fishing for it and i try to i haven't fished in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several years</TIMEX> i'll have to admit
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but when i do fish i do contact uh some of the local specialists
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so that i can then find out the uh the type of lures that they use and where they fish and any unique uh techniques that would help you
 	
 	
 		do you <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fly fish</ENAMEX> or are those streams too small
 	
 	
 		uh no we fly we <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fly fish um</ENAMEX>-hum
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i used to do that a little when i lived up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right now it's uh uh bass and striped bass is the only thing that uh i go for down in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh that's a pretty big fish
 	
 	
 		uh yeah they're they've uh the striped bass have accommodated themselves to the big fresh <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> lakes and they're pretty exciting when they're when they're running
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salt water</ENAMEX> fish in fresh <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> uh environment
 		it's
 	
 	
 		well well our our streams streams here are replanted with <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> uh about every year
 	
 	
 		it's all put and take
 	
 	
 		so that well they they they uh they have a pretty good idea of of uh
 		what what the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> are in these various locations and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they have  have certain areas that they plant you know a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundred</NUMEX> here and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred</NUMEX> there and this is of course x number of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> before fishing season opens so
 	
 	
 		what's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the season April</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September October</TIMEX> or something like that
 	
 	
 		that sounds about right um-hum pretty close
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah what's a license cost
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well as i say it's been <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several years</TIMEX> but the licenses weren't that expensive i seems to sticks in my mind <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">seven dollars</NUMEX> is about all what i remember
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		it's about the same as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		and i have oh probably a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a half a dozen</NUMEX> different kinds of uh fishing poles and and fly rods and so forth and
 		and i had been so busy in my work in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these last few years</TIMEX> that i haven't had time to fish
 		but i'm going to be retiring at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of December</TIMEX> and i i hope uh the next fishing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX> that i can sort of get back in and uh enjoy that that that was a really enjoyable uh thing for me to do
 	
 	
 		well i have all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX> so i think i'm probably going to be fishing for a long time
 	
 	
 		huh i just have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> and he he lives uh out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> now or rather in the eastern corner of it so i don't think he has time to fish either
 	
 	
 		i caught the disease from my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> and i'm passing it on to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> it's really
 	
 	
 		oh is that right
 	
 	
 		they love it yeah
 	
 	
 		oh my goodness well i i uh the disease i caught was simply because uh i was i was i was in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Norfolk Portsmouth</ENAMEX> area and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> there there's there's so much <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> around that you you you're either boating or you're fishing
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 		right
 	
 	
 		and uh i fairly enjoyed it that time i have a small uh aluminum <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> here that uh when i go on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the large lakes that we have here that i enjoy fishing for for <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">trout</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		what what are the  i i don't i don't know about the lakes in central <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX> are there many
 	
 	
 		from that
 		well as i say i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Center Center County</ENAMEX> there's um there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> different size lakes about
 		well <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">five five to six miles</NUMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State College</ENAMEX> now these aren't huge lakes from your point of view but they are probably fifteen twenty acres maybe
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		which which here is a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boats</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	