
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh uh do you have any uh particular books that you've read lately that are are good books
 		that you've enjoyed
 	
 	
 		i haven't read much lately i've always reading is one of my favorite things but somehow the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last few months</TIMEX> i just haven't read i've read more <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> than books it's which is most unusual for me but
 		um have you read anything lately
 	
 	
 		not real lately when they came up with this topic i thought gee i read a lot of books and now i thought what have i read lately  um
 	
 	
 		why what whoa i can't i know i read a bunch <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few months</TIMEX> back but i can't remember the titles oh
 	
 	
 		oh isn't that funny i will have to say
 	
 	
 		i'd have to go look around my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> for the books i've read and they're still stacked there
 	
 	
 		oh well it seems like i've have read a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s books lately  to my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and things like that but
 	
 	
 		well now i have too
 		well i have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandchildren</ENAMEX> and uh the oldest is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> but he you know loves books so so i have read more of those myself
 	
 	
 		oh
 		huh
 	
 	
 		lately i did buy the sequel to uh <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Gone With the Wind</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and i've read the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapter</ENAMEX> and and i thought it was real good and i have not even picked it back up you know and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Gone With the Wind</ENAMEX> is my all time
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		favorite book you know so you would have thought i'd a had the whole thing read by now
 	
 	
 		oh
 		is it by the same author
 	
 	
 		no uh no see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret Mitchell</ENAMEX> died uh oh maybe <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years</TIMEX> after she wrote <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Gone With the Wind</ENAMEX> and she that's the only book she ever wrote
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and uh so the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heirs</ENAMEX> to her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">estate</ENAMEX> after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fifty years</TIMEX> picked this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alexander Ripley i</ENAMEX> think is her name to write the sequel which she did and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well that may that may be the reason you can't get into it as as much oh
 	
 	
 		no no it it it was very good it it brought all those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> back to life i just i just well i don't know i've just been busy and i just haven't read
 	
 	
 		oh uh-huh
 	
 	
 		where i've i used to find time
 	
 	
 		yeah i yeah you know if i get reading a book i like to just close the door and just read you know and even stay up <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">really late at night</TIMEX> and and just stay into it until i finish uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		i used to be that way but
 	
 	
 		yeah sometimes it's hard to do that with our lives
 	
 	
 		well i get well i'm fifty <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> and i you know i just get sleepy and i go to bed early so where i used to do that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> i don't anymore and i do i work my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">accountant</ENAMEX> and we moved our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> home <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about two years ago</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		so i work at home but i have a lot of work to do you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh then when i'm not doing that like i have my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandkids</ENAMEX> a lot because my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> travels and she has a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty month</TIMEX> and then a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> month
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		so that's why we're going to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plano</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> that's where we pick them up at day care
 	
 	
 		i see
 		oh i see well some of the books that i have read um that i really enjoyed getting into was um the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellen Drury</ENAMEX>
 		books you know Advice and Consent and have you ever read any of those
 	
 	
 		now is that like a classic
 	
 	
 		it really is um
 	
 	
 		i mean i mean written quite a ways back that you like maybe read in high school or something or am i thinking of a different one with that name
 	
 	
 		it's been around awhile but it's not you know it's not from the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighteen hundreds</NUMEX> or anything this is it's a book um
 		it's written in the nineteen <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> and it's written uh about what goes on in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> you know in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		oh no that's not what i was thinking of
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> and everything and um it really gets into
 		kind of the wheeling and dealing type thing and it's just it gets really fascinating i didn't think something like that would catch my interest but uh the way it's written and everything it is excellent it just really uh it's well worth reading
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		i'll be darn
 		okay well i sure wish i could remember what i've read so i could tell you something i did read that oh gosh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh
 		there's another book out that's called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">All I Ever Wanted uh Needed to Know I Learned in Kindergarten</ENAMEX> have you ever heard of
 	
 	
 		now i have seen that what is that about
 	
 	
 		that's just real cute it's um it's just got a lot of ideas in it about basic things you know that we do and um
 		you know things that you learn in kindergarten that that really apply to your life um there's one little section in there that that talks about um
 	
 	
 		oh uh-huh
 	
 	
 		uh holding hands and sticking together and um
 		you know having <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cookies</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk</ENAMEX> and wouldn't it be nice if we could all still take a nap  in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the afternoon</TIMEX> you know and it's
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	