
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh i guess it's uh
 		watching the radio the TV <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> there had a lot of stuff on on uh crime in our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> right now uh recently they've had a lot of uh
 		uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rapists</ENAMEX> uh murder type uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">killers</ENAMEX> going around and
 	
 	
 		oh gracious
 	
 	
 		and well i i they've caught them and they they're in there
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> wasn't it your state that had the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">um guy</ENAMEX> that committed all those murders
 		there was that um
 	
 	
 		uh well yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wisconsin</ENAMEX> uh and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milwaukee</ENAMEX> area yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah that was really on the national news a lot
 		we heard a lot about that in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		no that's
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well i i live right on the border <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wisconsin</ENAMEX> so i kind of get both both news and
 		i know in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota</ENAMEX> uh
 		they had uh the one that just uh got out and went after a uh college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> and raped and killed her and
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		they're not too happy about that now
 	
 	
 		well i can imagine it seems like the
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		violent crimes are increasing a lot to me i i don't know
 		i don't know if statistically they are but it seems like you sure hear a maybe you just hear a lot more about them on the news i don't know
 	
 	
 		yeah uh that's hard to say for sure i uh sometimes i wonder if these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> aren't don't it just for the publicity and
 	
 	
 		you wonder about that sometimes
 	
 	
 		they they get their names in the in the paper and they become big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrities</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um-hum that's kind of scary i'd i'm  wish there was some way that we could change the news media so they didn't feature these
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> out stories maybe it wouldn't give other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> ideas
 	
 	
 		well uh i know one thing i i think <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> has the death penalty right
 	
 	
 		yes we do do you have it up there
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		no
 	
 	
 		i see
 	
 	
 		see i i not
 	
 	
 		do you think that's a deterrent
 	
 	
 		yeah well uh
 		it's it's it's not gonna prevent any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from doing it but the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> that's caught he'll never do it again if he gets the death penalty and that's and there are a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">repeaters</ENAMEX> uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		i guess that's another thing that to me is a a real problem and i know we've got so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison system</ENAMEX> now at least here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i mean they're really in a crisis there's been times they've had to
 		just close off the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prisons</ENAMEX> and leave them in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">county</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">jails</ENAMEX> or whatever because there just wasn't enough room for all of them and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		a lot of them they put out on parole and then some of the ones that they put out early
 		you know do repeat offenses and the crime rate's the worst than ever before
 	
 	
 		hum
 		yeah well some i'm just wondering a lot of times they'll put uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> lesser crimes
 		in uh with uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that did more severe crimes and they maybe they just tend to learn from these people
 		and they and when they get back out they just go into worse crimes and
 	
 	
 		i think that could be true too
 	
 	
 		maybe they should try and separate them a little bit more
 		um
 	
 	
 		i think the whole parole thing you know if somebody's convicted of
 		<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> degree murder or something gets fifteen <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> well they're out in
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six or seven</TIMEX> you know outbound on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> again
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and to me that's really scary some some of these crimes that they commit you know seems like the punishment's not
 		really equal to the crime
 	
 	
 		well uh
 		i don't know uh with with my limited uh psychology background i do have uh i don't i don't even feel that <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prisons</ENAMEX> and stuff are are the answer
 		if you wanna stop the crime i think you got to get uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> when they're kids
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		a lot of this probably just starts with from the from the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> also from the the the media the TV you see uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		all these uh gory movies on there becomes uh just natural fact of life
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		i think it's okay thing to do
 	
 	
 		yep
 	
 	
 		yeah i think that's a very good point you know i there's a lot more working <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> a lot more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> in day care centers
 		all that kind of thing morality is being taught more by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> a lot of times than in the home anymore
 	
 	
 		uh-huh well a lot of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> uh they tend to censor well they probably won't censor so much the sexual stuff as much as the violent
 	
 	
 		and
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they have a lot less crime
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		some of some of those <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> are are you can leave your your uh doors open and and and be safe
 		uh even uh i think <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Zealand</ENAMEX> is
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the places uh that's not
 		
 		
 	