
 
     		
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well it's not often you get uh many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> interested in <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX>  do you follow football very much
 	
 	
 		oh well
 		i'm sorry what
 	
 	
 		do you follow football very much
 	
 	
 		i don't no i i haven't recently um
 	
 	
 		
  
 		we can talk about something else do you have any uh you married
 	
 	
 		no i'm not no
 	
 	
 		no i guess <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are out
 	
 	
 		what's that
 	
 	
 		i said <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are out
 	
 	
 		yep
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		are you married
 	
 	
 		yeah i've i'm married i've got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> boys
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		wow so do you like football
 	
 	
 		oh i follow the uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cowboys</ENAMEX> but that's about it uh
 	
 	
 		see see same here
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		do you live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah i i i am a  pretty big <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> and been for a long time
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but but uh i haven't been to any games recently
 		but uh i try to catch the game <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every weekend</TIMEX> that i can
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		yeah have you ever been to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cowboys</ENAMEX> game
 	
 	
 		i haven't hum-um
 	
 	
 		um it's pretty nice
 	
 	
 		we decided we decided just to watch them at home
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but
 	
 	
 		that's good at least you uh follow the game a little bit
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um yeah i'm not a fanatic about it i don't know who played when and who does what like some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> are i just like to watch and and hopefully they win  that's about the extent of it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah right now i'm in um college so i'm more into college <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> than professional i think
 	
 	
 		oh i see what uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> are you going to
 	
 	
 		um i'm at BYU
 	
 	
 		BYU oh okay
 	
 	
 		yeah so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leslie</ENAMEX> what are you studying
 	
 	
 		nursing
 	
 	
 		nursing great my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX>'s an LVN
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		cool
 	
 	
 		so  what are you planning to go into do you want to be an RN or
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah um i haven't really picked a field i haven't
 		i i don't know i've i've thought a lot about labor and delivery but i don't know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		try that that's what my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> does labor and delivery
 	
 	
 		oh really wow
 	
 	
 		yeah she loves it she she really uh enjoys
 	
 	
 		is she a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurse</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no she's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurse</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Antonio</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		but uh she's been she's been working a uh a late shift she works the uh i guess the graveyard's what you'd call it she works the graveyard shift
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and she's worked that for oh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> when i was small
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		um i guess probably going on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years</TIMEX> now
 	
 	
 		wow
 	
 	
 		and she really enjoys it she likes the quiet that you have at that time of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night</TIMEX> and uh
 		and um
 		uh she's uh
 		she just started a new job at a different hospital closer to where she lives
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and she's really enjoying herself she really likes it
 	
 	
 		well that's great
 	
 	
 		hm well good luck to you in pursuing your nursing degree
 	
 	
 		oh thanks
 	
 	
 		think you'll like it you plan on staying in in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> area
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		um i'd like to come back to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> right now i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> of course  so um but my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>'s there so yeah i'd like to go back
 	
 	
 		oh huh
 		um-hum  yeah uh i think <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">uh San Antonio</ENAMEX> in particular has got a large uh base of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh i don't know about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> i think <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> is pretty scattered
 	
 	
 		are you in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Antonio</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no i'm i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> but i i'm originally from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Antonio</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 		hm
 	
 	
 		and they've got a large medical uh <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> down there they've got the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UT Health Science Center</ENAMEX> out there also
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		so if you ever wanted you know pursue anything more than your nursing degree that that'd be the place to do it
 	
 	
 		yeah my brother-in-law um is in the medical
 		profession i mean he's at medical school <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Antonio</ENAMEX> right now
 	
 	
 		um-hum oh great
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">great</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		well like i said good luck to you
 	
 	
 		thanks
 	
 	
 		all right well um take care and maybe we'll meet up again sometime
 	
 	
 		all right bye-bye
 	
 	
 		okay bye-bye
 		
 
 		
 		
 	