
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay
 		well <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carolyn</ENAMEX> the uh
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the main things i'd like like to know is uh
 		how do you feel about the knowing about the environment of a nursing home before you would send someone there to live and so forth what do you think would be required and so forth
 	
 	
 		well
 		uh i'll tell you i i watched what went on um with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Twenty Twenty</ENAMEX> show i don't know if you saw that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few days ago</TIMEX> that that talked about nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> and
 		actually they specifically talked about some in the area where i am here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		oh you knew of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> then you knew of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> themselves
 	
 	
 		pardon
 		well i no i'm not familiar with those <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> per se but um they were in the area where i live
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> and it was really revealing to see some of the you know the things that go on i guess in some of these <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> so i would definitely  you know want to really check things out and
 		uh  go i guess that the big thing would be once you got someone in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">home</ENAMEX> like that to to make sure that you went <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> you know and made sure that they were cared for and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well from your point of view how would you feel about actually sending someone that that's you know means something to you to one of those <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> i realize that you indicated you wanted to check out as much as you can about it and of course that makes sense but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		how do you think they would feel i should say about moving from where they have lived most of their life into a whole new new home situation
 	
 	
 		well actually i have that kind of situation because my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> lives with me and she's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty seven</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		and uh from the time that we were tiny she said you know i want you to promise that you'll never put me in a rest home
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so i know how she feels about it you know if i uh if i ever had to put her there i think uh it would be probably when i just could not handle it any more you know if i
 	
 	
 		yes
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		she got to the point where she was totally bedridden and and i mean i just didn't have the skills or the strength to lift her or whatever it needed i think that would be the
 	
 	
 		well how do you find that your your personal relationship is with her know that you're both together all the time and you are having to do a lot more for her than normal does that does that cause any problems between the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of you
 	
 	
 		uh i wouldn't say any more than usual
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> is she
 	
 	
 		i think it's very hard for her um to be waited upon so to speak i mean i think it's hard for her to
 		have that role of not being able to do as much as she used to
 	
 	
 		it's hard to accept the fact that you're unable to pursue life
 		at the level that you did before isn't it
 	
 	
 		yeah i think that's very true
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um on the other hand it takes on almost a a switch of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother child</ENAMEX> relationship
 	
 	
 		it is different i had that almost similar situation my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> lives in an <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> with my sister
 	
 	
 		uh
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		so i except for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the three or four months this summer</TIMEX> that's the only time i ever spent with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> and
 		of course since i see her only once or twice <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> i was just thrilled to have her here with me and i spent <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">every minute</TIMEX> i could to be with her and uh cooking <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">foods</ENAMEX> for her you know just to make her her life as though she were on vacation
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but somehow another it that doesn't work between my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> and they they find they they are
 		in speaking they i don't know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> feels uncomfortable around my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>'s uncomfortable because her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s there  and i guess it's just because they're there all the time
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so it's it puts has put pressure on both of them from that point of view
 		so that's that's kind of bad news and by the same token my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> is now moved into a nursing home
 		and after all she has been a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmer</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixty years</TIMEX> and now all of a sudden she's had to move off of her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farm</ENAMEX> into another <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> where the environment is totally different
 	
 	
 		um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		she's relatively happy but she doesn't like the food and when she complains about the food then everybody gets angry with her so that's another one of those things you have to solve
 	
 	
 		
 
 		huh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well that's got to be a big adjustment for someone that's as you say lived on a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farm</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixty years</TIMEX> and then
 		go to something like that
 	
 	
 		yeah after all their their life is so totally different because in those <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early days</TIMEX>
 		the food they had to make it from scratch so to speak i mean you raised your own <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">chickens</ENAMEX> and you killed your own <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">hogs</ENAMEX> i suppose and then they they had to store the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX> in uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i don't want to say <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">barns</ENAMEX> but they had regular little places they they would hang it you know to cure it and so forth and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and now all of a sudden it uh comes in differently it tastes differently
 	
 	
 		that's right yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	