
 
     		
 	
 		got to discuss movies you seen a movie recently <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mark</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		uh yeah as a matter of fact uh most recently i saw uh  <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dead Again</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i've heard that was real good
 	
 	
 		yeah i liked i liked it uh i went with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX> of mine
 	
 	
 		and enjoyed it huh who's the star
 	
 	
 		yeah it's
 		oh jeez  you know i don't even remember now
 	
 	
 		but it was good is it it's not a comedy is it
 	
 	
 		no it's uh
 	
 	
 		oh i know uh yeah i know the movie you're talking about yeah that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife star</ENAMEX> in it <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brannigan</ENAMEX> or something
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah i can't i can't even remember who's in it
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah where they were married <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> before or something
 	
 	
 		yeah they were they were married and then uh so the let's see who was it the the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">maid</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">maid</ENAMEX> kills the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and then the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> yeah the
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah i know what you're talking about
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Braun</ENAMEX>
 		oh really i didn't know the story but i knew it got a good review
 	
 	
 		yeah the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">maid</ENAMEX> kills the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> dies <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years later</TIMEX> something and they both come back as new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and it all kind of happens again
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		uh-huh i bet that was interesting sounds interesting
 	
 	
 		it was it was kind of strange
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		well i had the i i read the most reviews don't see too many movies we rent a few on
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		we don't go to them but i do enjoy a good movie i guess uh the most recent one i can think of that i saw was uh on the TV on the you know rental was <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Home Again</ENAMEX> did you see that Home Alone i mean
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah i saw that uh just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple weeks ago</TIMEX> as a matter of fact i finally got to see it
 	
 	
 		did you well it's been a little longer than that since i saw it but it was the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time i seen it and i thought <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> about <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> fourths of the way boy i thought what a i can't believe this movie is so highly rated
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		until <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about the last ten fifteen to twenty thirty minutes</TIMEX> of it then it then i was just rolling in the floor it was just hilarious
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i think that's what it i think that's what it is is it's that last you know fifteen <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX> or so that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> really get into it and they go hey this is a good movie
 	
 	
 		but i was really bored with it for so long
 		that would made the movie yeah it really is it was just hilarious but i did enjoy that well what else have you seen lately
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		uh  i also saw uh
 		the last of the uh Nightmare on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Elm Street</ENAMEX> series uh
 	
 	
 		i never have seen any of those they must be good i like some of those kind of movies was this one pretty good
 	
 	
 		yeah um this this last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> here wasn't very good at all it was it was only like <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an hour and a half long hour and fifteen minutes</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		it wasn't
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh really i can't believe it was so short
 	
 	
 		and uh it was i mean it was just boom it's over and and it wasn't very good the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the three</TIMEX> D effect that they have for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the last twenty minutes</TIMEX> of it was
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the worst i've seen yeah it's it's
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> and it truly is supposed to be the last of that series isn't it
 	
 	
 		yeah it is um the uh
 	
 	
 		maybe it's a good thing they bury it huh
 	
 	
 		well the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer director</ENAMEX> of the series is is going on to a new plot of of horror  i i i saw his new movie commercial on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX> i don't remember what it's called
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so he's moving on uh-huh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		on to another another topic of of horror yeah
 	
 	
 		of horror film  well well it's been
 	
 	
 		when you when you when you do it for so long it's all you ever basically know how to do is horror films
 	
 	
 		well that but if you you know if it's probably made him a extremely rich <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> too if it's successful i guess just keep with it  go to a different
 	
 	
 		yeah most likely
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		different <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">territory</ENAMEX> seem that's sure done wonders for old <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen King</ENAMEX> hasn't it
 	
 	
 		yeah really  even even even with crazy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> that try to claim that he stole their story and stuff like that
 	
 	
 		writing all those horror
 		yeah isn't that crazy i don't think he did do you
 	
 	
 		
 
 		no he's he's got too much integrity to do something like that yeah it it just
 	
 	
 		that and he's too successful and and too too warped a mind
 	
 	
 		i i think it just happened that some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> looked like you know kind of the character and everything and she decided well i can just say this is my story and
 	
 	
 		sure yeah and they say oh that's <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX> he stole they're trying to get some money that's all basically all they're trying to do i i would think anyway
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but uh
 		but i can't let's see i'm trying to think of another movie that i've seen lately and i can't think of
 	
 	
 		i i saw another rented one uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of mine rented it
 		i can't remember the name of it
 	
 	
 		isn't that funny you see them
 	
 	
 		must not have been good if i can't remember the name
 	
 	
 		you see them all the time and when you try to recall
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah you you i've i've watched so many movies here in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last few months</TIMEX> just you know seeing ones that i haven't seen before
 	
 	
 		uh-huh well it's good entertainment and it's it's so easy to do
 	
 	
 		yeah you can go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blockbuster</ENAMEX> and get you a movie and you know <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three or four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> can watch it rather than paying <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">six seven dollars</NUMEX> and
 	
 	
 		uh
 		yeah
 		yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blockbuster</ENAMEX>'s so successful i we don't go to them we just go  we don't watch that many but when we do we just go up here to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kroger</ENAMEX> because on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> they're ninety <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">nine cents</NUMEX> each for all their movies if you get down there in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX> you can you know get some pretty darn good movies
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but uh but boy Blockbuster lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> do go to them don't they
 	
 	
 		yeah i i've got a a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">membership card</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> different <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blockbusters i</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh-huh oh one one would doesn't work at all of them
 	
 	
 		no they they they issue a different card for each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blockbuster</ENAMEX> it's it's got their their particular address on it and stuff so that you don't try to take movies back to the wrong <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blockbuster</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		got to have each
 		oh uh-huh
 		yeah
 		oh i see well and it's successful the way they're running it so can't knock it
 	
 	
 		yeah i i i had moved for a while and that's when i got the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and then i came back home so i
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		and you live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Richardson</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> just made her call she talked to someone in Plano
 	
 	
 		do
 		
 		
 	