
 
     		
 	
 		okay i'll let you start this time
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well how much do you like lawn and garden work
 	
 	
 		well ah even though it's totally out of my ah my degree training i've been working as as in the horticultural
 		aspect uh for the last  you i don't know fifteen <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years</TIMEX> so uh i'm well i work for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> as as a groundskeepers
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh for goodness sakes what do you do
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well that's interesting um so at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this time of the year</TIMEX> are you doing much garden work
 	
 	
 		no mostly snow removal  which we've had a lot of
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but uh i don't know i i guess uh growing up on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farm</ENAMEX> and and that i i've always had a big interest uh i have a uh
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		when i have an area to do i i always had a big <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">garden</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		enjoy working on <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">lawns</ENAMEX> and and everything
 	
 	
 		well  i love to work outside really and i enjoy <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers</ENAMEX> and stuff i don't do a whole lot of it um at this exact point in my life um because i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> teenage boys
 		and so they do all the lawn all the lawn care
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but i still take care of the yeah flower beds and things like that
 		i was even planning to go out and to uh dig up some hibiscus <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> that will not make it through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the winter</TIMEX> here but you know were planted in the ground since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last spring</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i was going to dig them up for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> and for some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">starters</ENAMEX> for me and lo and behold about
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five days ago</TIMEX> we had a freeze down to about
 		oh twenty <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">three degrees</NUMEX> or something
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so the hibiscus hibiscus plants no longer exist and i really feel bad about it it's a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> that we've had for probably <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty five years</TIMEX> that these were cuttings off of you know
 	
 	
 		oh that's terrible <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty three</TIMEX> degree
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so
 		they're all gone at this point gardening in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> is really interesting though i grew up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and um  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> is just so hot in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> and so dry
 		why you know everyone that lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> and has yards practically has land um
 		a watering system
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so with that why our <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">lawns</ENAMEX> do stay um
 		you know pretty nice <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all summer</TIMEX> if you water but in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the winter</TIMEX> we have <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bermuda</ENAMEX> grass
 	
 	
 		huh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the winter</TIMEX> it turns as brown as a grocery sack
 	
 	
 		right yeah
 	
 	
 		and  and i just think it's ugly  when i go back home to my
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the winter</TIMEX> you know and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">grass</ENAMEX> is
 		fairly green
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah that's one one aspect of a lot of those grasses they go dormant
 		yeah i think the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ah Saint Augustine</ENAMEX> and uh  centipede <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">grass</ENAMEX> is another one you have quite a bit of down there yeah those two
 	
 	
 		um-hum um-hum  yeah some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have i think it's fescue
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		that stays green all winter
 		but they really have a heck of a time
 		keeping it going in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the middle of the summer</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		they have to water an incredible amount
 		but um those lawn those <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">lawns</ENAMEX> look nice during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the winter</TIMEX> but you know they almost stick out like a sore
 		i guess not a sore thumb a pretty thumb but you know
 		when you look at the neighborhoods and they're all brown except for one you know it's sort of like well
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well i know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> live uh in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX> there and uh you know they just grow rocks and and stuff there
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well and that's their gardening there so uh i guess as long as you can have ah some grass there
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		so i know i was uh in uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> and i i was working for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> once and we were taking care of <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">lawns</ENAMEX> out there and uh that particular year they had just tons of rain it was raining continuously so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then i know with all that moisture a lot of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">lawns</ENAMEX> get a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX> problems
 	
 	
 		yes that's true yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> is a a lot um a lot wetter than than <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas Dallas</ENAMEX> area that's where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plano</ENAMEX> is
 		and um  and just humidity
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know just all the time it's an awfully lot more humid
 	
 	
 		are are you uh able to get uh sometimes a double <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">crops</ENAMEX> of of certain things in your garden uh
 	
 	
 		yes uh-huh i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> do yeah i don't have a vegetable garden haven't for
 		i guess i never have here actually but um  but yes uh-huh i'll
 		we have <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neil Sperry</ENAMEX> talks on the radio
 		
 		
 	