
 
     		
 	
 		okay what kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> do you live in
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well uh we live in a a brick <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> in far north <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> and it's uh
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedrooms</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three and a half</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">baths</ENAMEX> and  swimming pool in the back and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		it's <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about thirty five hundred square feet</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		well it sounds like ours are pretty similar i live in one i don't have a swimming pool and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about twenty seven hundred</NUMEX> square foot
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedrooms</ENAMEX> and all the rest of it sounds just about  about alike i think it's pretty much typical for this area
 	
 	
 		it is have you been living there very long
 	
 	
 		i've been in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> i'm in here right now <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about twelve and a half</NUMEX> years
 	
 	
 		so you've been there longer we built this one about uh it's been
 		let's see
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		it's been <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six years six and a half years ago</TIMEX> and we subcontracted it on ourselves we bought the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lot</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh</ENAMEX> had an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX> draw the plans based on our specifications and then we subbed it out so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we've been here a little over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six years</TIMEX> now and uh have really enjoyed it because we built what we wanted to have to live in
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well i bet you have
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> got his big <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">garage</ENAMEX> he had we have a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> car <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">garage</ENAMEX> but he has a big work area in it and he likes to rebuild <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> and redo engines and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so he has all the work space he needs
 	
 	
 		well that sounds interesting i bet he's enjoyed having it that way because some kind of hard to find one prebuilt that's kind of fits those specifications
 	
 	
 		he
 		it is and that's why we decided to build we looked at things that were already uh built and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">garages</ENAMEX> were always
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		if the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> were was large it seemed like the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">garages</ENAMEX> were small even if they were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> car <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">garages</ENAMEX> which is what we have
 	
 	
 		well then most of them don't have a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> car <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">garage</ENAMEX> they're kind of rare
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		so we put a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> car <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">garage</ENAMEX> in but even if they had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> car <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">garages</ENAMEX> they didn't have a work space all of it was taken up with just car space
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so he has a big landing area that's between where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> are in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">garage</ENAMEX> and where the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> starts that he can work on
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well that my we've just got a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> car <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">garage</ENAMEX> but my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s got a big <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">space</ENAMEX> in between the where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> are and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> where he has a big work shop you know workbench and everything
 	
 	
 		well sounds like our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husbands</ENAMEX> have similar interests
 	
 	
 		now mine does not work on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> he just piddles on this and that but he likes to have a spot to keep all of his his piddling things
 	
 	
 		oh i see
 		uh-huh well that's nice that it's not in your house
 	
 	
 		it really is because you know they have a lot of little things of their own and i you know i wouldn't mind having
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time was gonna fix up when one of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX> left a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedroom</ENAMEX> to where i had a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> to just put all of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">craft</ENAMEX> stuff and sewing machine and all that kind of stuff
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i someone i don't know it ended up i got some furniture back that one of them had moved out or something so i didn't end up with my vacant <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> like i had thought i would
 	
 	
 		right
 		well we still have a a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> in college that come home and the other <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> we use as a guest <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedroom</ENAMEX> because my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> come
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> come and also the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> who come and stay and so it seems like it's always used as a bedroom
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well i've still <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all three</NUMEX> of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX> are married but i don't know i just still have need for the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedrooms</ENAMEX> just having <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> from time to time and some of them coming back home and things you know
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh i understand well
 	
 	
 		and we've got <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandchildren</ENAMEX> now so
 	
 	
 		well we  that's true and you don't want them to not be able to come because there's no room
 	
 	
 		when they come they have to have a place
 		that's right you sure don't at times i keep thinking though that might be kind of nice
 	
 	
 		well i okay i haven't reached that point yet i've heard <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> say that but uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 	
 	
 		my middle <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> is engaged my oldest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> has been going with the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> for a while he's out of college and has a good job so he could afford to get married but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		is not engaged yet and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>'s been going with the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> for a while but she's still in college and we're just as happy for her to finish her education first
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well i don't blame you for that
 	
 	
 		that's what she plans to do so i hope so
 	
 	
 		well i have the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> and then we ended up with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> grandsons
 	
 	
 		oh ho ho
 	
 	
 		and little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> are around the house
 	
 	
 		a whole new world um-hum
 	
 	
 		a whole lot more than girls
 		and uh i enjoy them coming but for short doses
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i can understand
 	
 	
 		it feels after they've been here <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ten minutes</TIMEX> they have already explored the entire <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> they know everything but they're they're fun
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		so you're all back to the safety catches and the whole <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">yards</ENAMEX> or either watching them every minute
 	
 	
 		well i just watch them i dust i never did put things up when my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> were little and i haven't with a them i try to teach them not to get into things
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		um
 		well that's the same thing that i did and i hope i'll be able to do the same with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandchildren</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i think that once you do that your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> kind of develop the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attitudes</ENAMEX> at least my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX> have they try to teach theirs not to get into things instead of having to put everything up
 		so it's worked pretty well there's i don't really think anything's been broken every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> and then we have to kind of go and say now don't bother this you know
 		but all in all they mind pretty well
 		but i guess most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> what kind of roof does your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> have here i'm getting off the subject
 	
 	
 		well we have
 		
 		
 	