
 
     		
 	
 		okay do you
 	
 	
 		well the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> that i subscribe to are i i'm i don't know if you're familiar is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Better Homes and Gardens</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah i'm familiar a little bit
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">okay and um Sesame Street</ENAMEX>  okay
 	
 	
 		Sesame Street yeah we've had that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> before
 		and uh i don't presently subscribe to any i think we've subscribed i've subscribed to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sports Illustrated</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um i think we've taken <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sesame Street</ENAMEX> actually before and um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		that's the big hit in this in this <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sesame Street</ENAMEX> because they have um you know the calendars and that kind of thing but i take the recipes and the home gardening and the furnishings from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Better Homes and Gardens</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		you uh do you do you read it all the way through everytime how often does it come out
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		once a month
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and i yeah i read it all the way through more than once and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> i find him reading it too
 	
 	
 		oh yeah huh
 	
 	
 		so and it's a free subscription my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> gave it to us so
 	
 	
 		oh well that's the the best kind oh oh we've uh i've had <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sports Illustrated</ENAMEX> we've had <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Geographic</ENAMEX> when it was free my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> got that for us it was free so we and uh
 		but um  i guess i found um i really i like reading them but i never i never seem to have because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sports</ENAMEX> see the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sports Illustrated</ENAMEX>'s weekly
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it and i just didn't seem to have time to sit down and read it
 	
 	
 		oh we we're always reading <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> because we we don't really subscribe to them we usually buy them off the rack and we're always buying <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Life</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> and um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		oh a few others i can't really think about but we're we're always reading <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> in this <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and oh and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Time</ENAMEX> and um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so we're we're we're always reading <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> in this house
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and um we saved all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Magazines</ENAMEX> from the um
 		from when um we went to war so we have all of those uh-huh well we saved yeah we saved them we thought maybe maybe they'd you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		huh you have a whole collection from the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gulf War</ENAMEX>
 		well that's a good idea
 	
 	
 		be useful later on in life when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> grow up because we have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> small
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah yeah do you get Life <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every month</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		um no the we don't purchase subscribe to those we just get them like maybe
 	
 	
 		no
 		yeah when it looks interesting yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah uh-huh maybe once every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three months</TIMEX> or something like that but
 	
 	
 		i haven't gotten a copy of that in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">well</ENAMEX> actually i don't know i my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> used to take it and uh when it was weekly
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and that that was i used to read it all the time then and i really haven't looked at it much since it went <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">monthly</TIMEX> except in the grocery line picking it up and looking looking at the pictures in it looked looked interesting
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		yeah
 		and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> is the kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> that prefers prefers the um  what do you call those the uh The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX> and um <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Star</ENAMEX>
 		yeah those suck  yeah he likes he loves those he'll read he'll read those all the time
 	
 	
 		oh yeah those the the tabloid things oh
 		does he really and <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">and and</ENAMEX> and you and you fess up to it huh
 	
 	
 		no i just i don't i don't read them
 	
 	
 		but you admit your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> does  huh
 	
 	
 		yeah he does all the time and
 	
 	
 		isn't that funny huh
 	
 	
 		and he'll sneak <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> home every once in a while in the grocery cart but that's just those i don't know those are just things i don't really i don't know i don't really find interesting i don't believe and he'll show me an article or two i i i don't believe it anyway so it's not
 	
 	
 		really
 		yeah i glance at them in line um but the stories are so ridiculous you know i mean uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		that's what he does he he'll stand in line and just laugh
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">right seven year old</TIMEX> gives birth to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">twins</ENAMEX> and um uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ninety nine</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year old</TIMEX> uh elopes with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten year</TIMEX> i mean you know i just huh
 	
 	
 		yeah  yeah well he he loves all of those yeah so those are his kind of
 		great role model for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> i guess
 	
 	
 		um-hum i read um the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> and i guess um
 		as i was thinking about it before the what i guess i like about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> is the article they'll cover the same material sort of
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but more more um more in depth and more thought out and more the whole picture instead of just you know one little
 	
 	
 		yeah uh-huh yeah
 		yeah
 		we usually just get get the newspaper on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekends</TIMEX> because we really don't have time during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX> but we usually get <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>'s and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>'s and that's really about it but uh we read like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dallas Life Magazine</ENAMEX> you know in there and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		those kind of pretty interesting so i mean just talking to you i i i realize how much we read i didn't really realize that that's just amazing
 	
 	
 		say it sounds like you read quite a bit really yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		we do now that i think about it we do read a lot so
 	
 	
 		i don't i've gotten to where i don't get one unless i'm on a trip a magazine
 	
 	
 		oh really oh
 	
 	
 		yeah just just about i mean i'll pick up when i'm going somewhere i'll pick up a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> and and uh usually a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sports Illustrated</ENAMEX> and uh occasionally i'll go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> and and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh you know they have all the current ones <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every every week</TIMEX> and i'll sit down and and read them read them there
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		yeah that's a good idea yeah i've only done it once but i
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well i uh i've got teenage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> so i you know they're usually there doing stuff and i'm and not ready to leave at the appointed hour so i end up i end up sitting you know while they're
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh
 		
 		
 	