
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		oh i guess uh this is a a topic near and dear to my heart since i am a uh am a healthy eater
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well i I try to be as well
 	
 	
 		well i'm not uh i there really isn't any kind of particular <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> that i i don't don't like really and i like a good <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> or a good uh um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh especially like good prime rib so if it's uh nice to get out and find a good <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> like that and i live here in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome New York</ENAMEX> and there are a lot of good <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> around here
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh you're in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> i was gonna there's a place if you ever make it to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> they have the best prime rib it's called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lawry</ENAMEX>'s like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lawry</ENAMEX>'s seasoning <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salt</ENAMEX> and it is absolutely wonderful
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		really
 	
 	
 		and uh we were there <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few months ago</TIMEX> and it i mean it's kind of pricey well from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> it probably doesn't matter but
 	
 	
 		well no i i'm in upstate <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> and it's actually very inexpensive i there's a there's a place um <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">half a mile</NUMEX> from me here that uh
 	
 	
 		oh is it okay
 	
 	
 		has uh fantastic prime rib for uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> dollars a whole <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meal</ENAMEX> you know a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">potato</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salad</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">soup</ENAMEX> and the whole whole <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">yards</ENAMEX> so it
 	
 	
 		wow
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah well i think the cheapest there probably starts at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighteen</NUMEX> and it includes you know <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salad</ENAMEX> and rolls and oh some other stuff but it is absolutely wonderful it's the best i have ever had
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah i was going to this place up the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> from me is the best i've ever had so  i'll have to go there when i get there get to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well yeah well we like uh lots of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> down here like <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> food
 	
 	
 		uh-huh sure
 	
 	
 		so um that's i i think <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> are probably my favorites
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but um i'm not into <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sushi</ENAMEX> or any of that kind of stuff
 	
 	
 		no no i'm not into the the don't do the the raw raw fish like that but i do like uh like a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">seafood bar</ENAMEX> like a raw raw <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX> like oysters and things like that uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that they uh i go on i'm an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX> and travel quite a bit on business so i uh find myself down in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Melbourne Florida</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every</TIMEX> about once once a month once every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two months</TIMEX> or so and uh
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		go and hit the the oyster <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bars</ENAMEX> down there quite a bit uh i love that
 	
 	
 		oh yeah get fresh <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">seafood</ENAMEX> down there
 	
 	
 		and um and uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX>'s great you get the crabs it's like i can't go anywhere where i i where i don't enjoy myself so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">seafood</ENAMEX> seems to be a little a little bit more expensive than than other types of food
 	
 	
 		that's true but
 	
 	
 		but it sure is good and it's supposed to be good for you
 	
 	
 		yeah well yeah it's really strange that that that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">seafood</ENAMEX> is so expensive because when you in reality uh
 		uh i say that the oceans have the greatest resource resource of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> on the planet and yet we haven't as human beings haven't figured out a way to harvest it economically  so
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 	
 	
 		we've managed to uh figure out how to get at just about everything else but uh but not uh not seafood
 	
 	
 		
 
 		uh-huh do you like uh spicy <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">foods</ENAMEX> or
 	
 	
 		what
 		yeah yeah i like yeah i'd make a a wicked chili and uh like around here the big spicy thing is like uh buffalo wings
 	
 	
 		oh uh-huh
 	
 	
 		and so uh  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> they you know you go out to get the chicken <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wings</ENAMEX> and those are really hot and the hotter the better and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah well we uh we like spicy food down here especially uh the hot <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sauce Picante sauce</ENAMEX> or salsa whatever y'all call it and uh we we sure go through a lot of that
 	
 	
 		right
 		sure
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but i like it hot but i don't like it real hot because then my nose starts running
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		my my generally my my scalp will start i can feel just the top of my scalp getting hot it's like weirdest weirdest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sensation</ENAMEX> almost like a tingling but uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i don't know but uh yeah well there isn't isn't too much in the way of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> that i don't like things that are kind of oddball like uh <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Thai</ENAMEX> cuisine i i never been
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		really fond of that stuff you talk about spicy that'll that'll literally blow your head off it's so hot  and i can handle just about any kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> without uh um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well but that that stuff is goes one notch beyond uh my tolerances so
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		although i guess on this topic i  talk about the uh service in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> is always nice though too that's one thing what's that yeah
 	
 	
 		oh yeah and and the price and the price make you wanna come back
 	
 	
 		well i find that lately that so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are working you know they're working waitressing jobs or waiter
 		
 		
 	