
 
     		
 	
 		go  what have you seen
 	
 	
 		do you want to talk first about the one that you've seen or you want me to go
 	
 	
 		oh mine was too scary go ahead
 	
 	
 		the last movie that i saw was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Little Man Tate</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh was it good
 	
 	
 		it was was a lot of fun yeah it was um  real popular obviously it was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a week</TIMEX> after it'd come out i think
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh i didn't really have any um  preconceived notions of what it was gonna be about so it was fun to i don't wanna tell you about it i don't know if i should uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah have you seen <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Paradise</ENAMEX>
 		with uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melanie Griffith</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don Johnson</ENAMEX> no i haven't seen that one either i was hoping you well
 	
 	
 		um
 		no no
 		let's see what else have you seen recently we can talk about one we've both seen
 	
 	
 		well i rented we rented my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> i have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teenagers</ENAMEX> rented <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Silence</ENAMEX> of the Lambs
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh
 	
 	
 		have you seen it oh it's
 	
 	
 		no see that
 		that's the kind of film that i probably wouldn't see um there's certain ones that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and i know that he might see with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> and i wouldn't want to see
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah well i probably shouldn't have
 		yeah i i don't know that i don't know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> chose not to watch it and he obviously slept <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">all night</TIMEX> and i prayed really hard that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> wouldn't have nightmares and i had nightmares for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two nights</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		did you yeah
 	
 	
 		oh it's just it's so interesting but it that is the last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> that i saw on home video
 	
 	
 		and and did your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> have any reaction to it what were the kind of comments that they had
 	
 	
 		well i probably shouldn't have let my younger ones watch it they are um
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years old</TIMEX> but and especially after this <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeffrey Dahmer</ENAMEX> thing really had my <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year old</TIMEX> going
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh boy
 	
 	
 		you know and it was and he had lots of questions and i had to do a lot of reassuring but what my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> made some really interesting observations about how <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hannibal the Cannibal</ENAMEX> you know was um playing with this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">gal</ENAMEX>'s mind
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		uh-huh they were aware that that
 	
 	
 		you know which was something he was supposed to watch for and i mean it was very awful and you know it teaches them to
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um be careful of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strangers</ENAMEX> and and and
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah i guess there is that in those scary movies there's definitely the element of uh caution
 	
 	
 		oh yeah so that was
 		but i have bought <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fantasia</ENAMEX> for my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and myself actually
 	
 	
 		you know i i would like that as well i i've been looking for that and i haven't found it yet but i know that it's um  i think it's at not not the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">warehouse</ENAMEX> but uh
 	
 	
 		Costco those those kind of places kind of discount places yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blockbuster Video</ENAMEX> that's the one that i think i heard that it was
 	
 	
 		oh yeah but you yeah you can just buy now the one i'm buying is a used one which i don't get till <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX> so <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> will be using it until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX> but i got it for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> bucks so
 	
 	
 		oh that's great
 	
 	
 		you know yeah well i hope it'll be okay that's the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> movie of all movies that i'm gonna buy
 	
 	
 		no i i have to ask you about foreign films have you seen <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angel at</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">My Table</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no is it wonderful
 	
 	
 		uh oh it's kind of like My Left <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Foot</ENAMEX> if you had a chance to see that it's very much like that you know it focuses on an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> who has
 	
 	
 		oh yes yes i did see that oh
 	
 	
 		well in in her case she's very very shy
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> and that's not a physical disability but it's certainly a social emotional disability in her case and it it's really beautiful you know because it shows how she blossoms and and about her her her development
 	
 	
 		oh yeah sure
 		oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">My Table</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh-huh um another one that i really liked was called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Truly Madly</ENAMEX> Deeply
 	
 	
 		okay we'll keep an eye out
 		nope
 	
 	
 		i believe it's a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">film</ENAMEX> as well and it came well there there are a couple they they tend to you know show up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		so you like foreign films
 		yes yeah more than <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yakima Washington</ENAMEX> i'm afraid
 	
 	
 		there are a couple <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theaters</ENAMEX> that usually show good ones you can count on them to show foreign films that you you feel like you might enjoy as opposed to some that are so eclectic that you can't really relate to them
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right  right
 	
 	
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">um Truly Madly Deeply</ENAMEX> is a love story about a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s let's see it's her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> that dies it came out shortly after Ghost
 	
 	
 		ooh
 		oh and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ghost</ENAMEX> was your one of your favorites
 	
 	
 		so um i i kind of i kind related to it a little bit because it it was about her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s love and her love being so strong that he was able to sort of
 		converse with her after he died in such a way to kind of help her make the separation from his death because she was having really hard time grieving for like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year or so</TIMEX> after his death and
 	
 	
 		ooh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		and it was called what Truly
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Truly Madly</ENAMEX> Deeply
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Truly Madly</ENAMEX> Deeply
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> that's how they they used to have a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a</NUMEX> a game about how much they loved each other they'd loved each other truly no truly madly no truly madly deeply
 	
 	
 		sounds wonderful
 		oh i see oh it sounds wonderful
 	
 	
 		yeah it's a sweet film it's actually kind of a a spoof on life after death because
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		he not only comes back to visit her and help her make the transition after his death but he brings all of his his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and a lot of them are you know playing cards in her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> oh
 		
 
 	
 	
 		jamming on musical instrument it it's pretty it's pretty funny
 	
 	
 		oh well that would be comforting in a way you know
 		oh  well that's great um what else have i seen
 		oh well we went to see um and you won't you don't go see dumb things but it was called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Hot Shots</ENAMEX> totally a waste of
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">um Hot Shot</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	