
 
     		
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hey Patty</ENAMEX> uh we're supposed to talk about uh child care
 	
 	
 		
 
 		okay
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are all grown
 	
 	
 		huh i don't have any  no
 	
 	
 		and you don't have any  well <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">some day</TIMEX> you will and then then you'll be real selective about choosing a child care right
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah i worked at a child care <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> for about a week
 	
 	
 		well you know all about them then well tell me about it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well that was all i could take not so much the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> but because of the director
 	
 	
 		oh those
 		you didn't like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		hum-um but um i had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about ten</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in a class  and i just know they take a lot of energy
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh boy i bet it did
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> worked at a child care quite <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years ago</TIMEX> and she liked it all right when her
 	
 	
 		huh how long did she work there
 	
 	
 		oh i think she worked there <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about two years</TIMEX> our
 	
 	
 		gosh she must be very patient
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two or three years</TIMEX> well we had small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> at the time see so so uh it worked out pretty good she'd be there with some of them and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> broke her in
 		oh great
 	
 	
 		and uh it worked out real good it was a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church school</ENAMEX> where we we went to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> there  and uh she worked there
 	
 	
 		good
 		hm
 		hm
 	
 	
 		but uh i have uh all my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are grown now and they have their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in day care <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one one</NUMEX> of them keeps her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> with a  with a relative though
 	
 	
 		hm
 		hm
 	
 	
 		and uh but the other one has used a day care for her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh
 	
 	
 		nice when you have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> that can do that
 	
 	
 		yeah they they uh her her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> and she needs the money and and plus she you know she's close and gives him good care and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		it's
 		does she have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> too or
 	
 	
 		and she has <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> too and he's just a baby but he does enjoy though she has <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">twins</ENAMEX> and they're <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two or three years</TIMEX> older than him but they
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		hm
 	
 	
 		all spoil him you know and he key likes it watching them play and everything  but uh
 	
 	
 		hm um-hum
 		well even with um <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> in my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>  it was still quite a handful
 	
 	
 		oh gosh i'm sure it was i wouldn't you couldn't pay me to work in one you know you got to like you just got to you know not mind <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> that much
 	
 	
 		so
 		
 
 		um-hum yep
 	
 	
 		but uh
 	
 	
 		because they try your patience you know not on purpose not on purpose but they just get into everything and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well of course that's just the way they are
 	
 	
 		uh-huh running around and diaper changing
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		and when you don't have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> of your own that's not a lot of fun is it  well but you probably will some day reckon
 	
 	
 		so
 		um-hum right
 		um yeah first i need to get married though first i need to get married  uh-huh  oh
 	
 	

 		plenty
 		huh
 		well yeah but you got plenty of time to do that you sound pretty young
 		but uh so i don't have a whole lot of experience with day care <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> myself now either
 	
 	
 		hm um-hum
 		well this one was pretty good um
 	
 	
 		was it in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh-huh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and since that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> was really really picky about kind of silly things you know nothing that really had to do with you know endangering the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> or anything you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um like she didn't like the way i answered the phone or you know she didn't like this she didn't like that things that didn't have anything to do with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		oh yeah uh-huh i thought it might have been something that the state required but that wouldn't
 	
 	
 		um-hum no it just she had such high expectations about silly little things you know
 	
 	
 		that wouldn't apply to that would it
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> that didn't make sense uh
 	
 	
 		right so but i probably could've put up with you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and  all that but it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well and it those kind it probably didn't pay a whole lot either
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">nope huh-uh nope</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so if it doesn't pay a whole lot it's hard to put up with a lot of
 	
 	
 		right um-hum
 	
 	
 		
  
 		that <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Mickey Mouse</ENAMEX> stuff that's my other line but i no i'll just ignore it while
 	
 	
 		you wanna grab it real quick or because it'll be recorded i guess
 	
 	
 		yeah i'll just i'll just ignore it and if they want anything they'll  in a little while
 	
 	
 		okay
 		hm
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		since we got
 	
 	
 		so are you you said your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> or
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandchildren</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> and they're happy with their day care <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> or
 	
 	
 		yeah well neither one of them have them in a day care <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> right now but uh um my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> that  has has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX> she is a
 	
 	
 		oh huh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you still there aren't you
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i guess it was that thing hanging up uh she had him in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and was real happy with it and then got unhappy with it and then she moved him to another <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and was just real happy with it it's in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Garland</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		huh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so uh she had really i'd say she had pretty good experiences with them
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh oh yeah the one she the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> one she quit they'd lost his medicine
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		sent it home with another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> and it made her mad but i mean that's you know you got fifty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> there i could see that happening
 	
 	
 		huh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but you course you lose a fifty dollar bottle of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX> but it looks like somebody
 	
 	
 		ooh you'd wanna be reimbursed at least
 	
 	
 		well it looks like they would've whoever took it home would've brought it back
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but anyway it made her real mad that's why she left it but other than that i mean it you know they'd been real good too so i'd i'd say she's had really you know real good experiences with them
 	
 	
 		huh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		that's good
 	
 	
 		nothing no horror stories or you know of course they're regulated pretty strictly by the state
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		um-hum yep
 	
 	
 		and uh which is good
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 		
 	