
 
     		
 	
 		tell me what you like to do
 	
 	
 		well  i i collect antique tools uh for one thing i well i'm sort of in a an antique business but it's it's a little sideline part time thing
 	
 	
 		oh
 		uh-huh wonderful
 	
 	
 		and uh i'm building a a log <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> at a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farm</ENAMEX> that i have in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Texas</ENAMEX> which you like a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a a hundred miles</NUMEX> from here
 	
 	
 		ah
 		wonderful
 	
 	
 		yeah it's really neat and i i been course i've been working on it for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX> but you know
 	
 	
 		oh but how wonderful how are you close to getting it done
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah it's getting real close to you know uh of course there's still a lot of work to be done and then when you get it completely you you know the shell finished uh you still have a lot of stuff to do inside
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		but uh
 	
 	
 		are you gonna move your whole <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> over there then
 	
 	
 		no actually uh  i'm i'm not even sure i may i'll probably always have a place here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Richardson</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh-huh  kind of your getaway place
 	
 	
 		yeah  escape
 		but it's beautiful it a you know it's eastern hardwood um forest  there are a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">pine trees</ENAMEX> but it's mostly <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">oaks</ENAMEX> and ah
 	
 	
 		oh how beautiful and it's pretty flat there
 	
 	
 		well it's it's kind of  <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">hilly</NUMEX> but it's you know low hills it's not uh
 	
 	
 		see i've only been to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> once i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> now um one in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX> one in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> and the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> is the one that got me to doing this
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and um i thought <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX> was beautiful i liked the hills and the trees
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX> it it's really different because that's kind of a you you know that's the chalk hills down there limestone limestone hills
 	
 	
 		oh and you've always lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> have you
 	
 	
 		yeah except for time in service
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		born raised <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Texan</ENAMEX> huh well i had never been there that's that's pretty neat my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> both seem to like it pretty well my brother-in-law works for the university um in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		he's admissions director
 	
 	
 		which
 		at at which one
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">uh University of Texas</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		oh okay that's just north of me here
 	
 	
 		yeah well that he's got a job there and this is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">his first year</TIMEX> so it's been a real interesting thing for them
 	
 	
 		that's great
 	
 	
 		but they seem to like it okay i think they're too far away from me but
 	
 	
 		well yeah
 	
 	
 		maybe some day they can get closer we'll see
 	
 	
 		that's a pretty good trip so what are you what kind of hobbies are you in
 	
 	
 		well i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> so basically i'm just real busy with  my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> right now in sports and we have a little <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Halloween</TIMEX> talent show <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX> it's
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i substitute at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> part time
 	
 	
 		oh that's great
 	
 	
 		well i am a travel <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> at heart and my hobby is just i love traveling and and being involved of that and finding out more uh but it's real hard to work in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summers</TIMEX> and holidays and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekends</TIMEX> when you have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		no kidding
 	
 	
 		i reluctantly gave that career up and am just substituting at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> so i've been <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">librarian</ENAMEX> all <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> which has been real interesting and i'm enjoying it i'm around my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hey</ENAMEX> that's
 		that's pretty easy substituting isn't it
 	
 	
 		oh yeah yeah it's great it's great and what else do i do i do lots of cross stitching when i have time and i enter things in our little state fair and that's pretty fun
 	
 	
 		
 
 		ooh
 		that's great
 	
 	
 		well that actually my hobbies is mostly is my sports tennis i play <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">tennis</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		ooh i love tennis too and i ski ski do you ski
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ooh</ENAMEX> do you yes we snow ski we snow ski at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mount Bachelor</ENAMEX> mostly in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oregon</ENAMEX> have you ever been there
 	
 	
 		uh that's great i
 		no uh
 	
 	
 		wonderful place
 	
 	
 		i've skied in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> and we usually usually go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Mexico</ENAMEX> because it's a little cheaper you know but uh
 	
 	
 		ooh
 		
  
 		uh-huh where in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh i've been to uh Telluride which is on the west side and uh <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Copper Copper</ENAMEX> is kind of my favorite up there Breckenridge uh
 	
 	
 		yes yes
 		really
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Keystone</ENAMEX> i guess those are the only places i've skied up there
 	
 	
 		i would love i can hardly wait to get up there
 	
 	
 		me too you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> are are you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> getting snow
 	
 	
 		we it is snowing right now we're to get <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">three inches</NUMEX> tonight
 	
 	
 		oh gee well
 	
 	
 		it's awful
 	
 	
 		i heard <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aspen</ENAMEX> got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> feet
 	
 	
 		oh yeah well we're yeah we are on the dry side of the mountain <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX> is <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">only about two and a half hours so</TIMEX> of course i'm a real <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Seahawks</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> and um going over that pass is just a real nightmare
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i can imagine my lord
 	
 	
 		and um  so and we're on the colder side they're on the rainy side we're on the snowy side
 		yeah and um
 		we we ski my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> all ski and we we have been to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whistler</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX> which is just a marvelous place <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whistler</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Black Home</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh super
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		is in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX> and then we've gone to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sun Valley</ENAMEX> several times that's a just a great place
 		but no <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> not in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> since i was in college because i went to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> haven't been there i keep hearing these marvelous things about <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Deer Valley</ENAMEX> and um  don't <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Adam  um  City</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		what about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX>
 		yeah i haven't either
 		i always wanted to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Banff</ENAMEX> or somewhere like that you know
 	
 	
 		ooh yes and your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> all ski
 	
 	
 		uh not all of them  my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are all grown uh but my youngest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">skier</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		really that's great well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> are at the point where they scare their mommy to death when they're skiing they're fearless and they go off
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	