
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well you go first you called
 	
 	
 		okay uh let's see
 		um
 		well i'm <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about forty</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years old</TIMEX> so i was um right at draft age back back when uh when that was all going on
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		so that pretty it very much affected me as you know as far as being
 		very impressionable right at that time um
 		i i didn't think i was kind of kind of a caught up in the in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hippie</ENAMEX> movement back then and i didn't think it was uh worthwhile or or right then and i'm not any i'm not like you know i'm not a not that way anymore but i still don't think it was uh
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		uh i still have a lot of questions about why we were there and and uh the way it was conducted and all kinds of things
 	
 	
 		
 
 		right
 	
 	
 		yeah how about yourself
 	
 	
 		well i'm i'm i'll be <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">forty two</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX> in fact my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> was in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> lottery you know he he was in the first
 	
 	
 		so you
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> lottery and uh he got a high draft number thank goodness so he didn't have to go but i never was for it either i um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i don't know i just felt it was a real political thing that i don't really think ever got us anywhere you know i don't i don't feel that we
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		that we accomplished much i think maybe i i don't know
 		i i want to say well maybe if we'd gone into really win it but then i i i'm much more of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dove</ENAMEX> than that so i don't know that i would have even liked that i just felt that it it drug on so long and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 	
 	
 		at such tremendous cost um and i think it was hard for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to keep up good morale in a situation like that i mean i i can't imagine what it was like for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> fighting over there i think that must have been a really hard thing to um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know to to keep their morale up uh when they knew that we weren't really trying to win and and all of that so i never was really for it i mean uh
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well i was in the uh last lottery
 	
 	
 		oh you were
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">yep</ENAMEX> and i was i came out number <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two hundred</NUMEX> and fifty one
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and i had been and they and uh they only took up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two hundred</NUMEX> that year
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i had been uh in in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ROTC</ENAMEX> too uh so i would at least have a choice about what i was going to do
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and when i came up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two hundred and fifty one</NUMEX> i went that's it  i dropped out of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ROTC</ENAMEX> and and uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh yeah i i don't uh
 		i guess uh i i kind of do the same thing i kind of think well you know i mean if if at least if we had weren't going all out to win it maybe it would have been worth
 		something but then again i i uh probably too much of a dub my self to really
 	
 	
 		well right i i don't necessarily like that philosophy but i think i would have liked that better than what we did
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		what we did
 		yeah because all we had is uh what <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten thirteen years</TIMEX> and fifty <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six thousand</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and and and we uh i don't know that we did we accomplish anything at all
 	
 	
 		exactly
 		i i i don't think so i mean uh
 	
 	
 		i mean the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communists</ENAMEX> got it anyway
 	
 	
 		and and it's still such a mess in that part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> you know it's not like you know i think if things had been resolved and that was in a better situation but i don't think that's true
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so uh you know i'm not sure that we
 		really accomplished much of anything
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so i don't know and and i still think we're paying for that i think that there are you know a lot of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> just suffered so terribly in that situation um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so i i don't know i i'm glad i never i didn't have anybody well i had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> close to me that went but that's all i didn't know a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that went did you did you
 	
 	
 		yeah i didn't know anyone that that i can recall that went that which is uh now i've met some i've met some after the fact you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that i worked with and stuff that had been several actually that i worked with that had been but i didn't know i no one that i grew up with
 	
 	
 		well i had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> and he was in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">infantry</ENAMEX> and he was little and what he did was he went into the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tunnels</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 		no you're kidding
 	
 	
 		no and he came back he he lived through it which is just amazing and he would not talk um talk about it much at all
 	
 	
 		huh
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		he he just would not discuss it um
 		he did tell us <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time about seeing someone a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a</NUMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> about his age you know he was probably <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty</TIMEX> i think
 		and he came up upon a a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Vietnamese</ENAMEX> and they both had their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> on each other and they just looked at each other and put their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> down and walked away
 	
 	
 		hm very sensible
 	
 	
 		i i thought so too and uh
 	
 	
 		yeah what what part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> were you in when all that was going on
 	
 	
 		i'm from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Phoenix Arizona</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		so i was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Phoenix</ENAMEX> where were you
 	
 	
 		i was in uh i'm from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> but i was in uh uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort Worth</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh you came out here to go to school
 	
 	
 		yeah so i was kind of in and i was you know there were there were about <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty hippies</TIMEX> on the whole campus i went to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCU</ENAMEX> and there were there were about <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty hippies</TIMEX> on the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campus</ENAMEX> and we we were
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		we were very much minority  so it was kind of it wasn't like being up in uh Kent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> with uh with uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten thousand</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protestors</ENAMEX> that were that were
 	
 	
 		oh
 		well i was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">State</ENAMEX> and i can remember um
 		coming out i had gone into a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> to eat and coming out and there were about oh i don't know how many <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> coming down the the street they had completely cordoned off the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> and you know there was lots of protesting going on there at the time so i
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	