
 
     		
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		
 
 		do you want to start
 	
 	
 		yes on uh taking care of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elderly</ENAMEX> do you have an older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relative</ENAMEX> that you are concerned with right now
 	
 	
 		i just have one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> that's that's alive and i'm she's i think in her low eighties but she lives by herself and takes care of herself and stuff and she's healthy
 	
 	
 		i see
 		that's very important
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i tell you i have uh faced this whole subject myself because my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> is not quite that old but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		she uh has <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Parkinson's</ENAMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		we tried taking care of her in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and it got to where it wasn't safe and then uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we had to to uh try different things and finally she's in a nursing home
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hm</ENAMEX> did you hear they're coming closer to a cure for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Parkinson's</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um i hope so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because it really is a bad disease
 	
 	
 		because a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in uh i think a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guam</ENAMEX> or something have it so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um they're studying those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and coming closer to a cure
 	
 	
 		well they know what causes it uh and you know it's a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">an insufficiency</NUMEX> in the brain
 	
 	
 		what
 		um-hum i think it was it was on the news and they mentioned something like that some chemical
 	
 	
 		yeah but uh
 		so far they haven't uh that i know of they haven't figured out why there's a <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">deficiency</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX> they give them is supposed to replace it but it it doesn't
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it also has side affects
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		how do you feel about having to place someone in a nursing home
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well i hope i can take care of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> someday i hope i can afford to
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 		um i guess it depends on what the nursing home's like because there's some very nice ones that i wouldn't mind checking into it myself
 	
 	
 		hm well well
 	
 	
 		and
 	
 	
 		i think another part of it it depends on whether you are uh physically able to do it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		to give them the care they need
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> that's true if you have to work you know you don't have a choice
 	
 	
 		well and then too uh i found that even if i didn't work
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i couldn't hold up to taking care of mother <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty four hours a day</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because
 	
 	
 		it's hard work
 	
 	
 		it just uh
 		uh you know she couldn't do anything by herself and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		her mind wonders and she wonders
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh i've tried it on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekends</TIMEX> and stuff and
 		i
 		my feeling on it
 	

 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		is that the nursing home is there if you need it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but you hope you don't need it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i think your health is important as important as theirs
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um have you ever thought about what uh kind of things you would look for in a nursing home if you ever had to choose
 	
 	
 		well i guess just a nice caring environment for one thing
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and just
 		cheery atmosphere
 		um i've gone to this nursing home over on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">um Forest Lane</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greenville</ENAMEX> out there
 	
 	
 		um
 		yes
 	
 	
 		um just for like field trips i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> and i take my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> to nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> because um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		good
 	
 	
 		we study old age and stuff and um there's this one particular <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> over there that i've visited that was really nice and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> would hug the
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elderly people</ENAMEX> you know hello and um we <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the days</TIMEX> we were there we played games with them and just real nice atmosphere real cheerful atmosphere and it's a gorgeous nursing home too
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		that's good
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		they love the the older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> love to be around <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> too
 	
 	
 		um-hum and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> i have to like drag them out of there too so
 	
 	
 		isn't that great
 	
 	
 		uh-huh i think it's mutual
 	
 	
 		yeah that's great
 	
 	
 		so like a grandparent or something
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so um
 		i don't know if i could
 	
 	
 		course there's a
 	
 	
 		um put my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> in a place like that i wouldn't feel bad
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know
 	
 	
 		well i think the worst worst thing about having to do it is the guilt you do feel
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i think the first thing is you have to be absolutely sure that's what you need to do
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		i know
 		in in my situation we had to consider nursing care and uh
 	
 	
 		um-hum that's another thing medical
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> available and the fact that it's clean and you also have to you have to uh pay attention to how much it costs too
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		um yeah i bet because it can probably cost a fortune
 	
 	
 		um-hum it it can and it costs more than most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> make in a year
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		but uh
 	
 	
 		does insurance help cover it at all or
 	
 	
 		there is a special insurance you can buy
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		for nursing home insurance in fact my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and i take it
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		
 
 		because we hope we never have to use it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh it would uh
 		take care of an interim period until you know if it was a long-term care until <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX> would kick in
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		do you have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> or
 	
 	
 		because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX> uh pardon
 	
 	
 		do you have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um-hum but uh
 	
 	
 		so you have um plenty of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to take care of you some day
 	
 	
 		well um
 		
 		
 	