
 
     		
 	
 		feel about um the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> situation right now
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well i am more uh
 		more scared than than ever actually by it because it to me if you look at the uh situation in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Eastern Europe</ENAMEX> it closely parallels the situation around <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the turn of the century</TIMEX> with the fall of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ottoman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		um it is very unstable right now
 	
 	
 		yeah and there's a the huge power vacuum and no one to control the local economies over there the inner
 		uh trade between those <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">republics</ENAMEX> and the satellites uh or what used to be the satellites of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> and i'm afraid that it's just going to  gonna have regional
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		infighting just like there was before <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War One</ENAMEX> and we're going to be stuck in another war
 	
 	
 		yeah i'm it's really scary because i you know i i had a conversation or i heard it over a conversation that they had with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gorbachev</ENAMEX> on the news
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		stating that he needs to get you know like a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> set up over there because they're not gonna make the winter
 		without the food and the electricity
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and if they don't if if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't have food and electricity they're gonna go after it somehow and they're and they're gonna fight it out instead of doing it calmly like he's trying to have done now
 	
 	
 		sure
 		right
 	
 	
 		um i went over to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about three years ago</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		and it was very sad  they it the economy over there is very poor um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		and it's worse now
 	
 	
 		oh yeah and when we went over there we were not allowed you know off this bus
 		or you know into the you know onto the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> or anything like that well when i went i did anyway and i got out  and um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		um you know yeah i know it we barely got back but um
 	
 	
 		rebel you
 	
 	
 		we went into the black market where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> our age were you know i'm <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty three</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and we went down there and these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> wanted anything that was made that was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Lee</ENAMEX> jeans your coats your shoes anything that you brought with you and they'd give you things
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because they wanted these clothes and they looked just like we did because they would ask for these clothes and stuff so after you came out it was very sad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were in the real drab clothing and whenever you bought something you'd have to go through <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four or five</NUMEX> lines to get it
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and it was you know really sad to see that but um
 		yeah it it's something else over there everything's breaking down when we the motel we stayed in you know you could only stay in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American hotels</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		um the we didn't have <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four days</TIMEX> and when we did get it it looked like <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">apple juice</ENAMEX> it was awful and and you know to see how they live over there
 	
 	
 		oh God  hey wait a minute the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> comes out here it it looks like that too
 	
 	
 		right  and it was just real sad to see it that way
 		but um you know like our tour guide was a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixteen year</TIMEX> old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> um she was married and living with her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> and you know they live in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment buildings</ENAMEX> around there
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		jeez
 	
 	
 		and because she got the job because she could speak <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so she got to be a tour guide and it was really bizarre because um she couldn't shave her legs or anything and they couldn't get razors and so um she asked for us to go into the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX> and buy her razors so that she could do that
 		and it was just something else to see
 	
 	
 		the wonders of Western culture get to shave your legs
 	
 	
 		yeah you know
 		yeah and and well you know and you know everywhere i went over there it was it was like that but she wanted to do that and and so did every you know all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> that were our age were
 		you know wanting to be more like that and so it's really scary because there's gonna be something something's gonna have to happen
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		so you did this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one year</TIMEX> in college where'd you go to school
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah i did um <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northern State</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Aberdeen South Dakota</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Dakota</ENAMEX> no i'm an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">uh Griffis Air Force Base</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		yeah so i'm i'm just a lieutenant i'm <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only twenty four</NUMEX> so i'm it's interesting hearing from someone
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		of my perspective i always think that my view is always so much older and uh more conservative but uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i don't know i've maybe done older spent a little more time learning from history than the average armchair uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">right</TIMEX>  listening to the TV type of thing um-hum
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah and everybody's jumping up and down praising all this and you you know it great
 	
 	
 		they don't understand what's gonna happen
 	
 	
 		yeah you know there's
 		i think there's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> thing that's worse than the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and that's no government
 	
 	
 		that's right and on right now they're bordering on that because there's nothing there
 	
 	
 		yeah there there really are
 	
 	
 		you know you've got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> one thinks he's doing it and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gorbachev</ENAMEX> thinks he's you know got it and
 		you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX>'s got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> and  and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KGB</ENAMEX> is supposedly gone but um
 	
 	
 		well i don't think uh
 		uh i don't think you can rule out anything like that
 	
 	
 		no you can't you can't they're to they were too powerful for too long
 	
 	
 		and especially when
 		when it gets to the point where things are really desperate then uh then the military becomes a threat as well
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and uh
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know there the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX> still has a lot of power
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and somebody has to control all those nuclear weapons it's not even  the the situation isn't even is so much
 		
 		
 	