
 
     		
 	
 		what are some of the TV shows that you watch
 	
 	
 		
 
 		um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Major Dad</ENAMEX> the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> comedies on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Major Dad  Murphy Brown</ENAMEX> is one of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">favorites</ENAMEX>  for huh for some reason she reminds me a lot of myself  it's just the writing i think the writing on that's real good
 	
 	
 		yes i love those
 		
 
 		yes she is great i just love her
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		it is
 	
 	
 		one i miss is uh <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Doctor Doctor</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		did you watch that one
 	
 	
 		i use we used to when it was on because i i thoroughly enjoyed it
 	
 	
 		uh-huh i didn't
 		did you i guess i never really watched that one i guess by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">eight o'clock</TIMEX> i'm watching football
 	
 	
 		uh yeah i understand that  i do understand that no
 	
 	
 		with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> so
 		
 
 		yeah that's a big one in our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh uh yeah well he used to be before we got married but my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s not a real big football <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> so my well he is if it's <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> and if they're on TV but if it's not then we'll watch anything else because he really likes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Major Dad</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">and Murphy Brown</ENAMEX> and all those too
 	
 	
 		oh he isn't
 		
 
 		right
 		um-hum well that's nice
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh and</ENAMEX> and uh what's the other one oh with the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> women <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Designing Women</ENAMEX> yes i like that one
 	
 	
 		oh  uh <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Designing Women</ENAMEX> yes with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sugarbakers i</ENAMEX> think that's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> reason i named my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julia</ENAMEX>  well that well and my great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX>'s name is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julia</ENAMEX> so we named her that too um
 	
 	
 		yes
 		oh really oh that's great
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh yeah</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		do you have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> oh okay i was going to say because we also have to watch <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Dinosaurs</ENAMEX> on channel <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight</TIMEX> because oh not the mama not the mama
 	
 	
 		um no we don't
 		believe me we do too  we do too yes i love that show it's so cute
 	
 	
 		well when my <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two year old</TIMEX> starts saying that it's like okay we we know what he's been watching too for too long i just i
 	
 	
 		oh no
 		yes no we watch that all the time we do it's a good show  i like it and then we watch the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cosby and uh um Cheers</ENAMEX> we watch all the time and
 	
 	
 		oh i like those i
 		
 
 		that's fun
 		but that's normally on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nights</TIMEX> we just kind of turn the TV off because neither one of us  really we usually either watch <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nights</TIMEX> and then the rest of the times it's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> it's like oh well  we don't watch anything else fine oh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		okay
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		uh-huh yeah <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>'s a big one in our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> but um
 	
 	
 		uh we used to when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX> had no that was on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um Matlock</ENAMEX> because i got my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> got me started watching that show just because she liked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andy Griffith</ENAMEX> so that was fun
 	
 	
 		okay
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh yeah
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s a big like mystery <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">watcher</ENAMEX> like the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the late night</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hunter</ENAMEX> and all those he really enjoys those
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		uh-huh i like yeah i used to like it when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Columbo</ENAMEX> and and all those were on and and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rockford Files</ENAMEX> but it's like  gosh that seems like a long time ago
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> really likes those  yeah they are and then we're on we're on a big one with uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Home Front</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they're fun they're fun
 		yes yes i like that  well no i guess you probably don't get to see <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Northern Exposure</ENAMEX> then if he's watching <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nights</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		he that's a real good show
 		sometimes i do if i'm at my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> she has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> TV's
 	
 	
 		that's it's it's a real strange one it's almost well it's like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Twin Peaks</ENAMEX> but funny
 	
 	
 		it is it's it's
 		right
 	
 	
 		and we did we used to like to watch <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Twin Peaks</ENAMEX> for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX> it was like oh this is really neat
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then it got weird
 	
 	
 		yeah i and it was a show i never started watching until like <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one night</TIMEX> i decided well they always say this is so weird let's let's watch it and see if we can get the hang of this
 	
 	
 		like real strange
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		huh-uh i couldn't understand by the by the end of it i was just going now what did i just watch for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the last hour</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		this this
 		no no who did what yeah because it's you really have to be dedicated we would like tape it and send the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> to bed say okay now we can watch this because you have to watch every scene to kind of figure out what it's doing and it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah because i was just like huh
 	
 	
 		even then it's like huh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		what
 	
 	
 		and then we got like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time magazine</ENAMEX> because we used to order that and his face was on the front <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> distorted and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> regular
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		uh
 	
 	
 		and it kind of talked about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Twin Peaks</ENAMEX> and i still just didn't understand what he was talking about  he was something else i just
 	
 	
 		
 
 		it was <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a really really strange</TIMEX> show but  it's like well i'm sorry it's gone but i really didn't got towards <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX> we didn't watch it at all anyway
 	
 	
 		yeah i think it got too strange because you couldn't pick up on it if you just yeah yeah i like the sitcoms
 	
 	
 		yeah give give me comedies i'll I'll watch those i like those i'm yeah i'm a i'm a comedy kind of person
 	
 	
 		um-hum i really do like just those <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">half an hour</TIMEX> sitcoms and that maybe a couple
 	
 	
 		yeah  well because yeah because you can like turn it off  you only have to watch <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">half hour</TIMEX> at a time
 	
 	
 		yeah and it's not
 		right and it's always not um <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week after week</TIMEX> and you have to watch <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every week</TIMEX> and you can pick up something the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		uh well unless it's like you have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and you have to watch Full <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> and you have to watch <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Dinosaurs</ENAMEX> and you have to watch <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Urkel</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nights</TIMEX> and you  you know
 	
 	
 		right
 		so you know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> we have to watch <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Urkel</ENAMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i understand that did you did you happen to see it last night
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		that was cute Pablo Pablo
 	
 	
 		where he where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carl</ENAMEX> killed his bug
 		uh yes  oh yes
 	
 	
 		i was like it's just a stupid bug
 	
 	
 		i know it it was it was something that that a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> what was it <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six hundred</NUMEX> dollar bug or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">four hundred dollar</NUMEX> bug
 	
 	
 		yeah but
 		i know i think it was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four hundred</NUMEX> and eighty something dollars s o they went to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Citizens Court</ENAMEX> ooh ah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		but i did see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Urkel</ENAMEX> regular
 		he was on some show and he is he's a good looking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> he is a great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> yes
 	
 	
 		did you really
 		huh without the glasses and the suspenders and
 	
 	
 		um-hum he is dressed normal and acted normal he doesn't have that high voice and
 	
 	
 		
 
 		but have you seen the commercial for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Urkel</ENAMEX> doll
 	
 	
 		yeah i he showed the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Urkel</ENAMEX> doll on that but i haven't seen the commercial for it
 	
 	
 		it dances i was like oh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> it dances it talks it sounds like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Urkel</ENAMEX> oh no it even snorts
 	
 	
 		um-hum it's
 		yes it does
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh well
 	
 	
 		he took that on the show and they played that and i was like oh my gosh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		it these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like they really have lives but it's just kind of strange
 	
 	
 		
 
 		um-hum but he's kind of what made that show because i heard it was gonna go
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		
 		
 	