
 
     		
 	
 		so who's your favorite team
 	
 	
 		
 
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">favorite team</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX> Steelers
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX> i used to be a big <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> when i was little
 	
 	
 		you bet
 		well i um
 		when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Stallworth</ENAMEX> played he was from my <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">hometown</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alabama</ENAMEX> so i kind of grabbed on to that team
 	
 	
 		oh really
 		huh that's pretty nice
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> back when
 	
 	
 		that's good i used i used to watch them a lot when they were playing the big iron curtain or steel curtain
 	
 	
 		that's right how about your favorite team
 	
 	
 		hm <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">well</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> it was <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Buffalo</ENAMEX> and i i still try to keep up with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Buffalo</ENAMEX> because they just they just impressed me as being so efficient and  they never score they never
 		blow out their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> they just score just enough points and that really impressed me but i've been down here i live <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laural</ENAMEX> is pretty close to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Orleans</ENAMEX> and i've been keeping up with the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saints</TIMEX> a lot
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well they're exciting aren't they
 	
 	
 		yeah the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saints</TIMEX> are starting to impress me <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> you know a lot
 	
 	
 		boy they are they are just a fun <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> to watch
 	
 	
 		this it they are really did you see the game <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>
 		or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		um no i didn't
 	
 	
 		it was funny they were they had uh a fireworks display at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">halftime</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah and some paper or something in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Super Dome</ENAMEX> up in the roof caught on fire
 	
 	
 		oh you're kidding oh my God
 	
 	
 		so they had to stop the game in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the middle of the third quarter</TIMEX> and put out this fire there was a big piece of something came flaming falling out of the roof landed on the field so there was at big fire on the field and they were dumping the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gatorade</ENAMEX> bucket and everything
 	
 	
 		oh i can't believe that
 	
 	
 		it was funny i mean you just really can't tell what's gonna happen
 	
 	
 		that's hilarious
 	
 	
 		i know it's like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about two weeks ago</TIMEX> i was watching the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saints</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morton Anderson</ENAMEX> kicked a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixty</TIMEX> yard field goal
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and it it was beautiful right down the middle
 	
 	
 		uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> he is tough he has a incredible leg
 	
 	
 		he is
 		he is
 	
 	
 		what do you think they're they're gonna be able to make it this year
 	
 	
 		uh i sure
 	
 	
 		past the first play-off game
 	
 	
 		i sure hope so i'm not sure i'm not sure who they play right now i've got it narrowed down to the top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		who's that
 	
 	
 		it's pretty much going between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> they're undefeated and uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Buffalo New Orleans</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> because <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>'s only lost twice and one of those was to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Buffalo</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and they beat the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saints</TIMEX> their only time they lost
 	
 	
 		what do you think about uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> i saw <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> play <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this summer</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Memphis</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah uh from what i saw they were playing when i was at the game we sat right on the front row right behind the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Houston Oilers</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		and from what i saw the game <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> looked <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> impressed me a lot but my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> watched it on TV and said that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren Moon</ENAMEX> was just having an off night and if that was an off night i'd hate to see what his uh good <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		hm
 		oh yeah he's
 	
 	
 		um-hum he's hm
 	
 	
 		he definitely uh is one of the best i think
 	
 	
 		yeah the their their backfield is really impressive hm <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Haywood Jeffries</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Drew Hill</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen Pinkett</ENAMEX> they really impress me
 	
 	
 		right
 		well they squeaked out a game on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> and
 	
 	
 		that's right who who did they play
 	
 	
 		they played <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> uh they won in overtime
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> that's right i was because
 		that's right i remember that now
 	
 	
 		so that was i i watched that game and uh that was uh
 	
 	
 		do you have a favorite between those two
 	
 	
 		well because i'm right here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> i i kind of pull for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		really they
 	
 	
 		yeah well also <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> is uh in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">division</ENAMEX> so i'll almost always root against them
 	
 	
 		well that's true
 		that's what i hate to say it but i hate <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>  i do
 	
 	
 		that's okay well i
 		you know i i was never really a big <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> until we moved here and they just kind of grew on me
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah i imagine that's the way i've never been a big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Saints fan</ENAMEX> until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last year or two</TIMEX> and they've they've actually started doing something
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		so i've actually paid paid attention to them
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		well
 	
 	
 		well do you know anything about the expansion <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> they're thinking about bringing in
 	
 	
 		to tell you the truth i haven't paid too much attention to that um what <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> are they looking at
 	
 	
 		really
 		uh right now i think this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Memphis</ENAMEX> they're they're trying to get a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> and that's that's where i was when i saw uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> play
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saint Louis</ENAMEX> is trying to get a team uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore</ENAMEX> is trying to get a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> and there's some other city i'm wanting to say <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Raleigh Durham</ENAMEX> but i'm not sure
 	
 	
 		you know i think you're right i think it is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Raleigh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		think so
 	
 	
 		i think i remember hearing that
 	
 	
 		um-hum because i i know they've got a world league <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> but i think it might be them
 	
 	
 		that'd be fun i'd like to see some more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> get in
 	
 	
 		i would definitely i think they're supposed to put <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> in by either <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year or the year</TIMEX> after
 		and right now i think <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Memphis</ENAMEX> and
 		it's <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Memphis</ENAMEX> and i think <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore</ENAMEX> have a really good shot at it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because i know  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saint Louis</ENAMEX> is much bigger than <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Memphis</ENAMEX> and when i went up there they were saying that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Memphis</ENAMEX> sold more tickets than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saint Louis</ENAMEX> did
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		yeah it's like the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Liberty Bowl or Liberty Stadium</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Memphis</ENAMEX> holds <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about sixty two</NUMEX>
 		
 		
 	