
 
     		
 	
 		okay well just to let you know i have uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> of my own i've got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one four year old</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one two years old</TIMEX> so so i'm just starting out
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh yes  i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> who are <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty eight and twenty four</TIMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> who's twelve
 	
 	
 		wow  wow that's quite a spread
 	
 	
 		yes  same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> everything it just uh  but
 	
 	
 		that's great
 		well i guess uh in one of things that that uh i like to do with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> when uh when i get <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> is i like to try and spend a lot of time with them you know they're not very old so they can't do a whole lot yet
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but they like to uh spend time with me we just oh just do various things nothing really they like to be outside as much as possible
 	
 	
 		if it's not raining
 	
 	
 		right uh but you know the weather's trying to turn now so
 	
 	
 		are are you down here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> oh
 	
 	
 		yes i i'm i'm in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay yeah then you know what i meant with rain  ah
 	
 	
 		right right right
 	
 	
 		okay uh  what
 	
 	
 		you know one of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the well one of the things i've noticed is one of the trends i've i've noticed is that uh it's always too easy to to just plop your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> down in front of the TV
 		and let them watch movies or or play video games or something
 	
 	
 		yeah i  i have can you hold on  just a second i have to answer a business phone i hate to do it on this call  good <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> ARE this is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arlene Lister</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		sure
 		sure that's okay
 	
 	
 		it was just a recorded message on our business phone anyway i'm sorry keep going
 	
 	
 		no  no it's okay um
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		so that was the thing that i i noticed that i know a lot of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> that we have they have a tendency to do the same thing and one of the things we try to do is we try to avoid doing that as much as possible
 	
 	
 		um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		although it really is very easy to do that type of thing just plop them down in front of the TV and let them be um entertained that way
 		and uh seeing as how you've got some older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> i was i'm wondering how did you handle that when they were growing up
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well
 		there there was not nearly as much of it in fact i i think things were were quite a bit different uh when my my big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> were were little uh you know if if all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> were home
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> got up in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX> and ate breakfast and poked around and then when they felt like it they went out to play you know when they were were little like that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		and uh  i i think it's gotten ah yeah very different when my <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> one was little they were coming out with <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sesame Street</ENAMEX> which he started watching and
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		other than that i mean there was basically there was not educational TV or uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know you got some cartoons and that was it but they they were never that interested in it anyway they'd rather i mean they'd take their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trucks</ENAMEX> out in the backyard you know go out and play and stuff but we always did uh
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		oh just you know to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> for walks and to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">zoo</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> we did a lot of stuff like that with uh with our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and course when they got bigger uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they were both quite into sports and and you know so whatever you know they would do we'd go along with and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh well a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> is very different  a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> would like you to spend time with her going shopping  so they're very very different but

 	
 	
 		
 
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh you know kind of the same thing our you know she now lot of time spent with her she's so busy is uh you know going to you know like <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX> was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">band</ENAMEX> concert and she
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		she plays on her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school volleyball team</ENAMEX> and uh stuff like that but uh we we still uh oh like to pack up
 		you know just go someplace for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> or uh you know just stuff like that one of our older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> now is going to graduate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> down at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">College Station</ENAMEX> so that's uh
 	
 	
 		right
 		oh that's nice
 	
 	
 		we go down there fairly often you know for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a weekend</TIMEX> for you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> get togethers and stuff like that
 	
 	
 		that's great that's great i know we'd i'd like to get into do more camping and outings and things and i think we probably will soon as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> get a little bit older
 	
 	
 		ah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh you know for right now they don't you know just getting out in the front just being outside is good for them they like just being outside
 	
 	
 		oh yes yeah i i think our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> just ours dearly loved that you know played bounce the ball or just  ah course when our big ones were little we lived up north you know and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this time of the year</TIMEX> it it the fun thing was to go out
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">swoosh</ENAMEX> around in the leaves you know and yes you know so it's it's very different and and uh
 	
 	
 		right that's true you don't see many leaves around <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know we also come <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX> time  we'd stick them on sleds and uh we had a pond across the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> and and from little on uh you know i'm
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it it's so different down here where you you go and take lessons to learn to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice skate</ENAMEX> or something you know when our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> were little you you got them a pair of skates
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 		
 		
 	