
 
     		
 	
 		all right i've never done it before so i guess that's all i have to do right i've been called several times you know i push in pushed in my number
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i guess so
 	
 	
 		they kept saying you have the invalid code and then i found out that my new phone wasn't working right so and this this so this the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time i've even done it
 	
 	
 		oh really
 		oh
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i wonder how long it's gonna be on for
 	
 	
 		i think <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five minutes</TIMEX> is the max
 	
 	
 		oh no i mean this whole thing like for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two months</TIMEX> or something do you know
 	
 	
 		oh i don't know i'm not really sure
 	
 	
 		yeah okay well back to crime i guess we're supposed to talk about that
 		they say what aspect are you worried about well i think at this point i for one am worried about every aspect
 	
 	
 		well especially uh you since you're in the same metroplex you know there's so much going on here
 	
 	
 		i think the drive by shootings are getting so be so common that's really a something you got to protect yourself from you know
 	
 	
 		well that and in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> too
 	
 	
 		um-hum God i know
 	
 	
 		starting to put metal detectors in and
 	
 	
 		have they done that in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Garland</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no i not that i'm aware of
 	
 	
 		no um
 	
 	
 		i just heard you know  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> at that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> school they started putting them in because there was that one shooting
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		so um
 	
 	
 		well we had a vice <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">principal</ENAMEX> shot at here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> on the you know on the school grounds after school
 	
 	
 		is that right
 	
 	
 		and then <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> killed himself <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years ago</TIMEX> in the in a grade school so you know these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> don't have any trouble getting a hold of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> in any in any neighborhood doesn't seem like
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		not at all
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		so
 		uh yeah it's kind of scary to think you send your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> to school and you wonder if he's gonna get shot i mean we never had to worry about that before
 	
 	
 		i know i know it's it's it's getting it's been out of hand i think for a while and it just continues to get worse
 	
 	
 		what next
 		right and you know we can't really depend on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> to solve all this they just can't do it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i think it goes all the way back to the break up of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> to a certain extent and  and you know how we're gonna bring that back together
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah that's yeah i think i agree i think that's where it stems from is that and um
 		you know you've got a lot of a lot more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> that are working nowadays that aren't home with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and that may impact it as well
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right and
 		i think so and and then there's a drop in uh the training of morals really you know
 	
 	
 		right right
 	
 	
 		these some of these young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> you read about just doesn't bother them to kill someone at all i think
 	
 	
 		yeah they don't think twice about it
 	
 	
 		i think <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> past maybe our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> had a little more morals morals you know wouldn't kill somebody in cold blood
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
  
 		either that or i don't know if it happened and it wasn't as highly publicized as it is now or what the what the case is
 	
 	
 		i think it was just rare i really do
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> well she's like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seventy four now</TIMEX> or she when she was a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> she had a beautiful beautiful <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX> that lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and she was dating this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">millionaire</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> and he wanted to marry her and she wouldn't marry him and so he drove out in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> and shot them both
 	
 	
 		you're kidding
 	
 	
 		and um no i'm the witness
 	
 	
 		himself and her
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		um that must've been at least <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fifty years ago</TIMEX> or more but the point of the story is that that was so unbelievable a thing in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">those days</TIMEX> that it was on all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> all over the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i bet
 	
 	
 		but now you know you would probably even read about it here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh i know
 	
 	
 		it's just you know another  killing
 	
 	
 		well they were i was watching some show <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX> and they were talking about uh mass <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">murderers</ENAMEX> and they  brought up what happened in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Killeen</ENAMEX> here recently and they were saying you know that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		um
 	
 	
 		these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> want attention and that when it happens they're glorified because all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> it's on all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TVs</ENAMEX> and and everything
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right and lots of their pictures and their life story and everything
 	
 	
 		right and then you get to their life story oh they came from a broken family oh this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> had mental problems oh duh duh duh you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 		right
 		i know how do we go into all these <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> and straighten up all these twisted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> before they do something terrible
 	
 	
 		i yeah
 	
 	
 		so it that story i just told you about my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s beautiful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX> well the same thing happened here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arlington</ENAMEX>
 		when was it i think it was oh it was almost <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year ago</TIMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX> to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> had graduated from high school with
 	
 	
 		is that right
 	
 	
 		yeah in fact it was on a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hard Copy</ENAMEX> she was a real attractive blonde <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> in in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">her freshman year</TIMEX> of college and some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> she tried to get rid of uh he was like in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">his twenties</TIMEX> remember that yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		i remember seeing that i saw that on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hard Copy</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right right that's uh she my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> graduated with her from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arlington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes
 		is that right
 	
 	
 		yeah can you believe it it's just uh
 	
 	
 		i'm trying to remember he um had her in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> in front of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taco Bueno</ENAMEX> or something and he just shot them himself and her i remember seeing that on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hard Copy</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taco Bueno</ENAMEX> right uh-huh um-hum right nobody
 		yeah  isn't that weird uh
 	
 	
 		yeah there's just too many crazy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> out there these days
 	
 	
 		i know and uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> are not gonna do anything until they've they have committed some sort of a crime
 	
 	
 		i'm
 	
 	
 		you know he was just begging her on the phone they can't do anything
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and there are times i've think gee maybe i should give my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> guns
 		
 		
 	