
 
     		
 	
 		supposed to talk about <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boats</ENAMEX> have you got a boat
 	
 	
 		
 
 		no i don't do you
 	
 	
 		no i don't i i've had one for quite <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years</TIMEX> but i've i've not had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last couple of years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		but it's something i've always enjoyed do you do you like boating yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah i love them
 	
 	
 		but uh
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> all have been grown for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple years</TIMEX> and we were using it less and less and less so
 		we decided to sell it
 		and
 	
 	
 		well i heard that's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the second happiest day</TIMEX> of your life
 	
 	
 		what's that
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> you sell your boat
 	
 	
 		oh no now i loved having a boat
 	
 	
 		no i just heard that that's just a joke i guess
 	
 	
 		i loved having it no
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> best day is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> you get and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> you get rid of it but
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		i'd like to have one i just don't know if i'd have the time to
 		use it
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> just you know he needs his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekends</TIMEX> free or
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		to be able to use it or a day during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX> or something but
 		but no i guess for the cost of them you don't really it's hard to get i don't know i felt like i got my money's worth out of mine i had bought it used and
 		kept it uh i don't know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years</TIMEX> and got within uh
 	
 	
 		did
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">hundred dollars</NUMEX> of what when i sold it of what i'd paid for it and had it all those <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so they hold their you take care of them they hold their value real well
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		so you know you couldn't complain about that
 	
 	
 		did you go fishing
 	
 	
 		no no it was a
 		uh big boat big ski <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> type thing
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		i had a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">hundred hundred sixty</NUMEX> horse uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mercruiser</ENAMEX> in it inboard outboard
 	
 	
 		oh wow
 	
 	
 		oh i did <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> out of it occasionally but i'm not too much of a fisherman
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		and uh but i but i did enjoy owning a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> would recommend it to anybody and uh
 	
 	
 		yeah i like to fish
 	
 	
 		uh
 		but uh and now sailing i've never been sailing have you been sailing
 	
 	
 		uh yeah i've sailed some i just like uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fourteen</NUMEX> foot Sunfish
 	
 	
 		uh-huh i've never tried i've always thought i bet that would be more fun but i'd want to be with a skilled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sailor</ENAMEX>  but it it
 	
 	
 		nothing big
 		yeah really
 		well they offer classes out at uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray Hubbard</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah well i i've always thought i'd like to i've never wanted to bad enough to make any effort to do it you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and at this stage of the game i'm not that interested in it anymore
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		we go out with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> on the
 		we go to the lake just about every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekend</TIMEX> down at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mount Vernon</ENAMEX> and uh
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>' next door <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> have a big barge and we go out and take them out on their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">barge</ENAMEX> they're getting kind of old and they like us to take them out on their barge quite often so we we get out on the water occasionally you know
 	
 	
 		okay
 		oh that's nice
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but uh
 		uh anyway it's
 		it's fun i i do enjoy the lake but
 		uh once the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> were grown and we'd go down there and i'd get the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> out on the
 		you know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> and we'd go for a ride and enjoy it so much it's such a pretty lake down there we'd enjoy it so much and
 		i'd say well i'm gonna leave the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> out because uh we'll probably do this again tomorrow
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		it got to where the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> was still sitting there and we never did go out again and i'd have to go load it up <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next day</TIMEX> and
 	
 	
 		where is that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">uh Mount Vernon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Cypress Springs Cypress Creek Creek Springs</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		okay that's south of here
 	
 	
 		yeah it's down at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mount Vernon</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		it's probably the prettiest lake in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		yeah it's just <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a hundred miles</NUMEX> from here
 	
 	
 		huh what do you take i <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh no you go down i uh uh you uh you go down uh
 		yeah <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty thirty</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">thirty</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's east of here
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">east</ENAMEX> of here <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">hundred miles</NUMEX> due east of here
 	
 	
 		all right
 	
 	
 		and uh
 	
 	
 		yeah it just  we just moved down here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple years ago</TIMEX> so
 	
 	
 		did you where'd y'all move from
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Colorado Springs</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh did you how are you liking it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh we love it up there
 	
 	
 		well good
 	
 	
 		that's where i grew up so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh
 		we're we like it down here pretty good
 	
 	
 		oh i think you'll like it better but of course it's hard when you don't have any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> around
 	
 	
 		yeah especially we got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> that are under <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's kind of tough when my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> call and they want to see them
 	
 	
 		yes it's hard on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> too i know they're all yours and your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> still live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> uh-huh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh there supposed to be uh some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from moving down here from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado Springs</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		yeah supposed to be
 	
 	
 		yeah that's right um
 	
 	
 		do you work at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TI</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i don't no uh a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of mine's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> is was a program <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> up there and he just moved down here to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McKinney</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		what do you  i guess it's
 		he's working at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McKinney</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh-huh yeah i don't either my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> does
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		but it's a good <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> but anyway we're supposed to be talking about <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boats</ENAMEX> so back to <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boats</ENAMEX> so tell me the last time you went for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> ride
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well actually i went uh canoeing down the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brazos</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this weekend</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh my gosh now that had to be that's boating that had to've been fun
 	
 	
 		it was fun it was fun
 		
 		
 	