
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		oh do you have a do you have a personal computer
 	
 	
 		yes i do i've had one
 		ever since uh like oh nineteen seventy <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> i
 		had several since then uh i built my <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> from a kit
 	
 	
 		oh A <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two or one</NUMEX> of those L two
 	
 	
 		uh it was an  a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">100</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bus</ENAMEX> uh model
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		uh yeah i don't know if you remember the old uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MIPS</ENAMEX> computers
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		uh well
 	
 	
 		is out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Antonio</ENAMEX> originally wasn't it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">uh San</ENAMEX> were they out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Antonio</ENAMEX> i thought they were i thought they were out of uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">uh New Mexico</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i really
 		it it
 	
 	
 		anyway
 	
 	
 		i may be confused on that but i remember seeing the ads in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Popular Science</ENAMEX>
 		uh i bought my <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> one in nineteen eighty
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 		what kind do you have now
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> now i have uh just a regular PC clone
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		it's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 8088</TIMEX> uh
 		it's an old one i've had it for oh i guess <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX> now
 	
 	
 		well uh
 	
 	
 		kind do you what kind do you have
 	
 	
 		well actually i'm between PC's right now i put my i i had an old one and i kind of got put it up on the shelf
 		and i bought one for uh for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> use and i've given that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> it's a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two eighty six</NUMEX>
 		a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two eighty six</NUMEX> clone uh an AT clone
 		and i've given that to him and he has it up in his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> which means i can still use it but uh
 	
 	
 		that's right um-hum
 	
 	
 		it's not readily available so i usually end up bringing home a
 		we have a little portable in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> and when i need to do something i usually bring that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> home
 	
 	
 		um-hum is that the laptop type or the yeah those are real convenient
 	
 	
 		a laptop yes
 		they uh
 		they're real convenient but sometimes they're kind of heavy to carry around because you get
 		
 
 		you know you get kind of tired if you have to walk a whole lot and i guess it's uh it's all what we get used to it's certainly better than to have a whole machine to take apart
 		my <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> machine was um
 		a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tandy</ENAMEX> model one or an old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Radio Shack</ENAMEX> model <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and
 	
 	
 		um-hum yes
 	
 	
 		that was like moving to take that apart
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yes sir it's still lighter
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">bust box</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		uh
 		yeah uh i i sold model one uh model threes i guess for a while in my store
 	
 	
 		oh did you
 	
 	
 		yes
 		i had a personal computer computer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> for a while
 	
 	
 		oh you did
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well that
 		at the time that was a good business i think now it's pretty cut throat isn't it
 	
 	
 		it's extremely cut throat now yeah i was uh you know it was sort of uh just before the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX> PC came out
 	
 	
 		ah
 		well i know uh
 		my model one i put a lots of you know lots of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> on it
 		but it was obsolete fairly quickly
 		it became nothing but a word processor for me so i could do uh
 		you know do letters and things like that at home
 		and uh you know i had
 		let's see i think i had <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about twenty</TIMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">seven hundred dollars</NUMEX> in that little system because i had uh <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">several the</NUMEX> floppy drives and all of that
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and you know twenty <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">seven hundred dollars</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> will buy you a pretty well equipped <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four eighty six</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh that's about right yes you can get a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a real screamer</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty seven hundred now</TIMEX> it's amazing
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		it's  you look at the computer power that the you know the personal computers put on our desk compare it you know with the you know i guess the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first</TIMEX> computer i used with a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a 7094</TIMEX> or something like that
 		and uh i mean you this is the you know you have more sitting in your desk than the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> then
 	
 	
 		yes
 		um my little model one is a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> and i made the great advancement of of uh kicking it up to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">forty eight</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> memory
 		and uh you know that was just a big deal in those days
 	
 	
 		my first computer came uh i had a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> memory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> with with yeah it's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> oh
 		did you ever wonder what you'd do all with all the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well at that time i was programming an assembly language right uh and and i had a cassette tape for my memory
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		for my storage i didn't have a floppy
 		and uh
 		it was uh you know you you there was you there was still a press to have more memory i mean grew went from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixteen</TIMEX> and it made a big jump to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty two</TIMEX> and you know
 	
 	
 		yes i uh
 		i think i paid
 		what did i pay i paid a
 		a pretty good chunk of money something like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">forty dollars</NUMEX> just
 		to buy the chips to upgrade <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX> of course
 		they it already had sockets on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX> because they had already uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know they they had the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> set up with the sockets in it so it it wasn't that bad but
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		you know now uh
 		machine i bring <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> has <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">two megabytes two megabytes</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAM</ENAMEX> and
 		
 
 		
 		
 	