
 
     		
 	
 		okay my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are all grown up
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh okay well no see i've got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and uh they're one's uh just turned to be a teenager and the other one is on his way so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i uh i'm a single <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> so i think it makes it more difficult for me to um you know find time with my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> since i work and then of course take care of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and and all this good kind of stuff
 	
 	
 		i'll bet
 	
 	
 		um so it's a real uh it's a real problem for me
 	
 	
 		i'll bet it is what is the favorite thing you do with your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		um the the thing that we like to do the most is to watch TV together and uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> like to play <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nintendo</ENAMEX> but i'm no good at it so i don't like to play that's right that's right
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		you just watch them play huh
 		i i've tried it once or twice but i didn't feel like i was very good at it either my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandson</ENAMEX> got me to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> but
 	
 	
 		me either
 		yeah they talk about these different levels and stuff and i've never got off of level one  yes  yeah
 	
 	
 		different worlds and how do you get to another world you know and i i don't even know where they're talking about
 	
 	
 		uh i know i i agree with you so uh but no the other thing i think we like to go to the movies too that's the yeah that's a that's a neat thing so i guess we're all in um you know movie uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fanatics</ENAMEX> or whatever around here so we like to do those kind of things
 	
 	
 		
 
 		do you
 		yeah i know when our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> were growing up our we were big into <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> sports we had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> and they all skied and in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> we spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">most weekends</TIMEX> on the lake with them skiing and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they always took other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> with them and we had a lot of fun doing that but i had all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> so we didn't do too much sportswise
 	
 	
 		oh how neat uh-huh
 		oh
 	
 	
 		i find my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandchildren</ENAMEX> are very involved in <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">soccer and baseball</ENAMEX> and little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> do all of those things but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh yeah oh yeah see i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> and uh you know it's <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the fall</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">and baseball</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the spring</TIMEX> and and it's one activity after another i i'm constantly going back and forth and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		i'll bet you really are
 	
 	
 		yeah uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> has uh tennis so it's between <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">tennis and and bowling</ENAMEX> my i bowl so you know we're pretty active as a sports you know in in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> so it's it's really neat
 	
 	
 		um-hum um-hum well when <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX> were real little they all played soccer but
 		you know that was just for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of years</TIMEX> when they were pretty small for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> and then they got more interested in other things  i'm not sure that they would admit it at that age that it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> but i think that's probably what it was
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX>
 		oh yeah i i know that uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> uh even though she goes out with the the sports and everything uh yeah she likes to watch the <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> for uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>  oh i'm sorry
 	
 	
 		uh oh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-oh</ENAMEX> that was a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> that hit the telephone get away cat
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		gosh  i guess it's why they wanted to do on this type telephone because there's all kind of activity that goes on  but uh yeah my uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are they're starting to grow up you know it's not gonna be too many <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more years</TIMEX> before i uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh you know they'll be gone and and uh there won't be as many activities do you uh
 	
 	
 		but they but you enjoy them i think the older <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX> get the more i enjoy them
 	
 	
 		yeah i i agree with you i i do i'm so glad they're out of the that young real young age and the babies
 	
 	
 		um-hum and i mean i didn't i it wasn't that i didn't like them when they were little but the older they got i enjoyed them as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teenagers</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 		yes yes
 	
 	
 		and now that they're each  of course <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> they're each becoming they're they've all become <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in themselves that it's been neat to watch them
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		how what kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> they are what kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wives</ENAMEX> you know
 	
 	
 		oh yeah yeah that's so that's so true well do you do the do your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX> live close where you can go out and
 	
 	
 		how they do things and
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of them live real close to me so we we spend a lot most of our time spent with them is they come over to eat
 	
 	
 		oh good
 		oh yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		and bring the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and we play with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> you know but uh we don't oh we go camp out they camp out and we spend <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekends</TIMEX> at the in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> with them quite a bit but
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		as far as doing any activity now that the grand <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are here we all just stay around the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> mostly  it's too much effort to go somewhere with all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah well that's true
 		oh yes oh yes well i know especially when they grow up like that so i'm trying these these <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last five or six years</TIMEX> i'm trying to make them really special and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh very precious since that's uh about the only time we've got left
 	
 	
 		they'll always remember it too
 	
 	
 		yes yes absolutely i I think so too
 	
 	
 		i hear mine saying well i remember <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daddy</ENAMEX> used to take us to do so and so i need to take my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> to do this or that you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i remember <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> we went to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney World</ENAMEX> as quick as my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are big enough we're gonna go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> World you know
 	
 	
 		there we go i know i know they can't wait
 	
 	
 		yeah they just really can't wait to be able to take their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> where they had fun but
 	
 	
 		that's right that's right yeah so well i still got a few <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more years</TIMEX> so i'm uh i'm hanging onto those and doing as much activity as i can with them
 	
 	
 		do you work
 	
 	
 		yes uh-huh i sure do and uh work full time so uh it it that cuts into our free time right there
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		it really does the time you have with them has to be quality time then
 	
 	
 		that's right that's right and uh vacations are very special for us and activities
 	
 	
 		i imagine that they have uh some a lot of homework too
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah you know this being a school night and stuff so uh it's it's in the same old you you know routine of uh you know doing homework and you know trying to talk between all of that and and uh the other activities that we all have
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well there's just so many things to do with them nowadays so and especially if they're active <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> like you say you bowl
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	