
 
     		
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
 
 		okay
 	
 	
 		do i recycle cans that's about it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		aluminum cans
 	
 	
 		yeah my son
 	
 	
 		do you recycle <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> or anything
 	
 	
 		no because there's no really place i think if they had more visible places for you to drop stuff
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would do it more instead of trying you know it's because it's hard it's bad enough you got to save the stuff but then you got to go find somewhere to put it if they
 	
 	
 		i think they would
 		right how about glass jars those are recyclable but
 	
 	
 		none of it  i mean see at at work all i do is paper and trash and cans
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		and then at home i just save cans because i i know where that is that's like on the way to work but i don't know where the paper and the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">the</NUMEX> bottles and all that stuff is but i think if like apartment <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complexes</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		honey i'm on the phone long distance
 	
 	
 		how
 	
 	
 		had to yell at my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> had to yell at my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		how many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> you got
 	
 	
 		well i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and we try and recycle my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> is in the packaging <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> and um they use recycled newspapers shredded up
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		for the filler for uh it's a pad that they put on top top of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">apples boxed apples</ENAMEX> when they ship <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">apples</ENAMEX> and it absorbs some of the you know the when the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">apples</ENAMEX> get the shipping you know
 	
 	
 		uh
 		yeah
 		oh i know yeah my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> hauls apples
 	
 	
 		oh he does for what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> what trucking company
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		uh he's independent he hauls them for anybody
 	
 	
 		oh that's great well he may have some of our <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">apples</ENAMEX> then probably <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>'s a very big <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">apple</ENAMEX> growing
 	
 	
 		yep
 	
 	
 		place especially Yakima you'll have to look for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yakima Washington</ENAMEX> on some of the box labels and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CVC Weyerhaeuser</ENAMEX> that's us
 	
 	
 		yep
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's us well so they have a recycling actually they it's called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central Washington Recycling</ENAMEX> and they have a a whole <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">center</ENAMEX> and they have it set up like a circus
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		where you know the green <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glass</ENAMEX> goes in this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clown</ENAMEX>'s mouth and the tin cans go up to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">alligator</ENAMEX> and and so we uh we don't recycle as much as we should but we do recycle newspapers
 		and cans and bottles
 	
 	
 		yeah i think if they would if they would have it more where you can get it
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		get to it you know like in different places like apartment <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complexes</ENAMEX> they got trash cans why not put the dumpsters for different things and uh and and that way <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would find it better
 	
 	
 		right
 		right i think that'd be a great idea we're gonna
 		right right
 	
 	
 		but if you can't find it
 	
 	
 		i would like to see them i would
 	
 	
 		who's gonna save it you know because after a while you get tired of saving newspapers i mean
 	
 	
 		yes you do you sure do in fact i put <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX> in my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">garage</ENAMEX> and i'm sick of them but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we take them my little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> she gets a collect the money you know since she has to haul them down there <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> so i let her keep the money um i was thinking <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX> about um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		plastic gloves that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dentists</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> and everybody has to wear now that'd be wonderful if they could recycle those you know as it is now they can't
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah but see those are
 		they can't
 	
 	
 		well i think they're nonrecyclable
 	
 	
 		yeah i think because of the the disease and all that going around they don't know
 		you know they're they're calling them uh like what do you call it contaminated yeah
 	
 	
 		right
 		contaminated is what they are you know they but that you know plastic just doesn't disintegrate
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">huh-uh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and that that's major thing i mean how many pairs of gloves they go through in a day
 	
 	
 		they use pair of gloves for every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> they see
 	
 	
 		right and i'm just thinking about the orthodontist where i take my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> you know for his braces
 	
 	
 		they use gloves for everybody i mean the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurse</ENAMEX> you the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dentist</ENAMEX> his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assistant</ENAMEX> everybody in there has on gloves and and then
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yep
 		yep everybody yep well it's too bad that they have to but be nice if those somehow could be recycled
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know that'd be better for everybody
 	
 	
 		yep but they don't recycle those so
 	
 	
 		and then the baby diapers you know i don't have anybody in diapers any more but gosh i used my share of disposable diapers
 	
 	
 		now i didn't use those i had a a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">diaper service</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well that's good
 	
 	
 		in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> because i couldn't my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> was allergic to something in the plastic
 	
 	
 		oh yep
 	
 	
 		so i had  so it wasn't by choice
 	
 	
 		yeah but that's
 	
 	
 		that i couldn't use them it's just he couldn't wear them for some reason i don't know what it was
 	
 	
 		uh-huh yeah i used them with my last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> uh-huh
 	
 	
 		but he couldn't wear them because of the something was he was allergic to something
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so i had to put regular diapers on him <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> that was a you know for a while i had the service but then you know after i didn't have it the whole time but the first i think the first
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah yeah it gets really expensive yeah but see i think if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> go back to cloth diapers that's better for recycling i mean that's better for the environment
 	
 	
 		yeah because you can always you just wash those you know so
 	
 	
 		sure well i see in the future i see <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> uh being more conscious of we're gonna be forced to recycle
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know i see even plastic shopping bags there's you can return those and our grocery bags our paper grocery bags has a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five cent</NUMEX> refund on them if you bring them back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> do yours there
 	
 	
 		you can return those
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh they do oh that's oh
 	
 	
 		no huh-uh if they did that i would take them back all the time because i go to the same <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> all the time
 	
 	
 		well see and i always forget and you know with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and you know <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in this family our grocery bill's pretty high and you know i get you know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> or more than that yeah i get fifty
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		but i think if they'd do it more with the with the money like a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">nickel</ENAMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">penny</NUMEX> even though <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> think it's not enough but if you have enough
 	
 	
 		yep
 	
 	
 		uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't understand <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a quarter</TIMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a quarter</TIMEX> it doesn't matter
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		you you know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> could take <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a quarter</TIMEX> and go buy him a candy bar or something but i
 	
 	
 		you bet oh yeah
 		
 		
 	