
 
     		
 	
 		okay do you work
 	
 	
 		yes i do
 	
 	
 		i think that's the main change what do you think
 	
 	
 		well i think that's a big part of it and i i think it maybe started because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> wanted outside of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> and i almost think with our society and and inflation and the cost of things it's anymore it's almost <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couples</ENAMEX> have to work outside the home
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> right
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		but but yeah i think that's a big change  i'd like to not work what about you
 	
 	
 		well i've worked all the time up until just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a year</TIMEX> ago
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and i just uh physically i wasn't able to and i mean i love my job but i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and that's real hard you have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> i assume so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yes i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> and that's been a big deciding factor because
 		i mean i never wanted to be a career <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> but as long as i was was you know was going to work i was going to do as as much as i could as well as i could etcetera and
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 		right
 	
 	
 		i i wanted to stay home when i had <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> well i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> i have a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four year old</TIMEX> and a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three year old</TIMEX> and we would like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> more but i it's like we talked uh i don't want <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> more unless i can quit and stay home and take care of them which is something right now financially it takes both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to work
 	
 	
 		oh
 		right oh
 		it's real hard it's real hard i mean even i
 	
 	
 		yeah it's full time work
 	
 	
 		yeah it was so hard for me to work full time course my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are are a little older but then you then you give up the money you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah you do there's saying course you know everything you give up something but i just i the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are so wonderful  but i do think that's one of the major changes you know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> i remember her being home
 	
 	
 		yeah that's
 		yep
 	
 	
 		uh you know she made breakfast in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX> for us and if she worked it was part time and it was work that was done while we were at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">maybe</NUMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and she was there when we got home you know and
 	
 	
 		fine
 		yep i know
 		yeah well i've decided now in fact i'm just i'm substitute <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> aid which is a a far cry from my travel <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> career you which i loved
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i'm i'm there in the same <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> as my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> my <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> littler ones
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i'm home when they're home in fact i've had an offer to just work <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the Christmas season</TIMEX> at a local jewelry store
 		and i'm just really hesitating because i've i enjoyed my <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first summer</TIMEX> home ever spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seventeen years</TIMEX> with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh
 		oh
 	
 	
 		i mean where i didn't have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX> or day care or working as a travel agent
 		and it was wonderful my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and i we just had a ball course their their ages they're seventeen <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">almost seventeen fifteen almost well sixteen fourteen eleven</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> and we're just running every direction and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		see and i think
 		oh
 		oh
 		but see it's such an important time to be home
 	
 	
 		it is yes
 	
 	
 		you know and that was important to me an that's my you know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> was raised uh his his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> were divorced when he was young so his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> always worked and he's like well you know what's the big deal about being home for your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		always were
 		what yeah
 	
 	
 		well as our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are getting older you know he sees it more i said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russ</ENAMEX> you don't understand what it was like to have her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> or to if you needed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> at school you know she was there to help or she was there to take you and you and and i want to be able to do those things so
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 		i think that you know it's good you know sometimes i'll have the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cookies</ENAMEX> ready when they come home and and a lot of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> uh my older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX>' junior high <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> will come over in fact everyday i've got <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> hanging around
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and it's wonderful  i'm real close to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and you know we're just i i'm very happy to be staying home
 	
 	
 		i think that's wonderful  so where do you see us changing in the future
 	
 	
 		but again i miss the money
 		i don't i  working
 	
 	
 		well see that was one of the things she the the question i think is you know what changes do we see and i'm  i'm not sure i i see it going anywhere i think they're still gonna have to work
 	
 	
 		right
 		that we are because it's so expensive if we want the extra clothes the extra car the extra  thing is when a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> does work
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		then there's the clothes to buy and then there's the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas</ENAMEX> and then there's the lunches and then <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> care you must pay a fortune in day care yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		the day care eats me alive
 		you know i pay <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four hundred</NUMEX> fifty to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five hundred</NUMEX> fifty a month for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>  they'd eat you alive
 	
 	
 		oh my gosh
 		yeah for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> it's almost hardly worth it for you to work till they get in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> then you work <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summers</TIMEX> unless you're a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> are you a teacher
 	
 	
 		i know
 		you no i'm not and i would love you you you talked about having the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summers</TIMEX> off and i thought oh that would be so wonderful and i love the little preschool they are in it's wonderful you know so i feel good about them being there but it's still not the same
 	
 	
 		
 
 		huh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		no it's not the same
 	
 	
 		it's just not
 	
 	
 		i i don't see things changing really and and it's terrible for divorced women
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know who are forced to work who maybe don't have a college education thank goodness i have mine and i could get a real good paying job if i wanted to you know do in fact i still have offers you know please come back and we'll pay you this
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hm</ENAMEX> please come back to work sure
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah and it's been a real tough decision but i'm very happy to be here with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> we've seen a remarkable difference in now that i'm home
 	
 	
 		that's wonderful that's wonderful
 	
 	
 		yeah i'm real and i'm but i've been doing a lot of volunteering at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and playing lots of tennis  yeah yeah i know
 	
 	
 		well i like that
 		well we're working on it i'm hoping in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about three to five years</TIMEX> i'll be able to stay home and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> of course will be in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> then but i'll be there mornings i'll be there noons i'll be there <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoons</TIMEX> and all i feel like that's good and i can work part days in my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s business you know so that
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah well
 		oh that'd be great right i think the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">the other</NUMEX> thing that that has changed for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> because we are working is we're having less children
 	
 	
 		he can afford for us to do that you know
 		
 		
 	