
 
     		
 	
 		okay well do you have a pet
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX> you're lucky
 	
 	
 		and do and oh and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and what do you have
 	
 	
 		well uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> you know how sometimes when you marry someone that you get along on everything except <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> major thing
 	
 	
 		oh no
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hunter</ENAMEX> fisherman outdoorsman <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marlboro</ENAMEX> type <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who had to have a sporting dog so we have a black <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Labrador</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		beautiful gorgeous black <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Labrador</ENAMEX> but to me he belongs up in the field you know in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ranch</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farm</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		right
 		does he sleep in your house
 	
 	
 		well  because we finally negotiated that i was losing my mind um he sleeps in the laundry <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> and then he goes out for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> but this this is a beautiful <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> and he is wonderful with our little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> and he is
 		he's comes from a purebred line and there's nothing you could say bad about him except that i was more of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> or a small dog <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> that you could sit in the chair and cuddle
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 	
 	
 		and this is huge you know of course when he runs around the yard he just digs he doesn't know that he's tearing up things but he does
 	
 	
 		yeah yep
 	
 	
 		and the worst part that i had with him he's he's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three now</TIMEX> was when he was uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about eight months old</TIMEX> and i did not know what to expect from a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> having not had one
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i left him in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen</ENAMEX> with the little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> gates up while i was gone for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about an hour</TIMEX> and i came home and he had ripped my wallpaper off my wall
 	
 	
 		oh my word
 	
 	
 		and it was in the floor
 		and i just about lost it and i called and said come home and get your dog
 		and so he said well puppies just chew when they're nervous and well i wish you had told me you know and it was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about eight months later</TIMEX> he ate a piece of a linoleum he kept picking at it and i didn't know the the tile in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen</ENAMEX> and picked a hole in it
 	
 	
 		oh dear
 	
 	
 		so the last thing he did was when i had set out a whole lot of begonias in the back yard and he dug them all up and brought them to the porch
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and i told my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> i said you know it's either me or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> and he looked at me like well you know so he loves this <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">every night</TIMEX> when he comes home from work he hugs it and talks to him and he's a good dog
 	
 	
 		good bye
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so it's one of those things i'm just having to get used to and that's why i laughed when they called it the topic i thought oh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> do i have a pet
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		but i i grew up with <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX> and i'm very comfortable yeah
 	
 	
 		i love my <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX> i had one <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eighteen years</TIMEX> i got her when i lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		before i even got married i had my <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		she's old isn't she oh i started to say then you broke your heart
 	
 	
 		well she i had to have her put to sleep <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last June</TIMEX>
 		oh it was awful it was just awful but and she just sat there on my lap you know she just just waited and
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh
 		bless your heart that makes me feel so bad
 	
 	
 		oh it was awful but her hair but the bad thing was though she would pee in my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s shoes you know and she just liked his shoes and he'd have to dress <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundred</NUMEX> dollar shoes
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh no
 		
 
 		oh
 		oh no
 	
 	
 		oh it's just bad and my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">closet</ENAMEX> and it was oh so sick
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh that's awful i've never heard of that before
 	
 	
 		it oh it's just terrible and once she did it you know then she would i mean she wouldn't if our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shoes</ENAMEX> sat side by side she would pee in my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s shoes she must have known he didn't like her or something
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		or the smell or something
 	
 	
 		oh anyway i've i've and i would shut i would bar the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">closet</ENAMEX> doors and i would carpet carpet vacuum
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh clean the carpets and oh dear it was just awful that was very funny
 	
 	
 		uh-huh well does now does your <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> sleep in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> they are they're house <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i uh well i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX> right now and of course they sleep with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> my my <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fourteen year old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> has an extra pillow on his bed just for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh yeah good
 		oh but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> doesn't destruct does it see it doesn't do anything
 	
 	
 		oh no i won't i'm not gonna have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> we've had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		see
 	
 	
 		and um they both got ran over after we've had them for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several years</TIMEX> just nice little outside <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> but
 	
 	
 		oh no
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		were just my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> they would go jogging i they would go with me when i would go running and and the last one got hit um as she was following my one of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX> across the road to the school
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh no oh that is
 	
 	
 		it was awful it was just and it just it's too heartbreaking but they do dig up and they just they just wreck things and i'm not a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> person
 	
 	
 		they do wreck things well i'm not either  i'm not either and it's just been
 	
 	
 		ooh
 		i wouldn't want a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lab</ENAMEX> it sounds beautiful but but
 	
 	
 		he's beautiful but it's just one of those concessions i just had to make but i kind of ignore him now <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s the first cold we've had in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> and it's really cold and drizzly and it's freezing and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are doing their fires
 	
 	
 		
 
 		um
 	
 	
 		and i brought him in because he's just a wet mess out there and he's in the laundry <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> with this little carpet <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">square</ENAMEX> and he's just huddled up like if you'll be nice to me i won't make any trouble you know again and then my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX> both have hamsters
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh and how old are your girls
 	
 	
 		and i i they're <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> and i gave in at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> and they have they keep their cages real clean it always smells of <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">cedar</ENAMEX> and they just sleep and eat bits of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">apple</ENAMEX> and carrots and
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		sure
 	
 	
 		i think they're cutting us off oh
 	
 	
 		no that's somebody's trying to cut in on my line and i don't want to answer i'll just wait no i've i've got incoming calls and i don't know why somebody's calling
 	
 	
 		oh okay okay
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		i i hate to cut it off i think they would cut us off so we'll just wait whoever it is will call back
 	
 	
 		i understand
 		okay well they'll cut us off pretty soon
 	
 	
 		well it's somebody calling for my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> you know jeez actually it's my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> i know it is my older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> he never likes to come home from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> but anyway that's what we have and i have i've tried to start a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish fish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tank</ENAMEX> and i keep losing all my fish
 	
 	
 		yeah i know
 		
 
 		how does  <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salt water salt water</ENAMEX> or basic yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		no just regular water
 		
 		
 	