
   
   
      
         
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> broadcast <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s criticism of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tiananmen</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zemin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> said, "I believe, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> believe, that the use
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> and the tragic loss of life was wrong." He also advocated free speech,
religious tolerance, and dialogue with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dalai Lama</ENAMEX> about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tibet</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
continued his appeal for freedom in a speech at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beijing University</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Pundits</ENAMEX>
agreed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s remarks and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s decision to air them were bold and
made up for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s previous timidity and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s petty, repressive
gestures earlier in the trip. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Optimists</ENAMEX> lauded <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s message that economic
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">freedom</ENAMEX> goes hand in hand with political freedom. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cynics</ENAMEX> argued that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chinese</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> have given up the idealism of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX> for the materialism of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">era</ENAMEX>. (
                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">surfs</ENAMEX> through <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>. Click here.)
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">6/29/98</NUMEX>)
            

            A
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> says she has told the grand jury
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> told her that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> limited their sexual relationship
to foreplay. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> says that according to her testimony, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
ruled out completion of sex so that he could technically deny they had had sex.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> broke the story. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cynics</ENAMEX> replied that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have
already said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> told them the same thing; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) it confirms only that there
was sex, not that there was obstruction of justice; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) the public has
already decided it doesn't care about the sex. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">6/29/98</NUMEX>)
            

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> issued <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> rulings on sexual harassment . <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) An employer
can be sued for the sexual misconduct of its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supervisor</ENAMEX>-level <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>, even
if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employer</ENAMEX> didn't know about the misconduct. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) Even if an employee does
not suffer adverse job consequences for rejecting a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supervisor</ENAMEX>'s advances, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employer</ENAMEX> can be held liable unless a) the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employer</ENAMEX> shows it "exercised
reasonable care to prevent and correct promptly any sexually harassing
behavior" and b) the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX> "unreasonably failed to take advantage of any
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">preventive</ENAMEX> or corrective opportunities." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> praised the
decisions for their balance. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> lauded their
coherence. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> warned that they set unreasonable
standards for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> and might prompt them to suppress <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>' civil
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">liberties</ENAMEX>. While hyping the idea that the rulings might revive the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paula Jones</ENAMEX>
case, the media reluctantly reported otherwise. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">6/29/98</NUMEX>)
            

            More
from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> ruled that the attorney-client
privilege continues after the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">client</ENAMEX> is dead. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> spun this as a
setback to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Independent Counsel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX> (who was seeking notes from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vince</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Foster</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>), giving short shrift to the decision's broader ramifications
for old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX>. (
                  Slate
               's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Explainer</ENAMEX>" pondered the question.) <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> ruled that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Disabilities Act</ENAMEX> bans discrimination against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who carry
the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> virus . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> spun this as a triumph of compassion, giving
short shrift to the broader implications of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>'s expansion of
"disabilities" to include reproductive troubles. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> upheld a law
imposing decency standards for federal arts grants . The media focused on
allegations that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> was firing a shot across the bow of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX>--overshadowing the subtler theory that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> was actually firing a
shot across the bow of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">6/26/98</NUMEX>)
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Scientists</ENAMEX> found a planet near a star <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">only 15 light-years</NUMEX> away . It is
the closest planet we have found beyond our solar system. The superficial spin:
It might be warm enough to support life. The sophisticated spin: It probably
can't support life, but its discovery indicates there may be <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">billions</NUMEX> of other
planets near us. Meanwhile, other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> say they have found bacteria
living in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Antarctic ice</ENAMEX>, raising the possibility that life exists on planets
previously dismissed as intolerably cold. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">6/26/98</NUMEX>)
            

            
Miscellany: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> struck down the line item veto . ...
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sidney Blumenthal</ENAMEX> told the press his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">grand jury</ENAMEX> testimony
about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s private remarks concerning <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> "supports
completely what the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> has told the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, and is contrary to
any charge that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> has done anything wrong." ... The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> finished the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World Cup</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. The sun rose. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">6/26/98</NUMEX>)
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AT&T</ENAMEX> is buying <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCI</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$32 billion</NUMEX>. It is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> biggest
telecommunications merger in history. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AT&T</ENAMEX> will also assume <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCI</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$16</NUMEX>
billion debt. This gives <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AT&T</ENAMEX> a network through which it can sell local
phone and high-speed Internet service to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of homes. The early line is
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">regulators</ENAMEX> will approve the merger because, unlike other recent telecom
deals, it will finally deliver some of the competition that was promised after
the industry was deregulated. (For a less sanguine view of the potential
benefits of telecommunications competition, see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jodie T. Allen</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Living</ENAMEX> in a
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Best World</ENAMEX>.") (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">6/24/98</NUMEX>)
            

            
               A
federal appeals <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> overturned a court injunction against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>. The
injunction would have prevented <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> from requiring computer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">makers</ENAMEX> to
package Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Explorer with Windows 95</ENAMEX>. The court ruled that under its
previous consent decree with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> could add
features to Windows that provide "advantages unavailable if the functionalities
are bought separately and combined by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">purchaser</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Analysts</ENAMEX> agreed this
sharply reduces <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOJ</ENAMEX>'s chances of winning its suit against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Windows</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">98</NUMEX>. The spins
from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) Now <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> will resume twisting the arms of
computer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">makers</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) Since the ruling only pertains to the consent decree, it
doesn't hamper the broader case that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> has violated basic antitrust
law. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) Who cares? Windows <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">98</NUMEX> looks like a bust. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">6/24/98</NUMEX>)
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX> is dumping <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan</ENAMEX>
Molinari as co-anchor of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Morning</TIMEX> after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">just 10 months</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Friends</ENAMEX> say she found the job insufficiently substantive. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> say
they wanted her out because she was stiff and amateurish and wasn't helping the
ratings. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">6/24/98</NUMEX>)
            

         
      
   
