
   
   
      
         
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kennedy</ENAMEX> died of head injuries after slamming into a tree during
a family game of <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX>-on-skis. The spins, in descending moral order: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)
Another tragedy for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s royal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>. Let's talk about his good works and
forget about that affair with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby sitter</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedys</ENAMEX> used to die
while serving their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. Now they die of self-indulgent recklessness. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>)
Come to think of it, the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> has been reckless all along. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) Here come
the revisionists again, hyping a dead <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX>'s good works and ignoring his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">misbehavior</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>) Here come the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> conspiracy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">theorists</ENAMEX> and gossip vultures
again, chiding the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> while exploiting its misery. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hey</ENAMEX>, at least this
time no innocent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bystanders</ENAMEX> got killed. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>) Now that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX> is out of the
picture and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> feel weepy for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedys</ENAMEX> again, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX> can re-enter the race
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1/5</NUMEX>)
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foreign</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Levy</ENAMEX> resigned , leaving the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin Netanyahu</ENAMEX> within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two</TIMEX> parliamentary seats of collapse. Levy
was protesting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX>'s insufficient funding of social-welfare programs and
his intransigence in peace talks with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Analysts</ENAMEX> predict that
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) peace talks will suffer in the short term because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX> must rely
increasingly on right-wing support, but <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) to avoid losing a parliamentary vote
of confidence, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX> will soon call new elections, which he might well
lose. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> have their fingers crossed. (
                  Slate
               's
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">International Papers</ENAMEX>" rounds up reactions and analyses from some
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>.) (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1/5</NUMEX>)
            

            Sports
roundup: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michigan</ENAMEX> won the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Rose Bowl</ENAMEX> and was named college <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX>'s
best <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sportswriters</ENAMEX>' poll. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nebraska</ENAMEX> won the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Orange Bowl</ENAMEX> and was
named the best <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coaches</ENAMEX>' poll. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Commentators</ENAMEX> went on debating which
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">team</ENAMEX> was better. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Football League</ENAMEX> playoffs , the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Denver</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Broncos</ENAMEX> will play the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pittsburgh Steelers</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> berth in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Super Bowl</ENAMEX>, and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">San Francisco 49ers</ENAMEX> will play the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Green Bay Packers</ENAMEX> for the other. The big
story was the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Broncos</ENAMEX>' upset victory over the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kansas City</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chiefs</ENAMEX>.
Sentimentalists groaned that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chiefs</ENAMEX> had choked again. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cynics</ENAMEX> predicted that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Broncos</ENAMEX> will advance to the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Super Bowl</ENAMEX>, where they will choke again.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1/5</NUMEX>)
            

            
Miscellany: <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Algerian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX> slaughtered <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 400</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">villagers</ENAMEX> in a
single night, a new record. (See <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International</ENAMEX>
Papers for more.) An <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">autopsy</ENAMEX> confirmed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">comedian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Farley</ENAMEX> died of
an opiate and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine overdose</ENAMEX>, just like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Belushi</ENAMEX>. Geraldine
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ferraro</ENAMEX> said she'll run against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alfonse D'Amato</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.Y.</ENAMEX>, calling him
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pothole</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Pundits</ENAMEX> look forward to a vicious primary fight with Rep.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Schumer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.Y.</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYC Public Advocate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Green</ENAMEX>. (See

                  Slate
               's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Assessment" of Ferraro</ENAMEX>.) A federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> struck
down key sections of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Telecommunications Act of 1996</ENAMEX>, theoretically allowing
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baby Bells</ENAMEX> to get into the long-distance market. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Analysts</ENAMEX> called the
decision screwy and predicted it will be overturned. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kenyan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">arap Moi</ENAMEX> won re-election. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pundits</ENAMEX> concluded, as one told the New York
Times , that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moi</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> had "cheated as little as possible and as much as
necessary" to win. (See what <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kenya</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nation</ENAMEX> had to say.) (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1/5</NUMEX>)
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s legal defense fund is shutting down. The fund
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>'s cover story: The anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> "political climate" (translation: the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlie Trie</ENAMEX> scandal) and unfair fund-raising constraints imposed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Office</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Government Ethics</ENAMEX> rendered the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">fund impotent</ENAMEX>, leaving the poor
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintons</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">nearly $3 million</NUMEX> in legal bills. The real story: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> are setting up a new legal defense fund to circumvent the restrictions.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cynic</ENAMEX>'s moral: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> crippled the original defense fund by accepting a
donation cap of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX> per <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> per year. The new fund will repeal that.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">12/31</NUMEX>)
            

            It's a
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wonderful Life I: Millionaire</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Sensenbrenner</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wis.</ENAMEX>, won the
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$250,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX> lottery jackpot. While many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">District residents</ENAMEX> live in poverty,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sensenbrenner</ENAMEX> is worth <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">nearly $8 million</NUMEX>, lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>, and is dubbed "the
biggest tightwad in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayer</ENAMEX> dollars" by his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief of staff</ENAMEX>. The
jaundiced moral, according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Associated Press</ENAMEX>: "Them that has, gets."
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sensenbrenner</ENAMEX>'s defense: "I faced the same long odds that anybody does who buys
lottery tickets." (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">12/31</NUMEX>)
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tyson Foods</ENAMEX> struck a plea deal with independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald Smaltz</ENAMEX> in
the investigation of former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agriculture</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Espy</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tyson</ENAMEX>, whose
senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX> is a close <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintons</ENAMEX>, will admit to having given
illegal gifts to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Espy</ENAMEX>, pay <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6 million</NUMEX> in penalties and investigative costs, and
cooperate with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">probe</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Spin roundup: 1</ENAMEX>) It's grim news for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Espy</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) The
probe is now turning a profit for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, undermining <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>'
charges that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Smaltz</ENAMEX> wasted tax money on it. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smaltz</ENAMEX> is cutting the gifter too
good a deal (allowing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tyson</ENAMEX> to pay a relatively small fine and to keep doing
business with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>) in order to nail the giftee (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Espy</ENAMEX>).
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">12/31</NUMEX>)
            

            It's a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wonderful Life II:</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Unemployed French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> occupied government <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> and blocked
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">trains</ENAMEX>, demanding the resumption of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$500</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year-end</TIMEX> bonuses from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protesters</ENAMEX> also are demanding higher welfare payments, calling the
latest <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>-percent increase "an insult." <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s socialist regime
promises to cut <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the work week</TIMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">40 to 35 hours</TIMEX> without allowing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> to
reduce salaries, and to create <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">350,000</NUMEX> government jobs for young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">12/31</NUMEX>)
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> issued new
restrictions on political speech over the Internet. The rules forbid
defamation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, transmission of state secrets, and promotion of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tibetan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Taiwanese</ENAMEX> independence. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Skeptics</ENAMEX> point out that enforcing the
restrictions on Web sites is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sisyphean</ENAMEX>, and enforcing them on e-mail is
virtually impossible. The only way to squelch subversive messages is to block
the Internet entirely, which would cripple economic growth. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">optimist</ENAMEX>'s
moral: This is how capitalism will destroy <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">totalitarianism</ENAMEX>.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">12/31</NUMEX>)
            

         
      
   
