
   
   
      
         
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seinfeld</ENAMEX> will end <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this spring</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Seinfeld</ENAMEX> reportedly turned
down a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$110-million</NUMEX> offer (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5 million</NUMEX> per episode) to continue the show for one
more year, preferring to leave the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> wanting more. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> appointed the
show to the pantheon of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zeitgeist</ENAMEX> landmarks, alongside I Love
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucy</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">All in the Family , The</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mary Tyler Moore Show</ENAMEX> ,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> . The elementary spin: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seinfeld</ENAMEX> was about the things
that really concern <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, e.g., parking spaces and low-fat lattes.
The intermediate spin: Yes, but this shows how shallow and self-absorbed we
are. The advanced spin: The show mocked our shallowness and self-absorption.
The business spin: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX> will return to the ratings <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cellar</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York</ENAMEX>
Times ' spin: "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> have a fondness for eccentric <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">New Yorkers</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Fans</ENAMEX>
speculated on spinoffs featuring <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seinfeld</ENAMEX> 's co-stars. Best suggestion
(from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tony Kornheiser</ENAMEX>): "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">SinnFeinfeld</ENAMEX>."
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">12/29</NUMEX>)
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">supreme</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> upheld a ban on female genital <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">mutilation</ENAMEX> . The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s
health <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX> banned the practice (removal of the clitoris and sometimes the
labia, often by family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> using razors or knives) in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Traditionalists</ENAMEX>
went to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> rejected their argument that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> law
authorizes mutilation "as an individual right" beyond the reach of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Advocates</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s rights think the ruling will help defeat the practice
elsewhere, because <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> regard <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX> as an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authority</ENAMEX> on Islam.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">12/29</NUMEX>)
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kong</ENAMEX> began slaughtering <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than a million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">chickens</ENAMEX> to stop the spread
of the mysterious "bird <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">flu</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">flu</ENAMEX> has sickened <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least 12</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and
killed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX> have no natural immunity to it,
but they also don't transmit it easily. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Experts</ENAMEX> from all over the world have
flocked to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> to make sure the virus doesn't spread elsewhere.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">12/29</NUMEX>)
            

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vikings</ENAMEX> staged one of the greatest playoff comebacks in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> history. After trailing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Giants</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19-3</NUMEX> at the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vikings</ENAMEX> got the ball, trailing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22-13</NUMEX>, with <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two minutes</TIMEX> left in the game.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vikings</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">quarterback</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randall Cunningham</ENAMEX>, who had worked as a stonecutter last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> after falling out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX>, answered the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Giants</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX>' jeers with a
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">30-yard</NUMEX> touchdown pass. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vikings</ENAMEX> then recovered an onside kick by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eddie</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">league</ENAMEX>'s oldest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX>, who had been dumped by several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cunningham</ENAMEX> drove the team <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">56 yards</NUMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX> kicked a field goal with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">seconds</TIMEX> left to win the game by a point. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cunningham</ENAMEX> gave credit for the victory
to God. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">12/29</NUMEX>)
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Terry Nichols</ENAMEX> was convicted of conspiracy and involuntary manslaughter
but acquitted of <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>-degree murder in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma City</ENAMEX> bombing.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Experts</ENAMEX> explained the manslaughter verdict as a finding of recklessness, not
premeditation, but puzzled over how to reconcile this with the conspiracy
conviction. The prevailing theory: an awkward compromise among the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jurors</ENAMEX>. Best
explanations as to why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nichols</ENAMEX> got off easier than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Timothy McVeigh</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) he
wasn't at the bombing and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) he didn't act like a sociopath in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Families</ENAMEX>
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> expressed outrage at the murder-charge acquittal. The catch:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prosecutors</ENAMEX> get another chance to win a murder conviction and death sentence
against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nichols</ENAMEX> in state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">12/24</NUMEX>)
            

            A jury
ordered the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">producers</ENAMEX> of 
                  Melrose Place to pay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hunter Tylo</ENAMEX>
nearly <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5 million</NUMEX> for firing her because of her pregnancy. She had been hired
to play a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>-stealing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vixen</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tylo</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> and some feminist leaders
called the verdict a victory for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> everywhere and compared <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tylo</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosa</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parks</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan B. Anthony</ENAMEX>. Pundits ridiculed the feminist spin, citing the
case's peculiar combination of glamour and sleaze. As a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
editorial put it, "if there were ever a case in which pregnancy really did
jeopardize one's ability to do a job, surely this was it." The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">plaintiff</ENAMEX>'s
argument: The show's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producers</ENAMEX> treated Tylo like a "a piece of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX>." The
defense argument: That was the job description. The punch line: She won the
case by looking sexy while pregnant throughout the trial, thereby convincing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jurors</ENAMEX> that she could credibly have played her TV vixen role while pregnant.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">12/24</NUMEX>)
            

            A
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> convicted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carlos the Jackal</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> murders and sentenced
him to life in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX>. He has been linked to scores of other murders, in
addition to bombings and kidnappings. In his final speech to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carlos</ENAMEX>:
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) dismissed the prosecution as a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Zionist</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> conspiracy; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) declared, "There
is no law for me"; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) extolled his terrorism as a struggle against "the
McDonaldization of humanity." After the verdict, he raised a fist and
exclaimed, "

         
      
   
