
   
   
      
         
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> won the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World Cup</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">playmaker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zinedine Zidane</ENAMEX> was the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX>,
heading <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> goals in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">3-0</ENAMEX> upset of defending <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">champion</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brazil</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX>,
having been accused of insufficient zeal, upheld the traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World Cup</ENAMEX>
post<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">-</ENAMEX>championship traditions of screaming, yelling, mobbing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX>, and
causing traffic accidents. The superficial spin: The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Europeans</ENAMEX> beat the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>. The sophisticated spin: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Black</ENAMEX>, mixed-race, and second-generation
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> (led by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zidane</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Algerian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX>) beat the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">team</ENAMEX> that had been embraced, overhyped, and overcommercialized by the global
sports media and business <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elite</ENAMEX>. The cynical spin: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Adidas</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sponsor</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX>) beat <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nike</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sponsor</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Brazilian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX>) and will use the victory
to sell expensive shoes to poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> all over the world. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">7/13/98</NUMEX>)
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ryutaro Hashimoto</ENAMEX> resigned after his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liberal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Party</ENAMEX> suffered losses in parliamentary elections. Free-market
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> called the vote a repudiation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LDP</ENAMEX>'s market-meddling <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pork</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cronyism</ENAMEX>. Others interpreted it as punishment for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LDP</ENAMEX>'s equivocation about
what to do to rescue <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>'s economy. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pessimists</ENAMEX> predicted that by weakening
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LDP</ENAMEX> and opening the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX>'s seat to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contenders</ENAMEX> even less dynamic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">than Hashimoto</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> have worsened <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>'s paralysis. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Optimists</ENAMEX> predicted the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LDP</ENAMEX>'s whipping may jar it into taking firmer measures (tax cuts and other
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">stimuli</ENAMEX>) to fix the economy. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">7/13/98</NUMEX>)
            

            Western
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> confirmed <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nigerian</ENAMEX> opposition <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moshood Abiola</ENAMEX> died of heart
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX> . Abiola, whose imminent victory in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX> presidential election
was annulled by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX>, died in detention <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 7</TIMEX>, just as he was about to
be released. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Nigerians</ENAMEX> suspect he was poisoned. The superficial spin:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abiola</ENAMEX> died of natural causes, not foul play. The cynical spin: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Natural</ENAMEX>? He
died because he had been unjustly imprisoned for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX>, which is a subtler
kind of foul play. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Analysts</ENAMEX> agree <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abiola</ENAMEX> is the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who could have claimed
a popular mandate to supplant <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nigeria</ENAMEX>'s military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rulers</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Pessimists</ENAMEX> say this
means the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s democracy movement is defeated. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Optimists</ENAMEX> say it means the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> can put aside the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX> controversy and move on to a new election.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">7/13/98</NUMEX>)
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>
decided not to fire <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Arnett</ENAMEX> for his role in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX>'s
now-retracted report that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX> used nerve <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas</ENAMEX> against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">defectors</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Vietnam war</ENAMEX>. The report's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producers</ENAMEX> were fired. Arnett, who
narrated the report, was reprimanded. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arnett</ENAMEX>'s spins: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) "There was no way in
hell I could have possibly gone through the vast material they had gathered,
the interview tapes and everything. I didn't even want to." <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) It's standard
practice for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producers</ENAMEX> to enlist <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondents</ENAMEX> such as him to ask scripted
questions on camera without having done the preparatory work. By contrast,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arnett</ENAMEX> says, he's an "action <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>," who generally does his own research. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>)
"There was nothing I could do ... to halt the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">onward</ENAMEX> rush of this story." <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) "I
was never informed that my face on the air gave me responsibility for a major
story." <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>) "I'm a company <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>. You want me to read a script, I'll read it." <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>)
After the story collapsed, "I was basically told to be a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team player</ENAMEX> and
not say anything." <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>) He didn't write the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> piece that echoed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">report</ENAMEX>, though he shared the byline. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>) "For those who say I should have been
fired with the others--my reputation has taken a major hit around the world."
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>) "I was being trashed on a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> basis in the right-wing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>." <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Far</ENAMEX> from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">damaging CNN</ENAMEX>'s reputation, he helped build it. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX>) "I hope they don't saddle me
with the blame. I think it's a cop-out." <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arnett</ENAMEX>'s alibis worse
than the crime. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Rich</ENAMEX> asked, "Is he really
still a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX>, or does he just play <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> on TV?" (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">7/10/98</NUMEX>)
            

            New
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jersey</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-ager</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amy Grossberg</ENAMEX> was sentenced to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a half years</TIMEX> in
jail for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> manslaughter of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX>, which was found in a trash bag
after dying of massive head injuries. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grossberg</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boyfriend</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>,
got a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two year</TIMEX> sentence. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prosecutors</ENAMEX> dropped murder charges because they
couldn't prove who had killed the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> called Grossberg spoiled,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">selfish</ENAMEX>, and blind "to the intrinsic value of the life of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>." The
positive spin: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rich</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> aren't above the law. The negative spin: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rich</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> get
off easy because they can afford good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> who know how to plea-bargain.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">7/10/98</NUMEX>)
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> announced that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> will destroy all
televisions and VCRs within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15 days</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> has also banned audiotapes
and other entertainment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>. An <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> explained that television and video
are "the cause of corruption." Human rights <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX> called it the world's
harshest ban on information. The good news: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> hasn't banned
Internet access. The bad news: That's because nobody in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX> has it.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">7/10/98</NUMEX>)
            

            
               Dow
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corning</ENAMEX> tentatively agreed to pay <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3.2 billion</NUMEX> to settle silicone
breast-implant suits brought by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">170,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>. The deal requires further
clarification and approval. The suits blamed the implants for numerous
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diseases</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Editorialists</ENAMEX> criticized <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">plaintiffs</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>, for trying to
enrich themselves by linking the implants to apparently unrelated <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">maladies</ENAMEX> and
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, for failing to warn <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">implants</ENAMEX>' genuine risks.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Analysts</ENAMEX> concluded the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> didn't want to risk damage awards by tear-jerked
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">juries</ENAMEX> and that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">plaintiffs</ENAMEX> didn't want to risk being discredited by further
studies. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">7/10/98</NUMEX>)
            

            A
federal appeals <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> ordered <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> to testify about
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s activities with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> administration
had asserted a "protective function privilege," which would preclude <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret</ENAMEX>
Service testimony on the grounds that if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> thought his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> might
testify against him, he might keep them at a distance, thereby endangering his
safety. Translation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX>' arguments for rejecting this privilege: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)
If <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> wants to grant such a privilege, it should do so explicitly. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>)
Even if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> can't testify against a naughty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, he might keep
them at a distance just to mitigate his shame, or at least to protect his
"privacy." <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) When deciding whether to keep his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> away, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s
self-preservation instinct will overcome his fear of inconvenient testimony.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pundits</ENAMEX> called the decision a reprieve for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>--who has lost some
recent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> decisions--but noted it doesn't affect the separate assertion of
attorney-client privilege for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Lindsey</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">7/8/98</NUMEX>)
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mikail Markhasev</ENAMEX> was convicted of murdering <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ennis Cosby</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Cosby</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>. Lessons for future <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">murderers</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) When you dump your <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX>, don't wrap it in
the hat you wore during the murder. (The cops matched the gun to the fatal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bullet</ENAMEX>, and they matched the hair and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fibers</ENAMEX> in the hat to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Markhasev.</ENAMEX>) <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) While
in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">jail</ENAMEX>, don't write letters virtually confessing to the crime. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Jurors</ENAMEX> say
that's what made this case "open and shut.") <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) Your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buddies</ENAMEX> will turn you in
for money. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Markhasev</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>" tipped off the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Enquirer</ENAMEX> and
led the cops to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Markhasev</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> in exchange for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> 's <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100,000</NUMEX>
reward.) The media sulked that the trial was over before it could become
another <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.J.</ENAMEX>-style circus. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">7/8/98</NUMEX>)
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX> resigned as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of The 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> . She will chair a
multimedia publishing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> in partnership with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miramax Films</ENAMEX>. Magazine
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mavens</ENAMEX> rehashed the debates over whether <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) she had made The 
               New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yorker</ENAMEX> trashy or refreshingly hip and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) its increase in circulation
outweighed its financial losses during her tenure. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX> says she's leaving for
the opportunity to transcend the print medium and "to own what we create." The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Associated Press</ENAMEX> notes she's leaving <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two months</TIMEX> after The 
               New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yorker</ENAMEX> brought in a new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">publisher</ENAMEX> and began to merge operations with other
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Condé Nast</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX> to save money. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Plotz</ENAMEX> foretold <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX>'s departure
in a recent 
                  Slate
                "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Assessment</ENAMEX>.")
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">7/8/98</NUMEX>)
            

            Singing cowboy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rogers</ENAMEX> died . <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Conservatives</ENAMEX> praised his old-fashioned fidelity, compassion,
chivalry, and humility. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Liberals</ENAMEX> lauded his nonviolence. The sunny spin: He was
as noble in real life as on television. He was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dale Evans</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faithful husband</ENAMEX> for
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50 years</TIMEX>; modeled good habits for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> who watched his show (he gave up
beer off-screen and never kissed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dale</ENAMEX> on-screen); and adopted abused, orphaned,
and ethnic-minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. The surly spins: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gen Xers</ENAMEX> don't know him and
think his name refers only to burger joints. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) Now that he's dead, the dirt
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">diggers</ENAMEX> will go after him, just as they went after <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ozzie and Harriett</ENAMEX>. Chapter
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>: His real name was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leonard Franklin Slye</ENAMEX>. (See "Summary
Judgment" for more.) (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">7/8/98</NUMEX>)
            

         
      
   
