
   
   
      
         
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>
beat the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World Cup</ENAMEX> soccer. This ends <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> hopes of
advancing in the tournament. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iranians</ENAMEX> rejoiced in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> and thanked
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Allah</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> were humiliated and, in contrast to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
post-major-victory tradition, did not attribute the outcome to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus Christ</ENAMEX>.
The surly spin, from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>'s chief <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">theocrat</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ayatollah Ali Khamenei</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>'s
"arrogant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> felt the bitter taste of defeat." The sunny spin, from
ordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iranians</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) There are no hard feelings. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> is just
a paper <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tiger/Satan</ENAMEX> after all. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) Let's be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> noted the
political rapprochement behind the game: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> administration
praised <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>'s moderate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and proposed to upgrade relations. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> called the soccer match "a love fest." <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> soccer
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> immediately launched into the all-American pastime of fixing blame and
complaining about bad luck. The chief whipping boy, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Sampson</ENAMEX>,
is accused of having panicked, fielded too many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rookies</ENAMEX>, and benched or cut
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veteran players</ENAMEX> over petty personality conflicts. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">6/22/98</NUMEX>)
            

            Update
on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> scandal : <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News & World Report</ENAMEX>
described more contents of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tripp</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> tapes. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">First</NUMEX> highlight: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>
sought <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s help in getting a new job before she was subpoenaed
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> case. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Pundits</ENAMEX>' spin: This undermines <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>'s theory
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> sought <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s help in exchange for lying to protect him in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> case. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX> highlight: On the tapes, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tripp</ENAMEX> apparently encourages
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> to obsess about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, to ask him for help getting a job, and to
send him letters via a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">courier</ENAMEX> service owned by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX>'s literary
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Pundits</ENAMEX>' spin: This supports the moral argument that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> was set up,
and it might support the legal argument that he was entrapped. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> reported that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> have reached the
same impasse with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> that stalled her <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> demands that she
plead guilty to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> crime, whereas she insists on total immunity.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Pundits figure</ENAMEX> any impasse is good news for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) The buzz over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brill</ENAMEX>'s critique of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> and the press extended into <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">its second week</TIMEX>,
highlighted by a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly Standard</ENAMEX> countercritique of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brill</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brill</ENAMEX>'s new
spin is that the anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> spin on his article didn't come from him. (For
evidence to the contrary, click .) 
               (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">6/22/98</NUMEX>)
            

            Two
major health <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">insurers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kaiser Permanente</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aetna</ENAMEX>, decided not to cover
Viagra except for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> who pay a surcharge. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kaiser</ENAMEX>'s spin: It's too
expensive, and other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> shouldn't have to pay for your intercourse. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aetna</ENAMEX>'s
spin: "Having sexual relations is not a medical necessity." The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York State</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health Department</ENAMEX>'s explanation for not covering <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Viagra</ENAMEX> under <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX>: Some
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> will turn around and sell it on the black market. The pro-coverage spin,
from the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pill</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pfizer</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Impotence</ENAMEX> is a "serious medical condition
that can seriously diminish <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>'s self-esteem and affect their relationships."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Analysts</ENAMEX> speculate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kaiser</ENAMEX>'s decision will accelerate a race by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">insurers</ENAMEX> to
avoid becoming havens for impotent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">6/22/98</NUMEX>)
            

            An
alleged copycat case of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> dragging a black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> from a car
has been recanted. A black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisiana</ENAMEX>, whose report of the alleged crime
was picked up in the national <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX> and was being investigated as a hate crime
(after the recent murder in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>), has admitted he fabricated the story. Two
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> say what really happened is that they ripped off the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> in a crack deal,
he tried to get into their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>, and he was dragged in the ensuing altercation.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">6/22/98</NUMEX>)
            

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Globe</ENAMEX> forced metro <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patricia Smith</ENAMEX> to resign for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fabricating</ENAMEX> quotes and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>. Nobody knows how long she has been doing it.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX>'s defense, in her departing column: She only did it "to create the
desired impact or slam home a salient point," and her career will survive "this
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">indiscretion</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Colleagues</ENAMEX> and media <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> compared her with ex- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> fabricator <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Glass</ENAMEX> with varying takes: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) Like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glass</ENAMEX>, she
was "stretched too thin." <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) Kudos to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> for instituting the
routine source double-checking system that caught <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX>. If only the New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> had done this. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) Shame on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> for having hired <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX>
despite a previous incident in which she had reportedly reviewed a concert she
didn't attend. At least the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX> didn't know it was hiring a
liar. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) As with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glass</ENAMEX>, the quotes from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> were too good to check.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>) Actually, the poetic quality of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX>'s quotes is what aroused her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX>'
suspicions. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>) Her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">talent</ENAMEX> for poetry is what inspired her to fabricate in the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place. So it's poetic justice that she was caught for the same reason. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>)
Glass showed superior cleverness by fabricating less perfect quotes. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX>
"championed the downtrodden and elevated the voices of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who would never
have gotten in this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>." <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX> invented those voices instead of doing the
work of talking to real downtrodden <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. (Why do <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> fall for the wiles
of the likes of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glass</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX>? Check out "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Glass Houses</ENAMEX>,"
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Shafer</ENAMEX>.) (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">6/19/98</NUMEX>)
            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> killed the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> tobacco bill . Editorialists were outraged. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> accused
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> of killing the bill at the behest of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Tobacco</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> said
the bill had lost sight of its original goal--reducing teen smoking--and become
a tax-and-spend monstrosity full of extraneous special-interest tax breaks and
off-budget spending. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> pointed out that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> had demanded the
extraneous tax breaks in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place. The initial spin: Pushing to kill the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bill</ENAMEX> was a big gamble for the tobacco <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, because they'll now have to
face suits from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>. The backspin: What gamble? The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>
had made the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>' decision easy by stripping the bill of the liability
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cap</ENAMEX> that would have mitigated the suits. (For an earlier look at the spin
war over <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco</ENAMEX>, click here.) 
               (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">6/18/98</NUMEX>)
            

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ennis Cosby</ENAMEX> murder trial opened. Even before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> selection, the
prosecution dropped a bombshell, alleging that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defendant</ENAMEX> Mikail Markhasev
belongs to the "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mafia</ENAMEX>" prison <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gang</ENAMEX> and that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">gang</ENAMEX> might threaten
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jurors</ENAMEX>. Similarities to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.J. Simpson</ENAMEX> case: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) It's a celebrity murder. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>)
National <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> are flocking to cover it. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) It's next door to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.J.</ENAMEX> civil
case courtroom. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) The racial angle is back, but this time, the roles are
reversed. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defendant</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ukrainian</ENAMEX> and is alleged to have told a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">companion</ENAMEX>,
"I shot the nigger." (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">6/17/98</NUMEX>)
            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Detroit Red</ENAMEX>
Wings won the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Stanley Cup</ENAMEX>, beating the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Washington Capitals</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> games.
This is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> straight <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Hockey League</ENAMEX> championship for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Red</ENAMEX>
Wings and the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> consecutive sweep in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NHL</ENAMEX> finals. The on-stage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Yzerman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Red Wings</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">captain</ENAMEX>, who won playoff MVP honors after having been
labeled a choker earlier in his career. The offstage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX>: former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Red Wings</ENAMEX>
star <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vladimir Konstantinov</ENAMEX>, who, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> after suffering severe brain damage in
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> crash, was rolled onto the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX> in his wheelchair to celebrate <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s
championship. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">6/17/98</NUMEX>)
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> are in a ruckus over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">homosexuality</TIMEX> . First,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Majority Leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Lott</ENAMEX> called it a sin and compared it to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">kleptomania</ENAMEX> and "sex addiction." Then gay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX> denounced <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lott</ENAMEX>'s remarks.
Then <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Majority Leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Armey</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lott</ENAMEX> is right and the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX> proves
it. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike McCurry</ENAMEX> said that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) "it's not a disease, it is
something that is part of defining one's sexuality"; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lott</ENAMEX>'s remarks show
that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> are "backward"; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> right
has pushed these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> to "the extreme." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> had a field day, recalling
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> crisis over a donation from gay <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Armey</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>
reference to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barney Frank</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mass.</ENAMEX>, as "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barney Fag</ENAMEX>." (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">6/17/98</NUMEX>)
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX>' highest
court decided that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">au pair</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louise Woodward</ENAMEX> will not go back to
jail. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woodward</ENAMEX> will soon be able to leave the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> upheld a
trial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>'s decision to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) reduce <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woodward</ENAMEX>'s conviction from murder to
manslaughter in the death of an <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8-month-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) reduce her prison
sentence from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15 years</TIMEX> to the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">279 days</TIMEX> she had already served. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> responded by filing a wrongful death suit. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woodward</ENAMEX> recently fired one
of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> for allegedly telling a state trooper she now thinks <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woodward</ENAMEX> is
guilty. (See the latest "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International</ENAMEX>
Papers" for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woodward</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British Airways</ENAMEX> ruckus.) (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">6/16/98</NUMEX>)
            

         
      
   
