
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Technical Truths</ENAMEX>, and Videotape

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fool</ENAMEX> , produced by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg Stevens</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kemp</ENAMEX> '96.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> accuse each other of lying about their respective <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>
proposals. In fact, neither side is lying: Each selectively cites facts and
offers proof. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> say they want to limit the increase of Medicare
spending to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">7 percent</NUMEX>. This is not a cut, they say, just a slowdown in the rate
of growth; the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> wanted to cut, too. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> maintain that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>' increase in spending is below the rate of medical inflation (the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> respond by pointing to the general rate of inflation). The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> trimmed the program only a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> as much as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> plan--which also
would have prevented <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">seniors</ENAMEX> from choosing their own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX>, and
would have denied coverage for services like <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diabetes</ENAMEX> blood tests (which
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> now promises will be a priority in the next <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>).

            Despite the bickering, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> know that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> is not their issue. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Voters</ENAMEX> are more likely to
believe the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> and more likely to believe the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> on
tax cutting, which means that there is a limit to what political ads can do to
reshape ingrained attitudes. So until now, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kemp</ENAMEX> ads ignored Medicare
almost entirely and engaged in a struggle to make welfare, taxes, and character
the defining terrain for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fool</ENAMEX> , produced by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultant</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stevens</ENAMEX>, abandons that agenda to respond on an issue where <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> can at
best neutralize, not prevail.

            This is the rare kind of
response ad that actually and almost exclusively responds. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fool</ENAMEX> is
entirely defensive, despite the obligatory knock on the other side's accuracy.
The spot's life begins dangerously, with an excerpt from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> ad
that not only references, but reinforces the charge that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> sought to cut
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> scene even shows <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> with the singularly unpopular
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX>--the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">campaign</ENAMEX>'s favorite piece of videotape. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fool</ENAMEX> 's
opening is frontal, audacious, maybe foolish, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> strategists
obviously decided to take the chance. The red "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wrong</ENAMEX>" stamped across the scene
is a standard technique that does little to detract from the effect of seeing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> widely seen, fairly or unfairly, as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Darth Vader</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>.

            The next scenes carry the
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lobby</ENAMEX>'s letters as third-party proof that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole-Gingrich</ENAMEX> Medicare
proposal was only to "slow" the program's growth--and both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> did it
anyway. The next quote--about "finger pointing"--seems to point the finger at
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. But the AARP fiercely complained that the excerpted quotations were
not true to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>'s letter--which did not take sides against
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> campaign agreed to pull <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Fool</ENAMEX> off the air (perhaps, in
part, because some inside the campaign thought it was too defensive and raised
the salience of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s best issue).

            In the next scene, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>
huddles with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">seniors</ENAMEX> on a neighborhood <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> (is this <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russell</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kan.</ENAMEX>?). The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">narrator</ENAMEX> says: "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AARP</ENAMEX> agrees with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX>"--the words leave the impression
that they agree on what's just been said, and then the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">narrator</ENAMEX> continues--"on
a bipartisan plan to fix <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>." The chyron goes even farther: "The AARP
agrees with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> plan . ..." The admaker would no doubt defend this on the
basis that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AARP</ENAMEX> wants a bipartisan solution; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> says he does; ergo ... a
truly tenuous technical truth.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> campaign's purpose
was not to win on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> issue--it can't overcome a perception that
basic--but to neutralize an issue which has hurt so much that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Kemp</ENAMEX>
recently complained that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> budget was a disaster for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>.
The spot ends with a brief nod to the offense: "Don't let <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> fool
you"--and notice what's underlined. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fool</ENAMEX>," of course, is supposed to have a
double meaning: That's what you are if you vote for him.

            But then
the spot disappeared, and now <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Election Day</TIMEX> dawns.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Shrum</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shrum</ENAMEX> is a leading <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultant</ENAMEX>. His deconstruction of
political ads is a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> feature of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> during the election
season.
            

         
      
   
