
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">War Room Strikes</ENAMEX> Back

            
               Hold, a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30-second</TIMEX> clip
produced for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> campaign by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Squier</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Squier</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Knapp</ENAMEX> &
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ochs</ENAMEX>.
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> commercials are
laboring to make taxes and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> the central issues of the presidential
campaign. The <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Clinton War Room</ENAMEX>--a state of mind this year, not a place--strikes
back with Hold , a tough, frontal (and potentially dangerous) response
prepared by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Squier</ENAMEX> at the direction of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s chief
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strategist</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Morris</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> ad begins not
with the issue of taxes but with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>, accusing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> of engaging in the
old "attack" politics (proving once again that the best use of negatives can be
accusing the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> of going negative). The bold red chyrons used in the
ad--<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">scarlet</ENAMEX> letters that appear here and later in the spot--are a chromatic
charge of wrongdoing leveled against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>. Hold both responds to the tax
attacks made by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sows</ENAMEX> seeds of doubt about future <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> assaults.
The timing is excellent: According to the polls, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has been attacked so
often that he is in need of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Teflon</ENAMEX> coating.

            
               Hold presents <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age</TIMEX>-emphasizing black-and-white videotape, with a drawing of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Capitol</ENAMEX> in
the background, indicating that the former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX> hasn't left that unpopular
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">venue</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Color</ENAMEX> footage, complete with a shot of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marine</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX> in the
background, lends <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> presidential depth and authority. The ad argues that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> cut taxes, thereby confronting both the tax issue and the
conventional wisdom about him and his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Voters</ENAMEX> believe that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
raised taxes and generally resist any argument that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> are better at
reducing taxes.)

            The danger of Hold
lies in its boldness. If taxes became the defining issue, the terrain would
naturally favor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>. But if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> seizes the tax issue, what does <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> have
left? This calculus of risk and gain reflects the thinking of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Morris</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultant</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early '80s</TIMEX> who switched <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> and often deployed taxes as a
wedge issue to get <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> elected.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s claim in
Hold that he has cut taxes for "working <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>" is based on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Earned</ENAMEX>
Income <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tax Credit</ENAMEX>, which helps the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">working poor</ENAMEX>. The choice of
language--"working <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>"--plays on the fact that most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> view
themselves that way. The narration and visual swiftly move on to "tax credits
for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX>"--which polls report as more popular than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>'s widely anticipated
proposal for a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">15 percent</NUMEX> across-the-board tax cut.

            
               Hold discounts the
popular assumption that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> are tax cutters by citing areas where it's
believable that they would increase taxes--"working <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>" and "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social</ENAMEX>
Security"--areas where <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> have the natural advantage. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>, again in
ghostly black and white, is paired with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> (who owns the highest negative
ratings of any national figure) in footage that runs in slow motion, making him
look older and less vigorous. Meanwhile, a list of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> tax increases scrolls
up the screen, annotated with specific bill numbers as proof.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>'s tax-raising sins
are totaled in red at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$900 billion</NUMEX>. Even "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>" are appalled, the spot
suggests, citing a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time magazine</ENAMEX> article (from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12 years ago</TIMEX>). The
appalled <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> quoted in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>--but not named in the spot--is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX>, who was then a backbencher in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> appears briefly in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">color</ENAMEX>--a visual cue that we are now watching him on the stump and not in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>--and promises that we are about to see "the real <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX>." This
implies that there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Doles</ENAMEX>, setting up the conclusion that the
campaigning, tax-cutting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> is the phony. The real <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>, the spot tells
us--and not just in words--is the aged career <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX> who has spent 35 years
raising your taxes.

            
               Hold goes against
the grain of popular assumptions about <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> and taxes; but it doesn't need
to convince completely. The tactic is to fight <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> to a draw or a near-draw on
the tax issue; that would be an intermediate victory for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, and make a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX> victory more likely.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Shrum</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
