
   
   
      
         
            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Strategy of Tactics</ENAMEX>

            This spot, produced by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dean</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> media <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultants</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Squier</ENAMEX>, begins by indicting the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> for "another negative" attack. Initially, it doesn't even bother to
identify the substance of the attack. Survey research shows that one of the
most effective negative charges is that the other side is being negative. This
ad seeks to create a context of doubt for any and all <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> attacks on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>. In fact, both sides run negative ads.

            Eventually the ad implies
that its subject (sort of) is immigration. The purpose is to pre-empt another
"natural" <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> issue. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Immigration</ENAMEX> continues to be social and political
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dynamite</ENAMEX>, and this spot tries to take the match out of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> hands. The
Buchananesque toughness of the pictures validates the toughness of the
language, leaving the impression that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is as <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrant</ENAMEX> as any
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>.

            The spot now shifts to its
own negative fusillade against <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>. They opposed protecting <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> from "replacement" by foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>. The actual issue is not
explained, but the charge taps into the populist anger about stagnant wages,
foreign competition, and the globalization that both <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>, in fact,
have supported. Next, the spot says the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> opposed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> on more
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> and anti-drug programs: another effort to pre-empt, or even reverse, a
perennial <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> advantage.

            During this attack phase,
the ad alternates film of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Speaker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX> with vaguely relevant
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">footage</ENAMEX> (What's inside the rug--an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> job or an illegal alien?), while
repeatedly referring to "the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole-Gingrich</ENAMEX> budget." But where is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>? His
picture can't be used because, in theory if not in effect, the ad is an act of
legislative advocacy, paid for by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Committee</ENAMEX>, not the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">campaign</ENAMEX>--and legally, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>, as an ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX>, can't be its obvious
target. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> campaign converts a legal restriction into a political
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">virtue</ENAMEX>, marrying <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> to the grainy black-and-white visage of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s most
unpopular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX>. By contrast, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> appears intermittently in decidedly
presidential footage.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> campaign
doesn't want to be <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about one or two</NUMEX> big things <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>; it's not the economy
stupid. This spot is the vivid expression of a strategy of many tactics. There
is no message here, but an almost telegraphic mix of hot-button words.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Shrum</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
