
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Character/Assassination</ENAMEX>

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Seconds</TIMEX> , produced
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Squier</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Squier</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Knapp & Ochs for Clinton</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> '96.

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Seconds</TIMEX> daringly
capitalizes on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jim</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarah Brady</ENAMEX>'s conversion to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> camp, combining
the horrific footage of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Hinckley</ENAMEX>'s assassination attempt on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX>
with a stirring endorsement of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brady</ENAMEX>, who was grievously wounded
in the assault.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy Reagan</ENAMEX> has denounced
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Seconds</TIMEX> as falling below "even the minimum levels of current political
advertising." Apparently Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> hasn't seen many political spots lately.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> himself decided to reject her demand that this ad be yanked
off the air.

            The spot is aimed at swing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>--suburbanites, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, and fiscal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> who disagree
with the dominant <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> position on issues like <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> and
abortion--precisely the kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarah Brady</ENAMEX> were when he was
serving as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press secretary</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1981</TIMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Seconds</TIMEX> speaks
not only to the swing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> who are swinging so decisively to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> that he
leads in normally <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> suburbs and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>; it captures and plays upon the
mood of an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">electorate</ENAMEX> that this year seems to despise the negative ads if they
involve personal attacks. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">campaign</ENAMEX> has run plenty of negatives,
but almost entirely focused on issues.)

            The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> scene is the
familiar news footage from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1981</TIMEX>: A smiling and waving <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX> outside the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Hilton</ENAMEX> takes a bullet to the chest. The message here is that even
the most optimistic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> can be struck down by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gunman</ENAMEX>. The
presence of this defining <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> ad signifies and
reinforces the appeal across partisan lines.

            The visual shifts to the
wounded and bloodied <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brady</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sidewalk</ENAMEX> and we recognize the voice, heard by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tens</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> during the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Democratic National Convention</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Brady</ENAMEX>'s slow
words hit like soft hammer blows--"It was over in a moment, but the pain lasts
forever." We next see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brady</ENAMEX> at home, recovered, lessened physically, but
seemingly indomitable. The scar across his forehead speaks to the injury he
suffered; and as he speaks, he passes the torch of his own courage to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> who signed "The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brady Bill</ENAMEX>." We don't even have to be told what the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bill</ENAMEX> is anymore; we may not know all the details, but we know--and the pictures
tell us--that it's designed to keep <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> out of the hands of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> and
unstable loners.

            In footage of the bill's
signing, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> hands the pen to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Brady</ENAMEX>, whose voiceover celebrates
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s "integrity" and his determination to "do what was right." Issues like
gun control--not Whitewater or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> files or some murky allegations about an
Indonesian connection--are the measure of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seconds</ENAMEX> . Without
a single negative word, this spot efficiently repels the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> campaign's
ninth-inning attack on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brady</ENAMEX>
says, "When I hear <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> question the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>, I say, look what
he's done ..."--cut to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> walking by himself, maybe even biting his lip--
"Look at the lives the Brady <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX> will save." The language is simple and
authentic; the witness carries a credibility that the anonymous, disembodied
narrators of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>'s anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> jeremiads could never claim.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Shrum</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shrum</ENAMEX> is a leading <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultant</ENAMEX>. His deconstruction of
political ads is a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> feature of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> during the election
season.
            

         
      
   
