
   
   
      
         
            

            Real
Quiet lost the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belmont Stakes</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Victory Gallop</ENAMEX> by a nose. This is the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> straight <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kentucky Derby</ENAMEX> and the Preakness
fell just short in the final leg of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Triple Crown</ENAMEX>. (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX>'s near-winner
was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Silver Charm</ENAMEX>.) The last <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Triple Crown</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Affirmed</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 years ago</TIMEX>. The
popular spin: How sad for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Real Quiet</ENAMEX>'s jockey, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kent Desormeaux</ENAMEX>, and for trainer
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Baffert</ENAMEX>, who also trained <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Silver Charm</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">backstage</ENAMEX> spins: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) How sweet
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jockey</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Stevens</ENAMEX>, who rode <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Victory Gallop</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> after having lost on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">board Silver Charm</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Desormeaux</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baffert</ENAMEX> are lucky they lost the
race outright, because if they'd won, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Real Quiet</ENAMEX> would have been disqualified
for interfering with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Victory Gallop</ENAMEX>'s run--and they'd be remembered for
scandal, not just defeat. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">6/8/98</NUMEX>)
            

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Rifle Association</ENAMEX> held its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> convention and showcased its new
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlton Heston</ENAMEX>. Click for a dissection of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NRA</ENAMEX>'s spin on
school shootings. 
               (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">6/8/98</NUMEX>)
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Terry Nichols</ENAMEX> was sentenced to life in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> for his part in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma City</ENAMEX> bombing. The dramatic spin: The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> testified
about their grief and received justice. The intellectual spin: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matsch</ENAMEX> sent a message against terrorism and in support of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matsch</ENAMEX> argued that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> who were killed had been establishing justice,
ensuring domestic tranquility, and promoting the general welfare. His sound
bite: "This was not a murder case. ... It is a crime against the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX>."
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">6/5/98</NUMEX>)
            

            The
constitutional amendment to allow organized prayer in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> , religious
displays in federal <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>, and the spending of tax money for religiously
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">affiliated</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>. The vote was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">224</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">203</NUMEX> in favor. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Supporters</ENAMEX> argued that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> should protect religious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> from anti-religious school
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">administrators</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Opponents</ENAMEX> argued that religious-minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> and school
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">administrators</ENAMEX> should be protected from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>. The naive spin: <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>
lost. The sophisticated spin: <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> won, by appeasing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> who will reward them at the polls in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX>.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">6/5/98</NUMEX>)
            

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> rejected independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Starr</ENAMEX>'s request to
resolve whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Lindsey</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> must
answer questions in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> investigation. Instead, these questions
will proceed to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Court of Appeals</ENAMEX>. For a look at how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> is
recovering ground in his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PR</ENAMEX> battle with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, click .

               (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">6/4/98</NUMEX>)
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> dumped <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Ginsburg</ENAMEX> and hired <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Stein</ENAMEX> and Plato
Cacheris as her new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>. Theories on why she did it: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) Unlike <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ginsburg</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stein</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cacheris</ENAMEX> know how to defend high-profile <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>)
Unlike <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ginsburg</ENAMEX>, they know how to shut up--and proved it by saying nothing when
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> presented them to the press. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ginsburg</ENAMEX>, meanwhile, went on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> to deny
he had been fired. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) Unlike <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ginsburg</ENAMEX>, they're willing to make nice with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX> in order to avert an indictment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Pundits</ENAMEX> hope the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> will cut a deal to get <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> to testify against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">6/3/98</NUMEX>)
            

            Several
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> held referendums and primary elections <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 2</TIMEX>. The headlines: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Californians</ENAMEX> approved a ballot measure to replace bilingual education with one
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> of training in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> opposed the measure, but
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> supported it across ethnic lines. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Pundits</ENAMEX> think other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> will follow
suit. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Californians</ENAMEX> rejected a measure that would have banned <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX> from
spending dues on political contributions without their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>' consent.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Pundits</ENAMEX> think this will hurt similar initiatives in other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>
Lt. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gray Davis</ENAMEX> beat <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane Harman</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">businessman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Checchi</ENAMEX>, who spent
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of their personal wealth, for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> gubernatorial nomination.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Pundits</ENAMEX> hailed this as a triumph of political experience over wealth and
negative ads. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alabama</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fob James Jr.</ENAMEX> fell just shy of the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50 percent</NUMEX>
needed to avoid a runoff in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> primary for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX>. The national
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">media</ENAMEX> clucked at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">James</ENAMEX>' embarrassment and blamed it on his putative religious
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">extremism</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">6/3/98</NUMEX>)
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s economy is in peril. Its stock market has lost <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than half</NUMEX>
its value <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>, including a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX> drop <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> before rallying
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Analysts</ENAMEX> fear the economic ills could spread to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> and that
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX> might resort to selling nuclear technology under the table. To stave
off disastrous currency devaluation, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is tripling
interest rates, spending reserves, and exhorting <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tycoons</ENAMEX> to invest
their money in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> markets to restore foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>' confidence. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> faces <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> dilemmas: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) It must make the situation look grim
enough to jar <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> into supporting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Monetary Fund</ENAMEX> but not
so grim that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> pull all their money out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) It must bail out
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> soon enough to avert collapse but not before <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> delivers the
politically painful tax, spending, and legal reforms necessary for its
long-term health. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">6/3/98</NUMEX>)
            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Gay</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lesbian Task Force</ENAMEX> released a report on public attitudes toward
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">homosexuality</ENAMEX> . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> agreed the findings show
increasing public tolerance for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gays</ENAMEX> despite persistent moral disapproval.
For analysis of the report and its spin, click . 
               (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">6/3/98</NUMEX>)
            

         
      
   
