
   
   
      
         
            Let <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole Be Reagan</ENAMEX>

            
               The Plan , created
by the all-star <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> media <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> assembled for the general election, is a
disciplined exposition of the dominant <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kemp</ENAMEX> message that emerged after the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> took his foot out of his mouth and started running again. The
strategy is clear and politically smart: "Let <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole Be Reagan</ENAMEX>," complete with a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> who is the original <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supply-sider</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-author</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan's 1981 Kemp</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roth</ENAMEX>
tax cut.

            This spot kidnaps the wage
issue, which historically has belonged to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> of labor, not the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> of
big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> scenes reach for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reagan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>, depicting
the blue- and new-collar middle class that loved <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> but deposed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voice-over</ENAMEX> describes the wage gap they face in simple words:
They're "working harder and longer but taking home less."

            Indeed, middle-class
income, which rose <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1.7 percent</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>, has stagnated during the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> recovery. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> has entertained proposals offered by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gephardt</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX> to boost wages--such as new incentives for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> to
share soaring profits with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>. But instead of drawing attention to
economic problems, the prevailing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> rule is to emphasize the good
news.

            The Old <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> would have
produced a spot that analyzed the economy in statistical and legislative terms;
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">New Dole of The Plan</ENAMEX> speaks directly into the camera in human terms,
in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Reaganesque</ENAMEX> language, about a family spending more on taxes than on "<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">clothing</ENAMEX>, and housing combined." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Visually</ENAMEX>, the spot returns to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>-like
scene of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>'s disastrous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> 
               of 
               the 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union</ENAMEX>
response, but this time the lighting is right, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> finally looks
presidential. (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last January</TIMEX>, he was done in more by shadows than by
substance.)

            The presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> is
shown talking with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> he claims to identify with, and the voice-over
switches to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">narrator</ENAMEX>, who describes "the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dole Economic Plan</ENAMEX>." The next scene
has no distracting images, just words, numbers, and this focus: a "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> Percent
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tax Cut for Every Taxpayer</ENAMEX>." The absence of any reinforcing visual actually
makes the simple message all the more vivid.

            The visual segues to a
nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, unifying <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> different <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> messages--the moral and the
material: The scene all but shouts that tax cuts are a family value. The spot
then computes what a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">15 percent</NUMEX> cut will mean to the average <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>. As we've
seen in other ads, the specificity of the number--<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,657</NUMEX> instead of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,600</NUMEX>--is
designed to secure credibility. Who would bother to make up the extra <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$57</NUMEX>?

            Just before The
Plan closes, we return to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> chatting with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> holding an infant, a
scene that further humanizes the tax plan and helps close the gender gap. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">narrator</ENAMEX>'s words about <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> keeping more of what they earn complete the
message. The subtext is that this may be the only real-income increase
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hard-pressed</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> will get.

            The final scene relies
once more on text in big letters to blend the tax issue--"a better
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>"--with the character issue--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> as "a better <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>." The Plan
dispels the notion that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rush Limbaugh</ENAMEX>, personally attacking the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX>, savaging <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>. He's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX>--and to
prove it, he has the true-believing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Kemp</ENAMEX> as his running mate. The spot,
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> broadcast <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four days</TIMEX> before <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kemp</ENAMEX> was picked, reveals the logic of the
choice and makes it less of a surprise, even to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX>, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> stood
in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russell</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kan.</ENAMEX>, watching <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kemp</ENAMEX> speak, the TV news made him look like a man
receiving a transfusion. He had a new sense of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spirit</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kemp</ENAMEX> tax cut.
He smiled, and his color brightened to a paler <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reaganism</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> may not win, but
maybe now he won't be disgraced.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Shrum Robert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shrum</ENAMEX> is a leading <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultant</ENAMEX>. His deconstruction of
political ads will be a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> feature of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> during the election
season.
            

            Previous <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Varnish Remover</ENAMEX>
columns

         
      
   
