
   
   
      
         
            

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> voted <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">80-19</NUMEX> to expand <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> to include <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Poland</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hungary</ENAMEX>, and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Czech</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Supporters</ENAMEX> called it a triumph for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintonian</ENAMEX> vision of a
big, happy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> of democracies. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> called it a triumph for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintonian</ENAMEX> vision of a big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> for happy <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> defense
contractors. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doomsayers</ENAMEX> warned it would freak out the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX>, who might
resort to nuclear weapons. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Half</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cynics</ENAMEX> argued that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>'
obligation to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX> and defend the new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> isn't worth the military help the
new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> will provide. Complete cynics replied that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Poles</ENAMEX> are better
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">allies</ENAMEX> than the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX>. (Also check out 
                  Slate
               's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Recycled</ENAMEX>.")
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">5/1/98</NUMEX>)
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s Whitewater <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">grand jury</ENAMEX> indicted former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX> official
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Webster Hubbell</ENAMEX> on fraud and tax evasion charges . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> also won
indictments against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hubbell</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">accountant</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Analysts</ENAMEX> agreed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> is turning up the heat on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hubbell</ENAMEX> in order to make
him finger the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintons</ENAMEX> for allegedly directing hush money to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hubbell</ENAMEX> to shut
him up <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about Whitewater</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Contrarians</ENAMEX> argued that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> really had the
goods, he'd have won indictments of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hubbell</ENAMEX> on obstruction of justice charges
and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) the indictment shows that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> has given up on cutting a friendly deal
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hubbell</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hubbell</ENAMEX>'s reply: "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> of the independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> can
indict my <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX>, they can indict my <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX>, but I'm not going to lie about the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> camp's spin: This connects <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hubbell</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan McDougal</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> in a web of obstruction of justice. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> camp's spin:
This connects <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hubbell</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">McDougal</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> in a web of obsessive persecution
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>. (See <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4/27/98</NUMEX> for an earlier in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX> update of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s recent
investigation.) (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">5/1/98</NUMEX>)
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> held his first solo news conference since the onset of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> scandal. He tried to talk about economic growth and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>
expansion, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> focused their questions on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>--and then focused
their follow-up coverage on their questions about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX> spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">38</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">seconds</TIMEX> showing its own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> asking a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> question, leaving <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">14 seconds</TIMEX>
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s reply. The pundit consensus: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> ducked all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>
questions. And they call this a news conference? <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) He tried simultaneously to
turn the other cheek (to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX>) and to portray <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> as the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">obsessed</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> of a partisan vendetta. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) His vendetta spin (which the New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times</ENAMEX> called "self-serving") curdled the turn-the-other-cheek spin.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">5/1/98</NUMEX>)
            

            
Computer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">programmer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Froistad</ENAMEX> was arrested after confessing in an
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX>/addiction-related Internet support <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> to murdering his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Members</ENAMEX> of the support <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> turned him in. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> seized on the Internet
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">angle</ENAMEX>, pondering whether e-mail is private (answer: No) and whether it's
ethical for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of an online support <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> to breach confidentiality if
they suspect a crime (answer: You decide). Big-picture <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">theorists</ENAMEX> concluded
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> will now treat Internet confessions as fair game. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Skeptics</ENAMEX> argued
that this case doesn't set such a precedent, because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Froistad</ENAMEX> confessed to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> by phone after learning that support group <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> had told them about
his postings. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">5/1/98</NUMEX>)
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt</ENAMEX>
Gingrich escalated the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> assault on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s ethics.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> said: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> is involved in the most "complex,
interlocking lawbreaking" and "the most systematic, deliberate obstruction of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice</ENAMEX> [and] coverup" in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> history. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Clintonites</ENAMEX> "unpatriotically
undermine the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> ... on behalf of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX>." <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) If <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
doesn't want to fire <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Starr</ENAMEX>, "he should tell his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> to shut up." <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) Other
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> should denounce <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> too. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pundits</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> was retaliating
against obstruction of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> fund-raising investigation by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>, who
in turn were retaliating against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Burton</ENAMEX>'s description of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> as a
"scumbag." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike McCurry</ENAMEX> suggested <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> is in cahoots with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">billionaire conspiracy theorist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Mellon Scaife</ENAMEX>, adding that "as soon as
[<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX>] comes back to his senses, we'll do business." (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4/29/98</NUMEX>)
            

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Reserve Board</ENAMEX> says the Year <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> problem will probably cost <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
businesses <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">at least $50 billion</NUMEX>. The problem is that computers that designate
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> digits must be reprogrammed to distinguish <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1900</TIMEX>. The bad
news: It could slow down the economy enough to force a recession, as the 1970s
oil shock did. The good news: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) For this economy, a slowdown is just what the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> ordered. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) Plenty of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> are desperately seeking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">programmers</ENAMEX>.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4/29/98</NUMEX>)
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel</ENAMEX>
Petrocelli, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> who won the civil case against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.J. Simpson</ENAMEX> , says
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simpson</ENAMEX> murdered his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ex-wife</ENAMEX> for resuming an affair with <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marcus</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Petrocelli</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dateline NBC</ENAMEX> that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) interviews with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simpson</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">associates</ENAMEX> always led back to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simpson</ENAMEX> envied <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen</ENAMEX> for staying
healthy and enjoying a longer football career than he did; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nicole Brown</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simpson</ENAMEX> had often used <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen</ENAMEX> to rile <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.J.</ENAMEX>; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) her affair with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen</ENAMEX> "made
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simpson</ENAMEX> snap." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Petrocelli</ENAMEX> conceded that he didn't present this theory in court
because he couldn't prove it. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> denies that the football star
had such an affair. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4/29/98</NUMEX>)
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alabama</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fob James Jr.</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s most vigorous elected advocate
of student prayer, apologized for cursing out a new <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alabama</ENAMEX> law requiring a
moment of silence in public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James</ENAMEX>, upset because the law doesn't
authorize audible prayers, told its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sponsor</ENAMEX> that it "ain't worth the damn paper
it's written on" and "ain't going to require shit" until <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> passes a law
to back it up. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James</ENAMEX> later discovered that his microphone was on.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4/29/98</NUMEX>)
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">celebrated Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX>'s birthday . <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX> marched in
his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">hometown</ENAMEX>. Young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> sang his praises. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Children</ENAMEX> staged a play for him. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> covered the celebration nonstop. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> reported that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22</NUMEX>
million candles were lit to honor him. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N. Security Council</ENAMEX> marked the
occasion by renewing sanctions against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">another six months</TIMEX>.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4/29/98</NUMEX>)
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">deputies</ENAMEX> interrogated <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">several hours</TIMEX> at
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>. The subject was her legal work for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">savings and loan</ENAMEX> at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">center of the Whitewater</ENAMEX> scandal. Videotape of her answers will be shown to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas Whitewater</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">grand jury</ENAMEX>, which will disband <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 7</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pundits</ENAMEX> played up the
tension between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">first lady</ENAMEX> (since she recently called him "a
politically motivated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX> who is allied with the right-wing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> of
my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>") and debated whether he will indict her. The overwhelming consensus
is that he won't. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4/27/98</NUMEX>)
            

            Paula
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> attended the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House Correspondents Association Dinner</ENAMEX> , as did
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> called her presence tacky (she was a guest of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Insight magazine</ENAMEX>), and some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX> booed her. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX>
called her dress "cleavage-coercing" and reported that her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">handler</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carpenter-McMillan</ENAMEX>, dabbed sweat from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>' upper lip and set aside a piece of
used chewing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gum</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> handed her. Most news accounts concluded that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> overshadowed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> with a funny, largely apolitical speech featuring
digs at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> ("a show about nothing"), the press corps ("I hardly have any
time to read the news anymore. Mostly I just skim the retractions"), and
himself ("I am so sorry ... about disco"). (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4/27/98</NUMEX>)
            

            A <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX>
boy fatally shot <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> and wounded another and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX>. He was
charged with murder and tried as an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adult</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> linked the case to other
recent shootings (in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mississippi</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kentucky</ENAMEX>) and focused on the
warning signs and the importance of taking them seriously. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> clues in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX> case: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> had said, "I'm going to go to the dinner dance
and kill some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>." <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> had nicknamed him "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Satan</ENAMEX>."
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4/27/98</NUMEX>)
            

         
      
   
