
   
   
      
         
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin Netanyahu</ENAMEX> is planning a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> public
relations campaign against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. The surface story: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rejected Clinton</ENAMEX>'s demand that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> accept withdrawal from another <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">13 percent</NUMEX>
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Bank</ENAMEX> as a prerequisite for further <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> peace talks. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">backstage</ENAMEX>
story, reported by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> : <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX> will visit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>,
the pro-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> lobby, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> media <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> to stir up criticism of the
pressure <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> put on him. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX>'s spin: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX> had to accept
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s offer, because it was too favorable to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> to pass up and because
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> couldn't afford to antagonize the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. The subsequent spin: If
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX> didn't accept, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> would take his case <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> to put pressure on
him. The new spin: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX> is passing up the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> offer, is willing to
antagonize the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, and is taking his case <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> to put pressure on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">5/11/98</NUMEX>)
            

            
               SBC
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communications</ENAMEX> has agreed to buy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ameritech</ENAMEX> in a stock swap worth <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $60</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">billion</ENAMEX>. This would be the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>-biggest merger ever (behind <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Citigroup</ENAMEX>)--at
least for the moment--and would create the biggest <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> local phone <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>.
The spins: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) Merger mania continues. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) This merger brings <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ma Bell</ENAMEX> back from
the dead by uniting <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> of her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baby Bells</ENAMEX> (spanning the West, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Southwest</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Midwest</ENAMEX>) and an additional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New England</ENAMEX> phone <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) Now <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AT&T</ENAMEX> will have
to buy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell Atlantic</ENAMEX>--which has already bought <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nynex</ENAMEX>--to form a rival phone
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">giant</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) So much for the competition we were supposed to get from the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>
            

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Aviation Administration</ENAMEX> has temporarily grounded old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boeing</ENAMEX> 737s
to inspect them for worn fuel tank wires. The first-day spin: What a nuisance
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">travelers</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>-day spin, after the inspections found that half the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">grounded</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX> had damaged wires like those suspected of causing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TWA</ENAMEX> 800
catastrophe: Don't panic; the wires are being fixed, and it's still safe to
fly. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">5/11/98</NUMEX>)
            

            White
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sidney Blumenthal</ENAMEX> apologized for calling <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hickman Ewing</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s deputy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX>, a "religious fanatic." <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Speaker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> and more than
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> had demanded that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> punish <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blumenthal</ENAMEX> for his
"religious intolerance." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief of Staff</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erskine Bowles</ENAMEX> said he had
discussed the transgression with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blumenthal</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blumenthal</ENAMEX> issued a written
statement saying, "I did not intend to offend Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ewing</ENAMEX>'s or anyone else's
personal religious beliefs and I regret if anyone feels offended."
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">5/11/98</NUMEX>)
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daimler-Benz</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler</ENAMEX> are merging. It's the largest industrial
merger to date, worth <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$35 billion to $40 billion</NUMEX>. The global spin: Merger mania
continues. The world auto industry is consolidating into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GM</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DaimlerChrysler</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Volkswagen</ENAMEX> (which appears to be buying <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rolls</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royce</ENAMEX>) in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toyota</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Honda</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>. The economic spin: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Foreigners</ENAMEX> continue buying <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> and endangering the jobs of their
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) Don't worry, there's little overlap between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daimler</ENAMEX> (which
makes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mercedes</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler</ENAMEX>, so nobody will be fired. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) Then what's the
point of merging? The union spin: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bosses</ENAMEX> are selling out
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) Wait a minute--we get to join forces with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX>, which
have even more clout and better benefits. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Workers</ENAMEX> of the world, unite!
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">5/8/98</NUMEX>)
            

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marine</ENAMEX> jet that killed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> by snapping a ski lift
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cable</ENAMEX> nearly struck the ski <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gondola</ENAMEX> in which they were riding, according to
testimony in a military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice</ENAMEX> hearing. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">jet</ENAMEX> allegedly came within <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">130 feet</NUMEX>
of hitting the gondola after flying just <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">300 to 500 feet</NUMEX> above the ground--well
below its permitted altitude--for <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">at least seven miles</NUMEX>, bolstering the theory
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX> was flying recklessly. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Crew members</ENAMEX> are charged with involuntary
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">manslaughter</ENAMEX>, negligent homicide, and other offenses. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">5/8/98</NUMEX>)
            

            New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York</ENAMEX>'s state supreme <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> denied a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> the right to implant her frozen
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">embryos</ENAMEX> in defiance of a contract she had signed with her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">then-husband</ENAMEX>.
Before their divorce, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> agreed their frozen <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">embryos</ENAMEX> could be used only
if both consented. A lower <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>, citing the right to procreate under <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Roe</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">vs. Wade</ENAMEX> , ruled that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> was entitled to "exclusive control over the
fate of her nonviable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fetus</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s high <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> disagreed. The superficial
spin: It's a defeat for <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Roe vs. Wade</ENAMEX> . The sophisticated spin: It's a
victory for the spirit of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roe</ENAMEX> , because the high court ruled that the
procreation decision had been rightly made by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX>--"not the state and
not the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX>"--through their contract. The pro-life spin: This means that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">embryos</ENAMEX> will be treated as just another contractually disposable commodity.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">5/8/98</NUMEX>)
            

            Judge
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norma Holloway Johnson</ENAMEX> rejected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s invocations of executive
privilege and attorney-client privilege to prevent interrogation of his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisers</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> affair. The spins: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) This means <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Lindsey</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sidney Blumenthal</ENAMEX> must testify. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) This ruling bodes ill for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s similar
invocation of presidential privilege to prevent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> testimony. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Starr</ENAMEX> is on a roll, having won <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> consecutive rulings from <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Judge</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> will appeal her decision to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>)
Comparisons to <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX> are resuming. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">5/6/98</NUMEX>)
            

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Burton</ENAMEX> follies continued. In the previous episode, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burton</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> investigation of the campaign finance scandal, was under
fire for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) releasing transcripts of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Webster Hubbell</ENAMEX>'s phone calls from jail
and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) omitting parts of the transcripts in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hubbell vouched for Hillary</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s innocence. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s episode, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burton</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) said he would bypass
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> objections by assigning the investigation's next step to a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>-stacked <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) reversed that decision, evidently at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Speaker</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX>'s behest; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) "accepted the resignation" of his chief <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigator</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Bossie</ENAMEX>, who is blamed for releasing the transcripts. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bossie</ENAMEX>
was fired. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Tribune</ENAMEX> called for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burton</ENAMEX>'s removal. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> groaned that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burton</ENAMEX> "once again lived up to his
caricature" as an overzealous idiot and pointed out that his real crime has
been to distract attention from the transcripts, which indicate that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">emissaries</ENAMEX>" encouraged <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hubbell</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> to fear their livelihood
depended on remaining silent about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintons</ENAMEX>' roles in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Whitewater</ENAMEX>.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">5/6/98</NUMEX>)
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Politicians</ENAMEX> of both
parties christened the new <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Building</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trade Center</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX> It is the biggest <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> government building,
aside from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX>, to have been erected, and it cost more than twice as
much as had been projected. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>-cynical spin: The joke is on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>,
because the building belies his rhetoric against big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. The fully
cynical spin: The joke is on us, because the building faithfully reflects
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>'s continuation of big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, despite his rhetoric.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">5/6/98</NUMEX>)
            

         
      
   
