
   
   
      
         
            

            A
gunman burst into the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Capitol</ENAMEX> and shot and killed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policemen</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russell Weston Jr.</ENAMEX>, lived in a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">shack 40 miles</NUMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Unabomber</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Montana</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cabin</ENAMEX>. He was wounded and captured. It appears <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> have managed to
save his life, which means he can be tried for murder in federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> and
possibly executed. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> launched into saturation-coverage mode focusing on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weston</ENAMEX>'s motive. The answer, paranoid <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">schizophrenia</ENAMEX>, is expected to provide
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weston</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">insanity</ENAMEX> defense. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Members</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> rushed forward to tell reporters
how close they had come to being in the vicinity and, thereby, to possibly
getting shot. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pundits</ENAMEX> pondered the dilemma between security and public access
to government <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Editorialists</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> blamed: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> of gun
laws (despite reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Weston</ENAMEX> stole the gun from his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) the mental
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hospital</ENAMEX> that discharged <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Weston</ENAMEX> after a nutty episode in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX>, for failing to take other previous nutty episodes
seriously. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">7/27/98</NUMEX>)
            

            
Independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Counsel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX> subpoenaed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to
testify before the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> grand jury. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Pundits</ENAMEX> think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> could delay the
investigation by refusing the subpoena and that he might even get it quashed on
the grounds that a sitting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> can't be forced to testify, but agree the
political cost of such a fight would be too high for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. (See "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pundit Central</ENAMEX>"
for more.) Instead, his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> are negotiating with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> over a less
embarrassing alternative. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> reportedly wants <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) to testify at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>, not at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courthouse</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) to limit the scope of the questions; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) to see
the questions in advance; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4</ENAMEX>) to answer in writing rather than orally; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5</ENAMEX>) to
have his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> present. Reports indicate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> is willing to give <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> the
first condition but none of the others. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Editorialists</ENAMEX> think this is a fair
deal. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">7/27/98</NUMEX>)
            

ruling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liberal Democratic Party</ENAMEX> selected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Foreign Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keizo Obuchi</ENAMEX>
to lead the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LDP</ENAMEX> and thereby become <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX>. The previous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX>
resigned after <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> seriously weakened the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LDP</ENAMEX>'s control of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parliament</ENAMEX>
because the economy is in shambles. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Obuchi</ENAMEX> promised to fix the economy by
cutting taxes and reforming the banking system. The pessimistic spins: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)
Obuchi can't turn around the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and the economy, because he is a dull
consensus-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">builder</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) even if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Obuchi</ENAMEX> were dynamic, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LDP</ENAMEX> has lost so many
seats it must now compromise with other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> to get anything done. The
optimistic spin: It will take a dull consensus <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">builder</ENAMEX> to compromise with the
other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> and get something done. (See "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International</ENAMEX>
Papers" for reactions from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>.) (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">7/27/98</NUMEX>)
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Press Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike McCurry</ENAMEX> announced he will leave this
fall. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Pundits</ENAMEX> agree this means the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> thinks <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is out
of the woods in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> scandal, so his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX> can finally depart for
lucrative private sector jobs without looking like <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX> deserting a sinking
ship. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX>, who depend on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press secretary</ENAMEX>'s good graces,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">lauded McCurry</ENAMEX>'s candor, nobility, and unfailing good humor in service to his
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and commenced sucking up to his designated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">successor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Lockhart</ENAMEX>.
Editorialists, who do not depend on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press secretary</ENAMEX>'s good graces, pointed
out that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCurry</ENAMEX> has helped <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> stonewall the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> scandal to death
while deliberately remaining ignorant of tawdry facts in order to preserve his
image of candor and nobility. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">7/27/98</NUMEX>)
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nigerian</ENAMEX> military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ruler Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abdulsalam Abubakar</ENAMEX> has called elections
for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early next year</TIMEX> and pledged to relinquish power to a civilian <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> by
May. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">editorialists</ENAMEX> protested the transition is too slow, but Nigerians
count themselves lucky, since previous "transitions" have been slower and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">illusory</ENAMEX>. The spins: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) The transition is a fraud, because <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nigerian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dictators</ENAMEX>
always lie. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) This time it will be different, because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abubakar</ENAMEX> seems like a
nice <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abubakar</ENAMEX> is such a nice <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> he must be a puppet for other, meaner
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generals</ENAMEX> who will cancel or annul the elections if they don't get their way.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">7/22/98</NUMEX>)
            

            Update
on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tawana Brawley</ENAMEX> defamation trial : <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rev.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Sharpton</ENAMEX>, who has
been found liable for defaming <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prosecutor Steven Pagones</ENAMEX> by accusing him of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">raping Brawley</ENAMEX>, refused to apologize and depicted the defamation suit as an
attempt to silence a brave civil rights <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">martyr</ENAMEX>, i.e., himself. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brawley</ENAMEX> may
face cross-examination in the damages phase of the trial, now that the judge
has ruled that one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defendants</ENAMEX> can call her as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX>. The superficial
spin: It's not fair to let her testify, since she failed to appear in previous
hearings. The sophisticated spin: The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defendants</ENAMEX> were counting on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> to
bar her testimony so they could claim she was being silenced. Instead, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> is calling their bluff. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">7/22/98</NUMEX>)
            

            Update
on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> investigation : <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prosecutors</ENAMEX> are interrogating
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">grand jury</ENAMEX>, reportedly about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
liaisons with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> and his meetings with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s chief
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodyguard</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Cockell</ENAMEX>, has been relieved of duty while he
faces questioning. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> has reportedly ordered <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Independent Counsel</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX> to show why he shouldn't be held in contempt of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> for
allegedly leaking to the press. This would force <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> to answer
questions and release documents, possibly derailing his investigation. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Ambassador</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Richardson</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> it was "very normal" for him to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">interview Lewinsky</ENAMEX> personally for a low-level job at the request of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> reportedly bought it. (For an analysis of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> endgame, click .) 
               (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">7/22/98</NUMEX>)
            

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">online virgins</ENAMEX> 
               scam has unraveled. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike</ENAMEX>" and "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diane</ENAMEX>," two
supposedly <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">virgins</ENAMEX> who were going to surrender their virginity live
on the Internet, have confessed they aren't <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18</TIMEX>, aren't <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">virgins</ENAMEX>, and aren't
planning to have sex. In a press conference before angry <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> at a condom
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">shop</ENAMEX>, they defended their stunt, saying it was meant to be "a moral lesson" and
"the biggest public service announcement ever" on behalf of safe sex and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">abstinence</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that was hired to transmit the event to computer users
says it was a money-making <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hoax</ENAMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike</ENAMEX>" and "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diane</ENAMEX>" said they hoped the event
would launch their careers. They announced their real names, which

                  Slate
                has mysteriously forgotten. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">7/22/98</NUMEX>)
            

            The
government is soliciting public reaction to a proposed national health
identification system . The simplest version would allow each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s
medical records to be accessed by inputting his or her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> number.
Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">insurers</ENAMEX> say it will help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> get past information about
their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> and will help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">administrators</ENAMEX> manage billing information for
insurance purposes. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> on the left and right joined the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Medical</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association</ENAMEX> in denouncing it as a threat to privacy. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Tribune</ENAMEX>
called it unnecessary, "frightening," and a violation of doctor-patient <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">trust</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> hopes to construct the database in a way that will satisfy
privacy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX>, but this seems impossible, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">since they 1</TIMEX>) oppose precisely
the easy access meant to justify the database and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) think <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">insurers</ENAMEX> will use
the information to discriminate against costly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">7/21/98</NUMEX>)
            

            Conservative and gay
rights <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX> have launched dueling ad campaigns about the ex-gay
movement . The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX>, borrowing from recent remarks by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>
Majority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Lott</ENAMEX>, argue homosexuality is an unhealthy lifestyle from
which many former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gays</ENAMEX> have successfully recovered. The gay rights <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> claim
the ex-gay movement is a public relations front for conservative efforts to
discriminate against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gays</ENAMEX>. (For an analysis of the strategic implications of
the debate, click .) 
               (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">7/21/98</NUMEX>)
            

         
      
   
