
   
   
      
         
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Springfield</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ore.</ENAMEX>, buried <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> killed by their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classmate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kip Kinkel</ENAMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cafeteria</ENAMEX> massacre . <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Politicians</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> debated the
meaning of it all. For a review of the arguments, click .
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">5/27/98</NUMEX>)
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Voters</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX> approved a peace plan . Among other things, the plan appeases
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholics</ENAMEX> by including <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern Ireland</ENAMEX> in an all-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">council</ENAMEX>, and it
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">appeases</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Protestants</ENAMEX> by abolishing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish Republic</ENAMEX>'s constitutional claim to
the majority <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Protestant North</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Editorialists</ENAMEX> cheered the vote as a rejection of
past violence and an embrace of peace and cooperation. Click for a
dissection of the hype behind the vote. 
               (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">5/26/98</NUMEX>)
            

            Judge
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norma Holloway Johnson</ENAMEX> ruled that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> cannot refuse to
testify before the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> grand jury about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s behavior. She
rejected the argument, advanced by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> and by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s surrogates, that this would endanger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidents</ENAMEX> by causing them to
evade the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX> who are supposed to protect them.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">5/26/98</NUMEX>)
            

            
Pro-democracy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> won the first legislative elections in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>
under <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> rule. The naive spin: The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">democrats</ENAMEX> won. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>-sophisticated
spin: The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">democrats</ENAMEX> get ripped off, because the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> rigged the election so
that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only half</NUMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">legislature</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">seats</ENAMEX> were available. The rest are chosen by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organizations</ENAMEX> from which most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> are excluded. The fully sophisticated
spin: Despite getting ripped off, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">democrats</ENAMEX> have secured a political base
from which to harass and embarrass the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">5/26/98</NUMEX>)
            

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> refused to hear a challenge to a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Carolina</ENAMEX>
child-endangerment law that has been used to prosecute pregnant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who
imperil their fetuses by using illegal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>. The challenge by pro-choice
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">groups</ENAMEX> was based on narrow arguments, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> are spinning the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>'s
action as a victory for fetal rights. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">5/26/98</NUMEX>)
            

            Retired
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">electrician</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Capaci</ENAMEX> won the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$195 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Powerball</ENAMEX> lottery .
It's the biggest lottery jackpot in world history, though after taxes it turns
out to be just <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $54 million</NUMEX>. The spins: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) Capaci on the moral of the
story--"All my life I worked and learned that I never got nothing for nothing"
... until the lottery proved him wrong. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) To his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adult children</ENAMEX>--"The only
reason I played the lottery was to give you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> a lift in life." <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) Since the
odds were <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">80 million-to-1</NUMEX> and everyone but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capaci</ENAMEX> lost, a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> math
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> calls lotteries "a tax on the mathematically challenged."
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">5/22/98</NUMEX>)
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Suharto</ENAMEX> resigned. He turned over power to his vice
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>/crony, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B.J. Habibie</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Reactions: 1</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Students</ENAMEX> cheered <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Suharto</ENAMEX>'s
resignation. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> praised the "peaceful transition." <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>'s stock market plummeted to a record low, signaling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>'
jitters about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Habibie</ENAMEX>'s flaky economic ideas. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">5/21/98</NUMEX>)
            

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> is debating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-</ENAMEX>tobacco bill . It would raise
the price of cigarettes (thereby ostensibly discouraging youth smoking) by
imposing <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">half a billion dollars</NUMEX> in fees on tobacco <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> to support
anti-smoking education, research, health care, and cessation programs. Thus
far, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> have offered amendments to cap <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>' fees (defeated) and
increase the price hike (defeated). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Pundits</ENAMEX> think the bill will pass
overwhelmingly. For a review of the spin contest, click .

               (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">5/21/98</NUMEX>)
            

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> voted almost unanimously to ban new <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> technology-transfer
deals while <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next month</TIMEX>. This marks the latest
escalation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican Party</ENAMEX>'s campaign to condemn <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> for allegedly
promoting technology trade with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> at the expense of national security.
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> money scandal. For an analysis of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> spin campaign,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">click</ENAMEX> . 
               (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">5/20/98</NUMEX>)
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Eighty</NUMEX> percent of pagers
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> were knocked out by a satellite malfunction in
space. The technophobic spin: This is what we get for relying on gadgets. The
technophilic spin: "Thank God for cell phones." (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">5/20/98</NUMEX>)
            

         
      
   
