
   
   
      
         
            Getting Bombed With <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>

            
               The Threat ,
produced for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> campaign by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don Sipple</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Century Media</ENAMEX>.

            Windows or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mac</ENAMEX>; download time, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">19 minutes</TIMEX> at 14.4K

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RealAudio</ENAMEX>; for sound only

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1964</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson</ENAMEX> for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> campaign produced the classic "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daisy Ad</ENAMEX>," which successfully cast
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">opponent Barry Goldwater</ENAMEX> as a nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">warmonger</ENAMEX> without even mentioning him by
name. The ad juxtaposed a little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> counting the petals on a flower with a
nuclear countdown/detonation and asked if <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> wouldn't feel safer with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LBJ</ENAMEX> as their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>.

            Now, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three decades later</TIMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> extract (esoteric) revenge with <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Threat</ENAMEX> for the spot
that has rankled them for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. Their ad portrays <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> who
is placing the same petal-plucking little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>--and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>--at
risk with his lax drug policies.

            After The Threat
aired, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> campaign gleefully revealed that the spot was a feint: It was
backed by <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">only a few</NUMEX> advertising dollars and a low time-buy. Its aim was to
provoke a hasty response from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> war <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>, and that is exactly what
happened. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> camp's rejoinder aired within <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> across the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>,
at a cost of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">millions of dollars</NUMEX>. But the feint also fooled the news media and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> spinmeisters. The ad was widely shown on the network news, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> on the talk-show circuit wheeled the verbal cannon toward the
drug issue. The effect was amplified by real news--a government report showing
a rise in teen-age <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> use.

            
               The Threat , the swan
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">song</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>--and now departed--media <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don Sipple</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murphy</ENAMEX>, is an opening salvo in the assault on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>. Shot in
documentary monochrome, The Threat moves from its defining
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>-with-flower" first scene to successive shots of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youngsters</ENAMEX> on a
playground using, buying, or being tempted by <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">narrator</ENAMEX> cites <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
incontrovertible facts as the front page of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Post</ENAMEX> ("TEEN
DRUG CRISIS") moves across the screen: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) "<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Teenage</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> use has doubled in the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last four years</TIMEX>"; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> cut the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of National Drug Control</ENAMEX>
Policy by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">83 percent</NUMEX>." In fact, this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>, an enclave of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>,
represents a barely detectable portion of the drug-policy budget. The effect of
the language, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">admakers</ENAMEX> hope, reaches far beyond its technical truth.

            As the parade of endangered
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> continues, the narrative glides explicitly to the character issue:
"And [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s] own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">surgeon general</ENAMEX> even considered legalizing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>." Though
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">surgeon general</ENAMEX> is long gone, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strategists</ENAMEX> assume that this is the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last</TIMEX> issue the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">campaign</ENAMEX> wants to discuss or respond to.

            As the spot concludes with a
very young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-ager</ENAMEX> about to light up, the narrator capitalizes on the public
perception that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is a weak waffler. The positive spin on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">waffling</ENAMEX> is that he is a moderate, pragmatic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX>. The negative spin is
that he suffers from character flaws. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> ad, naturally enough, pushes the
latter, and links <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s "weakness" to the drug war. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> said he'd
lead the war on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> and change <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>," the narrator says. "All he did was
change his mind." The Threat stimulates <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> to ask the question the
ad dare not raise directly: Is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> soft on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>--and on moral issues in
general?

            The ad
ends with an abbreviated nod to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>'s slogan, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Better Man</ENAMEX> for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Better</ENAMEX>
Future," as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">narrator</ENAMEX> asserts that "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> deserves better." Whether the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> deserve it or not, we're likely to hear a lot more in coming spots about
which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> is better--or worse. It may be a long-shot strategy, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> is far
behind.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Shrum</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
