
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Drug War</ENAMEX>

            
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News</ENAMEX> , produced
for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Friends</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phil Gramm</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alex Castellanos</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Media</ENAMEX>.

            Windows or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mac</ENAMEX>; download time, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">19 minutes</TIMEX> at 14.4K

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">;</ENAMEX> for sound only

            
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> Sen.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phil Gramm</ENAMEX>'s swipe at <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponent</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Victor Morales</ENAMEX>, is a standard
comparative ad in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapters</ENAMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Problem</ENAMEX>," "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Good Guy</ENAMEX>," and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bad Guy</ENAMEX>." It
opens with a favorite image from the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> political season, a black-and-white
close-up of a bag of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>. The narration implies that the reason <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are
using <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> is that we're not tough on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pushers</ENAMEX>, who get just "a slap on the
wrist." Valid or not, the view mirrors opinion polls. The language of the ad is
pretested, and this initial argument will encounter little voter resistance. A
subsequent image--a slow fade on a group of schoolkids, an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> flag behind
them--is a powerful <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. It tells us visually that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> we want is
fading away.

            Next, we see the Good
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guy</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phil Gramm</ENAMEX>. He's depicted in a photograph, not on film. During the
presidential primaries, ad tests showed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> reacted negatively to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gramm</ENAMEX>
speaking. So here he is, smiling, but in the safety of a still image. A shot of
a congressional bill and a blowup quote provide symbolic third-party
verification that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX> "has a plan" to get tough on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pushers</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gramm</ENAMEX>'s
picture promptly disappears, but its brief presence qualifies the ad for the
more lenient federal rules about "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>" spots: Such spots can't be
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">censored</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX> must sell the time at a lower "political" rate.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gramm</ENAMEX> maintains a presence
in the spot via a chyron (text on the screen): "The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Gramm Plan</ENAMEX>." This plan
consists, in part, of a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10-year</TIMEX> sentence with no parole for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pushers</ENAMEX>--another
pretested <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX> in polls. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> element of the plan--life sentences for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pushers</ENAMEX> who "exploit" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>--strikes another responsive chord by raising the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">specter</ENAMEX> of molestation. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Gramm Plan</ENAMEX> is accompanied by color film of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX> behind bars. Why color? Because in this spot, putting more offenders
in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">jail</ENAMEX> is a happy result.

            
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News</ENAMEX> now cuts to
a film clip of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morales</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">schoolteacher</ENAMEX> who won a stunning upset victory in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> primary. The clip cleverly gives the impression that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morales</ENAMEX> is
actually saying what's written on screen and sourced to a local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>: that he
opposes longer sentences as a deterrent against crime. The spot nails him as an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponent</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gramm</ENAMEX>'s get-tough approach, as a liberal softy. The red background
complements the negative text and images.

            Ironically, the spot
concludes by riffing on the slogan long used by liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard Metzenbaum</ENAMEX>
and adopted by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Dukakis</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Who's on your side?</ENAMEX>" The strategy
here: to invite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> to judge on the basis of social, not economic,
issues.

            
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News</ENAMEX> attempts to
set the campaign agenda. How can the underfunded <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Morales</ENAMEX> expect to raise issues
such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>, jobs, or education in his spots when he's tied down defending
himself against the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gramm</ENAMEX> blitz?

            
               The
News echoes and reinforces the message in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX>'s ads and speeches:
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> are weak on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>. No accident there: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News</ENAMEX> was produced by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alex Castellanos</ENAMEX>, one of the new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>'s media <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX>.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Shrum</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
