
   
   
      
         
            For <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Better</ENAMEX> or for Worse

            In one of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX>'s worst
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX>, his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth</ENAMEX> follows her brilliant performance at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican</ENAMEX>
Convention with a warm, well-filmed <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30-second</TIMEX> appeal on his behalf. The spot,
called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth</ENAMEX> , was produced by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alex Castellanos</ENAMEX>. He's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Helms</ENAMEX>'
ex-media <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, and this ad proves that his style surely does change with his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX>. Normally, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouse</ENAMEX>'s endorsement spot doesn't do much beyond making a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> feel good. If your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> isn't for you, who is? But
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Dole</ENAMEX>'s poll ratings and communication skills decisively exceed her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s. In fact, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pollster</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Luntz</ENAMEX> reports that his focus
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> show that the convention bounce was for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth</ENAMEX>, not Bob
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Visually</ENAMEX>, the spot creates
the sense of a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one-on-one</NUMEX> conversation between each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewer</ENAMEX> and the appealing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> in the soft yellow suit who's sitting casually in what appears to be her
living <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>. The smooth, slow camera <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">movement</ENAMEX> through the spot imparts a degree
of visual variety without disturbing the intimate mood. The surface simplicity
of the scene belies the sheer weight of the spot's message. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth</ENAMEX>
attempts to make <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> separate points, all of them critical to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>
campaign.

            The would-be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">first lady</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> vouches for her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s integrity--and by implication, points to the
contrast with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>. The spot is intentionally ladylike, a positive
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">oasis</ENAMEX> in a desert of attack ads on both sides. But it, too, is intended to be
negative: phrases like "doing what's right" and "living up to his word" play
off much-surveyed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voter</ENAMEX> doubts about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth</ENAMEX> next tries
to deal with one of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>'s central political weaknesses, a gender gap that
leaves him <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">as much as 25</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX> points behind among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>. So this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>,
successful in her own right, and except for her politics a poster <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> for the
"Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Generation</ENAMEX>," tells us that her "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>" has strong commitments on
domestic violence and equal retirement benefits for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>.

            But the spot doesn't linger
here. It moves swiftly and smoothly to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>'s most fundamental problem, his
loss of credibility on the tax issue. In part because his campaign ads dealt in
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weeks</TIMEX> after the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Republican Convention</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>
increasingly bought into the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> definitions of the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">15 percent</NUMEX> tax
cut--that it's probably phony, and almost certainly wouldn't happen even if
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> got elected. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth</ENAMEX> reminds us that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX> does what he does
"because it's right"--another <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">JFK</ENAMEX> line, straight out of the inaugural address.
Here, the line tweaks our now-collective memory of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>'s war service and
suggests that he wouldn't propose the tax cut simply because it was easy or
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">politic</ENAMEX>. "You can count on it," we hear straight from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth</ENAMEX>, "because it's
right for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>."

            Does this really reassure
us? It helps. After all, would this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> lie to us? And we know she's too smart
to be fooled. Just for insurance, she returns to the implicit comparison with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX> doesn't make promises he can't keep." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth</ENAMEX>
argues that we can trust <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> more--or at least distrust him less. The
sharpness of the message woven through the softness of the image recalls <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carl</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sandburg</ENAMEX>'s description of someone as "a steel fist in a velvet glove."

            This spot
concludes with footage of the empty <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kansas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">prairie</ENAMEX>, the place <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX> comes
from, where, as he said in his acceptance speech, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> is very small against
the sky. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>, the picture says again, is from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">heartland</ENAMEX>, the land of plain
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">virtue</ENAMEX> and truth-telling. The empty sky here leaves room for the words he wants
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to decide are true: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX> will cut our taxes." This last scene is
curiously disconnected from the preceding conversation with our friend
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth</ENAMEX>." Despite the ad<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">-maker</ENAMEX>'s intention, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewer</ENAMEX> may decide that the
winding two-lane road of the scene leads only to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>'s bridge to the past. But
whatever the outcome, the spot artfully--and literally--puts the best face on a
tough sale.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Shrum</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
