
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Slates You Can Wear</ENAMEX>

            
               Hotel <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Ballroom</ENAMEX> ,
produced by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Wolfe</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff Iorillo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Corey Stolberg</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Gondell</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foote, Cone & Belding</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX>.

            The inevitabilities of age
dictate that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Generation Xers</ENAMEX> grow up, get a job, and go places--whether they
want to or not. But <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the age-old</TIMEX> question remains: What to wear? This spot,
Hotel <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Ballroom</ENAMEX> , produced for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Levi Strauss</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foote, Cone & Belding</ENAMEX>,
suggests to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gen-Xers</ENAMEX> that your pants can have the same attitude as you--still
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">young</ENAMEX> (they're <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Levi's</ENAMEX>, but not jeans), and a good fit; comfortable in your own
identity, yet at ease in the establishment world. Well, just enough to get
by.

            At <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> look, we don't know
what the ad's about. We see a twentysomething <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>, wearing a tie but no coat
(it's in the garment bag--wear it only when you have to), entering a grand
hotel. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lobby</ENAMEX>, which is shot in black and white, possesses a grandeur seldom
seen <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> outside beaux-arts train <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stations</ENAMEX>. There's a sense of
something older in this space, but not of the past. It's the time-space of
grown-up commitments, where the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gen-Xer</ENAMEX> has to live--at least part time. Maybe
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">color</ENAMEX> is reserved for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nights</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekends</TIMEX>. But even in the black-and-white
world, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Gen-X</ENAMEX> attitude is still evident. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clerk</ENAMEX>, initially seen upside
down, hints at a world turned on its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>.

            As the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> in the pants
approaches the desk, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clerk</ENAMEX> accepts that he belongs. Like the pants, our
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> fits--but in his own way. With a wan smile, he asks for the phone. The
clerk <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>-reluctantly points it out. He can't question the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gen-Xer</ENAMEX>, who's
carrying an attaché case; this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> could be anything, even a young computer
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mogul</ENAMEX>.

            As he strides toward the
phone, we hear the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">narrator</ENAMEX>'s voice for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first time</TIMEX>: "You know those pants
that always fit ..." But our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> doesn't find the phone; he gets a little
lost. This world may accept him as fitting in--but he's in it, not of it. He's
kind of an innocent abroad--innocent, of course, in a limited sense. He wanders
into a political rally and ends up on stage. We see the scene from the
Gen-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Xer</ENAMEX>'s perspective: the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX>'s evident insincerity (aren't all
politics staged and phony?) and the endemic irrelevance of the proceedings. Our
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX>'s demeanor speaks volumes, as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX> shakes his hand and photos
are taken as mementos of this nonevent. But he does fit in--if only for a
moment and in his own way--before extricating himself and moving on.

            Almost Zelig-like in the
succeeding scenes, he continues to fit in without getting permanently trapped.
He backs across the stage toward a podium where they are giving out awards; is
this a case of mistaken award-giving, or is he just a reluctant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX>? He's
too young, and there are too many self-congratulatory award ceremonies anyway,
the ad seems to say.

            In another scene, he fits
into a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">wedding</TIMEX> ("There you are," the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> says); but at least he's not
the groom--he's not yet dressed in one of those (rented) black-tie outfits that
never seem to fit. The background for the picture is a painted outdoor scene.
That's where he'd rather be. Instead, he's suddenly in the hotel <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hallway</ENAMEX> again.
Hands on hips, he pauses, then strides toward another of those situations in
which maturing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gen-Xers</ENAMEX> will inevitably find themselves, as we hear the only
other bit of narration in the spot: "These are those pants ... these are
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slates</ENAMEX>." The hotel <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clerk</ENAMEX>'s hand hits the bell, summoning a bellhop to take our
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> to his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>--or is it a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">suite</ENAMEX>? What happened to the garment bag or
briefcase? Did he check them? Did he ever find the phone--and where's his
cellular?

            At the end, we glimpse once
more the rich wood-paneled <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hallway</ENAMEX>. Does it lead to a dead end, or to a
doorway? Whatever it is, the ad seems to say, you can go there wearing your
Slates, and still be yourself.

            You can
write what you want on a slate; it isn't just a copybook. You can go where you
have to wearing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slates</ENAMEX>, without losing your identity. You're still wearing
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Levi's</ENAMEX>, even if you're the only one who knows it. In their world, you're still
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Gen-X</ENAMEX>, and you still see it all the same way--mostly.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Shrum</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
