
   
   
      
         
            

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Education Association</ENAMEX> voted not to merge with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federation of Teachers</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NEA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">delegates</ENAMEX> who opposed the merger welcomed the vote
as a reaffirmation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NEA</ENAMEX>'s dignified professionalism. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Conservatives</ENAMEX>
welcomed it as a reaffirmation of the feud between the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NEA</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFT</ENAMEX>, which
cripples both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX>' resistance to school privatization. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">7/6/98</NUMEX>)
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Protestant</ENAMEX> strife flared again in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern Ireland</ENAMEX>. British
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">troops</ENAMEX> blocked the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Orangemen</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Protestant</ENAMEX> fraternal order, from marching
through a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> neighborhood. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Orangemen</ENAMEX> threatened to call a general
strike, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> agreed to let them stage another march in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belfast</ENAMEX> next
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Protestants</ENAMEX> called the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> blockade a violation of their right to
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">march</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Catholics</ENAMEX> called the march a violation of their right not to be marched
on. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Outsiders</ENAMEX> called the confrontation a test of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern Ireland</ENAMEX> Peace
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Accord</ENAMEX>. (
                  Slate
               's "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International</ENAMEX>
Papers" samples local coverage of the brouhaha.) (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">7/6/98</NUMEX>)
            

            Sports
news: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pete Sampras</ENAMEX> won his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Wimbledon</ENAMEX> title. This ties Bjorn
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Borg</ENAMEX>'s record for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wimbledon</ENAMEX> championships and brings <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sampras</ENAMEX> within <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> victory
of tying the record for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Grand Slam</ENAMEX> championships. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jana Novotna</ENAMEX>
won the women's championship, overcoming her history of choking in the finals.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holland</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Croatia</ENAMEX> reached the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World Cup</ENAMEX> semifinals.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX> is the favorite. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Croatia</ENAMEX> is the soccer tournament's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cinderella</ENAMEX>, becoming
the first <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30 years</TIMEX> to reach the semifinals in its <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World Cup</ENAMEX>.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">7/6/98</NUMEX>)
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> said on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> television that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s government
should continue to pursue "openness and freedom" but that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
should not simply "tell other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> what to do." <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Analysts</ENAMEX> noted that this
equivocation echoed earlier remarks at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s televised joint press
conference with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang Zemin</ENAMEX>, in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> said of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tiananmen Square</ENAMEX> massacre, "I believe, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> believe, that
the use of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> and the tragic loss of life was wrong." ( For a roundup of
spins on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> trip, click . 
               
                  Slate
                also surfs through
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>. Click here. Also see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Papers</ENAMEX> for reactions from around the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">globe</ENAMEX>.) (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">7/2/98</NUMEX>)
            

            A
federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> threw out <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Independent Counsel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>'s tax evasion case
against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Webster Hubbell</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Robertson</ENAMEX> ruled that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) prosecutors
unconstitutionally forced <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hubbell</ENAMEX> to incriminate himself (by using documents
they got from him under a grant of immunity) and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> exceeded his
authority by going "<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">six degrees</NUMEX> of relationship" beyond the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitewater S</ENAMEX> &
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L</ENAMEX> case to nail <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hubbell</ENAMEX> on the far more recent tax charge. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX>
drew attention to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robertson</ENAMEX>'s description of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX>' tactics as
"scary" and a "fishing expedition." The anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> spins: This confirms <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s
public image as a reckless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">zealot</ENAMEX> and removes the leverage he had hoped to use
to make <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hubbell</ENAMEX> rat on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. The pro-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> spins: This ruling doesn't void
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> investigation and, anyway, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> will get it overturned on appeal.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">7/2/98</NUMEX>)
            

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> crisis is worsening . <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serb</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> have recaptured a region of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">province</ENAMEX> (which they officially control, though its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">90</NUMEX>-percent
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Albanian</ENAMEX>) in heavy fighting with the ethnic-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kosovo Liberation Army</ENAMEX>.
The old spin, articulated by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> : <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serb</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">strongman Slobodan Milosevic</ENAMEX> is up to his old brutality and, if another <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX>
is to be averted, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> must quickly impose a no-fly zone and threaten
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">airstrikes</ENAMEX>. The new spin, explained by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> : The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> is becoming less concerned about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> and more concerned about the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KLA</ENAMEX>, which is proving stronger and more dangerous than expected, particularly
since it seems to be taking an ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nationalist</ENAMEX> interest in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX> of adjacent <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">provinces</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>. (In 
                  Slate
               : <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laura</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kay Rozen</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dispatches</ENAMEX>" from the scene, an "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Assessment</ENAMEX>" of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>, and a "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Gist</ENAMEX>" on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>.) (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">7/1/98</NUMEX>)
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alabama</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fob James Jr.</ENAMEX> won a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> gubernatorial runoff over
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">businessman Winton Blount III</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian conservatives</ENAMEX> called it a mandate for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> conservatism <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James</ENAMEX> has championed. The national media consoled
themselves by arguing that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) turnout was low, except among <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James</ENAMEX> made a last-minute racial appeal by airing an ad that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">paired Blount</ENAMEX> with black <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Birmingham</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Arrington</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) the primary
exposed and exacerbated the national <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> feud between social and
economic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX>; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> gubernatorial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominee</ENAMEX> will
capitalize on this in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">7/1/98</NUMEX>)
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ezer Weizman</ENAMEX> blamed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin Netanyahu</ENAMEX>
for blocking the peace process and urged him to call early elections. "Bibi
lives in a state of euphoria, in his own world, cut off from reality," said
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weizman</ENAMEX>. Although <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weizman</ENAMEX> lacks the authority to order early elections, he is
sufficiently popular that his criticism undermines <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX>'s public support.
A new poll shows <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israelis</ENAMEX> favoring early elections <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50-to</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">39 percent</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Netanyahu</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">accused Weizman</ENAMEX> of siding "with the left" and "strengthening" the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arabs</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">allies</ENAMEX> demanded <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weizman</ENAMEX>'s resignation. Eventually the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>
met and agreed to keep their criticisms private. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">7/1/98</NUMEX>)
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Fallows</ENAMEX>
announced he is being ousted as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News & World Report</ENAMEX> .
He will be replaced by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Journal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Editor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen G. Smith</ENAMEX>. Fallows
said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mort Zuckerman</ENAMEX> wanted him out because they
disagreed on what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> should cover, particularly when it came to
"celebrity news" such as the murder of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gianni Versace</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cynics</ENAMEX>' translation:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zuckerman</ENAMEX> is a shallow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fool</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News Editorial</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Evans</ENAMEX>
asserted that he, not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zuckerman</ENAMEX>, made the decision. "I have not been known
simply to be a lap <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evans</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cynics</ENAMEX>' translation: Only a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">lapdog</ENAMEX> feels
obliged to deny he's a lap <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Journalists</ENAMEX> tried to enjoy <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zuckerman</ENAMEX>'s
egomaniacal self-destruction but were restrained by contempt for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fallows</ENAMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sanctimony</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">7/1/98</NUMEX>)
            

         
      
   
