
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dope on Dole</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> campaign answers
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> ads that lambasted the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> as soft on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>'s Real
Record , which efficiently portrays the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> as a ghoulish,
sloganeering, anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid politician</ENAMEX>.

            Juxtaposed with the opening
shot of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-ager</ENAMEX> sitting on a curb is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>, in grainy and smeared video
footage that obviously has been blown up. The colors are off, giving him a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sickly</ENAMEX> look, and the narration all but mocks his delivery of his neo-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nike</ENAMEX>
anti-drug slogan: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Just Don't Do It</ENAMEX>."

            Next, we see a staple of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s drug ads--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> gathered in a school <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hallway</ENAMEX>. They're smiling, but
for how long? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>'s anti-drug slogan aside, the narrator informs us, he voted
"to cut the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s school anti-drug efforts." With that, the grim <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>
returns in black and white, and we're told that he voted against the creation
of a drug <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">czar</ENAMEX>.

            Suddenly the spot
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pivots</ENAMEX>--with no visual, verbal, or musical cue--from the subject of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> to
other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX>-related issues. The classic structure of response spots is to
answer an attack briefly and then shift the debate to stronger ground.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Real Record</ENAMEX> does this with such ease that we hardly notice the
transition. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">narrator</ENAMEX> tells us that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> voted against student loans,
against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s plan to limit tobacco ads aimed at <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>, and against the
vaccines-for-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> program. "That's the real <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX> record, ... one
slogans can't hide," says the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">narrator</ENAMEX>. Not only does this layer of varnish
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">paint Dole</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-</ENAMEX>education and anti-middle class, but the visuals give him
the politically unprized patina of old age.

            Illustrating the charge that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> voted against <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vaccines</ENAMEX> is a soulful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> with big, staring
eyes--an image right out of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter Keene</ENAMEX> painting. Her gaze <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reproaches</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>
not only for this vote, but for all we have seen and heard in the spot.

            When we return to a
scolding, finger-pointing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> growling, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Just Don't Do It</ENAMEX>," the slogan carries
a new meaning--that he just shouldn't have voted against the "pro-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>"
legislation and that we just shouldn't vote for him. And if not for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>, then
for whom? The spot closes with a cameo of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> that qualifies it for the
political ad rate on TV <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>--as always, in color--is shown
with one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> he allegedly is protecting from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>'s policies.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>'s
Real Record successfully broadens the issues beyond <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> and asks, "Which
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> is more caring<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>" As the spot unspools, its strategy becomes clear:
When you make a response ad, don't do just <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Shrum</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
