
   
   
      
         
            

            In
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kyoto</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">delegates</ENAMEX> from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">159</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> approved a treaty to reduce global
warming . Over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next 15 years</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, along with other
industrialized <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX>, must cut its emissions of greenhouse <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gases</ENAMEX> to a level
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one-third</NUMEX> below its currently projected output. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX>
called it "the most significant multinational agreement ever on the world's
environment." The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> praised the agreement while admitting
it faced immediate gridlock: Developing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> refuse to reduce their
emissions until industrialized <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> do so, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Senate</ENAMEX> refuses to
ratify the treaty until developing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> sign on. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">12/12</NUMEX>)
            

            A
federal judge ordered <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> to stop requiring computer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">makers</ENAMEX> to
bundle its Internet browser with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Windows</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> hasn't decided whether
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> violated antitrust laws, as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX> contends, but he
ordered the halt just to make sure that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> doesn't devour the browser
market while the case is in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX>'s spin: "Starting
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX>, choice will be restored to the public." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s spin: 'Tis but a
scratch. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Netscape</ENAMEX>'s spin: 'Tis but the first scratch. The superficial analysis:
It's just a temporary order. The intermediate analysis: It will probably be in
effect until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at least June</TIMEX>, screwing up the release of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Windows 98</ENAMEX>, which was
supposed to merge <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s browser and operating system. The advanced
analysis: Computer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">makers</ENAMEX> will keep bundling the browser with Windows anyway,
because it's free. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">12/12</NUMEX>)
            

            A grand
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> indicted former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Housing</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Cisneros</ENAMEX> on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX> felony
relate to his efforts to cover up an extramarital affair. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Defenders</ENAMEX> say the
affair is private and old news. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> argue that while the affair may be
private, the cover-up isn't. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX> heaped might-have-beens on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cisneros</ENAMEX>.
"There was a tragic element to his life story," waxed the New York
Times . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cisneros</ENAMEX> is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton Cabinet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> to be
indicted--following <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agriculture</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Espy</ENAMEX>--and would have been the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX>, if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commerce</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Brown</ENAMEX> hadn't died in a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> crash. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">12/12</NUMEX>)
            

            Update
on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Arlington National Cemetery</ENAMEX> 
               scandal : <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) Former <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Ambassador</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Switzerland</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Lawrence</ENAMEX> was dug up and removed from the
cemetery along with his tombstone, which, according to the New York
Times , "was engraved with lies" about his putative war injury. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editorialists</ENAMEX> want further investigation to determine how
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lawrence</ENAMEX> got in and what the rules are. (
                  Slate
                dug up the
details: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">See the "Cheat Sheet</ENAMEX>" titled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Arlington National Cemetery: Dying</ENAMEX> to get in?
Here's how.") <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) A former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Burton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ind.</ENAMEX>, who had expressed
outrage over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lawrence</ENAMEX>, says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burton</ENAMEX> got a similar burial waiver for a former
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX> who had never served in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX>. The old spin: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Did Lawrence</ENAMEX> get a
break in the vetting process because he was a big political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donor</ENAMEX>? The new
spin: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Politicians</ENAMEX> are exploiting the scandal for partisan advantage rather than
facing up to bipartisan abuse of military privileges. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">12/12</NUMEX>)
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">House</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> interrogated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney General</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Reno</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louis</ENAMEX>
Freeh about the campaign-finance scandal. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Freeh</ENAMEX> refused to
criticize each other or to discuss the memo in which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freeh</ENAMEX> had advised <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX> to
seek an independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pundits</ENAMEX> expressed disappointment but no surprise
at the lack of bloodshed. The spins: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX> wins again. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) The hearing was a
distraction from newly released notes suggesting that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>
counted on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Election Commission</ENAMEX>'s inability to enforce
campaign-finance laws. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) The phone-call issue was a distraction from the
soft-money-abuse and conflict-of-interest issues that truly demand an
independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) The independent-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> question is a distraction from
the question of whether <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> will continue to pursue <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>) The whole investigation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s means of winning re-election is a
distraction from the real scandal: that he intends to do nothing with the job.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">12/10</NUMEX>)
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oracle</ENAMEX>'s stock plummeted <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">29 percent</NUMEX>, breaking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASDAQ</ENAMEX>'s official
single-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> trading volume record. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Ellison</ENAMEX> lost <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $2</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">billion</NUMEX> on paper. The reason: a disappointing earnings report. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oracle</ENAMEX> blamed
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX>'s woes and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> market saturation. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Analysts</ENAMEX> debated whether this bodes ill
for the whole technology sector. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Contrarians</ENAMEX> called it a buying opportunity.
The spins: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tech</ENAMEX> stocks have climbed too far, too fast, and are due for a
fall. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tech</ENAMEX> stocks climb and fall too fast because their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> are too
emotional. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> regard <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oracle</ENAMEX>'s wager on network computers (an
alternative to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCs</ENAMEX>) as a wasteful distraction. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">12/10</NUMEX>)
            

            It's
open <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) Moderate <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> that boycotted a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>-sponsored conference <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX> are attending a
global <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Islamic</ENAMEX> conference hosted by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>, whose supreme <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cleric</ENAMEX> opened the
meeting with a denunciation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and its military presence in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Persian Gulf</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Optimists</ENAMEX> focused on the more pluralistic, pro-Western speech
by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louis Farrakhan</ENAMEX> opened his world "friendship" tour by
visiting <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> in defiance of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s objections. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) In response
to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madeleine Albright</ENAMEX>'s expressions of impatience with
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>'s alleged failure to fulfill the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oslo</ENAMEX> accords, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX> declared that "no external pressures" will make <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> budge.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">12/10</NUMEX>)
            

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Medical Association</ENAMEX> proposed to legalize doctor-patient discussion of
the possible benefits of medical marijuana . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AMA</ENAMEX> also urged the
government to facilitate grant applications for studies on medical marijuana,
including access to marijuana supplies. The story was overshadowed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AMA</ENAMEX>'s
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">messy</TIMEX> divorce from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunbeam</ENAMEX> and its forswearing of all product endorsements.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">12/10</NUMEX>)
            

            
Miscellany: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Businesses</ENAMEX> and many calling-card <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> are now being charged <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">28</NUMEX>
cents for each pay-phone call to an <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">800</ENAMEX> number . Consumer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> call
it a betrayal of the "toll-free" promise. Others respond that deregulation is
properly making <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> bear the cost of these calls. Former federal drug <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">czar</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee Brown</ENAMEX> was elected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX>. The national media touted him as
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> nonwhite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> but conceded that he will change almost
nothing. The latest uproar against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s racial-dialogue
project concerns a meeting in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>, moderated by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Transportation</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodney Slater</ENAMEX>, to which only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> were invited. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> said it was a
boo-boo and "won't be repeated." (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">12/8</NUMEX>)
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> changed
the mission of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> nuclear-weapons policy . The old mission: waging
nuclear war against a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">superpower</ENAMEX>. The new mission: deterring nuclear,
biological, or chemical warfare by lesser powers (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">formalizing</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s
implicit warning to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX> during the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gulf War</ENAMEX>). <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> consequence is
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> needs fewer land-based nukes since it is no longer
planning all-out war with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>. Meanwhile, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> is debating whether to cut
its conventional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> and authorize first use of its nukes as a substitute
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">deterrent</ENAMEX> (as the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> will still do). (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">12/8</NUMEX>)
            

         
      
   
