
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner Brothers</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lisa</ENAMEX> , produced by
Trippi, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McMahon</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Squier</ENAMEX>

            Of course, they aren't
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">brothers</ENAMEX>, but <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warners</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX>--are running
against each other in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John's Senate</ENAMEX> seat. On the surface, this
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">60-second</TIMEX> ad for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark</ENAMEX> is what political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultants</ENAMEX> call a "bio spot."
Underneath, however, it is an implicit "comparative" in which every favorable
item about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark</ENAMEX> is an unspoken (for the moment) push off against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>. The spot
attempts to define the race; it's a road map to where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark</ENAMEX>'s campaign intends
to go.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX> is older (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">69</NUMEX>) and a
career <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">31 years</TIMEX> in public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX> of them in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mark</ENAMEX>
is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">41</NUMEX> and a high-tech <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entrepreneur</ENAMEX>. The spot begins with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mark</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>,
emphasizing that he's created a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">multimillion dollar</NUMEX> business. He's trying, in
effect, to give <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX> a gold watch, to cast him as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past</TIMEX>--a
strategy often discussed in politics but seldom fully executed, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">challengers</ENAMEX>
usually turn to harder-edged negatives. Here <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark</ENAMEX> is graphically portrayed as
the future; the spot tells us this visually, not only with his looks but
with its look, right down to the cyberesque chyrons--the writing on
screen--and the moving cursor.

            Both <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark</ENAMEX> are
wealthy. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> hunt <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and the former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> of both a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mellon</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">heiress</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Taylor</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark</ENAMEX>, the spot tells us, is different:
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> in his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> to college, which was paid for with loans and part-time
jobs. His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lisa</ENAMEX> vouches for his effort to keep that old car running and pay
off the student loans (polls show that if you had them, you better have paid
them). This "common <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>" theme is also a pre-emptive defense. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark</ENAMEX> will spend
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">dollars</NUMEX> of his own money against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>, the odds-on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">favorite</ENAMEX> who
also has the clear fund-raising advantage. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark</ENAMEX> wants <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> to know that
he earned <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">every penny</NUMEX> himself.

            A skeptical electorate
tends to resist claims made in political ads. So as this spot returns to the
present, it relies on an increasingly standard technique: It invokes
third-party verifiers--independent journalistic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>--to tell <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark</ENAMEX> deserves credit for "building the information <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">highway</ENAMEX>." A <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> source is
used to prop up this improbable claim, while a short-sleeved <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark</ENAMEX> casually
reaches over a workstation in a postmodern <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>.

            Now the spot moves from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark</ENAMEX> the private-sector <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">innovator</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark</ENAMEX> the public-policy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">innovator</ENAMEX> in health
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">care</ENAMEX>. The images convey a sense of compassion and inclusion: The young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>
cares about the elderly and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minorities</ENAMEX>. And again, the implicit comparison with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John: Mark</ENAMEX> has new ideas--and even better for a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX>, they're not about big
government, but about a "public-private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partnership</ENAMEX>."

            Finally, the spot weaves
together the "common <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>" theme (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark</ENAMEX> himself replays it to camera), the
"future" theme (watch the blinking cursor), and a visual and verbal appeal to
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>" values. With this, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark</ENAMEX> is fishing for stray conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>
increasingly alienated from the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">twice</NUMEX>-divorced, now unmarried <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>, who is
pro-choice on abortion, voted against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarence Thomas</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>,
and adamantly opposed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oliver North</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> bid.

            Is that the subliminal
message of the slogan: "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Right Warner</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Future</ENAMEX>"? Just
kidding--the operative word here is "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Future</ENAMEX>."

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Shrum</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
