
   
   
      
         
            

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Bulls</ENAMEX> won their <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">sixth</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Basketball Association</ENAMEX> championship in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight years</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Jordan</ENAMEX> nailed the game-winning jump shot with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">seconds</TIMEX> left, cementing his legacy as the greatest clutch <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">performer</ENAMEX> of all
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>. Sports <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> gave the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bulls</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a few seconds</TIMEX> to celebrate before
bombarding them with questions about whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sidekick</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scottie Pippen</ENAMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phil Jackson</ENAMEX> will return to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bulls</ENAMEX> or disband the dynasty. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jordan</ENAMEX>
worshippers debated whether he should retire on this perfect note or return in
pursuit of even greater perfection. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cynics</ENAMEX> advised him to retire before the
impending salary-cap war between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> brings the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBA</ENAMEX> to a
grinding halt. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">6/15/98</NUMEX>)
            

            
Independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Counsel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX> confirmed he and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX> had briefed
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> on a not-for-attribution basis on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> case.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brill's Content</ENAMEX> , a new media <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>, broke the story. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Publisher Steven</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brill</ENAMEX> says the briefings violated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX> ethical guidelines because
some of the information came from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> who were about to give the same
testimony to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">grand jury</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> rejects this interpretation of the
guidelines and says he is authorized to brief <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> whenever necessary to
"counter misinformation" and "engender confidence in the work of this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX> are demanding an investigation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s conduct.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">6/15/98</NUMEX>)
            

            

               Sunbeam <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Chainsaw</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dunlap</ENAMEX> , who earned his reputation and wealth
by firing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> because they weren't helping the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s bottom line, was
fired because he wasn't helping the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s bottom line. "A taste of his own
medicine," clucked the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> . (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plotz</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Assessment</ENAMEX>" of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dunlap</ENAMEX> and here for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">James</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Surowiecki</ENAMEX>'s analysis of how <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dunlap</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">darkened</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sunbeam</ENAMEX>'s future.)
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">6/15/98</NUMEX>)
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>
is planning military exercises in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Albania</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Macedonia</ENAMEX> to deter further
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> aggression against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> . Background: <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yugoslav</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> (read:
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strongman</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan Milosevic</ENAMEX> has launched a military assault on ethnic
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebels</ENAMEX> who seek <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kosovar</ENAMEX> (read: ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanian</ENAMEX>) independence from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX>. Lots of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have been killed or left homeless. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ministers</ENAMEX>
say the exercises are designed to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) scare <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) allow <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> to avoid
actual military involvement. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Skeptics</ENAMEX> argue that this is a contradiction. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> doesn't want to undertake a military commitment in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> because
this is a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">election year</TIMEX>. (
                  Slate
               's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Gist</ENAMEX>" gives you a
backgrounder on the conflict, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laura Kay Rozen</ENAMEX> is filing "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dispatches</ENAMEX>" from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>.) (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">6/12/98</NUMEX>)
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mitsubishi</ENAMEX> agreed to settle a sexual harassment suit for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$34 million</NUMEX> ,
triple the previous record for such a suit. The case involved <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">300</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> at an
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX> auto <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Equal Employment Opportunity Commission</ENAMEX>, which
negotiated the settlement, says it will scare other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> into enforcing
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX>-tolerance policies on sexual harassment. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Skeptics</ENAMEX> argued that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mitsubishi</ENAMEX>
got off easy. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">6/12/98</NUMEX>)
            

            Local
and federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> are looking for grounds to execute the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX>
charged with the vicious murder of a disabled black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, who have been linked to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KKK</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aryan Brotherhood</ENAMEX>, allegedly
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">chained James Byrd Jr.</ENAMEX> to a pickup <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> and dragged him <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">two miles</NUMEX>, tearing him
to pieces. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">district attorney</ENAMEX> wants to justify the death penalty by adding
an additional felony charge, such as kidnapping. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> wants to charge the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> with violating <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Byrd</ENAMEX>'s civil rights. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> spin: Who'da thunk it could
happen here? The out-of-state spin: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> is in denial about its racism. The
high-minded spin: The whole <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> is in denial. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-</ENAMEX>media spin: Why do
we treat school shootings as a national epidemic but dismiss racial killings as
isolated incidents? (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">6/11/98</NUMEX>)
            

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> heard arguments on whether the attorney-client privilege
continues after the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">client</ENAMEX> is dead. (
                  Slate
               's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Explainer</ENAMEX>" ponders the
question.) Independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Counsel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX> asked the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> to strip this
privilege from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vince Foster</ENAMEX>, the late deputy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX>, so <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> can
see notes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Foster</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> took from a conversation with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Foster</ENAMEX> days
before the latter's death. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> thinks the notes may indicate that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> or others lied under oath about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Travelgate</ENAMEX>. He argues that the
privilege has already been curbed in some cases. Liberal editorialists replied
that a victory for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> would unacceptably deter other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> from speaking
honestly to their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>, and they predicted the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> will see it their way.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">6/11/98</NUMEX>)
            

            
Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Drudge</ENAMEX> is charming his way into the punditocracy.
Previously vilified for inaccuracy and recklessness, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drudge</ENAMEX> is drawing
favorable reviews <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> following a recent speech at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Press</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Club</ENAMEX>. To learn how <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drudge</ENAMEX> is rehabilitating his image, click .

               (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">6/10/98</NUMEX>)
            

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Trade Commission</ENAMEX> sued <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intel</ENAMEX> for alleged antitrust violations. It
says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intel</ENAMEX> denied <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> information about its chips (which they
needed in order to develop products for the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">80 percent</NUMEX> of computers that are
based on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intel</ENAMEX> chips), thereby forcing them to accept <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intel</ENAMEX>'s terms for use of
their patented technologies. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intel</ENAMEX> agrees that this happened, but says it isn't
against law. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Skeptics</ENAMEX> say that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) the case against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intel</ENAMEX> is far weaker than the
case against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>, because the allegedly victimized <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intel</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> more than its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s picture of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intel</ENAMEX>
as a fierce monopoly is outdated, since its market share is under assault. As
though on cue, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intel</ENAMEX> cut its prices. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">6/9/98</NUMEX>)
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nigerian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dictator</ENAMEX> Gen.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sani Abacha</ENAMEX> died , reportedly of a heart attack. Almost nobody is sorry.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Experts</ENAMEX> debated whether he would be remembered more for his brutal tyranny or
for his corruption and plunder of the economy. Western <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nigerian</ENAMEX>
opposition <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> implored the military to use <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abacha</ENAMEX>'s death as an
opportunity to restore civilian democracy. Instead, the military immediately
named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abacha</ENAMEX>'s top defense <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX>, a fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">general</ENAMEX>, to succeed him. The good
news: The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> might be angry enough to rise up against the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX>. The
bad news: Lots of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> might be killed in the process. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Read</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International</ENAMEX>
Papers" for media reactions from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nigeria.</ENAMEX>) (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">6/9/98</NUMEX>)
            

         
      
   
