
   
   
      
         
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> is threatening to detonate a nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX> in response to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>'s
nuclear tests over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past week</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> says this may be necessary to
deter <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aggression</ENAMEX>, since the major industrial <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> failed to condemn
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">their weekend</TIMEX> summit. Meanwhile the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> are waging a war of
words. To find out who's winning, click . (And check out "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International</ENAMEX>
Papers" for reactions from around the globe. "Pundit
Central" gives you the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">commentariat</ENAMEX>'s take.) (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">5/18/98</NUMEX>)
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> helped <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> get into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> of launching <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">communications</ENAMEX> satellites by transferring licensing authority over these
launches from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commerce Department</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York</ENAMEX>
Times reported that this decision overrode <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX>'s wishes and benefited,
among others, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> who subsequently funneled large
contributions to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic Party</ENAMEX>. The naive, dramatic conspiracy theory:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> shifted the authority in exchange for donations from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX>. The
sophisticated, boring conspiracy theory: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> shifted the authority in
exchange for donations from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> involved. The most
sophisticated, most boring explanation: <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fund-raiser</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnny Chung</ENAMEX>
used the illusion of an influence-peddling conspiracy to skim most of the money
for himself. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">5/18/98</NUMEX>)
            

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> sued <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> for "illegal,
anti-competitive practices." Among other things, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOJ</ENAMEX> seeks an injunction to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">force Microsoft</ENAMEX> either to separate Windows <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">98</NUMEX> from Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Explorer</ENAMEX> or to
include <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netscape Navigator</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> demand that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> stop bundling
additional programs with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Windows</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX> says the
government is attacking innovation and endangering the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> economy. Each side
says it is standing up for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> and free enterprise. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">5/18/98</NUMEX>)
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX> is in chaos. Protests against the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> of the world's
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> most populous <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> have provoked lethal gunfire from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX>. Riots and
looting have drawn <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">tanks</ENAMEX> into the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">More than two dozen</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are dead.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> has told most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> to leave. Diagnosis: Indonesians are
angry with their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dictator</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Suharto</ENAMEX>, and are ready to dump him now
that his corruption and mismanagement have ruined the economy. Everyone is
waiting to see what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> will do. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Editorialists</ENAMEX> argued: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) Suharto should
step down. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> should refuse to support him. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) Indonesians should turn
to democratic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cynics</ENAMEX> observed that there is little empirical
basis for any of these hopes. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">5/15/98</NUMEX>)
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Sinatra</ENAMEX> died at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">82</NUMEX>. Key stats: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,000</NUMEX> songs, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">240</NUMEX> albums, one <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oscar</ENAMEX>,
one <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Medal of Freedom</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Obits</ENAMEX> called him the pop <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singer</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the century</TIMEX>, noting
his range, durability, and influence through <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Big Band</ENAMEX>, blues, and rock 'n'
roll. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oldsters</ENAMEX> reminded <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gen Xers</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sinatra</ENAMEX> drew screaming <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowds</ENAMEX> and
swooning <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> before <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elvis Presley</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Beatles</ENAMEX> did. The unauthorized spin:
hot-tempered serial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mafia</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pal</ENAMEX>. The authorized spin: blue-collar
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Plotz</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 1997</TIMEX> 
                  Slate
                "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Assessment</ENAMEX>" of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ol</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Blue Eyes</ENAMEX> includes audio clips.) (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">5/15/98</NUMEX>)
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seinfeld</ENAMEX> signed off. The buildup: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX> of media hype by the
"Seinfeld industrial complex." Plot summary of the final episode: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elaine</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kramer</ENAMEX> went to jail for failing to aid a carjacking victim
in a small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Dozens</NUMEX> of peripheral characters mocked by the main characters
in previous episodes returned to testify against them. The spins, in order of
ascending cynicism: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) This teaches us that the current vices exemplified by
the main <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> (selfishness, narcissism, and greed) will be punished. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>)
This is the last time all <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> will share a communal TV experience--sniff,
sniff--before the cable/Internet revolution permanently disperses us. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) This
is the last time a network will be able to stuff a sitcom with <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$32 million</NUMEX>
worth of interminable commercials. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) The main <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> will get out of jail
and launch new shows to rake in new jackpots. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
headline: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sitcom Falls</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Survives</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Tribune</ENAMEX> editorial:
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Yada Yada, Get a Life</ENAMEX>." (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">5/15/98</NUMEX>)
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney General</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Reno</ENAMEX> requested an independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> to check out
influence-peddling and illegal fund-raising allegations against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexis Herman</ENAMEX> . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX>'s decision
proves she is not covering up for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
said the decision suggests that she is covering up for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> by not seeking
an independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> against him but going after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herman</ENAMEX> even though the
evidence against her is relatively weak. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">5/13/98</NUMEX>)
            

            The

                  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX> fired <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Glass</ENAMEX> for inventing stories in
his articles and fabricating notes to fool <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNR</ENAMEX> 's fact checkers. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Editors</ENAMEX>
at other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> for whom <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glass</ENAMEX> wrote are reviewing his published articles to
gauge the extent of his deception. The spins: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) He fooled everyone. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) He
fooled everyone except me. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) It's his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>'s fault, for not caring about
accuracy. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) It's attitude journalism's fault. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>) It's the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cult</ENAMEX> of youth's
fault. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>) It's his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>' fault. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>) The poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>, he was under too much
pressure. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>) Stop pitying him, he put himself under the pressure. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>) You just
can't trust anyone anymore. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>) If you reward <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> who con their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX>,
don't be surprised when they con you. (For 
                  Slate
               's take, see
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glass</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Houses</ENAMEX>," by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Shafer</ENAMEX>.) (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">5/13/98</NUMEX>)
            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Danish</ENAMEX> woman
who was arrested in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> for leaving her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> in a stroller
outside a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> has sued the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20 million</NUMEX>. She says she was
falsely arrested, maliciously prosecuted, and unconstitutionally deprived of
custody of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Reporters</ENAMEX> noted with irony that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>, having been
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">admonished</ENAMEX> to embrace <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> customs, has done so by filing a huge lawsuit.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> compounded the irony by accusing her of gall.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">5/13/98</NUMEX>)
            

         
      
   
