
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Picture</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dorian Gray</ENAMEX>

            When campaign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strategists</ENAMEX>
politely invite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> to retire an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">incumbent</ENAMEX>, they're said to be "giving the
opponent a gold watch." Legacy , a spot from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elliott Close</ENAMEX>'s
campaign against <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">95-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Strom Thurmond</ENAMEX>, is a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14K</NUMEX> example of this
technique. It cleverly places the still-popular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX> in a time machine
and gives <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Carolina</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> permission to ease him out of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> without
repudiating him.

            Juxtaposed with the visual
of a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thurmond</ENAMEX> is a reminder from the narrator that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thurmond</ENAMEX> began in
politics "way back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1928</TIMEX>." As that photo dissolves into one of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thurmond</ENAMEX> in
his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">40s</NUMEX>, then one of him in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">his 60s</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">70s</TIMEX>?), the narrator praises the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX>
for serving <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Carolina</ENAMEX> for "most of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this century</TIMEX>." The spot could have
reminded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thurmond</ENAMEX> was a hanging <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX>; a segregationist
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Truman</ENAMEX>; and a bitter-end opponent of
civil rights. But avoiding the negative is a smart tack. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Assailing Thurmond</ENAMEX>'s
record would only appear to upbraid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> for having sent him to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> a
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half-dozen</NUMEX> times.

            As the camera zooms in on
the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">liver</ENAMEX>-spotted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thurmond</ENAMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> photo, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">narrator</ENAMEX> voices what must be
the thoughts of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">constituents</ENAMEX> by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX>: "We appreciate all he's done." But
that's not just a "thank you"; it's a gentle "goodbye." This is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dorian Gray</ENAMEX>
brought out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">attic</ENAMEX> of memory, aging before our eyes.

            The next scene clinches the
argument. It begins with a tight shot of an open book featuring <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> photos of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thurmond</ENAMEX>. In one, he looks as if he's offering a farewell salute; in the other,
he's an old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> working out, trying to hang on. The camera cuts away to reveal
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Close</ENAMEX>, sitting in his own living <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>. Literally closing the
book on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thurmond</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Close</ENAMEX> says respectfully that this election is "about the next
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">century</ENAMEX>, not the last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>."

            The succeeding scenes are
more conventional, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Close</ENAMEX>'s every appearance, in vivid color, completes the
case. At what appears to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chamber of Commerce</ENAMEX> lunch, he chats with a woman
while his voice-over offers the assurance that he's for a balanced budget--a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thurmond</ENAMEX> priority--"without gutting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> and student loans." This is the
only implicit criticism of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thurmond</ENAMEX>, who voted the other way, but it is stated
in entirely positive terms. Next we see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Close</ENAMEX> in a country <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX>, pledging,
again via his voice-over, that he "won't be owned by the special interests."
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewer</ENAMEX> is free to read the cliché either as a soft criticism of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thurmond</ENAMEX> or
an affirmation that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Close</ENAMEX> will be like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thurmond</ENAMEX>, unencumbered by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">labor</ENAMEX>.

            Back in his living room,
Close promises to continue to do the one thing that everyone concedes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thurmond</ENAMEX>
does well. "I, too, will provide great constituent service."

            Close is a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Carolina</ENAMEX> has a large black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> things you'd never discern
from Legacy . <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">Race</ENAMEX> has increasingly become a predictor of party
identification in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Close</ENAMEX> can't risk conveying, visually or
otherwise, that he's a liberal--or even a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thurmond</ENAMEX> has no such
worries. Thanks to his record, he is at liberty to build <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridges</ENAMEX> to blacks
without risking white backlash.)

            Celebrating the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thurmond</ENAMEX>
"legacy" and then portraying him as worn-out, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Legacy</ENAMEX> is free to suggest
that a younger version of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX> should replace him. These <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> points are
efficiently fused together in the last scene, in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Close</ENAMEX> is surrounded by
his very young, very contemporary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">narrator</ENAMEX> gets the last word:
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elliott Close</ENAMEX>, a new conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Carolina</ENAMEX>."

         
      
   
