
   
   
      
         
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Judiciary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orrin Hatch</ENAMEX> offered to spare <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>
impeachment if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> admits to an affair with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>. Hatch
suggested that if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> had lied about the affair but not committed a more
serious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offense</ENAMEX>, he could avert impeachment by admitting to it, apologizing,
and "pouring his heart out to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>." The conventional wisdom is
that if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> finds <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sperm</ENAMEX> on a dress <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> has turned over to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> will admit to the affair, issue a "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">mea culpa</ENAMEX> " by
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 17</TIMEX>, and remain in office, but as a diminished <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. (: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
chances of survival.) 
               (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">8/4/98</NUMEX>)
            

            The
case of the switched <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX> took another bizarre turn. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX>, the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> newborn <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>. This raised ethical questions about whether the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> should be restored to their respective biological <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>, which raised
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age-old</TIMEX> question whether custody should be determined by the rights of
biological <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s need for stability. Now <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX>
reports one of the sets of biological <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> died in a car crash <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 4</TIMEX>. The
high-minded spin: The respective extended <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> should seek a "Solomon-like
compromise" that serves the best interests of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX>. The cynical spin: Good
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">luck</ENAMEX>, since the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pseudo-grandparents</ENAMEX> of the pseudo-orphaned <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> are already
fighting "a bitter custody dispute" over her. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">8/4/98</NUMEX>)
            

            
Independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Counsel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX> asked an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lab</ENAMEX> to test <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s
purportedly "semen-stained" dress for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX>. New reports
say the dress, which had been dismissed as a myth, was actually concealed in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> (to outwit <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX>' search of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX>) and has now been turned over to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX>. The other
purported physical evidence of a relationship--the tapes of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> talking to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s answering machine--reportedly are innocuous. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX> are
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">happy Clinton</ENAMEX> remains high in the polls but are surprised by the disclosure of
the dress and worry that it will turn the public against him. The big questions
now are: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) Did the dress actually contain <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX>? <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) Did <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>
launder the dress, and if so, did that destroy the evidence? <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Will Starr</ENAMEX>
withhold the DNA test results in order to set an additional perjury trap for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> when he testifies <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 17</TIMEX>? (For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier in the week</TIMEX> happenings on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> scene, see other items below.) (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">7/31/98</NUMEX>)
            

            After
completing her testimony before the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> grand jury, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Tripp</ENAMEX> gave a
prepared statement to the press, from whom her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">apologia</ENAMEX> drew sarcasm and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">incredulity</ENAMEX>. (: Why her message fell flat.) 
               (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">7/31/98</NUMEX>)
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> reportedly has agreed to testify that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> told her
how to cover up their relationship. In exchange for near-total immunity
from prosecution, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> allegedly has told <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Independent Counsel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> that she will say that: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) she and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> discussed
hypothetical ways to keep their relationship private, including falsely denying
what they did unwitnessed; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> told her he would deny they had a
relationship in his deposition in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> case; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> encouraged
her to say she visited the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> to see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betty Currie</ENAMEX>, not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4</ENAMEX>) she
wrote the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Talking Points</ENAMEX>," without the help of anyone at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">spins</ENAMEX>, in order of descending breathlessness: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is finished. When the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">public</ENAMEX> hears <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> say he lied, it will turn on him. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s testimony
goes beyond perjury to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX> tampering and obstruction of justice. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
will wait out <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s testimony and shape his story to avoid contradicting
hers. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) Testimony that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> had sex will surprise nobody, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> will say the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> did not tell her directly to lie. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>
has cleared the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> of the most serious charge: writing the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Talking</ENAMEX>
Points. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>) Where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> differs from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>, it will just be "he said/she
said," and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> will get the benefit of the doubt. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>) If necessary, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spinners</ENAMEX> will destroy <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> just as they destroyed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">7/29/98</NUMEX>)
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Motors</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Auto Workers</ENAMEX> have agreed tentatively to
end their strike. The work stoppage lasted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight weeks</TIMEX>, cost <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GM</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$12 billion</NUMEX> in
sales (the worst <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> loss ever caused by a strike), cost <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UAW</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">$1</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">billion</ENAMEX> in lost pay, and slowed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">second-quarter</TIMEX> economic growth by an
estimated <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> percentage point. The optimistic spin: Once both sides realized
they had escalated manageable material disputes (e.g., factory closures and
investments in equipment) into an unmanageable war over principles (e.g.,
moving jobs overseas), they settled the material disputes and ended the strike.
The pessimistic spin: The escalation reflects a deep distrust between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GM</ENAMEX> and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UAW</ENAMEX> that will cause an even worse strike when their national agreement
expires <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">7/29/98</NUMEX>)
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell Atlantic</ENAMEX> is buying
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GTE</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$53 billion</NUMEX> in stock. This threatens to reduce the
telecommunications market to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">giants</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell Atlantic</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GTE</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SBC</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ameritech</ENAMEX>),
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Worldcom</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MCI</ENAMEX>), and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AT&T</ENAMEX>. The spins: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telecommunication</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> must
merge lest they be destroyed by others who have already merged. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) This shows
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1996 Telecom Act</ENAMEX> has failed to promote competition, which may lead <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>
to overhaul it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) The solution to merger mania isn't regulation;
it's the market, which downgraded <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell Atlantic</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GTE</ENAMEX>'s stocks after the
merger. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> says this could be "the pin that burst the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">telecommunication</ENAMEX> stock bubble." Other spins on the drop: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) The stocks fell
because the market thinks <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">regulators</ENAMEX> are sick of mergers and are about to crack
down on them. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GTE</ENAMEX> agreed to the buyout not because it's good for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GTE</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> but because it's good for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GTE</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX>, who insisted on keeping his
job. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">7/29/98</NUMEX>)
            

         
      
   
