
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nikes Jumped Over the Moon</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cow</ENAMEX> , produced by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Riswold</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alice Chevalier</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Jay of Wieden & Kennedy</ENAMEX>, with
animation assistance from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gordon Clark</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter DeSeve</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wildbrain Animation</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">House.</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cow</ENAMEX> is an animated
fairy tale that targets the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subteen</ENAMEX> who still responds to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> within. But
it is just as likely to engage the old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> of the athletic shoe
market--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gen-Xers</ENAMEX> and the thirtysomethings. (As far as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nike</ENAMEX> is concerned, anyone
past these demographics is a retired <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumer</ENAMEX>.)

            Naturally, we never see a
real shoe in this animated spot--that would break its tone. It opens, instead,
with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cow</ENAMEX> grazing in a bucolic field. Out of shape and shoeless, this one is
an eater, not an exerciser. Responding to the whistles and taunts of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Old Man</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moon</ENAMEX>, she attempts to re-enact the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fairy</ENAMEX> tale and "jump over the moon."
Leaping, then falling ("<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ooh</ENAMEX>," says the moon), she lies splayed on her feeding
ground.

            The fallen creature now
responds to the strains of "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Destination Moon</ENAMEX>" on the soundtrack: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Come</ENAMEX> and take
a trip in my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">rocket ship</ENAMEX>." And what is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">rocket</ENAMEX>? A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nike</ENAMEX> "swoosh" logo appears
in a thought balloon over the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animal</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>. The brand doesn't have to be
mentioned: In the age of the advertised image, where television often seems
more real than real life, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nike</ENAMEX> swoosh is ubiquitous. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cow squeezes</ENAMEX> into
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">barn</ENAMEX>, then races outside wearing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nikes</ENAMEX>. "We'll travel fast and light," the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">song</ENAMEX> goes--as the animal soars over <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Old Man Moon</ENAMEX>, punching him so hard that he
sees <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cow</ENAMEX> 's message isn't
that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nikes</ENAMEX> are a substitute for working out. Rather, the spot tells you that if
you wear the shoes and just do the rest, you'll soar, whether your moon be the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBA</ENAMEX>, a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">three-mile</NUMEX> jogging path, or a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">playground</ENAMEX>. The high-jumping bovine also
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reinforces Nike</ENAMEX>'s core identification with <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bulls</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX>. And, because the spot uses an <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animal</ENAMEX>, excluding all references to race,
gender, or a particular sport, soccer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beverly Hills</ENAMEX> are as likely to
embrace it--and the product--as hoop <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shooters</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Harlem</ENAMEX>.

            The spot ends with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nike</ENAMEX>
slogan that is now as familiar as the swoosh. Evoking freedom, a safe
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rebellion</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Just Do It</ENAMEX>" is the life-affirming bookend to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy Reagan</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Just</ENAMEX>
Say No."

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cow</ENAMEX> recruits the next
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nike</ENAMEX> wearers by building a bridge between young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s innate
sense of play and the next stage--competition. Shoes signify more than sports
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX>. They stand for self-image. If young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> do it now, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nike</ENAMEX> knows
they'll keep doing it later.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fairy</ENAMEX>
tale goes on: Buy the shoes, and jump the moon. And it doesn't matter if it's
all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bull</ENAMEX>.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Shrum</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
