
   
   
      
         
            Making the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SportsCenter Team</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Talent Search</ENAMEX>,
produced for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESPN Inc.</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wieden & Kennedy</ENAMEX>.

            Posing as a casting call for
potential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">anchors</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Talent Search</ENAMEX> , produced for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SportsCenter</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESPN</ENAMEX>, is
a pointed, witty put-down of sports, television, and politics.

            Making no concessions for
the uninformed, the spot assumes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> are familiar with its principal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> and references. Only in the setup scene does a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> get a chyron
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ID</ENAMEX>: We're not supposed to instantly recognize the ubiquitous SportsCenter
producer who tells us that sports <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personalities</ENAMEX> do not automatically qualify as
sports <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">anchors</ENAMEX>. Reinforcing the idea is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Bullet</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gheorghe Muresan</ENAMEX>, who, besides being the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBA</ENAMEX>'s tallest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> ever, is known as
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of its least articulate: The Bullets use him in an ad whose entire point is
that he can't even manage to recommend that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> buy tickets to a Bullets
game.

            That <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Muresan</ENAMEX> has made it to
the interview lineup augurs well for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who follows him. The chyron that
accompanies our <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> shot of this next <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>, whom we see over the
shoulders of the interviewers, further lowers the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX>: This is "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid-season</TIMEX>
recruitment" in progress--anyone halfway decent could break in.

            The middle-aged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> on the
casting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couch</ENAMEX> doesn't identify himself, but he tells us that he won a gold
medal in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Olympics</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rhodes</ENAMEX> scholarship, that he played for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Knicks</ENAMEX>
for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 years</TIMEX>, and then: "I was a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18 years</TIMEX>." Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> will
recognize <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX>; others will know only that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX>
who used to play in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBA</ENAMEX>. As with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Muresan</ENAMEX>, you either get the reference or
you don't. The spot makes sense either way.

            The interviewers share a
glance--the mention of politics didn't go down well. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of them, clearly a
better talker than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> (and he has proof--the conspicuously inconspicuous
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emmy</ENAMEX> behind his shoulder), presses on: "How about any writing experience?"

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> books, says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of them on the best-seller list, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Tax Reform Act of 1986</ENAMEX>. There's no
pleasing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">skeptics</ENAMEX>: "But no TV writing," observes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. The political stuff
doesn't impress them, and given that they are probably making big money, why
would they want their taxes reformed anyway?

            A wider shot of a basketball
in addition to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emmys</ENAMEX> suggests that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> should be talking more about his
career in sports--but he doesn't seem to get it. The next question, "Any
experience in front of an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>?" elicits mention of another political
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">achievement</ENAMEX>. Yes, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>, all wide-eyed: the keynote address to a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Convention</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">interviewer</ENAMEX>'s reaction
is a sharp comment on the disconnect between popular culture and politics:
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ah</ENAMEX>," he says, unawed. "I meant a large <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> concedes--but
there's a twinkle in his eye. Proof that he's skeptical about politics? Perhaps
he quit the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> (a fact that some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> would know) because he wanted a
job in something that really mattered--like sports? The closing chyron, "This
is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">SportsCenter</ENAMEX>," reminds us this show gives sports an attitude. That other
stuff on television--politics--is boring, long-winded; and politics vs.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SportsCenter</ENAMEX> (or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Union</ENAMEX> speech vs. the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.J.</ENAMEX> verdict?) is no
contest.

            What's in
this for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>? The self-deprecating, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nonpolitical</ENAMEX> portrayal earns him
advance exposure with what would be a hard-to-reach <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">constituency</ENAMEX> if he ran for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>. That's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s real casting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couch</ENAMEX>. For <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dollar Bill</ENAMEX>, the
big game is in the future, when he hopes to anchor a lot more than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESPN</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
