
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Risky Business</ENAMEX>

            
               Tell , produced by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Squier</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Squier</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Knapp & Ochs</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">campaign</ENAMEX>.

            Windows or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mac</ENAMEX>; download
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">16 minutes</TIMEX> at 14.4K

            
               Tell --the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
campaign's new spot that aired <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two days</TIMEX> before <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX>'s acceptance
speech--all but defines a rapid-response ad.

            The spot capitalizes on
the ambivalence greeting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">15 percent</NUMEX> tax-cut proposal: The latest
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS/ New York Times</ENAMEX> poll shows that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> aren't sure the cut is good
for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, but still favor it <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">61 percent to 33 percent</NUMEX>. Tell 's
strategy is to highlight the cut's dangers without mentioning the benefits.

            
               Tell begins with
shots of the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Old Dole</ENAMEX>" filmed in the "attack colors" of black and white. It
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rips Dole</ENAMEX>'s economic proposal, but avoids calling it a tax cut. Instead, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">narrator</ENAMEX> warns of "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>'s risky economic scheme. ... He still won't tell us how
he'll pay for it all." The word "risky," displayed as a bold chyron atop the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> footage, bolsters this idea. So does a quotation from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Business</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Week</TIMEX> --also shown as a bold chyron--asserting that under the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> plan, we
can expect the "deficit to balloon."

            That <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> is silent about
how he'll finance his "scheme" makes his plan sound like a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> giveaway
program. This is more political jujitsu from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guru</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Morris</ENAMEX>, who
continues to pre-empt the other side.

            Although the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> proposal
is straight out of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX> tax-cut playbook, Tell tilts not
against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>, but against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>. The next shots plunge the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewer</ENAMEX> into scenes
from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> recession: an empty <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factory</ENAMEX>; a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> apparently struggling to
pay its bills; a "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Plant Closed</ENAMEX>" sign; a bold "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>" chyron over a poster for a
going-out-of-business sale. Tell poses the question, "Are you better off
than you were <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years ago</TIMEX>?" and suggests that a vote for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> would return
us to the grim black and white of the past.

            The spot's next target is
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">narrator</ENAMEX> says that "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>'s campaign co-chair, Sen.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D'Amato"</ENAMEX> (note the studied political correctness of "co-chair") might raise
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> premiums to "help" pay for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>'s "promises." Again, there is no
mention of the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">15 percent</NUMEX> tax cut--and the word "help" reminds the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewer</ENAMEX> that
we still don't know how the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> plan will be financed. The message is driven
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> as the camera pans across a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> to an elderly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> in a
wheelchair.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> is what broke the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gingrich Congress</ENAMEX>, so Tell naturally pairs <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>, who is
shown yielding the microphone to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt</ENAMEX>. Better than any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">narrator</ENAMEX>'s accusations,
this visual conveys the argument that it if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> wins, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> will run the
government and cut <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>, education. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Positioning Gingrich</ENAMEX>,
not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Kemp</ENAMEX>, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>'s running mate will be a recurring <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> tactic.

            The spot finally shifts to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, filmed at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> in glorious color. The previously ominous
music is replaced with an uplifting theme. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reaganism</ENAMEX> is reprised, with a
reference to a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100 billion</NUMEX> tax cut--but the tax cut is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s. This is the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time the magic words "tax cut" appear in Tell . The message is that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> can make his cuts work while "balancing the budget." We see a worker
clocking in while the narrator points to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10 million</NUMEX> new jobs and, as the spot
cuts to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Kennedyesque</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, it concludes with the phrase "a
better future."

            
               Tell is essentially
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about the past</TIMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s economic success vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s recession and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>. Expect <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> to respond by emphasizing that his <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">15 percent</NUMEX> tax cut
solves the problem not yet addressed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> recovery: that real wages
for most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> have stagnated.

            With <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> at last in the
race and equal to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> in campaign dollars, the struggle to define the
choice will peak. Will <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> go for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> tax cut, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican</ENAMEX>
equivalent of a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">15 percent</NUMEX> wage increase? Or will they stay with a president
who claims to have ended the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> recession and who offers a lesser tax cut?
Framing the election around the desirability of tax cuts is risky business for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>; since the age of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> assumes that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> are
the anti-tax <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Shrum</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
