
   
   
      
         
            The (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Young</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">People's Car</ENAMEX>

            
               Sabotage , produced
by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">J.J. Sedelmaier Productions Inc.</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Volkswagen of America Inc.</ENAMEX>

            
               Sabotage resurrects a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> import from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '70s</TIMEX>--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Speed Racer</ENAMEX> cartoon series--to sell a
'90s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> import, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Volkswagen GTI</ENAMEX>. Produced and directed by the legendary
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J.J. Sedelmaier</ENAMEX>, the ad exploits the nascent nostalgia of twentysomethings and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thirtysomethings</ENAMEX> who watched the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Speed Racer series</ENAMEX> in syndication
during their younger <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX>, or saw it during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '90s</TIMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MTV</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cartoon</ENAMEX>
Network.

            The spot plucks the
nostalgia chord in the first frames, opening like an episode of the cartoon
series, with the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Sabotage</ENAMEX> title splashed across the rotating wheel of
Speed's <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Mach-5</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> at the bottom of the title
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">card</ENAMEX> credit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sedelmaier</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX>, who have expertly mimicked the
Japanimation style of the original series. To make it look more authentic,
Sedelmaier corrupted the new animation by transferring the negative to a second
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to make the cartoon look <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25 years old</TIMEX>. This emphasis on authenticity
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">actuates Marshall McLuhan</ENAMEX>'s notion of medium as message: The cartoon is the
real thing, and so is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>.

            In the first scene, the hood
is up and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">smoke</ENAMEX> is pouring out. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Mach-5</ENAMEX> has been sabotaged. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Mach-5</ENAMEX> is
big, powerful, and gas-guzzling. What Speed needs something more
efficient--smaller, but with big pickup and quick response.

            Speed's obviously rattled
mechanic-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>, Pops, expresses panic--"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Speed</ENAMEX>, if you don't win, we could lose
everything." As in the series, the words are slightly out-of-sync--as if dubbed
from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX>. Just in time, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Inspector</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Detektor</ENAMEX> reveals the solution to
Speed's problem--keys with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VW</ENAMEX> logo--and presents him with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>. Speed
knows what it is--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Volkswagen GTI</ENAMEX>!"

            We cut/dissolve to a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">yellow</ENAMEX>-and-red checkered race flag and into the race. As the GTI gains on the
pack, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Trixie</ENAMEX>, sitting in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passenger</ENAMEX> seat, urges her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilot</ENAMEX> on: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Faster</ENAMEX>,
Speed!"

            With <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX> bumping
each other, Pops issues his warning from the back seat ("<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Look</ENAMEX> out!"),
previewing the coming assurance that while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GTI</ENAMEX> can race along, it still has
room for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>. It's instantly maneuverable, too. Speed slips through the seam
as a rival's car plunges into a fiery crash. Another note of authenticity: The
explosive sound effects come from the show's old episodes.

            Meanwhile, back inside the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>, Speed avoids another fiery collision to cross the finish line under the
black-and-white checkered flag. "It's amazing," Speed says. "It's got room for
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>," chimes in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pop</ENAMEX> from the back seat. Then <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Chim Chim the monkey</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Speed</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid brother</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spridle</ENAMEX> pop up from the hatchback luggage space. "Make that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>,"
says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spridle</ENAMEX>, a perennial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stowaway</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Speed Racer</ENAMEX> episodes.

            The green-and-yellow flag
that fills the screen signals danger past, victory won; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Speed</ENAMEX> survives to race
another day. As he jumps from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GTI</ENAMEX> in the cartoon's patented style, Speed
delivers the VW slogan in voice-over, shifting from nostalgia to the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">On</ENAMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> of life, there are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> and there are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX>." The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">twentysomethings</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thirtysomethings</ENAMEX> spent their time as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX>; their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> were driving while they were watching <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Speed Racer</ENAMEX> . Now,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sedelmaier</ENAMEX>'s spot brilliantly suggests, it's their time to do the driving--in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> and in life. Time to race ahead in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicle</ENAMEX> that saved our
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX>--unless, of course, they'd rather just hold back, stay at home, and become
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">couch potatoes</ENAMEX> staring at reruns of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Speed</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trixie</ENAMEX>.

            
               Speed
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Racer</ENAMEX>'s musical theme--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Go Speed Racer</ENAMEX>, go!"--finishes the spot as the VW
end card comes up: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Drivers</ENAMEX> wanted." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sedelmaier</ENAMEX> has rescued <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Japanimation</ENAMEX> from a
generational memory hole to sell a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> to young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> who may
consider it the opposite of cool. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> relic redeems another: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Drivers</ENAMEX> wanted for
the gee-whiz <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GTI</ENAMEX>--and it may just get them.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Shrum</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
