
   
   
      
         
            

            A
heat wave across the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> has killed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 100</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>,
mostly in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> is beginning <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">its third straight week</TIMEX> of temperatures
exceeding <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">100 degrees</NUMEX>. Death <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX> has reached <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">124</NUMEX>. Illegal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX>,
homeless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, and old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> who are stuck indoors without air conditioning
are in the greatest danger. Oklahomans have prayed for divine intervention to
no avail. The secular explanation meteorologists have offered for the heat
wave--"a persistent anomaly"--is no more satisfying. The bad news: There's no
relief in sight for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX>. The worse news: The heat is spreading over the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northeast</ENAMEX>. The good news: We're doing a lot better than <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Papua New Guinea</ENAMEX>, where
a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">23</NUMEX> foot tsunami killed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">an estimated 3,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 17</TIMEX> and left their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">corpses</ENAMEX> to be devoured by crocodiles. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">7/20/98</NUMEX>)
            

            
Military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> have proposed to relax their policies against
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">adultery</ENAMEX> . The proposed changes, prompted by embarrassment over the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kelly</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flinn</ENAMEX> affair and other recent adultery scandals, would reduce the number of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">prosecutions</ENAMEX> (by prosecuting only those cases in which the adultery has
demonstrably damaged troop morale) and the severity of the discharge imposed on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">violators</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Analysts</ENAMEX> have identified <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> of thought, in ascending order
of laxity: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marine Corps</ENAMEX>, which is resisting the loosening of standards
because, in the words of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX>, "If you can't trust the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Marine</ENAMEX> next to
you to remain <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faithful</ENAMEX>, how can you trust him on the battlefield<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>" <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX>,
which, unlike the other services, thinks <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> should be allowed to
fraternize with enlisted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX> who are not in their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">command</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>)
Military law <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> who prefer the civilian standard, under which adultery is
rarely prosecuted. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">7/20/98</NUMEX>)
            

            
               The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Food and Drug Administration</ENAMEX> approved thalidomide as a treatment for
leprosy complications. Everyone assumes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> will prescribe it more often
for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> complications. The real news isn't the approval, which was decided
upon <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months ago</TIMEX>, but the elaborate new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX> of warnings and restrictions,
which are designed to prevent a recurrence of the birth defects thalidomide
caused in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1960s</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Analysts</ENAMEX> credit the new rules to collaboration between the
drug's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Celgene</ENAMEX>) and thalidomide <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Optimists</ENAMEX> call it a
model of cooperation and prudent regulation. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> are taking the
opportunity to write once again about stumps and flippers. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">7/17/98</NUMEX>)
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lockheed Martin</ENAMEX> dropped its takeover of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northrop Grumman</ENAMEX> rather than
continue to fight a federal antitrust suit. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense</ENAMEX> departments
had argued the merger would imperil national defense by reducing competition.
The charitable economic spin: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOD</ENAMEX> has reversed its policy of encouraging
defense industry mergers. The cynical economic spin: Thanks to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOD</ENAMEX>'s
encouragement, every <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> small enough to merge legally has done so, leaving
a few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">behemoths</ENAMEX>. The charitable political spin, from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> : It's "a huge victory for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s re-energized antitrust
efforts." The cynical political spin, from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lockheed</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lockheed</ENAMEX> backed down
from the fight not because it respects the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s authority but because
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is "our biggest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">customer</ENAMEX>." (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">7/17/98</NUMEX>)
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Madison Square Garden</ENAMEX> hired <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marv Albert</ENAMEX> as a radio and TV sportscaster.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX>, he pleaded guilty to assault for biting an ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lover</ENAMEX>, whom he also
allegedly forced to commit sodomy. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albert</ENAMEX> had worked for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MSG</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two decades</TIMEX>
before going to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>. The spins, in order of ascending cynicism: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MSG</ENAMEX> is being
loyal to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albert</ENAMEX> because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albert</ENAMEX> was loyal to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MSG</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albert</ENAMEX> has paid his debt
and acknowledged that "what I did was wrong." <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) As the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX>
puts it, "The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> to redemption is getting shorter and shorter." <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>)
Redemption? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MSG</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave Checketts</ENAMEX> suggested <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albert</ENAMEX>'s notoriety would
boost the ratings. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">7/17/98</NUMEX>)
            

            A jury
ruled that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rev.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Sharpton</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> other "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisers</ENAMEX>" defamed former
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prosecutor Steven Pagones</ENAMEX> by accusing him of raping <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tawana Brawley</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX>.
This confirms a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX> grand jury report that exonerated <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pagones</ENAMEX> and suggested
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brawley</ENAMEX> "rape" was a hoax. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brawley</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisers</ENAMEX> are black; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pagones</ENAMEX> is
white. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisers</ENAMEX> called the defamation case an attempt to silence those who
challenge the white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">establishment</ENAMEX> and "to punish <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> who have clearly
given their lives and their careers to help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who could not help
themselves." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Editorialists</ENAMEX> called the verdict an affirmation that the truth
matters <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 1</NUMEX>) ideological fantasy and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) self-promotion camouflaged by
ideological fantasy. The softhearted spin: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sharpton</ENAMEX> will suffer the worst
damage because, ironically, he is the only one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisers</ENAMEX> to have sought
to moderate his public image. The hardhearted spin: Sharpton continues to
rationalize rather than recant or repent. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">7/15/98</NUMEX>)
            

            The
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> bailout . In exchange, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> agreed to clean up its budget
practices and reform its financial system to attract private investment. News
of the deal boosted <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> markets. The spins, in order of ascending cynicism:
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> has failed to deliver the reforms it promised in exchange for
previous loans. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) If we don't lend the extra money, there will be financial
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">meltdown</ENAMEX>, chaos, and maybe a coup. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) That nightmare scenario is just what
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> wants us to envision. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parliament</ENAMEX> is too irresponsible to
approve the necessary reforms. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Congress</ENAMEX> is too irresponsible to
extend further credit to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX> to support the bailout. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">7/15/98</NUMEX>)
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Tripp</ENAMEX> resumed her
testimony before the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> grand jury, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two days</TIMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX>'s lawyers
appeared on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several weekend</TIMEX> TV shows to portray their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX> as a good citizen
who was forced to tell <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s philandering and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s efforts to cover it up. (For a dissection of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">spin,</ENAMEX> click .) 
               (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">7/14/98</NUMEX>)
            

         
      
   
