
   
   
      
         
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>
exiled dissident <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wang Dan</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. He had been in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> on
and off for "subversion" after he helped lead the democracy movement that
culminated in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tiananmen Square</ENAMEX> massacre. The official reason for his
exile is health problems. The real reason is to ease the way for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>
visit to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> are touting his expulsion as a triumph of
constructive engagement. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> reply that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) he will be less of a nuisance to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> as an exile than as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoner</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) in exchange for his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">expulsion</ENAMEX> and other concessions, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> recently stopped sponsoring
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> resolution condemning <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s human rights policies; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> will further repay <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> by refusing to air <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wang</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dissidents</ENAMEX> on
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> government international broadcasts. ("<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">International Papers</ENAMEX>" gives you the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> spin.) (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4/20</NUMEX>)
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Octavio Paz</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Terry Sanford</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda McCartney</ENAMEX> died. Back-page scribes
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">remembered Paz</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>'s most culturally influential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> and recalled
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sanford</ENAMEX>'s pioneering leadership for civil rights as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX>
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 1960s</TIMEX>. Meanwhile, television fawned over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">McCartney</ENAMEX>, brushing aside
the "modesty" of her musical skills and marveling at her heroic struggle
against <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX>. The principal feel-good theme was the stability of her
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">29-year</TIMEX> marriage to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul McCartney</ENAMEX>, an exemplary contrast to the promiscuity
and serial marriages of other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrities</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4/20</NUMEX>)
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> joined other Western hemisphere <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chile</ENAMEX> for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Summit of the Americas</ENAMEX> . (An earlier installment of "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International</ENAMEX>
Papers" recaps regional coverage of preparations for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s visit.) The
big story was an agreement to begin talks on a hemispheric free trade zone. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> also announced an alliance against drug cartels and a collective
drug-fighting-certification process. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> condemned this as
an assault on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> control of certification. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cynics</ENAMEX> viewed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s emphasis
on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partnership</ENAMEX> rather than <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> dominance as a symptom of his lingering
humiliation from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>' refusal to give him fast-track trade negotiating
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">authority</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Optimists</ENAMEX> spun the same behavior as more friendly, respectful, and
effective. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4/20</NUMEX>)
            

            The
Teletubbies are coming . The colorful <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> toy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>, designed to
appeal to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>- and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2-year-olds</TIMEX>, speak in baby talk, smile, hug, and roll on the
ground. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> is airing their TV show and will earn a percentage of profits from
sales of their merchandise. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> protest the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Teletubbies</ENAMEX> are corrupting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>,
addicting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> to the idiot box, and robbing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> of what's left of their
pre-consumer innocence. An <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Associated Press</ENAMEX> reviewer gagged at the prospect of
"the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">In Utero Channel</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defenders</ENAMEX> countered that toddlers are already
addicted to televised toy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> (e.g., <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Winnie</ENAMEX>-the-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pooh</ENAMEX>, who was the
subject of a 
                  Slate
                "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Assessment</ENAMEX>") and
that if they can't watch the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Teletubbies</ENAMEX>, they'll rot their brains watching
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">soaps</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4/20</NUMEX>)
            

            Former
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cambodian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dictator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pol Pot</ENAMEX> died . According to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cambodian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">captors</ENAMEX>, he died of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">heart failure</ENAMEX> in his sleep. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Skeptics</ENAMEX> noted the convenient
timing of the report--the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cambodian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> was closing in on him and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> was building international support for a war crimes trial--but
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> saw the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">corpse</ENAMEX>, confirmed his death, and broadcast video of him to
prove it. Everyone agreed he was one of history's worst butchers, having killed
between <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one-fourth</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">seventh</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambodia</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>. The spins on his
death: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) It cheated <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cambodians</ENAMEX> of an explanation of his atrocities. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) It
cheated justice. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) It prevented him from testifying against his ex-lieutenants
who remain at large--which is why they may have orchestrated his death.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has promised further efforts to bring them to trial. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) Some
of these ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lieutenants</ENAMEX> serve current <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dictator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hun Sen</ENAMEX>, on whom the world must
maintain pressure to restore democracy and human rights. (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Plotz</ENAMEX> wrote this
appreciation of the much-misunderstood tyrant.) (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4/17</NUMEX>)
            

            
Independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Counsel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX> launched a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PR</ENAMEX> counterattack on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>. First, he renounced his job offer from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pepperdine University</ENAMEX>,
saying it would be wrong to make Pepperdine wait for him to finish his
investigation. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pundits</ENAMEX> theorized <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s true motive was to distance himself
from right-wing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> conspiracy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">theorist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Mellon Scaife</ENAMEX>, a major
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">donor to Pepperdine</ENAMEX> who is accused of funneling money to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> Whitewater
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">accuser David Hale</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> suggested the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX> could not
credibly investigate the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hale</ENAMEX> allegations because of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> conflicts of interest:
the threat posed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hale to Clinton</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOJ</ENAMEX>'s efforts to prevent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Service</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> from giving testimony sought by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Third</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> blamed
the slow pace of his investigation on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s invocation of executive
privilege. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> spin: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s withdrawal from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pepperdine</ENAMEX> is a
confession of a conflict of interest. The short-term spin: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s surrogates
have succeeded in focusing media attention on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scaife</ENAMEX>. The long-term spin: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>
is finally getting the hang of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PR</ENAMEX> game. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4/17</NUMEX>)
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> will appeal the dismissal of her suit against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. Nobody was surprised. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> said she was initially reluctant to appeal
because it would put "stress on my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>" but that she decided to go ahead for
the sake of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> everywhere. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>'s spins on her press conference: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) She
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cried</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) She appeared to be coached and directed by her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>/Svengali <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carpenter-McMillan</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carpenter-McMillan</ENAMEX> seems to have been demoted for being
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">loose cannon</ENAMEX>. The legal consensus: The appeal is doomed. The political
consensus: The public has stopped paying attention, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> will follow
suit, because the appeal is confined to matters of law rather than salacious
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">subpoenas</ENAMEX> and depositions. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4/17</NUMEX>)
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> are hammering <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> for having donated <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">only $353</NUMEX> to
charity <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>. His income was <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$197,729</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Committee</ENAMEX>
called him "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Scrooge</ENAMEX>" and peddled the story to radio talk show <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hosts</ENAMEX>, who dubbed
him "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cheap Al</ENAMEX> ." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX> pleaded that he has given <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$85,000</NUMEX> to charity
over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX>, and they accused the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> of trying to "slash money for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">education</ENAMEX>, health care, and the environment." The backspin: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">rivals</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bennett</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Minority Leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gephardt</ENAMEX>, won't even divulge their charitable donations, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> has done.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Commentators</ENAMEX> who deemed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> innocent of parsimony faulted him anyway for
permitting the appearance of parsimony. (
                  Slate
               's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">News Quiz</ENAMEX>"
asked <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> what <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$353</NUMEX> referred to: <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Click</ENAMEX> here to read their
speculations.) (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4/17</NUMEX>)
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Virginia</ENAMEX> executed <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Paraguayan citizen Angel Francisco Breard</ENAMEX> for the
murder (during an attempted rape) of an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Court</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX> had asked <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> to postpone the execution, saying <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> had
violated <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">the Vienna Convention</ENAMEX> by failing to inform <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Breard</ENAMEX> of his right to be
helped by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paraguayan</ENAMEX> consular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Justice Department</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Gilmore</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Supreme Court</ENAMEX> rejected these
entreaties, saying, variously, that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Breard</ENAMEX> had failed to protest in state
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) access to a consular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> would probably not have changed his
insistence on pleading innocence (against his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>' advice); <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) the murder
was especially vicious; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4</ENAMEX>) the case (complete with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> tests and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defendant</ENAMEX>'s confession) was open-and-shut; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>) an apology to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paraguay</ENAMEX> would
suffice. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madeleine Albright</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">internationalists</ENAMEX>
protested the execution would embolden other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> to deprive <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> citizens
overseas of the same rights. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4/15</NUMEX>)
            

            
Miscellany: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Colin Powell</ENAMEX> died in a car crash. He was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Obituaries</ENAMEX> recalled
his career as a hard rock <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drummer</ENAMEX> (he was better known as "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cozy"</ENAMEX>) and did not
mention the retired <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">general</ENAMEX> who bears the same name. ... <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Economist</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Barro</ENAMEX> decided to stay at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX> rather than take <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia</ENAMEX>'s
offer of a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$300,000</NUMEX> salary and lavish perks. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia</ENAMEX> is humiliated. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Observers</ENAMEX>
searched in vain for an economically rational explanation for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Barro</ENAMEX>'s change of
heart. (
                  Slate
               's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Krugman</ENAMEX> explains why universities
are throwing money at <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX>.) ... <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> budget director
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franklin Raines</ENAMEX> resigned to become <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fannie Mae</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">giant</ENAMEX>,
government-chartered home mortgage <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lender</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4/15</NUMEX>)
            

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pulitzer Prizes</ENAMEX> were announced. "Times <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wins 2 Pulitzers for Spot News</ENAMEX>,
Photos," declared the front page of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> . "Katharine
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Graham</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Philip Roth Win Pulitzers</ENAMEX>," declared the front page of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , praising the recognition of its former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">publisher</ENAMEX>'s
autobiography. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> highlighted <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> prizes won by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> . Eventually, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> got around to acknowledging
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grand Forks Herald</ENAMEX> had won the top prize for its coverage of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Dakota</ENAMEX> floods and fires. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4/15</NUMEX>)
            

            Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">famished</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">North</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Koreans</ENAMEX> are eating their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> , according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX> and aid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> account says a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> ate her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>. Another says an orphan was
killed, salted, and eaten. There have been other tales of cannibalism in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Korea</ENAMEX>, none of them confirmed. Cynics suggested the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> allows such
tales to be disseminated in order to attract sympathy and foreign aid.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4/15</NUMEX>)
            

         
      
   
