
   
   
      
         
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry Goldwater</ENAMEX> died. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Conservatives</ENAMEX> lionized him as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pioneer</ENAMEX> of
conservatism before his time. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Liberals</ENAMEX> congratulated him for repudiating the
religious right in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later years</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pundits</ENAMEX>, starved for candor among <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>, gladly overlooked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goldwater</ENAMEX>'s lousy civil rights record as they
waxed nostalgic about his blunt-spokenness. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, recognizing that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">unfashionableness</ENAMEX> has become fashionable, joined in the praise of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goldwater</ENAMEX>'s
integrity and independence. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">6/1/98</NUMEX>)
            

            World
nuclear powers are scrambling to defuse the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX> race .
After <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> reportedly detonated <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> bombs in retaliation for the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>
detonated by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1</TIMEX>) suggested <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>
would resume its "voluntary moratorium" on nuclear tests; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) proposed a
no-<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>-use treaty with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) urged talks on a "nondiscriminatory"
world treaty to limit the nuclear programs of all nuclear powers. The good
news: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> is trying to defuse its arms <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">race</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>. The bad news: The
known nuclear powers will never agree to a nondiscriminatory treaty. Instead,
they will ask <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> not to put their nukes on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX>. The
liberal pessimistic line: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sanctions</ENAMEX> won't solve the proliferation problem. The
conservative pessimistic line: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treaties</ENAMEX> won't solve it, either. The nonpartisan
pessimistic line: We'd better try something, because the alternative--mutual
nuclear deterrence--nearly led to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> disaster early in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX>
and is likely to be even less stable in the case of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>. For
a review of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of wordplay before the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Pakistani</ENAMEX> tests, click .

               (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">6/1/98</NUMEX>)
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt</ENAMEX>
Gingrich ignited a storm of controversies in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> . <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Two weeks</TIMEX> after <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>)
calling <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madeleine Albright</ENAMEX> "the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX>," he 2) "slapped" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> by saying non-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israelis</ENAMEX> have no
right to judge <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>'s security needs; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) told <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parliament</ENAMEX> that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Congress</ENAMEX> backs <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX> in his rejection of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s latest peace plan; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4</ENAMEX>) reportedly urged <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX> in a private meeting
to defy <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s plan (though the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> could not confirm the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">report</ENAMEX>); and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>) declared <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem Israel</ENAMEX>'s "united and eternal capital,"
contrary to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> policy. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pundits</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX>'s comments absurd,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">undiplomatic</ENAMEX>, reckless, destructive, disloyal, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">McCarthyist</ENAMEX>, and a cynical play
for campaign money from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American Jews</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> replied that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX>
were trying "to attack me when I am overseas trying to be helpful."
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">5/29/98</NUMEX>)
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Comedian Phil Hartman</ENAMEX> was shot to death , evidently by his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brynn</ENAMEX>,
in a murder-suicide. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Friends</ENAMEX> were baffled. Early speculation focused on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hartman</ENAMEX>'s alleged affairs, his demanding career, and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s history of
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">substance</ENAMEX> abuse. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , while recalling the drug-induced
premature deaths of fellow former <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Saturday Night Live</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Belushi</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Farley</ENAMEX>, distinguished <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hartman</ENAMEX> as well-liked and emotionally stable.
Most interesting factoid: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brynn Hartman</ENAMEX>'s real name was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vicky Joe Omdahl</ENAMEX>.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">5/29/98</NUMEX>)
            

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Trade Commission</ENAMEX> is preparing an antitrust suit against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intel</ENAMEX> .
The alleged offenses: abusing its monopoly power and using pressure tactics
against uncooperative computer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">makers</ENAMEX>. Future charges may include predatory
pricing and anti-competitive contracts. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Analysts</ENAMEX> linked the suit to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Department</ENAMEX>'s case against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wintel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> cheered the assault. Cynics
joked that once again, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is tackling a high-tech <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">monopoly</ENAMEX> just as
it is beginning to lose its grip on the market. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX>
reported that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FTC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffers</ENAMEX> will now get "to share the spotlight" after "stewing
that they let <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> become a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX> trophy."
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">5/29/98</NUMEX>)
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Springfield</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ore.</ENAMEX>, buried <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> killed by their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classmate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kip Kinkel</ENAMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cafeteria</ENAMEX> massacre . <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Politicians</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> debated the
meaning of it all. For a review of the arguments, click .
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">5/27/98</NUMEX>)
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Voters</ENAMEX>
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern Ireland</ENAMEX> approved a peace plan . Among other things, the plan
appeases <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholics</ENAMEX> by including <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern Ireland</ENAMEX> in an all-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">council</ENAMEX>, and
it appeases <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Protestants</ENAMEX> by abolishing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish Republic</ENAMEX>'s constitutional claim
to the majority <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Protestant North</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Editorialists</ENAMEX> cheered the vote as a rejection
of past violence and an embrace of peace and cooperation. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">5/26/98</NUMEX>)
            

            Judge
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norma Holloway Johnson</ENAMEX> ruled that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> cannot refuse to
testify before the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> grand jury about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s behavior. She
rejected the argument, advanced by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> and by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s surrogates, that this would endanger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidents</ENAMEX> by causing them to
evade the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX> who are supposed to protect them.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">5/26/98</NUMEX>)
            

            
Pro-democracy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> won the first legislative elections in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>
under <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> rule. The naive spin: The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">democrats</ENAMEX> won. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>-sophisticated
spin: The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">democrats</ENAMEX> get ripped off, because the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> rigged the election so
that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only half</NUMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">legislature</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">seats</ENAMEX> were available. The rest are chosen by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organizations</ENAMEX> from which most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> are excluded. The fully sophisticated
spin: Despite getting ripped off, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">democrats</ENAMEX> have secured a political base
from which to harass and embarrass the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">5/26/98</NUMEX>)
            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>
refused to hear a challenge to a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Carolina</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>-endangerment law that
has been used to prosecute pregnant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who imperil their fetuses by using
illegal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>. The challenge by pro-choice <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> was based on narrow
arguments, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> are spinning the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>'s action as a victory for fetal
rights. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">5/26/98</NUMEX>)
            

         
      
   
