
   
   
      
         
            

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Monetary Fund</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> are bailing out <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Korea</ENAMEX> . The cost is reportedly <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$55 billion</NUMEX>--a record--including <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20 billion</NUMEX>
in backup loan guarantees from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>, and another <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$15</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billion</NUMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Bank</ENAMEX>. This follows bailouts of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$17 billion and $40</NUMEX>
billion for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Thailand</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>, respectively. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX>
moved quickly because <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Korea</ENAMEX>'s situation is worse than was originally
thought and because, without the bailout, the crisis might spread to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> and
eventually to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">12/1</NUMEX>)
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX> approved a plan to relinquish more of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Bank</ENAMEX> to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> small problems: The plan doesn't specify how much land
would be turned over, or when. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cynics</ENAMEX> said the plan couldn't be
serious because if it were, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX> wouldn't have approved it so decisively
(<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16-0</NUMEX>, with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> abstentions). <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cynics</ENAMEX> said that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX> was counting
on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cynics</ENAMEX> to reject the plan, so that he'd get credit for offering
it (thereby appeasing the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>) without having to fulfill it (thereby
appeasing <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">right-wingers</ENAMEX>). Sure enough, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX> rejected it.
Meanwhile, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX> approved more <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Bank</ENAMEX> settlements in defiance of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> plea for a settlement freeze (after having complained that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> "humiliated" <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> by refusing to meet with him). (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">12/1</NUMEX>)
            

            A panel
of defense <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> and former military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> accused the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> of
gross strategic errors in battle planning and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> procurement. Among the
chief indictments: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) We're too well prepared for an implausible <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-war
scenario (<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Persian Gulf</ENAMEX> plus <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Korea</ENAMEX>) and too poorly prepared for an increasingly
plausible terrorist assault on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) We're armed for the
comfortable fight we'd prefer to wage (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX> bombing) instead of the messy
fight necessary to win wars (urban ground combat). <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) We keep buying fancy
technology that can't be supported from low-tech bases in battle zones.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Analysts</ENAMEX> agree that the criticism is largely valid and that it will be ignored.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">12/1</NUMEX>)
            

            
Public-relations buzzards are cashing in on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> showdown before it
disappears. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louis Farrakhan</ENAMEX> announced he will visit <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> as part of his
world tour and hopes to show that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX> (who is "more popular with his people
than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>") is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> we can work with.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> denounced <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Farrakhan</ENAMEX>'s trip, thereby helping him promote it.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) While seeking to limit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> access to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">63</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palaces</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>
paraded nearly <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> coffins containing what it said were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">corpses</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
killed by cruel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> sanctions. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> bashers renewed their efforts to link
the crisis to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> intransigence in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> peace process. This
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">enabled Israel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">apologists</ENAMEX> to denounce the linkage, thereby diverting attention
from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> intransigence. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">12/1</NUMEX>)
            

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Arlington National Cemetery</ENAMEX> cash-for-crypts story collapsed.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Insight</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Times</ENAMEX> magazine, initially reported that
burial plots "allegedly have been 'bought' by fat-<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reelection</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DNC</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rush Limbaugh</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ollie North</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gordon Liddy</ENAMEX>
made <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">hay</ENAMEX> of the story, and several congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> demanded
investigations, thereby entitling the mainstream <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX> to wade in. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX>
eventually released the list of those getting waivers for burials. It showed
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">donor</ENAMEX>, and he had served in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Merchant Marine</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War</ENAMEX> II.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Conservatives</ENAMEX> fell back on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> arguments: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) So what if it's a lie? The
larger truth is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s record made it plausible. (See

                  Slate
               's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Readme</ENAMEX>" for more.) <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> prolonged the story by
failing to disprove it more quickly. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) By broadcasting a lie, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX>
laudably hastened its exposure as such. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> consoled themselves with the
observation that with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX> like these, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> hardly needs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">media</ENAMEX>, as always, pondered what it all means for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">11/26</NUMEX>)
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Media</ENAMEX>
moves: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mort Zuckerman</ENAMEX> hired <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Evans</ENAMEX> away from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Random House</ENAMEX> to
oversee the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Daily News</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News & World Report</ENAMEX> ,
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Atlantic Monthly</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evans</ENAMEX> says he's delighted to resume "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boy</ENAMEX>
Scout" journalism. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> say he's all glitz and no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">talent</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Media</ENAMEX> reporters
are looking forward to a resumption of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evans</ENAMEX>' feud with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rupert Murdoch</ENAMEX>, who
owns the rival <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Post</ENAMEX> . <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Geraldo Rivera</ENAMEX> agreed to stay at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>. He gets <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4 million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> and gives up his lucrative lowbrow syndicated
talk show in exchange for more highbrow assignments. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Geraldo</ENAMEX>'s spin: "This is
something I need for my honor, for my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, for my own self-image." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC News</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Lack</ENAMEX> added, "I am <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s news <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>.") <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) Isiah
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX> quit as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toronto Raptors</ENAMEX> to broadcast
basketball games for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">11/26</NUMEX>)
            

            Former
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">South African</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">first lady</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Winnie Mandela</ENAMEX> was accused of murdering a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>. A former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodyguard</ENAMEX> told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Truth and Reconciliation</ENAMEX>
Commission that he saw her stab the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> to death. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mandela</ENAMEX> was previously
convicted of assaulting and committing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>, but not of killing him.
Problems with the accusation: The ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodyguard</ENAMEX> hadn't implicated her in his
previous accounts of the murder, and another of her henchmen has already been
convicted of it. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Analysts</ENAMEX> questioned whether her appearance before the
commission, which was supposed to help revive her political career, might end
up killing it. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">11/26</NUMEX>)
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tabloids</ENAMEX> are
having a field day with the divorce of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Earl Spencer</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Princess</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spencer</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> says that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spencer</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) committed
adultery with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a dozen</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) summoned his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> to his bath to inform her, "I
no longer love you and you're no good as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>"; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) expressed remorse by
telling one of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mistresses</ENAMEX> that his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> deserved a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> who could "help
her deal with her shortcomings." After <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>'s death, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spencer</ENAMEX> had questioned
the royal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>'s ability to raise her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> properly and accused the
tabloids of residing "at the opposite end of the moral spectrum" from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">saintly Diana</ENAMEX>. In view of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>'s divorce proceedings, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">crowed</ENAMEX>, "He is not fit to lecture anyone about morality and decency." (Also see

                  Slate
               's assessment.) (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">11/26</NUMEX>)
            

         
      
   
