
   
   
      
         
            On <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">With His Head</ENAMEX>

            
               Photo exploits the
controversy surrounding <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>'s most reviled political ad, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg Stevens</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Co.</ENAMEX> spot for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Warner</ENAMEX> that attacked challenger <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner</ENAMEX> as a national <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> and--heaven forbid--a liberal.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stevens</ENAMEX> ad featured a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">buddy</ENAMEX> photo of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, former <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doug Wilder</ENAMEX>, and Sen.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chuck Robb</ENAMEX>, in which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mark Warner</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> was superimposed on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robb</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner</ENAMEX>
was actually off to the side in the picture.

            It would have been a bad
idea to try this trick anywhere; it was an even worse idea to try it in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, using a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> photo. When the fake-photo story hit
the front pages, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stevens</ENAMEX>, one of the most respected <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultants</ENAMEX>
around, took the fall. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John Warner</ENAMEX> asked him to leave the campaign (although
he's still working for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX>, and it's still not clear exactly how all this
happened). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stevens</ENAMEX> himself is so closemouthed about it that he could do an ad
for No Excuses jeans.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mark Warner</ENAMEX>'s media team
responded with an ad that targets <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John Warner</ENAMEX>'s greatest strength--his
perceived integrity. Photo assumes, correctly, that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> is
familiar with the controversy, and opens--as the narrator says--with the "real
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">photo</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark</ENAMEX> is almost out of the frame; you wouldn't look past the three
powerful, well-known figures to find him--unless you were explicitly looking
for him, that is. The next scene piques the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewer</ENAMEX>'s interest by showing how
the trick was played. Though the image was computer-generated, the tactic is as
old as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stalin</ENAMEX> airbrushing the exiled <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trotsky</ENAMEX> out of photos with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lenin</ENAMEX>. But
where the old way always looked fake, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s technology can make the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fake</ENAMEX> look
entirely authentic.

            The next scene invokes a
newspaper story as a third-party <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">verifier</ENAMEX> of the scandal, and adds the charge
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>'s campaign is guilty of the dirty deed and of lying about it.
Here <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark</ENAMEX>'s spot adroitly turns the corner from response to attack. Indeed, it
ignores the essence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John's</ENAMEX> charge (captured in the succeeding scene of the
offending ad, which showed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Gephardt</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Dodd</ENAMEX>; they were the ones for whom <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark</ENAMEX> was accused in
the red chyron of "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Raising Millions"</ENAMEX>), choosing, instead, to use the phony
picture to segue into a general attack on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John Warner</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>. Until now,
this <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX> has been a rare exception to politics as usual: He
broke with his party to oppose <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Bork</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>; he opposed
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oliver North</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> even after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">North</ENAMEX> was the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominee</ENAMEX> against
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chuck Robb</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>'s No. 1 target in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>; he's pro-choice. These stands
protected him against the standard <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> charges against the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>, and education cuts.

            But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Photo</ENAMEX> punches
through his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Teflon</ENAMEX>. Charging that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX> was "less than candid," it asks, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">How</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">long</ENAMEX> has he been fooling us?" The fake ad becomes a moment of dark
revelation--a window into <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>'s true <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>. The charges pile up--and what
is a response spot dares to charge that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX> is "unprincipled," that we can't
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">trust</ENAMEX>" him. The visual recap of the trick-decapitation and the ensuing
newspaper story make the assault as credible as it can be, given the unusually
strong public perception of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX> as a decent and independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>, who was,
until now, the least likely of political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hacks</ENAMEX>.

            The fake
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">photo</ENAMEX> is the latest emblem of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultants</ENAMEX> have become more
notorious than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">famous</ENAMEX>, more <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Morris than James Carville</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mark Warner</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultants</ENAMEX> moved swiftly to convert the mistake into their best argument yet
for unseating <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John Warner</ENAMEX>, whose <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">campaign</ENAMEX> previously boasted that he made
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> proud.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Shrum</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
