
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hal</ENAMEX> what's uh what's crime like in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well it depends where in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> you are there are certainly parts of town
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i would not want to  live in
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		because it's a situation it is very location dependent
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and there are parts of town here where
 		when they talk about the nightly gunfire
 	
 	
 		oh yeah yeah in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore</ENAMEX> we have similar
 		i live on the outskirts of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore</ENAMEX> and uh we live right outside the city
 		and our neighborhood is pretty much working <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class people</ENAMEX> though i'm in graduate school uh i live here because it's close to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX> but you know we have uh it it's really funny the only crime we really see
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		is uh just the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> being malicious
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know and i think most of that is because their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> aren't around that make sense
 	
 	
 		yeah that uh the what they call the latchkey <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah something like that no one's you know or or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fathers</ENAMEX> are just missing you know so there's no uh
 		no consistency there in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> or whatever there's no one to tell them what's right and what's wrong you know
 	
 	
 		you know the suburb i'm in is more of the upper middle class so i think our uh not that we don't have a certain amount of local problems but on the other hand
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh we get the uh affect of the
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh the main crimes within the suburb here are the the theft crimes
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		a small number of assaults
 		uh well if we have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> murder a year
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		that's probably as many but then you know you go into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> and they are unfortunately
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh having murders at a rate greater than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> a day
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah i think that's we're about the same in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore</ENAMEX> though um <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> i think is uh
 		close by and you know they experience a lot more i think they definitely have more problems that uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		in in the area what what do you think can prevent crime
 	
 	
 		well uh the thing is i don't it's one of those things where if you're a grad student you can appreciate the statistics on unfortunately there are often these correlations that are
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		inverse of what they should be like uh
 		wherever there are more
 		uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> there are more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policemen</ENAMEX> but that's which came first
 	
 	
 		yeah  yeah
 	
 	
 		but on the other side of it is it's it's basically the the problem is within the in the society and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">society</ENAMEX>'s views
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh well since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> i'm in my <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid forties</TIMEX> when i was in grad school
 		or when i was an undergraduate growing up in a more rural area i thought you know crime was was reasonably unknown and just the situation that's developed with the
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		the drug aspect of uh
 	
 	
 		yeah i think
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pushers</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealers</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">addicts</ENAMEX>
 		um
 	
 	
 		yeah i i i think i agree with you there
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		because it just was not uh something back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the sixties</TIMEX> that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh i even had to worry about but i think you know that
 		there is a lot in the society where things have changed
 		uh so it's effected all of us
 	
 	
 		uh-huh yeah i think they the drug culture definitely has uh is one of the main problems yeah our uh our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore</ENAMEX> is one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that goes on national television and says they should
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> legalize drugs
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because it would eliminate the uh the violence
 		and the uh the under
 		the the market i guess the the hidden market of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> and everything that goes along with it that make sense he's one of the big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">proponents</ENAMEX> of that he gets on national television and and says that you know so it's um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and he was a
 		District <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney</ENAMEX> before and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX> before becoming becoming <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> so that's a really stranger you know it's a different viewpoint i uh
 	
 	
 		you know in a sense i don't i'm not i have real mixed feelings on that because it comes a bit from the angle that the uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh
 		it would certainly be an interesting test
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but the other side of it to me
 	
 	
 		what happens if we lose worse
 	
 	
 		uh you well the other side is that unfortunately
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		some of the down side and i think if i look back fifty or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a hundred years</TIMEX> i'd say you know back then there were the opium <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dens</ENAMEX> but the thing is if somebody ruined their life
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">society</ENAMEX> didn't try to then save themselves from it they let this person
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		who had ruined it
 		uh become well die or whatever i mean they probably became weakened physically and other things to the point that
 	
 	
 		right yeah
 	
 	
 		their life expectancy was real short but now we tend to
 		believe somewhere in the health care system otherwise we need to take care of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> even if they have
 		you know physically ruined themselves
 	
 	
 		yeah they have induced it themselves yeah that's true
 	
 	
 		and so to me that's i uh i would certainly like to see a real test of of making <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> real cheap to see if when you make them available <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> then don't use them
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		uh-huh well i think you know they did that in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alaska</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		that that actually Alaska just recently legalized marijuana
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i never i never heard results or anything like that so i never you know plus that's such a that's not a true um
 		you know it really couldn't be a good test because <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alaska</ENAMEX>'s so different than every other part of the country
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know so that but that was interesting you know i i don't crime is one of those things that's uh
 		i i don't know you know the drug culture the uh
 		the um
 		you know i i see it with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> in the neighborhood just stealing things not thinking anything wrong with it
 	
 	
 		yeah well the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">some of</ENAMEX> that and of course i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> of the old school but it it bothers me from the fifties on not that i'd remember that much from the fifties but but basically we have so much more of the something for nothing mentality
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah that's true that's true we worked hard for everything that's very true
 	
 	
 		and so you know in the there were the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixty four thousand</TIMEX> dollar question shows in the fifties but nowadays there's so much on TV where
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> seem to have the idea they can get something for nothing of course
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh i work with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> a lot and i see unfortunately we have this whole mentality that somehow there are these pots of money out there that you can sue somebody
 		and you know there's <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a million dollars</NUMEX> you can have
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh for mental <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">duress</ENAMEX> or whatever
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but you know the other thing that bothers me in the crime is the uh in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> they seem to have mentality and drunk driving is a good one is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are
 		well indoctrinated their society that drunken driving is unacceptable
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and yeah if you're going to drink and you may drink you better have your designated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX> in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and for example with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> or with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> is
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we don't seem to understand how to handle it as a society to say okay it is okay under these circumstances but if you step outside these bounds
 		the punishment is
 		extreme and we mean it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah that i think that uh the drunk driving has just actually just caught on uh uh and i i i really uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> was hit by a drunk <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX> when i was in high school and um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that was a very uh
 		that that was an awful <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX> afterwards you know of recovery and the difficulties
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh everything we did and you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> went free because this was twelve <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago thirteen years ago</TIMEX> there was no his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> was even the uh police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX> of the town
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so there was no repercussion at all
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know other than insurance but he was uninsured
 		so uh our insurance paid for everything but it was a very difficult time and and then later this was actually funny my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> and i were picked up by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> for questioning because this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fellow</ENAMEX> had bought a a new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and somebody had taken like a baseball bat to it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and broke all his windows and his lights and his dented it everywhere and they came and questioned us
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know and
 	
 	
 		but that kind of shows how our attitude toward drinking and driving
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		was uh misplaced for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> that you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yep
 	
 	
 		it was an acceptable social behavior
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah very much so yeah that those are some important points
 		yeah i that's
 		those are
 	
 	
 		what are what does your <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> have for gun control if anything
 	
 	
 		well see <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> is one of the most we just voted in uh gun control strong gun control here in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> i i think
 		
 		
 	