
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well we're gonna be talking about vacations i guess huh  where have you been recently
 	
 	
 		right right
 		i have been well i go quite a bit i travel about forty percent of my time but my vacations  my favorite spot is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX> well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> goes there but i am not a betting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> i've been there one time and i'll be honest i did not enjoy it no no
 	
 	
 		really i are there any particular reason you're not into gambling or
 	
 	
 		i i guess just because i'm not that type of a person i'm i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CPA</ENAMEX> and i i'm very conservative with my money and i just did to me that was not a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">vacation</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		i see
 	
 	
 		uh i now i'm a big world <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traveler</ENAMEX> i enjoy traveling the world i just got back from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX> uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this past July</TIMEX> uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the prior year before</TIMEX> that i'd been to uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tokyo Disneyland</ENAMEX>
 		uh i've been i've got a trip coming up <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX> i'm going to the EuroDisney
 	
 	
 		oh really in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh that's gonna be in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris France</ENAMEX> we're going there in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and at the same time we're also gonna go visit <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Norway</ENAMEX> i've always wanted to go see the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fjords</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Norway</ENAMEX> i just love have have have you ever been on a cruise to um Alaska
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		no uh my in-laws have and i i stay stay steer away from <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boats</ENAMEX> as much as possible only because i can't take it
 	
 	
 		okay
 		well i tell you what if i possibly can uh there's a spot that i would love to encourage you to go visit
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> same way
 		he had absolutely no desire to be around a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> he says <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> i get seasick i don't like it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the thing that is so wonderful about the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Alaskan</ENAMEX> cruise it is on what they call the inside passage
 	
 	
 		right right exactly
 	
 	
 		you're not in the ocean you are in a river almost
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		only only the only thing you have are cliffs on the left and cliffs on the right side and we're talking about <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">five hundred foot thousand foot cliffs</NUMEX>
 		absolutely gorgeous and
 	
 	
 		i yes everything i see that they brought back it i i definitely agree
 	
 	
 		and and and and every yeah and every <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">thirty yards</ENAMEX> here comes another uh waterfall which is nothing more than the melting snow
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's just more glorious than the last one it is absolutely fantastic and with those cliffs the sunsets are just oh my goodness uh
 		for me and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> it was probably the most romantic <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one week</TIMEX> trip i have ever ever taken
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		and the food  the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> on we were on uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Princess Cruise Lines</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> was just out of this world
 	
 	
 		oh yes yes
 		i it's it cruises from what i understand are are really the way to go and someday someday i will convince my or convince myself that i can handle it and i will surprise my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and and book a cruise  uh i
 		much definitely prefer warmer climates than <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alaska</ENAMEX> so i would probably head for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Caribbean</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well if that be the case
 		i was gonna say you can go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Caribbean</ENAMEX> but the now the problem with the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Caribbean</ENAMEX> though now you've got the ocean and i've been to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Caribbean</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times now you got the ocean and if you have a motion sickness problem now they have these little patches you can put behind your ear
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		i've used those right
 	
 	
 		uh you'd wanna use those but the same time though you you're not going to get as pleasant of a ride as you would on that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Alaskan</ENAMEX> cruise
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		interesting interesting i never i really never thought of that that's pretty good to know
 	
 	
 		uh but and and and there there are parts especially when you get close to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX> there are the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> can get very very rough
 	
 	
 		um-hum yeah
 	
 	
 		really can  but uh otherwise as far as vacation i've i've course i see i guess i like the cold weather i i've been up to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">New England</ENAMEX> and i thought that was fantastic
 	
 	
 		yeah and this is one spot you know being in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">New England</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> are not that far uh that is one thing that really has not interested us we do like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Virginias</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Carolinas Carolina</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 		now
 		oh have you have you been on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Blue Ridge Parkway</ENAMEX> oh wow now that's fantastic
 	
 	
 		oh yes several times
 		yeah and uh we <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX> we're leaving for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Orleans</ENAMEX>  and i'm i i do prefer the warmer the warmer
 	
 	
 		see i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisiana</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> so i know where you're talking about there
 	
 	
 		um-hum  but uh and i loved <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes now that was my <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> trip i've ever been to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX> yes
 	
 	
 		uh we had bought
 		really it it's it's uh it's just beautiful i just
 		i would be very happy staying in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX> and becoming a beachcomber when i retire which isn't too far off which is something i might wanna consider but uh
 	
 	
 		well stay away from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> coastlines <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> doesn't have anything for you
 	
 	
 		i you know i've i've been tempted i've gotten down as far as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Antonio</ENAMEX> but i've never gone down to uh really to the coastline
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		the the coastline yeah the coastline here is the pits uh there's there's much better in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> much much better uh other places <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX> was wonderful that was great
 	
 	
 		yeah so
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		i love it yes i  that
 	
 	
 		uh i thought <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Waikiki Beach</ENAMEX> was as nice of a of a beach as i ever wanna see and we went to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> different islands we had a great time
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yes it is and you have to do that uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that go and they only go to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> area you have to see it all
 	
 	
 		well tell you what i've got a i've got a phone ringing on the other line i better go answer it i've enjoyed talking to you though catch you later bye-bye
 	
 	
 		yes very good well it's nice talking to you okay um-hum bye-bye
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	