
 
     		
 	
 		okay talk about uh what kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> we we like to go to and what uh makes us go back and i'll start talking about it so
 		usually i just kind of like uh places that are family style kind of things because it's a a casual atmosphere and you usually get good portions of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> and stuff and and uh
 		but  we were in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> recently and i went we went to a couple of very uh i guess expensive extravagant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> because it was kind of the thing to do and we just wanted to see what it was like
 		and we got to get some real good <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> more exotic and uh we thought that the service was very good
 		and uh that kind of makes me want to go to those places again even though it is expensive you know like maybe once <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> or once every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six months</TIMEX> go to it or something like that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but how about you
 	
 	
 		yeah i i enjoy going out but my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> goes out for dinner a lot with his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> you know with his work
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so it's something that i end up kind of experimenting with with my girlfriends or maybe taking my girls out when he's gone and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so we end up usually finding something that's uh quick service and uh that's hopefully economical and uh
 		certainly tastes good i hate to uh pay any kind of an amount and then have the food be real mediocre
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX>  as far as to really go out for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an evening</TIMEX> though i do like to have a place that's
 		not real real formal but kind of on a formal side just because usually their atmosphere is more on a quiet atmosphere and it's real relaxing and then
 		uh the quality of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> is usually kind of is affected by how the mood is set so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um i guess my favorite kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">foods foods</ENAMEX> would be uh the ones that
 		well i don't know favorite is just going out for a good good hearty steak but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i i i find it amazing around here we don't have too many good steak <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> it doesn't seem and i i find that amazing being in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> i'm from another <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> originally and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i always thought <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> was supposed to be such a good <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX> state
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it seems to be a tough thing to do is to find a place that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cooks</ENAMEX> up a real good juicy steak so
 	
 	
 		um-hum you know what we have around here too is uh a place where you uh you pick your own <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX> and you cook it yourself
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		yeah and they they have everything else cooked you know but baked <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">potatoes</ENAMEX> and all that but you you pick your <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX> and you know whether it's marinated or or just regular
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh then they have a big grill and you grill it yourself you know and then have all the stuff to put on it you know like if you want to
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		i don't know <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">butter</ENAMEX> on it or whatever or garlic and stuff like that
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		you can you can do it that's kind of interesting it was really good
 	
 	
 		yeah it's kind of an interesting approach
 	
 	
 		yeah we we thought that was that wasn't too bad but most of the time you know i was really surprised like i say going at these
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		fancier <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> and and i thought i really liked the food you know it uh it was different because you know you see all these things like you see all these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chef</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chef</ENAMEX>'s shows and stuff like that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh and you know i always watched and thought well i wonder if that's any good you know it looks kind of small but actually it wasn't bad at all
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		you know when they have like seafood dishes uh but it's just kind of kind of sparse with different things put in it that that really uh
 		that really taste pretty good you didn't you wouldn't think it goes together you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh but mostly around here now we just kind of just do family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> type of things you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		because it's uh it's easier to go with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> now
 	
 	
 		yeah that's what we have too yeah and yeah you do have to kind of decide well are we there to get a good <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meal</ENAMEX> and and just
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		be comfortable as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> or are we looking to spend a lot of time and a lot of money which doesn't work with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right right
 		yeah that's true
 	
 	
 		so what would make you go back to a good restaurant
 	
 	
 		well i think uh some of the things that i liked were uh
 		uh well i would see the food and whether or not it tastes good uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> if they're you know courteous or if they just kind of are hasty you know if they just get your order and go and you never see them again or they coming talk you know talk with you a little bit or something
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		and do you find that when you have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> that it's it really makes uh you can really tell the difference between a good and a mediocre <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> by the way they treat you with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yes i have we have we have noticed that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yes so uh you know if they more you you can tell when they're oriented towards <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> now if they bring something for them to play with or to write with something you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		to occupy them you can really tell
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		the other thing i've liked too is uh now this isn't you don't have this at at family <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> but uh is some type of a like a a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pianist</ENAMEX> or something
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that will play some music while your eating and stuff and that was that that was kind of neat
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		yeah we have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> over here called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gershwin's</ENAMEX> that has a piano <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> always during your mealtime and it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it just makes for a real classy feel and uh it kind of carries over the conversations next to you so you're not concentrating what someone else is saying next to you but i mean but you know at the next table but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		just within your own little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> so it makes for a nice nice place to go
 	
 	
 		there was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">places</ENAMEX> that we went to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX> and one in uh in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monterey California</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX> is the top of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the downtown <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">big skyscraper buildings</ENAMEX> and it was really neat because you could had a great view you know of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX> and everything
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh and that's another thing that would bring me back to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> is the view and the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> in in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monterey</ENAMEX> was really nice because it was overlooking the water too
 		so that was that was a couple things that we liked
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but
 	
 	
 		well sounds good
 	
 	
 		okay you have anything else to say
 	
 	
 		no i think we covered everything
 	
 	
 		
 
 		okay well thanks a lot
 	
 	
 		well thank you for being home okay bye-bye
 	
 	
 		okay
 		bye-bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	