
 
     		
 	
 		well <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vic</ENAMEX> you said your professional your favorite professional <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> was the was the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cowboys</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		well you know i i could uh pick the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> team
 	
 	
 		oh you could
 	
 	
 		yeah i got a lot of northern <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> here
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		and uh they really uh pull for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> what are the what are the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> called the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bears</ENAMEX> yeah right
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bears</ENAMEX> right
 		i'm not sure how they'll do this year i don't know who they'll use as quarterback
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago Chicago</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		i'm not sure they know who they'll use at <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">quarterback</ENAMEX> yet
 	
 	
 		right well there's a lot of good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> out there in the professional world and uh course we hope also that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cowboys</ENAMEX> do good i know i do and it's your favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> so why don't you tell me about them
 	
 	
 		well what uh i get optimistic about is just uh the relative age of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> now with all the youth that they've added
 		and sort of a change in the nature of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> to the to more of the uh the the pure <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">athlete</ENAMEX> type at all the positions
 		um i like them having added a wide receiver with a nice track background that can high jump real high
 	
 	
 		uh-huh what's his name
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh Alvin Harper</ENAMEX> i think out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tennessee</ENAMEX> because he was a think he's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about six</NUMEX> foot <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> and apparently can catch anything that's anywhere near him and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harper um</ENAMEX>-hum
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i understand that in high school he high jumped <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> feet
 	
 	
 		i'll be darned
 	
 	
 		when he was in high school so uh he creates a real problem for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> now
 		uh particularly probably down in the end zone where <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Troy</ENAMEX> can go back there and put <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> up in the sky and let him go up and get it
 	
 	
 		well is he a fragile uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> you know they had an end or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a</NUMEX> a wingback or something like that that would go down the field and and uh he did real good for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cowboys</ENAMEX> and every time he turned around he was getting hurt
 	
 	
 		getting hurt i don't think this one has any a record like that he seems to be more of a
 		a a sturdy athlete
 	
 	
 		i see
 	
 	
 		i know they have lost a lot of their receivers to injuries in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last few years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		what's the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX>'s name <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy</ENAMEX> you think he can do better <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> than he did last year
 	
 	
 		well he did better <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> than most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> thought including including myself but uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		but what about his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> uh and their reactions to him and his uh kind of unorthodox professional <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> type uh coaching
 	
 	
 		well i guess you mean by that that he sort of brings a more of a college atmosphere to it than than certainly than his predecessor
 	
 	
 		yeah right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i really don't know how they they really react to that It probably does him well right now with with like i said the youth he has on the team
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 		i think one thing he did <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> that will probably pay some dividends is is changing the offensive
 		coach that bring in a new uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offense</ENAMEX> and new offensive system that i think the so far the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> are are uh responding responding well to
 	
 	
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy</ENAMEX>'s going to leave the offense to the offensive coach
 	
 	
 		well that's the theory
 	
 	
 		yeah uh-huh  and what about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">quarterback</ENAMEX> do you think he is uh going to stick in there and not wind up there with a concussion
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well i don't know whether anybody can for a whole year anymore
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		that's true
 	
 	
 		but uh he is uh he's pretty sturdy but he's got to learn to get rid of it pretty quick
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh well is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cowboys</ENAMEX> your your favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> as well or
 	
 	
 		well really in reality uh they are my favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> uh uh and have been you know back since the glory days or before the glory days
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		they used to practice you know right over here uh on uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six thirty five</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Coit</ENAMEX> right in that area
 	
 	
 		right
 		well over there at uh near <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forrest</ENAMEX> i think and uh-huh
 	
 	
 		yeah right uh-huh
 		and uh it was a dingy little old field uh uh that uh you you would have thought maybe a a high school would have played on and it's all surrounded you know by <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartments</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> and everything i was shocked when i saw it
 	
 	
 		that's the one that
 		i think that was the place that had the looked like corrugated tin fence around it painted blue
 	
 	
 		yeah and it had holes in it and it had big tire on it where the former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX> you know uh stood up in there in there and
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but i guess uh you know it doesn't take a lot of uh fancy things to make a good <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> team
 	
 	
 		well i guess not but
 	
 	
 		since they did uh they were <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">America</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> you know back then
 	
 	
 		yeah during that time period they sure were
 	
 	
 		and and i don't think they are now though looks like somebody else laid claim to that
 	
 	
 		do you go to many of
 		do you go to many of the games or have you before
 	
 	
 		uh i've been to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">several</NUMEX> games uh in my lifetime however i prefer to watch the uh watch the game uh via the TV tube
 	
 	
 		well i guess i do too really
 	
 	
 		yeah i i i find myself uh when i go to the football games of uh of uh missing a play by talking to somebody in the group
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		or a stands a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> stands up or i'm looking at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cheerleaders</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clowns</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and when something does happen i say what happened you know and then course uh you can see it on the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">on the playback</ENAMEX> out there uh but back there when i was going i don't think it was that good
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		or if they had it at all you know
 	
 	
 		right that's right i think i went to more of their games when they were still operating out of uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cotton Bowl</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah uh-huh
 	
 	
 		than i have since they moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Texas Stadium</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh-huh we we have a lake <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> see and we go out of town
 	
 	
 		course
 		oh that works out nicely
 	
 	
 		and yeah we just go down there and uh watch the game
 	
 	
 		i'm hoping that they'll be successful and they'll have a lot more sellouts and fewer blackouts this year
 	
 	
 		yes absolutely and and uh if the team you know starts off good <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> i think that uh they will be a a drawing card and perhaps they can uh return to their former glory days
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know i had <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> uh all over the world you know that i run into uh say you know they think of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> thing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dallas Cowboys</ENAMEX> and the movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		and so uh i think that uh they will come back and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> while he's unorthodox i think he is doing a good job and he's all uh he's all business
 	
 	
 		yeah he is that
 	
 	
 		and he got a lot he got he got rid of a lot of the cry babies uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that thought that had it they had it made because uh they were stars
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and he cleaned that out real good and and i'm sure he lost some good ones that shouldn't have gone but
 		in his type offense he was looking for youth and for uh uh uh to rebuild a new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> and i think that was the reason why he cut all the players
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i think also that oil man that uh that uh owns that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">oilman</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partners</ENAMEX> that own the team uh
 		is interested in making a dollar and and they've certainly gone to uh great lengths to you know to bring the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> back into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> for spring training
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and and also to build up the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> to try to satisfy the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and the various factions you know uh especially back in the beginning i think he's done a great job
 	
 	
 		well that's n ice
 	
 	
 		what's his name uh
 	
 	
 		oh the uh Jones yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> is his name
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> yeah
 		and uh he's an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">oilman</ENAMEX> and he's got a little money behind him and uh and uh so you know the they've got the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stadium</ENAMEX> out there it's a
 		
 		
 	