
 
     		
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		the budget seems to be
 		oh on a number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s minds and often times when peoples talk about cutting budget or wishing that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> didn't spend money here and there i hear them talk about uh cutting
 		what they call aid to some foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't understand why are we give <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a million</NUMEX> here or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a billion</NUMEX> there and
 		and whether they like it or not or whether they understand it or not the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> just simply develops dependencies on us uh you start giving a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> uh
 		x amount of dollars for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">so many years</TIMEX> and their whole economy and their whole
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> system is uh used to it and then you threaten with whatever
 		you wish you know you would say well you're not acting right we're gonna withhold it or you're not doing this that or the other or we want our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">base</ENAMEX> here or we want whatever
 		and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s been doing that for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and will probably continue to do that for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and i'm not sure if the general <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> uh
 		thinks about it that way when they start saying why did we give money here or money there and but there are some things even when we what we spend in inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> it seems a little
 		far fetched and not necessarily for the common good
 		uh lot of the money for the arts seem to benefit only a few
 		and usually those who are um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rich</ENAMEX> anyway or have enough have enough money to attend those kind of functions
 		so it's  that's a a controversy of course there's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only a hundred and seventy million</NUMEX> going to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NEA</ENAMEX> but <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred and seventy million</NUMEX>'s
 		a bit and it's something so
 		what would you do or cut or change in the budget
 	
 	
 		well
 		
 
 		um i agree with you on the international aid and um
 		i don't think a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> realize too on we can't live isolated our world is such an international economy now and um
 		uh especially with the problems in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Eastern Europe</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russia</ENAMEX>
 		uh
 		i know a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> feel that we've given so much aid and we have so many economic problems and and i agree that we do but um it's also in our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s interest um
 		to have a balanced world economy um sometimes it does seem like we're the ones doing all the giving um and i have to admit sometimes i have wondered if uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we run into problems which is is certainly a possibility if anyone would come  to lend us a hand but um
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i do think uh
 		this is a hard area i'm there's some areas that i feel uh
 		need a lot of work um  and improvement and education comes to mind i know they are working on trimming defense um
 		this has been such a long process that has gotten us to the point that we're in
 		but unless they start working on it um
 		it really it it already is is close to uncontrollable
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i'm not sure exactly what practical
 		uh steps
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> could be um i wish i had some of the figures in front of me now to know the percentage um
 		i do think <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> step once something you touched on in talking about the arts is that as far as percentages go i think uh money should go that benefits
 		the most um i say uh i believe in um education and not necessarily the
 		federal um it can be done on on different levels too because i think that's our future if we
 		um if our education system falls behind that of say <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> and um
 		some of the other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> we need to be able to be competitive um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's that's an area i would not want cut
 		there are a lot of areas i think that money could be better spent i think sometimes the money they spend on studies to decide on things is way out of proportion and and of course everyone's heard the stories of the
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">several thousand</NUMEX> dollar hammer and um you know somewhere along the line um
 		there've been some
 		gross errors
 	
 	
 		most of the the national or the federal dollars that go toward any project
 		uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> tend to want accountability but they don't want the so-called bigger <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> so they they wanna have fewer government employee
 		
 		
 	