
 
     		
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		all set actually i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plano</ENAMEX> too  i say <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> area when i'm talking to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> elsewhere
 	
 	
 		that's okay
 		that's okay it it's more uh concentrated so they know where you are
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um anyway uh i know here in here in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plano</ENAMEX> some of the things that we do are um <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kroger</ENAMEX> and some of the other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> too have said
 		if you bring your bags back to uh to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> to recycle
 		then they'll pay you a certain amount of money and that's one thing that started in the community
 	
 	
 		they actually pay you money for that <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">hm um Brookshires</ENAMEX> up in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Allen</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh you bring your bags back you know they uh the plastic bags back or the paper bags you put them in the one of the receptacles there but i didn't realize some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are actually paying you for that hm
 	
 	
 		um-hum yeah i know <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kroger</ENAMEX> will do it and i think <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Albertson's</ENAMEX> does it sometimes i'm not sure
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX>  and and yet i know that uh
 		some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> will actually help the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> not pay you the money back but will pay the
 		the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> like through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> or things like that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		interesting
 	
 	
 		so um that's always helpful  and i know that we have we have the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">the</ENAMEX> can
 		the can different can <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> around the city
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		that you can go to and do that
 		um one of the ways i don't know uh if this would be helpful it said on the
 		the computer what do i think would be helpful and i don't know if it would be helpful or not but i know on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> the the garbage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> pick up like just
 		um
 		uh any limbs or any extra trash that you might have
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and that might be an extra day to put out uh things that might be recycled if we had a a certain
 		colored can to put them in or or something in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> to put like either <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glass</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> or whatever
 	
 	
 		yeah i think they already do that out east um they have to it's a little bit more difficult because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have to remember okay <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s glass okay <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX>'s plastic and all that but i think that's the way we need to go it's uh it's pretty bad all these <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> we've been
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		especially in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> all the uh
 		the plastic and the paper and everything we just used to throw out
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		uh i know  getting a newspaper everyday i know i could just you know
 		do that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because i have to pick it up and it just goes out with our trash and i guess i'm not as um
 		recycling minded as i should be but uh that goes out with the trash and it really could be recycled
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about six months ago</TIMEX> i started and yeah and uh so what i do is uh
 	
 	
 		so
 		did you
 		tell me
 	
 	
 		it's not bad you just have to have a place to keep everything but uh it you'll be amazed if you ever start doing it
 		just put your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> in the same place <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> and it'll start stacking up take your glass um you know pickle jars or or whatever um uh liquid jars you know and just
 		rinse them out a little bit and put them all in a place and uh plastics
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		now do you have to take like labels off of those jars
 	
 	
 		no from what i understand uh you can leave the labels on um although i rip rip them off i don't i don't scrub them or anything i just tear them off
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		take them off yeah
 	
 	
 		throw the lids and everything out but uh put all the glass in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> place and plastics like milk jugs uh orange juice jugs things like that
 	
 	
 		soda both liter sodas can you do that okay
 	
 	
 		yes those also um and then of course uh cans <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coke</ENAMEX> cans whatever
 	
 	
 		right right
 	
 	
 		but uh i haven't been down to the recycling <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> yet to find out exactly what they need or what they're taking all that i've just read a lot about it and i'm keeping these big piles of it right now to try to dump it out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this weekend</TIMEX> in fact
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but uh you'd be amazed how quickly  it all stacks up there's a lot that we throw out
 	
 	
 		i i know with our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> that we could really be helpful if we could find a way to just um get it into different categories like that and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i i don't know what it would take to to get my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> to start working on it i
 		i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> older ones that probably would go along with the if i had it arranged so that it wasn't a big project you know
 	
 	
 		it's yeah it's not a big deal you get used to it one let me tell you one interesting thing when i went back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		and i said hey um i understand y'all are taking these bags back uh you know what do you do with them and they had told me  they look through them all and throw out the ones that don't belong there and then you know go and recycle the rest and i said what do you mean the ones that don't belong there
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and they said well you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> come in and put anything in the receptacles and what i found out is if you look at the bottom of those bags <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kroger</ENAMEX> or whatever the plastic ones they've got numbers on them
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh
 	
 	
 		yeah and it's it's got the little recycle symbol and inside it it's got a number like um bags from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drug Emporium</ENAMEX> have a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">four</NUMEX>
 		
 		
 	