
 
     		
 	
 		go ahead what do you have to say on the subject
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well i am a tax <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">preparer</ENAMEX> myself so i do <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about five hundred</NUMEX> income taxes a year in fact i even do television and radio shows here in the
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> market uh regarding income taxes make sure every one pays the  right amount
 		and i am convinced that uh most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> try to hum-um cheat ever so slightly
 		on their tax returns only because uh
 		the way the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> does things they're not gonna give you any breaks i mean they they encourage you to cheat because if you should get audited they're gonna get you for everything and and some more on top of that
 	
 	
 		and then they're gonna tax you on that for or they're gonna give you an interest on it i know somebody that it happened to
 	
 	
 		
 
 		that
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		no see believe it or not i'm one of these honest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX>
 		but i get to the point that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> we took a transfer and so therefore we had the boost in the income due to the transfer expenses when i sat down when we were through and i sat down with our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">accountant</ENAMEX> and we did it
 		if i'm not presently working outside of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> if i return to work
 		believe it or not with our state income tax our city income tax <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> we live in and city we work in
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i would have lost and with social security i would have lost <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">forty eight cents</NUMEX> on every dollar that i earned
 	
 	
 		easily easily
 	
 	
 		and well easily just as you said and i sat down and thought about it and i should be in a pretty good position because i don't have little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> any more that i need
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sitters</ENAMEX> for or anything like that if i go to work it would be for our fun money and we realized that how it would distrupt disrupt our
 		travel routine and things like that and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> gets <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five weeks</TIMEX> vacation and we said it's not worth it i'm not working any more
 	
 	
 		yep
 	
 	
 		it just isn't worth it and you get frustrated and yet i don't know what the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> rules are
 	
 	
 		well see
 		well <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> we are a community property state so we have some a little bit different rules than you have in the separate property <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> such as uh where you in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX> but
 	
 	
 		do you pay a state income income tax
 	
 	
 		we we do not have state income taxes yet but we see it on the horizon it hadn't hit here yet but we do have
 	
 	
 		you don't
 		um they start with one percent and then they get you every <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> year
 	
 	
 		yeah but how much do you pay in sales tax
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> sales tax we pay <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> percent
 	
 	
 		okay we're at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight and a fourth</NUMEX> right now
 	
 	
 		you're so you're higher but you get out-of-towners on that then you get everyone on your state uh sales tax which is good
 	
 	
 		true
 		true true
 	
 	
 		as uh the income tax what's not fair is paying in the city you live in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">right now</TIMEX> we're living where there is a reciprocity
 		so if you do pay more in the city you're working you don't owe your city anything
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s actually keeping track of all his time out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cleveland</ENAMEX> so that we can get the difference because our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> is a little bit less
 	
 	
 		but are you of the fact that when you prepare your tax return now obviously if you have an error in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX>'s favor they're going to be very quick to come back to you and say hey you owe this much more tax
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but if there is an error in your favor they do not come back to you and say oh you get a refund they
 	
 	
 		oh absolutely and much less they don't pay you an interest
 	
 	
 		yeah so you know if what's fair for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">goose</ENAMEX> is good for the gander
 		and unfortunately the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> is saying you know we have screwed y'all so many times that's why so many tax <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">payers</ENAMEX> are starting to cheat more and more which is a shame
 		but i think the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> has brought it on themself because they're not being very helpful to those who have made errors
 		and i think if they would i think if they would come back and say hey look this is wrong this is the way it should be done we're gonna give you some refunds and so forth and actually show an honest effort to be good on both sides of the fence we wanna collect as much tax we also wanna give back as much tax
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		i i think that you'd have a better feeling
 		and you'd have a lot better tax returns being done
 	
 	
 		well and it is now to the point that it has gotten so um
 		so complicated i can do ours in a normal year i have always done our income tax and i've done it with transfers and sale of property
 		but this last time it was so involved that i just threw it all up and said forget it let's go see a CPA well
 	
 	
 		and yet if you went to visit <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> different CPA's you'd get <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> different answers
 	
 	
 		that's what i understand uh this one seemed to do well and uh she did go over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">our last three or four years</TIMEX> and she said i have to compliment you you have excelled she said i cannot find one
 		thing to pull out that you haven't already pulled and i said well i do keep records
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all year</TIMEX> long as i go one on twice a month <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> on
 	
 	
 		i think uh you sound like one of the type of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> i'd love to have
 	
 	
 		well that's what she said i went in there and i had all my books and i said now what do you want to know and i keep every single thing as i write the checks twice a month i enter it
 		uh in either donations wherever it goes i do keep good records and so therefore this time i did not like having to go to someone else because i said well i've got all everything
 	
 	
 		but
 		
 		
 	