
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		now then i think that are you there all right do you have any one that has been in a nursing home
 	
 	
 		uh-huh yeah i'm here
 		uh well uh we may um my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> before very short time um
 		she uh she was just more or less in a in a nursing home for uh recovery from a broken hip
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		because she could receive more medical attention but um that physical therapy was there and whatever but i think in visiting her there
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		um it was very obvious to see that a lot of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the nursing home that she was in uh weren't there mentally uh she was probably the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> in the um
 		whole nursing home  that uh still had all of her mental facilities about her so that was uh that was very disheartening
 	
 	
 		well what do you think can be done about that i mean what can we do
 	
 	
 		oh yeah it's really hard i guess i i come from a family of um
 		of uh take care of your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elders</ENAMEX> i I guess um my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> is an invalid and she lives with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aunt</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncle</ENAMEX> and they care for her you know all around the clock though she's not
 		uh she doesn't have to receive constant medical attention she because of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">arthritis</ENAMEX> she's just unable to get out of bed
 		so i guess you know there's that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> commitment um i know that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s trying to let my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> stay in her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> as long as she can
 		um
 	
 	
 		well i can remember of course i'm old enough to remember when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> took care of all of this
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right yeah
 	
 	
 		we did not have to call on on someone else and i feel
 		no you tell me how you feel about
 	
 	
 		yeah well probably i think as long as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s able to um to understand what's going on around them and i think
 		you know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> right now still able to walk around and she's still able to um
 		to do some things for herself though she gets <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Meals On Wheels</ENAMEX> which i think is a great thing because um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it saves <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from having to prepare her <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> for her because you worry a little bit about her leaving a stove on or whatever though she does most things very well it still makes a little bit easier for her
 	
 	
 		certainly did i worked with an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Texas</ENAMEX> that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">hum-um</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they it's where they really started this concept of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meals On Wheels</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i think it's such a valuable thing for our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elderly</ENAMEX> if they didn't have to you know go into a kitchen
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> hexpired just just a little over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year ago</TIMEX> and we had finally she didn't wanna live with either my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> or me
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but we be got found a retirement <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">center</ENAMEX> for her and it was beautiful and they had all these they didn't even have nursing care there
 		so until as long as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> was you know mobile and got her food and she was with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with whom she enjoyed
 	
 	
 		um-hum right
 		yeah that i think you know it's really funny i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmothers</ENAMEX> still alive and my
 		my one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> says that she wants to stay in her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> for as long as possible she's like openly told <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> she's always been very good about knowing yes she's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty nine</NUMEX> and she said that she really would like to stay in her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> as long as possible because it's her home
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		but when the time comes um
 		she and she can't do things and she has to be cared for or whatever she would prefer and she's actually said this to move into some type of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> where she has her own apartment
 		uh probably with like a living space and a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedroom</ENAMEX> with maybe a kitchenette
 	
 	
 		yes sir
 	
 	
 		so that if she you know if she wants to fix herself something light she can do that but if she wants to go to a meal she can go down the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hallway</ENAMEX>
 		uh to a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> where there's a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cafeteria</ENAMEX> and there's other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> there and she can mix with them and talk with them and enjoy their company
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		being a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">widow</ENAMEX> i find that eating alone is one of the hardest things i have to do
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yes
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i have just recently retired and i am finding it extremely hard to adjust to
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		so uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> had the little kitchenette and she could do all these fine things that she just
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		had had a microwave had to pop her popcorn now this is wonderful but when it came time for a full meal
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		then <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> was able to go with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and and enjoy it
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah i think i think that probably until invalids until they're really invalids elderly the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elderly</ENAMEX> are invalids
 		i think that they should be able to interact with other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in in an environment that they choose if they can if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> can afford it i think um and see i know that
 	
 	
 		oh i think so too
 		well
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> would like to stay in her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> actually said you know that they may have to take their end <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sometime so</TIMEX> because you know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandma</ENAMEX> actually says who she wants to live with she's pretty you know she lets <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> know
 		so
 		
 		
 	