
 
     		
 	
 		okay we're on
 	
 	
 		okay well i just on on gun control i just always felt like that i think
 		i don't think it hurts for anybody to wait for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week or two</TIMEX> before they get a gun if somebody goes in to buy one so that they can check that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> out um
 		i don't believe that most of the criminal acts that are done are done by <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> that are bought in a gun shop though i believe it's probably
 		bought across the market and i don't think gun control is gonna have any control over that at all
 	
 	
 		so uh you're you're for no restrictions or
 	
 	
 		uh uh sort of a a little bit of restriction maybe i might say
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		if a criminal if a criminal should go happen to go into a gun store i don't think it would hurt anybody to wait a week
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		to go back and pick up that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> so that they can check them out
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right
 	
 	
 		and if it is somebody like that then no but i really think that most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> in our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> who have <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> do not go into a gun store and buy them i think they get them from other means
 	
 	
 		i what kind what what kind of means would those be
 	
 	
 		oh i don't know like from each other you know uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> in other words you're saying that it would be hard uh to get rid of all of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
  
 		i think so
 	
 	
 		well doesn't it doesn't doesn't <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> have a ban on firearms
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">England</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">jeez</ENAMEX> now i don't know
 	
 	
 		yeah don't they carry don't their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policemen</ENAMEX> over there carry these billy clubs
 	
 	
 		that's right nobody over there carries guns
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i don't know if we could get away with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> completely i guess
 	
 	
 		well it would be nice uh uh to be able to take your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> out uh especially when they're dependent on you and not worry about uh having to have a gun just to protect yourself and them
 	
 	
 		that's right i agree with that i agree with that i we do not own one um
 		and i don't intend to buy <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and i'm not a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hunter</ENAMEX> i guess those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> feel a little bit different but i don't believe in hunting either so  you know
 	
 	
 		well i have a couple of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> and uh one i always worry about somebody getting ahold of it that that you know won't know how to handle it
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and uh probably never will do me any good because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bullets</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> place and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firearm</ENAMEX>'s in another
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i carry <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> in the pickup uh and i worry about it being stolen and uh of course i'm like you i don't like to kill things
 	
 	
 		no i don't either  well it is terrible when you have to ride down the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> and think somebody could just shoot at you for nothing which has been in the news a lot lately you know no apparent reason
 	
 	
 		so
 		
  
 		oh yeah and and there's a lot
 		the crazies are out there in numbers
 	
 	
 		right right
 	
 	
 		well you know i would love to see a ban uh on firearms and i'd have to rate myself as a number one however i worry that that the that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> could ever get to that point
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		and then i worry about uh the fact that uh what if there was some sort of insurrection in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> in this country
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		then uh how would we as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> uh band together and ever put down an uprising if there were no firearms
 	
 	
 		uprising
 		you think we could ever get to that point where there would be no firearms
 	
 	
 		i don't think we ever will
 	
 	
 		i don't either that's the problem not in this country
 	
 	
 		yeah so somewhere somewhere along the line then uh you know there has to be a happy medium and uh i know the the uh oh what's the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> that uh
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">rifle</ENAMEX> association
 	
 	
 		oh yes
 	
 	
 		the gun the uh the gun <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">association</ENAMEX> is is heavily for no bans whatsoever
 	
 	
 		yeah well i think we ought to have some
 	
 	
 		yeah well i think so too so i'd have to vote for uh uh maybe a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> in uh and hopefully uh we could put some sort of restriction on the handling of firearms
 	
 	
 		right i could go for that
 	
 	
 		like like you suggested
 	
 	
 		yeah i think that would i think that's the only way
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">okay Betty</ENAMEX> well sounds good enough to me then
 	
 	
 		well
 		i've enjoyed talking to you
 	
 	
 		well same here and uh one of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> that name's gonna come back to me
 	
 	
 		
  
 		oh me me too okay bye-bye
 	
 	
 		okay sweetheart bye-bye
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	