
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay what do you think about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school systems</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh well
 		where i live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plano</ENAMEX> one of their big things that they hype it within the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> is their school system
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		and uh in fact i think that there's some areas of of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richardson</ENAMEX> that are in the those <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city town</ENAMEX> city limits but they uh
 		all of the the housing developments adjoining <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plano</ENAMEX> are in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plano</ENAMEX> school district and they use that as one of the things that they
 		uh you know that they try to market when they sell <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> in that area the fact that it is in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plano</ENAMEX> schools
 		uh i do have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in that school system uh
 		and have been personally pleased with that uh i'm not sure that it's that that there's that much glory in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plano</ENAMEX> schools versus say <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richardson</ENAMEX> and some of the other areas
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		what do you see as being a problem with the school system
 	
 	
 		uh
 		probably the biggest controversy within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">our school</TIMEX> system
 		is the use of the open classroom concept
 		uh where uh
 		all uh all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> at a given grade level are in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> large area for much of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> uh segregated you know by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> but not necessarily having walls between the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">classrooms</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh i've now had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> that are have been in the system in the system
 		uh one who seemed to do just fine in that tap type of atmosphere the other i'm not so sure about because of uh his attention span i think he's a little bit more easily distracted than was she
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and that seems to be the primary complaint uh
 		i think my biggest complaint problem with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plano</ENAMEX> schools right now is that many of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> do not have cafeterias and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> have to take their lunch back to their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">classroom</ENAMEX> to eat
 		uh rather than giving them a a break from that area during <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the day</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and
 		uh
 		that's  i guess i'm a fairly satisfied uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> as far as the school system goes myself uh
 		that
 		that it really boils down to the quality of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and their interest uh in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> individually is going to make the difference versus you know physical things such as the open <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">classroom</ENAMEX> versus a more closed classroom
 		uh what do you see as problems
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well i don't have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and it's been so long since i was in school myself i'm not really sure how to answer that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		when uh  i don't know it seems that they're you know that that the difference is between each school i think if it was
 		if it could possibly be standardized a little bit that it would be much easier to to gauge you know how uh a particular group of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> was doing
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh the curriculums differ so much and i'm not saying that that's bad necessarily but i think it makes very hard to tell where an actual problem is
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know you can't really tell from a group of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> if it's a if if it's the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> that's got the problem or if it's the book that's got the problem you know what the materials that they're using and everything
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		that could be causing a problem
 	
 	
 		now in in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> i know at least at some of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later</TIMEX> grade levels they have these magnet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> that i think were initially set up to address the segregation issues
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and i wondered uh what the real overall effect on education is of those uh i know i have a niece in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> system that
 		is a uh was just elected to go or selected whatever i i think you have to apply and be accepted to these magnet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> but she's interested in the arts and in in particular in dance
 	
 	
 		what kind of school is that
 	
 	
 		uh they call it a magnet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> where it attracts <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> of certain interest
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		and uh she will be attending i think <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Skyline Arts Magnet</ENAMEX> uh or arts and
 		something  magnet school uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX> when she enters high school
 	
 	
 		yeah i think that's kind of a good idea because
 		you know it doesn't it doesn't
 		it doesn't divide <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> by
 		by anything besides what they're interests are
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and it's a much higher it's a learning environment if you're <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> if you're interested in sciences and you're grouped with other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are interested in sciences
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it seems like it would it would uh it would help
 	
 	
 		now i would think that would would be a good point as well
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		they they don't have that type of thing in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plano</ENAMEX> they just have these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> gargantuan  high schools
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh but i do think they do provide some type of special interest focus i think the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later years</TIMEX> uh for for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay
 		what do you think about about sports in high school and about uh the competitiveness
 		i've i've know i've seen in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plano</ENAMEX> that there's a lot of really vicious competitiveness between the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> at the different high schools
 	
 	
 		well
 	
 	
 		and do you think that's healthy
 	
 	
 		oh not really uh i've not been that aware of it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh i live on it is somewhat divided by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">east</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">west Plano</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central Expressway</ENAMEX> down the middle
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and i am on the west side but just barely on the west side i guess my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are younger than that
 		and in they're in the non competitive uh just athletics uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> you know your typical <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">soccer and baseball</ENAMEX> and all that sort of stuff
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and because of where we live uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> has been on has have been from both sides of the fence if you will
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		they've drawn from both sides and i really haven't sensed any of that yet i it may become more obvious to me in later on
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i think the one of the more interesting things in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plano</ENAMEX> is that they have high <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and senior high schools
 		which a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't realize that
 		that <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">ninth</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">tenth</NUMEX> grade go to high <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> of which there there are quite a few in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plano</ENAMEX> and the senior high <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> are only the eleventh and twelfth grade
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		now i didn't even realize that at all
 	
 	
 		yeah that's was very different uh they have middle school <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">sixth seventh</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">eighth</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 		right
 	
 	
 		and then they'll have uh fact they have a couple of huge <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> that are actually almost all
 		middle school and elementary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> all of those grades in one building
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		but uh
 	
 	
 		well i know they've got a lot of elementary schools
 	
 	
 		for the most part
 		yeah bunch of elementary and they typically feed certain middle <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">sixth seventh</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">eighth</NUMEX> and then there a number at least i could probably think of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>
 		high schools
 	
 	
 		well now what is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shepton</ENAMEX> going to be
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shepton</ENAMEX> is a high school
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ninth</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">tenth</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		and uh there's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shepton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vines</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilson</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Williams</ENAMEX> and there's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX> and
 		i don't know whether there's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than four</NUMEX> i want to say that there are more than just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> but uh it's just <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">ninth</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">tenth</NUMEX> grade and then the the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> senior high <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> are just eleventh and twelfth graders
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		which is a sort of a different concept
 	
 	
 		yeah that does seem kind of different
 	
 	
 		and they're they're just so big i'm a little bothered by that uh just the sheer
 		
 		
 	