
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 		well <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy</ENAMEX>  uh as as i was talking
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> uh his name is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ainsley</ENAMEX> and he was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conductor</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goldman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">band</ENAMEX> and they did park concerts at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln Center</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		uh during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> season uh they were free concerts but he was with that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> for like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty one years</TIMEX> and uh did both very traditional marches a lot of you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Phillips Sousa</ENAMEX> and
 		uh all of and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franco Goldman</ENAMEX> in fact the name of the uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX> was because
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the famous uh march <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">composers</ENAMEX> of all time uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Franco Goldman</ENAMEX> and his son <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edwin</ENAMEX> actually i may may have those reversed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> and son
 		started the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX> like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seventy years ago</TIMEX> i think so it's the oldest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> really of it's type in the country
 		and uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> became involved with them over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years ago</TIMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> and then ended up being both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conductor</ENAMEX> for quite a number of years
 	
 	
 		oh that that must have been wonderful  were you able to hear
 	
 	
 		so
 		well i was able to uh to hear him about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years ago</TIMEX> for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time at a a concert there  and uh it was quite enjoyable um
 	
 	
 		yeah sometimes
 	
 	
 		in that uh he also had one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">composers</ENAMEX> well actually there were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">composers</ENAMEX> that he used were actually there at the performance also
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		so i got to meet them and in particular i got to go to the rehearsal before hand
 		and that was when i realized how good he really was was at a rehearsal as opposed to an actually performance of uh working with the musicians
 		and and one of his biggest struggles uh with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX> was that this was all union musicians
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		which didn't give him a lot of leeway once they were in the band
 		uh he had a very difficult time replacing them no matter how they were performing at that particular season
 		and uh he ended up with some very unusual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> in that that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> it was easy to tell that just from the rehearsal time
 		but uh anyway what were you going to tell me about your dad
 	
 	
 		well um actually that lead into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a couple</NUMEX> different things um my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> worked with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX> um
 		for placing so he could really relate to what you were saying but um
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> enjoyed opera and classical music and ballets and so um even as a child i got to go
 		to a lot of different um
 		kinds of musical events
 		um i grew up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Detroit</ENAMEX> and so we had opportunities for a wide range of things um one of the
 		regrets i have is that i grew up with a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> filled with classical music and music that i really loved but i never took the time to
 		find out um who the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">composers</ENAMEX> were or it it was just always there and there were certain things that um
 		i liked so much but i still have trouble to this day sometimes i will recognize a passage but i'll have no idea what it's from or whose it is and um over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last few years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and when my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> lived with us um i made more of an effort to learn but um that's something that i
 		regretted but um when you mentioned the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX> music my
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> just started high school <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> and has been in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX> since middle school but this was the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> year
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		with marching <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX> and i really enjoy band music um it
 	
 	
 		oh yeah i i was in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX> in high school and that
 	
 	
 		oh what instrument did you play
 	
 	
 		i played the clarinet
 	
 	
 		oh i like that a
 	
 	
 		and uh  so i i did that my all through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">high school</ENAMEX> and then i guess my <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">first year</TIMEX> in college i played but it wasn't a marching <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX> it was just a it was a symphonic band
 		and uh ironically in college the marching <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX> was part of the athletic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> rather than the music department
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and i was i was in the symphonic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX> that was actually part of the music <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> and i thought that was pretty unusual
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		what uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim</ENAMEX> played a trombone in high school and he also played in a a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX> in college not marching <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX> but
 	

 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">symphonic</ENAMEX> and that was
 		really the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time that i got to hear a lot of the um
 		band music and some of the wonderful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">composers</ENAMEX> other than the traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Sousa</ENAMEX> and things that everybody knows and
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		so i've
 		enjoyed this so much um with our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> now doing that and he plays tuba  so i don't don't get to see him when he's doing um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		a tuba tuba
 	
 	
 		concerts we just see the top of the bell at the back but in marching season he's easy to pick out
 	
 	
 		
 
 		right well does he bring the tuba home to
 	
 	
 		yes uh
 	
 	
 		oh my goodness
 	
 	
 		we uh
 		
 
 		laughed when they're in <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">sixth</NUMEX> grade and they try them out on instruments and try to find the appropriate instruments we thought of suggesting that they ought to also find out what <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicles</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> drive because
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh the tuba and the sousaphone don't fit in in every kind of uh car
 	
 	
 		yeah just anything i have a niece that plays the harp
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and she found the same thing that uh she had i think what they call a troubadour harp for a while and that she learned on and trained on but then uh
 		uh a harp became available which there are just not very many instruments uh and a used harp became available in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> and they lived in in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Missouri</ENAMEX> at the time
 		and they actually drove to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> to buy this instrument but they first had to go and buy a full sized
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">station wagon</ENAMEX>
 		uh so they'd have room to bring it home
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and that's dictated their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every</TIMEX> since then just having <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> large enough for a full you know concert harp
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		that she plays
 		uh
 		well i uh because of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>'s uh work with music for a long time he was a
 		uh a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Music Journal</ENAMEX>
 		and as a result of that he
 		well that was part of the reason he ended up with this incredible classical album uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> or collection which i have now inherited
 		and um
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		i i don't listen to in nearly enough it's the same sort of thing there's so much music that i recognize but don't who is yeah who is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">composer</ENAMEX>
 		but i've
 		based on just measuring number of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">inches</NUMEX> or in this case feet of albums that i think i have about a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a uh two thousand album</NUMEX> classical record collection now
 	
 	
 		oh gosh
 	
 	
 		so i figured that uh i could probably listen to a different album <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day of the year</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about seven years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		God
 	
 	
 		if i wanted to at this point
 		but then it's hard to find a place to stack that much music
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		most of it is still in boxes stacked quite high in a back room
 		but uh
 		anyway
 		um
 	
 	
 		well he must have collected that over a period of years
 	
 	
 		well he really did uh i know that he was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> probably in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early sixties</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> he had um
 		we were thirteen and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a half years</TIMEX> apart i think and he left home at like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixteen</TIMEX> to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Westminster Choir College</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		and you know he did not finish high school he just went straight straight to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Westminster</ENAMEX> s o i never really remember having lived at home with him
 		and after he did get out of college it was not long he
 		before he uh just moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> knowing that that's where he had to live to quote unquote make it in the music world
 		and um became a music <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> and that probably puts us somewhere around <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early sixties</TIMEX> uh when he was doing that
 		i've seen that date a good bit on the uh on some of the albums because he would typically uh sign and date everything that
 		i think everything that he owned he did that with but certainly all of his albums and all of the music uh he had signed and dated
 	
 	
 		i was going to ask you and it seemed that there must have been a big gap um i also have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> who's thirteen <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years older</TIMEX> and one who's nineteen <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> older you you don't run into that very often
 	
 	
 		my goodness
 		you have one that's nineteen <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> older
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		my goodness
 		that is a wide spread
 		well we were at the opposite ends there were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> in between
 		but uh because he left home so early i think there was one summer i can remember him living at home and i was maybe <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six years old</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i mean other than that uh i don't even ever remember living in in the same <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> with him at all
 	
 	
 		oh i'm glad you got to go and hear him in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> though that um that must have been
 		very special
 	
 	
 		well it was it was thrilling
 		um my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> was with me at the time and it was ironically it was the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time that we'd seen him conduct that particular group which he'd been with so long
 		she had seen him fact she had seen him conduct in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carnegie Hall</ENAMEX> before
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> and i'm not sure it was probably the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Symphony Orchestra</ENAMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leopold Stokowlski</ENAMEX> was
 		uh in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> that was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stokowlski</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">orchestra</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ainsley</ENAMEX> was an associate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conductor</ENAMEX> with him for quite a while  and it at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point did in fact uh
 		uh conduct there at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carnegie Hall</ENAMEX> so she got to see him there and i i didn't
 		
 		
 	