
 
     		
 	
 		where is your favorite place to go
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well we haven't traveled outside the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> that much um we usually take family type vacations we're looking forward to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disneyworld</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh that's great have you ever been there
 	
 	
 		a have a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nine year old</TIMEX>  when when both of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> were much younger and this time we're gonna be going with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">just one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> and she's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> so it ought to just be a ball
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh that's a perfect age for Disneyworld
 	
 	
 		uh-huh i think so too
 	
 	
 		oh that's great yeah so we've been there a number of times and uh we're going <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX> we have a business trip <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every fall</TIMEX> well we go on a lot of business trips i
 	
 	
 		oh wonderful so you travel a lot
 	
 	
 		i don't work well we do we go my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> travels <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a couple</NUMEX> times a month and in the position he's in they don't care if i go along
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so it's great i just kind of join up when it's something interesting and uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Disneyworld</ENAMEX> is the one for a week next year
 	
 	
 		sure
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it'll be at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this time of the year</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> we're leaving um uh matter of fact we're leaving <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next Saturday</TIMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Orleans</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh that'll be fun too yes we went <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> we haven't been lately and i know they've changed it a lot and upgraded everything but we used to have a lot of fun there
 	
 	
 		have have you ever been there
 		well you know we went there once in fact we had been in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> and we were on our way <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> and we were driving and we said let's go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Orleans</ENAMEX> so when he said well <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> you know i have a week there on a
 		a project he's going to be and then i said well i'll go along i hope it's swimming <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX> because it wasn't a tremendous thing not amount of things to do that i wanted to do there
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah if you don't like the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> life and the antique shopping there isn't much there but that can be fun
 	
 	
 		it well and and that's probably we do like the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> life to an extent and they do have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mardi Gras</ENAMEX> night planned
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i'm kind of anxious for that but um yours to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disneyworld</ENAMEX> sounds  a little bit better
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		did you know that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX> there's several TV shows coming from there in celebration of their anniversary
 	
 	
 		no i know this is a real good time to go because they are having so many activities and special shows
 	
 	
 		well and with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> it is just she's old enough to really grasp the meaning behind
 	
 	
 		yes be excited about all of it
 	
 	
 		uh if so uh well if you're working then you're probably on a limited amount of time per year that you can go
 	
 	
 		well not really uh we're doing the same thing tying it in with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s business trip and i just save vacation for things like that and uh just travel whenever we can
 	
 	
 		oh that's
 		well i really i think travel when i heard my topic <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> i thought okay that's my favorite that's my favorite because
 	
 	
 		
 
 		how easy
 		right
 	
 	
 		and really at our point of life our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are grown and um it has just worked out really well with this um
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		position he's in because i can go at a spur of the moment or what have you and it depends where he's going
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		whether or not i decide to go along but i do do like to travel and it's um i don't mind the pool life at all during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> and i like to sightseeing and i love to shop
 	
 	
 		sure
 		
  
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		um-hum  so that's perfect what more could you ask for
 	
 	
 		so it's
 		that's right but if this
 	
 	
 		and then get to pick and choose the places
 	
 	
 		well and one of my very favorite is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX> um that i would have to say we both end up going to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX> um probably once every maybe <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> and a half
 	
 	
 		ah
 		
  
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and presently we have quite a few frequent flyer miles and so i've just requested that they send us <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX> tickets because we have a lot of flying with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Continental</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they're recommending that you use those because they don't know the future of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Continental</ENAMEX> and i said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> that we have all the miles we better start using them
 	
 	
 		right it's kind of shaky
 		that's true it really is
 	
 	
 		uh so we are thinking that we might go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the winter this year</TIMEX> sometime for
 		just kind of a quick trip um when we normally go that way we like to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> at the same time because we really don't get out there as often as you could probably from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um-hum our last big trip we drove through <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Mexico</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> and went to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grand Canyon</ENAMEX> and and uh
 		back through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Silverton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Durango</ENAMEX> and oh it was fun it was so relaxing and a really neat part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> were old enough to really enjoy it our
 	
 	
 		i think that's a good trip and really for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> to learn as well for a family vacation that would be excellent
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		now we did what we sometimes do since we are in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX> and it takes a while just to even get to the
 		what i would call the more picturesque part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> we will fly to something like once we flew to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Denver</ENAMEX> and then we rented a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks</TIMEX> and we went through the northern route and through <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">as far</NUMEX> west as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX> and then we returned through uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Mexico</ENAMEX> that you just mentioned and it was oh it was just great
 	
 	
 		um-hum oh there's so too much to see really you just
 	
 	
 		oh i i think that's that's the way to
 		
 		
 	