
 
     		
 	
 		all right this is easy for me since i
 	
 	
 		
 
 		and me too because i eat out a lot
 	
 	
 		yeah  well i travel i do about forty percent of my time is on the road
 	
 	
 		so you eat all your meals out
 	
 	
 		i eat a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meals</ENAMEX> out um well i'm also married my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> is  A1 <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cook</ENAMEX> but she enjoys eating out so i have to
 		share it with her  and uh actually it's very easy for me because i i have a practice make it a practice when i am out i eat differently than what i could eat at home or around here
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		so so i look for just about anything and it's it's uh
 		it's a lot of fun i don't have to worry really worry too much about price considerations because i you know
 	
 	
 		i was gonna ask you could you go to you know nice <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">places</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		oh sure yeah and it's it's really great i i
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i like different types of food
 	
 	
 		so where are your places what what are places you you know memorable places you've eaten
 	
 	
 		uh oh you name okay you name it let's see you've got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> down in uh
 		down near uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Addison</ENAMEX>
 		um there's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> that i particularly like that i eat every time i get into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> or i get into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta Georgia</ENAMEX> i make sure i go and that's <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX>'s
 	
 	
 		oh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX>'s uh-huh
 	
 	
 		yep okay
 	
 	
 		it's a great place
 	
 	
 		it's it's great there's a a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> in um
 		right outside of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Reading Pennsylvania</ENAMEX> it's called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alfredo</ENAMEX>'s
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that does not look like
 		a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> that you would really wanna recommend to a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> but it is fabulous fantastic
 		uh there's a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> and i don't recall the name of it uh  in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Panama City</ENAMEX> of course not too <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people wanna</ENAMEX> rush back to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Panama City</ENAMEX> uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Panama</ENAMEX>
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Panama</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh okay because i was thinking well i i grew up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Panama City</ENAMEX> i get it
 	
 	
 		okay
 		no this is the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> this is the country <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Panama</ENAMEX> all right
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		but i have gotten to quite a few and i go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX> and get quite a few <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> up there i
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		you know and i know the locations and i know the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">places</ENAMEX> but i lot of times i don't remember the names i'd have to go back through some expense reports
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but particularly in down in your area i'm looking for some some more <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX>
 		so i you know i don't know what's what's down there other  the ones in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Addison</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		do you like <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> do you like <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> food oh
 	
 	
 		not particularly that's one of the few why which <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> were you gonna recommend
 	
 	
 		well i mean there's so many places here you know they're just it's just lots of good <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> here
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Addison</ENAMEX> well about everything that you could want in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> is in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Addison</ENAMEX> area anyway
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		i mean now there's a new <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> place called Sfuzzi
 	
 	
 		okay i have a
 	
 	
 		that has a great i've not been there but it has a great reputation as one of the best <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> and now there's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Addison</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay let i'm i'm writing it down
 	
 	
 		it's F S it's <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">S F U Z I</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		and it's on it's in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Addison</ENAMEX> and it's a great place also a great place that they have like <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Cajun</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Copeland</ENAMEX>'s
 	
 	
 		i've been there
 	
 	
 		oh i really like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Copeland</ENAMEX>'s
 	
 	
 		okay i've been there um <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> down there is the uh i think it's an old schoolhouse uh
 	
 	
 		oh the yeah  the i know no i don't like that place
 	
 	
 		well i like the food but i don't care for the clowning around
 	
 	
 		see uh uh yeah actually  actually when i went i thought the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> was not good
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Magic Time Machine</ENAMEX> is the place you're thinking of
 	
 	
 		oh i've had i
 		that's it that's it i've had excellent food there
 	
 	
 		see i when i went i thought the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> drove me crazy <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of all but then i just thought the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> was over priced for what it was
 	
 	
 		true true
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yeah all right well that's great uh no <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> that's fine i'm i
 		make it a habit of always going out to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pasta Oggi</ENAMEX>'s
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		which is right down there in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Addison</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		do you like like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southwestern</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		well now there's a good place in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Addison</ENAMEX> too called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blue Mesa Grill</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		all right
 	
 	
 		that's on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beltline</ENAMEX> that's close to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX>'s a matter of fact and um
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		it's great i mean they're they have i think sometimes i've been when i thought well it wasn't as good but i went there recently and i thought well this really is good
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so that's that's a very good place to eat The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blue Mesa Grill</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		good
 	
 	
 		and um
 	
 	
 		well this is great this is gonna give me a
 		some more places to go  okay fine
 	
 	
 		a whole new  dining experience
 	
 	
 		i guess our time's about up so
 	
 	
 		well they haven't beeped us have they
 	
 	
 		uh well they don't always
 	
 	
 		oh i thought sometimes they say you know this is <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three minutes</TIMEX> or whatever
 	
 	
 		yeah i
 		they've been doing that when uh the circuits are busy
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		and uh other than that they you know leave you go about <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five minutes</TIMEX> and then that that's about it i guess that's what they need for their machines to get everything down pat so
 	
 	
 		okay well thanks for calling for helping us out bye-bye
 	
 	
 		it was a pleasure talking you okay
 		you bet
 		bye-bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	