
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cathy</ENAMEX> do you have any <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pets</ENAMEX> in your home
 	
 	
 		we do actually we have a a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Golden Retriever</ENAMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> and we have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> and we have we just got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> um
 	
 	
 		how nice um-hum
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Russian Dwarf</ENAMEX> hamsters  which  dwarf hamsters lucky us huh
 	
 	
 		dwarf hamsters
 		how big is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dwarf</ENAMEX> hamster
 	
 	
 		real small they're maybe about oh <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">two inches</NUMEX> long they're real small they're real tiny they're cute they really are cute
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 		my goodness where did you get those
 	
 	
 		uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>'s baseball <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX> uh had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> and then had multiple  hamsters that he was trying to get rid of
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so that's that's where we got them from now we've been assured they're both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">males</ENAMEX> and they're in two separate cages so we don't want any
 	
 	
 		well
 		okay
 		i was going to say that
 	
 	
 		we don't want to go into the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dwarf</ENAMEX> hamster business
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh
 	
 	
 		how about you
 	
 	
 		well right now we don't have any <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pets</ENAMEX> we've uh we've tried various things we you know obviously do have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh we tried a dog <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> and we had a a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">puppy</ENAMEX> a uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		a what did they call him a Westie
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> is uh is are they very small uh-huh
 	
 	
 		they're small uh-huh it's a terrier and uh that didn't work out very well
 	
 	
 		oh uh-huh
 	
 	
 		and uh for a variety of reasons but the
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> was just all mouth and teeth it seemed like the only way it could of show affection was by nibbling you on things
 	
 	
 		oh really yeah
 		oh no kidding uh-huh
 	
 	
 		yeah so it it never worked out and uh
 		so we we have we gave up on that and then we tried cats
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and we ended up with a
 		a bad set of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX> if that's possible but i'm a i'm a big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX> i always had cats growing up
 	
 	
 		oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		are you yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> on the other hand was not a fan of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX> at all but we had these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> that they we knew someone that uh uh you know wanted to get rid of these kittens and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh so we gave it a try
 		and uh they were impossible to house train
 	
 	
 		really <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> that's real unusual for <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX> usually you just put down a litter box and that's the end of that yeah
 	
 	
 		that's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of that</TIMEX> and these it was real strange and uh they were both solid white <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh one had blue eyes and the other had white regular you know yellow eyed <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">brothers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> and we had them declawed and we had them neutered and uh invested all all that money in it into it but uh we simply one of them in particular we just could not uh
 		train to use we tried different types of litter changed it frequently and it was just unbelievable
 	
 	
 		really really huh huh
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and so we finally found someone else that was willing to to to give it a try with them
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and sure enough it it worked worked worked for a little while and then they too couldn't seem to get them to use the litter box
 	
 	
 		really really hum
 	
 	
 		uh so they ended up finding someone else that was willing to give it a try and that's when i lost track of these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		really yeah yeah oh that's too bad
 	
 	
 		yeah that was that was pretty sad because uh it took a lot of lobbying just to get the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> to begin with so we sure couldn't make another try at it
 	
 	
 		sure sure sure
 		yeah yeah well we were real fortunate with our <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pets um</ENAMEX> when my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and i were getting married we we had both been married before and so we were blending <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> and we had taken this blended <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> course through uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">P I S T</ENAMEX> you know they how they have the effective parent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> training effectiveness effectiveness training
 	
 	
 		hum
 		right
 		right
 	
 	
 		and uh so we took a blended <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> course and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Hitt</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who was teaching the course said sometimes when you have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> on this side and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> on this side
 		you have a you know a mutual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> that brings the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> together and we looked at each other and laughed and said we'll get a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX>  and uh
 	
 	
 		yeah i bet that's funny
 	
 	
 		and uh so we i had always wanted a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Golden Retriever i</ENAMEX> just think they're real <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">neat dogs</ENAMEX> that that's a nice <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">breed</ENAMEX> you know they're real calm and gentle and
 		and whatnot so my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> thought well for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> he was going to surprise me with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">puppy</ENAMEX> and he was looking around for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">puppy</ENAMEX> and
 		then um he saw he decided just on a whim i think i'll call the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SPCA</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and he called the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">SPCA</ENAMEX> and he said you wouldn't happen to have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Golden Retriever</ENAMEX> would you and they said you won't believe it but we had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> dropped off last night
 	
 	
 		good grief
 	
 	
 		and he'd they said he's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AKC</ENAMEX> registered he's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years old</TIMEX> and he's going to go fast
 	
 	
 		i'll bet yeah
 	
 	
 		so we thought okay what's wrong with this <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> who would give up a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two year</TIMEX> old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Golden Retriever</ENAMEX> you know that's a nice dog something's got to be wrong with this dog
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		nothing is wrong with it we have had him now for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX> and just love him to death he is wonderful yeah he is he's a great <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> he's he's
 	
 	
 		well that's great
 	
 	
 		he makes a real lousy uh watchdog though because he he just loves everybody and he wags his tail and you know
 		he's he's great he's great we just we think he's wonderful
 		and our <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> just kind of you know pays us the time of day when he's in the mood and otherwise
 		we don't see him
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		is it primarily outdoor <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> then or just
 	
 	
 		yeah he is he comes in and he goes out he's he kind of
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know is just around we we don't really don't see him except for feeding time you know or when he wants when he's in the mood for a little affection
 	
 	
 		that's interesting
 		he'll show up huh
 	
 	
 		he'll show up yeah yeah
 		but so that's our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and we just you know uh everybody seems to get along real well the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> so we're okay
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">great</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		well has the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> discovered the uh the hamsters yet
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hamsters</ENAMEX> actually it's the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> that is enthralled with the hamsters because the hamsters are recent you know they were just last week
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and
 		the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> we had them
 		somebody knocked over the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cage</ENAMEX> and we thought it was the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> we really did we blamed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> and we thought the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hamster</ENAMEX> had disappeared and had been eaten but we found him he he just he narrowly escaped with his life but he was found
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but since then we have discovered the dog sits and watches them for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> on end
 	
 	
 		oh my goodness
 	
 	
 		you know they'll get going in the little wheel and he'll sit there and just stare at them so i'm wondering now if it really was the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> who knocked them off the shelf it might have been it might have been the dog
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> doesn't seem to be too bothered with them it's it's the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> that just sits there for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hour</TIMEX> after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hour</TIMEX> and watches these hamsters it's it's funny
 	
 	
 		i'll be and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> has tried that with both hamsters gerbils and small birds
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it's amazing what their <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> has been able to do
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		i think that pretty much over time has figured out a way to get those small creatures
 	
 	
 		out really
 	
 	
 		eventually to get them out to get the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cage</ENAMEX> down from wherever it is even if it's the top of the refrigerator
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		to get that <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cage</ENAMEX> down and into it somehow
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah well we warned them you the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> you know we said you know with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> you know these may not last too long
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		is that right
 	
 	
 		but he doesn't seem to be bothered with them you know he's real content you know chasing flies and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">birds</ENAMEX> outside so you know he's he's not too bad
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but so are you going to try again with another <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> sometime
 	
 	
 		well i would like to we shall see i want it to be a you know indoor outdoor animal next time
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		
 		
 	