
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh do you want to give a start on it
 	
 	
 		well i think for me i i'm from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alabama</ENAMEX> south <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alabama</ENAMEX> and so i grew up in the midst of civil rights movement
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
  
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh in a pretty liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> for for that area at the time
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so i was very much a part of all the uh  you know what was going on there uh
 	
 	
 		uh-hum
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> are pretty active and uh it was very scary and but now we've seen you know  uh black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have a lot more civil rights
 		in that area and i guess all over than they did you know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years ago</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh definitely
 	
 	
 		there's still a lot to be  you know to be accomplished but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		for me when i think about social change that's what i <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> think of because i can remember you know separate public restrooms and separate water fountains and sitting in the back of the bus and everything
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		you can relate to that now see we didn't we don't have any of that because well like we live in the country
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Clarion County</ENAMEX> and uh
 		we really didn't have things like that going on that we you know uh ran into
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so we kind of uh i guess when i think of social changes i think think more of uh
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh</ENAMEX> visiting habits of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> and such uh uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well that's true
 		that's a good one right there
 	
 	
 		yeah that there's less visiting done i think on a whole than there used to be used to be that you took the family whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> wanted to go or not you went visiting
 		and uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> they do visit but it's not quite the same as uh what it was say <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years ago thirty years ago</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		right and i grew up in out in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> too basically in a rural <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">area</ENAMEX> and with lots of family
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so we were always at <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> in different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> but even now you know they don't even do that
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well they're so spread out i think has a lot to do with it
 	
 	
 		well and they're so busy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people people</ENAMEX>'s personal schedules are so busy
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		mainly because i a lot of it has to do i think with more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> working in our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> you know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years ago</TIMEX> not that many of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> worked and now uh almost all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> work
 	
 	
 		right right
 		that's right yeah
 		the majority yeah uh-huh
 	
 	
 		and so that means you know a lot of  a lot of the social visiting and all was i think probably instigated by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> at that time right and now
 	
 	
 		probably because when you work
 		you don't really care to go out and visit as much
 	
 	
 		that's right and now uh i mean my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> does not work and and she you know she's finds finds herself pretty alone a lot because most of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> are working women
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but even just social visits <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't do that anymore you're right and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't feel comfortable just to drop in on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> anymore
 	
 	
 		no huh-uh they don't do as much
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		there's a real
 	
 	
 		you have to make arrangements or have an invitation or
 	
 	
 		right you know you don't want to you want to make sure it's okay or i guess we don't not to make invade <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s privacy or whatever
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		well that could be part of it i don't know for sure what it is i know our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> mostly are scattered out at a distance so
 		we really don't have that even we don't yeah
 	
 	
 		well out of out of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fifteen grandchildren</ENAMEX> in my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> only <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of us don't live within fifty miles
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		and that and most live within <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ten or or twenty so</TIMEX> but that's you know that is rural it's a rural <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		oh that's pretty good yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> didn't go away i'm just one of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> out of fifteen that don't live in the you know even in the same state
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well apparently there must be work available
 	
 	
 		yeah there is in that area
 	
 	
 		for those that are
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> because around here there's really nothing for the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> no good i mean there's jobs there's minimum wage jobs but uh to make a good living there really around here there just isn't too much
 	
 	
 		um-hum and i guess you know that would greatly affect social change i use social change probably the job market has always and the the economy has always affected uh social change
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		probably
 	
 	
 		so  well there's the main things i can think of i really
 		tried to think of some other things and i couldn't really
 	
 	
 		well i think just also you know
 	
 	
 		that
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s movement too has affected a lot of social change uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> marry
 	
 	
 		yeah definitely some good and some bad
 	
 	
 		yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> marry later
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i mean basically i think now again where i'm from in in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alabama</ENAMEX> that's not necessarily true because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> do still get married right out of high school
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but now out here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> where i am now that's very unusual
 	
 	
 		they'd rather get their life started first before uh-huh
 	
 	
 		most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> get married i mean get go to college or at least get a job and even you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are seem to a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> seem to
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		be engaged for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time</TIMEX> before they get married because they do want to be financially set up
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah well even to get school finished i think a lot of times it's better if they do finish their schooling before they settle in because a marriage takes a lot of
 		effort and concentration  and if you're busy with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> it's i think it's really difficult for a family
 	
 	
 		right but probably uh you know more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> being in in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">work force</ENAMEX> also greatly greatly affects social change because it affects child care and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right right
 		yeah i know my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> that lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX> she has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> and they they've been in day care since you know one's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> and one's one
 	
 	
 		but
 		right
 	
 	
 		and they've done well  now i wouldn't want to do it that way but uh she's quite happy and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> seem quite adjusted
 		and uh
 	
 	
 		well and they're you know they're they're saying right now we don't know what we just now are seeing the effects of day care on the generation that's just now coming into the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">work force</ENAMEX> and in their twenties
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		that's right yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh yes uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they are the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> that basically grew up with day care and so you know it remained to be seen exactly what that what that does
 	
 	
 		that's right yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> now i'm going to babysit my granddaughter she's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">just eight weeks old</TIMEX> so this will be new for me
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so uh
 		but the others i'm too far away to help them out at all
 	
 	
 		where do they live
 	
 	
 		uh well i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> that live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX> one in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> and one in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Connecticut</ENAMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Connecticut</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well they're not too far though
 	
 	
 		no but like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Connecticut</ENAMEX> takes <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">eight hours</TIMEX> to drive home and uh it's too far to you know really go too often
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX>'s not quite so bad it's just <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a couple hours</TIMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maryland</ENAMEX> maybe <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">five hour</NUMEX> drive
 	
 	
 		well i live like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fourteen hours</TIMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> in fact i'm
 	
 	
 		that's
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> that's worse yet
 	
 	
 		i'm driving <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX> i'm i'm driving home <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX> so to go be there for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the Fourth of July</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh are you really
 		do you uh stay <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">overnight</TIMEX> on the way or you
 	
 	
 		no i can drive it all it's just me so i can make it i'm <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		you're young how old are you
 		okay well you're young enough yet to
 	
 	
 		although it's it's it is pretty i don't know i don't enjoy it that much it's pretty much like get there and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		it's work to get there yeah yeah huh
 	
 	
 		it's just not that pleasant even with other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i basically just don't like to drive that far
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> now my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> they they flew he rebuilt a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aranca</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief</ENAMEX> airplane and they flew down <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last weekend</TIMEX> they came down in it
 		and it still took a long time because it's not a fast it's not a high-speed airplane
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but they enjoyed in thoroughly
 		so
 	
 	
 		when you say you're in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> phase of this project what is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> phase of it
 	
 	
 		i'm not sure but you have to change phones you have to call from another a different
 	
 	
 		oh
 		
 		
 	