
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">hello</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">hello</ENAMEX> my name is Nola i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plano Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hi Nola</ENAMEX> i'm <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX> i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		not too far away
 	
 	
 		no that's unusual seems like usually
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i've had some from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plano</ENAMEX> too
 	
 	
 		oh yeah i think all mine have been <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Coast</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> so far
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		okay um let's see
 	
 	
 		so
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">social</ENAMEX> changes
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">social</ENAMEX> changes
 	
 	
 		what's that mean
 	
 	
 		uh sounds like not as recent social changes too like back to the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixties</TIMEX> or fifties i guess
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		think we can handle that
 	
 	
 		yeah i yeah i definitely i mean there's plenty of things to talk about there that's a
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 		okay uh shall i go ahead and push one
 	
 	
 		yeah sure
 	
 	
 		okay
 		
 
 		you want to go ahead and start
 	
 	
 		uh i was hoping that you would but oh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah social changes is that uh
 		it seems to me that uh
 	
 	
 		that involves a lot of different areas i think
 	
 	
 		does uh
 		yeah like a lot it seems like the rich are getting richer and the poor are getting poorer is even more true today
 		so
 	
 	
 		yeah there is a a big difference in the uh economic
 	
 	
 		that
 	
 	
 		um status of uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> although i think that has been true uh always um
 		perhaps there's less of the middle range then there was
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		it's like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are starting to give up hope and they start out
 		very poor let's see that's a bad tangent to get on what else has changed between the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixties</TIMEX> and the eighties
 		and the nineties no
 	
 	
 		um
 		i think uh
 		my in my situation i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and we're uh home schooling so education you know things that relate to to education um
 		are things that i think about a lot um i think that and i think that involves
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">social</ENAMEX> changes a lot
 		uh for instance
 		i think the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> are having more and more problems because of uh things that
 		are happening socially in the world around them and in in to because of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> and things that are being taught in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> are not taught in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> rather
 		more not than are and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> being put in day care <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> from very early and and i think that a lot of these things that have been happening such as the
 		day care <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> and things are having a big effect on the social changes
 		because of the way <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are being raised they're not learning the values they need to learn and they're not um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		they don't have the self-esteem that they need to have and they don't have the um a solid family life that they need to have to  confidently and
 		deal with the things in the world
 		and uh i think we're seeing a lot of
 		rebellion and things because of that and the things like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">gang</ENAMEX>
 		gang things that are happening and and um
 	
 	
 		yeah it seems so that yeah that is a pretty big change it seems
 		even not just single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parent families</ENAMEX> but with no guidance but it seems like
 		some of these even <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ladies</ENAMEX> that that'll work and have a baby and then you know after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two or three months</TIMEX> go back to work you know well that that i mean that's very young for a baby
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah oh
 		that's really sad i think that a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and they think they have to but i i think that if they really tried they wouldn't have to and i i think that if they didn't that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and and it became more of the standard not to
 		that uh i don't know maybe <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> would start paying <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> more so that their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wives</ENAMEX> could stay home you know and have a more solid uh foundation for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah i mean they're going to like you said i mean there
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		there's they might be saving money i mean even if they had to pay more now i mean in the long run it's going to cost society more to force <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to work even though it's higher productivity is short-term
 	
 	
 		that's right
 		it's already
 		it already costs society much more because of it you know it trying to do all these programs like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Headstart</ENAMEX> and things like those you wouldn't have to do that if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> would stay home with their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and do things with them you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um there's and i think uh a lot of it is selfishness <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have become very selfish they don't want to stay home with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> or something like that there are a lot of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> parent
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		um
 		situations where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> goes back to work because that's what she wants to do you know
 	
 	
 		oh rather than she needs the money just she wants the stimulating environment
 	
 	
 		rather than that she has to have the money particularly or maybe there's a small need for money so she does it partly because of the money but partly for herself too
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">huh</ENAMEX> is yeah is the thing how uh home study is that what you said home <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> is that uh is is it like uh a preschool level then or through grade <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> or
 	
 	
 		you know
 		home school
 		yeah
 		no we're i have uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> going into <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> grade and one starting kindergarten and then a preschooler and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> on the way
 	
 	
 		oh is
 		oh well you sound busy
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so you're teaching them completely huh
 	
 	
 		yes yes and i think uh it's becoming uh more popular then it has been for a while i think
 		home schooling's always been around but uh i can see more and more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> going to it because of the problems in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> um and a lot of it is discipline problems
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		a lot of it is and you can tell which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> have been in day care <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> it it's really obvious
 		to look at them and watch the way they act and things that um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		they've been raised in a day care center
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		that's pretty sad because
 		i mean
 		i don't know something's got to change with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> that's what it all boils down to in the end usually anyway when they're young
 	
 	
 		well i think it's going to have to change in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> before anything changes anywhere else the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> is the base
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it's the basic unit
 		and that's the where it all starts and if we don't start making changes in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> and maybe part of that is educating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> better
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and educating uh you know
 	
 	
 		changing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s expectations
 	
 	
 		i know they do do some they do have some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classes</ENAMEX> in um high <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and things for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> to uh give them an idea of what
 		family life is like and the uh you know
 		and uh that kind of thing but um
 		
 		
 	