
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay you have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> i had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> girls
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		my youngest is college age but he is so he's still around occasionally but um he's he's <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty two and</TIMEX> in his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> of college
 		but uh we were very active with them when they were young  whatever they were in gymnastics or soccer or baseball or basketball whatever we were always involved in the parent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX> and
 		coached some and went to all the games and
 		and course in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plano</ENAMEX> that's a big deal we'd even where we lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Albuquerque</ENAMEX> before there's a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> involvement in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s lives
 		how about where you are
 	
 	
 		that's good well i try i try to as much as possible um my oldest is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> he plays plays soccer and is getting ready to start playing <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh my
 	
 	
 		and uh i'm behind him <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a hundred</TIMEX> percent on that and
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and my my middle one is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> he's playing <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">soccer</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">T-</ENAMEX>ball
 	
 	
 		oh dear
 	
 	
 		my youngest is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> and he wants to do it all so
 	
 	
 		yeah  he's learning from the big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> huh  that's neat though and sometimes those that see their older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> do it turn out to be pretty good because they pick up skills
 	
 	
 		yeah that's that's right
 	
 	
 		seems  naturally you know just they start so young just kicking the ball and are are you pretty involved with with their uh
 	
 	
 		that's true
 		i try to be as much as i can
 	
 	
 		do you coach them or go out to parent <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nights</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh no i i uh go out to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">as many</NUMEX> games as i can get to
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's kind of hard hard hard with me just because i'm in the restaurant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> and i have to work <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekends</TIMEX> but my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s there all the time and
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		mean that's that's one of my that's my downfall on my side of that that that aspect
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		which is i think's a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s too
 		just in general
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		is that is there that everybody's working you know the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>'s away at work and then the then the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> goes away to work and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are stuck with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sitters</ENAMEX> and they're not involved in there as much with their their with their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> they let somebody else raise their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 		right right it well that's seems to be a a pretty current trend i i work in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and i see a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> that
 	
 	
 		what
 	
 	
 		obviously are looking for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and usually find it within a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> rather than
 		at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> because their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> are off working or uh usually you know a lot of times it's a single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> trying to raise and of course i i deal with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adolescents</ENAMEX> so that's where it <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fourteen fifteen</NUMEX> that's where it really starts coming out this
 		lack of of uh family life
 	
 	
 		what do you what do you what difference do you see in those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> that than ones with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> in the participation
 	
 	
 		well uh they look for their security and their uh self-esteem uh outside of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> and usually in the wrong groups
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		and and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">acceptance</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right and they find that they're very easily unfortunately uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> who make them feel the most welcome
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		when new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> come into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> are the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> that are are uh on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> or party a lot on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekends</TIMEX> and things like that and and uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		wrong side of the fence
 	
 	
 		they're the first but they are the first ones that will come up and say you know you want to sit at my table in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cafeteria</ENAMEX> and let me help you to your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classes</ENAMEX> and things like that and and uh
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		when you've got a a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> that's just coming from a situation a move is a terrible thing on a child it's it's just such a traumatic especially if they've lived for any length of time
 	
 	
 		oh sure i mean the
 	
 	
 		in in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place and they come up here and no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and here are these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> just throwing themselves and before you know it you've got a a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> involved in things you don't want them involved in and
 	
 	
 		it
 	
 	
 		and most of the time the move is made and then mom and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daddy</ENAMEX> go right back to work right away and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>'s coming home to an empty <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> or they're coming home to take care of little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> and and uh you've got these ready made <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> just ready to go
 	
 	
 		that that's right
 	
 	
 		and and uh i you i don't know
 		what the answer is because i am a working <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> and and i don't like to say if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> would stay home any more than i like to say if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> would stay home and and it's
 	
 	
 		right well you're fortunate that uh your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are grown and i mean did did you did you work when your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> were growing up
 	
 	
 		right when
 		when my youngest was in <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> grade i went back to work but i stayed home up until then when by that time my oldest was
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		oh she's about
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six years</TIMEX> older than he is so she must have been in about uh
 		tenth grade i guess my oldest was and i had one in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">tenth</NUMEX> and one in <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">ninth</NUMEX> and one in <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">eighth</NUMEX> and then this <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grader</ENAMEX> and and uh
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but i went to work for the school district where i was home in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> i had <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks</TIMEX> off at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> i got left <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three four o'clock</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> and was home
 		to take them to anything they needed to go to in the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoons</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		did you work in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> or in the administrative end of it
 	
 	
 		uh no in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> i i uh i did work <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">some summers</TIMEX> but it was never my work never took uh <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place if if my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> needed me or needed to go somewhere that's where i was
 	
 	
 		it
 		
 
 		right just
 		did you work at the same <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> that your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> was going through
 	
 	
 		and
 		um i when my youngest was in elementary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> i worked at in his elementary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and uh but i had an understanding with the principal that under no circumstances was i to be treated any differently i don't want i said i don't want <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> coming to me in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the middle of the day</TIMEX> when they couldn't get to anybody else's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the middle of the day</TIMEX>
 		that that it would be handled the same way they handled dealt with other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 		it it gets real easy when a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> is in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> or a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> even for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> to
 		every time some little thing goes wrong to run and pretty soon all you're hearing is negative things so it you know and those things need to be dealt with in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">classroom</ENAMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> and not tattled necessarily
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 		well it puts you it puts you in an awkward situation puts the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> in an awkward situation
 	
 	
 		but it it
 		it worked well
 		it worked well with me and i and i told the principal i said if if uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> does something that you feel deserves licks or some other discipline have at it  you know i'm i'm i have always
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		wanted them to respect rules and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> and and uh
 		i don't want them to think that i'm going to come riding to the rescue where every time something happens but
 	
 	
 		well they need to i mean any any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> as far as that goes there's that there's that certain there's that  that fine line between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A</ENAMEX> and C you know that you have you need to ride and all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> do they they need discipline
 	
 	
 		right
 		well i think unfortunately what what we're seeing in the very few of the instances is that
 		uh for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> who cannot be there to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> their idea of parenting is
 		to come riding to the rescue and take their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>'s side without knowing
 		the whole story or even when they do know the whole story
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		it's it's either another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX>'s fault or it's another it's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX>'s fault or it's it's anybody's and they
 		consider that being a good <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> and that what when really what the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> needs is their attention more of the time and it's
 	
 	
 		well that's usually what gets them in trouble to begin with not enough attention not enough attention like you were saying they go off into the wrong <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> and get hooked up with the wrong <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		it it it's and it's it's difficult i understand i i know a lot of single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> that are working <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> jobs just to keep a roof over the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> and keep <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> on the table and i don't know how these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> are supposed to have
 		time to to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> it's it's i don't i don't know what the answer is to it it's it's really sad i there may not be i but it it beats being it beats being homeless  you know and
 	
 	
 		you don't know if there is one
 		there may not i mean it's just an ongoing ongoing problem right
 		
 		
 	