
 
     		
 	
 		okay um does is this something that concerns you
 	
 	
 		well i think it does um  especially because i just moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX> and uh they're having real problems because they have so many uh police layoffs
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh personally i don't live in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a real bad</TIMEX> section of town but uh just because of the general area i live in the insurance rates are real high on your <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and there's a lot of crime within <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a few miles</NUMEX> of me
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		how about you
 	
 	
 		yeah well i live outside of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> and it's kind of in a little suburb so i feel pretty safe out here but i know the murder rate is going up <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah i uh
 	
 	
 		in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> and that worries me
 	
 	
 		yeah i recently moved here and when i was looking for a job there was a lot of openings right in the in the worst areas of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> and uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> was was what he his concerns were well not that i think you'll get involved in anything but it just
 		be an innocent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bystander</ENAMEX> just to be in that location and i thought how sad it was that just to be in a wrong location at the wrong time and and a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> you know are caught that way
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah there's a little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> just got shot and killed like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last weekend</TIMEX> down in what they call the projects which is
 	
 	
 		but
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know sort of a bad area but he was just out riding his big wheel and a couple of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> got into a fight with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> and he got hit and killed by a stray bullet
 	
 	
 		yeah that exactly
 	
 	
 		that's really sad i've so you know it must be frustrating
 	
 	
 		exactly what happened down here
 	
 	
 		frustrating for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> who can't get out of a situation like that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it'd be so scary
 	
 	
 		i know they asked in the topic for ideas on how to control crime and it doesn't seem like anything is working
 	
 	
 		it really doesn't it's kind of scary i think that uh
 		i think the laws have gotten so lenient you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> systems are too lenient
 		i think that's part of the problem
 	
 	
 		but in in on the other hand they have to be because the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">jails</ENAMEX> are full we can't at least in this area you know they don't have any room to put anybody so a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> just get out you know back on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> because there's no they can't keep that many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> they have
 	
 	
 		yeah they do that here too but i say you know they commit crimes let them be overcrowded  you know let them suffer a little bit
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		i know it they have all sorts of of rights that you know are questionable maybe they gave up that right when they committed the crimes
 	
 	
 		yeah i think so i think if they knew it was going to be really horrible wherever they were going maybe they'd think twice about doing it
 	
 	
 		that's true maybe the punishment should be more severe
 	
 	
 		yeah it the other thing that worries about it is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> that are doing such bad crimes so young you know like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> and twelve and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirteen year olds</TIMEX> that just go out and kill
 	
 	
 		i know it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> they i don't know if that's just a symptom of society and the breakdown of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and everything but that worries me i wonder what the next generation will be like
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		exactly exactly exactly because they get involved in things so young that they don't really realize what they're involved in
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> prey on that you know they'll take uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> who don't really realize the seriousness even at fifteen
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh get them involved in things because
 		uh well i don't know i was watching on a movie on TV i don't know how true those can be but you know they one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> got all sorts of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> under eighteen to do it by telling them you know you won't have a record because you're under eighteen to steal <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> and everything
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		so i guess if they had more of a deterrent if they had more severe punishments it might be but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> are so backlogged right now it takes forever just to go to trial
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		seems like if they had immediate more immediate uh consequences to their actions it would sink in faster
 	
 	
 		i think it would concern me even more if i had <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> which i don't but  if i had <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> i wouldn't know where to raise them to protect them
 	
 	
 		really yeah
 		yeah because it seems like now even in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> you hear about
 		bad things happening so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		it's true they uh and they they talk about too the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">gangs</ENAMEX>
 		spreading you know like everybody thinks of them only in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LA</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> but they spread out
 		to cover more area and i don't know if if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gangs</ENAMEX> occur much down in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> do they
 	
 	
 		yeah i think they have them in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> because i hear them talking about in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> different things happening and they've had some drive-by shootings outside of the schools
 	
 	
 		yeah the same in some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">areas</ENAMEX> around here but i've never had any personal you know i never met anybody that i knew had anything to do with it or seen anybody but uh
 	
 	
 		me either
 	
 	
 		that's a scary thing too because at that age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> want so much to belong to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> and i think that a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that sort of control them
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> what they're doing are older you know business you know trying to control whatever you know
 	
 	
 		yeah seemed like like in the fifties when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gangs</ENAMEX> were big it was just to be part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">gang</ENAMEX> but now they're so much into selling <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> and all that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it seems scarier
 	
 	
 		it's true and the weapons my God the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have are some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are more seemed to be armed better than the military or the same as the military i don't know where they get them
 	
 	
 		really yeah those <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">machine guns</ENAMEX> and all that yeah that's scary it's a wonder there's anybody who's willing to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policeman</ENAMEX> anymore
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		that's the other thing uh is
 		
 
 		it's hard to even i can't even think of what the benefits of the job would really be especially if you're an inner city you know you can't really feel like you're putting much of a dent in what's going on and you're putting your life on your on the line everyday
 	
 	
 		yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> they were saying in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> that they can't hire anymore <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policemen</ENAMEX> but they keep losing them all the time and that uh you know eventually we're going to be way short on the number we need because
 	
 	
 		i
 	
 	
 		they won't let them hire any new ones and they keep leaving
 	
 	
 		uh
 		yeah i just read an article <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> um where this what used to be a nice <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> in this area
 		they had a lot of budget cutbacks
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX> is broke right now and a lot of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX> are declaring bankruptcy and they had to cut <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">twenty</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> from their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> and the crime wave rate went up almost instantly because it was so well publicized that everybody in the area knew that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> wouldn't be patrolled as well
 		it's like
 	
 	
 		huh yeah they figure what a heyday huh
 	
 	
 		this is a depressing conversation though
 	
 	
 		it really is  well there's someone at the door so i guess i'll have to  go see what my <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> is barking about but it was nice talking to you
 	
 	
 		okay i hope things look up
 	
 	
 		well thanks same for you bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 		bye-bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	