
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 		okay
 	
 	
 		um well i guess <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of all i i could have asked that before do you have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		no okay because i i didn't know if that would make a difference in how you felt um what what do you think about the proposal that all young <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> should spend <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> or two
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i think it's a good idea i think everybody should should uh
 		put in their time so to speak for the
 		for the good of the the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> and for the good of themselves i think it's uh would everyone everyone grow up and mature and and realize what this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s all about
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i just um
 		i guess that's  my
 		that's something that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> has always believed strongly in and um
 		i had opportunities in high school
 		to work in some programs um
 	
 	
 		did you  oh
 	
 	
 		and and i agree with what you said that it's
 		uh it benefits the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> doing it so much i don't think they realize and i uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i i think it gives you a better perspective on life and uh it gives you a little bit uh more a glimpse of the the real world and and it would certainly help the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> too uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		really
 		yeah i think that's probably like uh quite a few things that that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> uh maybe not so much nowadays but used to go through you know they just they were they did things for people
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yes
 	
 	
 		you know for their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> for their their uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> for their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> where now i'm not sure they really do
 	
 	
 		yeah well i think sometimes through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> um
 		my first when i <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> thought of it i thought it uh when they asked the question i thought well that sounds wonderful and then i wondered if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were unwilling but
 		but i think even if you went in with a negative attitude i don't think it would stay negative very long um
 		but i do know through some organized <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scouts</ENAMEX> and church um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they do still have opportunities
 	
 	
 		yeah that's probably true
 	
 	
 		but i i think that's a small uh
 		number
 		that could
 	
 	
 		you know but even even through those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups groups</ENAMEX> do you think that they participate as much as maybe they used to
 	
 	
 		no um not since um
 		not as much as i remember growing up and that was something
 		uh
 		i think in the fifties and sixties um seemed more common in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last two decades</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah i think that's probably true
 	
 	
 		but
 	
 	
 		i think it's probably more true still still in the in the smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> then in the larger cities
 	
 	
 		yes
 		yeah where uh where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">abouts</ENAMEX> do you live what part of the country
 	
 	
 		well i live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Richardson</ENAMEX> right now which is just
 	
 	
 		oh okay we're in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plano</ENAMEX> so we're not far apart one of the calls i'd gotten before was uh down to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX> and and i know
 	
 	
 		right yeah okay sure
 	
 	
 		a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of mine talked to someone in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">midwest</ENAMEX> so i know there is the possibility that it could be out of the area
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		gosh i hadn't even thought about it being out of the area but you're right
 		yeah but i grew up in a real small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		i mean a real small town
 		and uh i think it was just
 		of course it was back in the in the fifties and i think it was real prevalent back then i  i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> thought more of others than they do now you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		as far as doing things for them and and then gaining benefits from it
 	
 	
 		well and maybe um maybe this would be a way to get that feeling back um if we've lost some of that and it it seems in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last decade or two</TIMEX> um
 		that's true maybe that's a way
 		if if young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> had to do it um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		maybe that would start the trend back because that's one of the things i always
 		thought was a wonderful part of our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> um
 	
 	
 		yeah i do to i do to
 	
 	
 		is helping others
 	
 	
 		i'm not sure that that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> would go for it though i think you would have to start younger
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know i i don't know how young you'd have to go but i think by the time they're oh early <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teenagers</ENAMEX> anyway i think it's too late <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> at least around here um
 	
 	
 		yeah i think uh
 		i think it does help um even preschoolers you know they're um things even just starting around the home you know little ones can do a little bit to help the family
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and and just watching the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> do things too um it can start a pattern there's always something  no matter how young and then that helps
 		develop that attitude um i guess i would really like to see this happen with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> more you know i think this is certainly a possible way um to handle it but
 		i wish ah that's something that i think that has been lost in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> and i think that's a good place to start again
 	
 	
 		uh yeah i would have to start in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> first because if you don't it for your for your own immediate family your sure not going to do it for anybody else
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		and i do think um the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> do try and do something even with food drives and um
 		sometimes what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richardson</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Plano</ENAMEX> both i mean when you live in areas like that where there's so much they don't realize what a small percentage of the world that is i mean that's uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		gosh i'm sure not even one percent of the world is as fortunate as these areas and uh
 	
 	
 		that's probably true that's probably true
 	
 	
 		it's i know our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> youth <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> um starts with projects young but they they have a high school <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> that works in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Appalachia</ENAMEX> area <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> they've done this for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fourteen years</TIMEX> now
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh that's great
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> and it is it's um
 		and they've also see that there's there's a different way of life and those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> are really close some of the things that we talked about that were common in the fifties are still there and um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it really every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX> that's ever gone really has felt that their life has been changed and it's changed their perspective and
 		and that's just the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two two weeks</TIMEX> during during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> so if <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks</TIMEX> um could have that kind of effect i would
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well that's that's great i'm glad that there are still some areas that
 	
 	
 		think uh
 	
 	
 		that that get the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX> involved in that sort of thing you know like i said i think it does
 	
 	
 		well that's
 	
 	
 		even even a small amount of exposure can make a vast difference in their attitudes
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		well
 	
 	
 		well i guess um
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		did you have anything else that
 	
 	
 		no i i guess that's about all okay
 	
 	
 		okay well i i enjoyed talking with you
 	
 	
 		well good talking with you
 	
 	
 		and i hope you have a good <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX> thanks bye bye
 	
 	
 		you too okay bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	