
 
     		
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay
 		um  well it's not such a bad idea to think about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> uh
 		you know taking the idea of uh
 		uh sentencing in into their hands versus you know the jury especially if it's a highly publicized case
 		such as uh you've got cases right now that are going on that everybody's very well informed of or have read uh certain
 		uh things in regards to cases like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dahmer</ENAMEX> case in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milwaukee</ENAMEX> and stuff so it's it may be an idea to think about
 		you know cost trying to find a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> so you can get a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> as far as
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um they may say they're not biased but deep down they are against against this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> or whatever so um i don't think it's such a bad idea to think about so
 	
 	
 		right that a that a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a</NUMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> would be more consistent from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> case to the next and not not depend and and uh
 	
 	
 		exactly
 	
 	
 		not depend so much on the on the emotions of a particular case but be able to put it in overall perspective well i i i certainly haven't thought much about this but um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yes yes some of them some of them do and some of them don't but uh this one uh
 	
 	
 		catches you off guard doesn't it
 	
 	
 		i was trying to remember back it seems to me that that you know when i studied civics in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> or stuff that this
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">juries</ENAMEX> being involved in the sentencing wasn't wasn't so much and i'm i'm trying to
 		figure out whether that's i'm remembering wrong or whether that's a by state
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i didn't think they were either i thought the sentencing was done by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> and it's either guilty or not guilty
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 		yeah and
 		uh i guess i guess  uh and i don't know whether it's by state or whether there's been some
 	
 	
 		changes
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Supreme Court</ENAMEX> decision perhaps that said that uh that uh as part of the trial by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peers</ENAMEX> that i had to include the sentencing or too or whatever i'd yeah but i
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah i i certainly wouldn't be uh uh worried about that i guess in terms of the uh
 		uh you know having having a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> do it would seem to me to be more more fair and and uh unbiased uh
 	
 	
 		oh sure yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		in terms of doing away with the with the unanimous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> i guess i guess i uh
 		would be a little more leery of that kind of a change in in a trial system that that's just a such a tradition that it's a that it's got to be a unanimous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> that uh
 	
 	
 		exactly exactly
 	
 	
 		i don't know where you'd where you'd draw the line anywhere else uh you know uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two thirds or three</NUMEX> fourths or whatever but uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and and i i i certainly wouldn't feel comfortable with just a just a bare majority um
 	
 	
 		exactly
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		that's kind of how i you knows in certain cases i can see them going uh uh just basically with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> guilty or not guilty verdict
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		uh simply from a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> in highly publicized cases versus the small
 		um maybe uh you did a crime that was uh
 		burglary or whatever and it goes into the court case or whatever and it's not highly publicized but when you get into these highly publicized cases
 		where everybody knows details whether it's through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Enquirer</ENAMEX> or whatever
 	
 	
 		whatever yeah
 	
 	
 		um it's the idea that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> might initially have this thought well jeez this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s guilty no matter what i'm not gonna listen to the facts or and and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		con their way into uh getting past the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> and and getting through that but um also there's the aspect of cost and i i'm not quite sure how much cost it does
 		take for uh the judicial system to try and call a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> whether it's uh very costly or if it's something that's not costly or what
 		you know being that i'm not in the that area i really don't know but i wonder
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		if there is some big expense in trying to call a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> to trial
 		and then having to pay whatever they have to pay if there's something that they have to pay i know <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> have to pay for these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to be off from work or at least give them the time off
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		from work uh whether it i think it's with pay if i remember jury duty is with pay
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well and and i'm i'd i'd i know it is i know it is where i where i work but i'm not sure that that's
 	
 	
 		and uh it's not it
 		hm
 	
 	
 		that that's necessarily required uh you know by law that it has to be paid um
 	
 	
 		paid right
 	
 	
 		i suspect that's a that's a
 		benefit of a bigger <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> but but there are certainly some
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		some that may decide not to
 	
 	
 		
 
 		some that some that wouldn't uh yeah
 	
 	
 		hm
 		
 		
 	