
 
     		
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		did you want me to go ahead
 	
 	
 		i'll let you go ahead and start yeah
 	
 	
 		okay well one thing i i i guess both of us have very much aware of the equality
 		uh it seems like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> are uh just starting to really get some kind of equality not only in uh jobs but in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">home</ENAMEX> where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husbands</ENAMEX> are starting to help out a lot more than they ever did um
 		it's not uncommon to see <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> doing dishes making supper or taking care of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> versus um the generation of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> and my great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> which uh they did everything they went to work and they took care of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		you know i think that's changed just in the last <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> just in the last little while because i know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father-in-law</ENAMEX> doesn't do that much of that
 	
 	
 		exactly
 		exactly yeah
 	
 	
 		kind of stuff but my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> is wonderful
 	
 	
 		yeah that's the way my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> is too i mean it it doesn't uh doesn't bother him at all to do the dishes it doesn't bother him him at all to do the laundry versus uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> from
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> back there is that well if you did that you were henpecked or whatever but
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah there still some that aren't cooperating but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> are starting
 		yeah those are very few i think those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> don't last very long in relationships because they think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> know what they want
 	
 	
 		they're not accepting that anymore yeah
 	
 	
 		right exactly and it's it's hard enough to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> out there trying to do everything uh you know and then
 		kind of realize hey there's just no way that we can be happy trying to do it all so it's it's kind of a
 		a neat thing to see as far as equality in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> and i think that's even gonna get better
 		even you know even more so i think it's just gonna be where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> will do as much cleaning as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> do
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and that it won't be your job description instead of your role definition is this it will be
 		uh hopefully for my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> who i instill into it doesn't matter if you wanna drive a truck <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">honey</ENAMEX> or if it doesn't matter if you want to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurse</ENAMEX> it doesn't matter if you want to be
 		uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> or it doesn't matter if you want to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> or a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> it doesn't matter it's what you want to be so i have always instilled into her and i think
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers um</ENAMEX> are doing a really good job in raising their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX> to say hey
 		you don't have to stay with nursing you don't have to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> you don't have to be you can be whatever you want to be and whether it be a welder a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">trucker</ENAMEX> or whatever
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		as long as you uh go to school for it and get the education so
 	
 	
 		yeah well i feel like um
 		to an extent that is really important you know that that um it is important for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who need to work uh or are in a position that they want to
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		if they want to right
 	
 	
 		that they can do that um but i also think it is important for them to be with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		i do too you know there's a certain part of me
 	
 	
 		i i think there there are some things that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> just
 		are designed to do better than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>  and there are some things that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> are designed to do better than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> i don't think it should ever be totally equal
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know that's not  uh we're not made like that that's right
 	
 	
 		well emotionally i think uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>  do a little bit uh i i think that's  the gap is coming closer  as um
 		what i've learned in uh just just
 		being out there it seems that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> are now starting to get into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>'s gatherings and they get together and they talk about issues of marriage talk about manhood talk about what they didn't have with their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fathers</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		are expressing more emotions learning what emotions are it may be in the future that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> you know some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> may be better <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> themselves um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i i know of some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> that uh i guess i'd rather be with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> is maybe more understanding more um
 		low keyed more apt to be a better <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> than some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> that i have seen that have been raised you know to develop whatever skills that they have and some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> are developing uh
 		very good too so it may come down to where it's
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it's individual basis where everybody's treated as an individual and not by
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		sex if you wanna stay home and take care of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> honey that's fine i will go out and make the uh take care of the uh money making and it it wouldn't matter if it's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> or a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> saying that
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the frustrations that i have with the way things have developed is that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and  for some it's not a problem but there's more and more it's difficult for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> to make a living on one
 	
 	
 		on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> income um-hum
 	
 	
 		income it can be done but you make sacrifices you know and and it's um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah that
 		kind of like what uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and myself are doing right now my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> even though at this current time she's ready to get involved with she's an only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> i don't know if you've only got one
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 		
 	