
 
     		
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well course my favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> there is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Rangers</ENAMEX> so  i watch them all the time
 		and who do you watch
 	
 	
 		uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mets</ENAMEX> but i don't do that anymore  because uh they're doing lousy  i don't know
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mets</ENAMEX>
 		this isn't their best season is it
 	
 	
 		no no
 	
 	
 		well the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rangers</ENAMEX> are the few games behind <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota</ENAMEX> but if we could win the next oh i guess we'd win have to win most all of them we could still go to the to the race to do the
 	
 	
 		i think you're uh  definitely an avid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> huh
 	
 	
 		well i watched the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> games <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the last two nights so</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		they just i gave up on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mets</ENAMEX> around <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX> you know
 	
 	
 		oh is that right
 	
 	
 		how many games out is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		pardon
 	
 	
 		how many games out are they
 	
 	
 		i think they're out <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>
 		and so they have to still win almost every single game that they have to play to the end now
 	
 	
 		right right yeah i think <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota</ENAMEX>'s got to get like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> wins or or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> has to lose <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> games or some combination of that  well maybe next year
 	
 	
 		or else
 		yeah yeah
 		i don't know <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota</ENAMEX>'s won a good game they're they're doing a good job <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> i don't know
 	
 	
 		yeah they they are they are
 	
 	
 		they really but i'm gonna watch <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX> because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nolan Ryan</ENAMEX>'s gonna pitch so i always like to watch him pitch
 	
 	
 		yeah who's who's who he used to be on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mets</ENAMEX> a long time ago but who's who's who else is like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>'s big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">players</ENAMEX> that that uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well uh we just traded <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buechele</ENAMEX> and i really liked him but but he's gone now  so i i guess uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sierra</ENAMEX> i like to watch him bat
 	
 	
 		right <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruben</ENAMEX> right he's supposed to be good
 	
 	
 		yeah he's he's really good <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franco</ENAMEX>'s good except that uh he's got injuries right now his hamstring's down in the bottom of his legs he can't run very well but
 		it he usually hits a home run then he just trots around the bases it's okay  and um
 	
 	
 		he's the shortstop though right <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franco</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah well they've moved him now since he can't move that quickly since it hurts him
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		they moved him to <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> base and they moved <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Petralli</ENAMEX> into that area in that runs now in between the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shortstop</ENAMEX> area and he takes <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> base
 	
 	
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sierra</ENAMEX>'s an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">outfielder</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">um Sierra</ENAMEX> let's see yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sierra</ENAMEX>'s into
 		is he middle field or left field he's not left field he must be center field
 	
 	
 		yeah i don't see i don't know the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American League</ENAMEX> that well once in a while i watch the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yankees</ENAMEX> um but rarely and uh but this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> that i'm i work with is in this rotisserie <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">league</ENAMEX> where they they choose
 	
 	
 		do you
 		oh now what's that i don't know what that is
 	
 	
 		well you choose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> and you do stuff based on stats and everything like that so he's always talking to me about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American League</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		like he gets points for every time uh i think he has <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruben Sierra</ENAMEX> on his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> and every time he hits a home run or steals a base or gets a hit he gets a certain amount of points and then you get <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pitchers</ENAMEX> and stuff like that
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh
 	
 	
 		so he's always talking about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American League</ENAMEX> which is like i said because i watch the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mets</ENAMEX> i don't really know that much about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American League</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah that's hard
 	
 	
 		you're not an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Astro</ENAMEX> fan
 	
 	
 		um no not too  not too much  i i guess i just don't watch them that much um
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i like to watch the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oakland A's</ENAMEX> play they have a lot of good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> too but i haven't watched them for a while so i don't know how they're doing too well <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this season</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		no they're not they they were doing well for a while but then they kind of fell off do you get all the games out there i mean you get you get to watch the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A's</ENAMEX> a lot and stuff like that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> once every so often mostly <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rangers</ENAMEX> games come on because that's our area but um
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		
 
 		every once in a while on a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> or a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> they'll put a another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">league</ENAMEX> on you know
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but it's it just depends
 		how to you know how they fill the time sometimes
 		anyway i um we got
 	
 	
 		this is my first conversation through this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Instruments</ENAMEX> thing
 	
 	
 		what
 	
 	
 		this is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time i've done <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of these conversations yeah
 	
 	
 		oh is it
 		oh well that's kind of fun
 	
 	
 		so i didn't even expect it i just i happened to have the uh i didn't even know what my um  my personal identification number was i just happened to have the folder right in front of me i'm glad i brought it into work just
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah uh isn't it's a fun thing i think you'll like it it's a it's a old thing to do and um
 		anyway we just uh if you get run out of things to say then you say good bye  it was nice talking to you too
 	
 	
 		okay well it's nice talking to you and uh be good thank you
 	
 	
 		and have <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a good day</TIMEX> um bye-bye
 	
 	
 		okay bye-bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	