
 
     		
 	
 		well how do you feel about spot testing spot testing for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well
 		basically i think it would be a good idea myself
 		i uh
 		i think if somebody's not on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> they have no reason you know to be afraid of it uh i do think that there has to be some controls uh like i don't think <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> test positive should
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh be uh
 		the end of it you know i i think they should test more than once
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah it's it's refreshing to hear somebody that has a similar opinion as mine i mean all these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are against it that may they yeah they may not even be on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> yet they they call it an invasion of privacy
 	
 	
 		it
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i don't see you know that to me that just doesn't sound like a valid argument because this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> is paying you good money that you're working for
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		and they i believe that they have the right to know if you're using a a dangerous substance
 	
 	
 		um-hum um-hum there's so many jobs that uh really have other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s lives in their hands or even their own life and you know and it's uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		but
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh how can you do anything about a problem besides if you don't know about it
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know and i just um
 		i i think there definitely needs to be some control to it i guess it is possible to have a false
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		positive report
 	
 	
 		yeah no i i i agree that you know you there there needs to be a a well thought out sane approach to how to administer that program just because you know you you something can get mixed in the mail or
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemicals</ENAMEX> could react incorrectly than than what you would expect them to and yeah you
 	
 	
 		or somebody's test get mixed up with somebody else's i mean those things do happen
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh i certainly wouldn't want <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s lives ruined uh wrongly
 	
 	
 		right and you know i've the the the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that i work for uh has just recently well you know within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last couple of years</TIMEX> instituted for all new hired <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> they submit to a uh urine test
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and
 		they they say that there've been you know they they they've also implemented random testing
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and  it hasn't happened to me in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the couple of years</TIMEX> that you know it's been in progress but uh i i fully agree with it and there's you know there's all these memos going around about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> that are disgruntled and feel it's an invasion of privacy and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i i agree with you if if if you feel it's an invasion of privacy you've you've probably got something you're trying to hide
 	
 	
 		yeah and you maybe need to look for some other type of job to do that uh doesn't require the testing
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh
 		to me
 		it's to me it's not an invasion of privacy i think it's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have a right to know if if uh their their life maybe is in jeopardy or uh
 	
 	
 		or the quality of their products
 	
 	
 		yeah their work the work they're doing for their company
 		uh those things are all affected if not immediately it certainly does eventually
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i think that's where a lot of the problem is at first it doesn't seem to
 		uh bother the quality of work
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but eventually it does
 	
 	
 		right because it usually requires more and more of that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">substance</ENAMEX> that you're misusing to get the same effect
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		course i feel the same way on the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> problem
 		i i don't think that's an invasion of privacy that's the only communicable disease that they're not allowed to test for
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		you know and it's destroying a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s lives
 	
 	
 		and then and one of the few that they don't have a cure for
 	
 	
 		yeah and it's you know it's it's destroying <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s lives and i i think
 		that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> plus anybody in danger should should be know about it and be aware of it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so i don't know it's it's kind of hard to
 		i guess the the gay movement has had a lot to do with considering that that uh an invasion of privacy of course that's not supposed to be what we're talking about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> i guess so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i kind of get off on a tangent here uh do you work for uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Instruments</ENAMEX> uh-huh
 	
 	
 		yes i do
 		and i'm i'm down in the the central but i don't know how familiar you are with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> but i'm in a we live in a town uh near a town called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Temple</ENAMEX> which is right in between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Waco</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX> on the freeway
 	
 	
 		um
 		oh that's probably way my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> did live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grapevine Texas</ENAMEX> that's near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right we're yeah we're probably about <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two two and a half hours</TIMEX> south of him
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		it's pretty hot down there probably
 	
 	
 		oh my it's actually we got <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about two inches</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rain</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about three hours</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> and it's cooled things down somewhat it's getting more <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">humid now</TIMEX> but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh did you really oh that's great
 		uh-huh we we need rain real bad up here it's uh everything's really getting dry it's uh
 	
 	
 		um
 		it's been <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about three weeks</TIMEX> since we had any
 	
 	
 		yeah it's kind of at a dangerous level here <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> hauling <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> and uh it's getting real bad
 	
 	
 		
 
 		hum
 		wow
 	
 	
 		so so
 	
 	
 		how about that
 		well i hope you do get some rain up there
 	
 	
 		um
 		so do i
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh i can't think of anything else uh
 	
 	
 		but
 		yeah i i i guess being in agreement kind of tends to limit the conversation you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		uh-huh uh i can understand i know if somebody is using <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> and doesn't think there's anything wrong with them
 		i can see them objecting
 		you know there's a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that think there's nothing wrong with
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the things i found interesting it it's funny that you mentioned that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> is pretty much a worldwide <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> and we have manufacturing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> all around the world
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		including some places where the use of certain <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> that are illegal here are not illegal
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and the policy doesn't apply to those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> is that right
 	
 	
 		yeah they don't have to submit to drug testing like like they do here in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">States</ENAMEX> and some places abroad
 	
 	
 		oh i'll be darn
 	
 	
 		yeah i thought that was kind of interesting too
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah the different cultures and that too uh
 	
 	
 		yeah i mean uh uh from from a quality standpoint that's not i mean just because it's not illegal doesn't mean it doesn't affect you the same way
 	
 	
 		no no i'm sure it would have to affect you the same way
 		i i can't think that would make any differen ce whether it was legal or not it it would have to affect you the same way
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right
 		yeah but like if you're going to do business in another <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> you've got to respect their rules i mean if if you know that's that's the trade off i guess
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh yeah you can't you go by their laws
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		the same way our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have to go by their laws when they're over there that's why a lot get in trouble
 	
 	
 		hum
 		
 
 	
 	
 		because they have to follow their rules and uh some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> are very much against <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		you use them you pay for it
 	
 	
 		usually with your life in some places you know
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah a lot of them yeah where where is it they lose a
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		if they steal they lose a thumb or a finger is that where it is i thought wow  you know that's quite a deterrent
 	
 	
 		yeah from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Middle East</ENAMEX>
 		yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq Iran</ENAMEX> in that area yeah
 		well in in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi Arabia</ENAMEX> you know using <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">uh alcohol</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> and stuff like that you get the death penalty
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		so it's pretty strict over there
 	
 	
 		yeah so i guess you know we really we have so many freedoms over here we sometimes forget about how great our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> is
 	
 	
 		well <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> tend to take the first amendment out of context which which means you know i could do anything i want to and you can't stop me and you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		they they abuse it is what they do yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		so that's
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		i don't know i'm i'm i'm glad to see more and more <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> implementing the policy
 	
 	
 		
  
 		um
 		
 		
 	