
 
     		
 	
 		okay um
 	
 	
 		where do you live
 	
 	
 		in Plano
 	
 	
 		in Plano
 	
 	
 		yes where do you live
 	
 	
 		in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		uh the air pollution isn't too bad in our area so we're very fortunate but
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		i know in some areas it's really it it really is bad
 	
 	
 		um i was trying to think uh something we were watching <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX> and they were doing
 		an overview of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> uh from an area that was up higher and you literally could see the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX> of smog that uh i've never been out there but
 	
 	
 		i haven't either
 	
 	
 		it was it was quite evident  that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it was a real brown area and
 	
 	
 		well i think it would be terrible to live in an area like that and unfortunately i think there are a lot of areas that are that that bad particularly in the areas where there are industries uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		where they are burning a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coal</ENAMEX>  and oil up more up north i guess uh i think it's a bigger problem with the car pollution antipollution devices i think the
 	
 	
 		yes
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">air</ENAMEX> isn't as bad as it once was from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> because we certainly have plenty of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> in our area
 	
 	
 		yes well i know uh that's been the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> they hadn't uh we have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> and uh
 		have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> that live near the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Black Forest</ENAMEX> area and large areas of the forest are being hurt from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> because when we
 		switched uh switched to the unleaded <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas</ENAMEX> and and had the emission control advice uh devices required on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>
 		uh that's something that <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> didn't do right away and now they're doing that and i guess it started in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last few years</TIMEX> because they have found
 		that in that particular part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> that's the only pollution that's been there it's not an area that is industry but they were losing a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">uh trees</ENAMEX> and a lot of
 	
 	
 		from <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid rain</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um i guess from from something that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> was
 		um
 		was giving
 	
 	
 		i think it gives off uh in the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">emissions</ENAMEX> it gives off <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gases</ENAMEX> which combine up in the atmosphere uh and form a a weak acid
 	
 	
 		yes and
 	
 	
 		it just makes the rain fall on the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> side and after a period of time i think that accumulates in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> because they take it up through their roots
 		as well as it landing on the leaves on surfaces like you've seen what it's done to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> even where it's really bad
 	
 	
 		yes yeah
 	
 	
 		what's interesting <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several years ago</TIMEX> i took a course
 		uh on uh well it was actually it was put on by the power <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> and about the various <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> of energy and
 		how much pollution there was and there wasn't from various kinds of of energy and uh
 		at that point in time <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> that was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX> brought up the topic of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid rain</ENAMEX> and it was kind of pooh-poohed you know oh you're making a mountain out of a molehill kind of thing
 		and it's turned out that that's been very true what he was forecasting about the accumulation of of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pollutants</ENAMEX> in the air and the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid rain</ENAMEX> and what it would do to foliage
 		so it's kind of interesting the change in
 		perspective
 		from when i took that course now a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are really afraid of nuclear uh i'm not afraid of nuclear having had that course because of how the nuclear that uh they use
 		is not bomb quality and we're so strict with all our controls in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> the chances of of an accident are slight and it doesn't pollute the air at all it's safer to be around a nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> then it is to be around a coal plant
 		many more deaths have occurred in and dealing with coal <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> then ever around nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> it's kind of funny because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are just petrified at least some are at the thought of nuclear
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		so i don't know in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> there's a lot of dependency on nuclear power and they recycle the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fuel</ENAMEX> and then instead of of some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are really afraid to recycle the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fuel</ENAMEX> because they're afraid it could become uh bomb quality
 		but that's the only sensible thing to do is recycle and reuse the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fuel</ENAMEX> and not store it down in the ground as far as i'm concerned where it could eventually perhaps there's some problem uh pollute the groundwater
 		so i don't know what the answer is the best answer of course would be solar or uh  fusion or something clean  well we've got a problem on the line don't we
 	
 	
 		yes
 		yeah i i get that sometimes um my line gets some static i don't know why
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		but uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">solar</ENAMEX> of course would be the clean cleanest
 	
 	
 		well and i would think in our um we did have a solar water heater when we lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> and uh oddly enough i thought our part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> was ideal
 	
 	
 		i can't hear you at all for all this static
 	
 	
 		oh  i don't know what to  usually it's the other phone i have trouble with it must just be on the line can you hear me
 	
 	
 		now i can again
 	
 	
 		okay
 		i don't know what uh
 		i i don't know what the problem is but uh when we lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> we had a solar water heater and we had thought this part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> would be ideal for solar <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> and solar energy and we have enough clouds that uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		there are other areas that would be better suited that surprised me because i think we have a tremendous amount of um sunny <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> and and it yes it can be used and it can help but uh that was a problem that they were still
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		working on but
 	
 	
 		oh yeah it it's still got a long way to go
 	
 	
 		what
 	
 	
 		it's just you know a possible solution in the future i think maybe to help in some ways it may not in all ways maybe they'll come up with fusion
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		you know control be able to control it i don't know how long that'll take but
 		
 
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> because that's perfectly clean
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		it's just we can't control it right now it takes more energy to cause fusion to occur then you get out so it isn't not at all and you can't control it unless you gotten a huge electromagnetic field so that's not going to work
 		at least not now but uh
 		who knows what the future will hold
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> as far as energy goes i i think
 		with solving some of the energy future energy problems we'll probably solve some of the pollution problems as well
 	
 	
 		uh i hope so
 	
 	
 		i do to
 		i like to be optimistic i don't like to be pessimistic about these things
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well i do think um i mean you've already mentioned several things i think uh just the change in attitude and the fact that more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are aware there's a problem and more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are interested in uh
 	
 	
 		we have one earth to live on and we got to take care of it
 	
 	
 		yes
 		yes well and and for the future generations too uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		i've noticed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> are are much more you know young young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are much more receptive to ideas about the environment and protecting the earth
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		and so if we can raise it uh you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generations</ENAMEX> with those concerns we'll solve a lot of our problems
 		i'm afraid
 		i know i was part of the me generation where they didn't so many of them didn't <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> didn't care you know it's whatever
 		you know recycle well if it's a problem forget that uh not throw the trash out the car window and leave it in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and then throw it away
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		how horrible  you know now i've always done those kinds of things because i just didn't like messes uh and create
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 		
 		
 	