
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		do you have any personal feelings on on uh the subject
 	
 	
 		well uh capital punishment's a hard thing but uh there've been several
 		there've been several things that have happened where i felt like if i had been involved in it i would have had to
 		to go along with with that being the punishment given to to the people
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		there have been some things you know i mean there's things done that are just
 	
 	
 		so outrageous i know i know
 	
 	
 		yeah that i i don't know how
 		i don't really think there's any other way to deal with it
 	
 	
 		right
 		well i i guess my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> is what we're reading especially in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> right now with them letting out
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> out of jail as soon as they're out of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> when they do and then having them go right back and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> they get out they're back in crime and and especially when they're assaulting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and then killing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i mean the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> that killed those <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sheriff</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah i think that that that that's <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a really</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">deputies</ENAMEX> he is out free walking the street i have a real problem with that
 	
 	
 		yeah if it's a if it it presents a clear and present danger i mean it
 	
 	
 		i think so
 	
 	
 		but it's something that's really hard to deal with the way that our justice system is right now
 		is basically set up in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> and and anybody will tell you that uh it is set up right now all the laws protect the criminal they're the ones with the rights
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 	
 	
 		they have the right to uh you know i think i watched something <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> um
 	
 	
 		well
 	
 	
 		that evict uh i'm sorry the accused has the right to a speedy trial
 		but the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> does not have the right doesn't have the same
 	
 	
 		doesn't have the right
 	
 	
 		doesn't have the same the same uh emphasis on those things as far as they're concerned so now the accused can can ask for delays and extensions and what do they call whatever they call them you know
 	
 	
 		right
 		right right and meanwhile the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> move and die and <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">and and and</ENAMEX> and they and there's no one to face them
 	
 	
 		exactly uh-huh uh-huh exactly a continuance continuance
 		they can get continuances on for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> before a a thing ever comes to trial and that makes the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> suffer more
 	
 	
 		right right well they can't get any if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> is going to have any award to the victim it just puts off their collecting it
 	
 	
 		the
 		yeah that too
 	
 	
 		it's it's really bad it uh i
 	
 	
 		um
 		i think that uh you know that there needs to be a way that you know once someone
 		has gone through
 		you know a trial a trial i don't know how to fix it i mean it just seems like there
 		there should be a limit on how many appeals can be made you know when someone has been
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		a a time limit too don't let it drag on for fifteen years
 	
 	
 		has uh yeah when someone has well even when someone has been convicted
 		and i mean
 		it's just so
 		so abundantly clear that they did it
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		that appealing you know and continuing to appeal like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four or five</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> times
 		to have convictions overturned and then they have to be retried and all that it's such a waste of time and energy and money
 		and it just that's what keeps that's what's keeping all the the you know the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> in a position of being able to be released all the time like this
 	
 	
 		right
 		uh do you feel like there's any certain type of crime that this should be the result this should be consequences of is capital punishment or or are are there some murders that committed that you think that leniency should be shown
 	
 	
 		oh
 		well i guess there's extenuating circumstances to anything like that um
 		you know like i could i could see
 		uh a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time offender being you know maybe  in in a in a robbery situation trying to hold up a a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> and getting scared and you know firing a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> and accidently
 		killing someone okay i could see that that might be a situation where uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> could be rehabilitated but i think just out and out murder and i'm talking about uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		cutting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> up
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		you know where there's shown to be pathological tendencies where this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> has done it over and over again in a serial fashion or whatever
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		that those kinds of things and any any kind of violent assault rape included
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		needs to be addressed in in in that context
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hm</ENAMEX> and and how do you feel about murders of law <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> or fire <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> or something that are because they have had them they have had them killed when they've
 	
 	
 		well that bothers me that that bothers me a great deal i had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> who was a police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> who was killed in the line of duty
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um um um</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and the thing that was the worst about it is that these
 		that uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> were uh well all of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> involved were very young
 		one was technically a minor and so he was sent back to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> he was an illegal alien <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">the other two</NUMEX> had lived here they had graduated from high school here and they had told their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> that
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		that i mean repeatedly uh during high school they had told their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> that they were going to be that they were going to to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduate</ENAMEX> from high school and kill cops
 	
 	
 		that was their goal oh
 	
 	
 		that was what they had told their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> and so that's what they did and uh they were they were given i think oh absolutely
 	
 	
 		that would be premeditated
 		
 
 		uh
 	
 	
 		he stopped them for a routine traffic violation and they
 		uh
 		several several things happened <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">that night</TIMEX> but they they beat him up and took his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> and shot him
 	
 	
 		they killed him
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um um um</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		with it and it was
 		it was really terrible i mean
 		uh i'd seen him like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three or days</TIMEX> before that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we'd we've gone out uh
 		with with he and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and that was really really disturbing
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know that that happened and that these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you know in the in the course of the trial you know came up with with all these you know things about well you know they were disadvantaged and all this stuff well nobody's that disadvantaged
 	
 	
 		no well that's right there's no reason for murder no i do not care if you're poor or if you're rich or if you're ugly or if you're prejudice or uh what there that that's just beyond the
 	
 	
 		and there's just no reason i mean
 		no
 		
 
 		yeah i think so too and that's uh
 		so i i do i do feel strongly about
 	
 	
 		i think this giving excuses is pretty prevalent uh uh you i work in the school district and the all these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> they've they've got an excuse for everything and i can see it continuing on when they're adults
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i just
 		it's just a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a</NUMEX> a bad habit uh uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> have got to learn from the time they're real little there's no excuse for for being bad or making bad choices deliberately or anything it's
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it's it's uh i i i sometimes think if if i were on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> and and had to make the decision could i and i like to think i could if like you if if especially especially especially violent
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		crime where it's a serial <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">type killer</ENAMEX> or where maybe a a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> has been deliberately killed or
 	
 	
 		the thing that even though <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">juries</ENAMEX> sometimes make the decisions and still the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> nothing ever happens to them
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know they stay in jail they get of f time for good behavior and stuff and they get released and they go right back and do it again
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	