
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 		well now i i have a question for you do you like uh fresh <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> fishing or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salt water</ENAMEX> fishing
 	
 	
 		okay
 		i like well what i usually do is fresh <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> fishing i haven't been <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salt water</ENAMEX> fishing since i was about <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		is that right
 	
 	
 		yeah and i do everything up at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Lake Texoma</ENAMEX> oh yeah i'm a striper fisherman
 	
 	
 		oh you do okay
 		oh where do you fish for striper there
 	
 	
 		oh everywhere wherever those little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suckers</ENAMEX> are
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but uh we camp at the lodge <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texoma State Park</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		over on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX> side and uh but usually when we go striper fishing when i go out for the big ones we travel down the you know where the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX> is down the middle of the lake
 	
 	
 		oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		uh-huh pretty much
 	
 	
 		we usually chase them down through there
 	
 	
 		okay so you're out in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> then
 	
 	
 		oh yeah oh yeah do you ever go up there
 	
 	
 		oh
 		i've gone up there camping like at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Eisenhower State Park</ENAMEX> and i've observed fishing but i've never actually fished there
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh it's good fishing up there
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		so you like to go for striper then
 	
 	
 		yeah of course i won't you know i won't throw anything back
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well the time i went and watched i went over to the uh to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dam</ENAMEX> and it was right after
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the major major <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rains</ENAMEX> that we'd had uh in fact i think it had been over the spillway recently when we went it was back down but uh some of the roadblocks were still up or there was evidence of them
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were they really had the gates open
 	
 	
 		oh my gosh that's supposed to be the greatest time to fish
 	
 	
 		big time
 		well i couldn't believe some of the striper that these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were pulling out and there were just <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> galore for that matter just just everywhere just huge fish
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh yeah
 		oh yeah
 		it's fun well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> got me hooked on it
 	
 	
 		so to speak
 	
 	
 		and uh yeah oh God pun pun and uh we'd go out he liked to go out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about five thirty</TIMEX> and you know watch the sun come up <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">every morning</TIMEX> and uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> we
 	
 	
 		all right
 	
 	
 		we knew a bunch of the striper guides and and so we'd follow them and he had a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CB</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> and all that kind of stuff and we'd just follow the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX> and when it's you know
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">middle July through late August</TIMEX> when it's so hot they stay down real deep all the big ones do yeah follow that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX> on up
 	
 	
 		deep in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX> huh
 		i'll be
 	
 	
 		but uh so now my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX> will i make him get up <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">early in the morning</TIMEX> and take me out striper fishing and then we usually <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> under the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridge</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and stuff like that because where we go a lot of times
 	
 	
 		oh wow
 	
 	
 		uh the waves are so big i don't want my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> out there because it's sort of dangerous but i love it i love it
 	
 	
 		right
 		well i used to fish go every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> to northern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		and so i i've been spoiled by that uh but i had a string of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight years</TIMEX> in a row
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		of uh sort of a close knit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> we would just hop in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and drive straight through <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two thousand</NUMEX> miles
 	
 	
 		oh how much fun
 	
 	
 		and uh we started out fishing out of a lodge and then we started uh either taking our own canoes or renting them
 		when we got there and hitting a few of the
 	
 	
 		oh my goodness
 	
 	
 		you know smaller lakes along the river <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX> and uh catch <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northern Pike</ENAMEX> and walleye primarily
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh my goodness
 	
 	
 		and sometimes <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Lake Trout</ENAMEX> also
 	
 	
 		oh how much fun
 	
 	
 		so we'd always go <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first week</TIMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX> you know essentially as soon as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> was out and everything is all over and done we'd uh we go uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		course <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one year</TIMEX> i went <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks</TIMEX> too early with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> that was he at this point he'd graduated from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> and was in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> and
 		he had a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two week</TIMEX> period he he had to work with before he got shipped off to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Germany</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh my goodness
 	
 	
 		and so i went with him in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the middle of May</TIMEX> and much to our surprise when we got there all the lakes were still frozen  no yeah <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first week</TIMEX> we were there we just had to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		oh you're kidding ooh not for me
 	
 	
 		uh we could go on the streams they were open up you know the flowing where the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> was flowing but the lakes themselves were still iced over for the whole yeah whole <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">first week</TIMEX> we were there
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh my gosh
 		ooh
 	
 	
 		but then <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next week</TIMEX> they were just just like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX> and night difference we had some <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rain</ENAMEX> and wind and it it cleared all the lakes off and uh you know the fishing was already really picking up but uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		those were my favorite fishing trips the most serious fishing i guess i've done
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah when i take the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> out like i say we in fact <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Memorial</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Day weekend</TIMEX> we went up to the lake and uh
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousins</ENAMEX> have a boat my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> is sitting in my driveway not running and uh so we go up there and we decided
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		that we'd you know go out first we got everybody's <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tents</ENAMEX> up and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> made and all that and said come on let's go fishing we hauled in well we brought in
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">thirty three fish</ENAMEX> and we had thrown a bunch of little ones back
 	
 	
 		good grief
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh so then we had a huge fish fry the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">next afternoon</TIMEX> and we went back out fishing and we caught and brought in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty three more</TIMEX> and had thrown a bunch of the little ones back but we had more fun those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		wow
 	
 	
 		they've got real fishing poles but they're the little short ones
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and it was so funny because i mean they'd just be hanging over the side of the boat <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> i think i got a fish i think i got a fish oh it was hysterical but
 	
 	
 		that's incredible
 		boy
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie</ENAMEX>'s getting to the age now that when i get up and go fishing <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">early in the morning</TIMEX> he wants to go too you know he doesn't want to get left behind anymore
 	
 	
 		oh boy
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so it's getting a little difficult to do that but
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		we love it we just love it
 	
 	
 		well i need to break my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> in they i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wesley</ENAMEX> that enjoys it but he hasn't really caught enough <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> to appreciate any fishing so i i'd like to break them in a little bit
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well i have to watch it because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ashley</ENAMEX>'ll out fish her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> half the time and so you know that gets a little sore
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-oh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but where we camp there there's a you know little bit of a inlet where we park the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boats</ENAMEX> and stuff so real <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">early in the morning</TIMEX> before it gets hot and then you know right at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">dusk</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um down in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> down there boy all those little sunfish come up and they'll go down there while i'm cooking dinner and just start reeling those little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX> in and they ha ve more fun with that
 	
 	
 		right
 		huh
 		what do they use for bait
 	
 	
 		oh usually i'll buy them a thing of worms or a lot of times i'll just give them a piece of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacon</ENAMEX> and they're taught they'll tear up <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacon</ENAMEX> and stick it i mean those they'll they'll bite empty hooks that's what's so funny
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		good grief
 	
 	
 		and when we're out chasing the big stripers we use those perch for bait
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah use the little ones for bait yeah why not
 	
 	
 		yeah it's great
 	
 	
 		oh me
 	
 	
 		but we just love it up there in fact <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie</ENAMEX> wanted to go up <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this weekend</TIMEX> with it being <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July weekend</TIMEX> but uh i can't put the tent up and all that kind of stuff quite yet i'm still pretty sore
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX> yeah
 		oh me
 	
 	
 		so anyway but
 		have you been um <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salt water</ENAMEX> fishing
 	
 	
 		i haven't really done any of that uh and oddly enough uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackie</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> live on the the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Carolina</ENAMEX> beach in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX> and and we've i guess we went out <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time
 	
 	
 		right
 		oh my goodness
 	
 	
 		and just fished you know from the shore like in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the winter</TIMEX> you know one <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> trip
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but other than that that's really been it yeah they uh i've always wanted to actually go out in the boat i think i went out on a a snapper party <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gulf</ENAMEX> once upon a time but uh and i was i was too sick to
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		to to enjoy that
 	
 	
 		right
 		
 		
 	