
 
     		
 	
 		TV show
 	
 	
 		
 
 		uh probably <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LA Law</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		huh why
 	
 	
 		uh i don't know i like all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> cases and uh the romance between everybody uh what about you
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		i like silly ones compared to  now i like um <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Perfect Strangers</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh okay my fiance likes that
 	
 	
 		you seen that
 		who oh your fiance
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and um i like that show with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Urkel</ENAMEX> i forget what
 	
 	
 		yeah she likes that too we always have to tape all those on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Fridays</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh-huh all those
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh yeah</ENAMEX>
 		and um i like those all those video shows they have now
 	
 	
 		oh yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Favorite Home Videos yeah on Sundays</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh-huh anything like that i like
 		what else do you like
 	
 	
 		yeah that's all right
 		i like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Price</ENAMEX> is Right too but i never get a chance to watch it
 	
 	
 		oh
 		you don't get to watch it
 	
 	
 		no huh-uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah i'm always gone at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		so you have to tape it or something
 	
 	
 		yeah or i just miss it
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		yeah i used to watch it all the time though i never missed it
 	
 	
 		huh
 		do you ever watch uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunday Comics</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no i never heard of that oh wait is that on like at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> or something yeah yeah i've watched that before it's all right
 	
 	
 		um
 		i think it's on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> it's funny there's this um black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">comedian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Wallace</ENAMEX> that makes a joke about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Price</ENAMEX> is Right you know
 	
 	
 		oh okay i never seen that
 	
 	
 		uh i don't know if you've ever heard that joke he's like uh he said that show is prejudice because they have like the dumbest hugest black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> on that show and they run down and they're like
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and its just funny you just have to see him because he's like grabbing himself and
 	
 	
 		oh so i'll have to watch it tonight
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> it's funny
 		and um
 		i i guess i just like funny shows mostly
 	
 	
 		yeah i usually have the TV on just for background noise all the time
 	
 	
 		uh-huh me too
 	
 	
 		yeah i don't i don't think it's ever off
 	
 	
 		uh-huh i have it on right now  CHiPs is on
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah i just turned it off when the phone rang
 	
 	
 		oh
 		um
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		um
 		you like soap operas at all or
 	
 	
 		no i can't stand those
 	
 	
 		uh-huh me neither
 	
 	
 		do oh wow that's that's odd <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> actually don't like them
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		huh
 	
 	
 		yeah i think they're the stupidest shows
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and um i guess i like like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Twenty Twenty</ENAMEX> and any kind of
 	
 	
 		yeah those all right <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sixty Minutes</ENAMEX> is okay
 	
 	
 		um-hum documentaries because i teach
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		and lots of times i can tape them and use them for school
 	
 	
 		oh that's a good idea so television's actually useful
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah it seems like we have cable and there's never anything on we just have more of nothing
 	
 	
 		i can't afford cable
 	
 	
 		oh it comes with our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX>  so you're not the huh
 	
 	
 		huh so do you live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> or are you from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no huh-uh
 	
 	
 		where you are from
 	
 	
 		i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay because <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> i got somebody in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and um before then i think everybody was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		so hm
 	
 	
 		no we have to have cable because we're up in the mountains and you can't get anything
 	
 	
 		oh huh that's interesting
 	
 	
 		
 
 		but there's nothing on TV ever hardly
 	
 	
 		huh because we have <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about a zillion</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX> here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh we we can't get anything we can get like one
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		without it
 	
 	
 		God that stinks is it like a rip off or cable or not not is it reasonable or
 	
 	
 		it's all right i don't think it's that bad
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		but there's never anything on
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's just background noise again
 	
 	
 		hm
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX>'s from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		um-hum what part can you um-hum
 	
 	
 		right in the middle
 		yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center County</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		yeah we don't have any TV <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX> in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> so they're all from other cities
 	
 	
 		become
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		hm
 		well
 	
 	
 		yeah i guess we watch a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> too
 	
 	
 		huh that's the news station
 	
 	
 		yeah but it always repeats like every <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">half hour</TIMEX> so we watch the same thing every <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">half hour</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		that's like <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Good Morning America</ENAMEX> i think if you watch it long enough i think they repeat at least like the headlines
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and
 	
 	
 		yeah after like an hour or so you just watch everything again and again and again
 	
 	
 		so
 		um-hum well at least you know the news real well
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> think are impressed by wow  how do you know all this stuff
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah then you get <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sick</ENAMEX> of watching like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> not this story again you don't pay attention to anything
 	
 	
 		huh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		huh
 		um trying to think of some other shows do you like <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Three Stooges</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no i like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Laurel</ENAMEX> and Hardy though
 	
 	
 		really because a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> like The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Three Stooges</ENAMEX> and they drive me crazy
 	
 	
 		yeah i never got into them much
 	
 	
 		huh i know how about cartoons do you like to watch cartoons
 	
 	
 		yeah i like the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Road Runner</ENAMEX> cartoons
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> loves anything like that <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Bugs Bunny</ENAMEX> or
 	
 	
 		yeah they're not on that often though
 	
 	
 		hm
 		and um
 	
 	
 		least not around here
 	
 	
 		hm
 		i like uh i used to like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pee Wee Herman</ENAMEX> before they took it off
 	
 	
 		yeah i guess no one will be watching that anymore
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pee Wee</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Playhouse</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well they said he might do something else now like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">branch</ENAMEX> off a different way like maybe more adult humor or something
 	
 	
 		yeah that's what he started doing anyway
 	
 	
 		yeah uh-huh i like that stuff i mean he was always a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pervert</ENAMEX> you know it didn't surprise me when he got caught you know doing that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah i wasn't too surprised either didn't look like him though
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> yep
 	
 	
 		all the pictures
 		yeah i've seen that show twice and it was the same one both times
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i guess i never will see it anymore
 	
 	
 		yeah because they're repeats now or they were repeats before they took them off
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		
 		
 	