
 
     		
 	
 		do you have any hobbies
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yes i do
 	
 	
 		what are yours
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">china</ENAMEX> painting and ceramics
 	
 	
 		ooh how great
 	
 	
 		i enjoy it um-hum
 	
 	
 		oh uh ceramic painting
 	
 	
 		i enjoy the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">china</ENAMEX> more
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">china</ENAMEX> more
 	
 	
 		and now that i have my eyes  corrected to the point that i can see the delicate part of china painting i do enjoy it
 	
 	
 		how did you ever get into that that sounds so interesting
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> kept begging me and he's been dead now for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years</TIMEX> so you understand that this was a long time ago
 		but he finally brought me the china the book the brushes and he said i have made arrangements for your lessons
 	
 	
 		how marvelous i
 	
 	
 		and i said i'll do it for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three months</TIMEX> and if i don't like it that's it
 		well i painted  an awful lot until his death which was several years
 		and it has just been the most relaxing enjoyable
 		self satisfying thing i've had i
 	
 	
 		now do you do it just for yourself or do you do it to give as gifts or do you actually sell it
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i have sold quite a bit i give a lot to our <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX> that are grown and have their home and then i just have the rest of my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> with lot of hand painting in it um-hum
 	
 	
 		oh that sounds marvelous now do you work outside of the home
 	
 	
 		i have just retired
 	
 	
 		you've just retired oh the oh what a great hobby i
 	
 	
 		yes
 		no it's not  it's a great hobby but don't retire  oh it's
 	
 	
 		uh don't retire well see i don't i never uh returned to work for the past i have stayed home for about the last <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nine years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh have you well
 	
 	
 		we've transferred around and our last area was in a rural section right on the lake uh on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lake Erie</ENAMEX>
 		so the lake life appealed to me and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s working and he left it up to me if i worked or not
 	
 	
 		wow
 	
 	
 		so in my spare time i love to sew there aren't too many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> around anymore that really enjoy sewing
 		but i do make all my own clothes and we recently purchased a new home so i enjoy doing my uh toppers for my window applications
 	
 	
 		oh i see
 		oh um-hum
 	
 	
 		and things like that but uh just when i thought i really enjoyed my hobby yours sounds great
 	
 	
 		well if my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> is the seamstress of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of us
 		and but she doesn't china paint so we both have our expertise sided
 	
 	
 		that is excellent
 	
 	
 		um  what part of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX> are you in
 	
 	
 		we're in the suburb i'm in the suburb of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cleveland</ENAMEX> and i'm about um
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fifteen</NUMEX> miles probably from downtown <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cleveland</ENAMEX> something like that and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cleveland</ENAMEX> is located right on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lake Erie</ENAMEX> and prior to this we were fifty <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">miles</NUMEX> west from here so we were right on the lake
 	
 	
 		yep
 		yes
 	
 	
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cleveland</ENAMEX> isn't all as bad as what you've heard  and you do find <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> uh into the crafts and the things that uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		various things for spare time but i have never heard and i have actually never run into anyone into the china painting and i'm just intrigued with it
 	
 	
 		well
 		if you ever start be sure and start with a large piece that you can i mean a large flat plate hm
 		that way you can get the feel of you're not cramped on these smaller objects
 	
 	
 		right where you're getting into the delicate work now do you where where did you first get your lessons from
 	
 	
 		that's right
 		in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Abilene Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		through a uh an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adult ed</ENAMEX> or uh strictly a china type
 	
 	
 		uh she just taught china painting um-hum and
 	
 	
 		oh how marvelous
 	
 	
 		and when then we had so much fun there i had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Albany</ENAMEX> which is <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about thirty six miles</NUMEX> away
 		and we would meet <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> at our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">instructor</ENAMEX>'s home because she did our firing for us
 		and she would help us and we bought lots of equipment from her supplies and it was just such a delightful time
 	
 	
 		oh and it's so nice it must be so nice for you now that you're retired
 	
 	
 		and then after i beg pardon
 		i have been a little bit negligent about it because i was so tired when i had to go to work after my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s death
 		so i have put it aside for a little while but i'm i have just found me an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">instructor</ENAMEX> to get started again um-hum
 	
 	
 		oh isn't that great and you'll probably really uh regain regain your enthusiasm for it once you get into a a class again
 	
 	
 		oh i know
 		of course i just have one beautiful <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">peonies</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">peonies</ENAMEX> uh umbrella stand and i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX> and they're both
 		
 		
 	