
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		all right um how do you feel about the health insurance problems
 	
 	
 		well uh i agree that they have problems but i i'm afraid i'm very much against universal health  um my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> is uh
 		uh stationed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> right now and of course you know they've had uh group health uh over there for some time um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i was over there last uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year ago</TIMEX> when my granddaughter was born
 		and uh she had some problems and uh i was horrified from beginning to end  <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of all they are about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fifty years</TIMEX> behind
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they don't have and their medical technology he <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> since they aren't responsible really to each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> don't feel they have to sit down and talk to you about the problems
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		when they want to do something to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few days</TIMEX> old or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty or ninety</NUMEX> they do it they don't ask permission
 	
 	
 		wow
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> went <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">um upstairs</ENAMEX> into intensive care to see the baby and they were doing surgery on the baby and she didn't even know they were going to surgery on the baby uh
 	
 	
 		oh my God what a terrible thing for her to go through
 	
 	
 		yes it was it was really terrible that's why i went over there i mean she was she cried she called and was you know really you know upset um <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> we were leaving the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> finally
 		um we were getting all ready to go home and finally you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> was okay and everything was fine and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> that had been working with her poked his head in the door and he said by the way he said in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six weeks</TIMEX> he want you to come back uh
 		for a test uh uh a test that we want to do on on her um for uh uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">multiple sclerosis</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		ah
 	
 	
 		and he turned around and left
 		and we just kind of looked at each other and said what
 		uh for what and i i tried for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">fifteen minutes</TIMEX> to find the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> and he was unavailable
 		so uh i've had some bad experiences with it i i uh perhaps not you know uh i don't know a good solution do you have any ideas
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well no i i i had never had experiences like you did which sound terrible to go through
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well the the thing is these are the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMO</ENAMEX>'s that they have now which are cheaper and you can in my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> my other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> belongs to an HMO or they used to thankfully they've just changed um you don't
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you only get a choice of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> that are in your area not necessarily of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> that are good or not uh see i i've worked for i worked for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John Hopkins</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> there and i've worked for a private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> and um
 		i got to slap in the face as far as the medical profession was concerned in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> uh now the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> that i worked for was good but there was another one in our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> that uh she didn't feel should even be practicing medicine and i said well why don't they
 		get him out of there she said well he hasn't done anything wrong it's just that he has poor judgment and i thought oh gosh i mean you're the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> telling you this you know
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		some horror stories like that but then with the HMO um the they sent here to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pediatrician</ENAMEX> that had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> gentleman that was uh
 		uh in his late seventies
 		and an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> that she couldn't understand and that had no patience with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		ah
 	
 	
 		and you know it was kind of that was kind of a bad experience too so when they changed she finally got
 		you know a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pediatrician</ENAMEX> but uh uh it it it's
 		it's just a little scary when you don't have as much when you can't just go say here's a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> i'm going to go to this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> you know um
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and i i fear that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> are going to not be as you know right now they're in a lot of fierce competition  so they they keep up to date you know at least most of them the good ones
 		um i i i don't know i just fear that uh that it may go downhill if we do indeed you know change to something like that uh
 	
 	
 		that doesn't give any incentive
 	
 	
 		no it doesn't uh also
 		uh we uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilian</ENAMEX> but we were uh stationed overseas for a while and so i had to go to
 		myself and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> had to go do military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> huh wow  now that's another story you know so but it's the same
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		same thing i mean these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> didn't want to be here okay they were forfilling fulfilling their military obligations and you know they uh of course i guess if you a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> gets into the field you know they uh
 		well enjoy the field but um the i have found
 		uh through <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that i know that have <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMO</ENAMEX>'s that most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> that they see there may be one or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> good ones and the rest of them are either foreign speaking
 		i mean not speaking but like <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> you can't understand them because of their their um uh accent
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> or uh <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> or and i have nothing against them in fact i went to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> that was a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> but i could understand what he was saying
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know so i just it just this is a bad subject for me to be on  only because i've had some real bad experiences and i've known some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that have uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i guess so
 		i just joined an HMO i just got a new job and i haven't heard i haven't been i haven't even actually paid for it or actually started my coverage yet but that's what they have is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMO</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		been
 		right well i'll tell you now what you do
 		is you go uh to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> and just meet them
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and get feel on you know you can usually tell if you go to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> and if you you give him
 		i don't know some ache or pain or just how they you know reply um if they're going to be good or not the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> that will sit down and talk  to you and that will you know do things like that uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		is uh uh
 		is usually pretty good but uh uh you know you i'll try him out
 	
 	
 		well what they told me at at work they told me that uh
 		they said that the most once you get to know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> well you get you get your choice of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> but there's huge waiting lines for the good ones and there's no waiting lines for the bad ones so you don't really get the good ones even if you choose them you don't get them for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> if at all
 	
 	
 		yeah ow it should okay see that's it
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		yeah so that's see that's what scares me about going into universal health
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		okay  i mean  you could  you could really be in serious trouble if you wait to see one of the ones that you feel are better if uh uh you know if we went to that and that was all there was uh
 		um uh
 	
 	
 		how would they decide who get's which doctor
 	
 	
 		oh well they don't  it would it would still be like it is now um the ones in your area
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh i see local
 	
 	
 		you know and that would be closest to where you live uh and you know those are the ones that you would see i mean i would presume um
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but uh but also now in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> how they work it is you go to see a regular <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MD</ENAMEX>
 		if he determines that it's necessary then he'll send you to a gynecologist or a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">surgeon</ENAMEX> or you know you can't just go there
 	
 	
 		right that the same for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMO</ENAMEX> and and because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> work for the HMO the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i work with are telling me you know <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMO</ENAMEX>'s are great if you're generally healthy
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		and you just go for the checkup <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> or whatever it's just <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">three dollars</NUMEX> but if you have a problem then it's real hard to get the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> to refer you to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">specialist</ENAMEX> because they're told you know not to  because it cost the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMO</ENAMEX> money
 	
 	
 		yes
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yep
 		um hum
 		that's right and uh i mean you know that could potentially be um
 		rather
 		
 		
 	