
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well the weather has been certainly has been hot and it's been humid i don't remember a year in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time</TIMEX> that the humidity has stayed up this high
 		for uh this late into uh well it's not really late into <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> but the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the humidity</TIMEX> has hung around all of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah are you native to this area
 	
 	
 		no i grew up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michigan</ENAMEX> so uh but i've been i've been in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> for fifteen years
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so uh but you know i know the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summers</TIMEX> get hot but it certainly uh this humidity has just really hung on there
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		yeah it seemed like well you know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> was so strange having all those heavy heavy rains in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> we really didn't have heavy rains until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX>
 		kind of like pushed the season back a little farther and now it's kind of lingering with kind of still a bit of humidity and it just tried to rain i mean i was coming in from my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> just <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a few minutes ago</TIMEX> and it was trying to rain which
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		seems strange to have it raining in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX> normally we don't have too much uh humidity or or uh rainy time when it's past <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh that's right that's right i can remember it not it's really <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX> that it happens you get those great big cracks in the ground where it's been so dry and it just gets so dry and the earth opens up
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		i can remember <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first year</TIMEX> i moved here and it didn't rain i moved here like in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late August</TIMEX> and it didn't rain from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX> until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX> until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX> and i went home and told it just doesn't rain in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> i mean it was great after growing up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michigan</ENAMEX> and not and all you know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> was cloudy <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">almost every day</TIMEX> was cloudy and i you
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		you sort of forget how much it did <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rain</ENAMEX> and coming here and then it didn't rain it was just wonderful
 	
 	
 		well yeah see i i lived in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX> mainly i lived in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pontiac</ENAMEX> just a little while before i came down here and
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		you know so many times when you were trying to schedule outdoor activities you just never knew if it was going to be a go or not because of the weather it might rain on your little parade
 	
 	
 		that's right that's right
 	
 	
 		you know and here it was like pretty much you could schedule some activity outside anytime and you really didn't have too much of a chance of it getting rained out
 	
 	
 		yeah uh
 	
 	
 		you could pretty much do whatever you wanted to do
 	
 	
 		that's right oh
 	
 	
 		what part of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michigan</ENAMEX> were you living in
 	
 	
 		oh i grew up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dearborn</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		which is a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">suburb</ENAMEX> of of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Detroit</ENAMEX> you probably know where that is because i know where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pontiac</ENAMEX> is so uh  anyway yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		anyway yeah oh a teaching job
 	
 	
 		what brought you down here
 		so you teach in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plano</ENAMEX> schools
 	
 	
 		yeah i did i did for a while uh-huh so i'm home with <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> so uh so new career
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 		okay
 	
 	
 		new career but uh anyway so that kind of uh well i had been down here to visit so i finished school and said hey let's you know find a place that has a nice job and uh
 		that's how it worked out
 	
 	
 		well yeah i think a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were uh leaving <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michigan</ENAMEX> all about the time i came here in the early eighties and it seemed like it was almost a mass exodus you know the the little joke about will the last <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> leaving <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michigan</ENAMEX> just turn out the light
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		oh well it's a nice place you know i mean it's it's a nice that's a nice place though
 	
 	
 		well you know i i said i lived in uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pontiac i</ENAMEX> didn't live in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pontiac</ENAMEX> i lived to the west of it uh
 		i forget the the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">county</ENAMEX> but you know where all the lakes are around there
 	
 	
 		okay sort of
 	
 	
 		i lived in an apartment <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the lakes it was real close to where i worked it was only like <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">four miles</NUMEX> to work
 		and it was wonderful being on the lake like that you know in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> you feel like you're you know on a vacation all the time because you're right on a lake and everybody's you know out enjoying the water and such and
 		uh in the winter time the lakes froze over you could still kind of go sledding and such out there but i thought it was just really neat to be out there on all those lakes there's lots of really small ones out there
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know like maybe <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a mile two</NUMEX> long that's enough to uh do some boating and it was lots of fun
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		that's right that's right <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Lake i think Lake Whitmore</ENAMEX> is the only one i have real memories of
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		which is
 		well i think it's i think it's toward <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ann Arbor</ENAMEX> so it's
 		probably out in that direction but that's the only one i probably could name after all these <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>  so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		but uh
 	
 	
 		but it was yeah just lots of little lakes and of course it was you know a little more expensive to live on the lake but i just thought that was grand and i think a lot of people
 		didn't really know that there were all those lakes out there unless you were from that area and kind of spotted them but there was quite a few lakes all around there it seemed like it was almost like you were living on an island there was so much <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> around where i was
 		i said i wasn't close to downtown <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pontiac</ENAMEX> i was way out to the west maybe <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four or five</NUMEX> miles from from the city limits and it was really nice out there
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		we had uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pine Knob</ENAMEX> you know to go skiing and stuff so there were things around there really was pretty nice
 	
 	
 		oh
 		right right
 		sure sure and don't isn't that where they have a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> music festival there too
 	
 	
 		right right in the summertime they have musicals there and in the winter time they make snow and have a ski slope
 	
 	
 		uh
 		that's right that's right i know we used to we we didn't do a lot of it but we did
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		we did so those are always fun and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alpine</ENAMEX> was it <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alpine</ENAMEX> was another ski slope that we went to so uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it was nice i always tell people
 		that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the winter</TIMEX> we use we used to uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> would kind of bank up the snow in the backyard and turn the hose on you know make a pond in the backyard for us
 	
 	
 		oh yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		so but uh you know we probably did some ice skating on it but then it chipped chipped and you know it would melt or whatever and get pretty uneven so
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah we used to have a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> time uh some of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> would come up from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alabama</ENAMEX> and i think most times we would have snow around <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> when they were young would just go nuts
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know because they were from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alabama</ENAMEX> where it never snowed and they just had a grand time watching the snow and getting out there and playing in it you know eternally
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh oh right right if only it would make nice snow here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> we'd be okay at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> time
 	
 	
 		
 
 		my <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX> here i i came down in uh <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">early eighty two and</TIMEX>
 		there was just a freak snowfall early <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one morning</TIMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX> before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">couple days</TIMEX> before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> it lasted <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">only a few hours</TIMEX> like by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX> it was gone
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		and i remember getting up and somebody telling me hey better wait to go to work because the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX> are all you know snow  and i was laughing going yeah right that's a good practical joke <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">ha ha</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		they said no really there's snow and there was but a very short time and the weather got warm so quick it just melted it all away
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah yeah i kno w
 	
 	
 		course when we get an ice storm that's not too much fun
 	
 	
 		no that's not fun either so uh i i just as soon have all the slushy snow on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> than have the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but uh well we have our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> is kind of on a little hill so uh we get the sled out and uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> go down the hill
 		the hill on the sleds when it's icy i mean they just go down the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX>  and if it's cold we say okay out you go i think we must be the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on the block that make use of that cold weather and get out there
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 		oh yeah i think it's fun even the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX> storms i've gotten out there in my ski pants or something and still just been out and enjoying it a little bit i mean
 		sometimes the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX> is pretty bad but if you get on the the uh grassy kind of part you get a little bit of traction you know not slip and fall i mean first
 		
 		
 	