
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 		okay
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		you there well have you had
 		this with one of your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> yet
 	
 	
 		uh not with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> although my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> are now in their early seventies
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh fortunately they have to this point been very physically healthy and very self sufficient
 		and they really look after themselves and i think considered what they want done as they get older and maybe less able
 	
 	
 		what what is do they want done that's interesting that they've already said
 	
 	
 		well the it it's more that they have when they retired and we are from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Dakota</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so they retired from the rural farming <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sioux Falls</ENAMEX> which is the biggest <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> in the state
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and set themselves up near medical <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> and i i can't say i can tell you what they've uh decided as to okay because i think some of that is that
 		maybe you think ahead somewhat but you don't uh book those <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		right and it depends on their health too i know some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> say they never want to go to a nursing home you know where others say well you know put me there if i get that bad you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		now my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> are seventy <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> and eighty one
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they're they're still
 		taking care of themselves but
 		when they were your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> age they were doing much better now it's gotten to where it's just barely and we know it's going to be probably
 		anytime you know that that we're going to have to
 		change them from their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> or something you know
 	
 	
 		well have they do they recognize the coming and try to make the decision themselves
 	
 	
 		no my stepfather is one that's always had a horror of nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> and don't ever put me there now my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> on the other hand i do not think would mind you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh they live in a small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">twenty miles</NUMEX> northeast of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> and uh
 		and so the nursing home there if if they had to go there there would be some of their old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> there you know and it's and rather than in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> where you probably wouldn't know anyone so that would be to their
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		advantage but uh i guess you know i don't know how long i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> stepsisters but
 		we really haven't really discussed it that much either we should have by this point you know at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">seventy nine</TIMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty one</NUMEX> but i guess we're just waiting to see what happens and then i guess we'll make a make decisions then
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh but my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stepfather</ENAMEX>'s health is is failing bad you know i don't know if he has starting of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Alzheimer</ENAMEX> or
 		or what but the last say <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX> since he had to have some kind of brain surgery he's been going down hill you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh so anyway i uh by this time we should have probably made some decisions but we haven't so i i can see a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>
 		here in the neighborhood too uh one's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> just got to where she couldn't take care of herself anymore in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> as far as you know eating <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meals</ENAMEX> and
 		all that kind of stuff she just wasn't doing it you know so she has come to live with her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> in the neighborhood
 	
 	
 		yeah that is one of the options but uh that is so related to the family situation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and
 		uh you know i guess not that it's happened in our case in my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> because it well i have seen it in their generation it what you do is first see your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> go through it with their parents
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i would say well at this point um you could say been through all that because i have no no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX> left uh and it's
 		you see all the different options and you see that they all can work uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		i've almost been surprised <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last three or four years</TIMEX> with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> in the neighborhood as many
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> it's always been <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> have come to live in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> but then maybe they'll have a stroke or something and and then then they'll go to the nursing home but they go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">home</ENAMEX> first
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well if they're uh that's the thing if they're physically able it is a much more pleasant more caring uh situation to be in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">home</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh the other side of that is that if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are no where near where the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> had spent their life then in a sense you you have no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> at the new place
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh in this that you are unless that you develop new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and uh the best thing is kind of a combination where
 		uh the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> if not several are uh uh back in the area where the parents uh had spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">their years</TIMEX> and then
 	
 	
 		that would make it easier yeah if if you were but like you say then to uproot them and take them to another <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> or something
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh in some of the cases i was talking about in the neighborhood though they have been up rooted from another <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> but then but then maybe things
 		had gotten where they live that they never really saw anybody much any more anyway you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		too uh they you know get to where they don't get out that much anymore
 		maybe especially if they hadn't always lived in that area they're moving from
 	
 	
 		yes well it's it's not an easy choice because it's but uh it's something that we all face and we uh
 	
 	
 		right
 		and then then it's then it's our turn so we better better handle it well because it will be
 	
 	
 		yeah but the way society changes it makes it so that uh what was acceptable for our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> and their parents
 		may not be as workable for us it it's certainly a problem as we as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> live older of course as long as you can live a healthy life uh
 		the uh the care is is not near the issue it becomes when you start having the physical problems
 	
 	
 		right and of course one thing we haven't even discussed that makes a big bearing on what you do is the cost
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		you know if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> if they are going into some kind of of nursing type home you know that
 		helps helps them uh you know do they have the money to pay for it or are the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> going to help out to make up the difference
 		you know if there's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> that might be <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">three thousand</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 		
 		
 	