
 
     		
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		all right well i am uh the product of uh
 		i think as much the changing roles of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> as anyone my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> uh we come from a my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> and i were uh really practice <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> generation divorce in our family
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		my uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> was divorced in nineteen uh fifty <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		when i was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven years old</TIMEX> and was i was the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> one of anyone that that anyone had ever known  to have a divorce
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		of course now fifty <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">percent</NUMEX> divorces in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> uh was treated very badly uh in a by a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> um especially from my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s side of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and also uh
 		uh
 		uh we were uh ostracized by his family uh basically just you know uh we just kind of dropped off the face of the earth
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		and they all felt that there there was never an issue that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> was the was the cause of the reason for the split up even though he had impregnated another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> and forced the divorce
 	
 	
 		oh mercy
 	
 	
 		uh it was always my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s fault she was not uh sufficient you know she just was not good enough what was wrong with her was she not attractive enough did she not take good enough care of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> to keep his interest it was that kind of an attitude
 	
 	
 		yeah that that's too bad
 	
 	
 		so uh yeah it was too bad it was really rough
 	
 	
 		um um that's sad it really is
 	
 	
 		uh so you know that's so changing some of the changing roles of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in that respect i have been a product of
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um i think that there are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that i think that uh i was a i was <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> generation going to college in my family
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh first my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> had always had a quote career but always a career as a uh uh in a secretarial position she did rise to the highest position that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> could rise to in a secretarial profession profession in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Des Moines Iowa</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's that's wonderful
 	
 	
 		she was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> to uh uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> as well as for him so that was a really high high status position she made over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty thousand a year</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well that's wonderful that speaks well of your mother
 	
 	
 		well yeah she a real hard lady yeah hard driving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> with a steel rod up her back you know
 	
 	
 		she had high standards yeah
 		oh bless her heart
 	
 	
 		but uh so i went to college and now since have completed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masters</ENAMEX> degrees and i am the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of music in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> um and but it's interestingly enough i am still everyday confronted with
 	
 	
 		challenges
 	
 	
 		absolutely challenges that have to do with my sex uh for instance uh well you know i am just not taken as seriously you know at professions
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		as many of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> as many of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> who are doing the same job i do
 		and uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">choir members</ENAMEX> treat me differently because i am a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> they expect me to be more motherly
 		they question my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authority</ENAMEX> more uh than they ever would a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> and i have experience with this because i work at both both as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of music and also as an associate under a man
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so i am pretty i am pretty obvious pretty constant i mean i am pretty aware of what goes on uh in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> so basically that's that's well i am done talking do you want to talk
 	
 	
 		surely
 		well i think that you carried forth your subject matter very well uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nickie</ENAMEX> and i can uh relate to that uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh i think it's it's the image that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> has and uh in the world as uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the lesser of the two
 	
 	
 		oh always
 	
 	
 		and uh i think things are changing but the changing is taking a long time longer than we would like it to
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		like it to take and uh i think we are progressing at a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">snail</ENAMEX>'s pace but we are progressing
 	
 	
 		indeed
 	
 	
 		so that's the main point is that we are going ahead
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh i think that uh in the long term that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> are going to be able to have the recognition that they deserve and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> uh have a lot of them have uh come around and have seen the error of their ways
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but there are a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">die-hards</ENAMEX> out there that will never change so we have to uh face that reality also
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		i have never been able to figure out why they can not ever change why they can not bend i mean why they can not just accept you know competent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> i i have never been able to understand that i guess it's fear  i i mean what
 	
 	
 		it could be if they are after they are not sure of themselves
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		the one's that uh go along with that they are sure of themselves
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they know that they can uh you know uh be on the same level
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they do not have any uh
 		ego
 		uh problems that they are fighting
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		i think that we are going to be uh on par with them in salary and in recognition in the long term
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 		and i what i would like to see happen futuristically is what we are discussing is that yes uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we each have our uh jobs in life and that we should recognize that and that we should support each other
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh i think our problems would be fewer if we supported each other
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and just looked at each other as equals and none lesser because we are equal
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> have a lot of trouble with that though
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they in their in their own peer relationships they do not treat themselves equal and so it's really difficult for them to treat <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> as equals they are they are really much more comfortable with somebody being the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> and somebody being the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">follower</ENAMEX>
 		uh it just seems that it seems it seems that they are more comfortable that way and i do not know if that's i mean that's it's a militaristic point of view i guess you know somebody can not be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colonel</ENAMEX> and everybody else is infantry but it's just really interesting to me i am married to a wonderful man
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		you know who treats me very you know with a with as i think probably is as enlightened as anyone can be at this particular stage in their life time but when he gets angry it's always over control issues it's always over power issues
 		it's never over you know it's always you said you were going to do something and you did not do it as if he is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> and i am the you know and i am the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slave</ENAMEX> and it those are the only only issues we ever fight about
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i think it's just i think it's just difficult for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> to uh to accept <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> equally even if they want to they are more comfortable when somebody is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX>  uh dictator <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dictatorships</ENAMEX> are real efficient
 	
 	
 		well i guess we would have to go back to the way that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lord</ENAMEX> made us and uh
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> when they are married they are to be subjective to their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husbands</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		and i believe that strongly
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		and uh but i think that they should be in harmony
 		with what they are with what the subject matter is
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		and i think the issue should be settled
 		before there's a conflict
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and i think that can happen in a very wonderful wonderful way
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		and if we <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> would do as the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX> said that we would esteem each other higher than ourselves can you picture that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i mean if your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> did that to you and you did that to your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> you would always be trying to please each other and not yourself
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah it's true
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		that's really the the divine answer and and the right answer  so uh uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that would be a beautiful
 		relationship
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> it would be
 	
 	
 		and i think there are some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that
 		have done that and i have seen it and it's it's just marvelous and i am just in awe to see this
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	