
 
     		
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> issue is
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		is a bit of a problem i guess the first thing that comes to my mind not having any immediate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> with that problem is is the financial end i mean how
 		can a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> stand to uh spend as much or much more than they already are
 		on such a problem uh but then that kind of thinking is also tempered with the the knowledge or at least the the rumor i'm not really sure if it's true or not that uh we're not spending
 		<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">as much</NUMEX> per let's say afflicted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> uh there's some uh take breast <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> for instance it seems to be doing much more damage and affecting much more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> mean more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AIDS</ENAMEX>
 		and yet uh more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> die of it and yet the funding is already uh exceeded <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> has more money than uh <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and well that's interesting isn't it yeah
 	
 	
 		so uh i mean if it's true i i've i've always heard these things i've never bothered to dig it out and make sure but uh
 		i've heard it on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than one</NUMEX> documentary that uh they were complaining that
 		whoever's sitting up there making these decisions uh or whatever <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX> raise the money and uh
 		it's just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PR</ENAMEX> campaign that yeah we think that's the world's worst thing so let's give money to <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX>
 		and yet we've had breast <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> problems for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and it's just one of those
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		well of course one of the shows i saw was taking it from the angle that since it doesn't effect <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> it's not gonna get funded
 		and uh having thought about that for a while
 	
 	
 		what did you think about that idea
 	
 	
 		well i i kind of i thought well that that might be possible since there are a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> in control of that kind of thing but then i got i got to thinking
 		the the number one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">killer</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> seems to be the prostate and there's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> test that just recently got developed uh a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood antigen antigen uh  antibody</ENAMEX> test for the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antigen</ENAMEX> in the blood
 		and that's fairly recent and yet <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> have been dying from <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">prostate cancer</ENAMEX> for years
 	
 	
 		hm they've not really given it attention either yeah
 	
 	
 		so it's not really cure for yeah it's not uh not that heavily funded either and that seems to be one of the the major
 		uh problems that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> have in the realm of cancer so i don't know i i guess there's just some strange public opinion as to who they want to give to um be it
 		through different <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Dimes type uh telethons</ENAMEX> or or bicycle rides or whatever
 		how they fund whatever um illness they wish it's it's kind of hard to
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		to get an even keel on that i mean it's really hard to say well there's you know a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundred thousand</NUMEX> per year affected by this one so let's give it this amount and then this other one's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only a tenth</NUMEX> of that so give it <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a tenth</NUMEX> of that and and just keep doling it out that way or
 	
 	
 		well i'm i'm glad i'm not the one that's  that's in charge of of making those decisions they uh
 		you wish that there could just be money for all these problems because they're all so serious you know i mean it's not so serious i guess until it affects your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and then all the sudden it's the most important thing
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		so i i would hate to have that  responsibility just personally but but then again we really we really do have it as a society just decides which things we need to address
 		i uh
 		i guess i it it frightens me to think  of so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> and with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> and
 		many of those things um if they're not able to to be insured then the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s gonna pay for it one way or the other
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		whether it's through
 		prevention or or treatment or you know
 		just uh just helping the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> when they are not able to take care of themselves
 		so it seems like one way or the other we're gonna end up paying for it
 	
 	
 		that's true
 		you know the the other thought that i had um i've had <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">several minutes</TIMEX> to think about this after i uh while i was finding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i uh
 		i could think about the topic longer than the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> that receives it so it's kind of a
 		a unfair advantage as they were but
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		the other thing that i've thought of on this is i wonder if there isn't enough money
 		uh in our economy or in our system uh it seems like there's so much that goes to things that don't really do a whole lot of good i mean yeah they're kind of nice but
 		we have such an affluent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">society</ENAMEX> society that i wonder if if we took a little from here and there and the other if we might wind up with a uh cure for just about everything of course then we wouldn't have any room to put <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> but that's
 	
 	
 		just change our priorities
 		right just change our priorities a little bit and
 	
 	
 		yeah you know you hear these ridiculous figures for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pizza</ENAMEX> or you hear these these  phenomenal amount of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">dollars</NUMEX> spent for this that or the other and then you have all the arts that that are nice and aesthetic but
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		are they that enhancing for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masses</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masses</ENAMEX> you know they certainly do well for those who go to the symphony <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">orchestra</ENAMEX> and all that but uh
 		had all that donation and time and labor and effort gone toward something else
 		
 		
 	