
 
     		
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		well did you go to college
 	
 	
 		yes i did
 	
 	
 		and where did you go
 	
 	
 		i went to a small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberal</ENAMEX> arts <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um it was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sweeper College</ENAMEX> it was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about seven hundred and fifty</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> i had
 		gone to a small
 		school growing up uh
 		and a lot of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> went
 		to univerty <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Michigan</ENAMEX> but my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> were retiring in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Carolina</ENAMEX> when i graduated and
 		um were looking for a southern <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> also <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U of M</ENAMEX> seemed overwhelming in size and
 		um
 		what about you
 	
 	
 		well i went to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Minnesota</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh so you're from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Midwest</ENAMEX> too
 	
 	
 		i am uh-huh where do you live now
 	
 	
 		um i live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> now where are you
 	
 	
 		well i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh um my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>'s in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX>
 		um he lives Lakeway he um had moved uh we're in Plano
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		i'm familiar with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plano i</ENAMEX> visited once or twice
 	
 	
 		and
 		oh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX> is so pretty i really like it
 	
 	
 		oh i love it i love it i really do
 	
 	
 		and your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> is going to be a sophomore
 	
 	
 		that's correct i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX> but my oldest will be will be a sophomore
 	
 	
 		is um because you live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX> is she thinking about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		she has her heart set on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U T</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and um you know having gone to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Minnesota</ENAMEX>
 		i know what a big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX> is like and um
 		one thing that i did <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this summer</TIMEX> which i thought might benefit both my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX>
 		is my youngest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> got involved in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baylor</ENAMEX> has a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">band</ENAMEX> camp
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		so she went for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> and it was <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">overnight</TIMEX> and they lived in the dorms
 		and i thought this would expose both of them to what it's you know like on a college a smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> campus
 		and um my oldest <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> just wasn't impressed at all with the idea of a small school
 		so um
 		i i i still think the exposure was good
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		the reason i ask if you went to college is i thought well you know what were your selection criteria did you base it
 		on what you wanted to major in or what you would feel comfortable with or what you could afford or you know there's all of these
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">areas</ENAMEX> to look at in making the decision
 	
 	
 		um yeah those um and those were several uh
 		that we did consider um my parents
 		uh um certainly didn't push but
 		wanted me to look in the south and because i had been in a small school
 		they suggested that i probably i when i say small my graduating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> had eighteen in it
 	
 	
 		oh wow
 	
 	
 		and so they suggested that i might want a smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> because i was used to a lot of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one-on-one</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh definitely
 	
 	
 		um or small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> situations and
 		i did pick it because at the time i was interested in majoring in
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">biology</ENAMEX> and i also wanted to spend
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one year</TIMEX> studying in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> um i had had an A F S student
 		from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> live with us our senior year
 	
 	
 		oh how exciting
 	
 	
 		i and we just thought that would be a wonderful thing and
 		i ended up majoring in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the reasons i picked the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> was because they had a strong science department
 		they also had a strong language <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> and i'd always loved working with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> um
 		and
 		i found that i couldn't
 		fit everything in
 		but because i had had a fair amount of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> going in i was able
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		to do <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">my year</TIMEX>'s study in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> and able to take a lot of the other <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courses</ENAMEX> that
 		interested me um
 	
 	
 		oh that was a that worked out very well for you
 	
 	
 		and so that was some of but
 		several of the things you mentioned were the things that um
 		our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> has talked a lot about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> A and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX> he's but he thinks he wants to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> and i don't think that
 	
 	
 		well then he should come to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U T</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> and really his
 		his graduating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> will probably be in the neighborhood of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight hundred and fifty</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a thousand</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 		and so he's used to a bigger size and because my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> is there
 	
 	
 		large classes
 	
 	
 		uh he would have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> close by so there there are advantages um but i also
 		because i had so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> who did go from our small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> to
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Michigan</ENAMEX> which was so large and they really felt
 		um like they were numbers
 	
 	
 		oh i went from a large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">high school</ENAMEX> to a university large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX> and i definitely felt like i was a number um i mean
 	
 	
 		you still
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it is a different feeling but that was that was my only option
 		i i mean i just really couldn't look at anything else that was the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and only thing i could really afford other than a junior you know a junior college which i didn't want to do
 		so that's how you know my decision was made but um
 	
 	
 		well that's that's certainly um
 		especially <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> with the cost of college i mean that is a a major
 		um consideration and i do feel fortunate that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> has so many good <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and even though <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baylor um</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		and when you mentioned that we we have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> who have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> there
 		who just love it and for a private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> it is not as expensive as most are and it is a smaller size and
 		um
 		i do feel like there are a lot of options it's it's
 		but  i had been hoping some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> i know give um
 		oh even this year <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jay</ENAMEX> had an aptitude
 		test um
 	
 	
 		what what does he hopes to be a writer
 	
 	
 		yes he thinks that's what he'd like to do but he's really strong in math and science too and
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		we keep encouraging him to keep an open mind does your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>
 		know what she'd like to do
 	
 	
 		oh she she has uh you know interests that are just you know going in all directions um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		what she talks about a lot is theater which i think is okay <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bethany</ENAMEX> let's be real  um
 		she really is is pretty unfocused at this point
 		and i don't know she's taken a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">French</ENAMEX>
 		and she may end up doing something with that
 		and i am a single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> so
 		i've been and i made the mistake of dropping out of college to get married so i'm trying to have my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> not make the same mistake
 		and i'm you know showing them if you're strong in math and science kiddos
 		this is one area where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> can make some decent money
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		you know i mean i'm kind of really putting the practical
 		application you know and and saying yet d o something that you enjoy
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		by all means go get that piece of paper you know do you just have one son
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		i see
 		well it sounds like he's got some really you know good strong ideas of what he wants to do
 	
 	
 		well he but he has even now that he's in high school um and of course there's there is
 		still time but he's beginning to feel that
 		as much as he enjoys writing he wonders if he can make a living at it you know it's the it's
 		
 		
 	