
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		i had uh just
 		my last <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> i bought was a new one i ordered it from uh you know from the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factory</ENAMEX> with all the little options and stuff i wanted on it
 	
 	
 		all the goodies
 	
 	
 		it was a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oldsmobile</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oldsmobile</ENAMEX> had you owned <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oldsmobiles</ENAMEX> before
 	
 	
 		yes i had i liked uh
 		i had had a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">four two</NUMEX> and i when i was younger and that was uh
 		quite a car
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		and you what just the memory of that made you go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oldsmobile</ENAMEX> again or
 	
 	
 		uh well i looked around uh
 		i think it may have had some influence i just liked uh
 		this particular car it was a good buy i got it through the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX>
 		they had at the time the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">fleet</ENAMEX> purchase agreement
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		so that uh took a lot of the hassle out of it
 		and uh you know i got all the things i wanted the sunroof and the luggage rack and all that
 	
 	
 		um-hum are you still driving that car
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		how old is it now
 	
 	
 		it was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty five</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty five</NUMEX> are you going to be looking again soon or how long do you normally keep <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time</TIMEX> or
 	
 	
 		well uh i am now i've uh
 		i bought a houseboat and had other expenses so i'm not i'm not in the any position to be buying a car right away
 	
 	
 		oh my
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		although i was look like i might have to but because i had a little trouble with it i had to have a valve job and so forth done on it
 	
 	
 		oh my
 	
 	
 		seem to be running pretty good now
 	
 	
 		was it still under warranty or
 	
 	
 		oh no no this was just recently
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		you put a lot of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">miles</NUMEX> on a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> or
 	
 	
 		uh yeah i do a pretty good bit i've got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about ninety six thousand</NUMEX> on this one here
 	
 	
 		oh my
 		for what <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">almost six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">well</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six years</TIMEX> huh
 	
 	
 		yeah i drive <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about eighteen miles</NUMEX> out to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> and back
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		each day i mean each way
 		thirty <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">six miles</NUMEX> a day
 	
 	
 		well we don't we don't buy new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> that often we drive them you know until they get
 		maybe <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven or eight years old</TIMEX> and then
 		we'll what we'll do is sell off we'll have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one about seven</NUMEX> say and one twelve or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirteen years old</TIMEX> and we'll get rid of it and then we'll
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		buy a new one and and uh i guess right now we have a
 		a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seventy eight</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chevy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">wagon</ENAMEX> and then a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a four year old</TIMEX> uh Crown <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Victoria</ENAMEX> that i love and
 	
 	
 		
 
 		you like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fords</ENAMEX> huh
 	
 	
 		uh-huh well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> got to chose choose the make  and then i got everything else
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		uh
 	
 	
 		he he he likes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fords</ENAMEX> and my youngest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> still lives at home he's in in college but he drives an old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX> seventy <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX> pick up
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		that he loves but
 		no i this was the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> they made the big Crown <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Victoria</ENAMEX> and before they started chopping it up and making it look ugly so i it look i i guess some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> think it looks boxy but
 	

 	
 		oh yeah
 		
 
 	
 	
 		always like to to have a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> in a car i'm not into compacts i like
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		that was uh
 	
 	
 		something you can relax in
 	
 	
 		something we uh
 		were interested in for our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> while they were learning how to drive was a pretty good size car although <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of them decided on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trucks pickup trucks</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 		well that's not that's a good choice for a child i think to start to start to drive in
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		our oldest <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> started in a old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Datsun</ENAMEX> of ours but our <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> one
 		uh bought a real old i i guess it was a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Olds</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ninety eight</NUMEX> but it was one that was still metal before they brought in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fiberglass</ENAMEX> and we she was such a nervous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX> we felt like she's probably better off in that
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		you know if she if anything did happen she was going to be all right but
 	
 	
 		yeah that's
 		well that's true i mean they uh they should have a little <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> around them
 	
 	
 		not well just for safety's sake
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and i don't know i i look at the new ones on the market now and the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX> are so
 		sleek i guess for wind resistance you know and and uh they just don't look like they're roomy inside i guess they are i haven't been looking at them to
 	
 	
 		plastic
 		
 
 		yeah
 		well there's a lot less <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> in this one i have than the earlier ones i've had yeah this is supposedly a
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		i guess they call it a midsize <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> is it supposed to seat <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah it uh well no it's a it's got bucket seats in the front and you can fit you can fit <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in it
 	
 	
 		uh okay
 		a lot of knee <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> in the back or
 	
 	
 		it's fair uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		nothing
 		anything like your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crown Victoria</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		just you know you can sit in there and it's it's reasonably comfortable
 	
 	
 		right right
 	
 	
 		i don't sit back there very often
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well i even even in our <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> i know like when my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX> and sons-in-law all have long legs they're tall <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and so if one of like my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s driving then he soot scoots his seat back
 	
 	
 		yeah me too
 	
 	
 		and so we can't put a we can't put a tall <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> with long legs behind him
 	
 	
 		
 
 		same here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six</TIMEX> i'm <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> foot <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> so
 	
 	
 		so it
 		oh my word yeah you're like my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son-in-law</ENAMEX> yeah
 		no that's so you can't then then like i could sit in back because i'm only <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five four</NUMEX> so my legs would fit
 	
 	
 		well
 	
 	
 		fine back there but you couldn't put a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a real long legged</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> back there comfortably
 	
 	
 		that influences my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> purchase decision too because i can't really get in a lot of these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toyotas</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Hondas</ENAMEX> and stuff
 	
 	
 		right w ell well yeah i wonder sometimes you know we have the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mavericks</ENAMEX> here that play and they'll show them sometimes on TV and they've all got these real low sports <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		maybe yeah well now sports <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> they have a lot of room for your legs you know you kind of sit lay
 	
 	
 		and i
 		well i've never been in one so i but i'm always wondering how on earth somebody <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">six seven six eight</NUMEX> getting into those little old things
 	
 	
 		you get into a little more of a reclining position
 	
 	
 		they must because i don't know where they're going
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah their feet go way up under i've driven a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Camaro</ENAMEX> i mean uh
 		yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chevy</ENAMEX> sports <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Corvette</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		Corvette yeah
 		well even to get out of it though i mean you're you're only a foot off the ground at the most
 	
 	
 		you got to
 		that's true
 	
 	
 		and it's got to be you know you can't get your leg out and so i i thought i always you always see them standing by it you know if they're advertising they don't ever show them getting in and out
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah right
 	
 	
 		and i thought that's the part i'd like to see
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		is them getting in or out
 	
 	
 		the unfolding and folding act
 	
 	
 		right well listen i never had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> that's had the swivel seats that where you can like when you're wanting to get out you just turn it to the side and then your feet are
 	
 	
 		no i haven't either
 	
 	
 		and and i don't even know if they i know for a while back i saw them advertise that and i thought that might be kind of a neat
 	
 	
 		looks like a real good idea to me
 	
 	
 		a neat thing to have but i i for some reason they don't carry them and i don't know if they found they were unsafe or
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		you know maybe to do that they had couldn't make them where they were just real stable
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		one thing our does our <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> doesn't have that i'd look for in another car is that that little
 		gutter like it runs so that when you open the door the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> doesn't just come off the it doesn't have that so when you open our car door it comes the new the new one does
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so they i guess that's  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> they learned that's not a good idea because it just comes right off the roof and straight down and just you know i try to put an umbrella up there but that doesn't help too much it just
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so i get the interior wet and i don't like to do that just along the side there
 	
 	
 		well you all don't get as much rain near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plano</ENAMEX> as we do here i'll bet
 	
 	
 		well i i don't know  we
 	
 	
 		
 
 		sure been wet this i never seen a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">spring</TIMEX> like this
 	
 	
 		how many inches do you all average a year
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		how many inches do you average a year
 	
 	
 		oh i don't know but we're way we must be way above average <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> because it's been terrible just rain rain rain
 	
 	
 		you just have had a lot
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		is it is it uh kind of a dirty rain you know i i've never been down in there but you always here how polluted with all the oil
 	
 	
 		no we're no
 	
 	
 		it's not
 		it's not
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">huh-uh</ENAMEX>
 		it's just rain
 	
 	
 		well i i didn't course
 	
 	
 		no it's uh i don't think it's any particularly polluted here i mean you can
 		i guess if you went uh if you went over by the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">refineries</ENAMEX> and stuff you might
 	
 	
 		oh it is up here too it is everywhere but
 		with all the oil right right that's where i was thinking of
 	
 	
 		no that doesn't
 	
 	
 		that doesn't that doesn't affect
 	
 	
 		huh-uh no we never notice that over here we live on the northwest side
 	
 	
 		ah
 		then you don't have any trouble with the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> or
 	
 	
 		hi there mister <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Colombian</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		just had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> come back from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colombia</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh my
 		well i just
 		i i don't know i you know i just hear that when you read about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> seems like they're course all their advertising or not advertising but news reporting is maybe an oil
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">refinery</ENAMEX> blowing up or something like that you don't ever i i need to get down that way i guess sometime when i retire
 	
 	
 		
 
 		they have a
 	
 	
 		see what they have
 	
 	
 		well yeah it's not that far
 	
 	
 		i know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandchildren</ENAMEX> keep me landlocked
 	
 	
 		they have a they have a
 		they have a uh big you know it's a big complexes all around the ship <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX> over on the east <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">east</ENAMEX> side of town southeast
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		other than that you know it's a nice clean city real modern
 	
 	
 		hum
 		hum
 		yeah i  that was where they had
 		when the economy went bad <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple years back</TIMEX> they had all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">limousines</ENAMEX> for such good buys
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 	
 	
 		we had one of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">principals</ENAMEX> at our of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plano</ENAMEX> an elementary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> went down and bought one
 	
 	
 		
  
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i think she paid eighteen or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">twenty thousand dollars</NUMEX> for a limousine and she's still driving that thing around and they tease her
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		just just you know to see her drive up in front of the school everybody wonders who it is
 	
 	
 		yeah never heard of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">limousines</ENAMEX> being a good buy know we had plenty of real estate though
 	
 	
 		it was just a
 		well they they just said you can you know the limousine <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> were going out of busy and and you could pick one up for
 	
 	
 		oh yeah oh i guess that's true yeah
 	
 	
 		for a real good buy and they had supposedly in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> they had a lot of them
 		so i thought well that i don't know we even debated about that at that time but decided no that wasn't the
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		that wasn't the route when our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> were little we had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">van</ENAMEX> which we loved for for traveling we had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and they just that allowed them to really move around
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		we did
 		we had
 		
 		
 	