
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 		we're to discuss a little bit about the process of putting someone in a nursing home and and making the decision on a family basis and probably the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> question would be whether you've ever had to go through that process
 	
 	
 		well not so much personally but my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">um husband</ENAMEX> has an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aunt</ENAMEX> who has been like a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> i mean always lived in the same <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> and took care of him and such
 		they live down in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">College Station</ENAMEX> where his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> do too and they put her in a home <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> she appeared to have a couple of light strokes and started to uh not be able to be in her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> on her own
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so they found a a place nearby that they put her in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		so it was pretty much a physical decision
 	
 	
 		uh yeah although she is uh in pretty good health and she's doesn't take any <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medication</ENAMEX> it's just she had had her own <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> and drove a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and everything up until that point
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		then she was starting to get uh you know lose memory sometimes and which is kind of frightening when she's in the car
 	
 	
 		yeah my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> are reaching that point but it's it's so difficult  was she in favor of it or or was she
 	
 	
 		uh
 		well yeah when it finally came down to it um she just got to the point after the i mean it wasn't a very um strong stroke it was just kind of all of a sudden she wasn't herself anymore
 	
 	
 		kind of opposed to it
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and she got kind of fearful of being on her own she never really ate very well it was one thing she hardly ever took care of herself and she didn't eat she ate very poor so i think she was you know bad uh nutrition on top of
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh she got to the point she didn't want to alone anymore so
 	
 	
 		so often i think though <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elderly people</ENAMEX> don't realize that their diet is that bad i work with a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elderly people</ENAMEX> i'm a trust <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		and so often they think they're adequately caring for themselves when they're really not eating very much or very balanced meals
 	
 	
 		well she was almost ridiculous like she'd eat <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice cream</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cookies</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes well you know that's part of the aging process that your taste <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">buds</ENAMEX> goes back to the sweet taste it really is yeah uh-huh
 	
 	
 		she'd
 		didn't one
 		
 
 		oh really well she didn't want to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cook</ENAMEX> for herself anymore oh that's too much trouble that's too much trouble didn't want to cook
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		and the portions <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't want to try to figure out little bitty individual meals i do that right now  and i'm not near nursing home age
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		although they've got uh <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Meals On Wheels</ENAMEX> which i understand is a really good you know way to handle that so that at least they eat
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		so as a family you all just
 		visited nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> or probably in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">College Station</ENAMEX> there wasn't a whole lot of choice
 	
 	
 		no i don't think there was um i know a little bit more from a a coworker her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother-in-law</ENAMEX> had been in for quite some time and had different degrees of a place that she was in
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um she was ambulatory and so there was a lesser care uh then she got uh uh hip broken and then uh she wasn't as ambulatory so they were almost you know to the point of saying she can't be here anymore but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i remember from her checking around she ended up staying at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arkansas House</ENAMEX> i think out in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arlington</ENAMEX> something like that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh you know the type of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> whether it's a shared <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> or two separate <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> that share uh a uh bathroom all of them all seem to say that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> there are going to steal their items
 	
 	
 		oh yeah that's a given
 	
 	
 		they
 		they're always saying that somebody's going to and some of them i think unconsciously do it you know as a just you know <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> senile
 	
 	
 		um-hum and sometimes the the help there does it i think
 	
 	
 		hum
 		so they they uh don't have too many <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> it seems for their personal items very limited space waste but um at least they all seem to have some
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that monitor their uh medication intake and dining <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> you know go to the dining <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> and and eat some good meals i know when my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother-in-law</ENAMEX> first went in i mean
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		very antisocial maybe it takes a while for them to say okay well i'll be with other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> but
 	
 	
 		adapt yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah i don't understand that they they don't want to be with anybody else
 	
 	
 		i as i think i mentioned i was in the trust business and i've seen so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elderly people</ENAMEX> usually there has to be some wealth involved which is great if if you're financially if if you don't make the decisions so late that you're worried about money but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">the</ENAMEX> places like <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Presbyterian Village</ENAMEX> and some of the the retirement places where where they have different levels of care seems to be so much better
 		as far as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elderly people</ENAMEX> adapting they're able to move in while they're still independent and still social and and they do group things
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then as health or or mental capacity deteriorates they're able to take the next steps without so much change and
 		oh i wish everybody could go that direction rather than just all of a sudden moving out of the home they've always been in it's really kind of difficult
 	
 	
 		yeah i have a um my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aunt</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> is uh gotten ill recently and uh she lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX> they live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alabama</ENAMEX> and they're saying hey we need you to be closer and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you have uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> like that i don't to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> it seems like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> out just out live their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husbands</ENAMEX> but very reluctantly that whole i mean they don't get out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> they don't socialize but it's my home and i don't want to leave it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well and it's the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> step in in actually accepting that you are failing and and aging
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		you know once you make that step you know that it's just going to be downhill from then on and and i've seen <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> really fight it that desperately needed to make the change
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		they they became in fact that's probably what's going to happen with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> she's going to endanger herself before she'll willingly and probably will never willingly make the decision
 		and that scares me the the thought of forcing somebody to do something
 	
 	
 		but it's it's so lonely you know they can't get out and see anyone and i mean it's hard for for someone like me to understand that because i think i think what do you have there it's a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> it's walls and it's furniture but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		not as independence
 	
 	
 		there's nobody there don't you want to be close to me
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i mean you know be with other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i just don't understand why they so much want to just stay in that building and there's no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> there they don't get to see their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandkids</ENAMEX> they don't get to see their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> they just there in that house
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah and the quality of life really isn't there
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		oh it's tough it really is
 	
 	
 		that's from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>'s standpoint the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> is going why don't you want to be close to me and your other family what does that <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> got attraction i never really thought of independence
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well they fear being dependent on somebody they they fear being a burden to to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> members
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> will have major surgery and we'll find out about it in a casual conversation
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		she'll let something slip and we'll  say wait a minute and and that's it she just well i didn't want to bother you she can't accept that we want to be the care givers
 	
 	
 		well when she got home who took care of her
 	
 	
 		yeah well she stayed she stayed in a temporary nursing home until she was okay
 	
 	
 		ah
 	
 	
 		you know it's just but it's frightening to us b ecause we live pretty far from her she's down in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Temple</ENAMEX> and we can't see her often enough to really know what's going on
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		um
 	
 	
 		so it's difficult it really is and we're all heading that way and
 	
 	
 		yeah my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and i we have been thinking about his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> are in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">College Station</ENAMEX> and we've pretty much planned that we'll be here in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> area and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		there's nothing to hold them there in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">College Station</ENAMEX> since they're retired so we thought maybe we could get them to move a little closer here
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 		
 	