
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hi Clarice</ENAMEX> um
 		have you had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> reunion recently
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">yes</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">just this last summer</TIMEX> we went back to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> and we met it was my we usually go to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> reunion but this one was my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they're usually quite similar i think
 	
 	
 		are you both from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> originally
 	
 	
 		no he's from here
 	
 	
 		oh uh-huh
 	
 	
 		but um most of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oregon</ENAMEX> so we kind of met halfway
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so this was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and they um planned it up in the mountains and got a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cabin</ENAMEX> and and had you know things like that have to be planned like they had planned that
 	
 	
 		oh how nice
 	
 	
 		we went to the reunion in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">end of July June</TIMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX> that part the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July weekend</TIMEX> but we had to plan everything like clear in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December January</TIMEX> to reserve that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		sure sure
 		now was this his entire family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousins aunts uncles</ENAMEX> things like that or his immediate family oh wow oh wow how many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were there
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		no this was everybody
 		oh i oh uh jeez i think over um <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three hundred</NUMEX> were there it was quite a large
 	
 	
 		wow wow
 	
 	
 		it was a great big lodge and so we had plenty of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> and everything and and some of them live in that area so it wasn't too hard for them to come in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> and leave but um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that was a great big thing and we do that with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> about every
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX> a great big one and then like immediate family we do like uh we try to do one thing once a year
 	
 	
 		oh that's wonderful oh
 		now how many how many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are in his immediate family
 	
 	
 		well he has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> so that's big by itself
 	
 	
 		oh wow
 		wow it really is and you get together once a year wow uh
 	
 	
 		yeah so we have a little shindig with them
 	
 	
 		are they all here in the area or are they scattered
 	
 	
 		uh they're close in a close proximity um
 		uh let's see there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> of them who live here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> and dad
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so um the others live in close neighboring <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">um states</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nevada Arizona</ENAMEX> i think like that and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh wow that's wonderful that's wonderful
 	
 	
 		yeah so it's been fun how about you
 	
 	
 		well we don't really get together i i would love to and that's why i checked that i wanted to do that because i would love to plan a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> reunion sometime um i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> and
 		uh a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> in upstate <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Connecticut</ENAMEX> and here i am in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> so we're kind of scattered right now
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and um my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousins</ENAMEX> have a you know they put on a family <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">reunion um</ENAMEX> once <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> but it's always like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the second week</TIMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX> so it's the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are already back in school
 	
 	
 		um-hum that's hard
 	
 	
 		and so and that's back in  and that's in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> and there's no way i mean there's just no possible way and it's not really a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekend</TIMEX> it's just like a day kind of thing because most of them are still you know um
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Connecticut</ENAMEX> the rest of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> stayed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> and uh on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Long Island</ENAMEX> and so they're all kind of local and close and so they just have a you know a day picnic
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh i've always thought it would be so neat even if it were just my immediate family to have like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a weekend</TIMEX> type thing
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		that would be so wonderful
 	
 	
 		it really is fun and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> does it once a year just like you said once a year um they have a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> through a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a Saturday</TIMEX> type thing you can come and go as you please type thing and they do that once a year i kind of missed it
 	
 	
 		oh wow
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> and felt bad but you can't go <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> you just cannot do that um
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah yeah
 		and do they they have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX> or where do you stay
 	
 	
 		um basically they just stay with each other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> there are enough in the area to
 		to just kind of span yourself out um whoever's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> it is you usually go and stay with them like i go stay with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		take everybody yeah
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousins</ENAMEX> they just go stay with their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> you know kind of thing and so it's not hard
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		in in that respect because they all are pretty centralized in one <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> area so that's not hard but
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah oh that sounds so wonderful isn't that nice
 	
 	
 		the real planning that's the real key and they send out my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> now this is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> reunion with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s family i've really been involved with
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> takes a turn <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one year</TIMEX> and that's how they divide it up and then
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> from each family
 	
 	
 		uh she has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> in that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and each <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of them take their turn and then the the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> whose turn it is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> whose
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh wow uh-huh
 	
 	
 		turn it is her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> help her like if it was my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s turn all of us <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> would help her put it on kind of thing yeah and um the thing is that um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh i see uh-huh uh-huh uh-huh oh wow
 	
 	
 		the the real part is there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> mailings that go out and the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> one is to just kind of give a an approximate date and time so you can start getting
 		
 		
 	