
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		you ready okay what have you seen lately
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well uh it's funny when i tried to make the call <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other days</TIMEX> i thought i hadn't seen anything since <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Dances With Wolves</ENAMEX> but <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> i went to see Regarding With <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Henry</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh i'm dying to see that
 	
 	
 		it was really good we uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jeff Warner</ENAMEX> just got out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> and uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deanna</ENAMEX> went and
 	
 	
 		oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> in the neighborhood and uh we all liked it we had uh both moms and uh fifteen <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year olds</TIMEX> and a twelve <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year old</TIMEX> and everyone enjoyed it and uh
 	
 	
 		oh my goodness
 		oh well i am just dying to see it i went to dinner with some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last weekend</TIMEX> and they said get a babysitter and we'll all go see Regarding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Henry</ENAMEX> and i said ooh i want to see it so bad
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> had gotten to see a lot of movies <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this summer</TIMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">choir</ENAMEX> tour and visiting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and one thing and another a lot of the ones i had wanted to see and so since he had this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> up from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> uh
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> had already seen so many and i thought they decided on this and i thought well i want to see this one too so  we uh i finally it's my <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">first summer</TIMEX> movie
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh my well let me see was it well we went to see <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">One Hundred And One Dalmatians</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last weekend</TIMEX> and that may be
 		no right before i went in the hospital my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX> said come on we're going to the movies and we won't well she goes all the time but i go maybe once every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> of months
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and when i go i go see <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> at a time so we went to see Soapdish
 	
 	
 		oh was that good
 	
 	
 		and oh hysterical we laughed so hard it was just you couldn't hear half the dialogue because everyone in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> was laughing so hard
 	
 	
 		uh well i want to see that and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Slickers</ENAMEX> both i love comedies but that's what i was
 	
 	
 		that's the other one that we went to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">that night</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh was it
 	
 	
 		and my face hurt so bad from laughing because i love <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Billy Crystal</ENAMEX> and course growing up on on the back of a horse you know and being on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ranches</ENAMEX> and stuff
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh
 	
 	
 		so much of that was so true and i was absolutely rolling in the aisles it was so funny both of them were great
 	
 	
 		oh well good i'm i'm glad to hear that because they
 	
 	
 		oh they are are we just laughed so hard and like i said with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Slick</ENAMEX> i mean with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Soapdish</ENAMEX> it is so cornball and it is so overacted that you're just hysterical you know just they just carried it off to the tee it was
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well i don't i don't know if you got to see <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Weekend um At Bernie</ENAMEX>'s that was out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of year's ago</TIMEX> they had a free showing at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Berkeley um United Artist</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no
 		how neat
 	
 	
 		and i don't know who was here or whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jay</ENAMEX> just called a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> and we didn't think we'd have much chance of getting in but we thought we'd try it you know free movie
 	
 	
 		shoot yeah
 	
 	
 		it was so funny and it sounds like uh what you were just describing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Soapdish</ENAMEX> too i mean we just we hurt by the time we came out and the whole theater was hysterical and it's just it's just goofy i mean it's
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		uh if you have a chance to rent it at least or it should be out on TV i would think
 	
 	
 		yeah i think it is i think it is
 	
 	
 		um because it's it's just a fun summer light comedy make your cheeks hurt laughing especially in the theater it was contagious you know i i imagine the way <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Soapdish</ENAMEX> was but with everyone laughing
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh gosh i never laughed and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were just screaming and applauding and you know it was just hysterical
 	
 	
 		well i'm glad you did that before your surgery
 	
 	
 		oh me too because i don't even know if i could live through it now i mean i'm getting around real good and i'm just still real sore and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> i was i course i went back to work <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks</TIMEX> after
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		oh gosh
 	
 	
 		uh but see i don't have permanent work i right now i'm working with a temporary agency
 		and so <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the second week</TIMEX> i was out of the hospital i went up and worked <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">half day</TIMEX> on the computers because you can learn all the software for free
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and so i went up to do <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WordPerfect</ENAMEX> because that seems like that's what everybody wants
 		and i was up there <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a day</TIMEX> and came home and collapsed and then they called me to see if i wanted to work <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a day</TIMEX> and i said yeah and i went and of course it took me the whole <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekend</TIMEX> to recover from that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh i worked <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about three days a week</TIMEX> ever since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two to three days a week</TIMEX> and
 		so i went to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Thursday</TIMEX> and this was my <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fourth week</TIMEX> checkup and he said well gosh you're just healing really well i just can't get over this he says
 		in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks</TIMEX> you can go back to doing your crazy normal things if you want to play ball you can go play ball he says now i'm not going to say you're going to feel like playing ball but you can if you want to and uh you know he was teasing me and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		he says yeah you'll be out there waterskiing i can just see it now
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and uh he says so you just take it easy for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two more weeks</TIMEX> you've only got <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two more weeks</TIMEX> i said okay fine i i will i will whatever you call easy i'll do it you know
 		but and i've been out trying to find a job because this is just not cutting it
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		and so i don't i'm real glad that we didn't go see those funny ones when i was when i'm still sort of on the sore side
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but well what what's your next have you seen <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin Hood</ENAMEX> yet
 	
 	
 		no that was one uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jay</ENAMEX> got to see  with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> and so i i and to try and uh
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		try and find time it's hard uh
 		with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jim</ENAMEX>'s schedule too just to get a time that we can both go and
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		um i'm holding out for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Slickers</ENAMEX> for the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of us because uh we had <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> that went to see that and said you know it's just perfect for our age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX>  and because i think he he needs a comedy too um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and that's what he would have liked to have seen Regarding <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry</ENAMEX> too but knew that
 		uh we've we've got a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this summer</TIMEX> which is wonderful we're really enjoying it but some of the different things we're doing uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		there's just not a time enough time to do it all and he said well realistically  you know he knew he couldn't get them all in but uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jay</ENAMEX> really liked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin Hood</ENAMEX> um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">choir group</ENAMEX> went to see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Backdraft</ENAMEX> and they thought that was uh
 		it was funny cause he sounded like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> he said you know the plot line and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> uh you know aren't real big but the the fire scenes and the drafts you know that action part is fantastic
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but he thought <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin Hood</ENAMEX> was great it was real different then you'd expect but he but he enjoyed it and so
 	
 	
 		oh really
 		well i went course i am a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Costner</ENAMEX> fan supreme
 	
 	
 		yeah me too and yeah i really uh like him a lot which is why <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dances With Wolves</ENAMEX> was the last movie we had seen for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several months</TIMEX> but it was i uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gosh</ENAMEX> was that wonderful
 	
 	
 		in fact uh a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> was visiting in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> and we wanted we didn't ran out of time we wanted to take him to see it we were going to sit through it again because we really wanted him to see it too
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		uh
 		i just thought that was terrific and i really enjoy <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harrison Ford</ENAMEX> which is one of the reasons i wanted to see
 	
 	
 		i do too i think he's really good
 	
 	
 		and he's very good in Regarding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Henry</ENAMEX> that's not an easy part to play i i don't think
 	
 	
 		i wouldn't think well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are going to their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> so i sort of think i may go do that
 	
 	
 		yeah that's at that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> won't your sides  um it was this the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time you got to see <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">One Hundred</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> Dalmatians
 	
 	
 		good
 		i have my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> took me when i was probably somewhere between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ashley</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie</ENAMEX>'s age and we went to the
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	