
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i really haven't seen any movies lately so when the computer picked this one i was a little bit surprised but i think i haven't been to the movie <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">theater</ENAMEX> here in about oh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six months</TIMEX> but um
 		you know the last movies that i've seen were probably on video
 	
 	
 		oh well that's we rent a lot of videos too  um we saw i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two little</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX> and we saw <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> movie recently and that was um The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Terminator</ENAMEX> movie um which i didn't like after all
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah now i haven't i haven't seen The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Terminator</ENAMEX> movie but and that's kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> and guts isn't it i don't particularly care for that sort of stuff
 	
 	
 		well i don't either it on all the the advertisements <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arnold Schwarzenegger</ENAMEX> says he doesn't kill anybody in the movie he doesn't he maims them
 	
 	
 		yeah right yeah he maims them pretty good doesn't he
 	
 	
 		so
 		um-hum he he uh i think he shoots off their knee caps for the most part  in the movie so
 	
 	
 		yeah uh-huh i i saw uh <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sleeping with the Enemy oh um i</ENAMEX> saw it uh oh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">couple weeks ago</TIMEX> i rented it and um
 	
 	
 		oh i haven't seen that one yet
 	
 	
 		watched it and i was i was pretty disappointed in it because i i was told by several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that it's pretty scary and intense and i was pretty disappointed in it now it's it's a good movie but i guess uh that they built me up too much
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh
 		yeah well it's
 	
 	
 		for my expectations in it there
 	
 	
 		with all the commercials uh and everything i haven't that's one we <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">wanna see i i wanna see uh Dances With Wolves</ENAMEX> but we haven't seen that one yet either on video
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah now i haven't seen it either but uh i've heard that it's real long that it's a good movie but it's long like <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three hours</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> that's what i heard too
 		yeah we've got to get it at a time when we can put our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> to bed and stay up late   to watch it so we saw uh the the uh movie with uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sylvester Stallone Oscar</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's right  that's right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oscar</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		supposed to be his uh his debut in comedy  which was an interesting movie but not very funny
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah i know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> saw that and she liked it so yeah
 	
 	
 		unfortunately
 		did she
 		well it was it was an  amusing movie it just i guess maybe it would have been better if  we'd have been at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theater</ENAMEX> as opposed to uh just at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> watching it with with no one else around so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX> and of course i get to watch all these movies like <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Look Who's Talking and Who's Look Look Who's Talking Too</ENAMEX> and because i have a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten year old</TIMEX> so we we watch a lot of movies
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh
 	
 	
 		around that category you know that she that she can watch
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> just turned <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> and so The Little Mermaid is now our favorite movie
 	
 	
 		yeah we seen <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Little Mermaid too</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we've Little Mermaid and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Pan</ENAMEX>  i think are are his <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> favorites that we've got
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		um-hum and there's some i think there's some good <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> movies fixing to come out on video um Shipwrecked
 	
 	
 		so
 		oh i haven't i didn't hear that was coming out
 	
 	
 		uh-huh yeah it's fixing to come out on video and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> i can't think of the other one that's fixing to come out
 	
 	
 		well they just had uh The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rescuers</ENAMEX> movie that was a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> movie wasn't it i think i heard that was just one was just out he's uh he doesn't sit still for the whole movie yet but he likes to uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		to listen to the music and stuff if there's a lot of that in the movie in the movie so that's
 	
 	
 		um-hum well i'm glad to know that there's somebody else out there that doesn't get to go to the movie theater
 	
 	
 		well i well tell you ever since my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are just small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX> and i tell you we we really want to go a lot and uh there's so much out on video now that it's almost you know the movie comes out quicker than you can go see it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		sometimes
 	
 	
 		that's right and then they go to the dollar movies
 	
 	
 		so
 		um-hum  that seems to happen i noticed that <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dances With Wolves</ENAMEX> was playing at the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Granada Theater</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh someone said that was a lot of fun to go do you can have dinner and everything while you watch the movie i thought that might be kind of fun to do
 	
 	
 		yeah that does sound fun
 	
 	
 		and of course you need a babysitter for that  definitely but uh you know i'd really like to get out to the movies more often course it's so expensive now too
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		that you can't hardly afford it i i don't know we get discount tickets
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		where my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> works but other than that it just seems like it's so expensive and then the popcorn and everything else you almost can't afford to do it
 	
 	
 		
 
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		no matter  what although we did actually get we went on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">vacation couple months ago</TIMEX> and we got to go see What About Bob
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that was kind of a funny movie with uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Dreyfuss</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Murray</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that was fun
 	
 	
 		golly i don't think that i've ever heard of that movie
 	
 	
 		oh he's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Dreyfuss</ENAMEX> is a uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychiatrist</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob</ENAMEX> is his patient
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bob</ENAMEX> follows him on vacation it's kind of
 	
 	
 		oh that's the that's the one where they burn down the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> or something the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> explodes
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		yeah that's the one
 	
 	
 		okay yeah another movie that i wanna see if it ever comes out on video so i can see it without my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> around is um oh i just forgot the title of it um
 		oh it's supposed to be a real scary one
 		um
 		darn well here here's another one that i've seen i saw um
 		um i can't remember the title of it either  um  yeah it really did it's uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		must have left an impression
 		
 		
 	