
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay i guess we're supposed to discuss the uh school system that shouldn't be too much trouble for the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of us right
 	
 	
 		no <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">as many years</TIMEX> as we've been involved in one i really feel fortunate in that there even though there are problems they're not a lot of problems where i teach
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but from talking to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">districts</ENAMEX> there are some major
 		problems uh with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dropouts</ENAMEX> um
 		when i was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last summer</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		there was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> who said that uh on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a given day</TIMEX> she didn't know how many of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> would show up and sometimes they didn't even show up for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> and she taught in high school in inner city uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minneapolis</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh they just didn't come to school and i cannot imagine being able to do much of anything when they don't even come to school
 	
 	
 		that's really sad isn't it
 		right well just recently in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> here were articles about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> um working high school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> that work and the percentage of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> that they work and how that affects their grades
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but then the follow-up <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next day</TIMEX> was i was kind of glad to see  because it it said that
 		you know yes but for those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> who are determined to do well anyway that you know handling a job was very possible
 		you know and that it seemed to have more to do
 		with other factors
 	
 	
 		i think so too
 	
 	
 		you know like what are their plans after high school you know and what's their home situation you know that
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> is the key i think really is because if the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">home</ENAMEX> does not place a high priority on education and um that the main goal is making money now
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 	
 	
 		and it may be a survival thing for the family which you can understand so um right
 	
 	
 		right
 		sure
 		but there can still be an attitude of you know this is a stopgap measure because we need it right now but but that the most important thing is still
 		you know getting your education well when they meant said the the topic you know of what's wrong with the public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> my my first impulse impulse was
 	
 	
 		your education
 	
 	
 		it isn't really what's wrong with the public public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> it's what's wrong with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's right it's what's wrong with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> and if if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> come to school
 	
 	
 		
 
 		and society in general
 	
 	
 		yes insecure and their more biggest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> is survival
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		both at home they don't know what to expect at home they don't feel secure there they don't know what's going to happen just out front of their
 		apartment <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> for example that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> that was shot
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh how can they concentrate on schooling i agree with you i think that's the main problem
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>'s now are supposed to solve
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">social</ENAMEX> problems uh mental and emotional problems as well as educate the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and try to provide them with some security and that's overwhelming
 	
 	
 		hm
 		yeah
 		well we've got um
 		you know at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">our school</TIMEX> we have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over a thousand</NUMEX> elementary kids
 		and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first year</TIMEX> that we ever had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counselor</ENAMEX>
 		and that's just really not enough
 	
 	
 		no it isn't
 	
 	
 		and i was talking to somebody that teaches in a middle school and they said oh but we need more in the middle <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> because that's when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are you know at a tougher and rougher age and all that but you know part of my feeling is that if you solve
 		help them to work through their problems while they're littler then they won't have as many problems up there
 	
 	
 		true i think they there has to be at least a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counselor</ENAMEX> and we just recently had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counselor</ENAMEX> at elementary we didn't even have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counselors</ENAMEX> in elementary we have always though had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> at middle <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> because we had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about a thousand</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		they divided them up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">between three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counselors</ENAMEX> but
 		for a good while <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> they'd have a different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counselor</ENAMEX> and they decided that didn't work so they started uh dividing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> up so that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counselor</ENAMEX> stays with her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of counselees
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		um-hum they they do that here
 	
 	
 		through you know through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all three years</TIMEX> of middle school and i think that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		would give them more security in going to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counselor</ENAMEX> if they have a rapport with their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counselor</ENAMEX> now if they don't
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i hope they have the flexibility to be able to change a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> that really is in need of counseling help if they absolutely refuse to work with them on and occasionally that happens
 	
 	
 		to change yeah
 		right
 	
 	
 		but it is frightening but
 	
 	
 		yes it certainly is
 	
 	
 		because um education is the key to our future and uh if we have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> who are not getting their education for one reason or another
 		than what are we going to do with them what's going to happen to them are they going to be
 	
 	
 		yeah that's right
 	
 	
 		able to uh work at other kind of menial jobs or are they going to be the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thieves</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> and our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prisons</ENAMEX> are filling up faster then we can build them that's no good
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right
 		i'm on that um campus
 		strategic planning <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> for my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and um one of the
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh  you know oh they have all these different names for things strategies and all these different things but anyway one of the key things was that that we believed that the public education is the best
 		economic value
 		then i think they decided to strike economic  anyway
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		you know the point was
 		what happens when public education fails you know will then <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> go to private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> you know well what kind of a situation do they get there and what are you know and what kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> are we in if
 		if most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are going to private schools
 	
 	
 		well i think uh one thing that we'll see is that we won't be educating everybody there will be a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who will not get even a menial education like in other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> of the world
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 	
 	
 		where they don't try to educate everyone that's one of the things that we do we try to educate everyone
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		that's right that's right
 	
 	
 		we're the only country in the world that does
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and let everyone have an opportunity to reach higher education if they're willing you know to work and have uh some ability they can do that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plano</ENAMEX> school district's you know goal is that they will graduate every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> that
 		um that is here in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">ninth</NUMEX> grade i believe it's something like that it's worded and um
 		i don't know
 	
 	
 		well you know if we can keep them in school
 	
 	
 		right that's
 	
 	
 		then that that helps a lot i think the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">gang</ENAMEX> violence is scaring everyone to death too
 	
 	
 		so important
 		oh gosh well that new movie that new movie out i hm really really a frightening situation i guess we're both lucky
 	
 	
 		it's scary to me
 		i
 		we are
 	
 	
 		to be in situations and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> where we don't see that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> talk about it a lot in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> was is was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and year s and um
 		they live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Peoria Illinois</ENAMEX> and their talking a lot about the
 		you know the school situation there too so
 		well
 		shall we wrap it up
 	
 	
 		um i would imagine that we've talked the amount of time necessary
 	
 	
 		I think we have to so i'll see you when we see you
 	
 	
 		okay
 		all right we were in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> the reason i was in the church
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and
 		we went to hear uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Win ensemble</ENAMEX> concert they left <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh how exciting oh that is wonderful what an experience
 	
 	
 		isn't wonderful
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> and uh the university
 		
 		
 	