
 
     		
 	
 		uh well let's see
 	
 	
 		how many you said yours are all i mean that sounds like an army
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh lord
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		that is an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> i came from a family of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>
 		and i have only got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> and they're one
 	
 	
 		well any number is nice let me tell you
 	
 	
 		well i kind of decided that single single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> that that
 		that's not parenting that's a hobby but
 	
 	
 		yeah it's not as fair to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> either i don't think
 	
 	
 		well don't tell that to all my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		they're into quality time i'm just into getting through <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the day</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 		yeah but sometimes you can hurt them by having too much quality time too
 	
 	
 		well i i can i can spot a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> who really you know whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> spend every quality time with them you know outside of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the work day</TIMEX> and when i take care of some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> you know when they when they have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX>' <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">holidays</TIMEX> and that kind of stuff i will take my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that are usually in day care and you can spot them because they have no idea how to just hang out and mess around
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		you can tell
 		how to just entertain themselves
 	
 	
 		yeah really
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		it's a problem for any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> and you take one that's used to being
 		uh busy being having something to do all the time it makes a big difference
 	
 	
 		it's not a problem for my <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> they're only <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eighteen months</TIMEX> apart
 	
 	
 		uh keeps you busy
 	
 	
 		they can
 		they can find things to do and mess around and and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		plot and scheme and everything else so you did all <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> of yours complete college
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well that's great
 		no our last <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> she didn't want to go to school she's uh but she's married now they built a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> just <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a couple miles</NUMEX> from us and
 	
 	
 		well how did you go about selecting a college then
 	
 	
 		well we didn't do it right all the time with our <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> we persuaded him to start here and i do not always think you should try to make them stay closer to home i think the main thing is to uh
 		right now i feel the main thing is to look at what they're interested in uh and take what they're interested in and then then start looking for schools
 	
 	
 		do you think that what they say that they are interested in is at eighteen is going to be what they are ultimately ultimately graduating at
 	
 	
 		no not necessarily
 		and but like our oldest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> i think he would have he wanted to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Embrey Ray Riddle</ENAMEX> and we talked him into going local here first
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and he only went <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few months</TIMEX> and then transferred to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX> he went to aeronautical uh oh just learning to work on engines and that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh it has to do with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">airplanes</ENAMEX> and everything which is what his whole life is  and i really wish we would have let him go where he wanted to go originally
 		and he would probably be flying is what he would be doing uh but but <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">right now</TIMEX> of course he's he's working for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pratt</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitney</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Connecticut</ENAMEX> and they build and rebuild uh jet engines
 	
 	
 		how about the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> who went
 	
 	
 		uh the other ones uh the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> one she chose we let her go where she wanted to uh we didn't want her to go but she went to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Erie</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gannan University</ENAMEX> uh or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gannan College</ENAMEX> i'm not sure which it is college i guess
 		uh she went there <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> and it was more expensive and she soon realized you know even though she didn't like <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Clarion</ENAMEX> she came back and finished at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clarion</ENAMEX>
 		because it uh saved her quite a bit of money and she got really the same basic education that she wanted
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and our other uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> they went to <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Clarion</ENAMEX> also and uh did very well there
 		and they've all really got uh
 		they've all really got really good jobs
 		and uh
 	
 	
 		when they were like in junior high and high school i mean had they did they have an idea that they were definitely going to go to college and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		uh yeah they kind of had that they just expected to go <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daphne</ENAMEX> never went she always said she would never go to college
 		she said i i always thought she'd change her mind you know but she didn't and there's nothing wrong with that you know if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> isn't for everybody
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh it it does make a difference in your pay wage income i think it's what they want out of life
 		because if they get an education
 		and are willing to go where the jobs are
 		they can make a you know a much better income
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		like my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> they're all making more than my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> was making when he retired from the state
 	
 	
 		yeah i was i was making more than i was making <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times what my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> was making as an executive in the insurance industry when he retired
 	
 	
 		you know that boggles my mind
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">okay</ENAMEX> did you go to college
 	
 	
 		yes i went uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX> undergrad at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Nebraska</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> is where where my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> lived and there really
 	
 	
 		you did see it makes a difference
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		there really wasn't a choice i mean the finances uh dictated that you had to go there
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i kind of i am not going to say i resent it but i was well one of the national merit scholarship qualifying and you know one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rhodes</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Scholars kids</ENAMEX> and the whole bit um
 	
 	
 		uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> didn't even discuss with me going to college out of state or anyplace else and i just knew that the finances you know would not support it if i had known
 	
 	
 		someplace else
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		how not i'm not going to say easy but how
 		much less difficult than i thought it would be to get a uh
 		scholarship to go anyplace else i think that i
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		would definitely you know have gone now when i finished there then i got a scholarship to go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard University</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> and that was uh i think that was probably one of the best things that had ever happened i mean i was
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		that's great
 	
 	
 		taken out of my element you know the the the homogeneous <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Midwest</ENAMEX> which is a lovely place to grow up and put into someplace else where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> thought differently looked differently sounded differently uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		different life styles yes yeah
 	
 	
 		different life style and i think it was probably one of the best things that ever happened to me
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		now my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> i keep saying that uh you know i would like them to go to the best <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> that they possibly could
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i don't know you know what the realities is going to look like you know we're putting money away already uh but i really think it's important to put these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> someplace where in addition to
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know them getting an education they really need a a you know a socialization away from what they are raised in especially if you lived a pretty insular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		an upper class suburb of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> let me tell you
 	
 	
 		it's quite a bit different
 	
 	
 		it's very different
 	
 	
 		see that's the way w e are we're more of a rural type of a area
 		and it does make a difference
 		i they say you shouldn't look at the expense of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> when you are looking
 	
 	
 		you should not
 	
 	
 		yeah not really because they say a lot of times you get more help
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		with a more expensive college
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		and so in the long run if it's really what they want
 		you know they're better off now our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> all pretty much borrowed for their school uh we we did all we could
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but they pretty much had to borrow a lot of their money to go
 		
 		
 	