
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 		okay
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hi Nancy</ENAMEX> well do you do a lot of dining out
 	
 	
 		
 
 		no um we don't although we enjoy it um we do it more when we have <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> come um what about you
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well we do some some dining out um i i do a lot of cooking so um
 		mostly like when we go out you know it's my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and i i we don't go out too often as a family um unless it's like a fast food kind of thing
 		but um but we do enjoy dining out <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of our favorite places here in in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> area is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Atlantic Cafe</ENAMEX> i don't know if you have you ever been there
 	
 	
 		i've heard of that but i haven't been there um where about is that
 	
 	
 		
 
 		um  well actually there's the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Atlantic Cafe</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cafe Pacific</ENAMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		oh okay i i've been to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cafe</ENAMEX> Pacific
 	
 	
 		have you the now that's down in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Highland Park</ENAMEX> it's <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Highland Park Village</ENAMEX> did you like it
 	
 	
 		right
 		yes um
 	
 	
 		oh i love it
 	
 	
 		before before we moved to the area my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> uh lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a number of years</TIMEX> and we came up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time when my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> was visiting and we all ate there and oh their <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">seafood</ENAMEX> was wonderful
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh it is it's fabulous it really is good
 	
 	
 		now where is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Atlantic Cafe</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Atlantic Cafe</ENAMEX> is down on i believe it's on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McKinney</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> and originally originally the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who owns the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cafe Pacific</ENAMEX> and the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who owns the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Atlantic Cafe</ENAMEX> were <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partners</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Atlantic Cafe</ENAMEX> and then they they separated and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> started <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cafe</ENAMEX> Pacific
 		and i loved them both i really do i think they're wonderful
 		that's our favorite you know what we'd really like if if we just have a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a casual evening</TIMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX>'s have you been there
 	
 	
 		no um but i've heard that's really good too and
 	
 	
 		it's wonderful the only thing is you have to wait you have you have to expect to wait <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">at least an hour</TIMEX> so you have to go knowing you're going to be sitting there there for an hour waiting to get in and
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		as long as you know that it's okay but they have i think one just about the best prime rib
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		um anywhere  in the area i love it
 	
 	
 		oh okay but
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> really likes their ribs so it's hysterical we go in and we sit there for an hour waiting to get in and then we get there and we don't even look at the menu  i know right away what we what we want yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		you know right away what you want
 		well we really enjoy prime rib too and uh actually the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">the Steak And Ale</ENAMEX> out here um
 		we've gone to uh
 		my in-laws also enjoy prime rib when they've had some of their specials on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday Monday</TIMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> and uh the time we went the prime rib was really good
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		was it
 		really i've never i've i've been there for like you know lunch but i've never been there for dinner and it was good yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		oh that's great that's great another nice place for for prime rib is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baby Doe</ENAMEX>'s
 	
 	
 		oh i've heard about that too but no  we've uh i guess we eat out even less than i realize
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maxwell</ENAMEX>'s nice have you been there
 		oh and i didn't think we ate out very often  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baby Doe's</ENAMEX> is nice and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> place i'd never been that i would really like to go to
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lawry</ENAMEX>'s i've heard that's real good <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lawry's Prime Ribs</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yes i'd i had heard that too um
 	
 	
 		i've i've never been there but i've heard it's real good
 	
 	
 		have you been to the little uh not for prime rib but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cafe De France</ENAMEX> um right here on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central</ENAMEX> Expressway
 	
 	
 		yes yes actually they have one in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Richardson</ENAMEX> that i've been to uh they have real nice <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lunches</ENAMEX> have you have you been there for lunch or yeah
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 		yes uh primarily lunch well and breakfast sometimes but uh
 		during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX> they often have a a limited menu choice but uh very reasonable complete dinners for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six ninety nine</NUMEX> that included the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">soup</ENAMEX> and or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salad</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		really
 		really
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">entrees</ENAMEX> and accompaniments and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dessert</ENAMEX> and uh the my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and i like veal uh a lot and their veal dishes have been good we've tried
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		different ones when they've had them
 		as one of the
 	
 	
 		the specials
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		have you ever been to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Biffin</ENAMEX>'s
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i keep hearing about it i keep hearing the advertisements of it and and they keep saying you know oh it's wonderful it's wonderful i have not been over there and i was thinking you know it's supposed to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> place
 	
 	
 		i yes no
 	
 	
 		over near <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Plano Super Bowl</ENAMEX> and uh i've i've not been there
 	
 	
 		right and
 		i haven't either uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> place and i've only been there for lunch but um i went with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> and we met her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> um down on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greenville</ENAMEX> down near the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Highway Twelve</ENAMEX> area is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gershwin</ENAMEX>'s
 	
 	
 		i've been there
 	
 	
 		oh i we just we it was and we had the uh we both enjoy <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mushroom soup</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda</ENAMEX> had told me they had the best <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mushroom soup</ENAMEX> and they did it was wonderful but um
 	
 	
 		that was nice
 	
 	
 		and we just had <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">soup</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salad</ENAMEX> so we could make room for the dessert uh  which was a chocolate sack i don't know if you tried but or something
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh i've heard of it where where it's made it's like it's like a it's all chocolate like made like a paper bag and it's filled with what whip <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cream</ENAMEX> and and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">strawberries</ENAMEX> and something
 	
 	
 		yes
 		it yes it had a sponge <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cake</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">whip cream</ENAMEX> and it had <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">strawberries kiwis</ENAMEX> and raspberries in a raspberry
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">puree</ENAMEX> and we shared <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> of us and it was plenty because it was very rich but uh i wished i'd had a camera it was beautiful
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh
 		oh i bet it was i bet it was
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		the last time we went to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cafe Pacific</ENAMEX> it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Father</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Day</ENAMEX> and we took another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> with us and
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		uh  for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dessert</ENAMEX> we thought we had just stuffed ourselves  and so we had they had uh like a
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">berry</ENAMEX> assortment it was it was raspberries and blueberries and and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">strawberries</ENAMEX> on a plate with like a custard on the bottom
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and you know they they did like the raspberry <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">puree</ENAMEX> just kind of like in a in a decoration on the you know how they do the
 		plates real fancy with the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">decorations</ENAMEX> and then piled the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">berries</ENAMEX> and shaved chocolate on top of it and it was outstanding it was really really relatively simple but oh it was good it was really good
 	
 	
 		yes yeah
 		oh
 		it sounds wonderful
 		well that's uh one of the things the that i do enjoy when you get a good restaurant uh i love fresh <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">berries</ENAMEX> and their
 		uh their <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fruits</ENAMEX> are always exceptional i don't i'm know they must have a special <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX> for getting them because even at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Farmer</ENAMEX>'s Market uh you can't find them like that and
 	
 	
 		you can't find them yeah  yeah yeah yeah you know i i'm originally from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Connecticut</ENAMEX> and uh
 		i was home <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years ago</TIMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> and brother-in-law were going to take us out for dinner and i was really amazed you know the the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> up there were kind of quaint you know they were real
 		real pretty
 		but they lacked the service and they lacked the atmosphere the just the i don't know the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> down here seem like they have uh
 		i guess there's so much competition that they really have to be good
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i thought i would really miss that
 	
 	
 		i would too because well i guess because we don't go out very often when we do go out um
 		in a way it's like a little mini vacation i guess and uh it is it's a whole experience of course you want the fo od to be good but the atmosphere and service i think are important uh too
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		and you know in order to survive in this area i think they have to be good because the ones that aren't so good don't just don't make it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		um that reminded me of a place for lunch that's a little off the beaten track but it is wonderful it's called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Cafe Max</ENAMEX> and it's at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plano Road</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Campbell</ENAMEX>
 		they have the most wonderful salads they do what they call a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salad sampler</ENAMEX> which easily could feed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two or three</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ooh</ENAMEX> really
 		
 		
 	