
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		where have you been on a wonderful vacation
 	
 	
 		well normally when we go on vacation we go home to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh that's where we go home too
 	
 	
 		really yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado Springs</ENAMEX> is where we're from
 	
 	
 		that's where we go
 	
 	
 		how funny
 	
 	
 		yes my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s family lives just off of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Academy Boulevard</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maizeland</ENAMEX> yes
 	
 	
 		really we live up up uh <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Lake</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Broadmoor</ENAMEX> area
 	
 	
 		ah
 	
 	
 		where my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> my in-laws are
 	
 	
 		oh we've been there we haven't skied at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Broadmoor</ENAMEX> we went there <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas time</TIMEX> and it was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">twenty seven</NUMEX> below so we had to cancel our ski lessons
 	
 	
 		oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> as  you can't even ski there anymore
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		yeah they closed it down
 	
 	
 		oh just this year
 	
 	
 		uh-huh they don't have enough money to keep it going it doesn't doesn't pay so
 	
 	
 		oh my
 		ah
 		so that wouldn't be a good spot to go on a vacation now if you were a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">skier</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well yeah and well now i don't know now <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado Springs</ENAMEX> is real accessible to like Breckenridge it's <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">only a couple of hours</TIMEX> away and uh so it's it might not be too bad if you wanted to go skiing somewhere else but you can't can't ski up there any more so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		no
 	
 	
 		oh uh i'd like to go on vacation i can't my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and i wanna go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney World</ENAMEX> but we have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> little ones that are under <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> right now so we wanna wait until they're a little bit older to do that and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yes
 		oh
 		well we went on a family cruise <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Premier Family Cruise Line</ENAMEX>  and then we went to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> it was all part of the package
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and on the cruise <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ship</ENAMEX> they had <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mickey</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Minnie</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chip</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dale</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goofy</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald Duck</ENAMEX> and it was really oriented toward little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well how fun
 	
 	
 		so the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> could eat with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chip</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dale</ENAMEX> you know and you know it's just a lot of fun
 	
 	
 		oh yeah oh i bet
 	
 	
 		so then we were on the cruise for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three days</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bahamas</ENAMEX> and then landed at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cape Canaveral</ENAMEX> and then drove over to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Orlando</ENAMEX> and spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four days</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		wow well that sounds pretty neat
 	
 	
 		yes that was the way to travel
 	
 	
 		yeah that sounds pretty good and it was all a big package deal where you just pay <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> price and get everything
 	
 	
 		yes
 		yes that's right that's right and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are really cheaper too
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		we really lucked out because the ship we were supposed to be on developed engine trouble <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two days</TIMEX> before our cruise so they said we could either cancel reschedule or take whatever was available so we took whatever was available
 		and we left a day early  and they put us up at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cocoa Beach Hilton</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ship</ENAMEX> that was available the only uh <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> that hadn't been booked were the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">suites</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		wow
 	
 	
 		so we got the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">suites</ENAMEX> at the same price as a regular cabin
 	
 	
 		oh what a deal
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		so then our cruise was actually extended <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a day</TIMEX> and our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> was extended a day so we turned a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven day</TIMEX> trip into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">great</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they paid for everything
 	
 	
 		well that's great oh
 	
 	
 		yes
 		so that was a wonderful vacation
 	
 	
 		yeah i bet uh that sounds like the way i'd wanna do it i think
 	
 	
 		yes
 		well what kind of things do you like to do when you go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh well we like to ski of course so we spend so much time with our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> uh and seeing our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> because we moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about two years ago</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		so when we go back we are just jam packed full of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to see and things to do so we don't we don't get a lot of time to just vacation we did um <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> though go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Antonio</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Memorial Day</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh
 	
 	
 		which was fun just to get to kind of walk around and see the sights down there and do that kind of thing
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh but
 		you know other  other than that with with both my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> being under <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> it's real hard to do any any kind of
 	
 	
 		right that would be
 	
 	
 		events that that uh don't require  babysitting
 	
 	
 		yes
 		i know i think one of the places i always hit in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> is that current outlet store
 	
 	
 		yeah  that's funny you should funny you should mention that i just got my catalog <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX> and was looking through it
 	
 	
 		that's what
 		oh with the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Santa Claus</ENAMEX> on the cover yes i've already ordered from that one but we will probably be going up at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thanksgiving this year</TIMEX> so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		oh do you live where do you what <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> are you in
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh you're in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes i'm in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> area
 	
 	
 		so am i
 	
 	
 		in Plano
 	
 	
 		i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Garland</ENAMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		uh so that's not too far
 	
 	
 		i talked to somebody from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wisconsin</ENAMEX> or something <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX> yeah so i guess they get <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from all over yeah driving for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thanksgiving</TIMEX> that's going to be quite a drive for
 	
 	
 		oh
 		yes
 		well it was when we left <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> we left on the eighteenth right before that big snow storm hit <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> and we pulled in just as it hit
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		wow
 	
 	
 		so how do you go do you go up through the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Raton Pass</ENAMEX>
 		when you go up there
 	
 	
 		uh no <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Raton</ENAMEX> uh oh well wait a minute yeah we do we do
 	
 	
 		do you
 		that's on like <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Route 287</ENAMEX> or something like that
 	
 	
 		yeah um-hum and then we go straight up through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trinidad</ENAMEX> and straight up <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">I-25</ENAMEX> from there
 	
 	
 		okay
 		okay we uh went a different way when we went <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Christmas</TIMEX> because of bad weather and because we were pulling a little <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">U-Haul</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trailer</ENAMEX> because we had to take our <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> in the car there was no room for luggage so we went all interstate we went up
 		um through <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma City</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then up through uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kansas</ENAMEX> and then turned left and went in on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">I-70</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and it wound up only taking us about an extra hour it was a little more mile wise
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but because you could go <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">sixty five miles an hour</NUMEX> on the
 		
 		
 	