
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 		okay well i guess i enjoy eating out um uh here and there or
 		it's it's a good change and good change from cooking and eating at home and i guess i like a variety of a variety of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh sometimes it's fun to go out and just have a hamburger and french fries and
 		and sort of a hamburger and french fry <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meal</ENAMEX> and sometimes
 		it's i enjoy going out having a formal meal
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		sometimes it's nice to go out and have a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salad</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		something you know
 	
 	
 		do you usually go out uh with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> or without them
 	
 	
 		well a variety i i like to go sometimes without them and sometimes i sometimes it's okay to take them along so  sometimes i think we pay the babysitter as much as paying for their dinner or lunches so uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		right
 		yes
 	
 	
 		it just you know it just varies we do a mix sometimes it's really nice to be able to go out and eat with just my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and it wouldn't even really matter which restaurant it was just to you know have a moment of peace and quiet without little ones at the table
 	
 	
 		yes
 		yes
 	
 	
 		so uh
 	
 	
 		well i
 	
 	
 		i guess i guess actually on those those times uh we even there are times i even say oh please don't sit us next to a table with other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no i
 	
 	
 		this is our night out so
 		but uh anyway where do you like to eat
 	
 	
 		uh well uh we don't have any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> so uh we tend to like to try all sorts of different things and uh we're very attracted to exotic food
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh we like <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Thai</ENAMEX> cuisine and uh sort of gourmet <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> and uh things like that
 		as well as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tex-Mex</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> and uh <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> and things and and things of that sort now yes of course we like to occasionally go out and get down and dirty with barbecue or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hamburgers</ENAMEX>  or something like that too
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and uh we probably go out <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> times a week
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		uh we're pretty much regulars at an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> local <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> restaurant
 	
 	
 		oh which one do you like
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Momo</ENAMEX>'s
 	
 	
 		oh okay well it's been a long time since we've been in there but uh but it's good there's an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> over over by the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mall</ENAMEX> over by uh <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Plano Parkway</ENAMEX> there past oh is it <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Campari's</ENAMEX> or something
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		i've heard about it i haven't been in there
 	
 	
 		well it's good i haven't my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> had been in there several times and we went in there actually we went in there for lunch <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> and uh their pastas were great
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		that's that's one of the things a good <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pasta</ENAMEX> means a lot to me
 		i i like different kinds of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> so when we go out i'm always looking for something other than the standard menu even if it's a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> like something other than uh you know the standard <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tacos enchiladas tamales</ENAMEX> and
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fajitas</ENAMEX> now
 	
 	
 		you're brave
 	
 	
 		yes yes and once in a while things backfire i mean we've gone for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Romanian</ENAMEX> food and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Lebanese</ENAMEX> food and things like that and i'm not fond of some of those things but we'll try we'll try anything just about <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Ethiopian</ENAMEX> we've had <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ethiopian</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh God
 		right
 	
 	
 		and uh not in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plano</ENAMEX>  of course  but we really we really do enjoy going out and uh and i'm pretty adventurous in cooking too which also occasionally backfires
 	
 	
 		no i don't think so you know
 		oh well  even though traditional it can backfire
 	
 	
 		yeah i think that we're supposed to say what will bring us back to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> or or what attracts us to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> how do you usually find a a new restaurant
 	
 	
 		uh
 		well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s kind of the ethnic he he's the ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> so he's i don't know you know what we read we read the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX> magazine
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> so do we
 	
 	
 		we we check that and uh the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> section in the newspaper the pull out section there they often do ratings of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> so uh we've
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh we've usually we often save those and adventured out on from there
 		uh just for something that had a high rating
 	
 	
 		uh-huh we have found uh a number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> either through <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX> and the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> paper and sometimes the the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Observer</ENAMEX> which my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> usually picks up
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		and also through coupons when a new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> opens up they usually send out coupons and you know when they say you know buy one get <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> free
 	
 	
 		that's
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		it's hard to resist so we'll go in and very often we'll find a place that we like and we'll stick with it once they give they they no longer give coupons we'll we'll uh we'll stay there
 	
 	
 		oh good oh good
 	
 	
 		but we've found probably <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of our sort of regular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> through coupons and the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> reviews
 	
 	
 		oh oh yeah we i guess we we use the coupons too that's true that's true
 	
 	
 		i mean it's wonderful particularly if you have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and you've got say <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> or something like that
 		it's very expensive to go out to eat
 	
 	
 		oh right right
 		right
 	
 	
 		so yeah that that is really one of our it's almost a hobby with us
 	
 	
 		well i think that it's just that's exactly  sometimes i think going out to eat it's it's sort of a recreation
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so uh just a just a change of pace
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		from uh
 		eating at home so uh anyway i guess uh <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">as far as as far as</NUMEX> service when we go out gosh it's nice it's nice to have somebody come and  wait the table and clear the table and
 	
 	
 		uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh absolutely
 		and do the dishes
 	
 	
 		yeah and do the dishes and uh actually it's kind of nice to you know i always uh a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">waitress</ENAMEX> or waiter that waits the table  it's nice that they're attentive but it's not nice when they're too attentive
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh yes
 	
 	
 		so uh we've had experience with that too so
 	
 	
 		oh my my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> who also lives here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> uh tends to uh chat with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">waiters</ENAMEX> and waitresses and become their best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> during the course of dinner which drives me absolutely batty
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		well  how we it may may help their tip may not huh
 	
 	
 		but
 		what's your favorite restaurant
 	
 	
 		gosh i guess just in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plano i Plano i</ENAMEX> like to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Souper</ENAMEX> Salads
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh Chili</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chili's</ENAMEX> is always fine
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		i guess if we go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> we like uh
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Routh</ENAMEX> is it <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Routh Street Cafe</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know we've never been there and that's supposed to be wonderful
 	
 	
 		we
 		well you would like it you'd like it especially it you're adventuresome
 	
 	
 		um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it just we've we've taken <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> there several times and uh they have a good they have a good choice of of things that are very different sounding i guess it's whether you call it <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southwestern</ENAMEX>
 		but uh oh we had venison
 	
 	
 		ooh
 	
 	
 		venison chili <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time which was absolutely wonderful
 		and then i guess it must be <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seasonal</TIMEX> and we've been back oh i guess it's in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the winter</TIMEX> season well they've never had it when we've been back so but uh well you ought to try that it's it's it's very good
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		i would probably like that one or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> times in my life i've ever had venison i've love d it but you know just it's just not i don't know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who hunt so
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		
 
 		uh God that's that's supposed to be a wonderful place well uh uh uh here in Plano
 		well we tend to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Momo</ENAMEX>'s a lot fairly often and uh
 		sometimes we'll go you know we we also go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chili's</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh Colter's Bar B Q and</ENAMEX> and uh
 		we go to little there is a little <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Thai</ENAMEX> place that's over on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> that we go to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> particularly likes that
 		we go into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> a lot and because we're both were from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Richardson North Dallas</ENAMEX> area up until fairly recently and uh we'll go down to uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blue Mesa Grill</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> food and
 	
 	
 		oh that's good yes i've been there
 	
 	
 		oh
 		
 		
 	