
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well my favorite type of music is classical music and uh i i enjoy orchestral classical music and i enjoy classical guitar and classical piano
 		you know and that's
 		those are my that's my favorite type uh probably the favorite instrument would be uh the violin
 	
 	
 		well
 		oh well my favorite well i i don't really have a favorite i i like everything basically um
 		i guess if i had to pick it would be like
 		like pop i would think
 		but i like everything so it's kind of hard to choose sometimes
 	
 	
 		yeah you know i guess i enjoy i enjoy jazz listening to jazz sometime although i don't feel like i have a good
 		good good understanding of it or a good a good good feel for maybe what's good jazz and what's not but but um i enjoy it and uh
 		sometimes i enjoy listening to uh fiddle music we were in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> recently and heard this
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		these uh
 		well we heard this fiddler and we bought his we bought his tape and it's kind of fun to listen to the fiddle pans
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		i grew up next door to uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Richardson Symphony Orchestra</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		oh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Xeros</ENAMEX> oh you lucky thing
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		so we used to go and listen to them all the time and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> still do
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so i grew up with a lot of his music and and what not
 		plus my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> are well especially my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> likes a lot of classical music and he introduced my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> and i both to a lot of it
 		so
 	
 	
 		oh gosh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Xeros</ENAMEX>  you grew up with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> too then
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		oh gosh
 	
 	
 		yeah sure did
 	
 	
 		gosh small world huh
 	
 	
 		yeah we all went to high school together and we're still in contact with each other we all go back to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> on the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekends</TIMEX> and what not so
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh gosh <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">well</ENAMEX> actually i used to play in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Richardson Symphony i</ENAMEX> played violin in the orchestra for several years
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		you know yeah so
 	
 	
 		it is a small world isn't it
 	
 	
 		yeah small world so i you know i know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah he a pretty nice guy
 	
 	
 		
 
 		most of the time
 	
 	
 		yeah  well i never i had to work for him and i never would want to work for him so
 	
 	
 		no no well life just took different turns here so uh it just  doesn't work out to do that now so he's he's about ready to retire <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">another year</TIMEX> and he
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah he sure is he just became a grandfather
 	
 	
 		yeah i heard that it's it's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> it's his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> that
 	
 	
 		uh uh-huh yeah they just had the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX>'s christening so
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		it was really nice so
 	
 	
 		was it a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> or a girl
 	
 	
 		he's a little boy
 	
 	
 		yeah what did they name him
 	
 	
 		i can't it it's a
 		oh gosh it's like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elijah</ENAMEX> or something like that
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		i keep forgetting what what she named him
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		his middle name is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris or Christopher</ENAMEX> for for her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daddy</ENAMEX> but i think it's Elijah
 	
 	
 		of course
 		oh yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		it starts with an E
 		i can't remember
 		
 
 	
 	
 		oh so you've heard the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Richardson Symphony</ENAMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		yes yeah we've heard them and liked liked it real well of course
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 		do you have a favorite instrument
 	
 	
 		um
 		actually one of my favorite instruments is a harpsichord
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		i really like those in fact i had a harpsichord played at my wedding
 	
 	
 		oh did you
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		which was real nice i got married uh during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the Christmas season</TIMEX> and we we played uh old fashioned <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas carols</TIMEX> instead of normal wedding marches and what not and it was real nice i liked that a lot
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		i liked the sound of the harpsichord
 	
 	
 		and it played by itself
 	
 	
 		no somebody played it
 	
 	
 		well i mean but you didn't have oboe or something with it
 	
 	
 		no no no no no just by itself just by itself
 	
 	
 		oh
 		yeah oh well that's really yeah that's i bet that was nice
 	
 	
 		it was real nice
 		yeah it went well it was a change you know from your traditional normal
 		normal normal you know stuff and since it was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas time</TIMEX> and and uh we had the church decorated with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas hollies</TIMEX> and poinsettias and you know stuff like that and
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		so we did the harpsichord with old time traditional <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> carols not not you know the bouncy you know sing along kind but
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 	
 	
 		some of the old older ones that some i don't even i recognize the the melodies and whatnot but i didn't recognize the names
 	
 	
 		right right
 	
 	
 		so
 		it was real nice
 	
 	
 		well actually i play i play the violin in in a string quartet that often plays at weddings
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		so um i always think it's a nice break from the traditional organ or piano
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it makes it makes it nice it makes you know you can say classy or it makes an elegant wedding to have something else
 	
 	
 		it does
 		it really really does and it it has such a different sound to it anyway it's almost i don't know the way it vibrates it's kind of haunting you know on on some of the notes it it's i'd i like it
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		i don't know how else to explain but we've got <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> that are in the music business that go around <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> they're uh called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Odessa</ENAMEX> it's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife team</ENAMEX> that we've known for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and
 		we try to make contact with them periodically to see what's going on and stuff too so we've had a lot of
 		stuff you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and and things to do with music that constant and plus my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s real big into music too so he doesn't play anything but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		he just likes to listen and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>
 		and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are now well my oldest is getting to the point where he likes certain types of music and favorite songs and when they come on we have to turn the radio up full blast and
 	
 	
 		oh now does does the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> in in your in your <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> does it
 		does it offer like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">band</ENAMEX> or some of the instruments
 	
 	
 		yeah well my my oldest is only <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> so he he hasn't really gotten into um that yet they have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">choir</ENAMEX> that they go to you know music <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> that they go to but um
 	
 	
 		okay
 		right
 	
 	
 		he's not old enough yet to get into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX> yet
 	
 	
 		right uh right
 	
 	
 		so i think that starts in <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">sixth</NUMEX> grade
 	
 	
 		probably oh gosh
 	
 	
 		so
 		but i don't know he he shows he the only thing he's really shown interest in wanting to play is the drums cause his my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> plays
 		and um
 		i i don't i don't know if he's really serious about it yet or not you know it's just one of those things i'm just going to wait and see if he's interested in something you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right
 		right you got a little ways to go too  right
 	
 	
 		yeah just a little bit
 	
 	
 		great wow well my my oldest is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> and and she's we've started her on piano so uh
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		but that's been it's been fun i mean it's a lot of work to see that she's  prepared but it's been fun it's it's been fun i feel like i've learned a lot about the piano i've learned a lot about playing the piano
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		and uh it kind of makes me listen a little closer to to the piano when i hear it at other places or when i you know see some see and hear someone playing i sort of watch their technique too and
 		and see if it corresponds up to what she's learning
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so it's been fun
 		so
 	
 	
 		i don't know if any of mine will be interested in it or
 		
 		
 	