
 
     		
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well what kind of pet do you have
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> very old fat <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX>  <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Prissy</ENAMEX> and that's why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat</ENAMEX> won't ever let me have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> at my house
 	
 	
 		that's right i remembered
 		that's right
 		Prissy get's you in trouble because you can't have them there
 	
 	
 		that's right
 		she does shed a lot of fur
 	
 	
 		and how many <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pets</ENAMEX> have you had
 	
 	
 		she's we've had her for a long time we used to have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spitz</ENAMEX> that kind of got deposited on us when a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX> was getting a divorce and we were supposed to keep her temporarily for about twelve years
 		usually we've had <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> or cats
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well you know we have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pumpkin</ENAMEX> so what we've had him
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> and a half
 		and uh it's okay i don't know i i i told my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> basically i would just not as i just soon not have a pet in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> but i give in
 	
 	
 		yeah i'm reaching that point too
 	
 	
 		yeah it's it's it's hard for me i like <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pets</ENAMEX> a lot but i just don't like them in the house
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so i wished you know i wish we lived in an area where we had a big backyard i'd have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX>  you know i'd have it outside but um i
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well i'm thinking of a next time about going back to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> though because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX> really do shed a lot you just never get rid of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> hair
 	
 	
 		do they
 	
 	
 		and i know there are a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> that are pretty clean and don't shed so <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emily</ENAMEX> wants a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> a lot of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> have little house mops kind of like yours
 	
 	
 		sure
 		sure
 		well it is easy and like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pumpkin</ENAMEX> is real easy i mean we don't even have to walk him much or anything he
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		but do you have to let him outside for all his business and all yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah he goes out in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		but see that's what would be hard for us since we're not there a lot
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well unless you got a doggy door you know like my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aunt</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncle</ENAMEX> have a doggy door and their <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> just goes in and out at will
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so that that's nice
 	
 	
 		i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jay</ENAMEX> would go <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bananas</ENAMEX> over that though he he likes for our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> to be as secure as possible
 	
 	
 		all sealed up
 		yeah i know that's that's the problem with it but um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but basically <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs our dogs</ENAMEX> worked out has worked out well and i think it's nice for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> i it's not my most favorite thing in the world but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		that can be so therapeutic though when when i really want to just crawl into a shell i think uh wouldn't it be nice just to lay on the bed and pet <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">the cat</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right well they are loving i mean that's
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's the thing uh you know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barb</ENAMEX> i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> who's just moved here and she's gotten <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX> and honestly she is just crazy about those cats
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and she's single lives by herself and they totally have kept her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> you know i mean it is just it's really meant a lot to her to have those cats
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		and i really i i don't think i'm prejudiced since i've had both but i think <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX> are more prone to really have personalities i mean they own you rather than the other way around
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i really do believe that i get a kick out of seeing my <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seventy seven year</TIMEX> old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aunt</ENAMEX> with her <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> and she had a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> get killed
 		not too long ago and she said no more you know i just i can't go through that again and it wasn't <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three months</TIMEX> before she had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">another one</NUMEX> and just adapting to it just
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		like she always had
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and it's really neat for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> living alone like you say with your friend
 	
 	
 		yeah it's really you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barb</ENAMEX> said she wishes that she had done it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> you know that she had um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		gotten an animal <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> because she's been single <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time</TIMEX> and you know she says it just makes a world of difference to come home and have them in the house
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		growing up it was so funny because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> would always have a soft heart for strays and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we never back then you didn't spay and neuter your <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> that much you just kind of put up with whatever happened and she could never get rid of them fast enough before the next litter came along it wasn't usual unusual for us to have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX> and
 		i remember my first camera experience as trying to put <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX> up on a porch and take pictures of them that were going to be award winning type  photos they've always been a part of my life
 	
 	
 		well i guess so you've had them so you had them just from early on then
 	
 	
 		oh yeah we had a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cocker Spaniel</ENAMEX> growing up but but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX> were the things that i loved and especially with being around kittens and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX> and all
 	
 	
 		now were they indoor <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX> or outdoor <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> never never would have allowed that
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		so they always just kind of showed up and came and went and had <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX> and  we played with them we we used them as dolls sometimes we'd dress them up and put them in carriages as much as they'd tolerate it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so it was always fun
 	
 	
 		uh-huh well now see we lived on a real busy intersection in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Phoenix</ENAMEX> and we had a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> but he was killed we we couldn't it was it was not it just wasn't conducive to animals
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		that was traumatic wasn't it yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah it was it was very traumatic my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> it was really upsetting to my little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> and and um so that it just we didn't have many <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pets</ENAMEX> growing up just because our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> wasn't conducive to that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh it just wasn't safe we didn't have a fence and our dog just got killed we'd keep him chained up but he got out and you know sure enough was hit by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah that's exactly what happened with ours and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> really took it
 		hard because he was the one that had left the gate open so he blamed himself personally although you know there were so many things that could have been different but it was hard for him to cope with it being his fault
 	
 	
 		oh
 		yeah i bet
 	
 	
 		so i do hate that i that's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> reason i like <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX> and critters that can stay inside because you don't face that
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		it's it's hard
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		especially if you really do get attached to them i'm i'm already kind of preparing for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prissy</ENAMEX> dying because she's pretty old and fat and oh i just know it's going to come sooner or later so that's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> reason i've been letting Emily talk about <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> because i think
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we we say that's going to be the end but i think when it really comes to it we'll want another pet
 	
 	
 		how old is Prissy
 	
 	
 		she's at least thirteen or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fourteen</TIMEX> we don't know exactly because we got her as a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kitten</ENAMEX> or a you ng <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> and didn't know that much about her she's a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">neat cat</ENAMEX> i mean she owns us all the way
 	
 	
 		um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but
 		it does require a little bit of work and housecleaning
 	
 	
 		well uh you know it does that's just it and right now it's i do well to just take care of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		you know without taking care of an animal too so
 	
 	
 		um-hum and you have the problem when you travel too we always we board her now and that gets kind of expensive
 	
 	
 		that's right
 		that's right we just we just were on vacation and uh it was you know it was expensive plus i think you know for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pumpkin</ENAMEX> he didn't you know he didn't like it we were gone <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks</TIMEX> and that was hard on him to be boarded for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		where'd y'all go
 	
 	
 		uh we can't talk about that can we  we went to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gulf  Gulf</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no i guess not  it's not pet related
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gulf Shores Alabama</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Orleans</ENAMEX> and so we had a really good time
 	
 	
 		oh boy yeah
 		oh how neat
 	
 	
 		so but yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pumpkin</ENAMEX> was
 	
 	
 		but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">puppy</ENAMEX> survived
 	
 	
 		yes he did i always wonder i think well now how much do they remember you know like
 	
 	
 		and you know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aunt</ENAMEX> says that they do drug them i just went <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bananas</ENAMEX> when she told me that that was a fact that she had shopped kennels
 		and vets and that they all very lightly sedate them so that they sleep a lot and that just gave me the creeps because i you know i hate to think they did that to anything or anybody
 	
 	
 		oh
 		huh
 	
 	
 		but she said every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vet</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> and kennel if they would let it if they
 		
 		
 	