
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay uh well since i initiated the call i guess i'll start off first uh number one i have absolutely no problem with random testing
 		uh i spend an awful lot of time traveling on the job and i feel
 		i would be very comfortable if they would do drug testing for particularly airline <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX> and the such i'd feel much more comfortable than i do now based on what i've been hearing in the newspapers
 		so i really don't have a problem with it
 	
 	
 		yeah uh i don't either i uh i've never worked i don't work at home right now i stay home with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> um but my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> works and they do have that at at his place of employment and
 		neither of us have a problem with it we've particularly like you said with the things that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airlines</ENAMEX> and and such it's uh it's a scary thing to know that uh you just don't know what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are doing uh before they go to work
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so and the the advertisements on television lately have been so um there've been so many you know there's uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		just about like <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">train train train wrecks</ENAMEX> and things like that that i feel like probably just for our own safety and when we're traveling and things that would be something i'd like to know that's going on
 	
 	
 		yeah i well i happen to be uh my job is i'm <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supervisor</ENAMEX> of personnel <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">safety</ENAMEX> for the world's largest paint company
 		so i it's very near and dear to me when we start talking about drug testing for random sampling and testing for cause this type of thing  and even in our field we have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are in
 		very high risk jobs and we at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the present time</TIMEX> do not have random testing and i am pushing towards that i i honestly feel if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have nothing to hide
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		they shouldn't have a problem with it
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and if they are trying to hide something then i have to know that because we're talking we're talking
 		major liabilities not only with themselves but with other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i really you know they they're talking about sports
 		sports <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personalities</ENAMEX> and all this type of thing but i would much much prefer having <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> and airline <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX> tested
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		on a random basis i i have a real fear of that at some point something's going to happen and they're showing it with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> so why you know they should they ought to start doing something with the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>  so i really have no problem with it
 	
 	
 		yeah well it's it's unfortunate i think that everyone doesn't have that opinion um some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> just yeah i've heard some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> just talking in our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> that they just feel it's an invasion of privacy and things like that but uh
 		in the long run it seems to me it's kind of like what they keep talking about the um the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> testing with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dentists</ENAMEX> and things and how that you know they feel that's not fair and whatever but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know those kind of things too i'd like to know myself it wouldn't be in my opinion i i've had a lot of dental work done and the last <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dentist</ENAMEX> didn't even use gloves at all so
 	
 	
 		yes
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		that kind of yeah and uh so that kind of thing really kind of concerns me um but
 	
 	
 		well that scares me because if this that's the way they are
 		i if i were a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dentist</ENAMEX> i'd wanna be protected too
 	
 	
 		well you would think so that is  because well and i worked for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dentist</ENAMEX> and that's uh you know you you come in contact with a lot of of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> and things like that and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's real real dangerous i i would think but with all the accidents
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		just with with uh everything happening  just <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airlines</ENAMEX> just drive me crazy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are afraid to fly now you know just because they don't know what their  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilot</ENAMEX>'s been doing and and things like that and
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i don't know
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well you where you're located i i do know <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Instruments</ENAMEX> has random drug testing
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i think they've had it for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several years</TIMEX> and their program they had i don't think had a lot of uh problems
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associated</ENAMEX> with it but uh my brother-in-law happens to work there and it it sounded very positive and i i think it's great i i would like i would encourage it i'm pushing our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> towards that and also
 	
 	
 		well and you know if they do find someone who who is uh having a problem with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> then they can get them the help that they need as opposed to just letting the problem go on with without any uh support
 	
 	
 		right
 		exactly
 	
 	
 		and and whatever because a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> seems like would probably obviously are trying to hide that uh from their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employer</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and things and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		too many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are just dying particularly in our area i don't know what the crime is like where you are but the crime rate here is just astronomical
 	
 	
 		right
 		ours is changing yeah ours ours is changing it's increasing i live in a  i live in a very nice <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">suburb</ENAMEX> and it's it's it's unbelievable what what what's going on and
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> the selling of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> it's just it's just too loose it's too free
 	
 	
 		um-hum i just got a piece of paper <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX> uh that now they have these i i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> little very little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> under <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> and i got a piece of paper from from my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> it's talking about these uh <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tattoos</ENAMEX> now
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		really
 	
 	
 		that they have got that look like it looks like a sticker and it's for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	