
 
     		
 	
 		how would you feel about sending an elderly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family member</ENAMEX> to a nursing home
 	
 	
 		so it
 		well i don't feel very good about it but i think that at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">some</NUMEX> times it can be the right thing to do we
 		sent my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX> to a nursing home at the point when he was really incapable of caring for himself anymore he actually died <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few months</TIMEX> after that and so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		as at least in retrospect it was the right thing to do because he
 		it was either you know a nursing
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> or a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> or something else that he would have been spending most of his time in those days
 	
 	
 		right
 		and what type of recommendations did you have when you decided where to place him
 	
 	
 		um well the
 		see uh well we
 		he wanted to get into a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mennonite</ENAMEX> nursing home which is very popular and hard to get into and had like a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten year</TIMEX> waiting list
 	
 	
 		oh my
 	
 	
 		right we wound up just choosing a another <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mennonite</ENAMEX> nursing home that was easier to get into
 		or we no actually no it was even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mennonite</ENAMEX> related i'm sorry it was actually not a particularly great nursing home mostly
 		the thing was that it was available when we needed it because he suddenly got sick and needed to be put in
 	
 	
 		yeah so the convenience
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh what do you think
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> lived with us um until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX> um and we made the decision to put her in a nursing home she has <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">leukemia</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and her the rest of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and her regular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> and everybody she trusted and knew was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dayton</ENAMEX> and were <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">several thousand miles</NUMEX> away
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so i made the decision to put her in a nursing home and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> being on the other end found one
 		that she could have what was called an independent living <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> she had her own little room and didn't have to share it with anyone and could bring in her own chair and TV set so
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah that's important i'd say
 	
 	
 		yes and that the other major factor is that she needs blood transfusions <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every week</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten days</TIMEX> and would have to be hospitalized <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a day</TIMEX> or two so in this <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> they can do it right there from her own room
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		so she didn't have to be transported back and forth so she's been there since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX> the thirteenth and seems to have adjusted pretty well it's not her favorite place to be in she'd much rather be here with me but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		when it got to the point i was spending more time at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> with her and i've got little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> here who needed me here
 	
 	
 		right so that
 	
 	
 		um she needed somebody to watch her <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty four hours a day</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		right and that becomes difficult then
 	
 	
 		so
 		she was falling down and hemorrhaging and you know all kinds of physical problems so it just became too much for me to handle even though i would have liked to have had her stay with her health being what it was she couldn't anymore
 	
 	
 		um-hum yep we tried to convince my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX> to live with us at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">several</NUMEX>  points during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last few years</TIMEX> of his life
 		but he was essentially too proud and too
 		independent so that even though his heart was
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		getting incredibly weak and his knees were going bad he
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		lived in
 		his own <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> as long as he could though he was living alone
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		had an <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">upstairs apartment</ENAMEX> could barely make it up the steps to the uh top without a great deal of pain
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and this eventually
 		things just went too far and he
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		he allowed himself to be put into a nursing home
 	
 	
 		yes
 		well i think sometimes when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> get to be a certain age other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have to kind of help them make decisions it sure wouldn't have been <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Granny</ENAMEX>'s decision to leave us and go back to a nursing home but she's accepted it real well now
 	
 	
 		right well that's
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		yeah that's right that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> have some responsibility too to their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> and such to
 		help decide what's the right thing
 	
 	
 		well we enjoyed having her here but we feel she's much safer where she is now she still continues to fall but when she does there a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurse</ENAMEX> is right there to help her
 	
 	
 		and
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i know she's eating the right things and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX>'s right there where he can come in and check on her so
 		it became dangerous for us to keep transporting her back and forth in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> because she was so wobbly and needed a walker or a wheel chair
 	
 	
 		yep
 	
 	
 		so i think she'll adjust
 	
 	
 		
  
 		
 		
 	