
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay well originally i guess <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> were um
 		in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> cooking and uh cleaning and all that good stuff
 	
 	
 		taking care of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah oh actually the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> they they don't have as many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		because they've gone out to work and they're um  uh well the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> of shrinking the divorce rate is up um they're
 		still trying to get the pay that uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> get
 		um i guess even farther back um they uh used to not even have sports for the women
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh then the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> starting wearing the tennis shoes and playing sports and going out to work um
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well i i was thinking too in terms of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">of</NUMEX> in terms of this you know the education is so different i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> are so much better educated now than they used to be and i think that makes a big impact on what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> do
 	
 	
 		oh sure
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> also i was thinking the the clothing has changed so dramatically uh you know you like when you said with sports i thought well it was so limiting because of their clothes
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they weren't allowed to to wear certain things and so then they couldn't participate you know they couldn't participate in sports because of it so um i thought that's that's made a difference uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah well it's kind of ironic they're also  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> they're trying they're working their way back into the house
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they're trying to have the best of both worlds
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they're just now figuring out in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nineties</ENAMEX> that it's not quite working
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and they can't have both
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so um i guess they'll have to make a choice
 	
 	
 		well i think so or spend part of their lives doing one thing and part of their lives doing another you know it
 	
 	
 		right they'll just have to allocate that time
 	
 	
 		yeah uh because you know because really it isn't that long a period of time that you have to be home with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> uh comparatively speaking if you look look through your whole look at your whole life um
 		and i do think there's real value in being in the home uh i do sort of both but um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know it it is it's an interesting topic i the thing that's been hard for me to believe too is that how long how short a time it's been since the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> had the vote and that's always been amazing to me
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that that's been a relatively short period of time and i think that made a major impact on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s roles uh you know from that point on
 	
 	
 		um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well i guess the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> have definitely figured out that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> are as smart
 	
 	
 		i
 	
 	
 		there's a considerable amount more
 		um there's a considerable more amount of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> than there used to have been and of course you like you said they're more educated
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		and um
 		uh we've we've uh brought quite a bit to the world
 	
 	
 		well and it will be fascinating to see within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next twenty to thirty years</TIMEX> how that changes even more i think the impact will be felt more and more as as better educated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> come into the work force
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> and more and more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> come into the work force um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i you know it it's going to just change things drastically i think
 	
 	
 		well some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> are actually leaving the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husbands</ENAMEX> home with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's right  that's right
 	
 	
 		
 
 		and well i don't wanna talk about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s changing roles but they're all they're learning to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cook</ENAMEX> now and to do the laundry and uh all of those good things
 	
 	
 		well i think that you know that one of the things that may come out of this is to let <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> do what they're best at you know some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> uh may <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> may stay home with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> better than some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> may and so whoever
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know whoever does which role best i think should do it  um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		if if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> can compromise and do that kind of thing
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that that takes a lot of
 	
 	
 		yeah it's no surprise that uh movies like <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Dances with Wolves</ENAMEX> have come out in the Nineties
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and their influence uh with the men
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh the changing of roles actually
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh that was a very good example of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nineties</ENAMEX> and
 		what's a real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> and a real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> you know they uh they do a little bit of both um the hard labor and uh
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		you know the smart the uh all brawn and no brains on both sides
 	
 	
 		that's right
 		that's right
 		well  i think that's all i have to say do you have anymore nice talking to you thanks bye-bye
 	
 	
 		okay well it was nice talking to you okay thank you bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	