
 
     		
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		okay well i uh i guess because i work quite a bit with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> i'm not a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> uh that i find a lot of things are so specialized that i'm not sure
 		and i i look at it more from the civil side of things that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">juries</ENAMEX> have any sense of of the value of and worth so that they have real problems when it comes to uh uh they can find guilt or innocence
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh but then when you quantify things and that might also hold criminal trials for how many <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> is appropriate uh that they might leave it to somebody else who uh has expertise in that
 	
 	
 		right i agree too i don't think the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> should be the ones that that put the sensings sentencings down i think the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> should or even a panel of of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> if if it got to that point
 		might be better apt than just regular civil people
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		not knowing you know exactly what things are  from from murder on up to like tax stuff you know
 	
 	
 		yeah because i find that uh i've been on a few <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">juries</ENAMEX> and uh as a say i i tend to be around uh civil cases
 		because i've been an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert witness</ENAMEX> some and uh
 		many matters are so complicated that it's so hard to uh come up with the fair value uh
 		or the fair sentence and one thing that you get if you have some expertise is
 		uh you know the range of of possible values or terms or you know how heinous was the crime
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh that uh when i only do something <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one two or three</NUMEX> times i'm hardly an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> on it and
 		most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">juries</ENAMEX>
 		over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a period of five or ten years</TIMEX> you might sit on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah and
 	
 	
 		and so how do you relate as to whether this
 		particular armed robbery was a you know worth <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty five</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		right that's yeah and and and most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that do sit on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">juries</ENAMEX> some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> just sit on them once in their lifetime you know if they're that lucky sometimes  or you know what whatever the case may be and and may not have any idea
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		of what what the standard punishment would be for it and it they may have some different idea i mean it might be more important for them to put a sentencing sentencing sentencing down that was uh
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		longer you know that didn't fit the punishment didn't fit the crime
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		or not long enough or you know whatever the case may be
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i i think the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> do have that that better knowledge of it the only thing i worry about sometimes is if if you get somebody in there that that has a name that is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defendant</ENAMEX> and
 		you know sometimes might have have more pull which that does happen i mean we we can't say it doesn't because it does happen i mean not everybody is is you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		has has the right morals sometimes and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> can be paid off or politically or
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		whatever the case may be and sometimes that's not real fair either though so
 	
 	
 		well one of the others things that gets me on on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">juries</ENAMEX> is that often in the newspaper
 		i i tend to hear <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> things well that go on one is you often see in the headlines
 		the big numbers
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and many of those get overturned or get reduced in terms of sentences or get changed
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> or an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Appeals Court</ENAMEX> and that never makes the the press and so when uh you or i as an individual
 		gets on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> we tend to have certain mental images of what's what because we see the headlines
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and we don't have uh again a lot of knowledge so we don't know what is really going on what is uh
 		really the range of sentences or awards that are uh are actually uh in the end applied
 	
 	
 		right right well well also what i don't think is fair either is when you have like a say a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rapist</ENAMEX> come in and and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX>
 		gets his sentences sentencing reduced because he's gone to a lesser charge like i don't know what assault or something or
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but which that doesn't make any sense to me either i know it's hard to prove rape and whatnot and and and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> that was raped or whatever doesn't i mean it's embarrassing and all this other stuff and they they're put on like
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they were the ones that caused it or whatever but to me when you do the crime
 		then you should pay for whatever you did and and you shouldn't be able to go on the lesser charge i don't i don't think that's right because all's that's going to do is say oh well you know that was a breeze i can go out and do it again and you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		have the same thing happen that's that's not right
 	
 	
 		well that's where uh uh the role of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">juries</ENAMEX> is is restricted and uh i'm not sure i'd want to change that aspect of it one is it's restricted in the sense that
 		juries only decide the charges that are actually uh brought you know if it's first degree rape <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> degree degree rape or whatever
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		they only get to decide on that well okay this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> has been charged with <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> degree rape uh and you can decide guilt or innocence on that uh such like maybe in murder they get to choose whether it's uh premeditated or
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of the lesser degrees and the other thing that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">juries</ENAMEX> are restricted on and and at least to me this has been one of the frustrating things in my even in my own experiences that you
 		usually don't get to hear all the information it's what information is presented and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh i don't know that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">juries</ENAMEX> have a right to know more because in a sense we call those safeguards but often <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">juries</ENAMEX> hear <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">only a fraction of the</TIMEX> of the story
 		when they have to decide guilt or innocence
 	
 	
 		and to me how can you how can you make a decision if you don't have all of the evidence in front of whether it be whether it pertains to the case or not somebody thinks it it had because they've got it there
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> are the ones that have all the information don't they
 	
 	
 		yeah and the truth that's brought out is uh as i say when i've heard about you know the oath is to tell the truth the whole truth and nothing but the truth
 		is that they want uh they don't want uh the whole truth i mean you can say yeah the because stories look very different when you hear different parts of the of the truth
 	
 	
 		they only put part of it
 		yeah
 		right well that's just like that old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX> game well it's a game <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> play too but um
 		somebody did it just ah
 		just for your <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">train</ENAMEX> of thought where they they showed something
 		and they asked there there there were uh like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> people
 		
 		
 	