
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		what do you think
 	
 	
 		um i don't know uh regarding um should the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>  do the sentencing or not i think the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> should have some in influence but i don't think the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> should i think that's too much
 		power in the control of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i agree i really agree with that
 	
 	
 		it uh it just doesn't seem to make sense that if the trial is by a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> of your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peers</ENAMEX> that the sentencing should be somewhat along that i you know i guess the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> should give the parameters
 	
 	
 		right
 		right right
 	
 	
 		and then the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> should work kind of within there and if they feel exceptional one way or the other do you know what i mean
 	
 	
 		right right yes i do i i have been thinking about this you're about the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">tenth</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> they tried to call for this  so i've had lots of time to think but yes i do because um
 	
 	
 		oh is that right
 	
 	
 		otherwise why have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> that's the point right yeah
 	
 	
 		right
 		it seems to granted you're found guilty or innocent by a a group of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peers</ENAMEX> of your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peers</ENAMEX> but then the punishment you know can be very very severe depending on the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>'s personal uh predilection to that
 	
 	
 		right right i think that you get a much fairer deal with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> than you do with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> and that's that's been my experience and and i really think that i think that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> are very prejudice
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah
 		i i would i
 	
 	
 		to just their own idea and they wanna get it over with
 	
 	
 		right i mean they're human they're gonna have their their pet <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">peeves</ENAMEX> and they're gonna have the things that they really care about or don't care about
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		um so let a group of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have you know try to try to make make you know use that uh make that decision
 	
 	
 		yeah i would feel much more confident if that were me so
 	
 	
 		unfortunately though it does string out the uh process but you know
 	
 	
 		well it does but i think it's because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are trying to be conscientious where a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> it's their job and
 		you they just wanna speed it along and get it done and i don't think they stop and think about that individual as much as a group of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right see i i also think there's a problem with the plea bargaining system in our in our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> in that you can uh plead to even though you're guilty as sin
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yes yes
 		yes
 	
 	
 		excuse me you plead to a lesser crime
 	
 	
 		yes yes
 	
 	
 		i think that that in of itself is a sin
 	
 	
 		i think that we're having a lot of problems um
 		with just everything and the whole the whole system is bugging me it really is our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">jails</ENAMEX> are over crowded with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leona Helmsley</ENAMEX> who's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seventy two years old</TIMEX> and with a blank check in front of her
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i don't think should go to jail i think the punishment should fit the crime i think that the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">jail</ENAMEX> should be filled with real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> that are dangerous and i don't think they should get out on parole in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		i think they should stay there they did it they stay
 	
 	
 		yeah i well i
 	
 	
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with traffic tickets and that there's another way to handle that i think
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 		um although i'll tell you the there is something about that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> uh her crime was is what they quote call a white collar crime as opposed to a blue collar crime such as crime stealing
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		uh well  but she stole
 	
 	
 		well yes but if you look at it in relation to the amount i mean it's <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">one million dollars</NUMEX> which to you and i sound exorbitant
 	
 	
 		it's a lot of money
 	
 	
 		but compared to the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six hundred million</NUMEX> that they paid in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX> that's like <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">one dollar</NUMEX> when we owe <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">six hundred</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		that they the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six hundred million</NUMEX> that they what now
 	
 	
 		so
 		they paid taxes <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">six hundred million</NUMEX> in taxes over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that five year</TIMEX> period
 	
 	
 		oh i see what you're saying
 	
 	
 		yeah so if you look at it they don't say that  very much in the newspaper
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well no but they also diverted uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> uh to their own personal assets that were hotel monies
 	
 	
 		well possibly you know i don't know but if they're willing to correct it
 		i i don't i don't see that she belongs in jail the same as somebody who goes out and kills and walks away i mean i there are worse things that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are getting off with you know that kind of thing
 	
 	
 		oh
 		see yeah yeah i have to i agree with that there are worse things that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have been getting off with but i don't think that that we then should have <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leona</ENAMEX> get off i think that they should be hit even harder see i'm an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocate</ENAMEX> of the death penalty myself
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		now i don't know of a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are well there are and there aren't and i just happen to feel that if somebody does the crime
 	
 	
 		well
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i mean if they murder somebody they take someone's life
 	
 	
 		get them out of society
 	
 	
 		i just don't feel like i have to pay my tax dollars to have them in jail i yeah i just it's a tough line
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i know i agree with you agree and
 	
 	
 		but i don't think the way we're executing the the capital punishment is is a deterrent although i think capital punishment is a deterrent
 	
 	
 		i do too
 	
 	
 		if it's done right and that means that this is the way it is no ifs no ands no buts a certain
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		it has to be a consistent thing
 	
 	
 		right a certain number of appeals and then that's it don't stretch it out for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> get it over with and get it done
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	