
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i you know actually in this modern day and age it seems like uh uh
 		we have more and more leisure time because uh we have so many uh convenience appliances and whatnot and
 		we don't even have to cook dinner anymore uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah really
 	
 	
 		but i uh i've heard i don't know this for a fact but i've heard that a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> really don't spend a great deal of time together that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> maybe on the average get
 		uh something like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">seconds</TIMEX> of quality time with the parents
 	
 	
 		that's what i've heard too uh
 	
 	
 		it seems bizarre to me i don't quite understand it although i think probably the the worst thing that's happening in the world at least the modern world <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> is  television
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		not so much because uh it's bad per se
 		although there is some pretty crappy programming and i think there's also some uh i think
 		um
 		poorer lifestyles illustrated but simply because it dominates so much discussionary time
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		it's so darned easy to turn the thing on
 	
 	
 		i know it i've
 		i've found myself sometimes just sit down after work and
 	
 	
 		so i refuse to have one in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		oh really well good for you
 		good for you a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i've talk to a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> about that and i've thought about it myself and
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i thought about it a lot
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		but uh i still haven't done it yet well that's good
 	
 	
 		well i'll tell you television sure makes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> rearing easy on you i mean the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> can be a real pest uh
 		and turning the TV on is almost like magic you know it's uh like
 		sticking uh an electrode into their pleasure <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> and you don't have to worry about them
 	
 	
 		that's true i've noticed that
 	
 	
 		but i don't think it's too good
 	
 	
 		i don't think so either
 	
 	
 		um so you know i don't know i take advantage i don't have a great deal of time to spend with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> but i take advantage of
 		um dinner time we always eat together and
 		you know whenever you're with your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> you wanna interact with them rather than just ignore them
 	
 	
 		do you keep your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> uh active in sports or anything or
 	
 	
 		uh i guess our big outlet is music um our <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirteen year old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> plays violin and our <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nine year old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> plays cello
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		and uh when our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> started playing violin i took up violin and when our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> started playing cello i took up cello so there's plenty of
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		plenty of interactive time in uh practicing although neither <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> likes to practice
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i guess that's not a big surprise
 	
 	
 		no not for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i mean i imagine with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">infants</ENAMEX> you  are
 		most of your time is sort of spent taking care of them rather than interacting with them
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well i i i try and read to them and
 	
 	
 		although you
 	
 	
 		and i take them to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> and stuff and
 	
 	
 		oh you know reading is so good
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i uh i took great pleasure in reading to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> when they were little and i still try to read to them although our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> is not liking that anymore
 	
 	
 		yeah well they get to this stage
 	
 	
 		uh but i read you know there's <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">this Doctor Seuss sleep</ENAMEX> book have you ever seen that yet
 	
 	
 		sleep book no
 	
 	
 		yeah it's called a sleep book and uh you ought to get it
 		i tell you i read that book to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> so many times i almost have the thing memorized
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		we've got a quite a few of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doctor Seuss</ENAMEX>'s books and
 	
 	
 		yeah well i think i think his sleep book is my favorite
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well
 		yeah i like to
 		i like to do it and they enjoy reading and i've actually i never read a lot growing up
 		and i never read until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years ago</TIMEX> i just started picking up books and
 		so it i've found that you know it's really important to me to get to read to i like to get away in a book you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so i've put a lot more emphasis on that on my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		to try
 	
 	
 		so how much time do you think you spend with your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> on the average per each day
 	
 	
 		oh i probably spend <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an hour</TIMEX> or two
 	
 	
 		oh that's great
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> works at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> so she does uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tupperware</ENAMEX> so she's gone a lot at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nights</TIMEX> and so i spend a lot of time with them
 	
 	
 		oh i see
 		so how old are your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> again
 	
 	
 		they're <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> and one
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> and one
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah so you have your hands full with them that's for sure
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 		
 	