
 
     		
 	
 		do you have a particular attitude about public education
 	
 	
 		
 
 		okay well i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> that's in public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> now i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> that went to a private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and then we put them into public school system and i think we did them a big disservice by putting them in public schools
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		um i think that they my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> now is in public school and we're getting ready to put her into a private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> because of it i just don't feel like they're they're getting enough out of it you know for
 	
 	
 		academic
 	
 	
 		yes yes i just don't think that academically they're and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school systems</ENAMEX> here is supposed to be really good they have i don't know if you're familiar but <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> has uh
 		oil money that finances their school system you know there there's no state taxes paid here
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh i didn't know
 	
 	
 		so the money from the taxes from the oil go to pay go towards the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and running of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> so they're supposed to have a really good program but uh
 		i don't know i just feel like my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX> are in college <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now and the last three years</TIMEX> their life they went to public school and they made straight As and they're really struggling in college now
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		and uh i think that it has a lot to do with it i don't i don't i don't know where where you can fix it  you know what you need
 	
 	
 		well apparently in your state there's more incentive to send your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> to public uh to a private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> because in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> you pay taxes for public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and then if you wanna send your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> to private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> you pay again
 	
 	
 		yes well you do that here too you pay higher uh property taxes for the area that you're living in depending on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and the area you're in
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh okay i got i got the impression you said the oil money paid for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		no it it supplements the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> that for therefore there's no state income tax that goes towards uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school systems</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		ah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because of that you know because of that but the property taxes that you have on your home depending on what area you are you know like they're higher in certain areas than they are in other areas you know but uh
 	
 	
 		sure
 		right i don't i don't have any experience myself with private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> so i really can't say they're better i did go to public schools
 		and what i'm finding um right now i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and i'm going back to work and i'm substitute teaching in public schools
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and what i see in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">high school</ENAMEX> is i don't know that it's public private i think times have changed
 		i mean i know that i would never not do my homework because lightning would strike me something terrible would happen
 	
 	
 		um-hum um-hum exactly yeah
 	
 	
 		but nowadays the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> don't do their work and they have the nerve to say to you so what are you gonna do and you're not gonna do anything
 	
 	
 		exactly well there's no disciplinary actions you know that can be done taken against them at all yeah
 	
 	
 		but you
 		yeah i think the most important thing that a public school can do to help the problem is to
 		to maybe go backwards in some ways um i find the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> trying to be like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> uh telling their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> i teach art and they'll go yeah that's cool well
 		maybe they should talk like grown-ups and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> should learn to act like grown-ups instead of the grown-ups trying to act like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> to get their acceptance i find the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> are very concerned about being liked
 	
 	
 		being friendly being <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		being being <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> with them and you know they don't wanna be so strict they don't wanna be so hard on them and i find that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are not turning in quality work because there's nothing to impress upon them that they better
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right right
 	
 	
 		and you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i think that that's right i think i think a lot of that right there and and i think that that's where you come into the private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> the private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> have more power
 		you know i mean because in public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> really don't have any authority to do anything or to really punish these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> in any way i mean they can't even hardly give them detention you know without
 	
 	
 		well maybe they'll make them
 	
 	
 		having to call their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> and have their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> come in and all this kind of stuff i mean it really is a major thing
 	
 	
 		well you know yeah well maybe they'll make them stay home for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a day</TIMEX> but that's no torture for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no really exactly yeah to stay home is like oh yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah and i know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> if they you know if they're late enough often enough they get a letter home and they get to the mail <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">box</ENAMEX> before their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> because their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> work so you know it's not a problem and i find that you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		they send oh because they send the report cards and and failing notices and stuff <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> in the mail
 	
 	
 		um yeah well they they sent me yes that's true it progress reports
 	
 	
 		progress reports well see up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX> now they do that but here they don't do that they give these progress reports to these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> is a senior and he failed a class <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this last six weeks</TIMEX> and i'm like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin</ENAMEX> how could but he didn't even tell me you know and so i called the school i'm like i didn't even know that he had was failing this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> and their like but we sent the progress report home with him well you think he's gonna give it to me
 		i mean is he  you think he's he may be failing a class but he's not an idiot
 	
 	
 		oh sure they
 		yeah they never have homework they always did it in school i have a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fourteen year old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> who is just getting into you know realizing that he can dupe me i think
 	
 	
 		
 
 		right right i know i
 	
 	
 		but i i think the the public school it's not that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> are inferior or that the materials are inferior i think what's going on is that
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> have to be backed up when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> don't do what they're supposed to do um the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> have to have some way to
 	
 	
 		well they have to have parental support the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> have got
 	
 	
 		they need the parental
 		
 		
 	