
 
     		
 	
 		uh do you have any brilliant inedeas about how to reduce crime
 	
 	
 		
 
 		no i really don't they need to do more with uh you know the police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> they need to make sure you have more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> out on the street i think
 		you know to try to keep track of what's going on and be harder on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> when they go to court you know make sure they go to jail and they serve all their term
 	
 	
 		it seems
 	
 	
 		but other than that i don't really know what about you
 	
 	
 		well it it seems like such a catch <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty two</TIMEX> you know my first inclination is to say stop being so lenient when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> do something rotten you keep them in jail and you make them know that your serious you're very serious  uh but then again uh
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		the taxing situation you know how can we pay to keep all these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">jail</ENAMEX> that's when you say well don't raise my taxes you know maybe we shouldn't lock up the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who has too many traffic tickets yeah maybe we shouldn't do this and you know and then you stop start eroding it
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know i substitute teach i deal with high school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		right
 		oh you do
 	
 	
 		and i i find that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attitudes</ENAMEX> at home are such i mean the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> will <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">curse</ENAMEX> right in front of my face and
 		they won't even go oops you know they they just have no regard and i'm not saying they're gonna turn into <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> but i think it's a general trend toward
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> just relaxing their standards so much and i think that's why we have more crime because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> are not stopping this when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are young
 	
 	
 		that's true
 		um-hum oh
 	
 	
 		and they just keep pushing
 	
 	
 		i believe i believe that's true i think you have to do more the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> as well education but before they get to the high school of course because by then they're pretty much set i think
 	
 	
 		yeah well you know
 	
 	
 		you start way back when
 	
 	
 		yeah generally you know a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>'ll do something that's outrageous and they'll say well what are you going to do to me and it's almost like the criminal system
 		there's not much i can do to them i can't really do anything to them one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fellow</ENAMEX> said i said how about you do your work and he said well how about i throw these scissors at you
 		and instead of getting uh flustered i said well i wish you would because then i can really punish you i can send you to detention <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">et</ENAMEX> cetera if you just bad mouth me and generally giving me a hard time there's really nothing i can do
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		and and i think you know minor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> feel the same way like what are they gonna do
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and and i think that's the the biggest thing that unless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> know that you're serious and you're not gonna tolerate that kind of behavior in anybody i this is just gonna keep going
 	
 	
 		um-hum well i think that's like the problem with you know drunk <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't they're not cracking down they let them back out on the street they don't really take away their license they don't really make sure they can't drive anymore
 		so <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't think it's any big deal and they just go out and do it again nothing's gonna happen to them
 	
 	
 		well we had a yeah we had a big incident at the local high school a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> who happened to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> were um in a horrible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> on accident a drunk <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX> hit them
 		um the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who were in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> who got hit <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of them died and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of them seriously injured this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> you know crossed a divider he had been arrested twice for drunk driving driving
 		um they didn't lock him up they took his license away but they didn't take away his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> key
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know there he was you know it's like you know in the old <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> you know you steal they take your hand away i mean this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> can still drive as long as he can get into a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> he's driving
 	
 	
 		right um-hum so it doesn't do any good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> just do it again same thing with when you have like sexual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offenders</ENAMEX> and you don't make sure they have
 	
 	
 		you know he's just
 		yeah and i
 	
 	
 		adequate counseling then they just go out and do it again because you haven't really fixed their problem at all
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		so and that's probably the problem too because do you bother counseling these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> or you make them go to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">jail</ENAMEX> will it really do any good to counsel them or is it just gonna waste <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX>' money
 	
 	
 		well you know i think counseling is kind of like dieting until you decide you really want it to work you know
 	
 	
 		right right
 	
 	
 		it it's not gonna work anyway you have to cooperate with that kind of stuff i i it's a real scary problem i don't know what the answers are
 	
 	
 		yeah and the problem is
 		yeah
 		i guess that's why we have the problem nobody seems to know what to do about it but yeah that's true yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 		you know and then they bring up the thing about um whether we should have death penalties
 		uh i guess you know the the top of the the bad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> ladder maybe you know some of those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would be affected but there's lots of crime going on besides murder where
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know it's still out of hand
 	
 	
 		i'm just afraid that if you put back in the death penalty every place that
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> be um the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">juries</ENAMEX> won't want to convict a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> because what happens if they are they're really innocent because once and you kill them they're gone you can't like fix the problem so
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		there'll be that much you know there'd be really really worried about sending them to jail when they really should be in jail they'll be like well i don't know and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who don't wanna put them
 		you know to death who think that's wrong won't convict them either even if they really believe they're guilty because they're really just problem on their part things like that
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> makes a joke about well an armed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">society</ENAMEX> is a polite society if if good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> had <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> as well as bad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> then you know maybe that wouldn't be but i said nah you still have survival of the fittest because
 		you know then the bad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> would become better at using the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> you know
 	
 	
 		right right and if nobody had <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> they would just use some other
 		
 		
 	