
 
     		
 	
 		okay i um
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		to let you know what i feel about drug testing uh i have my qualms about having the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> or anyone else for that matter
 		testing randomly everybody across the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> for various <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> however i am not against
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		testing those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are in critical uh jobs for example airline <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX> subway <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX> you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are responsible for other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s safety
 	
 	
 		right
 		for uh for uh uh a larger number than just their own personal safety
 	
 	
 		
 
 		correct i just think that it's
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh unnecessary and really the medical testing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> that are available now have been shown to have problems in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past</TIMEX> as far as reliability is concerned
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		and uh we have had situations here where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were accused of um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">utilizing drugs</ENAMEX> and uh it turned out they were on some other <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medication</ENAMEX> which was giving false positives
 	
 	
 		right
 		right and the same goes with uh you can eat poppy bagels <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">poppy</ENAMEX> seeds
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they'll come up as a as a positive for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> as well
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		which is i you know i'd i'd just heard that uh just recently and i thought that was interesting
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		uh do you more or less follow on the same lines as i do or
 	
 	
 		yeah i i do i um i have a little problem with somebody testing uh for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> just in general as an invasion of privacy
 		uh but i do agree with you or regarding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that deal uh with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> of other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that their lives should be they should feel a little more safe and there should be more of a safeguard
 		you know air traffic controllers airline <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX> uh anybody that deal with the public in a uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i don't know what uh a fashion  that their lives are in their  in in their hands
 	
 	
 		yeah i i know that they were up here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> um
 		uh i've noticed what they have been trying to do the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> here isn't thrilled with the idea and we have uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		various <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> here who basically don't feel that is a good idea for along the same lines but they're continuously clashing with the federal government which because of it's antidrug war
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> figures well since we're not really accomplishing much of anything internationally let's make big headlines by going out and being for mandatory drug testing and
 	
 	
 		within the community
 	
 	
 		yeah and and that way we'll we'll nail those <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker users</ENAMEX> without really solving the problem
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		of trying to really do something and through education and that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah they the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> seems to be a lot more aggressive about this um
 	
 	
 		that's
 	
 	
 		than uh anything else it's interesting that you find out with all these little scandals going on now such as in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> with the post office <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX> scandal
 	
 	
 		right yep
 	
 	
 		you know all that um
 	
 	
 		well did you hear about the uh what was happening in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> area
 		uh for i guess for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about the past five</TIMEX> they've been testing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		but not releasing the information
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah i
 	
 	
 		they were just testing to find out how prevalent it is uh in what demographic and segments of the population
 		but they weren't telling anybody if they did it when when the results came up positive or negative they weren't telling anybody
 	
 	
 		hum well their sure they were probably afraid of being sued
 	
 	
 		well i'm sure and also bringing light to the fact that they weren't getting parental permission for it
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		they were just doing this test
 	
 	
 		yeah it's one of these slippery slope issues where once you start by allowing this kind of randomized drug testing it's the same thing with the lie detectors
 	
 	
 		yep
 	
 	
 		and uh the physiological test  tests that go on um really i think you know we are seeing more and more of privacy taken away
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		um courtesy of the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> as time goes on because of the almighty rights of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employer</ENAMEX> to know every possible thing about their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yep
 	
 	
 		and uh at times it's hypocritical as well because those in positions of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> that want these things certainly don't want them applied to themselves
 	
 	
 		right
 		exactly they want to they want to be just above in that regard
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		yeah i i i don't know how much you've had experience as far as in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> coming across <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who have gotten into trouble with the drug stuff here in in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rochester Rochester</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		in western <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> there hasn't been a terrible lot but we of course hear about the subway <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yep
 	
 	
 		who slammed into someone and of course you know the airline <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX> are rumored you know there are already rumors of rampant <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">alcoholism</ENAMEX> now <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX> usage
 	
 	
 		uh well there's always there's a standard joke about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northwestern</ENAMEX> pilots
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh yeah wasn't that that thing in  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minneapolis</ENAMEX> or something when they were supposedly smashed out of their minds and then flew or they had their light
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 		
 	