
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so uh i i guess it's subject is uh gun control
 	
 	
 		yeah i um probably would put myself on a um <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five or six</NUMEX> scale being up here in the uh northeast um
 		i'm considered liberal  but uh i believe in the right to own and uh have a gun for yourself if that's what if that's what you want as long as you don't have a record
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
  
 	
 	
 		in the past of um committing crimes or uh something in that order i think that it's important that there be some check
 		um background checks before they just hand a gun over to any old person
 	
 	
 		um-hum yeah i sort of believe the same way i think i'm i'm probably considered more of a conservative but i still think that uh
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		uh with regards to gun control the
 		uh like convicted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">felons</ENAMEX> you know they shouldn't be able to have one um also i'm in
 		if if if you look at it uh like say a waiting period i'm in favor of a waiting period as just that a waiting period before
 		someone buys <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a a handgun</NUMEX> and like i say <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week or two weeks</TIMEX> as a cooling off period but uh i i guess the uh NRA they kind of look at it as a springboard towards more restrictive gun controls and
 		so i can kind of see both both sides of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">of the</ENAMEX> of the uh issue on that
 	
 	
 		yeah absolutely you know that's that's the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> that uh i have too is that
 		you know once you go down the path and you start with first it's it's background checks and and uh then it's suddenly age restrictions and then it's totally illegal
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah um-hum
 	
 	
 		and you know i i come from up here i'm not in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> area by any means so i'm in a a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rochester</ENAMEX>'s not heavy crime area
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
  
 	
 	
 		but um you know and i and it's been a political issue up here um a a big deal about whether or not
 		they should <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> should have access to handguns and uh some of these <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> specials and plastic handguns and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		all of these new things i think pretty much up here everybody agrees that  there should be more control on semiautomatic slash keeping automatic <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> banned
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um just because you know what kind of legitimate hunting use can you do with an <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">AK-47</ENAMEX> i mean
 	
 	
 		yeah that that is true um as a as a toy you know i mean if you call a gun a toy they would be it would be interesting to have one shoot <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> but uh
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		but you're right there's no no real legitimate need for one unless you consider
 		um
 		like personal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defense</ENAMEX> like if your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> or something that's it's kind of extreme i i don't personally own <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> but uh
 		it's it's really it really is a touchy issue i know uh
 		the uh like you mentioned the plastic handguns the Glock
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it seems to me like like that that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapon</ENAMEX> they could it seems it seems to me like they could bypass all the i i think the um the major concern is is that they think
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		that it can be slipped through airport security like it it say invisible <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">X</ENAMEX> rays seems to me like technically that'd be very simple to solve just put some sort of a
 		uh a metal <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">flake flake</ENAMEX> or something that would show up on <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">on X</ENAMEX> rays you know it to show the outline of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> and then you'd still have the advantages of the gun which is i believe light weight and uh it would
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah up here you know we have a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hunters</ENAMEX> up here if you go just to the south of uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rochester</ENAMEX> here you have a bunch of state <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX> and there's a lot of hunting that goes on and uh
 		that i think is by far the majority of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that own <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> around here
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		tend to either be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hunters</ENAMEX> or they live in the inner city and they're concerned about um uh their safety
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		um we've had up here the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NRA</ENAMEX>'s main focus up here has been on protecting the hunting
 		uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are doing a lot of hunting because being not a large urban area like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> where you have an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NRA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">movement</ENAMEX> that's more um attuned to personal protection
 		versus hunting <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">um</ENAMEX> that's pretty much how they've gone about it up here and some of the tactics i mean i noticed they changed their commercials
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> used to be they'd mention and with every membership you get fifty <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">thousand dollars</NUMEX> dismemberment insurance
 	
 	
 		yeah   yeah it's uh the NRA they're uh they're almost a little too radical in the other extreme i'm i'm i'm pretty strong in favor of of personal gun ownership
 		but they uh they might even get a little carried away you know with the lobbying and and whatnot but
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well it's a powerful lobby i mean i've debated issues um on some other issues regarding the cable TV and that and uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NRA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lobby</ENAMEX> is the most powerful that's up there in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol Hill</ENAMEX> and uh they do a number
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	