
 
     		
 	
 		let's see i know
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i can guess i know what the rules are in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no handguns are permitted in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX> at all
 	
 	
 		but on the other hand in in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> it's supposed to be close to wide open right
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		uh sort of yeah i live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> i don't i work in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so i'm uh and i'm well i'll give you a clue i've if if <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> caused crime there would be a lot of crime in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> and not much in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but uh
 	
 	
 		so how does that rate you in the uh the scale that they've given us
 	
 	
 		on a scale i guess i'm about a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nine and a half</TIMEX>
 		so i've let's see so <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> means what <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> means no controls and one means uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		one means total restriction
 	
 	
 		one means total restrictions i guess i'm
 		i'm about uh
 		yeah i've i'm between <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine and a half</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> i'm i'm not saying no control but uh
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> and a half
 	
 	
 		but uh
 	
 	
 		are you an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NRA</ENAMEX> member
 	
 	
 		yes i have been since uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		you know it's it's one of those things where they say uh that you're biased you're uh you're you're uh
 	
 	
 		right this is a rather a interesting
 	
 	
 		you're a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> and so then the question comes up uh well if you really believed in it why wouldn't you be a member
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but anyway i uh
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		let's see okay now so you tell me where you are in the scale then
 	
 	
 		i fall i fall i fall smack dab in the middle yeah um
 	
 	
 		you're about a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five</TIMEX> you think sometimes it's right and sometimes it's wrong huh
 	
 	
 		exactly i mean i'm originally from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		well it's i know it can be uh
 		it can be kind of scary the idea of just everybody wandering around with uh uh
 		you know absolute no limits or anything like that on the other hand the truth is that all the bad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> let me put this way all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> that i'm scared of already have it
 	
 	
 		right
 		already have them or can get them if they want them
 	
 	
 		and uh and uh uh when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Lennon</ENAMEX> got uh nailed
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		shot  i should say
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh one of the
 		some some of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> were saying you know that's another argument for gun control i said oh yeah he should have lived in in uh
 		he should of have lived in in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX>
 		where they have a total ban you know in northern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX> yeah that
 	
 	
 		well i mean the same thing went everyone everyone uses <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> as an example saying oh well you know there there's no one has <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> and look at the crime rate there it's so much lower
 	
 	
 		but
 	
 	
 		but
 	
 	
 		the reason when i say i was really talking about northern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX> you know because in northern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX> there is a lot of crime and it's totally banned
 	
 	
 		right right
 	
 	
 		and uh the uh the uh
 		how do i say this the uh the thing that i have noticed
 		with uh this topic is that that i know some very intelligent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and i i say well here's a little brochure why don't you read this and see what it says i don't want to read that okay and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		where as i'm the other way i'll read i can read about when i say i'm the other way that's not to say i'm open minded uh as much as i think i am
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but i'll read anything
 		
 
 		and uh try and and pick it apart so uh let's see what was the other thing i was going to say uh
 		now my <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX> statement about if if they caused crime then <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> should have a lot of them
 		should have a lot of crime uh i don't know that that kind of reflects my my feeling about it because you notice the states
 		where they claim all of these things are coming from they don't have a very high crime rate
 	
 	
 		right well i mean look at <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX> i mean you're talking you're talking about a district where handguns are illegal to be have to have at all and it's also the murder capital of the country
 	
 	
 		and
 		yeah
 		yeah well the the the thing that i see is it's not the availability because availability is you know <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX> is is is outlawed too but
 	
 	
 		right exactly
 	
 	
 		but but it's the uh it's the nature and and my feeling if you go back to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> is one of those places where they have relatively low rates
 		but also the rates of other crimes are lower
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and the other thing that happens is they also have the ability to stop you and say uh mister you look like a pickpocket would you please empty your pockets
 	
 	
 		crime
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and if you try that here in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> i mean you could unload <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">four four pounds</NUMEX> of dynamite and uh
 		you'd walk because they they're not allowed to ask you
 	
 	
 		they're not allowed to do that right
 	
 	
 		so it's it's kind of like uh dandelions i don't know if you have any if do you own a house
 	
 	
 		uh no
 	
 	
 		well anyway if you had a lawn
 	
 	
 		what okay
 	
 	
 		uh uh if you
 		if you've ever had a lawn
 	
 	
 		i get the point yes i've had a lawn before
 	
 	
 		if you've ever had a lawn uh and somebody says uh wait till the place is full of dandelions and then go try and and pull the heads off as fast as you can you'd be pulling heads off <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all day</TIMEX> you know of of dandelions
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and whereas in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> where they come up they come up to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> and they say uh you look like you've got a problem and he says i don't no i don't and then they say well uh let's go they can even go to your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> and uh
 		force you to open your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> and anything they find in there is used as evidence so the result is that uh
 	
 	
 		right
 		
 		
 	