
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		your turn
 	
 	
 		oh i i start okay well uh we keep a budget to an extent um
 		and really it it we were really forced into keeping a budget because i'm i'm paid once a month which sort of sort of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> some uh
 		uh restrictions and you need to make sure all your bills are paid
 		uh how about yourself
 	
 	
 		well i have to say i really don't have a budget
 		both my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and i uh grew up in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> of rather modest means and uh
 		our family income at this point is comfortable upper middle class i guess you might say and uh we're both so
 		uh frugal
 		that um we really don't need a budget you know we just sort of invest the money and go on vacations and always never seem to have any money problems which i guess is a comfortable thing
 	
 	
 		yeah well i guess that really is sort of of keeping a budget you know you stay within your uh
 	
 	
 		well we stay within our means but we don't do it uh by conscious effort it just sort of happens automatically
 	
 	
 		within your means
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		although we just moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> and uh the cost of living here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> is um i would say rather pathological
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		uh housing prices are you know like from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> times more expensive than um
 		um they were where i came from in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>  yeah so uh
 	
 	
 		oh you moved from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX> that is a huge difference
 	
 	
 		uh that presents um a real shock  actually actually our standard of living has gone down somewhat since we've moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		but you have good sour <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dough</ENAMEX> and it's a beautiful place to live
 	
 	
 		yeah it's God's <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> uh and one way you know that is that only God can afford it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 	
 	
 		um so budget is not a problem for us
 		uh least it hasn't been it may it may be at this point but uh up until this point it really hasn't been when i uh was in uh
 		undergraduate school a long long time ago i uh noted that the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">monthly</TIMEX> salary starting average <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">monthly</TIMEX> saly salary for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineers</ENAMEX> that  in my discipline was like
 		oh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six hundred and ten</NUMEX> dollars <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX> or something like that and uh i noted at that point that i was
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know if that's what my salary was that i drew then i would be making almost twice as much as my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> made during his best year ever so
 		i stopped worrying about money and uh never have worried about money since then
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well that's that's a system too
 	
 	
 		sometimes uh it's a bit of a a problem you know because i guess i don't really manage my money the way i should but uh i suppose i've lost money on not taking good advantage of of uh investments but
 	
 	
 		well then again you know you said you you are able to take trips and you do obviously have enough to live on so i guess you're indirectly budgeting
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh just by by the fact you said that you're both very frugal uh in spending the money so i mean that's that's a form of budgeting i would think
 		it's kind of a kind of a strange topic to to try to for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who don't really have a budget to talk about budgeting and how they manage their money
 	
 	
 		well i guess we're both lucky in that regard then
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh how big is your family
 	
 	
 		uh well we're we have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> on the way um my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and then we're we're having <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> on the way in uh in uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		i see
 		so how do you and when once you get <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> though you may have
 	
 	
 		no i think it's just going to be one
 	
 	
 		oh all right
 	
 	
 		how about yourself
 	
 	
 		i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one nine</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> thirteen and they are beginning to be a budget problem but uh have not been really up until this up to this point
 	
 	
 		oh
 		do they budget at all i mean do you have them on an allowance or
 	
 	
 		i give them uh i give them an allowance and they um i basically give my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> ten dollars <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> and i put
 		half of it in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> and i give give him the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> in cold cash
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh he has a teller card so he can uh do what he wishes do what he wishes with the money that i put in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> but at least it isn't you know burning a hole in his pocket
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		if he wants to use it he has to go get it and that usually
 		
 		
 	