
 
     		
 	
 		all right so i guess we're all right um i don't know what the laws are up in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> what's the law up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> for capital punishment
 	
 	
 		like it
 		yeah
 		well <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Governor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mario</ENAMEX> the uh holy <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>  up here <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mario Cuomo</ENAMEX> has been against capital punishment since he hit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> here i'd say <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six years ago</TIMEX> he's
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		he's for the concept of um uh life in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> without parole
 		and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every single year</TIMEX> up in here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> state the uh government the state assembly gets together and tries to pass a death penalty bill and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> he vetos it  and upsets people
 	
 	
 		
 
 		gets sort of repetitious
 	
 	
 		yeah he upsets <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> up here um every time he does it i don't what it is down in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> these days
 	
 	
 		it's legal down here um
 		i i know they've done a few most of the time they'll get real close and then
 		they'll pardon him or
 		it hardly ever gets to that point uh i don't think they've done one
 		in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time</TIMEX> but i know it's legal and i know one just about happened recently but it never went through
 		so they try but you know very few actually go
 	
 	
 		yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mario</ENAMEX> up here is claiming that um
 		the reason why he's against capital punishment is because to send these  things through the court system
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		on appeal then another appeal then another appeal ends up costing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX> more than just putting the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> away for the rest of his life with no chance of parole
 		so you know if it if it comes down to a money issue
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i you know in that case then i'm all for putting them behind bars as long as there's no chance of parole but you know what it's like when they
 	
 	
 		yeah there's always those loopholes
 	
 	
 		yeah they fill the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> there the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">jails</ENAMEX> up and suddenly let them go and they're back on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> we had this murder up here
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um Art Shawcross</ENAMEX> up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rochester</ENAMEX> killed nineteen <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prostitutes</ENAMEX> up here
 	
 	
 		ooh
 	
 	
 		and he was let out on parole from up in uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">um Watertown</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		was that was that on purpose or was that a a snafu
 	
 	
 		
 
 		uh he was just well actually he it was on purpose i guess
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		he was uh he was a real psycho though and uh as a matter of fact it this happened under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cuomo</ENAMEX>'s watch so the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> was thinking if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cuomo</ENAMEX> is going to run for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> they were gonna do instead of
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		that was his dirt huh
 	
 	
 		yeah instead of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willie Horton</ENAMEX> now we have the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Art Shawcross</ENAMEX> deal you know
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so so yeah i don't know what your feelings are about it being in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> where you've had it before
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		um well i can i can vouch for the fact that the uh the appeals will go through and go through and go through
 		and yeah it drags on for about forever you know i guess i'm about your your opinion of it i have nothing against it philosophically
 		in terms of if you're absolutely sure i mean uh uh i i would feel that you better make sure it's one of those cases that has virtually no possibility of
 		no you know you you pretty i mean supposedly you get through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> you're not supposed to have any reasonable doubts anyway but i guess it would have to be one of those extremes in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place but there's enough of them
 		but i i've also heard that that these things cost so much in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX> that uh
 		that it really doesn't save you any money if it's a money thing and as a deterrent thing i don't really think uh personally i don't feel that capital punishment punishment as a deterrent is a is a big deal i don't think that really works that much
 	
 	
 		yeah well of course you know we have New York City up here i'm in being in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rochester</ENAMEX> we're kind of
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		they consider us more in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX> than in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York State</ENAMEX> area
 	
 	
 		

 
 	
 	
 		but uh up here you know we have we don't have too many serious problems with crime but i know in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> it was a real it's a big deal they would like to have it back
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh  i think it's gonna boil down to changing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> if they really wanna put it through
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh they're building more <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prisons</ENAMEX> up here to try and put <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Attica</ENAMEX> is not too far away
 		from where we are and that's at capacity and of course you know <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> is just packed with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> that have done everything
 	
 	
 		
 
 		right
 		it's
 	
 	
 		so i you know i don't where it's going to go to in the end i just think that um
 		i i i agree with you i'm not really that terribly against it as long as it looks like it's going to work and reduce the court load and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		the like
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh down here it's not all peaceful either though i don't if you've been following any of this stuff course we had the big snafu right now with the the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mets</ENAMEX> thing but there have been a lot of uh
 		a lot of things going on down here all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gainesville</ENAMEX> murders
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah i we heard that yeah
 	
 	
 		course i don't think they've they that then actually down here there's been more more publicity going on on police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> screw ups and and uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">beatings</ENAMEX> and everything than than actual murders and uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gainesville</ENAMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gainesville</ENAMEX> picking up <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> seemingly
 		
 		
 	