
 
     		
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh i'll start um up here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rochester</ENAMEX> or down here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rochester</ENAMEX> recently they put in a law for mandatory recycling
 		in our area which involves collecting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> and and bottles and cans and
 		a recent new statute that they just put into effect requires us to open and sort every single piece of our junk mail
 		and actually separate  the uh standard nonglossy paper and uh  from the glossy stuff
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		and uh throw the plastic windowed envelopes away while recycling the junk cover letters for all of the sweepstakes entries and all this nonsense
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so it's been uh hectic it takes me a lot more time now to go through my mail
 	
 	
 		oh my Lord here in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Framingham</ENAMEX> they just started recycling and we have to mostly they're doing the plastic bottles which we have to soak the labels off of
 		and you know milk containers orange juice containers and uh they're doing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> and we have to sort out the ad pages
 		and just you know the regular newspapers go in
 	
 	
 		huh
 		hm
 	
 	
 		and uh we can put like regular white paper in and they've started recycling in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school systems</ENAMEX> white paper only not yellow <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> or lined paper you know just the plain white paper
 	
 	
 		well they they've got up here where we can recycle our magazines our our um uh any correspondence paper anything that is not of glossy
 	
 	
 		wow
 	
 	
 		um finish except for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> they'll take <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> they'll take um uh
 		most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kinds</ENAMEX> they take plastics i think beginning with numbers <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one and two</NUMEX> on the little bottom uh on the bottom of the bottles and the like  and of course we've had to bottle bill here with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mario Cuomo</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		so we've i actually what i did is i went out and i got a separate trash barrel where i put my recycled papers in and we don't have to separate out like for example a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kraft</ENAMEX> envelope
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you don't have to sort that from um a sheet of typing paper
 		um i basically just kind of keep pushing down on it and i i  try to get it all in there <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every week</TIMEX> and then take this fifty pound barrel
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 	
 	
 		out to the end of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> so they can pick it up and haul it away
 	
 	
 		um-hum that's what everybody's complaining about they gave us these big restorage bins you know they're plastic they look like <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk</ENAMEX> crates only about they're about <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times as long
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		are they the blue buckets we have them
 	
 	
 		yes  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Framingham</ENAMEX> has a lot to catch up on  and um  you know it's quite a pain in the neck
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well you know what happens what we hate is when the wind picks up everything blows everywhere because and and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> won't put things on top to hold the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> there
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		or they'll or even worse is when it rains
 	
 	
 		oh God
 	
 	
 		they don't like it if you give them soggy they won't take it if it's a soggy magazine uh we
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		we have these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> up here that do the same thing as far as bottles and that if they're not washed out
 	
 	
 		right they're getting to be real stinkers here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Framingham</ENAMEX> too they used to take them no matter what but now they have to be washed out and everything else and it's like nobody bothers anymore
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well it it is it's terrible because uh we have a chain <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> here <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wegman's</ENAMEX> and they'll only accept bottles from uh products that you've bought at their store
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so if you're shopping in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> grocery <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> you have to remember okay um
 	
 	
 		
 
 		this came from
 	
 	
 		yeah because they won't well we don't sell this so you know we're not gonna take it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um oh it's terrible we've just recently um they've been they've been fighting more and more because they wanna they wanna have it so that we can give them all of our junk mail
 	
 	
 		right that would be nice
 	
 	
 		in it because it's terrible i mean i normally normally i open just bring the mail bucket i get <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> and just hold it over the trash can and just start shaking you know
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		no i'm not interested in this no i'm not but now we have to open every single piece up and sort it
 	
 	
 		oh that really
 	
 	
 		so you know you don't fill out <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Publisher</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clearing House</ENAMEX> you know you got oh let's see now are these
 	
 	
 		yeah you have to take all that stuff out
 	
 	
 		yeah are these stamps uh recyclable and we have this book that tells you what is and what is not recyclable
 	
 	
 		oh my Lord
 	
 	
 		so you got to like scan down let's see now  it's
 	
 	
 		that must be hysterical it sounds really funny we have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> here they started locking up private dumpsters
 	
 	
 		well  this doesn't
 	
 	
 		because everybody was taking their trash to the dumpsters  so they didn't have to recycle
 	
 	
 		oh
 		yeah it's it's been it's been rough you know they they've been complaining because
 		
 		
 	