
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so uh what things do you consider an invasion of privacy
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well i don't know what do you think
 		
 
 	
 	
 		oh i don't i don't know i had a little bit more time to think about it i was thinking of like uh
 		
 
 		i don't know i started i started to think about all the big
 		you know data bases they have with all the information about you on them like the  credit reports and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and all those you know demographics studies that they do that
 		um you know have
 		who knows how much you know
 		stuff about all the purchases that you've made and
 		everything kept tract somewhere and
 		
 
 		i don't know i don't know how much the stuff actually what they actually have in there but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i know they use that i mean they
 		they sell those to
 	
 	
 		well what about the required drug testing uh as a uh condition of employment
 	
 	
 		yeah that was that was that was the other one i was thinking of
 		
 
 		i think that's uh
 		i mean i know <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> are illegal
 	
 	
 		it  a subtle thing actually um
 		
 
 		i uh have worked at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Instruments</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh they instituted a drug policy there drug testing policy where they randomly would test uh employees
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and actually to tell you the truth i really didn't think much about it i i hadn't you know it really didn't relate to me but there were some things that people
 		brought up like well what happens if they they get a false positive you know what recourse do you have
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and
 		
 
 		also um
 		uh this is against the law for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> to do this kind of thing this kind of big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> activity and yet uh
 		a lot of these large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Instruments</ENAMEX> although they don't admit to it it's actually
 		oh a drug testing policy comes about as a result of government pressure
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so
 		
 
 		what that means is to me that really it's the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> that's requiring this although they don't actually execute execute it themselves it's really the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s that so in that sense at at least uh
 		philosophically it's really borderline legal
 	
 	
 		um-hum  well i i think that um
 		i think that you know a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s competence should be more determined by
 		you know their actions and their behavior and if they're
 		you know if they're on some kind of
 		you know controlled controlled substance then you know it kinds of takes away from the job of you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supervisor</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> type person
 		know who is able to evaluate them i think they should be evaluated that way rather than  with a
 		you know a chemical you know
 	
 	
 		well what about this uh <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> epidemic now where you find that uh
 		
 
 		uh you know certain <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are actually are are criminal in their disregard for
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carriers</ENAMEX> and don't uh don't reveal it
 	
 	
 		
 
 		others yeah and
 		and uh of course the ultimate solution is to operate on their brain so that it doesn't get uh
 		it destroys their libido
 	
 	
 		yeah that's that would be kind of an extreme
 	
 	
 		now uh you know if they ever
 	

 	
 		i mean i've heard of things like you know making them
 		you know uh marking them somehow or you know or something like that or
 		you know putting them all some some place like in a kind of a
 	
 	
 		so what about that as an invasion of privacy
 	
 	
 		yeah well i guess it kind of borders on where
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i mean
 		what do you value more the invasion of uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s privacy or the possible danger to
 		you know other people
 	
 	
 		so really it it gets to balancing uh personal freedom against
 		uh the general welfare
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		of society
 	
 	
 		i guess that's always that's been the big role of government i guess
 	
 	
 		well are it's supposed to have been
 	
 	
 		i mean  generally
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		well
 		yeah that's kind of a difficult one to go into i mean that that particular case
 	
 	
 		now it
 	
 	
 		because i mean there's a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that uh i mean they could require one you know
 		obligatory obligatory <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> testing for everyone because i'm sure you know there's a huge part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> not a huge part but a you know the the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> i guess that have it that don't know they do
 	
 	
 		a growing part
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and are spreading it
 		but again to require you know such a test and just and then to make make it known they have it is to subject them to to discriminatory discriminatory practices
 		and other things
 		i don't know uh i don't know how exactly i feel about that
 	
 	
 		maybe chop their weenies off
 		
 		
 	