
 
     		
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh what are your thoughts
 	
 	
 		well uh interestingly enough i've been reading in the paper about uh the option that says basically none of the above
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and and uh given the choices that's sometimes how i feel i generally support <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> and i feel like he gets a lot of bad press you know the the economy is really not his fault i don't think
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		no no
 	
 	
 		but uh as far as anybody else running i think
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">wow</ENAMEX>  is this the best we have to offer <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two hundred fifty million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to choose from and this is what we get
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		uh-huh yeah i uh uh on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> i was listening uh listening to uh the radio and they had they had speculated that uh there was some rumor that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tsongas</ENAMEX> was thinking of running again
 	
 	
 		yeah what i heard <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX> is that although he has dropped out he's still got a lot of support in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> apparently
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> you know it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> primary and they seem to be saying that if he got a good he's still on the ballot in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> and they said if he got a good showing in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> then he would jump back in
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well that doesn't that seem sort of uh
 		uh
 		it doesn't seem seem like it's useful for him to uh doesn't it seem like a waste of money though for him to come back into the race this late uh what are his chances of winning at this point
 	
 	
 		well  obviously he thought they weren't too good if he if he backed out
 	
 	
 		exactly
 	
 	
 		uh
 		i don't know maybe you know <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> is a big primary
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and there are a lot of others still to come maybe he feels like if he can carry <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York</ENAMEX> strongly then he could still make it
 	
 	
 		uh-huh sure
 	
 	
 		but uh i don't know
 	
 	
 		yeah what what did you think about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> this term
 	
 	
 		uh
 		it's hard to say it's nice to get somebody in there i would certainly never vote for him as far as i know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but it it's nice to have somebody else bring some issues to the front and at least ask the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> some questions and have him have to defend himself
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so i think in that sense it's good i don't think that uh he's experienced enough to do the job uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		on the other hand maybe he is i mean  the newspaper <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> tell us all the politics anyway so maybe he can just go ahead and keep doing it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right right well it's yeah i i agree with you it does seem that he came in and kind of fluffed the pillows uh you know uh for the campaign for the campaign anyway so we didn't have to hear the same thing again
 	
 	
 		how about you
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh we didn't have to uh  we didn't have to ignore a lot of uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s success because you know he really did a lot in the last term he uh
 		with with the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gulf War</ENAMEX> and all we could have we could have had our judgement clouded just by his his accomplishments you know i i really do think i am going to vote for him again <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next term</TIMEX> but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh i wanted to know exactly everything that happened you know a lot of times maybe i forget
 	
 	
 		well when you look at it too how much does the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gulf War</ENAMEX> really count i mean how for example how much has it helped us as as a people
 	
 	
 		oh sure
 	
 	
 		i'm sure that we can say it helped the uh enemy rate of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuwait</ENAMEX> um and uh sure it shook a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> a few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		is is that a success or is that just sort of uh part of the job description as far as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> goes
 	
 	
 		right
 		right uh what what i mean is though the strong sense of uh nationalism that occurred you know right after the war uh sort of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroized</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX> you know whether or not it was you know a success for us or whatnot  he tended to come out of the out of the
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		experience you know as the great <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		oh yeah yeah his his popularity was somewhere close to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">ninety percent</NUMEX> at the time
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		and it
 	
 	
 		so i i i am i'm glad that uh he can't get into office this time without at least uh addressing a lot of the the home front issues
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh well <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Todd</ENAMEX> uh it sounds like uh
 		we may have covered a uh a minuscule portion of politics today
 	
 	
 		a very minuscule portion so what about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Libya</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		what about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Libya</ENAMEX> i have no idea what to say about
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		you you've heard of the goings on there i guess
 	
 	
 		yeah i i don't know uh
 		
 
 		if you know if you'd asked me the same question about uh uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuwait</ENAMEX> you know at this early in the game i don't what i would have said then either i i don't
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> now of course the last time i listened to anything was on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and they had still refused uh the concessions by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Security Council</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		i thought it was let i have to make sure i get the uh stories right because because there was also <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> the attract the attacks on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Embassy</ENAMEX> but now didn't <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Libya</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 		
 		
 	