
 
     		
 	
 		all right do you have any
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh strong feelings on schools
 	
 	
 		well um i think that uh the majority of the problem with the school system um
 		is similar to the majority of the problem in a lot of other areas in it's a question of economics and the school system is not designed to be successful um
 		by that uh it's not really profitable
 		for good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> to be in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school systems</ENAMEX> uh if there are good school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> good really qualified <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> as school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> it's because they're dedicated not because they're rewarded for doing so
 		um
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> the public school system uh needs to be viewed i think kind of like
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">highways</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> and everything else it's part of the infrastructure it's something that has to be and has to be you know highly highly maintained in order for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> itself to be successful and when you um
 		when you neglect part of the infrastructure be it the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> or whatever then everything kind of follows with that it's just a question of how long before you pay the price
 	
 	
 		i've i've uh
 		heard heard the that proposed before and i'm not uh discounting it completely but
 		the counter argument to that is that uh there are <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> around that are uh
 		private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> not necessarily uh parochial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> are paid no more than they are in the public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and they and their track records are much better
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		uh
 		the uh
 		in in fact
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> there's a lot of  uh there a lot of
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">uh Catholic</ENAMEX> and other parochial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> around that are not staffed by nuns and and i'm not a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> so but i was just reading about this and what they were the
 		the argument that i've heard is that uh and i subscribe to some of it by the way
 		that uh
 		our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> are reflecting the same kind of mismanagement that uh lead to the demise of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> and that is when you've got an absolute monopoly
 		and uh you can't uh you know it's a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> party system so to speak then what you're going to have is gross inefficiencies and nobody cares
 		and reality uh uh is just not a market base system and i know i've been in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Orient</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about three years</TIMEX> and
 		the public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> are not very good but the all all of the good <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> are private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> over there
 		and uh it's not that we're spending i i think that we're spending a lot of money uh relatively speaking on schools
 		but uh
 		as with other things you know it like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Detroit Detroit</ENAMEX> or some of the other problems uh with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Detroit</ENAMEX> it's not the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX> it's the uh it's the management
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		and uh management frankly just doesn't have to they don't have to compete these days
 	
 	
 		yeah i'd heard something as a matter of fact uh kind of along those lines with i think it was the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> school system
 		where they suddenly instituted a sort of market system where um basically the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> were allowed to take whatever classes they wanted to and go to whatever school they wanted to and it was up to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> to attract the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> and offer stuff the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> wanted and what turned out happening this was like area of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> with the highest drop out rate and all this kind of stuff  and what ended up happening is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> didn't just take fun classes or anything like that uh it ended up that
 	
 	
 		yes
 		yeah
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh the rate of of graduating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> went way way up and they ended up taking real courses but it was because they wanted to and because they chose to instead of were being forced to and
 		and the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were forced to compete and and the good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> were getting the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> and that kind of stuff
 	
 	
 		yeah and and well i see that as a as what i consider the biggest problem uh
 		as with
 		with uh oh there there are other problems and number one it would be nice if if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> got paid uh uh i i hate to see the
 		how shall i say it the garbage the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> that collect garbage and and uh
 		uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">sanitation engineers</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes you know well the sanitation <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineers</ENAMEX> that go out there with uh and  just lift uh
 		i hate to see those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> get paid more than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah and
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> are uh under a lot more stress
 		and don't get any tips at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the day</TIMEX> at you know at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> time
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so uh uh from that standpoint and frankly the private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school systems</ENAMEX> uh
 		uh including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX> and things like that uh do quite well uh because there is a lot of competition
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and if somebody decides that they're going to if their decisions are out of step with reality uh pretty soon <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't stop going there
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		or they get a horrible reputation and they get this uh what do they call that uh
 		
 		
 	