
 
     		
 	
 		person i've ever gotten
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 		yeah me too i guess it's the east coast time you know everybody else is asleep
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well i figured i'm available now and actually i've had this thing on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX> phone and it's it tried about fifteen time
 	
 	
 		oh yeah yeah i've got i've initiated a few at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> like that and it takes a while during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> uh well it's an interesting topic wanna get going
 	
 	
 		okay i
 		oh okay here we go
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		what are your thoughts on fitness
 	
 	
 		uh well i exercise fairly regularly  i work for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> out here uh in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Livingston New Jersey Bellcore</ENAMEX> yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell Communications Research</ENAMEX>
 		and um we have in the corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> where i work a health enhancement center HEC they call it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it's about as convenient as can be it's uh just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">floors</ENAMEX> down from me
 		and uh so i exercise regularly during <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the daytime</TIMEX> when i'm at the office
 	
 	
 		do they have <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Nautilus</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">machines</ENAMEX> and that kind of thing
 	
 	
 		and
 		they have oh a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> of maybe <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> jogging machines they have a a um
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		progressive weight machine that uh you know you dial up the weights on it it's not <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Nautilus</ENAMEX> but it's similar to that and then they have uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bicycles</ENAMEX> and free weights
 		but they also have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who chart your progress uh and encourage you to come if you slip off for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of weeks</TIMEX> they send you a a nice friendly aggressive reminder that says hey we haven't seen you for a while
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and they also provide towels and shower <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> and lockers and everything so
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		uh you i've been through the routine i guess like most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> where you know i've joined health <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clubs</ENAMEX> i've been at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX> where you know it's a pretty good distance away you know <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">quarter of a mile</NUMEX> walk and
 		uh nothing seemed to work for me as well as having it in my own building
 		doesn't work at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">at</TIMEX> at home you know i've bought home exercise equipment and stuff and
 	
 	
 		right is this something you do on your lunch hour
 	
 	
 		uh no i generally go down there um <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">midafternoon um the time</TIMEX> that seems to be best for me is around <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two o'clock</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two thirty</TIMEX> but
 	
 	
 		oh they allow you that free time to do that
 	
 	
 		but  yeah and that's you know there are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> down there all the time you could almost hold meetings sometimes because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> tend to set up a regular schedule and go down there uh but the the etiquette of the place is that you don't really talk too much business
 	
 	
 		oh i really wouldn't have thought they'd give you that much free time this is part of your day
 	
 	
 		when we're down there
 		uh yeah yeah it just you know works out that way um and there have been a lot of studies i have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> who uh
 	
 	
 		huh
 		
  
 	
 	
 		who work in the recreation <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">field</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> like this and actually um a break like that increases productivity and and with the commensurate um
 		increase in physical fitness by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who attend these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> regularly you have uh fewer absentees and things like that so the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporation</ENAMEX> can justify it pretty well
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		and it's not like i'm taking time away from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> i probably put in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">extra hours</TIMEX> because i'm now physically fit and
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		reenergized i mean that  my routine around <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two two thirty</TIMEX> to go down there for an hour
 		probably makes the last <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three hours</TIMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> then more productive than i would if i  you know just sort of went on through so
 	
 	
 		well i i  i used to exercise at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> and i found that you don't come home tired you come home with a  new found energy so you i can see what you're saying
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		and that's what the late kind of the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">late afternoon</TIMEX> is i you know i have a very light lunch because i know i'm gonna be working out and uh you you know usually then my lunch is just a a quick tuna sandwich at my desk so then and i sort of skip that luncheon
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> and uh you know catch up on reading and then work out so that's that's kind of my routine
 	
 	
 		hm i belong to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Y</ENAMEX> and i substitute teach so i would love to get there <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday Wednesday Friday</TIMEX> or you know every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">other day</TIMEX> but when the phone rings at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">six o'clock in the morning</TIMEX> that's it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and and it's kind of upsetting because if you go once a week it hurts every single time
 	
 	
 		yes yeah
 	
 	
 		you know i what i like about exercise i love the inaerobic exercise i like
 		the weight machines and i like the free weights i enjoy that it's sort of a personal challenge to get better at that and you do see results real quickly um  you know the the
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um stationary bike and those skiing machines that's work i'm not crazy about that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah we have the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Nordic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">machine</ENAMEX> and i tried it a couple of times it just made me feel stupid and uncomfortable and uncoordinated so i don't do that i sometimes it is used regularly by you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> but uh i i didn't like it
 	
 	
 		well i find i i you know i read somewhere that <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty minutes</TIMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bike</ENAMEX> is what you need <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every other day</TIMEX> and and i can do that and be pretty comfortable about it but i tried the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Nautilus</ENAMEX> machine yes it you do feel kind of goofy but even <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five minutes</TIMEX> makes you feel tired you work harder on that thing
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		um-hum yeah it it appears so i generally use the um the treadmill uh i kind of like it it's it's mindless you just get on and it's a a way to sort of
 		um
 		reach a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Karma</ENAMEX> very quickly you know
 		
 		
 	