
 
     		
 	
 		so uh what do you think about child care
 	
 	
 		oh  well my my feelings on are it is uh i wouldn't take a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> to a day care
 		you know i mean i'd i'd wind up um just a babysitter in a home
 	
 	
 		right
 		probably find someone how come you wouldn't take them to a day care just because of the
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um um</ENAMEX>
 		well too many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and and i think too many infections and things coming in
 	
 	
 		yeah they seem to pass a lot a
 	
 	
 		yeah sicknesses and i don't know then all the things you hear about them and
 	
 	
 		yeah you kind of wonder whether or not
 	
 	
 		yeah i mean i'm sure there's some good ones but i just i don't think that i would hum
 	
 	
 		i took uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cammy</ENAMEX> to a
 		oh it was a preschool day care type of thing
 	
 	
 		oh uh-huh
 	
 	
 		but i kind of i liked it in some ways and some ways i didn't um i think the ratio of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> is really important
 	
 	
 		oh yeah yeah how was it
 	
 	
 		and
 		well
 		i think they had a
 		they had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> and i think there were <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty kids</TIMEX>
 		but i only had her going <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two days</TIMEX> and most the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> were going more days
 		so that was probably my own fault
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		that she didn't oh you know one thing i noticed is uh
 	
 	
 		she she went
 	
 	
 		um just they were trying to get her to teach her to write her name
 		and uh i didn't notice it until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this summer</TIMEX> when i was working with her that she'd bend her wrist all the way oh not in a natural shape form
 	
 	
 		oh she did
 	
 	
 		yes and uh i was kind of mad mad that they had never noticed that and either pointed it out to me or
 		or uh tried to say look you're holding your she's holding her pencil in the right fingers and stuff she but she was
 	
 	
 		uh wrapping her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX> all the way around yeah
 	
 	
 		yes
 		and uh i hadn't worked with her on writing at all at that point she was <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">four</NUMEX>
 		or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> yeah she was uh it was last year
 		and uh then <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this summer</TIMEX> i got the thing from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> that says things to work with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> on and i worked like i said i didn't notice it till then
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		because i hadn't worked with writing letters or anything and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		stuff like that
 	
 	
 		well they'd never picked it out though huh or just never said anything
 	
 	
 		no they never
 		course like i said i took her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two days a week</TIMEX> and maybe that was my main reason for taking  her was um just social skills more than anything else
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		i felt she needed the social
 		just i didn't feel like she was mature enough socially and
 	
 	
 		yeah well one thing that's kind of different too though a preschool than than taking a  a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">infant</ENAMEX> under to a day care where they're taken care of
 	
 	
 		um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh yeah i think it would be hard to take them to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you don't know
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">preschool</ENAMEX>'s a different thing but i think it's hard to take <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> to somebody you don't know and or unless you have awfully good references
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		reliable um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i don't know it's so hard to take young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> anywhere for very long
 	
 	
 		well i think it's hard to leave them it is
 	
 	
 		it is the older ones it's not you don't even really have any
 		real worries because you know that they'll play with whoever's there and they usually adapt pretty well
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but uh
 	
 	
 		yeah it it is i think  just hard to leave them because nobody will give them the kind of care their own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> will um
 	
 	
 		well and you know their kind of their schedules and you know if they're upset and
 		that type of a deal
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		i don't know how um <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> uh that have young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> work and work full time and
 		and do it really without being stressed out all the time i think it's
 		well i don't know
 		then then on the other hand i think it's harder to stay home in some regards
 		it's hard to
 		always keep yourself feeling like you're doing something productive and
 		at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the day</TIMEX> your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> still feels like it's a mess and you haven't got anything done and what am i gonna fix for supper
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		oh yeah that is uh
 	
 	
 		yeah it's kind of hard to always feel like gosh what is is this important what i'm doing and
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah well um <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the work never ends</TIMEX>  for sure  uh
 	
 	
 		no no it
 		it doesn't
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		but i think that taking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> to a probably <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that take them to uh preschools and day cares full time
 		oh they would  i don't know
 		probably just feel a different uh
 		i think i just think it would be hard to do that full time i feel such a responsibility even when we go out for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a few hours</TIMEX> that are they driving the babysitter crazy and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh uh-huh</ENAMEX> or is everything okay
 	
 	
 		you know what
 		
 		
 	