
 
     		
 	
 		what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> are you reading these days
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well i get a uh
 		quite a few uh
 		we've said that our
 		our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> subscriptions uh really add up to a strange bunch but i get i get <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Business Week</ENAMEX> uh i get one called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">uh Dulcimer Player's News</ENAMEX> i get uh
 		uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly</ENAMEX> magazine
 		uh we get <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> uh and then i get uh uh well i guess i don't get any electronics <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> anymore i get uh electronics uh
 		news newspaper
 		uh what about you
 	
 	
 		well i get the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">um weeklies</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> and
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US News</ENAMEX> i also get <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sports Illustrated</ENAMEX> guess those are the only ones i get <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> and then once a month we get a whole slew of them we get <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Money Magazine</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">um Southern Living and Country Living</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		and um my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> has a whole ton of them she subscribes to
 	
 	
 		oh yeah  yeah
 	
 	
 		a whole whole bunch of those
 	
 	
 		well
 	
 	
 		well i guess i guess the good thing about these um <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> especially how they put things in them you know they have time to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">at least</NUMEX> put things in perspective
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but uh you know i guess the bad thing is they don't have the immediacy of you know radio or TV or a or a newspaper but they certainly can you know give you a bigger picture on things than than the than the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> can
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah that little bit of the of the whys behind what's happening and not just the the facts yeah i uh
 	
 	
 		they can be responsive too i know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this summer</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US News</ENAMEX> was going to take a week off in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX> and then when the attempted coup came along they quickly came out with an issue an issue that they weren't going to do
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		which shows that they're that they're certainly are responsive to changing events
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		well i know that yeah and the category that i forgot is the the uh
 		professional uh ones i'm i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of uh I triple E and uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">uh ACM Association for Community</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Materials</ENAMEX> i get uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three or four</NUMEX> uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> magazine form things uh that way uh too so uh
 		i i don't know what the what the status is in general of of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> reading magazines i i certainly uh do a lot of it and and uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> for that matter but i uh
 		i've heard that the trend in reading in general and and in especially <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> is down that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> just
 	
 	
 		well i think you're right i think trend in reading i think one reason that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times Herald</ENAMEX> folded and other papers folded is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are reading <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> less than they used to and i guess that means they must be reading <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> and you know other written stuff less too
 	
 	
 		yeah i think i think so i i don't i haven't heard exactly how it's effecting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> maybe not quite as much but uh i think that the
 		more and more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are just depending on the TV for what what news they do get and
 	
 	
 		of course then you have the specialty <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Golf Digest</ENAMEX> or or knitting or crocheting and all these things
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		that have a selective market  that just aim at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> kind of thing those maybe it's that the that the special purpose <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> are doing better and the ones that are more general aren't doing as well
 	
 	
 		that could be that could be because there's not there's not really an alternative uh  uh source for that kind of kind of information but uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah i guess if you want to find out a specific item you have nowhere else to turn if you want to find out the the latest in gardening trends unless you read a gardening magazine you're not going to find this anyplace else
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		whereas if you want to know what happened in in in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> today you can turn on the radio or TV and you don't really have to read a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> to find out something
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		that may be it and with desktop publishing and stuff i think a lot more <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> that are that aim just smaller market will be coming out
 	
 	
 		yeah i i wonder if that i wonder if that will uh uh make things different i've heard that uh
 		read an article <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">just last week</TIMEX> about fax <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> coming out and wonder if they'll do that with uh you know magazine kinds of things as well i uh was it uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh Skip uh</ENAMEX> Bayless
 	
 	
 		yeah i heard uh i heard it too <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Skip Bayless</ENAMEX> wasn't it yeah
 	
 	
 		from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times Herald</ENAMEX> is doing a a fax sports column
 	
 	
 		yeah i read <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times a week he's going to fax you the sports column i don't know i don't know how that will catch on
 	
 	
 		uh
 		no but uh uh it was interesting uh
 	
 	
 		yeah i thought that i that would be interesting to to see though
 	
 	
 		um kind of
 		and it they for a long time they've been talking about that you know that that
 		moving away from paper <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> uh i guess would it be included in that in terms of of uh computer access and stuff but that that
 		doesn't really seem to have caught on to the extent that they keep predicting uh
 	
 	
 		well you know you you you don't have time
 		
 		
 	