
 
     		
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy</ENAMEX> do you have any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes i have a twelve year old
 		and i've been very lucky i haven't needed child care except for my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> so i've been real lucky i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurse</ENAMEX> i go to school i mean i go to work early
 	
 	
 		oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> comes over in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX> and gets her ready for his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> or just hangs by while she gets ready drives her to school then i'm home to pick her up so i'm very very lucky
 	
 	
 		well that's nice
 		that is lucky well how old um does a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> have to be before you have to you get to stop making arrangements for him i wonder
 	
 	
 		well i could do it now but she gets lonely <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">in the morning</TIMEX> and i feel better um she has a crazy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> out there somewhere that i just don't let her out of my sight so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well and um it's nice for them not to be alone
 	
 	
 		um
 		you never know yeah yeah she feels that way you know and we have a neighbor on the next block that she could always walk over there and go to school with but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we just feel better doing it this way so i don't know what day we'll stop we we were about to stop <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> and then her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> called the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and made all kinds of threats and so
 	
 	
 		that is a rule
 		oh no
 	
 	
 		we didn't stop and so  so um you know it you realize that it only takes <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one second</TIMEX> for something to happen so even though she's twelve she's still a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		yes
 		she is
 	
 	
 		you got to be careful
 	
 	
 		well i'm glad you had that um opportunity to have your mom
 	
 	
 		yeah i'm i'm glad too
 	
 	
 		well i I have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and uh <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five and six</NUMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> and um so far i haven't had to make a lot of child care arrangements for them because um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i'm at home now full time but um when i was going to school i would go to school a time that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> wasn't you know when he was at home
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so that we would just switch back and forth like that but um it's really scary and i would really hate to be in a position to have to find child care
 	
 	
 		well i would too because even though a place can look pretty good on the outside we're finding out now that it's not always on the inside and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i i just don't know what i would do if i had to do that i know the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> that i work in is big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> and they provide child care and of course they charge for it but at least all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurses</ENAMEX> can leave their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		no
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they're always watching them they can eat lunch with them if they feel sick they can call them at work and they run over and check on them and they feel a little better than if they dropped them off somewhere on the way
 	
 	
 		um
 		well that's nice
 	
 	
 		so yeah it is nice
 	
 	
 		and i know that i have um done some babysitting myself
 		and uh when i was in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and needed extra money and i know how i feel how i felt as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">provider</ENAMEX> of child care that even though you're you're taking care of someone else's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> and you're forcing yourself to
 		you know treat them equally and you know better usually better than your own um it's not the same and it made me realize that um no one will love your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> as much as you and your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> your
 	
 	
 		right right
 		well that's right
 		yeah right
 	
 	
 		and um the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and no one will look out after them and i just think um
 		so far i think my preference would be rather than to have like a
 		oh a big day care that um what is that like child <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KinderCare</ENAMEX> and things like that rather than having one where they would deliver the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> to school in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">van</ENAMEX> or something
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		i would prefer to have in home care either my own <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> or a neighbor or something
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah just never know i babysat for the little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> next door for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year or so</TIMEX> when her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> first got divorced and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it it was hard to treat her equally with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> they were the same age and they played together and they were good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>
 		but like you said you tend to go more for the other one's side just because you are responsible and so it it got hard and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> got jealous and
 	
 	
 		right
 		it is hard
 	
 	
 		um it just wasn't the same as when they were just playing as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> because she had to be there <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> so i stopped that after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> because it was difficult to balance it so
 	
 	
 		no
 		no
 		and i know um when i pick my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> up from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> they wanna come home and i and i would hate for them to have be picked up by a day care and be taken to another large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> situation
 	
 	
 		they do
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		i know i know
 	
 	
 		so i think uh my preference would be a small small if i had to find day care would be a small someone that i knew
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah well i would rather do without some things and i know that some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> they both do have to work but a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> where i live are working just because they want bigger and better
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i would never do that i never have done it and i just never would do it i would rather do without some things that really aren't very important compared to being with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> when they're growing up so
 	
 	
 		no
 		well that's true because even <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> when they're gone to school it seems like there's just not enough time left over in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the day</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		no there isn't there isn't any time that's true
 	
 	
 		and uh by the time they have to eat and have homework and they want some free time and there's just not enough to time in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> to do anything good quality for them
 		but that's really
 		
 		
 	