
 
     		
 	
 		hey this is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bryan</ENAMEX> how you doing
 	
 	
 		
 
 		this <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jay</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> how are you
 	
 	
 		i'm fine thanks nice to meet you
 	
 	
 		good where are you from
 	
 	
 		i'm from right right now i'm living in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> but my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>'s in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plano</ENAMEX> and that's where i'm at right now
 	
 	
 		oh okay yeah
 	
 	
 		so calling pretty close at home right now well you ready to give this topic a a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whiz</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 		that be great
 	
 	
 		all right here we go  all right would you like to go <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> or
 	
 	
 		go ahead
 	
 	
 		all right um i'm pretty young so i don't have a whole lot of credit cards i when i <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> i made a big mistake and got pretty far into debt and
 		ever since then i've decided that it's if i'm gonna make a purchase i i make it and have the check written out at within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next week</TIMEX>
 		for the purchase i made and that way i i keep my credit cards at an even balance
 	
 	
 		yeah that's right i i think that's what happened to everybody out there gets back when they just sent them to you without any
 		i've got i don't know how many tons of them but uh
 		i use uh well this one particular one for everything i mean everything i buy including groceries
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it runs up pretty high <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every month</TIMEX> but i then i pay it off because i get a a air uh advantage miles on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		with it so i i can get a you know i've already gotten a free trip just from using that card so i don't uh i don't have any carry over balances any more
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		but i just i was wiped out there for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> but that was the way to do stuff and uh you i think you have to make the decision
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 		right
 	
 	
 		but um <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> is uh you know it's a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">debtor state</ENAMEX> and if you get in too big of a trap you
 		you can just blow them off and that's not good but i know lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> do it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it's what runs that interest rate up you know pretty high yeah
 	
 	
 		right um-hum
 		and i agree you know i think there's a lot of benefits for example i know that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> and brother-in-law as well as my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> they they use them quite like you do you know they just they're within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every month</TIMEX> they're within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five</TIMEX> dollars knowing within <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five dollars</NUMEX> of what it is and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then they right it off but to that advantage it gets
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know the privileges of like you said like the the mileage and the
 	
 	
 		well it's uh the interest rates are still crazy up there you know i i i mean they've come down every  except the credit cards
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so it's not uh it's not really an advantage to have them now they're
 		uh some of mine are up i think up over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty</TIMEX> percent i don't use them anymore but i think
 		think they've gone over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty</TIMEX> percent a year
 	
 	
 		you're kidding
 		wow
 	
 	
 		and some of them you know i think the one i'm using is about fifteen but i don't use the interest anymore so it doesn't make a difference
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and then when i travel i travel a lot in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> i use <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Diners Club</ENAMEX> and that gets
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 	
 	
 		all  my um
 		uh insurance on rental <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> and  and plus they have a pretty good uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh plan on the gifts and things like that i try to get something out of them now
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		well that's right you know i i think too one of the things that i've become very
 		aware of in terms of when i'm looking for a credit card is i'm looking i look for something that doesn't have an annual fee
 	
 	
 		right absolutely there's no use paying that fifty or whatever it is a month a a year
 	
 	
 		absolutely i just you know i think that if you're doing that you're pretty stupid because you could be using that on something that you really want
 	
 	
 		oh sure um personally the not my next project i think is to take those that i do have uh listed and cut them up
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		that i'm not using uh especially the ones that don't i that there's a working asset to these that gives a lot of uh
 	
 	
 		yep
 	
 	
 		money to um
 		the environment and things like that that's my <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> here but i've got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cigna Visa</ENAMEX> that doesn't give you a damn thing so
 	
 	
 		right
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh i think i'll cut it up <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> for my <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">New Year</TIMEX>'s resolution
 	
 	
 		yeah and i think i agree with you too you know i'm i'm should have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Visa</ENAMEX> i haven't this is my <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">first year</TIMEX> i've had a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Visa</ENAMEX> and i think i'm gonna cut up everything that i'm not using it's just stupid to have them around and
 	
 	
 		yeah i've got a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">um gasoline</ENAMEX> credit cards that i don't use anymore because they take all the others so i might as well pitch them i mean it's just weight carrying it in your pocket
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah and i agree and i think the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> the one thing that i've really learned too is that if you're gonna have a credit card just you know if you're not gonna use it for example like you said a
 		with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Visa</ENAMEX> card really you can almost do anything now and i'd just as soon have it all on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">card</ENAMEX> so i know exactly where it's my bills are gonna come from and
 	
 	
 		absolutely yeah
 	
 	
 		i think a lot of times especially like i'm a student so i don't have a really big income but
 		i have to you know be really careful not to over extend myself and when i'm using it on other cards it
 	
 	
 		oh yeah you can
 		i was absolutely um <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> checked me <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time and they said nobody in the world could have paid this much interest
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i said well i'm glad you mentioned that because i've got receipts for all that
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but you know something else i couldn't have proven but uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		that was uh i'm not young anymore so i uh took a long time to learn but a lot of young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> do get trapped on it it's easy you know you don't have any money and
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">yep</ENAMEX> and i think it's uh i think you know i was really lucky in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that this summer</TIMEX> when when i did it i i had enough and i was working enough that i could
 		basically pay it all off within you know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six months</TIMEX> or so so it wasn't where i was over my head but i i got enough of a taste of it to realize what i didn't wanna do anymore
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh sure and they got all those late charges now and stuff they didn't used to have and if you go over the limit there's a charge i mean they're they're really starting to hit us
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		you know a lot harder than they used to they've they've
 		
 		
 	