
 
     		
 	
 		uh what uh guess i should have talked before uh what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> do you wanna
 	
 	
 		
 
 		huh
 	
 	
 		are you familiar with i guess or do you have a favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> i guess
 	
 	
 		um
 		yeah my favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX>'s probably the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reds</ENAMEX> yeah i'm from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cincinnati</ENAMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		is it are are you really great
 	
 	
 		yeah but uh most national <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">league teams</ENAMEX> i'm pretty familiar with
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah i uh i'm i'm familiar with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reds</ENAMEX> myself we lived out there in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dayton</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX> so we used to root from the line i don't know they got a pretty good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> but i see i kind of think the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Braves</ENAMEX> are the gonna ones be the ones to go places this year
 	
 	
 		oh really
 		yeah that's what i thought even <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> i thought they'd be doing pretty good
 	
 	
 		yeah they're pretty they're so young and everything i i was just starting to get <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave Justice</ENAMEX> is one of my favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		yeah he's pretty exciting to watch
 	
 	
 		i'm hoping he can pull them through and maybe have a good series like they did against the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Twins</ENAMEX> again
 	
 	
 		yeah i think the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dodgers</ENAMEX> you got to look out for with all the the hitting they've gotten recently
 	
 	
 		oh yeah and who else did they pick up they got <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Strawberry</ENAMEX> and who else did they
 	
 	
 		they got <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reds</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Davis</ENAMEX> too
 	
 	
 		yeah and uh they traded away for some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pitcher</ENAMEX> too
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah because they dealt <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Belcher</ENAMEX> and then they got someone else i forgot his name though
 	
 	
 		huh yeah i've i've kind of i they always make me nervous because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lasorda</ENAMEX>'s good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX> and everything but uh they got the bucks to spend they can get all those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah it seems like they always get the the high paid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> and they always seem to end up doing pretty good for a while
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah i uh i'm kind of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mets</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> myself too i uh like to see them go i don't know why but because they're
 	
 	
 		well they just signed uh what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bonilla</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		Bonilla  i see that's being from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX> i thought you'd maybe be a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but no huh  do you
 	
 	
 		no i keep up on it yeah i tell you though he's getting what <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> or something
 	
 	
 		yeah you cannot it's kind of hard to turn that down that's for sure
 	
 	
 		yeah you got to think <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bonds</ENAMEX> is worth more than that too
 	
 	
 		yeah definitely i wonder if he is he gonna stay with them or
 	
 	
 		no he's looking to leave from what i hear
 	
 	
 		oh if he leaves then they're they're done with they won't go anywhere <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> i mean that's their <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> biggest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> that are walking so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		they signed a couple of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pitchers</ENAMEX> who are gonna be free agents
 	
 	
 		yeah they resigned them well that's good that'll help but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah they got Walken someone else they resigned
 	
 	
 		i wouldn't be surprised to see them if they go after Bonds but
 	
 	
 		they're not gonna give them more than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> they can't afford it
 	
 	
 		well i don't think anybody can i don't know if anybody's worth that much for what they do but uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i don't know i really i say i really hope the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Braves</ENAMEX> can pull it through they're i think they caught everybody's imagination <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> it was a it was great series but it'd been fun to see them win it
 	
 	
 		yeah you got to like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">underdog</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true maybe they can pull it off again but i tell you i don't know it's
 		so are you a big baseball <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> or do do you
 	
 	
 		yeah pretty much yeah up where we are we don't get much baseball news but uh i try to keep up on it
 	
 	
 		oh do you just through the  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> or whatnot
 	
 	
 		yeah reading the little transactions column is about all we get
 	
 	
 		oh huh
 		well what do you think about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A's</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Canseco</ENAMEX> and those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> have they got any chance or
 	
 	
 		i don't know they really surprised me <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> when they dropped off so quick
 	
 	
 		yeah i'm wondering if they're maybe just getting a little bit too high paid and thinking they're so good and
 	
 	
 		yeah too many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attitudes</ENAMEX> out there
 	
 	
 		pardon
 	
 	
 		too many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attitudes</ENAMEX> out there i think so i think it
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true that's definitely true
 	
 	
 		they got a lot of high paid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> that could start somewhere else as backup
 	
 	
 		yep that's true got to get <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Canseco</ENAMEX>'s mind off <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madonna</ENAMEX> and then he might be able to play a little bit  yeah exactly
 	
 	
 		yeah or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Pickett</ENAMEX>'s
 		yeah but they were in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World Series</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">so many years</TIMEX> straight then they were in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">like third or fourth</TIMEX> or something
 	
 	
 		yeah then they that's like they dropped off the map and they had all the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> but
 	
 	
 		yeah the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reds</ENAMEX> did the same thing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> then down into <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		yep
 		oh yeah that surprised me because they were so tough and then i just i just wonder like i say if they lose the desire they did it once and then they just forget it and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i don't know but uh
 	
 	
 		you figured after all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rose</ENAMEX> stuff was over everything would be fine and it was but then i don't know what happened <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah they just like i say they tailed right off but yeah i heard <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX> was hurt quite a bit so that kind of hurt them
 	
 	
 		yeah but he always is i mean that's why they got rid of him he only plays like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a season</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true
 		yeah it'll be interesting to see what he does now that he's out there with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bud Strawberry</ENAMEX> and if all of a sudden he becomes healthy all the time
 	
 	
 		yeah he kept on saying that uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reds</ENAMEX> should switch to natural grass just for his knees but uh they never did but they got that out in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LA</ENAMEX> that should help him
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah it'll help
 		but yeah we used to i was back there with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reds</ENAMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray Knight</ENAMEX> used to play and when he yeah when he took well it was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> that he took <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pete Rose</ENAMEX>'s place and of course he couldn't do anything right and
 	
 	
 		yeah <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> base
 	
 	
 		but uh we used to go i used to get free tickets for from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and go out and watch them but uh so they were always kind of were kind of a good my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> still loves them that's his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">favorite team</ENAMEX> but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah i can remember going to games there when i was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah that was good fun if i the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stadium</ENAMEX>'s what was amazing to me i mean we've got nothing that big out here as far as a you know baseball or football <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stadium</ENAMEX> you know walk inside and it was just huge to to see them but uh
 		it would seem like it was always bigger on the inside than it was outside
 	
 	
 		yeah because it looks small on the outside
 	
 	
 		yeah i had all these huge i we always were up in the nose bleed seats so we never got a chance to get too close but
 	
 	
 		yeah and anytime you try to walk down the uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ushers</ENAMEX> would always tell you to go back
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah i did that a few tried that a few times can i see your tickets and then you just get up and leave because you know there's no other
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah or uh oh i left them up in my seat
 	
 	
 		yeah  yep but uh i don't know yeah i like i enjoy baseball i play a lot of softball
 		
 		
 	