
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		which baseball <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX>'s your favorite
 	
 	
 		uh i don't really have a favorite baseball <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> but of course the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rangers</ENAMEX> play here
 	
 	
 		oh uh-huh
 	
 	
 		and and they've made a whole <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> history of trading away <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> that become all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> later on so
 	
 	
 		oh have they like who are some of their who are some of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> that they've traded away
 	
 	
 		uh several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pitchers</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toby Harra</ENAMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doc Meddich</ENAMEX> a another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pitcher</ENAMEX> and of course now they've they've sunk all their money into <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nolan Ryan</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh oh
 	
 	
 		but they they they have they have <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruben Sierra</ENAMEX> and they have um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh Julio Franco</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh so they've had some real good ones over the years
 	
 	
 		yeah and they they traded away um <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Incaviglia</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Detroit</ENAMEX> i think and then he hit more home runs <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> than he'd ever hit before
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh ah well that's good do they is is baseball for young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> there a big thing do they start them out early or where do they get all these good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> from
 	
 	
 		uh no well they get them from you know <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Puerto Rico</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> and the minor leagues
 	
 	
 		oh oh
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball baseball</ENAMEX> has a big minor league system
 		especially in a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a few</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> come out of college and then uh more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> um go straight to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minors</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and that gives them time to see uh pitching at a higher speed you know and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		how do so do they have a a program at all for young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> there for <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX>  or is soccer the biggest thing or
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah they do it's it's mostly in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> the i think the biggest thing here is soccer
 	
 	
 		that's that's what i thought that <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">soccer</ENAMEX> is bigger it used to be around here anyway that <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">um baseball</ENAMEX> was real big for the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> but now it it soccer is
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		making a real quick catch up um i know they have the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four and five year</TIMEX> old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> start like with the tee ball
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		are you familiar with that at all
 	
 	
 		right yeah
 	
 	
 		the tee ball and i think they go until they're <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> then they have the pitching machine i think <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> and then and then just the regular pitching after that but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's not it's not a big as program as it as it used to be and i'm i'm not really familiar around here we don't have any baseball <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> i don't think that even in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Salt Lake City</ENAMEX> there is a
 	
 	
 		no there's not <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>'s the nearest place
 	
 	
 		there's a
 		right right so it it's not there's no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> around here that i really follow and am close with have you ever played baseball
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		uh no just in P E uh it's it's pretty big here in high school and they've they've had several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> um picked in the draft you know they they're picked in lower rounds
 	
 	
 		is it
 		oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		especially pitchers
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		uh but mostly they just go on to college because because because they need the experience and the education so
 	
 	
 		right
 		uh-huh right well that's i remember uh playing <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> when i was just in grade <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> but by the time you know we got to P E it it wasn't a real
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		a real big thing either but i enjoy baseball just for a fun pastime now with you know a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> gets together a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> reunion or whatever or or it  we we live in a real small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> and
 		they have uh like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Fourth of July</TIMEX> celebrations and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'ll get together and play softball and
 		that's fun i really enjoy that i think it's a fun game i think it's funner to play than to watch myself
 	
 	
 		right yeah
 	
 	
 		so do you do you enjoy playing it at all or do you enjoy watching it even
 	
 	
 		yeah i i um i enjoy playing and it took always took me we'd play you know during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the spring semester</TIMEX> always took me <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about six weeks</TIMEX> before i could see the ball before i could hit the ball
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh
 		oh uh-huh
 	
 	
 		and uh
 	
 	
 		yeah it's do you
 	
 	
 		and
 		but i enjoy playing i enjoy uh watching the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">All-Star Game</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World Series</ENAMEX> was really good this year
 	
 	
 		right
 		oh
 	
 	
 		the there were some spectacular catches and a lot of home runs and they had uh several double plays you know and
 	
 	
 		oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		was it in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Candlestick Park</ENAMEX> again
 	
 	
 		uh no it was uh uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Twins</ENAMEX> versus the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Atlanta Braves</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> were in last place at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the season</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		my word
 	
 	
 		then they fought their way back up to the top and then of course <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota</ENAMEX> won i think in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">seventh</NUMEX> game and ended up
 	
 	
 		oh wow  oh that would be exciting i i was
 	
 	
 		so it was really exciting
 	
 	
 		listened a little bit about it but i didn't know you know much about it oh so it had to go the full <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> games
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and it looked for a while that like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX> was gonna the win you know before they went back to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota</ENAMEX>  but it didn't happen you know they played
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh
 		
 		
 	