
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay uh what do you feel about the nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> would you put an elderly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relative</ENAMEX> in one
 	
 	
 		um only if i had to
 	
 	
 		that's the way i feel right now i'm uh concerned with both the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister-in-law</ENAMEX> and the
 		and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> that i'm uh uh you know one of them will said if anything happens send me there and the other one says please don't send me there
 	
 	
 		yeah it's real hard on both the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i mean
 	
 	
 		yes yes it is it's hard my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> uh well i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> takes turn staying with us and you know she's getting to the point that
 		that i'm worried about her needing more care than we can offer her
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so uh she can't she it's hard for her to get up and down stairs and everything and i just think what are we going to do
 	
 	
 		yeah well how old is she
 	
 	
 		uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty five</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		i see yeah well um would like if do you think you're gonna have to it's gonna come to that
 	
 	
 		so
 		i hope not i we will we will do everything in our power not for it to
 		happen so i i'm hoping that we can take care of her till you know
 	
 	
 		yeah i went through this with both my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmothers</ENAMEX> we had to get someone to look after them but we were lucky and we found someone to look after them in their home we didn't have to put them in a home
 	
 	
 		well mother uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> lived about fifty miles from me and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a hundred miles</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">five hundred miles</NUMEX> from the other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> and so if she if someone could've stayed close by she could've stayed in her home longer
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but as it was uh she had to come and start living with us and and she gets more dependent all the time
 	
 	
 		yeah well my great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> that we had to put in a nursing home because it got to where my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> couldn't take care of her she after they put her in there with i mean she deteriorated i mean her health really got worse after
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh i think that happens yeah i think they just give up then
 	
 	
 		after she would yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and another thing what  what would you do if you had to what would you look for
 	
 	
 		well that's um i guess references or whatever from other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> first of all and then
 	
 	
 		well
 	
 	
 		i mean all the you'd have to check i think all the licensing that they go through
 	
 	
 		um-hum and i would check on cleanliness and another thing i'd check on is the food
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister-in-law</ENAMEX> was in in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and uh she just just had her hip replaced
 		and so she just went to one you know for the little time for it to exercise and thing
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they'd feed them really weird things like  <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">uh salad</ENAMEX> for breakfast and broccoli and she was she had her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> about her and she didn't i mean she knew that they were doing it wrong
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so i think they're
 	
 	
 		yeah see that's what it is is most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are so old in there that they don't really know what's going on
 	
 	
 		yes uh-huh
 	
 	
 		and i think that they can get away with that
 	
 	
 		yeah i think that's a problem too so
 	
 	
 		you have to i think you have to really check into them real closely and then even after you put someone in there then you would wanna
 	
 	
 		i do too and i
 	
 	
 		be you know be able to check up on them on a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> basis just to make sure that they were treating them properly
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well the one that i that i we would put my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> in would be <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about three miles</NUMEX> from my home
 	
 	
 		oh that wouldn't be too bad
 	
 	
 		and so i would check her to i mean she was in there when she had her her hip replaced too
 		and so i would check on her <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two or three</NUMEX> times a day
 	
 	
 		yeah it's a scary thought
 	
 	
 		they
 		it is it is and you just you know well it comes right down to it i think it'd be heartbreaking how old was your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> when you put her in
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i think she was like my great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> was about she was i think <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ninety two</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		your great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX>
 		oh my word and how old you have a longevity don't you in your family
 	
 	
 		yeah one of my girlfriends her her great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred and two</NUMEX> but she still lives at home with her with her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> or whatever
 	
 	
 		uh-huh oh that's great yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah no it's a it's a tough decision it's a tough decision to put to put them in there and then
 	
 	
 		
 
 		what
 		oh it is and it and it you know it's a tough decision to take them into your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> when you're used to your freedom
 	
 	
 		um-hum but just it's a lot of responsibility
 	
 	
 		yeah it is and and uh you know uh well it's just like having a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> again do you have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> oh
 	
 	
 		no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ma</ENAMEX>'am
 	
 	
 		oh you're just a youngster then
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		oh oh well i don't think we've solved any great problems but i wish  what
 	
 	
 		no what um trying to think what else
 		we went through oh and then the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medication</ENAMEX> if they have to have <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medication</ENAMEX> that's another thing that that i mean
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you never really know and you never really feel confident with anything unless you're actually doing it yourself and if they're at a home you don't know that they're being given their medicine
 	
 	
 		right right and not and uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX> and i think you know just giving her the right amount checking her <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> and giving her the right amount
 	
 	
 		they
 	
 	
 		and then again back to the food i think that they have uh
 		if they don't eat if they don't eat by themselves or if they don't want like what's that served <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that day</TIMEX> they don't eat it and i think a lot of them starve to death
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		they just wither away and
 	
 	
 		well it's kind of like you know you put them in there someone else so someone else can take care of them and then you really wonder you can't feel really confident that they're being taken care of
 	
 	
 		no no i don't i i just think the solution if every  but a lot of people can't either can't take care of them at home
 	
 	
 		what
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">hum-um</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know if you're working and i i think the ideal situation is like with your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> have someone come into their home and live with them and take care of them and a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like to do that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		
 		
 	