
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay universal health insurance right
 	
 	
 		okay
 		um that's right
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		what would we like to say  i think
 	
 	
 		well i think universal health insurance like national health like what <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX> has is that what you're you're thinking this subject is about
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		i think that's what the subject is about
 	
 	
 		did you read uh the article in the paper <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> about this particular subject
 	
 	
 		in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morning Times</ENAMEX> i guess i did not
 	
 	
 		yeah uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota</ENAMEX>
 		is uh going to begin testing a program
 		a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">state</ENAMEX> funded program for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> of those <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>
 		and there's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fourteen</NUMEX> other
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh</ENAMEX> states that are considering it least according to the article in the paper this morning
 		i think it's a trend that's that's that's uh probably may go nationwide eventually because i think national health is something that we all need it's getting to a point that
 		you have to have it you have to have some form of health insurance
 		and extremely expensive though
 	
 	
 		well it's been interesting that we
 		yes
 		so we live in a society though where everyone if you ask them on polls will um say that they think that everyone has a right to health care
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and yet i don't think we've ever quite decided who's really supposed to pay for it and
 	
 	
 		well that's the thing you know uh unfortunately the ones that currently pay and pay the premiums for health insurance are are paying for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that don't have health insurance
 	
 	
 		which is why <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are talking about we ought to just admit it perhaps and then try and somehow subsidize it in a way that's more fair
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i don't think you um
 	
 	
 		you have health insurance through your company
 	
 	
 		yes i do
 		uh through my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> yes
 		but i have been in a situation uh recently where
 		i was laid off from a position as a sales <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> and was off work for about a year
 		and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> developed <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> and we didn't have any insurance
 	
 	
 		oh my goodness
 	
 	
 		and it was uh
 	
 	
 		that must've been horrible
 	
 	
 		go to <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Parkland type</ENAMEX> situation
 	
 	
 		how was your care at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parkland</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> because it was a life threatening situation it was very good
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> as it as it turned out <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">um people</ENAMEX> or one of the top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> that is involved in cancer treatment was at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parkland</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Camp Parkland</ENAMEX> is not free either
 	
 	
 		no it's not free but uh
 	
 	
 		is it affordable
 	
 	
 		it's it's a situation that because i didn't have any insurance and i was on unemployment it was paid by the county
 	
 	
 		so you did have a good experience
 	
 	
 		i had a bad experience as it turned out
 		um i was fortunate that there was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parkland</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		is your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> better i hope
 	
 	
 		uh no she passed away oh that's all right that happens
 	
 	
 		i'm real sorry
 		sure it does happen but it's very sad
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		but in any event um i'm in favor of national health
 	
 	
 		well so am i  actually um i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pediatrician</ENAMEX> and i feel very strongly about um <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and um developed very strong feelings about this during our <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">measles</ENAMEX> epidemic last year
 	
 	
 		if i had to vote for it
 		oh is that right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		where we certainly proved that we're not doing a very good job with preventive health care among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and particularly the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> who need it most
 		so um i'm really quite active in trying to uh uh be proactive at least to for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s issues it's very complex very complicated but
 		um i just strongly believe that all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> have a right to immunization glasses hearing aids  basic health benefits
 	
 	
 		well i when i grew up and i grew up in south central <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kansas</ENAMEX> um we had and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> worked for the health <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> the county health department
 		and we had <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">X</NUMEX> rays <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> we had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dentist</ENAMEX> come to our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and uh check our teeth once a year at least
 		um we had all our flu shots taken care of our measles mumps rubella and all that other stuff and uh when my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> were growing up
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		we didn't have that we had to pay for it which i wasn't opposed to paying for it i had the money to pay for it but i'm sure that there were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that don't
 	
 	
 		well and the costs of so much has gone up so much the cost of immunizations for example
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> and just the legal
 		the legal benefits um that has really forced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> into doing a lot of things unnecessarily <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">et</ENAMEX> cetera
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so well i don't know it's it is interesting in case you didn't know <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> leads the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> in uninsured <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty one</TIMEX> percent of all <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		did not know that
 	
 	
 		do not have insurance and are not on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX>
 		so uh one out of every <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> has nothing to reimburse them for their health care
 		and i work in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Parkland system</ENAMEX> and it's pretty overwhelming to me
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but um it's pretty hard to be indigent and to be dependent upon indigent health care <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">systems</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> county
 		
 		
 	