
 
     		
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		me think a political event that happened <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah i
 	
 	
 		well
 		there's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Duke</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and then there's the dissolution of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		those <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> pretty much take care of everything
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 		so what do you think about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Duke</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well  if i was a mind to i might burn a cross on his yard
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		thing that what scares me is some of the things he says i agree with
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know i just don't agree with his methods
 	
 	
 		that's true i
 	
 	
 		you know i think that the way to you know cut out the welfare poor is not to cut out welfare it's to provide an equal opportunity for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to make a living
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		definitely i agree with that
 	
 	
 		and protect them from themselves
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		basically you know i've i've seen this very close hand
 		a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">twelve</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years old</TIMEX> can make <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about three thousand dollars</NUMEX> a day dealing crack
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		if he lives to his <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty</TIMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> birthday it would be a miracle
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so we're we as a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> have an obligation to our future generations to
 	
 	
 		provide them some other <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">avenue</ENAMEX> or
 	
 	
 		yeah to make dealing crack a a crime punishable
 		in such a way that nobody would want to do that and and it our constitution expressly forbids that kind of punishment
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah it's like i say what kind of you know what kind of punishment that's <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">three thousand dollars</NUMEX> a day that's that'd take some kind of punishment to deter deter deter it
 	
 	
 		yeah i i'm considering doing it you know and i got a job <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> anyway
 	
 	
 		yeah definitely i mean
 		yeah
 		surely i uh i uh
 		i haven't listened to a lot of his views i just you know the thing about that i kind of concerned me is how they the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> now want to keep him off the presidential ballots and stuff
 	
 	
 		well
 	
 	
 		and i've kind of wondered you know really if that's right or
 	
 	
 		right or wrong rarely has anything to do with politics
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true
 	
 	
 		uh what i'm seeing here is that
 		the real problem see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Duke</ENAMEX> addresses symptoms
 	
 	
 		um-hum he's getting to some some serious issues
 	
 	
 		the real problem is if
 		i work for a man
 		say i work for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> as a matter of fact i'm going to work for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> new job
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		he sells <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kelley</ENAMEX> tires
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		now if i roll in there a brand new set of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">B F Goodrich</ENAMEX> tires <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week after next</TIMEX> should i expect my job to be there
 	
 	
 		yeah uh well uh see
 	
 	
 		see what i'm saying
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know if you drive onto the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX> manufacturing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lot</ENAMEX> in a Datsun
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i believe that not only should you be fired you all of your assets should be given over to the government
 	
 	
 		why is that
 	
 	
 		because you're crippling the very economy with which you're trying to survive in
 	
 	
 		oh that's true that's true
 	
 	
 		now i believe in free choice don't get me wrong
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i'm i figure i'm allowed to drive any kind of car i want because i don't work for a car company
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i drive <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> made
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's just because i'm an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> i believe that that's the way you ought to do it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i mean sure having a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mazda</ENAMEX> or a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nissan</ENAMEX> or whatever they're called <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> sure that'd be a real status symbol but you ain't gonna impress my <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know my <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX>'s driving a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty year old</TIMEX> pick up truck
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		you know
 	
 	
 		well i think you got a point too i can see we do a lot of complaining but you don't see a lot of us you know a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> willing to buy the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> stuff they're like you say they're all out for that status symbol and
 	
 	
 		you know
 		sure
 		yeah now the last time i bought a calculator i bought one from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Instruments</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> works at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Instruments</ENAMEX> and uh the next time i buy a computer it will be a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Instruments</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well that makes that makes good sense like i say if we i think we're the of the opinion now that
 		uh somebody's got to support the economy but it's not necessarily going to be the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> they want somebody else to do it because we're not willing you know we're under the impression that somebody else makes a better product or little snazzier or something but
 	
 	
 		they they do make better products the scary thing is we finance their research
 	
 	
 		exactly that's true
 	
 	
 		you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">T I</ENAMEX> came out with the with the transistor they didn't make <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beans</ENAMEX> off of it
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 		um-hum yeah we just did the core research and then they put it into some consumer product and make all the money off it yeah
 	
 	
 		you know
 		right exactly
 		you know i i have a real fundamental problem
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who drive a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mercedes</ENAMEX> and have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sony TV</ENAMEX> and scream and holler about the welfare poor i really have a problem with those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		yeah because they're not doing anything themselves to really help
 	
 	
 		they're exagerrating exagerrating as a matter of fact they're exagerrating exagerrating exagerrating what's it exacerbating the problem
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		they're making it worse
 	
 	
 		i can see i can see i i see what you're saying
 	
 	
 		i used to work for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this summer</TIMEX> he drove <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMW</ENAMEX> i i quit him
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		i say hey you know
 	
 	
 		what uh
 		was it in the tire <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> again or
 	
 	
 		no it was in construction
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		um i i i see i am a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealer</ENAMEX> for construction software
 	
 	
 		oh uh-huh
 	
 	
 		i had worked for this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> as as an employee
 		
 		
 	