
 
     		
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		you bet they tell you our topic hm you've got it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">uh pets</ENAMEX> do you have pets
 	
 	
 		yes we do uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> that's soon be <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight years old</TIMEX> and we have a a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> which is uh i guess <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about five years old</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh my goodness
 	
 	
 		how about you guys
 	
 	
 		we have a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">birds</ENAMEX> at this point parakeets
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">birds</ENAMEX> what kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">birds</ENAMEX> you have
 		no kidding enjoy enjoy them
 	
 	
 		oh have a ball with them
 	
 	
 		you let you let them out and let them fly around everything
 	
 	
 		well no because my <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> chase them  so if in order to have the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">birds</ENAMEX> not stuffed i have to keep them in their cages
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 		we you know this is like a cruelty joke and i apologize if you're a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bird</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lover</ENAMEX> but uh we had a parakeet
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and my fault put up our <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> electric <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> and never thought about it knocked that parakreet right right out of the air
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well we had that happen once um my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> had the bird back in his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> because it's his bird well the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> one that we had was his <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bird</ENAMEX> and
 		i had the ceiling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> put up and it the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bird</ENAMEX> got away from him one <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX> and i mean that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sucker</ENAMEX> hit that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> and went flying up against the wall i thought oh so much for the bird no he's still alive and kicking
 	
 	
 		it kill it
 		oh that's no it killed ours i'll be darned
 	
 	
 		no i guess we didn't have it high enough or he didn't get hit in just the right spot but it threw him up against the wall you know and he slid down the wall
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well speaking of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pets</ENAMEX> i'll tell you my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are older now my both of them are either in or out of college but
 		but we had for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years about five years</TIMEX> i guess had a my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> had a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burmese</ENAMEX> boa <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">constrictor</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		oh gosh
 	
 	
 		that thing grew to be <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">seven and a half feet</NUMEX> in in length and finally my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> bless her heart got rid of it because i didn't really like it
 	
 	
 		oh i hate them
 	
 	
 		and we also had a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one year</TIMEX> down in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> on a vacation for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Father</ENAMEX>'s Day my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> maybe uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years ago</TIMEX> go bought me a skunk from a like exotic pet shop it'd be like it'd had been like deactivated as far as uh
 	
 	
 		oh my goodness
 	
 	
 		smell and everything and we had that darn pet <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">skunk</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about five years</TIMEX> and and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> left
 		went to school we finally sold his boa constrictor but my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> needed some money and we we sold it for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about two hundred</NUMEX> and fifty dollars so ah
 	
 	
 		you're kidding
 	
 	
 		so when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> came over he was infatuated by that skunk so i made him a deal i said you take that skunk
 		and he said i'll sell that snake to you for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> fifty i said otherwise i'm gonna give it to this other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> so he took the skunk too and the skunk was a good a decent pet but you know it does its little jobbies in the litter box and
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh well that's pretty good
 	
 	
 		and it was sort of a neat but they just stink too much
 	
 	
 		oh yeah oh yeah
 	
 	
 		that was sort of fun you i  tell everyone this story because my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> is a real pet lover
 		i used to visualize my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> for  many times my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> be lying there on the sofa and this snake honestly would be stretched across the top of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> with with its with its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> right on her neck
 	
 	
 		oh you're kidding
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and the skunk would be sitting at her feet
 		that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> would be on the back of the sofa and a dog be running around crazy  oh
 	
 	
 		oh my gosh i can not imagine i just i don't do my in fact my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> has a uh
 		a exotic pet shop out in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> and he keeps threatening to send a snake through the mail you know i'm going don't do that because they won't come in my house
 	
 	
 		oh gosh
 		oh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> bought this snake uh  someone gave it to him when he was in junior high school and it was just a small thing then but it got to be pretty big and you know you'd feed it you can put and feed him that small <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> to big rats and things like that and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's just uh too much that snake used to watch our <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> walk around i always told my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> i said you know what your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>'s gonna get our cat one of these days
 	
 	
 		oh my gosh yeah that's right oh my gosh that is wild oh i just can't do those and the lizards and the
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh me neither
 	
 	
 		all of those things ugh they they need to stay outside far away from me
 	
 	
 		we're down to a simple <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> now and that's the way it should be and haven't had any <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">parakeets</ENAMEX> for quite a while or birds uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customer</ENAMEX> of mine has a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">parrot</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh gosh sticks in my mind he paid eighteen <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">hundred dollars</NUMEX> for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">parrot</ENAMEX> and that was just mind boggling
 	
 	
 		oh yeah they are so expensive
 		well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> was just dying for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bird</ENAMEX> and i'm really allergic to them so i i tried to stay away from them except i've gotten real attached to this one and and uh we went down to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canton</ENAMEX> one time oh gosh
 	
 	
 		are you
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two or three years ago</TIMEX> now and he'd saved up his allowance you know and picked him out a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bird</ENAMEX> and a bird cage and and that stinking <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bird</ENAMEX> when i brought it home tried to take it out of the little box that they give you
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yes
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">clamped</ENAMEX> onto my finger and would not i mean i had to literally shake him off to get him in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cage</ENAMEX> and he has tried to bite me for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> and all of a sudden this <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bird</ENAMEX> and i have become wonderful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> he'll gives me kisses he talks now
 	
 	
 		oh gosh
 		that's neat
 	
 	
 		and it's just hysterical i'm the only one that pays attention to him
 	
 	
 		why sure
 	
 	
 		and i'm a substitute <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> and one of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fifth graders</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> came up to me and said my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX>'s making me get rid of the bird we have too many <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pets</ENAMEX> i thought yeah right come tell me about it you know
 	
 	
 		come to my menagerie
 	
 	
 		they knew the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sucker</ENAMEX> when they saw <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> so now we have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">parakeets</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	