
 
     		
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay i'm definitely for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug random drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> testing and any kind of drug testing to try
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		and get rid of it
 	
 	
 		hm but don't you don't you find that that sort of imposes imposes a um
 		i mean it it i i
 	
 	
 		taking away <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s free agency
 	
 	
 		pretty yes i think so i mean i
 	
 	
 		how many times do you think drug <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have taken away <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s free agency
 	
 	
 		well not probably not as often as as as you'd like to think and and when you when you take and i i mean it's like
 		would you like to have somebody would you like to have the police able to come to your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and search for for let's say weapons uh twice <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a day</TIMEX> without telling you
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> would you like to have them come and find and look maybe for uh oh uh
 		illegal illegal books and and could they come and and and just knock on the door and walk in your house
 		and say i want i wanna find illegal books
 	
 	
 		no but as long as you are working for somebody you are
 	
 	
 		yeah well
 	
 	
 		more or less under their jurisdiction
 	
 	
 		um-hum okay well would would you
 		the place at work would you like them to be able to search your purse and and then every time
 		anytime they wanted to just come and and check to see if you had anything that was maybe against the company
 		i i i'm it's not that i'm in favor of of you know that i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> should be allowed to take <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> at the job or or you know anything like that of course but
 		on the other hand it it's it seems a little bit nasty to me just to have this uh um
 		you know it seems quite an imposition on on personal freedom to have
 		um you know it the the the vast majority of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are at work aren't aren't taking <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> and have nothing to do with them and yet they're being subjected to the to the same kinds of of imposition
 		that everybody else is and and i think i think that that's just unfair if you put it in a different context you see the same either the same you know it it get becomes a little clearer of course you know i'm my assumption is that
 		that you don't take <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> and and and you of course would never have have nothing to hide in that sense and so it that doesn't doesn't hit home very close right but when it's something else it it does hit home and and
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		i've you know it ah it it gets more like a police state um and it's a lot less like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> to me and and i find that uh
 		i find it pretty offensive to have you know to have to be subjected you know i mean to to subject everybody to that kind of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">of</NUMEX> of uh how you know random search
 	
 	
 		it wouldn't bother me and i don't think it would bother any of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> that's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> and i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> that's an airline pilot
 	
 	
 		
 
 		and
 		yeah uh
 	
 	
 		and i think they're they are among the top ones that should be subject to to that
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah uh you know and and again again you know in my case i have nothing to hide and i'm not gonna you know it's not gonna hurt me but on the other hand i'm very
 		uh it it perturbs me to have the this issue
 	
 	
 		uh one of our freedoms so called
 	
 	
 		yeah i mean just to to to be able to walk in and say you know now you have to show us this or you have to do that or you have to and
 	
 	
 		taken away
 	
 	
 		um it it seems it it seems like it's an erosion of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">of</NUMEX> of a lot of what makes uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">the United States</ENAMEX> what it is and and i i i strongly dislike that um and so
 	
 	
 		well i'm for doing it because i think that it is a protection against the majority of the of the citizens
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah now actually actually i i don't take a a totally strong position on it i mean i think that i think there are certain certain positions
 	
 	
 		you're just trying to argue with me to show another point
 	
 	
 		no no no i i think that there are there are certain positions where the
 		the benefits of it outweigh the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the the disadvantages</TIMEX> of it and and like you say you know maybe airline <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX> or or um you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who who whether
 	
 	
 		i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> that's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> what about him
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah i i suppose you know i i i kind of wonder about sort of random testing in general i i guess random testing is a way to make <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> not not feel like they're being singled out
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		right because  you know it seems like that that um you ought to be able to tell who who has a problem and and uh
 		and be able to deal with them um but but i suppose that has uh some uh some negative side effects too right i mean <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> still
 	
 	
 		maybe they would feel like they were being
 	
 	
 		persecuted or something right um and uh and i supposed that the random testing and i guess the logic is that if as long as
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know if if if you're not involved then you don't have a problem with it it shouldn't it shouldn't be any an issue for you and and and eventually the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are actually
 		doing that and causing the problems will be will be caught at it but um
 		i don't know
 	
 	
 		i just really feel strongly against <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> because i think that they're they're tearing our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> apart they're tearing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> apart they're tearing
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that
 		you know uh could would be asset a asset to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> and to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> and i just think that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> is
 	
 	
 		um yeah
 	
 	
 		i just try so hard i would try so hard to get them out of wherever they were
 	
 	
 		yeah i i you know it's it's sort of like  you know i i i don't i just disagree with your position in general it's it's just that it's kind of
 		
 		
 	