
 
     		
 	
 		what do you how what do you think of your news coverage and where do you get most of it
 	
 	
 		
 
 		uh usually uh either TV or radio
 	
 	
 		oh oh
 	
 	
 		it it seems like
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		sometime uh we get <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX> paper but uh even then it just seems that sometimes you're so busy you don't wanna take an hour or so to sit down  the paper
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so it's so much quicker just to hear you know hear it on the radio or watch TV
 	
 	
 		yes we don't go to bed at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>  usually until we've seen the news at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> so that's probably well we do take a daily <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> too
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh you do uh-huh
 	
 	
 		um-hum but it's out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ogden</ENAMEX> and so it it's not very you know it's not probably as big as yours and sometimes i wonder about the newspaper coverages too anyway
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		because i've known stories that have happened and then read it in the paper and it hasn't been all that accurate um-hum um-hum
 	
 	
 		not quite the same yeah and a lot of times when you have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> different um papers you get <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> different stories
 	
 	
 		that's true although i think that's the same on TV too you know you'll get one you know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next day</TIMEX> on the same thing and so but i
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right  oh excuse me
 	
 	
 		i enjoy i enjoy the news i like to keep up on whatever's happening
 	
 	
 		oh i do too
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		it's just it's so much easier just to
 		you know listen to the radio in your <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> it seems like or just to sit down for a short while and watch the news than it is to sit down and you know i mean i'll read <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">periodicals</ENAMEX> and stuff too but um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		usually those come out after the fact and course they give you more information so if you want that then that's fine
 	
 	
 		uh
 		yeah well i think sometimes you know you'll hear it on TV and you want want to go into it deeper you uh you can get it in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> or a paper
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 	
 	
 		a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> and then on the radio you know they usually uh give the news <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">every hour</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so i i like that too especially when we're traveling
 	
 	
 		right yeah i know that when i'm on vacation i am like seems like i'm totally out of it i don't know what's going on and i don't really care
 	
 	
 		so
 		well that's true too
 	
 	
 		it's kind of nice to get away from it all
 	
 	
 		yeah uh-huh but you know if there's a story that you're particularly interested in it's good to  to be able to follow up on it  you know so
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but uh  we have a a news <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">station</ENAMEX> too that is  uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KSL</ENAMEX> out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Salt Lake</ENAMEX> that covers just it's a talk show and there's news almost constantly on it
 	
 	
 		oh uh-huh
 	
 	
 		and then <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> has news constantly too
 	
 	
 		right right
 	
 	
 		so do you have cable
 	
 	
 		no we don't so we don't watch <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh  well we couldn't get TV here if we didn't have cable we live close to the mountain
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		and uh the signal the signal doesn't come because we're kind of behind a mountain
 	
 	
 		right right
 	
 	
 		so we couldn't get it if we didn't have cable cable in fact we've when we first moved out here for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> probably <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years</TIMEX> we couldn't it was really snowy
 	
 	
 		oh is that right
 	
 	
 		our reception and you know we'd watch it and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> would watch it but it wasn't all that good
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		so you figured might as well get the cable huh
 	
 	
 		yeah well  we were glad when it came but it just keeps going up in price too so that's kind of detriment too
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but we've thought of getting a satellite so that we could get more <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stations</ENAMEX> but uh it wouldn't i don't know
 	
 	
 		now that'll be nice
 	
 	
 		yeah but i don't think we're gonna to do it because it's uh you can't get local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX> and that's the news that we're mostly interested in
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right yeah
 	
 	
 		and back to news flash from our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">high school</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> we have one <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">high school</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> and they had to evacuate it because the furnace was acting up and was threatening to blow up
 	
 	
 		oh is that right i bet the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> were happy
 	
 	
 		yeah they i think they were
 	
 	
 		yeah well we had uh i don't know if your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> told you but we had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> and now we just have the one
 	
 	
 		we saw it on TV before he told us
 	
 	
 		oh okay so that'll probably make a difference in the reporting
 	
 	
 		yeah does uh how much does your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> cost
 	
 	
 		they are um on the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekends</TIMEX> gosh um let me see i've got this on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> it's a dollar
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX> i'm not really sure how much it is it's probably i guess you know seventy <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five cents</NUMEX> or so i would think
 	
 	
 		um-hum ours is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">eight dollars</NUMEX> a month so how would that figure up with what you'd do
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		but you get it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> don't you oh so that's that's really good then
 	
 	
 		yes
 		yes it's kind of a  skinny <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> except when the ads you know like at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas time</TIMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thanksgiving</TIMEX> or
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		so it's uh but we i enjoy it i'd hate to be without a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> and then we get the local you know the little <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brigham City</ENAMEX> one it's uh comes once a week
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah that must uh do you have a hard time keeping up with it
 		reading everything
 	
 	
 		keep
 		no
 	
 	
 		oh well that's good
 	
 	
 		no but
 		
 		
 	