
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		what i like in a good job is i like good salary but also i think they should have insurance benefits and profit sharing and
 		retirement funds like that so that you can plan for the future and they don't do that any more like they used to in the big companies
 	
 	
 		well i i i agree with what you say and of course uh
 		in addition to what you mentioned uh you know i'd like to see them have some uh have more <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> have like dental care
 	
 	
 		yes uh-huh
 	
 	
 		and uh
 	
 	
 		medical and dental
 	
 	
 		yeah and more benefits for uh working <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> uh
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		i noticed here lately there's some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> have been providing what they kind of call an in-house day care <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> can come and leave their uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> with somebody locally at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> and go to work and if something happens they're immediately there
 	
 	
 		that's great
 		oh wouldn't that be great
 	
 	
 		yeah i have a couple of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teenagers</ENAMEX> i have a couple of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX> uh one of which is married and has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two two</NUMEX> small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they stay in a day care and and they have a lot of sickness because they're around the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		and it would be so nice if uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> she worked for provided that uh you know in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> or or nearby or
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		now there is there is one benefit that uh is uh offered now um where they pay
 		they pay they pay for hospitalization
 		uh with funds uh before income tax funds uh before with funds that are not taxed
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		but i think that's more or less kind of in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> insurance field
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so that's a new innovation too for a benefit
 	
 	
 		well that in-house day care is excellent they could go on their <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">lunch hour</TIMEX> and see their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> or any time
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah that's true
 		and uh let's see what other benefits do you have any others uh that you'd like to see
 		how about uh
 	
 	
 		well i the profit sharing and the retirement they just don't offer those like they used to
 	
 	
 		yeah in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the old days</TIMEX> of course they didn't have any any benefits at all they preached job security but that that went out fast
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh it didn't that's right
 	
 	
 		and uh so now days i guess funding takes part or rather uh
 		uh your benefits are locked in after you're there with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX> but the benefits are so small
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and usually they're tied in with social security
 		and uh it
 	
 	
 		most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> retire on social security now that's all they have
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right and uh so uh even if you have benefits and you and then when you get to social security age they're not as great because they're tied in to social security benefits so you don't get both of them in full
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so it's hard <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> to live off of social security if you don't have your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> paid for
 	
 	
 		that's right that's right
 	
 	
 		so uh
 	
 	
 		that's what my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> did they're just living on social security
 		they had  <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> and they were trying to buy sell <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to pay off the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and
 		oh they waited for like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four or five years</TIMEX> trying to  sell that one house
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so they could pay off the other one because they're just living on social security they had a real hard time
 	
 	
 		i see
 	
 	
 		yeah you got to have your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> paid for
 	
 	
 		well you know uh benefits uh
 		are great and uh the more that a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> can provide the better off we are but it's so hard now for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> to make a profit as you no doubt uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		know you know most of our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> uh are losing their shirt
 	
 	
 		that's right that's right
 	
 	
 		going bankrupt and uh so some kind of system has to be devised were more  more competitive perhaps we've uh uh
 		been uh we were too used to off time and all these benefits that are not uh taking care of us in our old age but we're getting immediate effect of them like for example like <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">seven hour</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> and
 		and uh when in effect while we're young we ought to be working harder and come up with better benefits so that when we get older we have the uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we we have those benefits available to us in in a need that would make it easy for us in retirement
 	
 	
 		yeah they don't have to work so hard
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh you know social security again most of the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> are paying in they don't have any any they don't believe that anything will be left over
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		when they get to retirement age
 		course the old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> never gets out you know
 	
 	
 		i heard that all my life there wasn't going to be any when i was on it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> and uh so uh
 	
 	
 		or when i got on it
 	
 	
 		i guess uh we can make our dollar go lower and lower and lower until you get to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX> and then everybody can say okay nobody has anything and start over again
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well the insurance that's that's the main thing that i worry about is the insurance
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		insurance costs are going up
 	
 	
 		well and they and they just
 		
 		
 	