
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		okay
 	
 	
 		okay uh so what do you think about the school system
 	
 	
 		well i think they're they're having a lot of trouble right now i know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> goes to a private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> but uh
 		i think they're big <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> by definition are having a a tough time right now just from uh probably from budget cuts and and everything else going on
 	
 	
 		uh why why did you choose a private school
 	
 	
 		well i had one that was needed to be able to be moved along
 		at a at a pace a little faster than he was gonna be able to moved be moved in public school so  he's he has been going to private since kindergarten  so
 	
 	
 		public school
 		oh has he and how does he like it
 	
 	
 		oh he's loved it he's a senior in high school <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> so he's  yeah he's done it the whole twelve and a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">so many years</TIMEX> and it's been uh it's been really good for him
 	
 	
 		so he's been there all time
 		how big of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> is it
 	
 	
 		uh overall on campus <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about twelve hundred</NUMEX> but in the upper school upper <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> grades uh <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about four hundred</NUMEX> and something so it's maybe <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred</NUMEX> per grade
 	
 	
 		a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundred</NUMEX> per grade that's a good size
 	
 	
 		yeah it really is
 	
 	
 		kind of gives them the  you know like  get a little leery of the real small ones  that they don't get much interaction with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> but uh
 	
 	
 		yeah that was  we were kind of looking for one that would be a mixture and
 	
 	
 		so they don't that's good
 	
 	
 		he's done he's done really well and just he was just
 		ahead at an early age and i didn't feel like uh in what was available particularly in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> grades
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and even in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> grade when they started what they called reach was still a pull out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> program
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		and i just didn't think that was gonna get it i thought he needed to be exposed to a situation where he could push ahead uh everyday
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but yet still be with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peers</ENAMEX> age wise
 	
 	
 		still enjoy the  right um one thing i think i've noticed is uh my my oldest is in kindergarten so i'm in a little different ballgame i'm just starting i
 	
 	
 		you're just getting started
 	
 	
 		but uh seems to me that uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> uh
 		can really get away with murder and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> don't have as much aren't respected as much and uh they have to be some careful of the things they do and say
 	
 	
 		yeah i know that's that's a big problem
 	
 	
 		and uh makes me a little nervous that uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> don't seem to show that respect and
 	
 	
 		we wouldn't have thought of crossing a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> when we were in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> wouldn't have thought of it and you know and they'll stand there now with them toe to toe and
 	
 	
 		no heavens no
 		no you wouldn't
 		and uh the things they can say and do to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> and they do from what i understand
 		uh i think that's wrong
 		i think we need to
 		get back to the  show some respect and course i guess the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> used to warrant that but
 	
 	
 		yeah but a lot of times it's not being taught in the home anymore like it used to be basic respect for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elders</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> particularly in in responsible positions  have not uh
 	
 	
 		right
 		for other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		i don't think it's  had that basic  upbringing in a lot of cases and so then you wind up with little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brats</ENAMEX> on your hands
 	
 	
 		well how do you think that's happened you think our society's just uh stopped talking out or this uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX>'s just kind of changed a little bit uh
 	
 	
 		i guess i
 		well the world changes so i mean obviously <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are not the same now as they used to be i mean they're exposed to a whole lot more things they have a whole lot more
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh variety of things that they're that they see and do at an earlier age so life is not maybe as simple as it was at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time but
 		but still i think it goes back to a commitment
 		by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> to to teach uh basic values and basic uh
 		respectful of uh respectfulness of authority
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and i just don't think that this doesn't always get emphasized anymore uh
 	
 	
 		that just isn't coming through is it
 		no i mean i remember uh
 		well it was a big thing when they let <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> wear <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Levi</ENAMEX>'s we used to have to wear dresses and then you had to uh go to dresses they had to be a pantsuit and it was polyester and it had to be matching and
 	
 	
 		yeah had to wear dresses didn't you
 		and when it was skirts it was like get down on the floor and we hold the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ruler</ENAMEX> up here and it's no more than so many <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">inches</NUMEX> above the knee  because it was mini skirt time back there at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time
 	
 	
 		yes exactly
 		yes
 		yes so it's really changed it's uh
 		really kind of
 		gone the rounds so i think think that maybe that's effected it to some degree they say you kind of act how you're dressed a little bit  so i
 	
 	
 		yeah i think that probably does have have something to do with it that it's also
 	
 	
 		do uh does does this school your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> goes to do they uh required required to wear a uniform or
 	
 	
 		no they do not do uniforms although one's where he was between like <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">eighth</NUMEX> grade did
 	
 	
 		uh-huh yeah there are quite a few of your schools
 		
 		
 	