
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		do you have any thoughts on uh uh uh our jury system
 	
 	
 		yeah actually i i have quite a few thoughts on it before i became a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> i was going to law school because i wanted to change how our law system right now is working
 	
 	
 		oh really
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because it's not
 		it's not working correctly
 	
 	
 		what parts of the of the system would you change
 	
 	
 		well i mean when they pick like when they pick a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> they're supposed to have an equal or almost equal number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> to get different viewpoints and they don't have that because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> can't appear in court because they have take care of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 		right
 		sure yeah and
 	
 	
 		so they they end up having an all male jury
 	
 	
 		right does the system not provide the system provides uh compensation for wages but they don't provide compensation for like say day care
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		they don't
 	
 	
 		no they don't
 	
 	
 		oh i'm that surprises me i didn't know that
 	
 	
 		and a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> have to cancel their appearance and tell the judge hey i can't i've got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two or three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> at home that need me you know
 	
 	
 		sure yeah
 	
 	
 		and all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> can do is say oh okay you're excused
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		there's nothing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> can do about it because there's no law that says you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> has to help them with day care so he you know they don't bother
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">juries</ENAMEX> if if anybody did a study of most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">juries</ENAMEX> they'd see that it's almost always an all male <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> can't leave their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		sure yeah
 	
 	
 		and if they do get a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> on the jury she is beyond the age of fifty
 	
 	
 		huh
 		that's curious i i i never even thought of that uh before um i i i did notice that uh most of the time the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">juries</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">males</ENAMEX> and  uh but i'd never thought of any reasons why or why not
 	
 	
 		well i wanted to go to law school mainly for the purpose that if i was doing something in the legal profession i thought maybe if enough <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> knew about the problem maybe we could do something about it but then of course i got married and became a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		it's kind of taking a back burner right now but i'm i still intend to finish law school i've got <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> left
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		where where did you begin
 	
 	
 		over in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX> A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S U</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> a okay all right
 	
 	
 		but i
 		i just don't think it's very fair
 	
 	
 		right yeah
 	
 	
 		because they say well it's all equal and you know we send papers to this many women yeah but how many do you actually pick because they can appear
 	
 	
 		right right yeah
 		um uh what are your thoughts on uh leaving the sentencing to the judge
 	
 	
 		i don't think that's right
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i mean
 		most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> that would be fine because they're pretty open minded
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but if someone accidentally got a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> that wasn't and there are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> out there that are racist or prejudiced <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about one</NUMEX> thing or another
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> could be convicted just because of personal feelings and i don't think that's right
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		i think they need more views than just one
 	
 	
 		right
 		that that that that's curious uh i'm  i'm currently uh i have been asked to appear in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Denver County</ENAMEX> Court uh uh for uh
 		a traffic violation which i kept uh uh i i tried to uh plead not guilty by mail and uh
 		for some reason i really uh hacked the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> off and so now i'm supposed to appear uh in court uh and and so i've been thinking a lot lately about uh
 		<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of all what i'm gonna do i don't know if i'm going to uh just go ahead and pay the ticket now pay the plea bargain or or fight this thing to the end i i wasn't guilty and
 		uh but it's almost impossible uh you you know what what really aggravates me is it's impossible it's impossible i'm in graduate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and they set the court date on a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> so to go from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Denver</ENAMEX> uh to fight a ticket
 		on a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> would mean i'd have to leave either <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> and be back yeah and i go to school that misses <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a full week</TIMEX> of graduate school well you just can't survive uh missing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a full week</TIMEX> of graduate school uh
 	
 	
 		and you'd miss school
 		oh yeah no kidding
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX>  and uh it's it's completely absurd <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of all that i that i got the ticket and it's completely absurd that i should appear on a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> at court you know i could appear at Spring Break uh you know theoretically and and i wouldn't mind doing that but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so i'm trying to figure out what uh what action i'm going to take if any or if i'm just gonna go ahead and
 		forget it all and just pay it to to ease my uh ease my pain  but but you know it there there's a point uh  i guess you and i being younger uh tend to be a little more idealistic uh
 		uh but but i see uh
 		i i definitely see a an instance now where maybe i won't be as idealistic where where i would be able a uh willing to give up my ideals for uh
 		a little peace of mind and get them off my back which which is new to me i'd never been that way before
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well  a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of mine got in really
 		
 		
 	