
 
     		
 	
 		set
 	
 	
 		
 
 		okay
 	
 	
 		you you got the topic right okay um well where in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> are you
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Richardson</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh okay so you do recycling do recycling there okay
 	
 	
 		yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richardson</ENAMEX> has um well they have a newspaper pick up once a week supposedly if it's not raining
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they also have a couple of areas where you can take uh cans <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">plastic</ENAMEX> and paper to uh you know dump them off there if you don't uh want to wait and have a pick up least of paper but they don't pick up the other items they don't pick up cans or the plastic
 	
 	
 		um-hum are they going to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later</TIMEX> or do you know
 	
 	
 		i'm not sure they only started to do the newspaper uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late last year</TIMEX> just try like a trial basis and see how it goes so i don't know if they're going to pick up the other things
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		hm well i'm i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> proper in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> and i know they do have you know a pilot program going on but it's not here
 	
 	
 		what about you
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		um
 	
 	
 		so they're not picking up anything  so i mean we we collect everything we've got all these boxes in our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">garage</ENAMEX> for you know green <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glass</ENAMEX> and clear glass and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">plastic</ENAMEX> and everything
 	
 	
 		oh
 		where do you take them
 	
 	
 		but um well there's there's a couple places unfortunately we can't find a place that'll take everything
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		um there's a lot of places to take like the plastic um shopping bags like most of the grocery <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> and there's a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wal-Mart</ENAMEX> nearby that takes almost everything i can't remember what it is they don't take
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		hm
 	
 	
 		and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> will take <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glass</ENAMEX> so we end up you know on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX> we pack it all in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and and as we go places we oh wait we can drop the glass off  you know drop things off <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> at a time
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh
 	
 	
 		but um and it's kind of disappointing i mean i would even be happy if they just had one you know one place where you could do everything you know it would still be more convenient than what we have now
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> i think used to take a lot of the stuff to a recycling <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> that was for the benefit of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dallas Shelter</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		hm where is that
 	
 	
 		i think that was closer to downtown uh she's not here anymore but uh yeah
 	
 	
 		oh i'm pretty far north i'm not
 		i'm i'm i'm just i'm north of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Addison</ENAMEX> actually
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		so i'm i'm really  i'm sort i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> but only technically
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well sometimes we take our uh we we always keep our <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">aluminum</ENAMEX> cans  and a lot of times they take them over to one of these can banks
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh yeah</ENAMEX>
 		yeah i've seen those
 	
 	
 		you don't get too much money back i figure it pays for the gas to take my cans over there but normally i collect oh like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> trash bags full
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yep
 	
 	
 		and i take them over to that can bank and it's more fun just to kind of like crunch the cans  in the can bank you don't get too much money for them but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		well you get something
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh we used to do that but again that's another stop and it doesn't take plastic bags and and all that sort of thing but um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i think that you know i heard that it was going well in the pilot area wherever that is and so hopefully they'll do it soon that would be good because we have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> trash pick ups a week
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		where i grew up we only had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> and that was certainly sufficient so if they just do one of them will be trash and the alternate time would do recyclables that'd be great
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		so i hope they do
 	
 	
 		ah i'm disappointed sometimes they're not always consistent in picking up those papers you know i seem to put them out there on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> and like sometimes they come by
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		sometimes they don't i'm not really sure why they're not always consistent in that
 	
 	
 		oh
 		hm
 	
 	
 		but i could certainly have uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> bins out there for you know plastic and and tin and paper whatever they were going to uh separate into and and have them pick it up on on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two days</TIMEX> per <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX> that would be easy
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah do you have to um sort the paper and take out the glossy pages and that that sort of thing or do they take the whole thing
 	
 	
 		you're not supposed to have like the coupons in there
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		um or you're not supposed to put <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> in there and you can't take <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> now at work
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh you know we have changed our recycling at <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> they were kind of finicky about what kind of paper you could recycle
 		and not too long ago they finally decided if it's anything that's paper and tears you can throw it in there because at <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> they said
 	
 	
 		let me guess you work at <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> right
 	
 	
 		yeah at <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> they said they said no telephone books
 	
 	
 		so do i
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know that well that's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stupid</ENAMEX> and then they said no newspapers well in the my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> everybody gets the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i know
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		there was like a lot of paper coming out of our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> that wasn't recyclable so i thought that was pretty good to expand upon it and say anything paper
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well they and they take cans now too which is great
 	
 	
 		yeah i still put my cans in with the cans i think i don't want it with paper somehow it just seems weird to me
 	
 	
 		well our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> used to collect the cans anyway for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the Christmas</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX> project
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and in fact we got <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this past year</TIMEX> we got all of our money for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the Christmas</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX> because we saved cans for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the entire year</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and it worked out really well
 	
 	
 		well we had the the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who used to take things to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> Shelter i think that's what that was called
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		she collected she used to collect from the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> but she took them all down to that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dallas Shelter</ENAMEX> place
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i wish i could remember that whole name of that place but it's a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">charity</ENAMEX> for the benefit of this shelter
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh yeah she used she used to collect them from everybody in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> she'd go up and down with her little bag  collecting from everybody
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yep yep because we would get it
 		
 		
 	