
 
     		
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		okay where have  you been on vacations
 	
 	
 		well i've been to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe uh England</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> uh specifically i like those
 	
 	
 		oh wow
 		international huh
 	
 	
 		but uh my favorite things to do i think are going skiing in the winter <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah Colorado</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">uh et</ENAMEX> cetera
 	
 	
 		oh great so when you went to uh you know to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> and did you go on was that a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> trip or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> different trips
 	
 	
 		that was a single about a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten day</TIMEX> swing through uh maybe <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 		uh-huh how did you like that was that too fast oh was it oh uh-huh
 	
 	
 		it was great yeah because i had my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> with me uh my <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixteen year old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> and so uh it was it was a good experience for him to see some of the things he had studied and so forth
 	
 	
 		boy i'll say
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> now was that before um before the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Germanies</ENAMEX> were when they were separate or
 	
 	
 		no it was a it was well yeah it was as it was happening actually
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		was it really oh wow
 	
 	
 		kind of uh it was it was pretty close to that time but
 	
 	
 		you were there right while history was taking place
 	
 	
 		but we weren't over in that part of the world so it wasn't really uh something that we
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		got a lot of of input into but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh
 	
 	
 		how about yourself where do where do you like to go to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">vacation</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		well uh we take our vacations we mostly go camping in the mountains we live in a little mountain <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> and um
 		even when i was growing up though we would go to places like oh <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Redfish Lake</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Idaho</ENAMEX> and um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Island Park</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Idaho</ENAMEX> different places like that i have been to uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and i have been different places like to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney World</ENAMEX> and
 		i'm not a real big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> for flying  i just as soon would would travel you know on the ground um
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 		you get some great camping areas in your
 	
 	
 		we do we do
 	
 	
 		area there close i'm a i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boy Scout</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> so i'm out backpacking camping quite a bit too and
 	
 	
 		oh boy i'll say you probably are
 	
 	
 		i've done uh mountains in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Mexico</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> but i never have gotten up into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Idaho</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wyoming</ENAMEX> and and those parts of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> that are so pretty and
 	
 	
 		oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh there there are there're some gorgeous places have you you've never been to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tetons</ENAMEX> or
 	
 	
 		no i would like to
 	
 	
 		any of those spots oh it is nice now when you go skiing do you you fly here i imagine no
 	
 	
 		um-hum yeah you either fly into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Denver</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Salt Lake</ENAMEX> or somewhere and then rent a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and go the rest of the way
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh and do you enjoy that
 	
 	
 		yes yeah in fact
 	
 	
 		do you come alone or with your
 	
 	
 		usually with uh just whoever uh uh the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> is going skiing i'm taking my my whole <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> in uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Crested Butte</ENAMEX> and then uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh
 		oh
 	
 	
 		in a week mom and i agreed to chaperon my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>'s school trip to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vale</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about fifty five</NUMEX> young people
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh
 		oh wow  i'm oh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> you will have your your hands full how long is that gonna be for
 	
 	
 		and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX>  so i'm in
 		uh
 		that'll be uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five days in March</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh huh
 	
 	
 		but uh sometimes i've taken my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl friend</ENAMEX> and gone last <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last winter</TIMEX> i did that and so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh well how fun now when you went abroad did you was it a package plan or did you plan it yourself or
 	
 	
 		planned it myself and uh arranged for a private uh <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">residence</ENAMEX> in um <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> through a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> that we knew that had a flat there
 	
 	
 		oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then uh the travel <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> downstairs helped me with uh a lodging place in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and then we  kind of booked some other things on our own that was so it was sort of a piece meal thing
 	
 	
 		uh-huh oh well that did that work out good would you do that again
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah i think so it depend depend on where i was going i had good inside information about where i was headed and so i knew uh kind of what i was getting into but if
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh
 		what
 	
 	
 		if i were to strike out to a part of the world i didn't know anything about i i might not do it all on my own
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		um-hum did you have places arranged that you wanted to see that you know on your schedule then
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah we kind of had a list going of things and we
 		did some trade-offs and we saw most of what we wanted to see uh uh we had a list of far more than we could possibly see so we kind of had to pick and choose a little bit
 	
 	
 		oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		had to cut decide what you really wanted to once you got there
 	
 	
 		yeah and uh sometimes you wound up staying longer at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> place and than another
 	
 	
 		oh well that's fun i um i can get tickets airline tickets through my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> and uh
 		he's a pilot and so we take a few but <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekend</TIMEX> type jaunts to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> and and different places around and that's fun too that's a good little vacation they say
 		you know just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple days</TIMEX> getting away it makes means a lot it
 	
 	
 		oh sure
 		but if you don't like to fly then
 	
 	
 		i don't but i am getting better  used to be i'd i'd almost couldn't
 	
 	
 		you're uh
 	
 	
 		you know bring myself to stay on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> but but now i'm getting better  so huh any other vacations you wanted to talk about or
 	
 	
 		well uh i <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> place i haven't done is go somewhere like a cruise in in a warm climate or or down into a tropical place for a beach <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">vacation</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 		
 		
 	