
 
     		
 	
 		the most  the interesting political development of the whole year and everything that's been happening in the former <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> with the break up and the reconstitution
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah i agree i been interesting to see how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gorbachev</ENAMEX> has uh been releasing the power to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> including including the uh button for the nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arsenals</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well you've got to wonder what really happened in the so-called <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX> Coup who really planned that thing out who stood to benefit
 	
 	
 		yes uh i agree it's uh  that's some things that nobody may ever know for sure
 	
 	
 		oh well i suspect that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mister Yeltsin</ENAMEX> probably knows a lot more about it than he's ever let on
 	
 	
 		yeah he may but it'll be interesting to see how this sort of loose commonwealth uh
 		works from the standpoint of uh being as one political <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entity</ENAMEX> or whether it's really just going to be kind of a loose confederation
 	
 	
 		well
 		of course there's always the problem of the twelfth republic <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgia</ENAMEX> that's in a civil war right now what happens with them
 	
 	
 		also uh did uh did those <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Baltic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> did <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Astonia</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Latvia et</ENAMEX> cetera did they
 	
 	
 		no their no they they went <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all three</NUMEX> of those
 	
 	
 		pitch their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lot</ENAMEX> in with them or
 	
 	
 		Latvia <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Estonia</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lithuania</ENAMEX> went completely independent and had nothing to do with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">commonwealth</ENAMEX> of states
 		so they each <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> separate <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">republics</ENAMEX> although i think the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> of them have gone in together in some sort of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">confederation</ENAMEX> while they each are are supposedly independent
 	
 	
 		it may be interesting to see how when they start talking about border defense whether they're gonna i think most of those independent <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> are going to decide that they want to defend their own borders
 	
 	
 		well then what happens in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UN Russia</ENAMEX> supposedly gets the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX>'s seat and what happens with the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">republics</ENAMEX> i guess they don't get anything who knows
 	
 	
 		well  i think the
 		what <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s going to bid for is the seat on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Security Council</ENAMEX> but i suppose that all of the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> can or the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> others or however many there are can be admitted as regular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UN</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i don't know if these all are really independent <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">like</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> it almost looks likes some ways like the old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Confederate States of America</ENAMEX> is almost what this arrangement looks like
 	
 	
 		yeah could be it's gonna be
 	
 	
 		you've got uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> or twelve basically quote independent <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">republics</ENAMEX> which are in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">confederation</ENAMEX> does look a lot you know i think if we went back and looked at <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Civil War</ENAMEX> documents it'd be a similar arrangement to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Confederate States of America</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah could be  could be although they
 		a lot of those existed as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> prior to uh to their being a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> so i i don't know
 	
 	
 		well you have to look back to the great expansion of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter the Great</ENAMEX> followed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Catherine the Great</ENAMEX> uh which pretty well set the course for what then became the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX>
 		i mean it has its roots back there in the in the early <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seventeen hundreds</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true i don't know what uh currency things are going to be done too whether each <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> will have to completely establish a currency based on whatever system
 		or whether they can rely on the ruble somehow and uh
 		and uh
 	
 	
 		oh i think <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> put it aptly the ruble is rubbish
 	
 	
 		well that's true probably for any of them
 	
 	
 		course then the problem is what they do with their nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> that's the more interesting problem
 	
 	
 		well there's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> that have any though only the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ukraine</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Belorussia</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> themselves and then that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> middle <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> the one that starts with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K Konestan</ENAMEX> or something whatever that is
 		uh they're the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only four and two</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> have said they would like to destroy them
 		it's only that <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> one that worries me a little bit but they don't have any intercontinental ballistic <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX> down there either they have short range
 		nuclear capability and presumably not very many of them
 		judging by where that is
 	
 	
 		well who knows what they're going to do with them
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> had <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">ninety percent</NUMEX> of them on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> soil so they're still going to control the by and large the large amount of those
 	
 	
 		well of course the question is what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gorbachev</ENAMEX> does i guess he goes and writes his memoirs or something
 	
 	
 		he's been offered a position in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> to teach
 	
 	
 		i think he's turned that down now
 	
 	
 		yeah i imagine he would because he'd have to move over here lock stock and barrel and he's still got <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandchildren</ENAMEX> there in in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		well i don't think he i don't think he wants to do that but he he certainly would be like an elder statesman or whatever
 	
 	
 		well he certainly give lectures around the world if he wanted to do that on an informal basis he could also uh  like you say uh write a book probably be a best seller
 	
 	
 		or how i survived the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX> Coup but really didn't survive it
 	
 	
 		yeah well it's all been a outgrowth of what he started he started  uh
 		
 		
 	