
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay so what kind of books do you like to read
 	
 	
 		um i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sidney Sheldon</ENAMEX> is probably my favorite author
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> and so when i read for pleasure i read strictly for escape
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so i like you know i like books that are pretty high adventure and just real simple easy reading what about you
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		um i prefer my favorite types of books are um human interest type books biographies
 		um it can be fiction about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i like books that are about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that have historical you know that tell you something about the history at the same time you know or a certain area so
 	
 	
 		oh that's good that's good what book have you read that you really like
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		do you like about recent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in history
 	
 	
 		both either one yeah um i've read lots of books i really like let me think um  have you ever heard of a book called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Hiding Place</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		both
 		oh yes that's wonderful that's one of my favorite books that's really neat yeah i like books like that too
 	
 	
 		by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corrie Ten Boom</ENAMEX> yeah
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah that's a wonderful book that's funny you should mention that one
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah i like um i guess my preference is for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> biographies but i i'm interested in both you know because i you learn a lot from reading about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s lives and
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		um
 		so
 		yeah that's probably one of my all time favorites what what would you say is your favorite book that you've ever read
 	
 	
 		oh i don't know with all the hip and hype i still love Gone with the Wind i haven't gotten a copy of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scarlett</ENAMEX> yet but uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i'm sure i won't love it as much as Gone with the Wind but that's that's just a real masterpiece  um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i guess that really is my favorite book
 	
 	
 		yeah are you uh-huh
 		uh-huh i remember a long time ago i read some books by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Glen Bristol</ENAMEX> you ever read any
 	
 	
 		no i never have
 	
 	
 		yeah those um
 		i don't know why Gone with the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Wind</ENAMEX> made me think of that but those are books that are um like they some of them took place in
 		well there's one that took place in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgia</ENAMEX> and another that took place <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> yeah they're historically based fiction so they're
 	
 	
 		are they historically based
 		uh-huh i like historically based fiction
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		when um
 		oh all those books by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Jakes</ENAMEX> came out
 	
 	
 		uh-huh i i don't think i am i don't think i am but go ahead yeah
 	
 	
 		are you familiar with what i'm talking about there were like huh
 		oh it started with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Bastard</ENAMEX> and then it when it came over to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and took us through the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Revolutionary War and the Civil War</ENAMEX> i've forgotten what all of them were
 	
 	
 		oh yes uh-huh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they were right around the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Centennial year</TIMEX> though um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they were really
 		you know i really i i got into them and read i guess probably <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four or five</NUMEX> of them and then i got burned out and said oh i think i'm tired of this group i like ones that are families
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		like you read <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and then you read about the next generation and the following generation
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		yeah i'm
 	
 	
 		i think they also asked do you ever read books for self improvement
 	
 	
 		yeah that's right i do sometimes but um
 		they have to have illustrations or else i i get bored with them
 	
 	
 		what do you mean by illustrations
 	
 	
 		for for the most part i mean illustrations real examples you know instead of just giving me a sermon or giving me a you know how to type idea
 	
 	
 		right right
 		do you know what i hate i hate to read books by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">How to Raise Children</ENAMEX> and they're single
 	
 	
 		yeah  yeah see they have to have some real
 	
 	
 		you know  dealing with your teenager and they're never around <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> you know right
 	
 	
 		yeah some real examples from their own life that proves that they know what they're talking about i just read one called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">uh The Language of Love</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Smalley</ENAMEX> and someone else and that was really good yeah it's full of personal illustrations and illustrations of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> they'd work with their um psychologists
 	
 	
 		was it good
 		hm
 	
 	
 		so what about you what do you like to read for self-improvement
 	
 	
 		i don't know i  i really
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i get i i like i would rather read a book that's like for inspiration than a real self help book i mean
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		i don't know i don't get off on them just a whole lot i get bored real fast
 	
 	
 		yeah i guess i agree there
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		when i when my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> were younger i used to read books on how to raise <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and had nothing they said worked so i  i said enough of that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh dear yeah
 		uh-huh yeah so uh-huh
 	
 	
 		but i do like you know i like various and sundry kinds of books i like to read ones like by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Cosby</ENAMEX>  fun <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Erma Bombeck</ENAMEX> things of that type too
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh yeah with humor in them those are
 	
 	
 		yeah i love humor
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah those are good
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well i think that probably covers the topic
 	
 	
 		oh
 		yeah i think it probably does well
 	
 	
 		okay i've enjoyed talking to you
 	
 	
 		yeah i have too though good-bye have a good <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX> thank you bye-bye
 	
 	
 		okay uh you too bye-bye
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	