
 
     		
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh subject is gun control uh do you own any guns
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		uh besides a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a</NUMEX> a BB gun no um a lot of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> owns a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> and stuff and
 		i i have a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> that do also a lot of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> are really into <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> as far as knowing the specifications of every gun there is just about
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah i know the sort
 		i'm not much into <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> myself either i don't know i enjoy working with them from time to time but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um personal opinion there's a whole lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> available on the market that really shouldn't be available at all
 	
 	
 		yeah that's that's my opinion is that some of these high powered handguns need to go out the window because they're obviously not for hunting
 	
 	
 		um yeah they've got
 	
 	
 		and a handgun was never designed for hunting
 	
 	
 		well very few of them it they do make some for <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bird</ENAMEX> hunting but still those aren't real high powered they're just you know small caliber with a long barrel on them
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but uh no these and and these assault <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> with
 		real short stock short barrels and
 	
 	
 		yeah these these the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">the nine millimeter the nine millimeter</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Glock</ENAMEX> to to top the charts
 	
 	
 		armor piercing ammunition
 	
 	
 		it's a it's a plastic automatic <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapon</ENAMEX> that fires
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		they sell them here at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wal-Mart</ENAMEX>
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> different models of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Glock</ENAMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wal-Mart</ENAMEX>
 		wow wow
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wal-Mart</ENAMEX> sporting goods <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> here in town carries carries the Glock
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		they haven't got the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the latest</TIMEX> version but uh they've got them
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		something like seventeen rounds in a double wide clip
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seventeen seventeen</NUMEX> rounds of clip that fires by itself
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">craziness</ENAMEX> like that
 		practically yeah
 	
 	
 		did did you hear about the the killing spree in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Colleen</ENAMEX> over here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no no i didn't
 	
 	
 		we had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> that went through a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Luby's</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Colleen</ENAMEX> and like killed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">twenty three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and injured <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred</NUMEX> plus others
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Luby</ENAMEX>'s
 	
 	
 		and then killed himself
 	
 	
 		what's a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Luby</ENAMEX>'s
 	
 	
 		uh it's a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cafeteria</ENAMEX> or restaurant
 	
 	
 		oh wait yeah uh uh that's been <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several months</TIMEX> ago
 	
 	
 		yeah <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several several months ago</TIMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		okay yeah i did hear about that
 		and they weren't the least bit sure what happened what what set him off
 	
 	
 		that's
 		that's what well nobody really knows what it was it was they determined that it was a a series of events over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> of some sort form of hatred of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and that's why he was mostly shooting women
 	
 	
 		oh see i hadn't heard anything about you know what the bulk of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> were but
 	
 	
 		uh he was just a wacko
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but that shows you what a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a</NUMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Glock</ENAMEX> automatic <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapon</ENAMEX> will do
 	
 	
 		that's what he was using
 	
 	
 		yeah he had that and uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> other <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> which i don't recall what it was
 	
 	
 		was it a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">rifle</ENAMEX> or a pistol
 	
 	
 		but
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Glock</ENAMEX> oh the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> it was another handgun
 	
 	
 		no no the the other gun
 		okay no i hadn't i i hadn't heard what it was he was carrying all i knew is he'd been in there shooting i hadn't heard any about what he was carrying
 	
 	
 		yeah it was that's what it was he went around putting holes in anything he wanted to at whatever rate of speed he felt like
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah i do know they have uh fast uh fast recovery
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh goodness
 		well uh they
 	
 	
 		i i i also agree with the uh the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven day</TIMEX> wait on handguns that's a
 	
 	
 		yeah probably ought to be longer than that really
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> is probably as long as you can expect the law to to require
 	
 	
 		yeah at at the moment they want <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven days</TIMEX> and that's you know that's the best thing we got to work with go for it
 	
 	
 		yeah <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven day</TIMEX> wait waiting period and the check through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> files and
 	
 	
 		yeah because i i really can't understand why these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">legislatures</ENAMEX> wanna fight it unless they just don't have anything better to do
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		they ought to carry they ought anybody with a permit to carry a gun uh you ought to have a permit for any kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> you carry period
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		whether it's <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pistol</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">rifle</ENAMEX> or it doesn't matter and the permit
 		you ought a ought to be required to keep it in your billfold at all times whether you got your <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> with you or not like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX>'s license
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		you should have a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a</NUMEX> a permit to use it and a uh be trained on how to use it
 	
 	
 		yeah uh it's part of the problem with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> in general they got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> out there you know the only experience they got is the you know the last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">couple</NUMEX> times they got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about half</NUMEX> looped and went out and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> and went out in the woods and started blowing up bottles
 	
 	
 		yep
 	
 	
 		every hunting season scares the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">stew</ENAMEX> out of me even just to drive by a section of woods bothers me a little bit because i know there's maniacs out there <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first couple of days</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		um yeah
 		my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> has borrowed a uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty thirty</TIMEX> from uh
 		his uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nephew</ENAMEX> and is supposed to go hunting and i i'm really really kind of nervous about it myself because i don't want him to
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		go out there and get hurt
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hm</ENAMEX> later on in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the season</TIMEX> it gets to be less of a problem especially
 		
 		
 	