
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		what kind of movies have you been seeing lately
 	
 	
 		uh  it's been probably
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month or so</TIMEX> since i've been to the movies uh
 		course my my favorite now is is <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dances With Wolves</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh it's an excellent movie
 	
 	
 		uh
 		Silence of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lan</ENAMEX> uh of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lambs</ENAMEX> was good
 	
 	
 		Silence of the Lambs
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		what was that anyway because i didn't get a chance to see it
 	
 	
 		oh it's a
 		i guess it's a mystery you'd call it it's with uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jodie Foster</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		and it uh
 		it's pretty good another one that i think i really liked was uh The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Fisher King</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		let's see who was in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Fisher King</ENAMEX>
 		that was um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin Williams</ENAMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and um i can't say the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fellow</ENAMEX>'s name
 	
 	
 		how about you what are you
 	
 	
 		uh we've not been having many opportunities to see movies lately um we really enjoyed um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dead Poet</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Society</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		um <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several years back</TIMEX> when we saw uh we saw the we really really enjoyed was uh Ordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">People</ENAMEX>
 		with um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Timothy Hutton</ENAMEX> and uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Tyler Moore</ENAMEX> and uh
 		uh who played the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> anyway excellent movie
 	
 	
 		right that was that was an excellent movie have you seen <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dances With Wolves</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes we have
 	
 	
 		that what'd you think of it
 	
 	
 		oh we loved it
 	
 	
 		i don't think i can see it enough times
 	
 	
 		i know what you mean i know what you mean
 	
 	
 		course i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Costner</ENAMEX> fan
 	
 	
 		yeah um pretty impressed with stuff he's done uh he made kind of an odd sounding <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin Hood</ENAMEX> but uh
 		i mean you know basic  thick western <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> accent for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin Hood</ENAMEX> just doesn't seem to fit
 		but
 	
 	
 		no but you know it wasn't bad movie it got such bad reviews really and and i thoroughly enjoyed it but i then i wasn't expecting any classic either
 	
 	
 		oh no it was a good movie
 		well um they did a real good job with it
 	
 	
 		i thought so
 	
 	
 		um they didn't try to make him super human or you know invincible
 		they just
 		he worked hard at it
 		
 
 	
 	
 		have you seen The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Fisher King</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no i haven't not had the opportunity to see that uh
 	
 	
 		uh it you
 		you know i guess it it really isn't for everybody it's it's pretty deep and and uh
 		uh philosophical
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but i thought it had a wonderful message to it it's kind you came out
 		and looked at somebody says you know i think i liked that  and then the more you got to thinking about it the more you thought you know i did like it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but when you first came out you weren't real sure
 	
 	
 		it sounds kind of like one uh we saw at home here on the we rented it um <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Clara</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heart</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		haven't seen that
 	
 	
 		um it's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Whoopi Goldberg</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yes i did yes i did
 	
 	
 		yeah she played a uh
 		they um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> nanny the nanny type
 	
 	
 		she was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">housekeeper</ENAMEX> yeah she's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">housekeeper</ENAMEX> she
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">housekeeper uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		she was um
 		oh no i can't say it not Haitian
 		anyway
 		she uh
 		she seemed to be that sort of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> that you know about seems <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> crazy but then again she's got a whole lot on the ball and the movie had the whole uh a lot of philosophical content more than
 		more than you know it it wasn't a mystery it wasn't a you know <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> and guts and violence and and and car chases type thing
 		it was just a good movie
 	
 	
 		i saw <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX> that was A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Kiss Before Dying</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Kiss Before Dying</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um-hum i had not heard about it when it was on the movies but was out on video
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and it's with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sean Young</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and it's a it's a mystery it was very predictable i mean you knew you knew when the murder was gonna happen or something but it was still so well done
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		that it was enjoyable
 	
 	
 		that's that takes a good bit to make one that's predictable but still worth watching
 	
 	
 		that's right  i had uh
 		oh uh i like the
 		i think it's called the uh
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Razor</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Edge</ENAMEX>
 		the
 		no no the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Jagged Edge the Jagged Edge</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		not familiar with that one
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		with uh
 		
 		
 	