
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		think the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cowboys</ENAMEX> are gonna go further or is this the end of the line
 	
 	
 		no i think the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cowboys</ENAMEX> have a good chance to really um
 		possibly take it all the way they're one of the they're one of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> that actually beat <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> Redskins
 		ah however <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> has been uh
 		what do you call it has been resting up
 		and uh that could really hurt the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cowboys</ENAMEX> especially if they have a lot of injuries coming into uh  the next <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> games
 	
 	
 		well there was a uh article in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX>
 		oh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple weeks ago</TIMEX> before the play-offs started and it said their long shot prediction was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cowboys</ENAMEX> versus <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oilers</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Super Bowl</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		then they gave their reasons why they thought both of those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> had a
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		had a decent chance at it
 	
 	
 		well uh that would be an interesting game i think that game would be sold out what do you think
 	
 	
 		yeah i don't think there'd be any problem there the only question is would the rest of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> be interested in watching <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> slug it out
 	
 	
 		yes i think so because uh i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren Moon</ENAMEX> and uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Beuerlein</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Troy Aikman</ENAMEX> are some of the hottest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">quarterbacks</ENAMEX> for the uh for the nineteen nineties
 	
 	
 		yeah they'll probably want to see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emmett Smith</ENAMEX> and uh and uh see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Novacek</ENAMEX> and see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Irwin</ENAMEX> out there and and the no name defense so who knows
 	
 	
 		yeah the no name defense that's pretty good
 	
 	
 		well and then <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX>'s got a a good core of about good <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> good receivers out there that uh that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moon</ENAMEX> likes to likes to throw to
 	
 	
 		well did you see in the paper <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Sunday</TIMEX> about uh the salaries for the different um
 		uh players
 	
 	
 		yeah i sure did
 	
 	
 		well what do you think about uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Montana</ENAMEX> being paid so much for not playing this year
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well he he had himself a good contract
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		you know if he's got a contract that pays him regardless of injuries he's in good shape well you know that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Irvin</ENAMEX>'s going to get a big boost and already uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> has said that uh they anticipate that he'll be giving <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Irvin</ENAMEX> a big pay raise
 		so i think that'll be coming
 	
 	
 		sure
 		sure i think it will be too and i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Beuerlein</ENAMEX> might get a little raise too he's uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um Troy Aikman</ENAMEX> i wonder even though he's a real good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> i wonder if he's going to be able to uh stand the physical abuse that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NFL</ENAMEX> offers he might not make it
 	
 	
 		well his problem is that he since he doesn't seem as mobile as some of the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">quarterbacks</ENAMEX> he seems to get one bad injury <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> so <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beuerlein</ENAMEX> or someone like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beuerlein</ENAMEX> is going to be a necessity while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aikman</ENAMEX>'s around
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">yep</ENAMEX> so what do you think about uh the games that's going to be played uh tomorrow <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Buffalo</ENAMEX> and
 		who they playing the uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">uh Buffalo</ENAMEX>'s playing um <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kansas City</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kansas City</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chiefs</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well i i really think <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Buffalo</ENAMEX> will will win the game i'll be surprised if <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kansas City</ENAMEX> wins it
 		but uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston Denver</ENAMEX> um that one might be more even than than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would otherwise think i don't think that one's gonna be uh blow out for anybody it might be a pretty close game
 	
 	
 		yeah i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Elway</ENAMEX> still has a hot hand the trouble is is sometimes it's cold
 		and uh he's not consistent he he has <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a good day</TIMEX> he has a bad day
 	
 	
 		and you and you never know
 	
 	
 		um i like that these other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">quarterbacks</ENAMEX> that that are are more consistent i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beuerlein</ENAMEX> has been more consistent
 	
 	
 		well <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beuerlein</ENAMEX>'s only had interceptions in one of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> games he's played and although he isn't throwing that many passes or completing that many you know if you're completing them to the right <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> at the right time you've got a running game you don't have to throw fifty times
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know you know we're watching the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Bowl games</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> and there's some amazing <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Bowl</ENAMEX> games
 		some of those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX>'ll be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pros</ENAMEX> there's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fellow</ENAMEX> plays for my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s school <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Carolina</ENAMEX> named uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff Blake</ENAMEX> and he's gonna  almost surely be drafted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pros</ENAMEX> he had an incredible day yesterday
 	
 	
 		right
 		hm
 	
 	
 		he um threw for <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">four</NUMEX> touchdown passes and ran for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and
 		he had an amazing day he rallied the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> down from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seventeen</NUMEX> points in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the middle of the fourth quarter</TIMEX> to score <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> unanswered touchdowns in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">less than six minutes</TIMEX> it was an amazing performance
 	
 	
 		i missed the name who was that again
 	
 	
 		it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff Blake</ENAMEX> B L A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K E</ENAMEX> he's the quarterback <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Carolina</ENAMEX> he's pretty well rewritten the record books and i guess the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pros</ENAMEX> will pay a good attention to him
 	
 	
 		i didn't i didn't watch that game uh i did watch the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Notre Dame</ENAMEX> game
 	
 	
 		well they certainly came from behind to pull it off didn't they
 	
 	
 		yes i i think that um
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX> there is uh really made a name for himself with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX> now with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Notre Dame</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well both those games were the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only two</NUMEX> exciting <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Bowl games</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> i think the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> games were either blowouts or like the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cotton Bowl</ENAMEX> a disaster
 	
 	
 		yeah that was a low scoring game
 	
 	
 		but well it was it was a disaster a total disaster
 		well i don't i don't know about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Detroit</ENAMEX> they they've got a lot of injuries they may have beaten the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cowboys</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty four to</TIMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX>
 		
 		
 	