
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		do you have any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> twelve and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixteen</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">twelve</NUMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixteen</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		um-hum how about you
 	
 	
 		well i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> and uh they're <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> and nineteen months
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		so we kind of got a different ball game but uh
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		what uh
 		do you feel like you have anytime  to spend with them
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well
 	
 	
 		they're probably at an age where they don't wanna spend anytime with their <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">parents parents</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's true  you actually of course spend less time with them when they get older but it's of course still really important um
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 		right
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i have a kind of a fortunate situation i think right now with my <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixteen year old</TIMEX> um  i work <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two nights a week</TIMEX> at a i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">librarian</ENAMEX> and i work <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two nights a week</TIMEX> at the senior high school <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> they keep it open you know for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> to
 	
 	
 		oh uh-huh
 		
 
 	
 	
 		do their work and he um  and then they the school district <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hires</ENAMEX> an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX> you know to work for me well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> is my aide
 	
 	
 		right
 		sure
 		oh well that's nice
 	
 	
 		so <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two nights a week</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">four hours</TIMEX> we're stuck together  and there's usually not very much business i mean some <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nights</TIMEX> it's just real real quiet so
 	
 	
 		you're stuck together
 		no
 		i would suspect your <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nights</TIMEX> would be pretty quiet for the most part
 	
 	
 		yeah so we i have sort of a captive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> so i really do spend probably more time with him than than most you know but um of course i'm away from my other son <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">those hours</TIMEX> too but his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>'s at home
 	
 	
 		right
 		and so that kind of gives him uh time with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> then gives him a little bit of that individual time
 	
 	
 		pretty much that time
 		yeah that's true yeah
 		but but it is hard once they get that age i mean their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> are the most important thing there is
 	
 	
 		right and they want to be able to spend uh
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		well i've even noticed that with my <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five year old</TIMEX> she started kindergarten <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		everyday that she's not at school uh she thinks we need to have someone over and play
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and that kind of  yeah it's hard i think uh i find myself getting my little projects going and
 	
 	
 		yeah it's kind of hard
 	
 	
 		not taking the time that i should i'm more worried about oh i didn't get this done i didn't get the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen</ENAMEX> needs to be cleaned this needs to be done and and i need to remind
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		remind remind myself to slow down and it'll still be there <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX> but that's kind of hard to do you know you don't see yourself getting
 	
 	
 		right yeah that's true yes it is hard to do right yeah well if you're kind of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> that likes things you know organized or neat or you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		then i think it that it is hard it's um i think one of the nice things about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">holidays</TIMEX> is that you know it does give you the opportunity to spend more time
 	
 	
 		slow down a little bit um-hum
 	
 	
 		yeah with family we have we often go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> and we're not <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> and it's just really nice because we can do you know the things you want to do and
 	
 	
 		you can do a lot more than
 	
 	
 		yeah just yeah that's right
 	
 	
 		than when you travel this is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first year</TIMEX> we're staying home too and uh  i think it's going to be real quiet but uh that's an opportunity to
 		get out the games and
 	
 	
 		yeah right we usually do that my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> even have already gotten out um  my twelve <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year old</TIMEX> got out the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legos</ENAMEX> which of course he hasn't touched since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last summer</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 		of course of course
 	
 	
 		but you know but <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every now</TIMEX> and then i mean he's got a lot of those technical those hard kind you know and he wants to be an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineer</ENAMEX> so he still likes all that kind of building stuff and um we have the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">train</ENAMEX> and we haven't had that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lego</ENAMEX> train together for years
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		and um so he sat down and i told him i really wanted him to build the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">train</ENAMEX> and we would put it under the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX> and that i would keep it together i wouldn't take it apart
 	
 	
 		can't wouldn't take it apart  after that
 	
 	
 		yeah and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> i'd have the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lego</ENAMEX> train under the tree
 	
 	
 		that'd be kind of fun
 	
 	
 		and um so he worked on that for the longest time ever since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> was out on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> and um then his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixteen year</TIMEX> old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> started helping too you know so you know it was just kind of things like during the normal
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		rat race  those kinds of things never happen but um
 	
 	
 		right right
 		no no in fact in
 		i think if a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would learn to turn off the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TVs</ENAMEX> and  i think that's a lot of the breakdown of the communication
 	
 	
 		um-hum yeah
 		yes yeah
 	
 	
 		any communication that would take place in a family uh usually <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are ending up sitting in front of that
 	
 	
 		which is
 		um-hum and there's always a few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> that when they stare at it  you know they're totally turned off to everything else  the rest of
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yes  you can't communicate while you're doing that right
 	
 	
 		no that's right
 	
 	
 		whereas uh i'm the type of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> i could not sit sit still well i shouldn't say i could not but be very hard for me to sit down and watch a program all the way through without doing something
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah me too  yeah i don't watch very much of it at all even to to the extent that sometimes i feel almost embarrassed at work and stuff like that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are
 	
 	
 		
 
 		because they talk so much isn't that the
 	
 	
 		yeah they talk about TV shows and i'm huh you know don't you watch that you know  it's the best show on i go no   but
 	
 	
 		you're kind of like what what are you talking about and uh
 		you feel like you're a little bit out of it don't you
 		they need to have a highlight in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> or something tell us what's the
 		
 		
 	