
 
     		
 	
 		oh do you have very many family reunions that one you have over to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bear</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Lake</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX> of all of them isn't it
 	
 	
 		um
 		oh yeah now that one's a fun one that that is fun i know that sometimes i've the one that's been hard for me is the one that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Skidmores</ENAMEX> used to do at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> time
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and i i think its just because it was  i seem to always be bad weather and i'm just going over the
 	
 	
 		oh uh-huh
 	
 	
 		you know the yeah its just right after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> that one was kind of hard i think that was a hard time but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">mountains uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh they don't have that anymore
 	
 	
 		well they haven't since his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> died and i don't know if you know they they just continued it kind of while
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		she was still alive and
 		and uh just nobody's done anything about it since she passed away but i don't know i mean it was always nice but it was just kind of a hard time i think
 	
 	
 		uh-huh do you have any other reunions
 	
 	
 		yeah um yeah my my side of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> usually has let's see i went to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> at that was at my um actually it was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Layton</ENAMEX> and it was up my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">grandfather</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> where his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> had been raised a little bit of the time they've they've still got this old <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> in their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and that uh uh it was really a fun one that was nice to get to know a lot of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> though that we don't know and we just had a big
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um they had big grill that they cooked <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chicken</ENAMEX> and what'd they have <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chicken</ENAMEX> and i guess ribs and then they just did they had a little program and they made a quilt and gave it away
 	
 	
 		hum
 		they didn't auction it or anything
 	
 	
 		um well they they um i think they drew names is what they did
 	
 	
 		oh oh uh-huh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> well no they did auction it well <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> bought a ticket that's how they did it and then the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> with the winning ticket got it and things like that and that was kind of a fun one yeah
 	
 	
 		oh
 		with the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> up to the up to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bear</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Lake</ENAMEX> do you uh do anything like genealogy or or anything like that
 	
 	
 		no we just goof off  just play yeah
 	
 	
 		oh  uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> goes up to uh <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Cub River</ENAMEX> up to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willow Flat</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh uh-huh
 	
 	
 		for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three days every year</TIMEX> i mean it's there's not as much to do up as there is up at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bear</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Lake</ENAMEX> but we just go and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> out and wade in the river and
 	
 	
 		now now is that the same time of year
 	
 	
 		no that's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the fourth of July</TIMEX> one that we go down to the cabin
 	
 	
 		no
 		okay because i it's is that kind of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> reunion too yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh uh</ENAMEX>-huh yeah but but that's but the one that we go up to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bear</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Lake</ENAMEX> with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> is
 		the more more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> come it's my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> that go to that one
 	
 	
 		oh i see oh and
 	
 	
 		so but and then we have a great big <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> one about every other year that we make that we make a quilt and sell it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then we'll we'll sell chances on it and then that pays for all of the mailing and everything that's concerned with it yeah it does it works out really good
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh that's nice nice yeah
 		we have they've organized a um like a family i don't know just some family <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> on my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>'s side and we do we pay dues
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh uh-huh
 	
 	
 		i think <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> we just paid like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> dollars and and then they sent have started sending out a news letter on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and and um you know somebody's gone to a lot of work and they've they're doing a real good job and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so oh yeah  i'm not good at things like that so
 	
 	
 		just wait till it falls in your lap huh  neither am i but it's really important i think to keep those connections
 	
 	
 		it is it is and i know there's been a lot of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> we haven't gone and then when we do go it doesn't seem like we know anybody and so i think it is good to keep going and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and keep those family ties up
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		well i i don't know we've the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Waites</ENAMEX> had a reunion too but that that fell every other every other year but that fell through because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> just wouldn't take charge and do it
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		so and maybe there's a time to let go too
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah but that's that is kind of sad when uh nobody does want to do it yeah
 	
 	
 		i don't know i
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		but then <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> get involved in other things and involved in others you know but i think it's really important to keep the your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> and the earlier generation together
 	
 	
 		oh it is it is oh well and and so you just you have the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> on
 	
 	
 		so
 		
 
 	
 	
 		either side but you didn't have the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> is this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first year</TIMEX> you didn't have it on your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s side
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		we had a we had the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the the one the small one</TIMEX> and then for his too we have a great big <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> party <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh i see oh
 	
 	
 		and and then the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer one fourth</TIMEX> of around the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		huh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but the the i don't know they those are are just his immediate family
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		they're not extended it's not extended
 	
 	
 		
  
 		huh
 	
 	
 		is that say we have to quit
 	
 	
 		i don't know i've never  heard that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> before
 	
 	
 		
 
 		neither have i
 	
 	
 		you you say how many calls have you made
 		
 		
 	