
 
     		
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		um well i basically listen to um all kinds of music
 	
 	
 		like what
 	
 	
 		um
 		even you know from easy listening you know i just find that so relaxing um you know i like fall asleep to that um
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		i listen to uh
 		i listen to rock the only thing the only thing i don't like um is um hard rock do you like you don't like um  my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boyfriend</ENAMEX> listens to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guns</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Roses</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i don't like that either hm no
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i just you know i just can't um grasp that you know i just don't understand why he likes that um
 	
 	
 		well
 	
 	
 		i listen to the lyrics and i don't know
 	
 	
 		you don't wanna do that they're vulgar
 	
 	
 		yeah and you and you right you listen to the lyrics and un and and uh he even went to their concert and i'm like uh i don't know this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> he
 	
 	
 		um
 		did he go to the concert where they gave them about <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">fifteen minutes</TIMEX> and then left
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> with very they were like <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an hour and a half</TIMEX> late coming
 	
 	
 		no no they yeah they made them they made them wait <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">forever</TIMEX> and yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah that was a real rip  i have a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fifteen year old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>  and uh she has kind of mellowed over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> and so now she's liking <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> but there was a while there where she liked
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		Poison and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Motley Crue</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Guns and Roses</ENAMEX> you know that
 	
 	
 		to me that just scares me uh because he's he's not really like that i mean he doesn't you know he
 	
 	
 		uh well
 		no you know
 	
 	
 		he's not wild or anything but i just i don't know
 	
 	
 		well i like all kinds too i can kind of you know when my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> was into that i  kind of listened to  what she wanted to listen to and said well this isn't too bad because she never got into the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the really</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh well you're a you're a pretty cool <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> then my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> would've would've never gone for that
 	
 	
 		but i sing in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">choir</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> and i like you know that kind of thing even more
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> would've probably ripped the radio off the
 	
 	
 		no that won't that  not what one needs to do either  i mean you'll find a mess on your hands
 	
 	
 		out of the stereo if i'd have turned that on
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i i like i have season tickets to the opera hang on just a minute
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		oh okay  i have season tickets to the opera and i love that and i have season tickets to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> musicals and i love that so i have
 	
 	
 		what what is that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> musicals i've heard of it but i don't i'm not
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> musicals down at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">State the State Fair music</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hall</ENAMEX> down at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Fair Park</ENAMEX>  um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">musicals</ENAMEX> like uh well sometimes you go back to the old <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodgers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hammerstein</ENAMEX>'s of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX> and Carousel
 		Carousel uh <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South Pacific</ENAMEX> you know it's like <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">theater</ENAMEX> in singing
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		what what um
 		what um
 		what year was all that popular
 	
 	
 		oh dear it still is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every summer</TIMEX> they have they have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about six</NUMEX> shows
 	
 	
 		is it was it in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the sixties</TIMEX> that it was that it that uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hammerstein</ENAMEX> what did you say <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hammerstein</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		what
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodgers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hammerstein</ENAMEX>  oh dear they really was very very popular mainly in the fifties um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		fifties
 	
 	
 		your main <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> now are <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sondheim</ENAMEX> and uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Lloyd Webber</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Phantom of the Opera and Starlight Express Cats</ENAMEX>
 		um
 		and it's really become quite sophisticated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this summer</TIMEX> they had <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Grease</ENAMEX> and they had the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buddy Holly Story</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		um
 	
 	
 		and some really good stuff so i like a real variety
 		of  well musical
 	
 	
 		so it was just concerts or did they did they like oh they acted out the scene and oh
 	
 	
 		oh no they're stories they're like a play oh yeah they're like a they're like a play only most of it's sung
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they're they're wonderful  they're just wonderful there's a lot of dance to them
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		wonderful sets and costumes
 		just really good
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Les Miserables</ENAMEX> is a wonderful one it's based on uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Victor Hugo</ENAMEX>'s  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Les Miserables</ENAMEX>
 		which takes place in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> during it's not really during the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">French Revolution</ENAMEX> it's pre <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> revolutionary <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> but
 		talks about you know the poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and them rebelling and the the music is just  unbelievable it's just
 		almost operatic in style  it's really wonderful it it's very different but very wonderful ooh good stuff
 	
 	
 		sounds really different you know from what we've got
 		do you listen to country
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">yep Garth Brooks</ENAMEX>  and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reba McIntire</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		really i'm a i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clint Black</ENAMEX> fan
 	
 	
 		how about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Strait</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i don't
 		yeah he's okay he's
 	
 	
 		he's okay and and who else Dolly Parton
 	
 	
 		um she's okay
 	
 	
 		and
 		um i don't watch
 		tremendous amount but some
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		have you gone to um <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garth</ENAMEX>'s concert
 	
 	
 		no my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> have but i haven't
 	
 	
 		i heard his concert was
 		did they did they tell you that he swung from a rope like Tarzan like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tarzan</ENAMEX> he he he swung through the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> like
 	
 	
 		no
 		oh how funny
 	
 	
 		on a yeah i think that's true
 	
 	
 		i somehow or another i wonder if his hat fell off
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 		so what else do you listen to
 	
 	
 		oh what else i like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cher</ENAMEX> she's an old you know she's kind of old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singer</ENAMEX> she's been around a while
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		yeah but she thinks she's young
 	
 	
 		she looks
 	
 	
 		do you ever watch <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	