
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well
 		how do we feel about the nursing home right  um i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad eighty eighty</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nine years old</TIMEX> and uh he has <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Parkinson's</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and  there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> of us <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister brother</ENAMEX> and i and we decided that we could not live with him going to a nursing home
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> we took turns my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> and i live here my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Longview</ENAMEX> going back and forth up there helping her she has him in her home
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		we just decided we couldn't put him in the nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> but i decided i couldn't keep on with that
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and now she won't put him in the nursing home i think she's getting close
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but the problem with these nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> is  the cost
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and um he has a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and
 		since he has a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> it would cost oh i don't know something like <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">two thousand dollars</NUMEX> i think to keep him and um
 	
 	
 		uh-huh right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh i really need to know more about it
 	
 	
 		yeah i think we're kind of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>'s in the same situation my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX>
 		is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about ninety two</NUMEX> right now and just really has lost her senses she's gone senile and we basically take care of her between my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncle</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aunt</ENAMEX> and ourselves and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncle</ENAMEX> lives in in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		it's really it's a challenge for our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> because my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> still have a lot of young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and it's really tough for them to
 	
 	
 		oh yes
 	
 	
 		to handle my grandma as well as
 		as well as um the rest of the family
 	
 	
 		yeah is she still mobile though
 	
 	
 		no not at all we're we basically push her around and she's lost control of her bowel and it's just it's really sad and it's kind of like you said that
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		we've we've looked at some nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> and and just the situations that i've seen is most of the time when there are when they they go into the nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> they just lose even more than what they had before
 	
 	
 		right they become a vegetable more or less  and uh they don't they sedate them and
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		forget them
 	
 	
 		yeah and really you know they say that they're going to help them be productive but basically what they all do is they lay on their beds all day
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it just to me that seems really sad
 	
 	
 		well it really is um  my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> can't even feed himself  and um he still you know health is pretty his mind pretty much and that's why we can't put him there i guess if he didn't have his mind you know it would be easier to do that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but anyways
 	
 	
 		yeah it's kind of a challenge i guess
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well hopefully  they're going to clean these things up i don't that they will
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah i think you know i think they big thing is just to find a nursing home that really cares for other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and it's not just the money they're bringing in but it's it's more of a humanitarian thing where they want to help these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the best years</TIMEX> of their lives that are left
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and i think that's the real problem personally
 	
 	
 		yeah i guess one problem that they're having in these <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> is is help
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		they don't have enough help to go around
 	
 	
 		yeah and see that's i couldn't do it i think that that'd be super tough just because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that you learn to love you see dying off <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and i think that would just be really i admire those who can i couldn't handle that personally
 	
 	
 		yeah  i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> here  that i think her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ninety seven</NUMEX> or something and um she's been pleased well pleased with the care of course she goes every day
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and i think as long as you go <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> to see about them they get better care
 	
 	
 		yeah i think you're right
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i think as you learn to know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteers</ENAMEX> and help them know a little bit about your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> i guess that would make a difference too
 	
 	
 		yeah right  well  i do you know anything about the um qualifications uh i mean of knowing qualifications of the nursing homes
 	
 	
 		i i really don't to be honest with you i'm just seen i've done some work in nursings <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> and i've kind of
 		but in terms of specific qualifications i don't know other than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> square meals a day
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fruit</ENAMEX> and supposed sanitation type things but
 		i just it seems like every time i've sung a lot and so every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">almost every Christmas</TIMEX> and every holiday you can think of we've gone in and sang at nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> and
 		it's sad because really they're not and to me at least it doesn't seem like they're very well taken care of and any of them that
 	
 	
 		no no they're really not
 	
 	
 		but
 	
 	
 		and i think as long as they're is a family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> to go in and see about them they get better care
 	
 	
 		yeah i tend to agree with that and i think more than anything for them that's important that if you're going to find a find some place where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are around them really and truly love them
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they know that they're still wanted and they're still they can still be a productive part of society
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and i think too often the nursing home for example my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandma</ENAMEX>'s case she doesn't want to go to a nursing home because to her that's just a sign of losing everything and completely being completely unproductive forever
 	
 	
 		um-hum  well that's kind of the way my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> was when he had to leave his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> he  he left my home and went to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>'s and of course you know as far as
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	