
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
  
 		hi
 	
 	
 		hi i'm <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carol</ENAMEX> and i'm calling from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Garland Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah uh this is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jan Noak</ENAMEX> i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh okay because <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> i talked to someone upstate i'm not even sure where and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> talked to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> so
 		um anyway let me press one
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		
 
 		okay um let me see
 		i think we've only planned <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> reunion in our life so we don't do this too often
 	
 	
 		i
 	
 	
 		um most of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>'s in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> but my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s is in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Antonio</ENAMEX> and so we did this in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Antonio</ENAMEX> and um it was an experience that i i won't do again
 	
 	
 		how big a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> do you have
 	
 	
 		um well it wasn't that big of a family but um
 		it just got out of hand and um so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were coming that we were trying to figure out how much <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> we were going to need and
 		and um how much <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">um beverages</ENAMEX> we were going to need and this and that and oh it just grew and grew and grew and um
 		when the time came <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only about half</NUMEX> that amount of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> came so it wasn't you know you have to really just get an accurate amount and but overall we all had a good time we saw <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> we hadn't see in a while so
 	
 	
 		did you have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> coming from far away
 	
 	
 		no it was all in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Antonio</ENAMEX> area
 	
 	
 		uh sometimes it's
 	
 	
 		but it it just kept growing and growing and growing and growing and we're going oh my gosh so
 	
 	
 		well you have you have family lives too close together they see each other too often they uh they don't take that kind of thing seriously
 	
 	
 		uh-huh basically
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and if uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		they they come from far away it's uh
 		it it they take it more seriously
 	
 	
 		uh-huh i think you're right yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>'s not very big but uh we're kind of
 	
 	
 		your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>'s from where
 	
 	
 		well i have a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a</NUMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX> a sister lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> live back in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Buffalo New York</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh no
 	
 	
 		uh
 		i i guess we have reunions about once <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> or so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we got together over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> they're they're all in upstate most of them are in upstate <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> they have regular uh regular family reunions every <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">summer</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh those are nice
 	
 	
 		and it's yeah it is it's uh
 	
 	
 		and i'm i'm sure they're a lot more organized too because they've done it before
 	
 	
 		yeah and it's it's just something that they they plan on doing every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> they just have a weekend picnic and uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> everyone asks when is it happening and where is it happening and they just plan on being there
 	
 	
 		that's great
 		oh
 		yeah that makes a big difference too
 		when everybody's real eager to participate
 		yeah well that's great
 	
 	
 		yeah they
 		they had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> reunion for uh well for my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother-in-law</ENAMEX> at her seventy <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX> birthday and they managed to get just about everybody
 		everybody into town uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last November</TIMEX> including a a number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from out in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh
 	
 	
 		so is uh
 		it it was good it uh it worked out very well
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		one interesting interesting thing that they did at the time is they um
 		they videotaped the the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">shebang</ENAMEX> which
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it made a nice remembrance of of the entire party
 	
 	
 		yeah more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> want to come back again
 	
 	
 		yeah they want to come back
 	
 	
 		yeah that's good
 	
 	
 		so so that that works pretty well that way
 	
 	
 		my uh
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> is um  which is my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>'s part side of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> is planning a reunion um <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this spring</TIMEX> but we won't be going because um
 		i don't know how they thought of this it's going to be on a cruise
 		and um it seems like most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> is uh going you know all the nieces and all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandchildren</ENAMEX> and all that are going most of them are going but
 		it's too costly for us but anyway they're going to go on a cruise and um it sounds really neat it really does
 	
 	
 		yeah i i can go for that that what what the i i guess interesting if you had uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh a very extended <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> that that kind of involved a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cousins</ENAMEX> and things that you don't really know that you've never met it'd be interesting to meet a lot of those people
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh
 		i don't know how you would go about uh
 		getting them together but
 		that uh would be uh
 	
 	
 		and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of mine um she plans her family reunion
 		um <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> and they go camping and she says they have the greatest time and she says usually everybody shows up in exception to maybe <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> but she said they all go camping and they have a really good time for the whole weekend
 		so that's
 	
 	
 		yeah i kind of wonder what what kind of tradition we're going to establish for our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> you know i had hoped that our our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> get together uh at least regularly
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		right now we only have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> so i
 		
 
 		
 		
 	