
 
     		
 	
 		so uh what kind of home repair work have you done
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well um  done a little uh repair on the um shingles on the roof recently we've had a lot of wind around here
 	
 	
 		y'all been pulling them up huh or just loosening them until the rain came in
 	
 	
 		yes uh it looks like i'm gonna have to get up there again because we may have a leak
 	
 	
 		are you in the section of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> that's been getting so much rain
 	
 	
 		we've been getting quite a bit maybe not quite as bad as some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> down around <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Antonio</ENAMEX> but uh well i'm right uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Plano</ENAMEX> is just north of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		and uh there are parts of downtown or near downtown <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> are under water right now i guess i saw on the news
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		so you're probably what about halfway across the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Antonio</ENAMEX> though aren't you
 	
 	
 		well we're up uh we're north in um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		oh about uh i don't know uh eighty to <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a hundred miles uh</NUMEX> south of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX> line i guess
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		okay
 		but you're still getting a good bit of the rain though
 	
 	
 		uh we did have a little bit of rain <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> so far we haven't had any <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> and uh i suppose that means i should be uh
 		getting up there to look at that uh shingle but uh i had something else planned <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> so i guess i'll let it go awhile
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah is it asphalt shingles or or clay
 	
 	
 		they're uh no they're uh  uh wood shake
 	
 	
 		ooh that should be a lot of fun did did you put them up originally or you just uh uh going up  stopping leaks in them
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		no i uh as a matter of fact we've never had a leak actually yet now this we just bought the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> and um uh just before we took possession of it we had a fellow go up there and do whatever needed to be done on the shingles so
 		i've just recently had to start looking at it myself
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so it's a small problem so far but i guess you just have to keep on top of it what kind of roof do you have
 	
 	
 		uh we were in um uh <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campus apartment buildings</ENAMEX> with flat top uh
 	
 	
 		oh
 		well then you don't have to do too much with
 	
 	
 		not too much they're just tar and gravel uh treated flat top roofs have you got pretty low pitch on that roof or is it pretty steep
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh it's pretty steep um parts of it are steeper than others
 	
 	
 		well what do you use to keep from sliding off that rascal
 	
 	
 		well uh  you wear uh shoes with good traction and  and and try to remember where you are at all times
 	
 	
 		yeah i imagine
 		i imagine
 		anyway
 	
 	
 		and remember to yell <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Geronimo</ENAMEX> if uh all else fails
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 		yeah that would be just too much of a fall for me
 		um have you been uh visit was the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> reasonably new or you been doing some remodeling work on it or
 	
 	
 		it's actually just twelve <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years old</TIMEX> now
 	
 	
 		that's pretty new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> yet
 	
 	
 		yeah it um this part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> actually they  they say that when the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> is uh fifteen it's already old but uh if you take good care of it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		thing is we've um
 		the main thing that we've had with this <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> recently has been some um
 		uh squirming squirming i call it of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundation</ENAMEX> we're just on a concrete slab you know but uh the soil right under this is a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">clay</ENAMEX> and it um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		it's settling unevenly
 	
 	
 		well it uh depending on it's moisture content it either swells up or shrinks
 		and um course the soil right under the slab retains it's moisture a lot longer
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so during the dry season you have to water the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundation</ENAMEX> to keep your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundation</ENAMEX> from uh from uh drooping and um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but anytime there's a change in the weather like the temperature uh
 		drastic changes in temperature or in uh moisture uh you get little spider web cracks all around uh windows and doors
 	
 	
 		well that sounds like a lot of fun
 	
 	
 		well usually what you do is just wait until you think it's stopped and then you patch them up
 	
 	
 		hm what is it like uh stucco walls or
 	
 	
 		uh well this is all uh it's all drywall
 	
 	
 		or
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">wood</ENAMEX>
 		all drywall
 	
 	
 		uh i think with um
 	
 	
 		wood framing
 	
 	
 		yeah right
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		but uh somehow or other that does manage to uh show these little cracks i don't know quite how that works maybe it isn't drywall
 		i don't really know
 	
 	
 		well if they've plastered over drywall i remember my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> home is drywalled and then they uh almost like a small grade stucco type plastering over the drywall
 	
 	
 		yeah i think it is
 		i expect that's what it is yeah
 	
 	
 		give it a textured sort of a look and made for kind of a hard shell on the on the drywall
 	
 	
 		yeah i think that's the way this is done fortunately we haven't had any real big holes in it yet so i
 	
 	
 		well that's good
 		yeah
 		well that would that would be in terribly terribly exasperating to have the
 		a slab floor like that swelling and giving like that
 	
 	
 		yes well the uh previous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> had a major problem with it because um
 		oh probably a variety of things uh his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX> used to have
 		
 		
 	