
 
     		
 	
 		hi
 	
 	
 		so what well what do you think
 	
 	
 		well
 		providing universal health care insurance for the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> is a pretty big task and i uh personally i don't approve of it for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> reasons number one
 		is that i think that uh the federal government
 		has a problem with the deficit <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">right now</TIMEX> and if they were to administer this they would uh get us more and more into debt
 		further than we can ever get out ourselves number <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> i think that the quality of health care would go down because the competition would
 		would be dried up and really no one would be would only answer to to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> to a big bureaucratic bureaucratic mess
 		and uh i've seen what it has done in other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> and so i don't think uh
 		i don't think we should head in that direction although that we have problems <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">right now</TIMEX> and i do agree that they exist because health care insurance for for everyone
 		is skyrocketing and it's become to a point where basically no one can afford it anymore
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		how do you feel about the whole whole ordeal
 	
 	
 		well i agree that it's a big task but i think that i think that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> should move towards some kind of national health care plan
 		at least as a long term kind of goal
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know possibly
 		you know just starting with more regulation of health insurance and that sort of thing but i think that ultimately it would be
 		a good idea to
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> and not have a completely socialized
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		medical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">system</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> but maybe something about halfway between that and what we have now
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		okay
 	
 	
 		it um just because it seems that
 		um health insurance costs are sky rocketing well as fast as the national deficit
 	
 	
 		oh yes
 	
 	
 		perhaps and so that's
 		and that's a that's a vicious cycle of course
 	
 	
 		but what what you're think
 		yeah so what you're saying though is instead of having the national <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government government</ENAMEX> administer
 	
 	
 		because
 	
 	
 		giving health insurance to every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man woman</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> with throughout the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> you see more of them as regulating the high costs
 		uh that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are forced to pay for it right now
 		is that is that correct or do you think that
 	
 	
 		um
 		well
 		i um
 		well i wouldn't exclude the possibility of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> actually administrating it ultimately i don't think that that would necessarily be such a bad idea
 		and
 		um
 	
 	
 		well with the with the costs as they are right now do you think that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> uh because what that would require is for us to pay uh more taxes and the
 		the income the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that can afford taxes the middle income and the upper income will be paying more cash taxes to to pay for health insurance for everyone whereas right now the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> themselves
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		get health insurance and they provide their own health insurance
 	
 	
 		the well as it is now the middle and upper <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classes</ENAMEX> are paying more than their share for the health care of the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> because they're the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that can afford health insurance
 		and so that the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have no health insurance and you know they'll get medical care anyway at least in emergencies
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and somebody winds up paying for that and
 		basically the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> paying for it are the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are buying health insurance
 		so i do not see that anything
 		this situation would get any worse that way it might get better
 	
 	
 		you think it might be get better huh i i kind of disagree  the reason being is uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we have i don't know i guess it's my my fear of the national <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and also because the bureaucratic
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		rules that it would take to administer it and um
 		the the health insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> right now pretty much regulate and are pretty picky and and uh don't allow
 		cases where they might throw them out of business whereas the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> if they took over everything they wouldn't care because they'll never go out of business <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would still have to pay taxes the money would have to come from somewhere
 		and so you'd see i i feel that the cost would increase
 		dramatically also but in the same sense the the care and the the attitude of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> within the medical uh field
 		would would diminish
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um i
 	
 	
 		yeah well i think
 		
 		
 	