
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		say you did uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">starters</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Bendix</ENAMEX> springs such as that on an old one
 	
 	
 		yeah and uh  helped my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> replace some carburetors
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		some that she had to uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">um</ENAMEX> label everything
 	
 	
 		she had to label everything what was she driving
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah because it was a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cadillac</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they uh well  they quit making those the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quadrajet</ENAMEX> carburetor and they quit making it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		they rebuilt it and it never did never did run right again
 	
 	
 		yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quadrajet</ENAMEX> not real easy to get rebuilt just right
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um
 		what were you replacing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">starters</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Bendix</ENAMEX> drives on
 	
 	
 		um  a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Maverick</ENAMEX> and also um a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">station wagon</ENAMEX> before that
 	
 	
 		yeah did you replace just the uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Bendix</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">station wagon</ENAMEX> or the whole starter
 	
 	
 		uh the i'm replacing the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two or three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">starters</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">starters</ENAMEX> are kind of fragile
 	
 	
 		they
 		yeah and the
 	
 	
 		especially if you need a tune up
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		they kept saying that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler</ENAMEX> that's what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chryslers</ENAMEX> did is they wore out starters you know
 	
 	
 		yeah well if if if they start real easy you know you just hit the key and it starts up and when it's properly tuned up that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">starter</ENAMEX> will last for a long time
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		see they built that starter so it'd fit every <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">V-8</ENAMEX> and all the slant sixes
 		that they built in like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty five years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		they all take the exact same starter they'll interchange completely i mean completely one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">starter</ENAMEX> will fit all of them
 		so they've got a whole lot of torque but to do that they did uh they use an underdrive system where they geared it down
 		so its motor spins really fast
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so it's got to spin for very long it's kind of tough on the bushings usually what goes is the bushings you take a little time replace the bushings you still got a perfectly good starter
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right
 	
 	
 		but uh most places don't put don't rebuild them with with good with good enough bushings so it's you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		after you get rebuilt one you have a tendency to go through them pretty quickly especially if you need a tune-up
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		anyway what are you driving now
 	
 	
 		um my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler</ENAMEX> van
 		and it's it's pretty maintenance free you know and uh and beginning <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year last year</TIMEX>
 		and drove a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chevrolet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Cavalier</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">station wagon</ENAMEX> and it didn't give me any trouble at all
 	
 	
 		that's good
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		what is it a late model set <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler</ENAMEX> van
 	
 	
 		it's a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty seven</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the little minivans
 	
 	
 		um-hum yeah
 		is it
 	
 	
 		do you like the way it rides and such
 	
 	
 		uh rides or runs
 	
 	
 		rides rough
 	
 	
 		it yeah well yeah it rides rides rough it runs good you know i kind of it took me a while to get used to a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> cylinder engine
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you have to kind of wait for it especially when you get on the highway
 	
 	
 		yeah right now without getting some of the sportier models uh the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> cylinders aren't real peppy
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but uh
 		they're starting to change that out in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last couple of years</TIMEX> too
 	
 	
 		you driven <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> all
 	
 	
 		uh see i've driven <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> import uh i drove a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Volkswagen Beetle</ENAMEX> for a while <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a month</TIMEX> um in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that month</TIMEX> i think i put uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> oil coolers on it um
 		every time i turned around i was having trouble with it everything else i ever owned was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX> built
 		uh mostly older <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> um i've been a mechanic well i worked starting working my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s service <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX> when i was about uh
 		<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">twelve</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so i've been around <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> a lot
 		but uh driven a lot of old Pontiacs
 		my <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> were uh seventy model <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Pontiacs</ENAMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GTO</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bonneville</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">station wagon</ENAMEX> and
 		i had a couple of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chryslers</ENAMEX> had a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Super B</ENAMEX> for a while with a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">four forty</NUMEX> in it
 		it a lot of fun
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but uh
 	
 	
 		not not much gas mileage though
 	
 	
 		i don't know gas mileage wasn't too bad i got about seventeen
 	
 	
 		oh wow
 	
 	
 		well till you got crazy with it you know you get the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> barrel all worked up and suddenly it it it drops off fast but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		long as you didn't spin the tires too much or or spend too much time with the secondaries kicked in it it didn't do too bad on gas
 		didn't have to work very hard to move the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> around
 	
 	
 		now do you think since they started with electronic ignition that it improves the way the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> runs
 	
 	
 		oh yeah yeah definitely
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know the my last <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> was a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seventy</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chevy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">station wagon</ENAMEX>
 		uh it still had the points and condenser in it
 		when i rebuilt the engine on that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about a hundred</NUMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty thousand</TIMEX> on the car
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i uh pulled that old points <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">distributor</ENAMEX> out and got a an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HEI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">distributor</ENAMEX> electronic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">distributor</ENAMEX> and put into it
 		
 		
 	