
 
     		
 	
 		okay um do you have any <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pets</ENAMEX> now
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well we don't right now no we've uh i grew up with uh with <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pets</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> and i always had a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat some birds</ENAMEX> but uh right now we don't have anything
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh okay um
 		that a matter of choice or compulsion
 	
 	
 		what about you
 		well we've just um
 		it seems like we've always been at a place where we'd have to go away for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> or something and uh it was never convenient to have anything i we're thinking about getting a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> if we get into a house
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> someplace where there are you know we can take care of it and everything we've got some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> who would just really uh enjoy having an animal you know a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> i think and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		what about you all
 	
 	
 		well right now i'm <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> and campus housing does not even allow thinking about that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh no
 	
 	
 		no we almost got chased out of here for feeding a stray <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		is that right
 	
 	
 		yeah they're very strict about it
 	
 	
 		but you like uh you like <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pets</ENAMEX> and things
 	
 	
 		oh love animals
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		i was raised our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> when i when i was growing up there was almost never uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> it's almost almost always <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> sometimes you know like <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fifteen</ENAMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh always <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX> in the house
 	
 	
 		oh yeah we enjoyed we enjoyed them uh we like we like <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pets</ENAMEX> but um you know you've got to deal with uh taking care of them and and feeding them and everything like that
 	
 	
 		always
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are we've got some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and they're not
 		not used to it you know on a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> basis they they uh and
 	
 	
 		how old are your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fourteen</NUMEX> down to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		um okay
 	
 	
 		you've sound like you've got some small ones in the background
 	
 	
 		one our first he's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about ten eleven</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX> now
 	
 	
 		is that right
 		oh great congratulations
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah uh originally <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Virginia</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		where are you from
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		okay
 	
 	
 		um i don't know how familiar you are with that area of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> but
 	
 	
 		i been to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charleston</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charleston West Virginia</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes uh-huh
 	
 	
 		okay that's pretty much the south end of the state or the southern <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">quarter</NUMEX> of the state anyway
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay in the north end of the state you got that little narrow strip of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Virginia</ENAMEX> going up between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right at the base of that northern peninsula is my <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">hometown</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well that's yeah that's interesting so it's really up north in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> really uh it's i guess uh
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah it's well uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> is like <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">three miles</NUMEX> south of where the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mason Dixon Line</ENAMEX> would have hit the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ohio River</ENAMEX> had it continued that far
 	
 	
 		gosh i see
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		pretty nice <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> up there
 	
 	
 		oh it's beautiful
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hills</ENAMEX> or what
 	
 	
 		uh well from my neck of the woods it's hilly um you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh maybe <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">three hundred four hundred feet</NUMEX> elevation
 		uh that type
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		variations from the valleys up to the hills to hilltops
 	
 	
 		is it a farmland
 	
 	
 		um
 		not a lot of farmland there mostly it's uh i mean you know there's you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> with their own own farm uh growing their own food
 		uh most of the agriculture it's more in the way of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">uh sheep</ENAMEX> and cattle
 	
 	
 		oh yes um-hum
 	
 	
 		and even that's you know small time mostly uh the biggest chunk of what's going on there is is uh industries coal <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mines</ENAMEX> and chemical <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> and power <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		sure
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		okay
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">aluminum</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> there's like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">aluminum</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> with you know
 	
 	
 		what are you  what are you studying there at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hattiesburg</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		computer engineering
 	
 	
 		oh yeah what year
 	
 	
 		uh just finished up my <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fourth semester</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		well great
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah i hope that works out well
 	
 	
 		it it's a big change
 		i spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years</TIMEX> as a mechanic so yeah
 	
 	
 		was
 		oh did you
 		well you've got some experience behind you in the work force
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah are you uh shooting for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bachelor</ENAMEX>'s now or master's or what
 	
 	
 		i'm working on a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bachelor</ENAMEX>'s degree
 	
 	
 		all right okay good
 	
 	
 		i'm working on a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bachelor</ENAMEX>'s degree it'll be computer
 	
 	
 		hope it's a good program there
 	
 	
 		pardon
 	
 	
 		hope it's a good program there
 	
 	
 		uh it seems to me from what i've been able to find out that's considered a pretty good program it's nice and small which means you know
 	
 	
 		yep
 		yeah good
 	
 	
 		if you don't get the class <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this semester</TIMEX> then you got to wait <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three or four semester</TIMEX> you know anywhere from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two to four semesters</TIMEX> to get it again but uh it's it's worth it once you get it
 	
 	
 		hum
 		well yes that's good and probably a good uh student <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> ratio and things yeah
 	
 	
 		oh yeah yeah most the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> is pretty small
 	
 	
 		good
 	
 	
 		that works out real well
 	
 	
 		well i was wondering what if you all were to get a pet like if you were to move into an <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> or a house somewhere what would you get
 	
 	
 		uh well um
 		<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> off we'd probably wind up with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">uh cat</ENAMEX> or maybe a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">puppy</ENAMEX> uh i'm partial towards the larger dogs um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		our last we we've had a couple of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX> before we moved on campus uh had a hamster or two they were they got to be a lot of fun
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		a hamster um oh yeah
 	
 	
 		uh it's amazing how much character you can
 		
 		
 	