
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay all set then
 		uh what do you think about it
 	
 	
 		uh i think it's a real good concept uh drug testing procedures would have to be refined
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		from what i've seen on the news  there's a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a</NUMEX> a pretty good size problem with poor accuracy poor procedure in uh drug testing
 	
 	
 		oh i didn't realize that
 	
 	
 		yeah um there have been <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who have been turned down for jobs because there was a drug showed up in their in their uh test but they didn't know for sure what it was but it was a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> so they got turned down
 		and uh turns out it was a prescription
 		or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> getting somebody else's blood test
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		same sort of problem that happens sometimes with these some of these uh like <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> tests and such
 	
 	
 		okay
 		um-hum yeah that's right i have heard uh  i don't remember what they call it sort of like a
 		positive negatives or some some kind of word they use when a uh you get a uh
 		a positive indication of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> but there's not really there weren't really any there uh every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> and then there's an error and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are really upset about that when it comes to their rights and their rights being violated
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah i i work here at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Instruments</ENAMEX> so uh we we do a let me think do we yeah everyone coming in i guess i did <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years ago</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		everyone coming in uh goes through the drug testing procedure and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they talk about it as a  you know as as better for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and better for the working conditions uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		if they uh they test for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> i i'm i can't even remember if we do random sampling anymore i know we did in the military but i don't know if once your in they continue to do it but i guess you're always on call for it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 		yeah i not very long ago worked for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wal-Mart</ENAMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a year and a half ago</TIMEX> they instituted a uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		a uh drug testing program uh well drug and alcohol testing program it's it's not a random  through the system as each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX> comes in
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		part of the hiring procedure is a a blood test  um
 		but and uh i think the big problem though is is they send these  off to large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">labs</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		in my
 		uh-huh right
 	
 	
 		and then they have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of the samples that uh going through it in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a day</TIMEX> and
 		bottles get mixed up and things like that  a potential for inaccuracy
 	
 	
 		so your big <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beef</ENAMEX> with it is the uh
 		is is it's a good idea but
 		like you said the drug testing procedures need to be defined a little better or make sure it's a lot safer because a couple of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are going to be discriminated against unfairly or whatever yeah i i i tend to agree with you <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> used to work for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wal-Mart</ENAMEX> and then i don't know if he still does or what because i don't know if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam</ENAMEX>'s is actually part of it but he you know is working at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam</ENAMEX>'s now
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam</ENAMEX>'s is part of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wal-Mart</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay yeah then he's been working for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> for a while too yeah he enjoys it good company um you all uh have some his
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh yeah
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> i thought was a great place to work
 	
 	
 		telling me about good profit sharing and all that so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's good news
 	
 	
 		yeah they got to have had <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two or three years</TIMEX> in with them then you start buying stock and you have a have a little taken out of your check each each payday to put against uh uh stock portfolio uh not portfolio just you know against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wal-Mart</ENAMEX> stock
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh you can build a pretty fair amount of stock after a while
 	
 	
 		yeah that's what my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> was telling me that's good good news good deal well uh how long were we supposed i haven't done this in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple months</TIMEX> how long were we supposed to discuss for
 	
 	
 		uh you're supposed to get <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five minutes</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay we got <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a couple more minutes</TIMEX> then i guess  uh think what else i can say about that um
 	
 	
 		um
 		do you have any idea uh
 		let's see were you were you were tested for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> as you got into uh as as you got into <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right um everyone coming in gets goes through the drug test
 	
 	
 		yeah uh now uh were you asked to wait before starting to work until the drug test came through or
 	
 	
 		uh no well let me think about that yeah it was after i was i had already been hired um yeah you get hired then you come in the first i
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		seems to me i remember that uh i was hired came in and went through some orientation and i thought i
 		boy i can't remember that would seem strange to already be working here in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first week</TIMEX> of the drug test maybe it was during the interview i came up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a couple</NUMEX> times for an interview so it's hard for me to remember where i was when all that happened
 		but uh i guess just like other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> i've been hearing about that have been moving around it's it's before they have to wait for the drug test to come in before you actually get employment so i'm sure that happened to me too
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		what what about oh they just instituted it there at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wal-Mart</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		yeah they they it was after i was already working there and they weren't testing any of those that were already working so
 	
 	
 		right
 		right yeah i wasn't
 		
 		
 	