
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		um what sort of camping do you like to do the most
 	
 	
 		uh well i i do uh real rough type camping i have a motor home
 	
 	
 		huh rough type huh okay
 	
 	
 		yeah uh
 	
 	
 		oh yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">motor homes</ENAMEX> can be a lot of fun
 	
 	
 		yeah they really are they really are i've i've enjoyed it i've never actually done any uh like tent camping but uh one of these days i'm gonna try that too
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		uh that can be a lot of fun too
 	
 	
 		yeah like to go to visit to the national <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX> and state <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX> and and uh just get out and see nature
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		how about you
 	
 	
 		well so far my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and i have pretty much had to stick with tent camping
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this summer</TIMEX> we went to uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Smokey Mountain National Park</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh how great
 	
 	
 		and uh stayed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about three or four days</TIMEX> in there
 		it was wonderful <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nights</TIMEX> were cool enough to where they're comfortable and the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the days</TIMEX> were nice and warm and it was beautiful beautiful few days
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> that's great
 	
 	
 		it worked out particularly well especially considering she was what <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six months</TIMEX> pregnant
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i don't know it worked pretty well it was one of those uh those <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dome</ENAMEX> type pop up tents
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		nice and quick and easy to put up and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		packs away nice and small
 		yeah about had to be something like that getting around in a Pinto
 	
 	
 		well that's true that's true
 	
 	
 		it was a lot of fun
 	
 	
 		yeah i guess the last real uh camping trip i took was has been <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple years ago</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh i went to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> and up to the Sequoias
 	
 	
 		ah that's got to be beautiful territory
 	
 	
 		yeah it's gorgeous i love the big trees
 		just just the drive up through um up the coast line and then cut over in into the into the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX> it's gorgeous though
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		what like <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Sequoia National Park</ENAMEX> yeah uh
 	
 	
 		um-hum um-hum yeah i had been there before when i lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> that's my <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> trip back in oh goodness hm hm <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty years</TIMEX> maybe  but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		that is God's <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> it has to be
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yep
 	
 	
 		do they still have the uh the scenic uh <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roadways</ENAMEX> that cut through the center of some of those trees
 	
 	
 		uh no no they don't that and the last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> um and well the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time i was there the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX> was still standing but it has since come down
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		yeah but they are huge if you've never seen them it's it's very awe inspiring
 	
 	
 		no so far <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Orleans</ENAMEX> is far west as i've gotten
 	
 	
 		um-hum yeah
 	
 	
 		well <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Orleans</ENAMEX> and uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minneapolis</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um-hum well there's lots of pretty country further west
 	
 	
 		oh yeah we're hoping one of these days soon after we're out of school to head that way
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah yeah and needed need to take the little one
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		show them all the all the pretties before they go away
 	
 	
 		yeah they seem to be trailing out quickly
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah  because of there there's lots to see  there's of course the  the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grand Canyon</ENAMEX> and uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Painted Desert</ENAMEX> is is real pretty in a in a different sort of way
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 		yes
 	
 	
 		and course the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">the Sequoias and the Redwoods and</ENAMEX> and you get up into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bryce Canyon</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yellowstone</ENAMEX> and uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grand Tetons</ENAMEX> are gorgeous too
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i imagine
 	
 	
 		yeah course i'm i guess i'm partial to big tree country
 	
 	
 		i would imagine they are
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i don't know why i got stuck down here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>  i think it's called a job i don't know
 	
 	
 		
 
 		uh not a whole lot of forestry down there is there
 	
 	
 		no not around here not around here  hm
 	
 	
 		oh
 		the place is forested with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">concrete</ENAMEX> with those concrete trees
 	
 	
 		um-hum lot lot of concrete and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glass</ENAMEX> you know hm
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well i guess that's God's place too
 		anyway
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um
 		what do you figure has been the longest trip you've taken camping
 	
 	
 		uh  probably the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the last one</TIMEX> that i went to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> i took uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three weeks</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three weeks</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		so i was actually yeah on the road a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">little more than three weeks</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> in with in on this
 	
 	
 		um-hum everybody
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yep
 	
 	
 		that would have to be a blast
 	
 	
 		yeah it really was it was great
 	
 	
 		what well you went out from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> up in into that area
 	
 	
 		um-hum yeah we went uh we took the southern route and went went through uh uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grand Canyon</ENAMEX> again and we stopped at uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">um  Las Vegas</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a couple of nights</TIMEX>  and then uh
 		went into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malibu</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> over on the coast and then went up the the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Sur Highway</ENAMEX> all the way up to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and  uh couldn't even cut across through the wine <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and went down to the to uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sequoia National Park</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay
 		oh wow
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">okay Big Sur Highway</ENAMEX> that's uh
 		well you're pretty much in view of the ocean almost all the time aren't you
 	
 	
 		oh yeah uh-huh you really are
 		
 		
 	