
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so what kind of dining out do you enjoy
 	
 	
 		well we usually do things that have to do with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> because i have a family of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> so
 	
 	
 		uh-huh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> or
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> yeah <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> of us altogether so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		when we go out it's usually someplace that caters to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>  more so than adult
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		so that has a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s menu or uh-huh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		how about you
 	
 	
 		um well i don't have any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> um and i'm a newlywed
 		so right now i guess my favorite type of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> is is a place that's fairly quiet and has a pleasant atmosphere
 		i sort of like the either an old <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> look or something um dim lights or something just you know the
 	
 	
 		have you found <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> that you like
 	
 	
 		um well i enjoy Steak and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Ale yeah</ENAMEX> that's that seems to have a pretty nice atmosphere usually not i don't like noise i just hate it when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> are like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bennigan's</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		they just opened up an <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Olive Garden</ENAMEX> here in Plano
 	
 	
 		that's the other one that i really like yeah i haven't the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">in Plano i</ENAMEX> haven't um oh yeah
 	
 	
 		do you like it there
 		i'm sure they're probably the same all over i've heard that their <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX> sticks are terrific
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah i've been to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 		yeah they are they really are i've only been there once uh but <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">almost a year ago</TIMEX> and i wanna go back i'd thought about it ever since it's not on our side of town
 	
 	
 		huh
 		yeah we've been meaning to try this one out here
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		do you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> like what kind of food do you like
 	
 	
 		um  well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> loves anything <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beef</ENAMEX> so he likes steak or ribs or something but i kind of like more variety i like to be able to
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		me too when i go out i like to have things that i don't cook at home you know when just he and i go out then it
 	
 	
 		yeah exactly
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's almost always <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> or something that i don't wanna do at home
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah i like to have a choice of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chicken</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> food <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> food
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know something
 		um
 		yeah something that i wouldn't
 		that takes more time to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cook</ENAMEX> at home
 	
 	
 		yeah what um what makes you go back there
 	
 	
 		um i'd say well one thing is the price i don't like it
 	
 	
 		yeah i was gonna say price is probably my biggest concern
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah if it's overpriced or you know i mean if it's i like to still be able to get a meal for well i'd prefer <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five dollars</NUMEX> or less they that's unusual <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> if you go out
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		it seems like you can get the same menu for lunch cheap have you ever tried that just going for lunch and then
 	
 	
 		uh-huh  yeah yeah we like uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Roma</ENAMEX>'s it's a rib place
 	
 	
 		oh yeah i've heard of that where is it
 	
 	
 		uh-huh well um let's see there's there's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> up at um see what is it just as um loop twelve turns into <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty five</TIMEX> it merges it's right there it's sort of a restaurant row in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> there
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and then there's also one down at the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Marketplace West End</ENAMEX> Marketplace
 		and we found out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> by mistake that lunch is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about half</NUMEX> as much as dinner is and you get about almost the same amount
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		in almost any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> that's almost the case that we've seen
 	
 	
 		yeah um-hum
 		so i'd say that's the first thing i look for is price and then atmosphere
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah how about you
 	
 	
 		probably price would be first
 		um we're not  you know we seems like we're always rushing rushing around doing something so location that would have a lot to do with it too i mean we don't really travel to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mesquite</ENAMEX> or you know somewhere that takes <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">half an hour</TIMEX> to get there so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we've you know tried most of the places around here and that's kind of where we stay
 	
 	
 		yeah so so what would your favorite place be or one of your favorites
 	
 	
 		oh gee
 	
 	
 		or some of your favorites
 	
 	
 		have you tried um The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisiana Purchase</ENAMEX> do they have any of those over there
 	
 	
 		no i've never heard of that
 	
 	
 		those are good and it's kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cajun i</ENAMEX> usually don't like spicy <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> but that's real good especially lunch you know because for the same reason because it's got some atmosphere and yet the price is is good
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> really likes <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> so we go <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> just a little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> and pop kind of places
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		more so than the bigger
 	
 	
 		yeah i like <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> too
 		yeah and sometimes you can uh you can often get that at a good price
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and some of them have good atmosphere too so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">places</ENAMEX>  doesn't seem like they really cater to atmosphere  the ones around here anyways just
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah some of them don't
 	
 	
 		just authentic that's all it you know it says authentic on the outside
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		so do you like places that are noisy that are lively  yeah
 	
 	
 		no not necessarily
 		um when i go out with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> i just want to be able to to talk to him so that doesn't lend itself to that and when i'm with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 		the more noise there is the more nose noise they think they can make  so it doesn't it tends to make them wilder so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 		yeah i'm sure it does
 	
 	
 		i really like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Black-Eyed Pea</ENAMEX> but i also think that's real noisy have you ever been to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Black-Eyed Pea</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um-hum yeah i have
 	
 	
 		it's got such a open atmosphere and clanking and banging that i love the food but it is really noisy
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah that's what i found too
 		so
 		well
 		do you have anything else you wanted to say
 	
 	
 		no i think that's pretty much what makes me go back
 		
 		
 	