
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		okay the change how <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s roles have changed
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		uh well i think we've moved out of the stereotype of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homemaker</ENAMEX> uh and i think it's been through necessity
 		with the economy and with the dysfunctional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes
 		yes but i think it causes a lot of dysfunction in the family
 	
 	
 		well
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> going out to work
 	
 	
 		uh possibly you know if if they're doing it simply um
 		for the money i think you know that
 	
 	
 		for the money
 	
 	
 		if if it's something that they need to fulfill themselves then that's something different too
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		that uh they should have the opportunity to do it and the quote <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homemaker</ENAMEX>'s role should be divided equally between the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">partners</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i do too when it's a necessity i know uh but it's funny how it's changed because when my mother
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh</ENAMEX> graduated well she took <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one year</TIMEX> of normal school and then she taught <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX> before uh she met my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> and they married and she had to quit teaching <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> because she was a married woman
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX>  that's right
 	
 	
 		so it it's changed a lot from then
 	
 	
 		and of course now <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> can be anything they want to
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh one thing that has not changed is
 		is the equality of pay among the sexes
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and uh i don't see any great hope for that being changed in the near future quite frankly
 	
 	
 		no no i don't either i just think that well <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> are just kind of in charge and they're not about to let women
 	
 	
 		but if you look at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who make the decisions
 		uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> they're primarily male
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		you know big decision <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">makers</ENAMEX> are still male until we get that changed  you know i'm a single
 	
 	
 		parent
 	
 	
 		parent well a single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are are grown and married but uh i still have to support myself
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i you know i personally i don't work because i want to get out there and do it i work because if i want to eat i'm out there working
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well i think that makes a big difference and i think it makes a big difference too if if after your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are raised uh you want to go out and fulfill yourself
 	
 	
 		well i did i didn't work while my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> were young and i was married because i did want to give them the background that they got at home i did find afterwards though
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you take the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> whose you know in a in a healthy family which i don't know how many of us have healthy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> anymore  uh but i did find that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> of working parents
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		or working <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> uh were more independent
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and maybe that goes to where it break it's breaking down the family bonds but i don't know of too many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> really work because they want to
 		uh most of them
 		are working and it's not to buy the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TVs</ENAMEX> and the new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> it's to survive
 	
 	
 		yes i definitely think so and especially uh in those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> does not have a college education
 	
 	
 		well even you know here our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> are paid so poorly
 	
 	
 		they are in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> too
 	
 	
 		and i don't know of any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> is not having to work
 		so it's it's not just the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> without a college education it's
 		our economy is really bad right now in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX> it's real bad
 	
 	
 		oh is it  i don't think it's  quite as bad in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> as it is throughout the nation
 	
 	
 		yes
 		well <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX> is certainly in the recession
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh we've been there we've been here for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about three to five years</TIMEX> now and it's really hurting
 	
 	
 		oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh you know i don't i don't know that any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> would choose that a married <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> would really choose to work because
 		when you're working and you're married you're holding down <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> jobs one at home and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> at
 	
 	
 		right i i think that that's more though with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> that's working
 	
 	
 		well yes
 	
 	
 		than than just a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> because i'm i'm not just a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> but a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> i i'm grateful that none of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX>-in-laws at this time are working
 		because they all have small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> and they're just i just think it's so sad when a  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> has to get a tiny baby up in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two months old</TIMEX> and it's cold here and take him to a babysitter
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	