
 
     		
 	
 		okay uh do you have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		no
 	
 	
 		have uh
 		are you a grandparent or you just have never had children
 	
 	
 		i've never had any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh oh well this is kind of hard topic for you then isn't it
 	
 	
 		that's all right i'm opinionated
 	
 	
 		you're what
 	
 	
 		i'm opinionated
 	
 	
 		oh  oh okay we're we're grandparents now and uh we did spend a lot of time with our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> they were we had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> and one girl
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they were all into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Little League</ENAMEX> and and athletics and fact we had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two two</NUMEX>
 		state wrestling champions
 	
 	
 		wow
 	
 	
 		and uh then we had uh they were in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Little League</ENAMEX> they were in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cub Scouts</ENAMEX> and uh
 		they were just busy and we just spent time with them i mean with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> you're just following one or the other all the time
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		wow
 	
 	
 		and one girl
 	
 	
 		uh-huh well you had to have something to even it out there
 	
 	
 		you what
 	
 	
 		had to have something to even it out
 	
 	
 		yeah we had a <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> and this cheerleader
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but um we and then we went camping with them and everything and uh we enjoy our uh enjoyed our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> they're scattered all over the world right now we have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> one in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i was going to say that's a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Black Forest cuckoo</ENAMEX> clock you have
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i can tell by the sound
 	
 	
 		
 
 		right right and then we have uh one in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> he's an airline <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilot</ENAMEX> and then one in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago Cleveland</ENAMEX> that's a doctor
 	
 	
 		airline <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilot</ENAMEX> for what airline
 	
 	
 		pardon
 	
 	
 		what airline
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		uh-huh do you  do you are you connected with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> flies <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> he's retiring in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh my goodness
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		well how long has he flown for them
 	
 	
 		oh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty some odd years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh oh
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">twenty four</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty three</TIMEX> something like that
 	
 	
 		well our our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>'s been with them <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about eight</NUMEX> i would maybe not <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> maybe <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six</TIMEX> but he's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">captain</ENAMEX> now so
 		we're happy with that
 	
 	
 		well uh he'll he'll enjoy the the freedom that that kind of a job gives you course
 	
 	
 		he does he says and to think they even pay me for it
 	
 	
 		yeah that's what my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> says you know as soon as he is retired he's gonna you know hire some hire an airplane
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because he really likes to fly
 	
 	
 		yeah well our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> that's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> uh has his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilot</ENAMEX>'s license too but just it's a small craft
 	
 	
 		huh
 		well huh
 	
 	
 		but  uh how old are you may i ask
 	
 	
 		i'm <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty seven</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh and you don't have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> do you
 	
 	
 		uh we can't
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		we tried but it's just not gonna happen
 	
 	
 		well sometimes that happens and sometimes uh you fill your life with other things so
 	
 	
 		well we have <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> and we have uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">chickens</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX> and birds
 	
 	
 		oh do you do you live on a little farm then
 	
 	
 		yeah we have a little you know just <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about ten acres</NUMEX> out here out you know about <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">ninety miles</NUMEX> north and uh west of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		so it it's stop it's it's a lot of fun i'm building our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> right now
 	
 	
 		oh that
 		oh my goodness you must be talented
 	
 	
 		well i was a you know <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contractor</ENAMEX> for past fifteen years
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		doing uh anything from you know bagging <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">concrete</ENAMEX> for a pad or uh you know i did uh couple of complete remakes of a house you know tore down and started over  almost on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of them
 	
 	
 		oh uh-huh
 	
 	
 		yeah my uh specialty is in restoration restoration
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		i figured well i'll build myself a house
 		you know and i'm doing it now as a matter of fact i just got out of the shower
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh  your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> answered the phone that's why  oh well we're just watching the BYU
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> game at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holiday Bowl</ENAMEX>
 		you probably don't follow that
 	
 	
 		no not not that close hey don't televise that down here
 	
 	
 		oh it's on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESPN</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well we don't take cable i mean it would cost a fortune
 	
 	
 		oh uh-huh oh
 	
 	
 		see we're  they just put the phone in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years ago</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		well
 		oh my goodness
 	
 	
 		you know there was no phone service for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> miles
 	
 	
 		oh you're really rural
 	
 	
 		yeah we are crazy as they say
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		well we we're <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about sixty miles</NUMEX> north of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Salt Lake City</ENAMEX> so have you ever been there
 	
 	
 		um
 		i went to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Salt Lake</ENAMEX> once
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and i was very i guess we were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		but uh
 	
 	
 		well we better get back to the subject did um
 	
 	
 		oh yeah raising kids
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i think the first thing you got to do is unplug your TV set and give it to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Salvation Army</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well
 	
 	
 		they watch entirely too much TV they have
 	
 	
 		uh i think a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> do nowadays our with the with the athletics and the well they all took music lessons
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh so with everything that they were involved in the arts especially our high school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> didn't have time for TV
 	
 	
 		yeah but i've worked well i work and live in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Denton</ENAMEX> area
 	
 	
 		into what
 	
 	
 		in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Denton Texas</ENAMEX> just north of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh you know i'll tell you i went to i graduated from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Nor th Texas</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple years ago</TIMEX> and i you know went back as
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	