
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		do you wanna tell me about your budgeting plan
 	
 	
 		yeah our budgeting plans includes me getting a job
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 		we're we're at the point now i i uh i quit working <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about six months ago</TIMEX> to start this house
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i'm out of cash and i'm not out of project yet
 	
 	
 		oh no
 	
 	
 		so uh i'm gonna go back and do some consulting work as far as budget's concerned i'm
 		i'm fairly fortunate uh we've
 		we're right now where if we don't buy anything extra we can make it on what my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> makes
 		so
 		uh the project's kind of halted until then
 		as far as budgeting is concerned you know we have uh some pretty strict guidelines that we go for you know we always put <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> percent back
 		and that's a never touch
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> into savings
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		either savings or investment one of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> but
 		we don't ever put it at a high risk it's just always gonna be there
 	
 	
 		well that's pretty good
 	
 	
 		and as far as the rest of it's concerned we don't have any kind of uh what i would call extravagant expenses you know
 		uh we uh we pretty much live on <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about eight nine hundred</NUMEX> a month
 		you know just travel to and from work and clothing and food
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> that's pretty good
 	
 	
 		and the rest of it you know we pile into the house
 		and uh you know i'm fairly fortunate i mean our credit cards are out to the max right now because i'm
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		a little a little behind on that but uh we're still making the payments on them it's just uh
 		when you see in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> you cannot borrow the money to build your own home
 		and do it yourself
 	
 	
 		yeah it's it's tough here too you have to have the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contractor</ENAMEX> sign with you
 	
 	
 		right exactly
 	
 	
 		but it's easy to find a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contractor</ENAMEX> for a couple of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundred</NUMEX> bucks who'll sign it and let you do it here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> where i live that is
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		and where i live it it's pretty scary
 		because <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> is one of those strange <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> where if you have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contractor</ENAMEX> sign on your note like that and you screw up you don't get it finished the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> can eat the contractor
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh bad for him huh
 	
 	
 		yeah bad for him
 		but the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homeowner</ENAMEX> can't be touched
 		it's a homestead state
 	
 	
 		hum
 		is that right
 	
 	
 		yeah see right now if i quit paying any of my bills the only thing they could do is cut off the electricity
 		they can't take your land unless you don't pay your land taxes
 		period
 	
 	
 		wow
 	
 	
 		you know they take your <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and your clothes and your anything that's not the tools of your trade
 		but as far as uh you know
 		
 
 		you're pretty much bullet proof in this state
 	
 	
 		well that's kind of handy
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i just finished <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Michener</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> book
 		pretty interesting
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> has quite the history
 	
 	
 		well you know we're we're not ones to budget much you know  we just got to spend it all
 	
 	
 		
 
 		that's kind of what we do we uh we're LDS and so we pay <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> percent tithing
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then i know we put i guess it's like
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fifteen</NUMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty</TIMEX> percent
 		into a savings account
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but that sometimes we use for emergency type things
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but uh
 		and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> doesn't work we're fortunate that way that i make enough to
 		do what we wanna do
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah we're pretty pretty fortunate as far as the uh the budgeting is concerned because you know we don't have any long term debt
 		you know uh we paid cash for car <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">well</ENAMEX> we bought the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> on time one of them
 		but we you know we since paid it off and
 	
 	
 		well that's pretty
 	
 	
 		the land is paid for cash so we don't have to worry about that
 	
 	
 		that's a great position to be in
 	
 	
 		well it's fraught with other problems
 		
 
 	
 	
 		is that right
 	
 	
 		yeah i'm not very motivated
 	
 	
 		oh
 		what kind of consulting do you do
 	
 	
 		uh systems consulting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">computerization</ENAMEX> for construction firms
 	
 	
 		is that right i'm into computers too i i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">E D P</ENAMEX> auditor
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		are you
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and
 	
 	
 		you into mainframes
 	
 	
 		yeah and PCs
 	
 	
 		and oh really
 	
 	
 		yeah i'm just brushing up on well C plus plus
 	
 	
 		are you really
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		i just got that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few days</TIMEX> ago
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">trio</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh jeez don't get me to lying i bought it at a fire stale
 	
 	
 		
 
 		ah
 	
 	
 		this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>'s place burned down and he had a bunch of computer stuff and
 		you know i bought it all it was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two hundred</NUMEX> bucks for everything he had
 	
 	
 		you got a buy
 	
 	
 		well some of it  wasn't worth anything you know you know a lot of the uh diskettes were just totally unusable
 	
 	
 		sure
 		melted
 	
 	
 		well yeah or wet
 	
 	
 		or just wet or
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		but i did get out of there with uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Vermont Views</ENAMEX>
 		which is a huge subroutine library
 		
 		
 	