
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		okay  well considering you moved here from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> i guess the rain for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past few weeks</TIMEX> has been different than what you would have down there
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh
 		yeah we have um in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> i'm in central i lived in central <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> we have rain <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">couple</NUMEX> times a year and other than that you know it'd be maybe <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX> and then in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the spring</TIMEX> and then other than that there wouldn't be any rain
 	
 	
 		especially <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last few years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		so
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		it's kind of has it's kind of been a drought out there hasn't it uh
 	
 	
 		yeah there has
 		so here i know that um <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> there was some ice storms while i was out of the state and i'm glad to see there haven't been any this year
 	
 	
 		that's what i was thinking
 		yet  generally if we're gonna get them it's not going to happen uh prior to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX> one you know you may get a cold snap or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> or some <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rain</ENAMEX> or something like we've been getting in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX> but
 	
 	
 		yeah yet still could come huh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		usually the bitterest weather if we're gonna have any comes in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January and February</TIMEX> then by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> things are getting warm again so we really don't have as long a cold season i guess as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> up north
 	
 	
 		hm
 		yeah yeah it's so hard to predict here
 	
 	
 		it's been eighty degrees on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas day</TIMEX> here before  lots of times
 	
 	
 		yeah well <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> it's not bad out there
 	
 	
 		no it's nice i just came in from outside and it's it's really pretty it's kind of nice to have it dry all the ground out
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		before it rains again i'm a i'm a scoutmaster and so i wind up going out camping with
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh a bunch of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time and so its better for us if it hasn't been just totally wet before we go
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah so you do that even in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX> huh uh-huh
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		yeah we camp <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> round
 	
 	
 		yeah oh that's interesting
 	
 	
 		but uh it's uh it's definitely different and then i guess you've been through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of summers</TIMEX> here too right
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah yep and they're not too pleasant  it gets so humid to me it's humid here <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that i know that come from um like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgia</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX> yeah they say this isn't humid
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well it is
 		it's not as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">humid</TIMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> say or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX> but it
 	
 	
 		yeah but i find it humid
 	
 	
 		its more humid than <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> for the most part
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		were you northern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i was central <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central Valley</ENAMEX> so it's very dry there
 	
 	
 		central okay so that was
 		dry but pretty even climate wasn't it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> round fairly not wide fluctuations
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		well it's pretty hot in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> it's in the usually you know for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a good three four weeks</TIMEX> we have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over a hundred</NUMEX> degrees but it's a dry heat yeah
 	
 	
 		but it's a drier
 		hundred  when you have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred</NUMEX> here everybody's dying
 	
 	
 		uh-huh yeah i know huh well i lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple years</TIMEX> in
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cameroon</ENAMEX> and that's a tropical climate and it really feels similar to this during the summer
 	
 	
 		what types of what take what type of business takes you to those climates or was that just vacation or something
 	
 	
 		no i was um working with um i still work with <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wycliffe Bible</ENAMEX> Translators
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		it's an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> where we are looking to translate the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX> into languages of the world that aren't yet written
 	
 	
 		not so much still trying to translate old texts as just trying to translate modern versions into other languages
 	
 	
 		right languages that don't have anything written yet so this is like the first thing that's written down or you know first an alphabet is developed and then um
 	
 	
 		oh
 		that's interesting you don't think about that as a career a normal career uh when you're thinking of things that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> might be doing
 	
 	
 		so
 		yeah
 		yeah well it's based here um the international <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wycliffe Bible Translators</ENAMEX> is right here in in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh so you're you're with the home <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> now
 	
 	
 		yeah right now i am so that's what brought me here
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		well the uh
 		i think uh all in all there are a lot worse climates than <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> uh the weather
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know does change fast and things do happen severely a few times <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> but there's an awful lot of good weather too in between
 	
 	
 		yeah i agree i agree i
 		i thought the fall was really nice
 	
 	
 		yeah and usually a lot of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the spring months</TIMEX> are really nice too after the last freeze and and when it begins to be in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the sixties</TIMEX> and seventies most of the time uh i like that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah uh-huh
 	
 	
 		particularly if i'm gonna be outdoors and doing uh outdoor activity hiking and things and that's nicer yeah i do quite a bit of that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah and you probably do a lot of that with scouts scouting uh-huh
 	
 	
 		think we're going in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">just a couple of weeks</TIMEX> out to the east <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> and it is a little more humid out there than it is here so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i guess we'll
 		the only thing you have to watch out in this part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> is during the change type <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seasons</TIMEX> is the
 		really severe storms that occasionally come through out here on the plains there's not much between us and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North Pole</ENAMEX>  and then when you get one of those tornado type
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		systems through or severe hail or thunderstorms and it
 		it doen't seem to be
 		
 		
 	