
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		you do a lot of uh camping up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh i used to do more when our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are were younger we'd go we'd go for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> and and have uh stay up in the mountains it was really fun
 	
 	
 		well in in the mountains up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> or where
 	
 	
 		well in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Idaho</ENAMEX> and we have camped a lot in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> too but mostly in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Idaho</ENAMEX>
 		we're right we're <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">only about fifty miles</NUMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Idaho</ENAMEX> border so we've camped there a lot do you camp a lot
 	
 	
 		well i go camping a lot with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boy Scouts</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh
 	
 	
 		we do we do several types uh we do several types of camping <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> type of camping we do is called a
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Base Camp</ENAMEX> where we simply go to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> set it up and spend <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX> the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> type of camping we do is backpacking where we simply go to an area backpack in
 		spend <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a night</TIMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> and then backpack out and then <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a third</NUMEX> type of camping we do has to do with uh aquatics
 	
 	
 		aquatics
 	
 	
 		well canoeing for the most part we we we take a long
 	
 	
 		oh um-hum
 	
 	
 		trip <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every June</TIMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buffalo River</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about nine days</TIMEX> of canoeing
 	
 	
 		is that with older scouts then
 	
 	
 		uh no the scouts have to have achieved the rank of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First</ENAMEX> Class which they generally get done after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> and then they're eligible to go on the trip
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		so we'll have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> on the trip that'll they all should be twelve by the time we go all ranging all the way up to seventeen
 	
 	
 		oh yes i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> that are  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eagles</ENAMEX> so they've done a lot of camping too and they've they've uh one thing they've done is gone on a fifty mile hike
 	
 	
 		well  these hikes that we've taken our boys
 		uh generally are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about six six</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> miles but uh they'll go they have the chance to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Philmont</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX> and then they'll do the fifty <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">mile</NUMEX> or whatever hiking then
 	
 	
 		oh oh well our camping is just with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> we've well  part of the time we've been in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trailers</ENAMEX> and part of the time we've been in tents
 		but uh we've uh and then when we've we've been camping we floated down the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buffalo River</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Idaho</ENAMEX> and done things like that
 	
 	
 		you have you have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buffalo River</ENAMEX> up there too huh
 	
 	
 		in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Idaho</ENAMEX> uh-huh
 	
 	
 		i wonder if they're connected to the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh i would doubt it i think this empties into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bear River</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well we do some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> camping too where we just all go for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a weekend</TIMEX> but we only have time to do that a few times a year because the scouts go camping
 	
 	
 		you sound like you're a very active <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scout</ENAMEX> Master
 	
 	
 		well <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assistant</ENAMEX> at the moment
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		uh but we're very we're very busy because we go camping <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every month</TIMEX> except <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX> and and then in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> either go to regular <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> or to Philmont
 		and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other months</TIMEX> we all go camping
 	
 	
 		my goodness
 		where's Philmont
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh Philmont</ENAMEX>'s up near your end of the woods
 	
 	
 		i've heard of it before
 	
 	
 		it's in the uh i don't know exactly where it is but it's somewhere in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Montana</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Montana Wyoming</ENAMEX> area
 	
 	
 		oh uh-huh
 	
 	
 		but we we have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> that'll go there in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX> and they'll go up there for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> or two
 	
 	
 		our our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> that's our youngest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> uh went to a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Life</ENAMEX>
 		and it was up in uh and that's been a fantastic deal they really put out on their own and they're not they can't go until they're seventeen or eighteen but they're put out on their own and they just have to survive camping
 	
 	
 		here you can go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philmont</ENAMEX> but you have to be thirteen as of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January first of the year</TIMEX> you want to go which is in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX> so most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> that go are at least <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fourteen</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh well that sounds exciting does uh do you have uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> that are scouts
 	
 	
 		well i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> that's a scout
 	
 	
 		oh how many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> do you have
 	
 	
 		i have also a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> she's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Girl Scout</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh oh
 	
 	
 		they don't do as much camping
 	
 	
 		oh well our our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> really enjoys camping they the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> will even we live in along the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wasatch</ENAMEX>  and they'll go up the mountains just above our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and camp
 	
 	
 		well i'm afraid the nearest mountains to us are several uh <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> away
 	
 	
 		yeah we have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plano</ENAMEX> that we visit all the time
 	
 	
 		well that's why they call it <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plano</ENAMEX> because it's just plain
 	
 	
 		it's terrible
 	
 	
 		it's plain you can from my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> on a clear day i can see <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort Worth</ENAMEX> which is <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about thirty five miles</NUMEX> away
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh well i i when we've been down there i just can't believe the flatness of it all
 		so do you live near Plano
 	
 	
 		well i i live uh just south of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plano</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Richardson</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yes i know that
 	
 	
 		which is the next <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">suburb</ENAMEX> just south going down the freeway
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well we we spend uh part of our time camping <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> we go up into an area and our whole <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> goes
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> and we spend
 		
 		
 	