
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		do you take magazines
 	
 	
 		well the only one i get right now is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> and i'm really kind of tired of it because it comes out on the newsstand before i ever get it
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		so i don't think i'm gonna subscribe to it anymore
 	
 	
 		oh i really enjoy the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> i take i take several uh or i take two through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> and then i take uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reader's Digest National Geographic Geographic</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Better Homes and Gardens</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McCall</ENAMEX>'s
 	
 	
 		so
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh hm Redbook
 	
 	
 		oh that's a lot i like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Redbook</ENAMEX> i'm i never would have time to read all those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> most of the time when i grab <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> i'm at the airport
 	
 	
 		oh do you travel a lot
 	
 	
 		i do i travel a lot and i just usually will do that you know grab <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> then and that's about the only time i read them so sometimes i'll pick one up because it looks good and i don't even get to see it so
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh well i i um
 		uh i work volunteer at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> and a lot of times i'll take them in there and go through them and pick out the articles i like and and read them but i really enjoy the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> i don't i really don't
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		read them as much as i would like to but i  do like to pick them up and go through them especially if they're <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Geographic</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reader's Digest</ENAMEX> i really enjoy those two
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reader's Digest</ENAMEX> is always a good <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> it's always great it's got lots of different things in but as far as the articles go i just find we go round and round on the same things an awful lot so i'm just sort of tired of that and
 	
 	
 		yes
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh
 	
 	
 		i don't know
 	
 	
 		well if the only time you read them is at the airport i can see why
 	
 	
 		yeah and i prefer to read a book i really do i like to do that better
 	
 	
 		um-hum well you must be you must have a job then
 	
 	
 		i don't know
 		i'm sorry
 	
 	
 		you must have a you must be employed
 	
 	
 		oh yeah i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurse</ENAMEX> and and i work float and so i work lots of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> and lots of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> and different times and so
 	
 	
 		oh are you
 		oh
 		you don't have time to read then oh you you said you like a book better
 	
 	
 		yeah i do
 	
 	
 		i read books too but i read them at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> before i go to bed
 	
 	
 		well i read <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about one</NUMEX> page and then i'm asleep so i don't get very far at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> that way and i guess with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the holidays</TIMEX> and all i haven't even picked up a book or a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a month</TIMEX> but
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh uh-huh
 		oh oh we have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> that fies flies for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Airlines</ENAMEX> he's a
 	
 	
 		oh does he really
 	
 	
 		he's a pilot um-hum we have another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> that's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> too but anyway i but when i wake up in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night</TIMEX> and can't go back to sleep a lot of times i read and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> has been really good about that
 	
 	
 		ah
 		yeah yeah that's good
 	
 	
 		because i i do enjoy reading a lot but i'm not employed outside of the home either so i
 	
 	
 		so that gives you a little more time to do that yeah i i have an application in with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> right now for flight attendant actually so
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		that's what i would like to do
 	
 	
 		oh he sure enjoys it
 	
 	
 		yeah well i i was married to someone who worked for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> and i miss having my flight privileges
 	
 	
 		boy we would too because we've got <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> all over the world
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh and</ENAMEX> and it's just really you know i've got <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> all over the world so if i ever want to see them again i need to get me a job at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airlines</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i've always wanted to fly so with my nursing background i'm hoping that i will be able to
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so we'll see but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX> is the best so  trying to hold out for that
 	
 	
 		oh he sure thinks  he sure thinks so i saw by the paper <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> that they're going to lay off <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a thousand</NUMEX>
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two hundred</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> though but it's mostly going to be ground <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		oh really yeah
 	
 	
 		and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> is a pilot too so he'll be okay i
 	
 	
 		he'll be okay yeah yeah i've heard that they were expecting some layoffs but
 	
 	
 		yes uh-huh uh-huh
 	
 	
 		i don't know
 	
 	
 		oh don't you have time to read when you are at work
 	
 	
 		no never  no i don't even have time to go to lunch
 	
 	
 		it's busy huh
 		oh
 	
 	
 		we grab lunch on the floor we bring our lunch and we spend <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ten minutes</TIMEX> where we can and we're busy most all the time there are <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> when you know we can kick back but then we sort of visit
 	
 	
 		oh
 		uh-huh which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> are you at
 	
 	
 		yeah that kind of thing so i'm at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Presbyterian</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandson</ENAMEX> just had open heart surgery but i'm not sure which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		probably <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Children's Medical</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i imagine so um-hum
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah how did he do
 	
 	
 		real well real well yeah he
 	
 	
 		that's good yeah well i float i go to different <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> i work for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> besides <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Presbyterian</ENAMEX> so it it stays pretty interesting that way
 	
 	
 		oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		different places at different times
 	
 	
 		um-hum oh but
 	
 	
 		i keep learning then
 	
 	
 		oh well the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> is one of my the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ladies' Home Journal</ENAMEX> is that what you're referring to
 	
 	
 		uh-huh right
 	
 	
 		that's one of my very favorite magazines
 	
 	
 		it's always been one of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">favorites</ENAMEX> and i <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> turn to <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Can this Marriage be Saved i love that</ENAMEX> column and
 	
 	
 		oh yes me too  uh-huh  that's
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX>  and it's always been one of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">favorites</ENAMEX> but i've just noticed that by the time i get it i would like to have bought it someplace
 	
 	
 		oh
 		
 		
 	