
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay it's what movies have you seen lately and which
 	
 	
 		well uh we just saw JFK uh like yesterday
 	
 	
 		oh did you
 	
 	
 		yeah and
 	
 	
 		did you like it
 	
 	
 		yeah um i'm a big <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oliver Stone</ENAMEX> fan i mean so anything he does i mean i like but yeah have you seen it yet
 	
 	
 		no i haven't
 	
 	
 		i mean you know it's just about the assassination and everything so
 	
 	
 		is it just more or less the things that we've seen and heard before
 	
 	
 		well what some of you have heard some of you haven't i think it's just it's it's pretty much every
 		it's the most plausible theory that i guess um theories that they kind of pulled together in kind of a um
 		pretty much an order pretty much i don't know it's kind of hard to describe i mean it's kind uh you have to kind of see it because it wasn't what i expected because i was thinking it's going to be just kind of a typical rundown of what you know you've heard the past you know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years</TIMEX> but um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i think it's a great movie because uh you leave the uh movie thinking that you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> actually was
 	
 	
 		involved in it
 	
 	
 		they they yeah i mean they you know they did there's always that cover up and that was in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixty</TIMEX> you know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixty three so</TIMEX> i mean uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty eight years later</TIMEX> there's been
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		there's so much more that they've done i mean that screw the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> around so it's it's a great movie
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>'s in actually my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>'s here <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight um</TIMEX> and they're wanting to see it so i'm probably going to go see it again and i'm not one i usually don't like to see a movie you know twice but if it's
 	
 	
 		i
 	
 	
 		gee that's <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a three hour</TIMEX> and like <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty minute</TIMEX> movie and i mean i want to see it again it's a great movie
 	
 	
 		oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's really good
 	
 	
 		oh well we we uh most of our movies are we rent them
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		because uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and i are the only ones left home so we just rent the movies and the last one we saw was Home Alone
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i just loved it
 	
 	
 		yeah that's a good movie i saw that last year
 	
 	
 		yeah well my my even my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandchildren</ENAMEX> like it
 	
 	
 		when it came out
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so it it's been a good movie and we've we've really uh we've in fact we bought the video
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so uh is there any others that you especially stand out that you like
 	
 	
 		yeah i've seen uh
 		saw <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bugsy</ENAMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		oh was that good
 	
 	
 		that's a good movie yeah
 	
 	
 		that was on the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">racketeers</ENAMEX> wasn't it
 	
 	
 		what's that
 	
 	
 		that was on the racketeering
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah that's um
 	
 	
 		and the twenties
 	
 	
 		right it's about uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bugsy Siegel</ENAMEX> who pretty much started <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flamingo</ENAMEX> out in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vegas</ENAMEX> he had like the vision of you know <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vegas</ENAMEX> what it could be what it is today
 	
 	
 		that's right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		at the time it was you know just a complete desert and
 		pretty much
 	
 	
 		they built it on a
 	
 	
 		yeah he had he was given a budget of like a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">million dollars</NUMEX> to go out and build this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flamingo</ENAMEX>
 		and they thought he was crazy it was a stupid idea and you know he built it but it cost like <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">six million dollars</NUMEX> because he had so many overruns and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i mean there was nothing out there and they thought you know it was stupid so he got killed for it because you know he
 	
 	
 		he never did live to see the
 	
 	
 		right and you know the the great thing is you know his <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">six million dollar</NUMEX> investment turned out to be a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">two hundred billion</NUMEX> dollar return so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they killed him because they didn't think it was going to work out but it's a great movie it's a good movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren Beatty</ENAMEX> did a good job and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i've seen uh God what else
 		oh
 		i'm trying to think
 	
 	
 		do you go to a lot of movies
 	
 	
 		uh lately i've just seen <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this past week or so</TIMEX> because
 		i'm uh i had <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple past couple weeks</TIMEX> off so i saw couple of movies we just saw <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bugsy</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JFK</ENAMEX> like in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a two day</TIMEX> period so that was one thing and
 		i can't think of anything else i've seen lately i mean i i i'm a big movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> so i mean i usually rent them too but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well we we really
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cape Fear</ENAMEX> that was another movie i saw <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cape Fear</ENAMEX> is real good
 		
 
 	
 	
 		oh have you seen that one you've see a lot of the latest ones haven't you
 	
 	
 		yeah that's a great movie
 		yeah i'm a big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Martin</ENAMEX>  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		oh did you see uh Beauty and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beast</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no i hadn't seen that yet but uh i'm probably i guess i probably i probably will these at first you know you think of animation as a cartoon that's kind of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> film but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but the more i've heard i'm might have had a couple of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> actually saw it and says it's a pretty good film but
 		um i you know i'll probably get around to seeing it
 	
 	
 		do you have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no i'm i'm <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty three</TIMEX> but i got a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl friend</ENAMEX> she's big time
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh
 	
 	
 		she's been begging me to go you know i want to Beauty and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beast</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> so you'll probably take her and go
 	
 	
 		i
 		yeah so
 	
 	
 		uh-huh we were we're going to that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX> and take our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandchildren</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		well how's the weather up there
 	
 	
 		foggy
 	
 	
 		foggy
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and what part of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> are you all living in
 	
 	
 		uh <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">sixty miles</NUMEX> north of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Salt Lake</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		wow
 	
 	
 		where uh
 		how's the weather down there is it still raining
 	
 	
 		it is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about forty nine forty eight forty nine</NUMEX> fifty degrees it's been pretty mild actually you know
 	
 	
 		yeah kind of cool for down there isn't it
 	
 	
 		kind of muggy yeah it rained <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all last week</TIMEX> had like record uh
 		
 		
 	