
 
     		
 	
 		do you do you have a lot of credit cards
 	
 	
 		um no i have i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> actually
 	
 	
 		well that's all i have too
 	
 	
 		yeah i um one of them one of them i use one of them i don't
 		uh one of them is like an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Airlines</ENAMEX> thing where you get free mileage
 	
 	
 		oh yeah i've heard about those
 	
 	
 		i
 		yeah it's pretty good i use that and i got i'm close to a free plane ticket anywhere in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh that's nice
 	
 	
 		and and the other one is uh um
 		a credit card i got it was a while ago i got it like a free <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX> card and it's good if i ever rent a car it pays for uh it pays for the insurance
 	
 	
 		oh really
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so i keep that i never use that one but i happen to be going on vacation soon and i'm going to be renting a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> so i'll put it on that card and then if i got an accident they would pay for the insurance yeah they would pay for the accident
 	
 	
 		really
 		really
 		yeah i only have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two one</NUMEX> of mine's a gas card that i use just for my <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas</ENAMEX> to and from work and the other one's a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Visa</ENAMEX> for emergencies only
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		like if i go on trips and stuff i take it with me in case my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> breaks down or something but other than that i keep it locked up
 	
 	
 		yeah i never i never uh like i always pay you know like sometimes i use it out of convenience but i don't i don't run like on a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a monthly</TIMEX> balance you know i always pay whatever it is that that month
 	
 	
 		yeah i just i make it a habit not even to carry my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Visa</ENAMEX> because i've seen too many of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> get in deep financial trouble with it
 	
 	
 		um
 		yeah well you can't it sometimes it easy i live in in in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> and uh if you're going to go out and buy something for a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">hundred two hundred dollars</NUMEX>
 		not that it's such a dangerous place but you know i just sometimes i don't feel that comfortable carrying a lot of money around so it's good to have a credit card to pay for it with that um i use it for that where you live in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LA</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		no thank heavens i live in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National City</ENAMEX> which is almost as bad
 	
 	
 		where is that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National City</ENAMEX> it's outside of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh okay okay
 	
 	
 		and unfortunately
 		there's a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gangs</ENAMEX> around here so it's like i don't carry money and i don't carry credit cards
 	
 	
 		right
 		uh yeah it's probably a good idea
 		but uh yeah but i i don't mind i i don't see what the big deal is with um i i i couldn't see spending more than i had to pay the bill with because eventually it's going to catch up with you
 	
 	
 		i know i don't see how <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> can do that either but i know a lot of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> have gotten in trouble deep trouble with them and it's like well why'd you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> do it oh well it's so easy to use
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and it's like yeah it's easy to use but you have to pay for it you know  didn't this dawn on you but
 	
 	
 		sure sure
 	
 	
 		i got my credit cards through a guarantee <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> do you know what that is
 	
 	
 		right uh no
 	
 	
 		you give them you put so much money in an annuity
 		and it guarantees your credit card like say if something happened to you they could still pay off the balance with what's in there
 	
 	
 		right
 		that's cool
 	
 	
 		and whatever your limit is you keep that much in your annuity fund
 		and it's worked pretty good for what i've had it for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about five years</TIMEX> now
 		and you can take the annuity out the money out of the annuity if you want to but it's just there like you know in case you died suddenly or something
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know they wouldn't be stuck with the bill
 	
 	
 		cool cool that that's
 	
 	
 		so i like it that way
 	
 	
 		yeah you know they get paid for if you're dead right you know
 	
 	
 		yeah at least they won't be coming after my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> you know saying hey your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s charged so much money on this credit card we want the money
 	
 	
 		that's true but then again you don't have to deal with him if you're dead so
 	
 	
 		no but
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i don't know i wouldn't want to leave him and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> in that kind of a situation
 	
 	
 		that's true that's true
 	
 	
 		but i'll tell you what it comes in real handy when you've got kids
 		cause we went we went on a trip to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX> we drove there and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> broke down and it was me and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and our <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> in that car and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX> is really hot
 	
 	
 		
 
 		right
 	
 	
 		and it's like you know if we didn't have that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Visa</ENAMEX> we would've been stuck there in that heat for heaven knows how long
 	
 	
 		yeah that was like yeah like like the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time i ever got a credit card was for that reason because i was in uh where the heck was i
 		i forget where i was i know i was in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one time</TIMEX> and they ran out of money but i couldn't get money on my credit card either oh i was up i was dating a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> upstate <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> and i was up in uh upstate and i
 		had been in college and i guess i took like a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">hundred two hundred dollars</NUMEX> with me or whatever at that time time maybe fifty bucks was enough to live on for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> but i  i took some money with me and i ran out of money like at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the end of the first</TIMEX> weekend i was supposed to be there for a week
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		huh
 	
 	
 		and i needed to i called up my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> and i said <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> you know go to my bank account and withdraw a couple of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundred</NUMEX> bucks or whatever it was and could you
 		send it <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Western Union</ENAMEX> and it was a pain in the neck i had to like wait till <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> and you know wait till the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> opened and it took time and everything became a pain so what i did was i uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so what i did right after that is i got myself a credit card in case it ever happened again i can always you know buy something on the credit card and and not have to worry about carrying cash around
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so that was about <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten ten</NUMEX> twelve <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> and i've always had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> since and like you said for that reason it's it's easy
 		you know if you need the cash i couldn't imagine
 		
 		
 	