
 
     		
 	
 		why don't you tell me about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brewers</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well uh  i guess the thing about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brewers</ENAMEX> is i think their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX> policies have been a little misguided lately
 		um
 		i think that's their main problem uh they seem to have have stuck with the same core of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin Yount Paul Molitor</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Gantner</ENAMEX>
 		who uh they're real good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> but they seem to just depend on them to produce a pennant and it it doesn't it isn't working
 	
 	
 		well the problem with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rangers</ENAMEX> is they've got a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offense</ENAMEX> they just don't have any pitching and really haven't had any pitching for years
 		they're the top offensive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> around but
 		defense and pitching wins your games over the long haul
 	
 	
 		except for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">papa</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ryan</ENAMEX> anyway
 	
 	
 		well that's true but he only comes every <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> times so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		that's right he can't win them all for him
 	
 	
 		he can't win them all and he's getting a little bit up there
 	
 	
 		yeah i think uh the thing about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brewers</ENAMEX> is too their pitching they never have really had real good pitching uh
 		last time they had really good pitching was back in the early eighties when they got to the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World Series</ENAMEX> was with uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vuckovich</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fingers</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rollie Fingers</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah and of course uh
 		he got them to the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Series</ENAMEX> but then just before the Series <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that year</TIMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty two</NUMEX> he um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh</ENAMEX> threw his elbow out or something shoulder or elbow i can't remember which and uh
 		they're number <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">right-hander</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bullpen</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pete Ladd</ENAMEX> who was kind of a rookie <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that year</TIMEX> uh had to take his place and uh i think that's why they lost the series because in in game <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saint Louis</ENAMEX>
 		they had a pretty good lead going into late innings and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ladd</ENAMEX> got rattled when he didn't get some calls and they ended up losing the game uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ole Mustache Fingers</ENAMEX> would not have done that
 	
 	
 		well <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rollie</ENAMEX> was
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rollie</ENAMEX> was more uh  well i guess he's uh is he in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hall of Fame</ENAMEX> already i don't even remember
 	
 	
 		i can't remember if he's made it or not yet he he may not have been i don't know when he retired actually
 	
 	
 		you got to be retired for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX> to be eligible
 	
 	
 		yeah but that was i think eighty <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> was
 		well eighty one was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> i think that he won the the uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cy Young and the MVP and the Fireman of the Year Award</ENAMEX> all at the same time i think but uh but in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty two</NUMEX> i think he won something some kind of award had a lot of saves anyway
 	
 	
 		yeah we had a game here where uh
 		we had <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goose Gossage</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Goose</ENAMEX> and uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ryan</ENAMEX> combine and
 		they got i don't know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ryan</ENAMEX> got his <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three hundred</NUMEX> something win and at the same time <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Goose</ENAMEX> got his <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three hundred</NUMEX> and something save and they were you know the same number and they said that it was an unusual occurrence to have that
 	
 	
 		well i'd forgotten that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gossage</ENAMEX> was with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rangers</ENAMEX> the the he was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year last year</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah but he's not coming back
 	
 	
 		now did they pick him up uh sometime in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the middle of the season</TIMEX> or what
 	
 	
 		well no they got him at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the very beginning of the season</TIMEX> but he and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bobby Valentine</ENAMEX> didn't come along so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goose is Goose</ENAMEX> is history
 	
 	
 		yeah well he's been quite a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reliever</ENAMEX> in his time
 	
 	
 		oh yeah he's a he's he's definitely headed to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hall of Fame</ENAMEX>
 		But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rangers</ENAMEX> have you know a a pretty good lineup now um with the with the addition of the uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dickey Thorne</ENAMEX> at uh short stop that ought to help them but their problem is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">other than Ryan</ENAMEX> and an occasional flash of brilliance of other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> there's just nobody there
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well we'll be looking for them to uh to improve in that area i guess because at least the uh
 		now that i think about them a little bit i'm getting sort of back through the football season back into <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> i realize when you think of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rangers</ENAMEX> now you got a real good looking young outfield there for the most part and uh
 		quite a few of the infielders are
 		uh probably have good real good careers still ahead of them i'm not sure why they got rid of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buechele</ENAMEX> but i guess it worked out for him okay
 	
 	
 		well at least he got to play in a championship the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rangers</ENAMEX> have never won the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">division</ENAMEX> so
 		we're we're obviously not going to last year
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Inky</ENAMEX> went the wrong way though didn't he
 	
 	
 		yeah i think he's history
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		he is history
 	
 	
 		now who did they trade him to i forgot <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cleveland</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Detroit</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Detroit</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well they didn't yeah they he went to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Detroit</ENAMEX> they really didn't get much for him
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh they released him really didn't they
 	
 	
 		yeah they released him and he had to go around trying to sign up with somebody
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but he proved to be a total disaster
 	
 	
 		my goodness when he was when he was when he could really get into a ball though he was uh had a lot of power i tell you he reminds me a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gorman Thomas</ENAMEX> remember him
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">center fielder</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brewers</ENAMEX> there for a while there was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> that
 	
 	
 		yeah he did something he i saw i saw him hit a grand slam once in a game when i was there but i also saw him
 		drop a ball that cost <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a couple</NUMEX> runs ended up costing the game so he could you know he could be both brilliant and with a bat and just a disaster in the field
 	
 	
 		uh well i don't think his fielding was generally that bad he uh as a matter of fact he was to
 	
 	
 		it was early on it got better but it was pretty bad at the beginning
 	
 	
 		yeah right
 		yeah he did get better and i think uh he was one of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bamburger</ENAMEX>'s big projects when he took over at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brewers</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Milwaukee</ENAMEX>
 		he was the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> that was up and down uh
 		
 		
 	