
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		now are we off and running
 	
 	
 		that you were saying sorry
 	
 	
 		oh i was just saying i guess old age has a few compensations i don't have to plan as carefully as i used to but uh
 	
 	
 		do you feel like you you took the steps that you you were glad that you took um earlier i mean would you have done anything differently
 	
 	
 		no i don't think so uh we have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and we were able to put <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all three</NUMEX> of them through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> and um
 	
 	
 		that's that's quite a feat in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		economic situation
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		that's wonderful um i'm sort of beginning in that score um we have a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two year old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> and hope to have another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> soon so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's it's not easy putting enough aside but we're doing a um our best to try and have fairly regular meetings to discuss at least where our goals are sometimes um
 		it is less consistent than than it could be in terms of our ability to put money aside but um
 		i'm i'm curious about the things that you did that that seemed to work best for you that you'd pass on to somebody else
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh well
 	
 	
 		as as advice
 	
 	
 		the only way if if you spend all you take in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every month</TIMEX>
 		you're uh living beyond your means
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and emergencies or what we could would consider an emergency uh always come up
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i i i don't care how how you how closely you think you figured and then planned something always comes up
 		so uh when i i guess we started by necessity because we went to uh law school on my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">GI Bill</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the days</TIMEX> when uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> paid
 		uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX>'s tuition and and bought books up to a certain amount plus uh gave the veteran a stipend we started off with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ninety</NUMEX> dollars <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX> and then a little bit later got up to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five dollars</NUMEX> a month
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so there was no way that we could do except when we cashed our <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">monthly</TIMEX> stipend was to put <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty</TIMEX> dollars a week in an envelope
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		deciding that it was better to go without <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day a week</TIMEX> than for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four days</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the month</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then uh later on
 		when we got out of school my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> got recalled into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX> when the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Korean</ENAMEX> mess came up
 		and uh
 		so we had already established the envelope habit and uh
 	
 	
 		and the envelope is your savings
 	
 	
 		no no no this was our <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> budget
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		but uh we realized very early on that if we were going to have money to buy <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> and that sort of thing that we would have to save up beforehand
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so uh
 		we uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh</ENAMEX> began uh in nineteen fifty uh to pay cash for everything we bought a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> in nineteen fifty and paid it off in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three months</TIMEX>
 		so since then except for a house
 		houses we've paid cash for everything and uh to illustrate how well that works so that you have the opportunity to take care of special pricing
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX> was transferred from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Carolina</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> one time
 		and because <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">gas</ENAMEX> was much much cheaper to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cook</ENAMEX> with than electricity
 		this one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> that we were transferred with uh bought a gas stove
 		a very simplified gas stove for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a hundred</TIMEX> and forty some odd dollars
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we had uh in storage and used uh just a little teeny gas stove but after we got to Waco
 		we saw an ad in the paper <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> where a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> who had uh was moving into a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> with a built in oven had
 		the very best stove that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sears</ENAMEX> made at the time with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> ovens a grill in the middle on top clock all the fancy amenities
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and we were able to buy it for a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">hundred dollars</NUMEX>
 		because we had the cash
 	
 	
 		yes yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh uh
 	
 	
 		that's that's been the case for us with with uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> and our preference recently has been used <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> so it's been nice to be able to negotiate when you have cash when you're buying a car
 	
 	
 		the
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		well that's a that's a an important lesson do you feel like you've passed that along to your <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> given how different the economy's been in their lives
 	
 	
 		no unfortunately we have not except for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> daughter-in-law and uh  rise up and call her blessed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh for some reason or other my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> didn't see fit to give the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> a meaningful allowance he just felt he had to keep control control of the purse strings
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh when they went off to college they had never really budgeted
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh that that was a big mistake so even though you know your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are going to make mistakes
 		uh i don't i don't know how to tell you
 		
 		
 	