
 
     		
 	
 		name's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		hi i'm <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rita</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Garland</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh nice to meet you <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rita</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh we have quite a in depth subject here don't we
 	
 	
 		yeah we do
 	
 	
 		why couldn't we get something simple like movies or books something more uh more fun
 	
 	
 		exactly some of the boring ones you just kind of babble on i guess
 	
 	
 		yeah well we will we'll just give lots to talk about won't we
 	
 	
 		all right we ready to give it a shot all right
 	
 	
 		yeah that's right
 	
 	
 		
 
 		okay
 	
 	
 		okay well uh i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> of my own
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i feel pretty strongly about it i don't mind being drug tested and i don't feel the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> should
 	
 	
 		yeah i agree with that i think especially in some of the the jobs that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> has you just need <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are you know
 	
 	
 		now you know
 	
 	
 		who are sober all the time to take care of them you know you're paying them to do a certain job and if they're
 		they're on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> and doing things they're not supposed to be doing
 	
 	
 		no i i i you know i think sometimes that when you fly for example you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX> and things like that or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that are even  using uh automated equipment of some kind where another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> could be injured you know
 	
 	
 		absolutely
 	
 	
 		you know and uh well a lot of times i think it depends upon
 		the occasion but you know i've never had any problem with being drug tested and i wouldn't think that other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> should have either i guess that's sort of a personal opinion
 	
 	
 		yeah well you know what i think part of the thing that you do when you apply for a job is you you know you tell them that you're gonna do a certain type of work and be a certain type of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> and
 		you know i think part of that is living the law
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i know if i had my own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> i'd want <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are honest in all they're dealings so
 	
 	
 		well i have a private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">high school</ENAMEX> and uh we uh get permission from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> before the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> enroll
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		to allow random drug testing because i've seen what can happen
 		to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youngsters</ENAMEX> who were not on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> being around it and getting influenced by their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peers</ENAMEX> who are
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and there's a lot of it in the public school system
 	
 	
 		oh absolutely i was i went to school in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plano</ENAMEX> when i was growing up
 	
 	
 		and
 	
 	
 		and just i don't know it was  i was surprised how much of it was there
 	
 	
 		yeah and of course good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> try to stay away from it but i've seen kids
 		start out not being on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> and end up being there because it was being sold right out under under their noses you know
 	
 	
 		yep
 	
 	
 		so uh you know i feel pretty strongly about it i you know i know that
 		there are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that say we're violating the civil rights and what have you but they don't have to enroll
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know they don't have to take that job if that's the way they feel about it
 	
 	
 		yeah and i think the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> part to that is you know they're also violating civil rights when they're using these <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> illegal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah that's right they're violating ours you know
 	
 	
 		yeah and i think you know
 		personally i the way i feel about it is it's a lot better that we go ahead and and help these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you know that when we find that they're they're using <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> that we help them to get over that so they can be
 		good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> or not not necessarily i'm not saying they're bad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> but they they can be productive people
 	
 	
 		well they can be more productive and more useful yeah i feel that way too we don't uh kick them out we ask that we call <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> in if we haven't had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> test positive yet but
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		if it did we would call the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> in and uh you know get help for them before it's too late
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		absolutely you know i think i look at especially some of the professional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">athletes</ENAMEX> and i was a big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mavericks fan</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time</TIMEX> and i watched <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roy Tarpley</ENAMEX> you know
 	
 	
 		oh he just
 	
 	
 		he could have lost his life if it wasn't for someone who cared enough to say let's give you a drug test and find out where you're at
 	
 	
 		um-hum and uh you know it's just really a shame that he he couldn't get enough help to keep his career going
 	
 	
 		absolutely i think it's important that we remember that it's not the job that's important thing it's it's the individual
 		kind of like what you were saying that it's just i don't know to me that's it's putting the focus back where it should be you know sure
 		some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> might not appreciate it but when it comes right down to it you're more worried about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> and where their status is
 	
 	
 		yeah i think so and uh i think that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youngsters</ENAMEX> who looked up to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roy Tarpleys</ENAMEX> and
 		uh the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that have gotten into <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> i think they're going to be more conscious of the effect it can have and they get you know look at what he's thrown away
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know a wonderful career a tremendous amount of money uh because he couldn't get enough help to over come it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and probably wasn't started early enough either
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		no but i think they can influence the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youngsters</ENAMEX> in a good positive way when they're good role models
 	
 	
 		oh absolutely
 		and i think that's the key
 	
 	
 		now i think so too and like it's important you know i don't i have never been against being drug tested myself and so i feel that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> of a company you know you set forth the policy and you follow through with it too
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know and it doesn't exclude this one or that one it's everybody's it's all it's all inclusive
 	
 	
 		yep
 	
 	
 		i know <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> does that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> uh you know they never know who who's gonna be called
 	
 	
 		well that's good i i i like that idea very much
 	
 	
 		you know
 		um-hum it's just a random thing that they'll get a call in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX>
 		
 		
 	