
 
     		
 	
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s place in the workplace huh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh to quote my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>'s place is in the stove
 		i have to disagree my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> works  say what what do you do
 	
 	
 		oh i disagree i disagree
 		yeah so do i so do i
 		um i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lab</ENAMEX> tech
 	
 	
 		are you
 	
 	
 		yep
 	
 	
 		well i guess as far as roles in the workplace they've uh they've made some you know pretty serious uh ground in the last <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty forty years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		that right they've generally increased considerably
 	
 	
 		uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> is a she's a medical professional
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		and you know she says that in in in order to get paid the same as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> you have to do twice the work
 	
 	
 		yeah see i can
 	
 	
 		but fortunately it's not that tough
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well yeah that i can see that i can see that  i i i do think that uh um higher positions like administrative more often go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> than they do the woman
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah yeah i i'll grant you that
 	
 	
 		but hopefully that'll change soon
 	
 	
 		well it hasn't been true of any of my companies
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		yeah because the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> that i hire are ones that are capable
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		if they're capable they can do anything they wanna do
 	
 	
 		right well i work for a private <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">laboratory</ENAMEX> and and when it's a small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> you see where you're you're kind of overstepped because you are a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> and but i think uh it i think it's starting to change
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		well i hope so i really do
 	
 	
 		yes i do too considering i am a woman
 	
 	
 		yeah well for your sake sure but uh i think that as long as
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> society is inundated as it is by the commercial market you know the
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		television's commercials in particular uh  progress is gonna be rather rapid but shaping role <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">models</ENAMEX> is gonna be a problem
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because you know they don't wanna rock the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> with anybody
 	
 	
 		right right
 	
 	
 		and you know i don't know how you perceive life but i know that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are prejudiced and they bigoted and they carry their their convictions all the way to the bone no matter what  they say
 	
 	
 		right right right
 	
 	
 		and uh you know i'm the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> one well i flunked the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MCP</ENAMEX> test big time
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		you know what that is
 	
 	
 		no huh-uh
 	
 	
 		oh  a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> were driving along the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> in a convertible
 		and they have a car wreck and the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s killed
 		and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> is rushed to the emergency <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> walks in looks down says i can't operate on him that's my son
 	
 	
 		all right the that was his mother
 	
 	
 		all right you passed
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		believe me it's not that easy for a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> to understand that
 	
 	
 		i yeah i can yeah i can see that i can see that
 	
 	
 		yeah and i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman doctor</ENAMEX>  yeah
 	
 	
 		oh really  isn't that strange i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> doctor
 	
 	
 		really well actually we go to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doctor Garcia</ENAMEX>'s office we started going with him soon as he got done with his residency
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		he was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> at the emergency <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> when we went there and then when he got his office <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">well</ENAMEX> we just you know stayed with him and he's hired this other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> and uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> says that she's a better doctor
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i don't know you know  i see <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> once every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six months</TIMEX> you know
 		but uh
 	
 	
 		well that's what that i think that's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> place that you know the roles of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> are changing you don't see um
 		uh you well you see a lot more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in medical profession higher up as in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> and everything i know several that are are pathologists and forensic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pathologists</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know used to you didn't see that or hear of it at all
 	
 	
 		yeah well getting into medical school is no no mean trick either
 	
 	
 		right that's true that's true
 	
 	
 		but uh as far as a you know the the the role of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in the workplace i think <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> has come remarkably far considering considering the  the high density of rednecks that there are around
 	
 	
 		oh yeah isn't that true isn't that true
 	
 	
 		i'm a i'm a transplant i'm you know we came from out of state
 	
 	
 		uh so did i
 	
 	
 		when i was very young but it was too late i was already formed
 	
 	
 		oh i came as an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adult</ENAMEX> here
 	
 	
 		yeah well you know i was like uh i guess <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and we came from uh a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> that was
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> is strong to say the least
 	
 	
 		did she work
 	
 	
 		um no not outside the home
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		no she was a she went to college and you know correspondence <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courses</ENAMEX> and whatnot but my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> were in my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> was in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and all the time that uh you know he was in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">well</ENAMEX> she's never had to work
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know he always provided the the financial support but she has worked uh therapeutically you know she something to do
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		i mean raising <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	