
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		do you rely on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> or TV or what for your current events
 	
 	
 		well uh mostly the radio i listen to the radio i'm <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> and so i have the radio going and listen to the news there and then uh
 		i watch the news on TV at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> we have a local newspaper that we subscribe to but that's
 		um all the newspaper my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and i used to take the the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> and that had a lot of good information
 	
 	
 		are you in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Salt Lake City</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		we're fifty <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">miles</NUMEX> north
 	
 	
 		so you're a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">suburb</ENAMEX> of it then
 	
 	
 		right right so we don't take the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Salt Lake</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> how about
 	
 	
 		okay
 		we have we have in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> what's called talk radio
 	
 	
 		oh yes
 	
 	
 		and it's news <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty four hours a day</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you don't listen to it <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty four hours</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		if you're in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty minutes</TIMEX> in traffic you sure get a bunch of news real quick
 	
 	
 		get caught up on it fast
 	
 	
 		so you primarily rely on on the radio
 	
 	
 		right
 		right yes and we have um the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX> we listen to is out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kansas</ENAMEX> or out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Salt Lake City</ENAMEX> and it's an all news or an all talk <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">station</ENAMEX> also it doesn't have the
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		the music and thing so
 	
 	
 		do you have where these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> call in express their opinions and talk back
 	
 	
 		yes yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah same thing down here it's uh really gets some really neat information that way don't we
 	
 	
 		uh right get a lot of different different viewpoints  have you
 	
 	
 		i definitely take the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> and read the headlines of every <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> and that helps keep up on too how about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> do you take any magazines
 	
 	
 		i
 		at the office
 		nothing newsworthy uh uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Geographic Reader's Digest</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh
 	
 	
 		uh i'm afraid we're probably reliant on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> and radio
 	
 	
 		right that
 	
 	
 		television news i'm not interested in their in them
 	
 	
 		
 
 		right that you don't like the television news the television reports
 	
 	
 		uh no i don't uh especially in depth things like <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">60 Minutes</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but
 		oh uh-huh
 	
 	
 		or or whatever else they call i think they're very biased
 	
 	
 		they are right presents <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> viewpoint and not the other
 	
 	
 		uh
 		uh
 		journalistic uh they'll go into some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> with TV cameras rolling and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because he sticks up his hand doesn't want to be seen he's considered he's supposed to be considered guilty
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they're charging they're making a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> look guilty before he's even given a chance to hear his side of the story but
 	
 	
 		well you know i think there's a lot of that in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> reporting too i  because a lot and i don't know how much of what we read is is really accurate a few of the stories that
 	
 	
 		definitely
 	
 	
 		that you know i've been personably <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> known what's going on and then you read what's in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> about it and it doesn't always match up
 		so
 	
 	
 		you really wonder what you hear from this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> thing that going on is is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> all that great you know is he really going to
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it sounds as more and more came out that he and what's his name is gone now
 	
 	
 		um-hum <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gorbachev</ENAMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gorbachev Gorbachev</ENAMEX> got into a political quarrel <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about three years ago</TIMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gorbachev</ENAMEX> just got beat to the punch politically
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and i mean even with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gorbachev</ENAMEX> goes to his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> to clean out his desk for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next day</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> is already there sitting there
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		oh that's ugly
 	
 	
 		uh it is and and like you say we really i'm really not sure how much of what we hear is reliable
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and i went out we have a golden spike
 		um railroad
 		monument oh it's probably about fifty miles from here and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Friday</TIMEX> we went out there to watch the train come in the steam engine and there was uh there was a probably a group of
 		oh maybe fifty to seventy <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> out there and the newspaper <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> was there and he took a picture and it was in the paper <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next day</TIMEX> and it
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		well just the opposite they probably had oh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the picture and he said
 		um just a small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> had turned out to watch the steam engine come in and the way it was printed and the way the picture was it looked like that was all there was was right there when there was
 	
 	
 		i'll be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> gummed
 	
 	
 		quite quite a few more there you know so
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		i think you have to be careful when when we take in the information what we take as truth and what we don't
 	
 	
 		we lost the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this month</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh i read that
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dallas Times Herald</ENAMEX> went under we were one of the few
 	
 	
 		yes
 		
 
 	
 	
 		few <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> remaining big <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> that had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> papers
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and and we're sorry now you got the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fort Worth Press</ENAMEX> and uh uh no <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fort Worth Star Telegram The Press</ENAMEX> went <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dallas Mourning News</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		oh
 		
 
 		oh was it financial trouble that's what they went under for wasn't it
 	
 	
 		yep yep competition killed them and and then well the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morning News</ENAMEX> finally bought out the the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herald</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh yes oh well that's that's too bad which one did did you subscribe to that one
 	
 	
 		of course closed it down
 		
 
 		but
 		oh i've been with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dallas Morning News</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh ah
 	
 	
 		it is the conservative paper and i'm probably lean to being conservative as opposed to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberal</ENAMEX> so and the other was kind of the liberal paper so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh oh</ENAMEX>
 		oh huh well that
 	
 	
 		so i feel sorry for all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> in town they have to read the good stuff now
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh yes well that's i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom</ENAMEX> and i think um
 	
 	
 		
 
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	