
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		hi uh how do you feel about gun control
 	
 	
 		oh i don't like a total ban on it
 		but on the other hand i don't like total <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">idiots</ENAMEX> pulling what they did down in uh my home <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> down in uh near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort Hood</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh i think the right of ownership needs to be protected but i don't think there's too much wrong with having it registered and having you think about it a little bit
 	
 	
 		i don't think so either and i think that every <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> should be covered cover covered
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		because i think that uh and it doesn't hurt <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to have a waiting period
 	
 	
 		well they make us wait to get married in most <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> i don't
 	
 	
 		yes  right
 	
 	
 		
 
 		unless you want to fly to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX> or so
 	
 	
 		uh-huh but i
 	
 	
 		yeah uh
 		it's just sickening i was on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Texas</ENAMEX> campus when that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chapman</ENAMEX> climbed the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tower</ENAMEX> and killed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">twenty two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> one of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> was wounded and he was from
 	
 	
 		kill a
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Paz</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bolivia</ENAMEX> and they flew and got his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> here real quick but and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hippie</ENAMEX> pulled him out of the out of the additional gunshot range so ever since then old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oscar</ENAMEX> said hippies are okay my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buddy</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 		
 
 	
 	
 		it was back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the sixties</TIMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> was going on so
 	
 	
 		yes i remember when that happened
 	
 	
 		so i've lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> where they have a uh pistol control and uh
 		big deal you go across the county line into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yonkers</ENAMEX> and you can buy a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pistol</ENAMEX> and come back into the city
 	
 	
 		so there isn't really a gun control there
 	
 	
 		not really
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		well i i think that every <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> should be covered from <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">rifles</ENAMEX> and the automatics and and handguns because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> need if they're out after a gun they need a cooling off period
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		we have <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> in our home but my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> uh used to hunt all my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX> hunt
 	
 	
 		um i've got a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">shotgun</ENAMEX> and a pistol
 	
 	
 		oh we have
 	
 	
 		and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> have BBs
 	
 	
 		
 
 		sometimes i think they're about as dangerous but uh
 	
 	
 		well i'd shoot it more often it wasn't against the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> ordinance those birds steal my <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bird dog</ENAMEX> food my i don't think that's fair
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 		well we live close to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wasatch</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">well</ENAMEX> we live right on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wasatch</ENAMEX> front so we're only about well we have  mountains in our backyard and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">deer</ENAMEX> come down and eat our
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">uh shrubs</ENAMEX> during the winter
 	
 	
 		do they really
 	
 	
 		uh-huh we we had a snow storm <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">deer</ENAMEX> come down and eat the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">shrubs</ENAMEX> they keep them trimmed for us
 	
 	
 		we got the air-conditioning going in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> today
 	
 	
 		oh my heck
 	
 	
 		it must be <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">seventy five degrees</NUMEX> out there
 	
 	
 		i think it's about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty</TIMEX> well it's <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about twenty eight</TIMEX> here
 	
 	
 		i don't think that has anything to do with gun control
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		
 
 		uh
 	
 	
 		but i i'm i
 	
 	
 		i i don't think it's a constitutional well so what if it's constitutional or not if if if my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> drives to west <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> alone she's going to carry a gun i don't care what they say
 	
 	
 		well don't you think too if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> i mean like in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX> and these places that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> comes in and takes over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> don't you think if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> had a gun they would have more say in in in establishing a democracy
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		wasn't that amazing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX> was a semi <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> and no <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> were allowed and all of a sudden everybody has one that wants to fight the war where did they come from
 	
 	
 		yeah uh-huh
 	
 	
 		they were hidden under the bed all these years
 	
 	
 		then they must have been
 	
 	
 		i don't know i don't know
 	
 	
 		they must have been hidden somewhere because they came out
 	
 	
 		well you know one thing about the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Killeen</ENAMEX> situation that was pointed up is there were a lot of military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the  in and around
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX> had been allowed to carry even side arms they could have stopped this idiot quicker
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 		i had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cop</ENAMEX> once say
 		in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> it's not against the law let's see what i say i said it would be all right legally if i put on a a side <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> and walked down the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> with a gun strapped on my side it's clear view and you couldn't arrest me he said yes i can arrest you i said what for he said breaking the peace i said who's peace am a bothering he said mine i'm the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cop</ENAMEX>
 		that was that was a joke it was a joke
 	
 	
 		is that right
 		oh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		but i think if you take them away from everybody then only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> will have it and you would have more problems but but registration won't hurt anybody will it
 	
 	
 		no that's what i think that it should be is registration and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> that can be traced
 	
 	
 		yeah you can go to pawnshop i don't i don't know if you all live near big <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">city Salt Lake City</ENAMEX> if they've got them or not but you go to a pawnshop and buy it for cash and you don't have to show nothing
 	
 	
 		but then
 		no
 		i think they have um
 		and you just hand over the cash and that's it
 	
 	
 		yeah you if you can show them a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX>'s license but you can steal those so easily it's pitiful
 	
 	
 		uh-huh well i'm <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about an eight</NUMEX> on that i think that uh that we need gun control but you know so many laws would be uh necessary if we'd just use common sense
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know just registering the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> and wow i don't know i guess <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> lose their common sense when they when they get mad or when they
 	
 	
 		get too drunk
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i'll be there's a law in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> says you can't have them in bar i think it would be a lot more sense if they say please check them at the front door because i know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are in there with them on
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		oh yeah i it just nerve racking to know that if you're in a
 	
 	
 		that that you're in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX> and somebody has a gun next to you
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		they're not supposed to but then again so
 		
 		
 	