
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		um the one that i'm most familiar with are the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Utah Jazz</ENAMEX> i guess that's because they they're <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Utah Jazz</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		what are they called
 		Jazz oh never heard of them
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">uh-huh the Jazz</ENAMEX> right and  they're a fairly new ball team as far as ball <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> go  um
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh
 	
 	
 		they probably oh it's probably <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five to ten years</TIMEX> that they've they've been
 		you know in existence and but they've done really fairly well for for a new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> they i think out of the last like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> games they've won
 		won <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> which is pretty good because a lot of them were on you know on the road and um
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		i think as far as whichever <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">division</ENAMEX> they're in they're rated either number one or number <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> so that's yeah that's fairly good and how about
 	
 	
 		uh-huh well that's good
 		yeah well maybe we'll hear of them more often
 	
 	
 		yeah and how about yourself
 	
 	
 		well i guess what we have here is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mavericks</ENAMEX> is that right basketball what is
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		what is our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> basketball i'm not really sure
 	
 	
 		
 
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dallas Mavericks i</ENAMEX> that
 	
 	
 		one is soccer one is basketball the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mavericks</ENAMEX> must be basketball
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> plays basketball you wouldn't know it would you from this conversation i'm familiar with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Teddy Bears</ENAMEX> and they're my favorite
 	
 	
 		oh well well tell me about yeah tell me about her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> how old is she
 	
 	
 		well now she's twelve so she but she's been playing <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four or five years</TIMEX> on a little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Teddy Bears and</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh has she
 		well how fun
 	
 	
 		that's been fun so now she just made her middle school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> so that's
 	
 	
 		well great
 	
 	
 		and they've won so far that's good but uh
 	
 	
 		she must really enjoy it
 	
 	
 		yes she likes it a lot yeah she really does and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lakers</ENAMEX> i guess is my favorite as far as
 	
 	
 		well good
 	
 	
 		as anything i know about <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX> yeah because i my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boyfriend</ENAMEX>'s in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> professional <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX>
 		oh uh-huh
 	
 	
 		i'm gonna have to look at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lakers</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> a lot so i guess i'll get used to it i learned a lot about <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX>  so
 	
 	
 		have to at least
 		oh  uh-huh well does a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> was was your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> just interested in <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX> or why did she start playing
 	
 	
 		uh i guess because her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> signed up
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and she wanted to sign up she twirls and she's she's been real real involved in that so we haven't had time for soccer
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh
 	
 	
 		which is the most important thing around here pretty i mean all the little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> play soccer
 	
 	
 		oh is it
 		oh
 	
 	
 		they even have like a preschool soccer team
 	
 	
 		my word
 	
 	
 		it's big in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> and i maybe all over now i don't know but
 	
 	
 		oh wow
 	
 	
 		uh it's very big here but we didn't have that time
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so i did let her play <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX> and i like it because it's indoors
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah  i like indoor things so yeah
 	
 	
 		right  well that's good if she made her middle school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> she must be fairly fairly proficient
 	
 	
 		yeah well she's pretty fast she's not real big but she's real fast and so um
 	
 	
 		uh-huh oh oh well yeah it's hard to just for me to picture these little ones that <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX> is pretty big to be thrown
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know up that that high
 	
 	
 		yeah but oh in the beginning you know they couldn't even make the basket and they were allowed to stand halfway forward to take that take solid shots and they couldn't even get the ball that high because they were so little and not strong enough
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh
 		right uh-huh
 	
 	
 		and then uh her last game just before the whistle blew they had <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two seconds</TIMEX> left
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		she threw the ball from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">center court</ENAMEX> and it went right into the basket
 	
 	
 		oh wow  well great  oh that's great  now do
 	
 	
 		so she was the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> after all those years of trying to get that ball up in that basket so and so that was pretty fun to see the improvement  and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX> was behind us in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bleachers</ENAMEX> but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		from the other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> and he said  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> came <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early this year</TIMEX>  so yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well how fun now do you have any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> that play or
 	
 	
 		no my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> never played uh basketball he's he's grown and he he's in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX> and he swam some
 	
 	
 		how old is he
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		mostly he was a student  so
 	
 	
 		oh he was he was he was in
 	
 	
 		yeah he's a national merit <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> and he speaks <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> languages and all that so he wasn't much into sports he did play <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> for a while and he liked that
 	
 	
 		great oh great
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh
 	
 	
 		but um he didn't he didn't play <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX> at all
 	
 	
 		well that's fun have you ever played basketball
 	
 	
 		i did i played <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX> in high school i loved it that and volleyball
 	
 	
 		that is i've just played it for fun i've never done anything you know organized or on a a school <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> or anything but i think it's a real fun game
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah i love it i think it's my favorite and it's my favorite to watch
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and when i was in high school i was a twirler and so
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		i always enjoyed that and cheerleading you know we got to do it indoors
 	
 	
 		oh uh-huh right
 	
 	
 		so i always liked the basketball games better than the football games because you weren't out in the cold so
 	
 	
 		right
 		well it seems like i don't know basketball maybe i don't know that much  but it doesn't seem like <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX>'s that aggressive compared to <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		well yeah and it's easier to follow
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		if the ball goes in they get <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> points football everybody falls on top of each other and it's real difficult to say
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		who  right right that's
 	
 	
 		exactly what went wrong you know for me anyway  so
 		
 		
 	