
 
     		
 	
 		what do you think
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well  uh this is this is about drug testing right
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		well uh i'm  i'm certainly under the uh uh the influence of the idea that that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> needs to have less control on what uh
 		what the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> do although i do see this as uh
 		uh something that definitely needs to be taken care of whether that whether that should be put in the hands of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporation</ENAMEX> or in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> or the hands of hands of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is a you know a a different question i think as far as i'm concerned uh in a in other words i am favor in favor of drug control or or or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> testing
 		um i was drug tested when i came to my job here at <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> yet but but at the same time i don't think uh that should be governed by by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> uh per se i think it should be by more by the private institution
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		how about you
 	
 	
 		yeah i think they the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> should uh do all that they should uh have drug screening before they hire an employee
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh anytime that an employee like if they're coming to late work all the time and uh and if they if they're especially if there's not on the line or any kind of sensitive job where
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know if they can if they made a mistake it would cost a lot of money or or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s lives then they need to be watched carefully so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		sure
 		uh-huh yeah i i agree with you i you know i would even think that um uh i could in theory take that alone a you know a step further and say anybody in any job you know if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporation</ENAMEX> felt like uh  and and this is why i mean uh <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> are
 		the biggest problem i think to face <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> today i mean  it's what drives crime it's what drives
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um uh any sort of of uh uh pain and discomfort in the world  or in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> i think it's somewhat it's somewhat um driven by <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> and i think that
 		uh were <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> and uh private industry to take um take command in this situation that maybe
 		maybe we might have some some control over that we you know if you can't work then you can't  be a little bit harder to take take the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> or whatever i don't know
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		course that might up crime you know and uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> go in and steal your television and steal and sell it just because they can't they can't work anymore you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah but you got to have a a safe work place that's all there is to it
 	
 	
 		definitely you're you're you're definitely right that  you can't you can't have it any other way
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh yeah you know whether  whether in in the case that you brought up you know whether  uh you know whether if it's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policeman</ENAMEX> and he's working with uh the public and he has a and has a gun in his holster or or even you know if it's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald's</ENAMEX> cooking a burger i think
 		they're dangerous in either situation
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um i don't what what do you think um what percentage of of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> and uh private industry do you think use uh drug testing
 	
 	
 		i think it's it's more frequent now it's probably like <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">forty fifty</ENAMEX> percent
 	
 	
 		oh really uh-huh
 	
 	
 		yeah because uh all the jobs that i've applied for have uh mentioned some type of drug screening yeah
 	
 	
 		right yeah what kind of work are you in
 	
 	
 		uh i work at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sears</ENAMEX> and i just do warehouse work
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> and did they give you drug testing
 	
 	
 		uh not they hired me in nineteen <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty four</NUMEX> so yeah but now they they uh they issued a statement about that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about  three months</TIMEX> ago
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh so are they going to uh begin spontaneous uh drug testing
 	
 	
 		uh not that i know of it was more about uh all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s problems like they've been laying off a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and uh and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		they sent out uh employee assistance cards for anyone that had any sort of drug problem or work related problem family problems you know it kind of covered everything
 	
 	
 		sure uh-huh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i know they have a lot of drug problems so
 	
 	
 		yeah  what do you think about um you know  something that kind of concerns me is uh you you know you and i are tested for for whatever work we happen to do do you think there should be drug testing for political officials
 	
 	
 		yes i do because because a lot of them are you know they're hypocritical they they talk against <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> and then they get caught you know
 	
 	
 		yeah i do too
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		in stings in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> whether it's <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> or any other kind of uh like the the money laundering scams all that was drug related so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		and that cost us the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> you know <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billions of dollars</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		sure sure yeah i would agree with you i i can't see i can't see how we can expect the you know uh uh
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> working in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">in</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> to um uh to put any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">trust</ENAMEX> into our political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> if they don't you know  uh
 		it just doesn't make sense to have them  it it to to worry about legislation unless they're doing that themselves
 		
 		
 	