
 
     		
 	
 		gonna go first
 	
 	
 		
 
 		no go ahead  you called
 	
 	
 		all right um right now i'm a college right now i'm a college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> as a matter of fact so i'm pretty fresh with it i just think a lot of it depends on a variety of thing it depends on for me it was a combination of finance
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um being in a place where i would enjoy the atmosphere and where i'd feel comfortable as well as just the general type of education that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> gives
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well i i don't know i think it depends a lot on um well all those things decided that's true but i had got my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> into college <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> and it was really a major decision
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but there were just so many things to consider and i don't really think we even considered all of the things we should have
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh so she's out in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh is she
 	
 	
 		yeah but what we didn't consider was coming back and forth and things like that you know  yeah really so that's kind of
 	
 	
 		yeah exactly
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		that was kind of hard so i don't know i think it's always confusing it's hard to make a choice
 	
 	
 		oh absolutely i think you know like you said a lot of it there a lot things for example i go to school out in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> lives here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> and so it's kind of like you said uh i never realized what an expense it would be trying to come home and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		it really is and you don't get to come home as much as you think you will
 	
 	
 		no i maybe have been home oh twice in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last two years</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah yeah so it's really hard to do that
 	
 	
 		yeah it is and i think to there's there's a lot of times like you said that's one of the major considerations is you know how much do you want to be with your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> or how much do you wanna
 		and that's something that i didn't think about until  i was already out there
 	
 	
 		and i don't think you even know that answer until you go either
 	
 	
 		yeah exactly
 	
 	
 		you know everybody's anxious to get going and get away and go do their thing but then they really want to come home and they can't always
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		yep that's for sure
 	
 	
 		so that's kind of hard too but
 	
 	
 		you learn to appreciate what you had
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true isn't it  yeah it is i know
 	
 	
 		it is  so what other points did you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> look at when you were trying to find her school
 	
 	
 		well the size of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> because we live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plano</ENAMEX> so the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> are really big here very crowded so she didn't want a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> that was really too big
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and we looked at that and i don't know that that's really relevant because you're gonna end up with your little <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> anyway
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so i'm not sure that it makes too much of a difference although we did find that like down in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">um</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UT</ENAMEX> you know down in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classes</ENAMEX> are so full like you can have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two hundred</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> in a class
 	
 	
 		yeah and see i think that makes a huge difference where i
 	
 	
 		so that would be horrible you know
 	
 	
 		it is where i'm going <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">my freshman year</TIMEX> i didn't have a single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> with less than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine hundred</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's horrible oh my gosh
 	
 	
 		yeah and it was it was frustrating you'd see a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TA</ENAMEX> once a week and even the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TAs</ENAMEX> rarely knew who you were so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it became a thing like you said where you're where you're competing either to you know to get someone's attention to get help or you just kind of if you're not self motivated where i'm going it's really hard to
 	
 	
 		where're you going
 	
 	
 		um to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brigham Young University</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it's that crowded is it really
 	
 	
 		um in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">freshman classes</ENAMEX> that are you have there's  <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about twenty four thousand</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and so it's kind of  it's a lot of fun when you get in the upper level upper level classes it's a lot easier but
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah wow gosh
 	
 	
 		and that's something that i hadn't considered because i was i was raised in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plano</ENAMEX> as well and i went to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Plano East</ENAMEX> and i never you know there's lots of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> but there wasn't that many you know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty or thirty five</TIMEX> in a class i didn't mind
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		where are you in college now
 	
 	
 		i'm a junior
 	
 	
 		junior yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> went to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plano East</ENAMEX> too she twirled
 	
 	
 		oh did she
 		oh cool
 	
 	
 		yeah but she was the only twirler they've ever had  so but that's what she's doing out in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> that's why she's out there
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">great</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because we had to consider where a good spot was too and
 	
 	
 		yeah and that should you know i think a lot of it depends on like you said i think for me what i wanted to get out of the college experience had a lot to do with it it wasn't it was a combination of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">academics</ENAMEX> as well as other things so
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah well but a lot of times <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> aren't sure what they want to be like she started out with sports psychology so we looked all over that was a hard thing to find
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		and then she changed her mind anyway and i think most most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> do that i think these days you know yeah see and they say that that's average
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		uh i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three or four</NUMEX> times
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		because that's very common so maybe that's not such a great reason to look at a school i don't know
 	
 	
 		yes i think for me personally when i was choosing i was looking more the overall experience instead of just
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know but the specific field that i was looking into at that time so
 	
 	
 		yeah well she was too when you live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plano</ENAMEX> you know you sort of have everything
 		you really spoiled everybody here at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> we all are all our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are you know to be honest and we went out to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USC</ENAMEX> because they wanted her to twirl for them
 	
 	
 		yep
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and she was terrified she was just terrified of living in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LA</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		she was too scared to go there so i guess you have to look at that too
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and i understood it at the time when we went to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campus</ENAMEX> and visited i thought oh gosh it would just
 		
 		
 	