
 
     		
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well would you like to go <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> or shall i
 	
 	
 		well as a science teacher i been encouraging recycling for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time</TIMEX> and uh we collect things at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> such as foil
 	
 	
 		we have different communities
 	
 	
 		and cans and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glass</ENAMEX> to a certain extent uh i coach an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> and we save everything the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> at school bring some things in but not as much as i'd like and i have recyclings bins at home
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and we've had a uh we save foil which i think a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't realize they could sell along with the aluminum i mean aluminum cans
 	
 	
 		i think it's true yeah and and there are some areas where i believe they limit it they want you to just strictly go with the cans because of the different content but i think you're right the more often you can
 	
 	
 		well <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reynold</ENAMEX>'s aluminum has this big balls of foil competition thing going and i don't know where we're supposed to turn it in another science <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> is in charge of that and
 		got all the materials on it but we're saving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foil</ENAMEX> and accumulating balls of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foil</ENAMEX> in our room
 	
 	
 		that's great
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		do you have um  curbside pickup in your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> as well
 	
 	
 		not yet it it is in some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> but it isn't here and it is experimental in some areas at this point they're trying it out and deciding what what they're gonna do with it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		we just started it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> and it's really nice to be able to have that convenience as opposed to having to go to a local
 		dump and you know take your recyclables i know that i am much more motivated  when i know that they'll come pick it up because there can be so much that you load in your <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> as to as to when i had to get
 	
 	
 		that's true
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> gets irritated sometimes because of the even though i bought recycling bins
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and we keep our cans in one thing and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glass</ENAMEX> in another and paper in another it once it gets full getting it loaded into the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and taking it is a pain
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh it is and it's dirty and
 	
 	
 		yeah and uh sometimes you go to those recycling <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">places</ENAMEX> and like with cans often times there's a long line
 		uh you know if it's one of those where you get change for your cans
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		now if it's just a donation type of thing like at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> or some places like that sometimes people'll just dump their stuff at right at the front they don't go to the back of the
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		like if it's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> or whatever for paper
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and then everything's just starts getting piled outside which is a pain because that's not what's supposed to be happening
 	
 	
 		right it seems like it would be better all the way around if there were more curbside recycling
 	
 	
 		i think so too i i am uh in hopes that that will be successful and that they will decide to go ahead and and spread it to our neighborhood as well
 	
 	
 		
  
 		the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> thing that they don't recycle uh pick up they actually don't care if we mix together the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">aluminum</ENAMEX> and the bottles we put those all in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> big bag and then put the paper goods separately but the one thing they don't pick up are the plastic goods you know um
 		those big <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk tubs</ENAMEX> and that constitutes a big portion of our trash so i would hope at some point those things would either
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		that's true
 	
 	
 		stop being manufactured or that that they would be able to figure out a way to recycle those economically
 	
 	
 		some of them are recyclable and i started trying to save those but we couldn't find a place to dump them
 	
 	
 		right yes
 	
 	
 		and so we just had to throw them away um
 	
 	
 		they say on the cans or on the not the cans but the um the containers in fact that they are recyclable but i've i'm the same with you i haven't been able to at least not convenience probably outside the city limits or something
 	
 	
 		well i think
 		i was talking to someone who lives really almost on the other side of town said she knew of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> place where you could go and so once a month they made this trek with all their recyclables but they also have a pickup
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh and</ENAMEX> and they would take everything but that is it used to be such a pain and it's so far away from us and that's the only one she knew of
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		you have to be motivated to do that when you're that far away after a point
 	
 	
 		so i i guess what we've decided is that we're doing our part by recycling <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> and going out of our area way but to have to go clear across <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">plastic</ENAMEX> because
 	
 	
 		yeah well the fact that you're doing it at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> with the with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> is a great idea too because then they're also encouraged to learn about how to do that
 	
 	
 		and there's a a little booklet called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">uh Fifty Things Fifty Ways You Can Save</ENAMEX> The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX> have you read that
 	
 	
 		oh uh-huh
 		i like that yes uh-huh
 	
 	
 		yes well i read some of those to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> from time to time
 		so that they get some of the ideas uh from that but they are a lot more into recycling than they used to be um
 	
 	
 		
 
 		um-hum the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> uh-huh because i teach middle school
 	
 	
 		oh is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> that you teach
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it's uh surprising some of them aren't but that probably goes right into their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>
 		but there are even <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> that are <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Recycling Coalition</ENAMEX> type deal where they're really making speeches to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PTA</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dad</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Club</ENAMEX> and everything trying to get more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> involved
 	
 	
 		um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so it's um
 	
 	
 		that's great
 	
 	
 		it it's on its way if we could get more support through the public utilities
 	
 	
 		um-hum and i think when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> the local or the the state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> attends to support it the more happens i know that in our hospital i work in a hospital i'm a therapist and
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">just about three years ago</TIMEX> when we started recycling everything um
 		they not only recognized that they could save money with all
 		
 		
 	