
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		what are some of your hobbies
 	
 	
 		well it's interesting to talk about hobbies hobbies when you're so close to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> and don't have time to do any of them
 	
 	
 		right right
 	
 	
 		but um
 		well i love to sew
 	
 	
 		oh great
 	
 	
 		i like to
 	
 	
 		clothing for yourself or your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> or
 	
 	
 		well i really don't do as much of that um i enjoy that but i work full time so i just don't have time to do too much of that but um
 	
 	
 		or craft
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i really spend spend more time doing crafty kind of sewing yeah you know doing
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		you know appliques on T-shirts and you know that kind of fun stuff and and i make a lot of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> gifts too
 	
 	
 		oh cute
 		fun you
 		oh do you like for instance what
 	
 	
 		oh well let's see um
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one year</TIMEX> i made a lot of um jewelry bags kind of a little round thing that you draw up with a string you know and has compartments compartments in it and they're you know they go pretty quickly and
 	
 	
 		oh
 		uh-huh well how fun
 		oh
 	
 	
 		um make a real nice gift you know
 	
 	
 		that sounds fun oh
 	
 	
 		yeah so what kinds of things do you do
 	
 	
 		well i enjoy right now i'm kind of into uh tole painting on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wood wood</ENAMEX> type projects
 	
 	
 		oh neat
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		did you take a class
 	
 	
 		no i just i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister-in-law</ENAMEX> that kind of has taught me and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then the projects i do are not real complicated i know some people
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		just do elaborate and beautiful i i don't think i have a real talent for painting  so i haven't done anything like that yet but we've done a few like little <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">carousel horses</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		yes yeah
 		
 
 		ooh neat yeah
 	
 	
 		um little for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> i made some tulip recipe <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">card holders</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		and and different things like that i also
 	
 	
 		well that's neat
 		have you painted on T-shirts or sweat shirts at all
 	
 	
 		i've painted um just with that oh it's called scribbles you know the little paint in a bottle
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i've just done things like that but i haven't i've seen some T-shirts painted on them and they're really cute but they look hard to me  are they have you done those
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 		no i really haven't i i just haven't done anything with with paint i think i could do some i could do some i'm not an artistic like you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right uh-huh
 	
 	
 		um but a lot of the stuff they do really you know evidently is pretty easy but i've just never
 	
 	
 		never attempted it
 	
 	
 		you know never gotten to it  i just you know don't have time
 	
 	
 		uh-huh well that's yeah that's what they say i've heard them say that's it's just kind of like coloring or paint by number
 	
 	
 		um-hum yeah
 	
 	
 		but i don't know it it sure looks complicated
 	
 	
 		yeah it comes out looking really nice we just had a there's a gal in the um i'm a school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">librarian</ENAMEX> and there's a a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> at our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> that
 	
 	
 		right
 		oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		is really quite an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> and she does these adorable um little
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> that are just funny i mean i just look at them they just make me laugh  they have you know hair that sticks straight out and stuff like that
 	
 	
 		well how cute
 		oh how fun
 	
 	
 		and she also she also makes dolls but she also paints so
 	
 	
 		wow
 	
 	
 		i've had her paint on like a denim <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jumper</ENAMEX> these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> around the bottom and it's so cute
 	
 	
 		oh how darling
 	
 	
 		and recently i had her to do um a couple of T-shirts for me and my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX> that um have the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> on them and it has um a little stack of books and one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> is reading and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh how cute
 	
 	
 		one's wearing a T-shirt that says I Love to read and then it has the name of our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> on you know on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>'s um shirt
 	
 	
 		oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh that sounds really cute
 	
 	
 		so they really are cute and uh she does them so quickly and she only charges <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> dollars
 	
 	
 		oh does she
 		uh you're kidding
 	
 	
 		to paint i mean there must be <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> on the just you know on the front of the T-shirt plus all this other little stuff
 	
 	
 		wow
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> that is something
 	
 	
 		and it was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> dollars to to do that
 	
 	
 		my word <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> does she have a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> asking her to do it
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yes yes um this particular one i told her i said if you do this real cute i said you'll probably have about fifty more orders from all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> in my school
 	
 	
 		i bet a line probably
 		right i bet and she probably did
 	
 	
 		so
 		yeah well she just did them i just got them <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">couple days ago</TIMEX> so i think as soon as we wear them to school and everybody sees them it'll be it'll be good
 	
 	
 		oh oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh have you ever sewn the stuffed animal type things
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		
 
 		any <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">stuffed animals</ENAMEX> or
 	
 	
 		just a few i made <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> bears this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> uh not out of furry but you know out of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> kind of fabric um
 	
 	
 		oh how fun
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh how fun
 	
 	
 		they were they turned out real cute and they were easy they were um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know from the fabric <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> buy the already stamped on it and all so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh well how fun
 	
 	
 		but they're real cute they're real cute you know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> looking patterns so i gave <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> away and
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and kept one
 	
 	
 		well how fun
 	
 	
 		but i also love to do things that have to do with like either dried <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers dried flowers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">silk flowers</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		oh do you arr ange
 	
 	
 		you know make not so much arrangements like to sit on a table but you know to go on a wall or
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh
 	
 	
 		you know some pretty stuff on top of a basket or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">around</NUMEX> a basket you know the dried stuff around the top edge of the basket
 	
 	
 		uh
 		oh yes yeah uh-huh
 	
 	
 		with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">moss</ENAMEX> and all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers</ENAMEX> and stuff and um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh oh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i do fabric in baskets a lot with all the ruffles and all that stuff you know um
 	
 	
 		oh do you
 		oh
 		well you sound like you're talented
 	
 	
 		well
 		it it's called talent with a hot <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glue</ENAMEX> gun you know
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	