
 
     		
 	
 		what vacations have you been on that you like
 	
 	
 		
 
 		um
 		well i really enjoyed um i went to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mackinaw Island</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years back</TIMEX> it's in the middle of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lake Michigan</ENAMEX>
 		and so that was nice i like um driving to a different <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> because of the scenery
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so that was nice
 	
 	
 		so you mostly yours is kind of driving and
 	
 	
 		yeah we've i've been all over the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> except for pretty much east
 		um it's very pretty driving like um up north in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wisconsin</ENAMEX> too
 	
 	
 		um
 		how how far uh do you usually end end up driving just
 	
 	
 		um the furthest i drove was probably
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> and then i've taken a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">train</ENAMEX> before to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		now where you're from where
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kenosha Wisconsin</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wisconsin</ENAMEX> okay
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota</ENAMEX> that used to live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wisconsin</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		so yeah that's quite a ways
 	
 	
 		yeah it is
 	
 	
 		i've uh
 		we went to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this last year</TIMEX> and uh liked it but it was too crowded <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Walt Disney World</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh
 	
 	
 		all those places it's just the wrong time of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> to go
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh course uh you get in any of those tourist traps and everything's uh outrageously priced and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		kind of  you wonder if they're it's really worth it to pay uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty five</TIMEX> dollars or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">forty dollars</NUMEX> just to get in
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true
 	
 	
 		but
 		there's lots of fun places to see um i think the scenery kind of that's something do to you like to get up in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">mountains</ENAMEX> or
 	
 	
 		oh yeah um-hum
 	
 	
 		do you have any mountains nearby
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		it's pretty flat isn't it
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		um i think uh
 		the biggest limitation is a lot just time and money isn't it
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		what vacation have you enjoyed the most
 	
 	
 		um
 		probably uh when we go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wisconsin</ENAMEX> Dells
 		um it's pretty fun there's a lot to do up there it's pretty busy though you have to like crowds you know i
 	
 	
 		what is it
 	
 	
 		um oh it's uh
 		like a huge amusement <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX>  um they have water slides
 	
 	
 		okay
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it's just a big big tourist attraction there's the downtown is all like little <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> and candy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> and
 		it's it's really neat i don't think uh hardly anybody lives there because it's just kind of like you know tourists
 	
 	
 		probably a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> in itself kind of like huh
 	
 	
 		yeah it's mostly a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a summer summer</TIMEX> place
 	
 	
 		summer place how far away is it
 	
 	
 		um from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kenosha</ENAMEX> it's <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about three hours</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		it's <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about a hour</TIMEX> away from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Madison</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay sure
 	
 	
 		yeah so that's nice it's it's pretty ride up there too i  really like the city <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wausau</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wisconsin</ENAMEX> it's really pretty
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		it's nice out there i i like all the nature things there are to look at you know
 	
 	
 		right well and you could probably you're in a climate that's kind of humid so you have probably a lot of green and
 		a lot of real pretty things our our climate's real dry and
 	
 	
 		where is that
 	
 	
 		you have to kind of get up into the mountains to get much of the greenery most of the most most the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">land</ENAMEX>'s pretty brown you don't have as much of the greenery like you have
 	
 	
 		oh where is that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">uh Idaho</ENAMEX> is where i live and uh yes
 	
 	
 		i don't <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty five</TIMEX> oh okay
 	
 	
 		it's by uh i have a little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> thinks he needs to cry now that i'm on the phone it's by um <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boise</ENAMEX> you ever heard of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boise</ENAMEX> and uh  it's fun it's nice it's uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		it's  lot different kind of i lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX> for a while and it's a real different uh
 		land and scenery than there it's kind of fun to have a little bit diversity and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		things like that i think uh
 		there's a lot of places uh oh down even in southern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> the canyons canyon lands and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bryce Canyon</ENAMEX> and
 		oh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> they're gorgeous  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lake</ENAMEX> Tahoe
 	
 	
 		oh  do that yeah
 		
  
 	
 	
 		those are kind of fun places we usually go over to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bear</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Lake</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> which is uh
 		kind of on the border of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Idaho</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> and  the lake goes on forever and that's real pretty over there too
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		but i think i'm kind of a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> vacationer
 	
 	
 		yeah i do
 		oh yeah me too uh me too unless i'm going somewhere warm  for the winter  yeah that'd be nice
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 		
 
 		when'd you try and
 		
 		
 	