
 
     		
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> are you presently looking uh for a used used car
 	
 	
 		well as a matter of fact i just bought <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>  just just within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last three weeks</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		just bought one
 		so what'd you get
 	
 	
 		i got a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lexus LS</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four hundred</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lexus</ENAMEX> um
 	
 	
 		which is made by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toyota</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">okay Lexus</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toyota</ENAMEX> sub brand
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		okay i was wondering where that came from because they're talking like it was an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> built car
 	
 	
 		it's kind of their
 		right it it sounds like it but it really isn't  it's uh marketed of course it its own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dealerships</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		usually usually or somebody that's maybe got a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cadillac</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lexus</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dealership</ENAMEX> uh sometimes they do that but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it's uh a brand car but i've really liked it it it drives just wonderfully and there is it's so quiet you almost can't tell the engine is running
 	
 	
 		that's their big selling point uh other than general luxury and and but the particular seems to be the uh the quiet ride
 		it seems they it's
 	
 	
 		it really is it's got pretty good acceleration too it's got a CD <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> in it so i can i can play those and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh</ENAMEX> was that wasn't a standard  feature was it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">hum-um</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		but there's not very many options on that car
 	
 	
 		uh i get the impression
 	
 	
 		there's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only about five</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> options everything else is standard uh some of the tracking control things and skidding control things for up north the CD and the premium sound system
 	
 	
 		yeah you get the impression that's
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah skidding control you mean the antilock brake system
 	
 	
 		yeah it's kind of a traction control i think they call it it's it's not just antilock brake i think that's already on most of them but there's a further traction control uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh this is a uh
 		uh probably suspension tied into the brakes
 	
 	
 		yeah and and also the suspension can be raised for driving like in the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX> and snow it can raise the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> up a little bit
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		for going under a lot of piled up stuff if you were up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michigan</ENAMEX> or somewhere
 	
 	
 		yeah uh shoot  some of these muddy driveways use it around here
 	
 	
 		Mississippi probably doesn't
 		Mississippi probably doesn't have to worry too much about that
 	
 	
 		no <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">snow</ENAMEX> doesn't happen very often
 	
 	
 		if it does <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> go what's this stuff
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah uh originally i'm from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Virginia</ENAMEX> we got a pretty fair amount of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">snow</ENAMEX> but uh i got down here in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty four</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh well you had some there yeah
 	
 	
 		and the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX> down here was probably <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the worst winter</TIMEX> they'd seen in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years</TIMEX>
 		and it was amazing how <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a few inches</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">snow</ENAMEX> would turn normally sane manly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adult men</ENAMEX> into playful little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh i know
 	
 	
 		we had this group of uh surveyors come into uh a shop i was working in
 		um <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four or five</NUMEX> of them these big old flame worn suburbans and the snow all over the place
 		they had just come in to get <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas</ENAMEX> in their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicles</ENAMEX> and get the oil checked but while they were there they set back  drank <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about four or five</NUMEX> cups of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX> apiece and made snowmen on the hoods of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicles</ENAMEX> threw snowballs all over the place
 	
 	

 		oh no
 		
 
 	
 	
 		had themselves a ball for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about an hour</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		well the uh
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lexus</ENAMEX> uh really and the moon roof i think is also an option although most of them are ordered them with it but there really is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only about a half a dozen</NUMEX> uh things and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		everything else is pretty standard i did not get the traction control which also when you take the control traction control and the  and the suspension thing it also puts heaters in the front seats too
 	
 	
 		oh so that's kind of
 	
 	
 		you go out and get in that real cold <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and you turn that on and it yeah and it kind of uh but that's only available if with the traction control and the other option and those <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> are sold together so you have to take a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">two thousand dollar</NUMEX> option there to
 	
 	
 		it's a package deal
 		yeah
 		ouch
 	
 	
 		to uh do it so i i opted not for that but
 	
 	
 		no it doesn't sound real necessary in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dealership</ENAMEX> i dealt with they order them all with the uh moon roof and uh you know nice floor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mats</ENAMEX> and everything in there
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah i worked for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so the only thing i had to decide on was whether i wanted a CD or not in the stereo system and that was pretty much it and they had like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three or four</NUMEX> basic packages that they
 	
 	
 		yeah sounds like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln Mercury</ENAMEX> dealer i used to work for they didn't order anything but the extra luxury version of whatever they got little <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mercury</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Tracer</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they offer
 		yeah i've been over i've been
 	
 	
 		imagine or not they make a they make a luxury <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mercury</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Tracer</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah i've seen that in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dealership</ENAMEX> i was driving a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mark Seven</ENAMEX> for the last <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX> before i traded it for this and uh
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		i'm leasing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lexus</ENAMEX> i usually lease them since i own a business i just run it through my business but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but it the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> ride is certainly good too but the this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lexus</ENAMEX> is nothing like i have ever been in before it just
 	
 	
 		like sitting in your living room
 	
 	
 		yeah it really is and it's got a lumbar support in the seats adjustable uh power and just kind of brings that support up in the small
 	
 	
 		adjustable
 		yeah
 		
 		
 	