
 
     		
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yes
 	
 	
 		uh crime is our subject
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		have you ever been accused of a crime
 	
 	
 		have i um no i guess not
 	
 	
 		i haven't either really i guess other than you want to count car accidents or something like that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh they asked for solutions uh
 	
 	
 		yeah that's it
 	
 	
 		i'll i'll be i'll be very out forespoken here uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arabs</ENAMEX> don't do everything in the world right but gosh they sure don't have too many repeat <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offenders</ENAMEX> over there
 	
 	
 		that's true that's true they uh in in fact uh also i don't know if you're familiar with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> method of of dealing with crimes
 	
 	
 		uh no i no i'm not
 	
 	
 		but they don't they have an extremely low rate extremely low especially considering the uh the density of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> and stuff um they have uh they have this this sense of of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> that's very important to them and and family honor
 		and what they do the the main punishment the most effective portion of their punishment is that they take and publish
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offender</ENAMEX>'s name in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> that gets spread all over the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and especially in the region that they're in
 	
 	
 		and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>'s name too
 	
 	
 		it well it gives the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s name and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> is typically so embarrassed
 		that they have to they sell their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> they leave they leave the region and move to to the opposite end of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> and so it shames the entire <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> including the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX> and and maybe aunts and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncles</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah that's similar to what was this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> maybe it was here in some place that on prostitution
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		when they caught a uh a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a</NUMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customer</ENAMEX> trying to solicit a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prostitute</ENAMEX> either way however you wanna say it they would publish the names of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customer</ENAMEX> and address of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customer</ENAMEX> in the newspaper
 	
 	
 		right
 		
 
 	
 	
 		there are a lot of divorces lot of family counseling going on but prostitution went down in that city
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i i'm willing to bet yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		it just about killed the business  well publicity huh it doesn't work over in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> does it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah well well you know the thing i guess the thing is is you know with the uh the in part uh one of the things to blame is the disintegration of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> in general and and the importance of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and and and that's
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but you know you can't just magically push a button and make that come back i guess but uh
 	
 	
 		uh if you yeah if you can wanna compare crime rates by divorce and and single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> and everything else i'm sure they'll be at a direct proportion to it
 	
 	
 		probably uh related
 	
 	
 		uh unfortunately uh
 	
 	
 		but incidentally incidentally um i just uh just just reading in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> about um uh this they're i don't know they were moving some of the uh highway uh things in here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> recenttly the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		and they had ranked <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> as being uh
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> out of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> on scale of of quality of life and i assume that that that includes that includes crime nowhere nowheres else nowhere else in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> was above <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about a three</NUMEX> point <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> yeah and <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">and and</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> was a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> point <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 		if if you live but we cut them off at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five hundred</NUMEX> a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year and January</TIMEX> first we had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i swear uh
 	
 	
 		i i really yeah i really i thought it was pretty surprising
 	
 	
 		i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Austin</ENAMEX> should be <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> that is i went to school and graduated from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UT</ENAMEX> and oh it's hey if i  if i hadn't stayed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX> i should've gone to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Stephenville Texas</ENAMEX> i'll tell you
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		well they they uh even even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Austin</ENAMEX>'s had it's share of of nasty crimes recently right with the with the sort of senseless murder of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> at the um
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		at uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice cream</ENAMEX> parlor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> just walked in and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		pull the trigger
 	
 	
 		yeah i guess so
 	
 	
 		well obviously in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> we let them out too soon
 	
 	
 		but you know look at the what's the cost of keeping them in it's something like uh uh yeah it's like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty</TIMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">thousand dollars</NUMEX> per per year to keep somebody in jail
 	
 	
 		astronomical
 		did you see where the private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">ventures</ENAMEX> that built the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">jails</ENAMEX> and they're gonna help alleviate the overcrowding conditions are don't have any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		hum
 		nobody wants  the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> or the the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> doesn't wanna let them do it
 	
 	
 		
 
 		who
 		i i guess
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		it looks to me like you know whether you you you get <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> out of it and give it to private enterprise it's done cheaper and more economical and more efficiently put the profit motive in front of anybody and all of a sudden it it works
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		all of a sudden it works huh
 	
 	
 		isn't that awful no it's not that's what makes just <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customer</ENAMEX> go around you know i was telling a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> and and i said something about profit he said thank goodness for profit i said i beg your pardon he said yeah  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Internal Revenue Service</ENAMEX> we tax profits  i wouldn't have a job if there wasn't any profits
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		huh
 		
 
 		yeah yeah that's true
 		you rather have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to cry to yeah but i don't know you know i mean obviously you know obviously some more <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">jails</ENAMEX> isn't really the solution either i don't know i mean that doesn't seem to be
 	
 	
 		um well
 		maybe we ought to um
 	
 	
 		terribly effective
 	
 	
 		put them in these <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Air Force bases</ENAMEX> that are closing and utilize those you know
 	
 	
 		yeah well there's there've been several you know those those kind of died on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">vine</ENAMEX> they were there were separate proposals around to do that kind of thing and i haven't heard anything about them recently and maybe maybe i'm the one that just hasn't been paying attention
 	
 	
 		um
 		i read an interesting article in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monthly a few months</TIMEX> back about this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> that was a uh a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guard</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ellis</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Unit</ENAMEX> down in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Huntsville</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and he was a regular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guard</ENAMEX> a a what they call a new boot or something like that and one thing led to another somebody asked for light of a cigarette or a cigarette and before long he was running dope for them and he got caught and now he's in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> himself
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and the the article purpose of the article was just to emphasize that nobody's above it um
 	
 	
 		yeah  yeah i know
 		
 		
 	