
 
     		
 	
 		kind of a heavy topic <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX> right about uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		that's you have to start <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the new year</TIMEX> out by the way <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Happy New Year</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		thank you same to you
 		what do you think about the uh  that idea that they're recommending for the young people
 	
 	
 		i hadn't really heard that before um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i had at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point thought about doing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace Corps</ENAMEX> myself <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many years ago</TIMEX> um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many years ago</TIMEX> it seemed like they had uh um involuntary enlistment and mainly like in the fifties i know a lot of uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> that were into the military you had to go into the military
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 		i don't know about that a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i don't think would like it because it's gonna interrupt <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> plans but a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't have plans so for them it might give them a little help to uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		get uh some kind of more awareness about the world and be of some use for a while
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		i i personally think it would be a a good idea
 		um  i have kind of a same well it's not a really a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace Corps</ENAMEX> experience it's a little bit similar
 		you may assume that being from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mormon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> and we do a lot of missionary work and i spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> when i was nineteen in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Argentina</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		um
 	
 	
 		and uh i'll tell you that gives you a different perspective of uh you know some of the things we have here in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> that uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> really uh don't appreciate
 		and seeing a different culture and uh getting to know a kind of a different a different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i think was a good experience for anyone regardless of uh
 		you know their particular  endeavor they're engaged  engaged in i think just getting out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> is a great benefit to anyone so have you ever lived abroad or spent anytime outside of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		i haven't no but um i had known of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace Corps</ENAMEX> because i had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace Corps</ENAMEX> course you know it was much more publicized in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the sixties</TIMEX> i don't even know if they have it today
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> though in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">seventies</ENAMEX> join uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vista</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		which is a similar program although you stay within the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US</ENAMEX> which can be very beneficial too i mean a lot of times there's a lot of help we can do within the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US um</ENAMEX> and that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh sure you bet
 	
 	
 		it program i thought was excellent
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um i just don't think they even i don't know if they have those programs anymore or if they even try to publicize it and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recruit</ENAMEX> and i think that's a shame because both of those programs programs are excellent and uh hopefully don't
 	
 	
 		and i it seems like they excuse me but it seems like they used to advertise it on TV in the the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace Corps</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i don't remember i just i haven't seen it recently
 	
 	
 		yeah so
 	
 	
 		not that you know not down here any i don't  i don't remember seeing anything about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vista</ENAMEX> or or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace Corps</ENAMEX> recently
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well i think it would be a good idea is a it is kind of a delicate time but
 		by the same token at that age they haven't really settled down don't have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> or other commitments as well and so there's some divantages to going at that particular time in your life
 	
 	
 		right right
 	
 	
 		and uh well well  i think
 	
 	
 		yeah i think it would be extremely beneficial to just about everybody
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um i i could see that there'd be some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that you know would throw up their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX> about it and go i'm going to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX> and i you know this isn't something i wanna do but
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh you're right it would give everybody a better perspective of uh you know ourselves and what we have maybe make us appreciate  what we have a little more so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah that's that's certainly my was my experience just uh
 		it was like the the uh clock had been turned back <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about ten</NUMEX> or fifteen years
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know just the difference in the technologies in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> the  kinds of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> they drove the you know simple things like  central heating and uh
 		and having a gas fired um water heater you know things that that we really appreciate are are not commonplace in in every uh in every uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> that i was uh living in
 	
 	
 		um
 		right i had uh twice now been a big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>  you've heard of big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh yeah</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh i have had uh two little <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> and even though they were local to me it was almost being in a different world because both of my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> little <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> came from very poor backgrounds
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and of course they don't have usually normal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> i mean  there's not a a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right
 	
 	
 		they live in pretty poor housing and um their education is very lacking because their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> you know don't uh  encourage them to go to school
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um so that was beneficial to me as well as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> because uh made me appreciate my background a little more and i helped to give this person
 		um  a more <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> on one idea of there can be a different life than what they've had and it to uh experience some things that otherwise they wouldn't be able to get out and do
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah  is that uh a program where you're you uh commit for a certain number of  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> or or you you're assigned a  a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> and you you stay with them for as long as you can
 	
 	
 		it's usually a year um and they try to find somebody in the local area to you and um you know the age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> that you wanna work
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	