
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh what are the capital punishment laws in your state
 	
 	
 		uh they're
 	
 	
 		or do you have it
 	
 	
 		uh they're they're the death penalty can be imposed
 	
 	
 		yeah uh or is it set for a specific crimes uh you know if you're convicted of this then it's the death penalty or or is it kind of just to the discretion under certain cases
 	
 	
 		uh it's uh murder it it can be
 		is i think is the only can be tried for you know for
 		uh capital punishment
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and i firmly believe in it
 	
 	
 		yes uh i
 		i'm the same way i feel that capital punishment ought to be mandatory under certain crimes
 	
 	
 		i do too here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> there's been a a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> that's been on death row for
 		i oh seventeen years i think and they just keep retrying and retrying and i just it's just a waste of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX>' money and and i really think it would be a deterrent
 	
 	
 		sounds like he'd grow old and die long before they get to kill him
 	
 	
 		yes yes
 		but uh
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seventeen</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> on death row
 	
 	
 		um-hum uh i think he's that he's the longest one in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> that and they just keep retrying him and retrying him
 	
 	
 		well uh
 		since they reinstated the death penalty was it <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about seven</NUMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight years ago</TIMEX> i think the shortest anybody's waited has been <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two or three years</TIMEX>
 		i mean death penalty does not seem to be swift for anybody
 	
 	
 		no is what's the death penalty in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mississippi</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i
 		so that's my understanding they do not have death penalty here right now um
 	
 	
 		i mean the capital
 	
 	
 		
 
 		it doesn't make any sense that they don't but they don't
 		um
 		and right now to the best of my understanding there is nothing afoot to get it reinstated
 		uh
 		personally i think there should be death penalty for
 		uh
 		the death penalty should be available almost any
 		major violent crime
 		and mandatory for murder
 	
 	
 		i i agree with you
 		they believe
 	
 	
 		it should be at least available as punishment for rape
 	
 	
 		yes definitely
 	
 	
 		i think if it was a serious  possible of being executed for doing any of the major crimes that it would be a little less likely for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to commit them
 	
 	
 		well one thing i can't understand is is these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that uh
 		uh torture torture <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and then murder i mean you know and then they're they eventually kill them
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		and i definitely think that that should be a death penalty and they get less than than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that have are murdered
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i don't understand that i i just can't see how come a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> that has kills a little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> can get away with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two or three years or five years</TIMEX>
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> to fifteen
 	
 	
 		yeah and it
 	
 	
 		because
 	
 	
 		i don't know i if i think also they should be
 		they uh somebody providing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> to someone that kills the person
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		that ought to be considered murder and potential death penalty
 	
 	
 		boy we think alike
 	
 	
 		i uh
 		they used to have the death penalty in my home <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Virginia</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and
 		there it was death by hanging
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh but
 	
 	
 		how old are you may i ask
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">thirty four</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh uh-huh
 	
 	
 		and it when they eliminated death penalty all kinds of things changed
 	
 	
 		yes they do
 	
 	
 		uh the rate of crime doubled within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about about a year</TIMEX> or so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and at that point when they were still hanging the uh state <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> in Mountsville
 		uh
 		had a very small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guard force</ENAMEX> and they had very little problems with their their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inmates</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh after they eliminated the death penalty shut down the gallows
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh the place has gotten to the point where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who live in that area
 		are all trying to get moved away it's become a maximum security prison they have had a whole lot more problems with breakouts with uh with violence within the the prison
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 		uh just the whole whole tenor of the thing has changed completely
 	
 	
 		i wonder why i wonder why they don't uh
 		don't uh see that they need the death penalty then
 		because haven't you heard that they say that the death penalty does not
 		uh deter crime
 	
 	
 		who is it who said the death penalty doesn't deter crime well i'm sure it doesn't much now because the death penalty is very seldom uh given and
 	
 	
 		used
 	
 	
 		even then like you say it could be <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty twenty years</TIMEX> between the time
 		
 		
 	