
   
   
      
         
            Easy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ryder</ENAMEX>

            
               Movies
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Girl</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Interrupted</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia Pictures</ENAMEX>). Excellent performances
from the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> leads, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Winona Ryder</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angelina Jolie</ENAMEX>, lift this movie above the
thicket of clichés it veers toward. Based on the best-selling memoirs of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susanna Kaysen</ENAMEX>, it follows a confused teen-age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> who checks herself into a
mental <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX> and then finds that she can't check out. Although many note
that this is "a junior-league <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">One Flew Over the Cuckoo's Nest "</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Owen</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gleiberman, Entertainment Weekly</ENAMEX> ) and that the film lapses into trite
battles between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> and hospital <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>, the film stays mainly on target,
at its best when displaying its "meticulous, true-to-life portrait of a time
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 1960</TIMEX>'s) and place (the hothouse world of upper-middle-class <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">suburbia</ENAMEX>)" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Holden</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ). (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to visit the official site.)

            

               
                  Topsy-Turvy
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">October Films</ENAMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> gripe a bit but still
give a standing ovation to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Leigh</ENAMEX>'s ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Secrets and Lies</ENAMEX> ) new film,
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about</NUMEX> a short span in the lives and work of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gilbert</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sullivan</ENAMEX> as they
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">compose</ENAMEX> and stage The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mikado</ENAMEX> . "Only a lunatic would call
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Topsy-Turvy</ENAMEX> , with its <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">lame first hour</TIMEX> and host of loose ends, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">masterpiece</ENAMEX>, but by the finale I was ready to have myself committed" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edelstein</ENAMEX>, 
                  Slate
               ). It's "one of those films that create a mix of
erudition, pageantry and delectable acting opportunities, much as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare in Love</ENAMEX> did <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>," and it "vigorously and amusingly
explore[s] what it means for an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> to renew his energies by returning to
square <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Maslin</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ). Several note its slow
start and general disorganization: "[<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">I</ENAMEX>]t teases us with the feeling that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leigh</ENAMEX>
had a basic plan for the picture and never realized it" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanley Kauffmann</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX> ). (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> to read the rest of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edelstein</ENAMEX>'s review in

                  Slate
               .)

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holy Smoke</ENAMEX>
               
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miramax</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane Campion</ENAMEX>'s ( The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Piano</ENAMEX> ) latest offering draws divergent
reactions, most tending toward the negative. Either it's "clumsy, lumpy" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX>
Morgenstern, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> ), or the sparring of co-stars <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kate</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Winslet</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harvey Keitel</ENAMEX> (as a cult <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> and her deprogrammer) makes for a
film that "creates more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> electricity than any other movie <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Clark</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> ). The film's core, a showdown between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Keitel</ENAMEX> and
Winslet, is "a knockabout fusion of sexual warfare, New Age therapy,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cross-generational Socratic</ENAMEX> dialogue, and feminist role reversal" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Owen</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gleiberman, Entertainment Weekly</ENAMEX> ). Mentioned in nearly every review: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)
Winslet bares all; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) Keitel ends up in a red dress and lipstick. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX>
here to watch the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">trailer</ENAMEX>.)

            

               
                  Tumbleweeds
                (Fine Line Features). The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>
free-spirit-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX>-on-the-run-with-teen-age-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> story in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three months</TIMEX>
receives much better reviews than the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Anywhere But Here</ENAMEX> ): It
"impresses with its freshly considered action and total avoidance of the stale
and routine" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jay Carr</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Globe</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> stage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McTeer</ENAMEX>'s performance as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> stands out, and the low-budget, genuine
feeling of the film results in "one of the few movies ever made that doesn't
feel like a movie," in which the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> "throb and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">course</ENAMEX> with life"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Hunter</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> ). (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> to read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Edelstein</ENAMEX>'s
review in 
                  Slate
               .)

            
               Book
            

            
               
                  Miss <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wyoming</ENAMEX>
               ,
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Douglas Coupland</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pantheon</ENAMEX>). Has <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coupland</ENAMEX>, once on the cutting edge with
Generation <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">X</ENAMEX> , lost his touch? <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> seem to think so. Always read
"more for his trend-setting insights than his novelistic dexterity," he loses
his hipster cred with this novel "by jumping on the already tired
beauty-pageant-bashing bandwagon" ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Publishers' Weekly</ENAMEX> ). Even worse, "his
brand labels are just slightly faded," and the story feels "curiously clipped
and uptight" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Shone</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ). On a more positive note,
many also point out that despite his faux pas, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coupland</ENAMEX> has put together "a
brilliant set of riffs" on pop culture and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> life (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Poniewozik</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> ). (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to see some of
the furniture the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> has designed.)

         
      
   
