
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Politicians</ENAMEX> Never Die 

            A new
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">adage</ENAMEX> is proving true in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ex</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> don't retire. They join
Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>.

            
Traditionally, those who lost elections or opted out of public service after a
long stretch have sought sometimes lucrative and often cushy appointments to
corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX> of directors. It's either that or lobbying. Lately, however,
the flow of newly liberated politicos joining the Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Economy</ENAMEX> is so great
that some of these dot-coms might as well be known as dot-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pols</ENAMEX>.

            To be
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">blunt</ENAMEX>, many of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> know about as much about managing an Internet
business as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX> knows about the chemical makeup of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Viagra</ENAMEX>. They plead
ignorance about servers and banner ads and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cookies</ENAMEX>. But they do know politics,
and that's precisely why so many venture-capital-backed startups are wooing
them. For many fledgling dot-coms, the big-name former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicos</ENAMEX> will play a
key role in their dash for notoriety during this make-or-break presidential
election year.

            The
latest virtual migrations from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">S.V.</ENAMEX> came <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> when former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike McCurry</ENAMEX> and former <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Hampshire</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>
administration <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief of Staff</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Sununu</ENAMEX> joined a slate of political
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultants</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contenders</ENAMEX> on the advisory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>-based Web site
calling itself Grassroots.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. The
site, which will officially launch <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next month</TIMEX>, is a nonpartisan "political
action destination," one of a growing number of sites betting that average
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> would rather rattle off an e-mail to an elected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> than sign a
petition, call, or actually put pen to paper.

            "I've
generally avoided corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sununu</ENAMEX>, who sits on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> other
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX>-that of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Collegelink</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com Inc.</ENAMEX>, in which he holds <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">43,750</NUMEX> stock options,
[
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Correction 1/26/00</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sununu</ENAMEX> serves on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kinark</ENAMEX>. He is a large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shareholder</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Collegelink</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX> but does not serve on its
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX>.
               ] But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sununu</ENAMEX> really liked the idea of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grassroots</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. "I
liked the fact that they understand the biggest contribution they can make is
to give <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> access to political information at the local level," he said.
"There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">120,000</NUMEX> local elections <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>. We read <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about a few hundred</NUMEX> of the
most prominent ones. Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are concerned about local issues involving
school <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX>, city <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">councilmen</ENAMEX> and -<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>. That's where the real intense action
is on the political side."

            As the
presidential race heats up, new for-profit political Web sites are launching
almost <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every week</TIMEX>. They've cornered the market on generic, political-sounding
names-Politics.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Voter</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX>, Vote.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">SpeakOut</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX>, etc., but none has yet to turn a
profit. Their business <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">models</ENAMEX> are all based on attracting a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to
content or chat <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> or polls or on making it easier to e-mail elected
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>. They all seem to believe they'll reach solvency by attracting
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">advertisers</ENAMEX>, which tends to overlook the tendency of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on the Internet to
turn to already trusted brands for information and commerce.

            This
<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">crop</ENAMEX> of political startups is appealing to legions of brand-name politicians
willing to lend their names and credibility to often exciting-sounding
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ventures</ENAMEX>. Many said in interviews that these new sites that help put <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in
electronic touch with their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> remind them of the politics of old,
when door-to-door campaigning and kissing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX> won out over
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">multimillion</ENAMEX>-dollar TV blitzes and negative campaigning.

            But
that's not the only thing that's appealing to the likes of former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Reps.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Downey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Molinari</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy Tate</ENAMEX>; former <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> Deputy Chief
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Staff</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Deaver</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adviser</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Carville</ENAMEX>; former vice
presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Geraldine Ferraro</ENAMEX>; and former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quinn</ENAMEX>. The flow of former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brass</ENAMEX>,
presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultants</ENAMEX>, and former political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contenders</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX> (and,
less often, to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffs</ENAMEX>) of politically oriented Web startups is so great
that one would think they were giving something away. Oh, wait, they
are giving something away: stock options.

            
"You're seeing the inevitable cashing in of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> on the Internet," joked
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Downey</ENAMEX>, a former <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18-year</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">congressman</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Long Island</ENAMEX>, who is now a
high-powered <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyist</ENAMEX> in town. "The Internet has already changed commerce and
it's going to do the same thing to politics."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Downey</ENAMEX>
serves on the advisory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SpeakOut</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>-based startup that
aims to empower users to interact with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">decision-makers</ENAMEX> through a community Web
service. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> has already secured <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $8 million</NUMEX> in
venture-capital financing. And it has attracted a bipartisan who's who panel of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">advisers</ENAMEX>, including <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deaver</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Molinari</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bond</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> such
as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carter Eskew</ENAMEX>, a former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adviser</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>. Among the duties
of the advisory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX> are guiding the technologists about politics and helping
design products that attract <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> to the site, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Howard</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founder</ENAMEX>, who also founded <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hayes Corp.</ENAMEX>, the modem <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX>.

            
"There's no question it's a marriage made in heaven," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Downey</ENAMEX>. "It's your
opportunity to be involved in politics, touch on policy, have some impact, and
have a piece of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that could conceivably do very well."

            No one
will divulge the numbers of options they are getting. These are private
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> right now. They don't have to make large <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stockholders</ENAMEX> known until the
company files with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX> to go public. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCurry</ENAMEX> jokes that he doesn't even
remember how many options he's been promised, and he really doesn't know if
they're worth anything. (The rule of thumb is that they're only worth something
if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> is a success and is acquired or goes public.)

            "We're
not stupid," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCurry</ENAMEX> joked, about the steady stream of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> he's
following to the Web. "But there is a little more noble cause in this for me.
I've been spending a lot of time, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> plus since I left the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>, talking to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> about how we can improve the quality of information
available to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen</ENAMEX>. There should be a little altruism in
everyone's life," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCurry</ENAMEX> said, "and a few stock options."

            Some
startup <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEOs</ENAMEX> say they don't want to play the game of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Battle</ENAMEX> of the
Political <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Boards</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Justin Dangel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founder</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Voter</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX>, said he was more
interested in hiring political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX>, such as former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy Tate</ENAMEX>, who led
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian Coalition</ENAMEX> until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX>, and former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> political
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Craig Smith</ENAMEX>.

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Consultants</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisers</ENAMEX> are liabilities you pay for," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dangel</ENAMEX> says. "Staff are
assets."

         
      
   
