
   
   
      
         
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Arguments</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Online Fund</ENAMEX> Raising

            Online
contributions for the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> top presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> totaled <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3,290,000</NUMEX>
during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>, according to a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Politics Online</ENAMEX> survey. That sum is less than 3
percent of the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$138,600,000</NUMEX> they raised overall. And even this unimpressive
number is inflated by contributions that are mailed in but accompanied by
downloaded contribution forms. (When you account for this, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX> and not
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> in online fund raising, with <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.3 million</NUMEX>
collected.) But although online fund raising has yet to catch on in any serious
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX>, there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> good reasons to believe at least some of the hype about how
big it may turn out to be before the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> election cycle is over.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>.
It's cheaper. Online fund raising is less costly than direct mail, phone
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">solicitations</ENAMEX>, or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000-</NUMEX>a-plate fund-raising dinners. Raising money the
old-fashioned way requires hiring professional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fund-raisers</ENAMEX> to identify
potential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contributors</ENAMEX> and convince them to write checks. Raising money on a
Web site is much less expensive. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> campaign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">treasurer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Max Fose</ENAMEX> estimates
that it costs <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">roughly $300</NUMEX> to raise <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX> through direct mail, while it costs
only <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100</NUMEX> to raise <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX> online-that's <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">66 percent</NUMEX> cheaper.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>.
It's easier. E-fund-raising enables <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> to cut down on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">time-consuming ballroom</ENAMEX> speeches and the humiliating spectacle of posing for
pictures with wealthy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Companies</ENAMEX> such as Politics Online handle the
donation transactions and instantaneously transfer the dough into the campaign
bank accounts for <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX> of the take.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>.
It's faster. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX> reduces the otherwise tedious process of contributing
to a campaign to a mere click of the mouse. By facilitating instant
contributions, the Internet could help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> capitalize quickly on early
primary wins by buying more TV ads. This may allow <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX>
to remain competitive through later primaries if they do well in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hampshire</ENAMEX>.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>.
It brings in new money. While traditional fund-raising methods tend to
plumb the same ranks of potential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX> attracts fresh contributors
to the political process. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> campaign estimates that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">39 percent</NUMEX> of its
online <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contributors</ENAMEX> are first-time <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX>.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>.
It's cleaner. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Candidates</ENAMEX> benefit from the perception that online donations
are purer than checks written in response to personal appeals. This may be
true, since the average online contribution is low-dollar and not "bundled,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">i.e.</ENAMEX>, not gathered en masse with the interests of some industry or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> in
mind. For this reason, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Makinson</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center for Responsive Politics</ENAMEX>
argues that e-fund-raising is "the only healthy development in the
campaign-finance process."

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. It has symbolic value. Online cash intake is already being
used as a barometer of grass-roots support. On <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>
recently touted his Internet fund-raising success as an answer to charges that
of big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contributors</ENAMEX>. Of course, the increasing tendency of political
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">handicappers</ENAMEX> to cite the size of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>' Web war chests will encourage
campaigns to pump up their e-fund-raising efforts. It will also encourage them
to artificially pump up the amounts raised in this way, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s campaigns are currently doing with contributions that aren't really
made online.

         
      
   
