
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> Connection&nbsp;

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> political corruption scandal is spreading across <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, and on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>
it led not only the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> papers but several <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> ones as well.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Le Figaro</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> splashed across
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> columns an allegation aired on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> television that one of
ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chancellor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helmut Kohl</ENAMEX>'s secret financial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">benefactors</ENAMEX> was late <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">François Mitterrand</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mitterrand</ENAMEX> was said to have used <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>'s
state-owned <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Elf</ENAMEX> energy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> to channel <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">millions of dollars</NUMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kohl</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union</ENAMEX> in order to get him re-elected-an odd idea because
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mitterrand</ENAMEX> was a socialist and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kohl</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>'s most powerful
conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>. But several <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> papers noted that their personal
friendship and shared commitment to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> ideal overrode ideological
considerations. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Frankfurter</ENAMEX> Allgemeine
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zeitung</ENAMEX> reminded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>' intimacy by republishing a
famous <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1984</TIMEX> photograph of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kohl</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mitterrand</ENAMEX> standing hand in hand at the site
of the bloody battle of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Verdun</ENAMEX> during a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franco</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> reconciliation ceremony
to commemorate <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">I.</ENAMEX>

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Die Welt</ENAMEX> led on growing fears within
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDU</ENAMEX> that the scandal could split the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> and even destroy it. This, as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Le Figaro</ENAMEX> noted, was what <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>'s corruption scandal did to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian Democrat</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Party</ENAMEX> after it had been in power <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">40 years</TIMEX> and, like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDU</ENAMEX>,
seemed unassailable as a major political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunday Times of London</ENAMEX> exposed a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> dimension to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> crisis when it fronted allegations that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stuart</ENAMEX>
Iddles, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Airbus Industrie</ENAMEX>, had arranged
kickbacks worth <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">millions of dollars</NUMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karlheinz Schreiber</ENAMEX>, the German
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">businessman</ENAMEX> at the heart of the scandal, who then passed at least some of the
money on to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kohl</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schreiber</ENAMEX> allegedly got the kickbacks for helping sell <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Airbus</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Thai</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airlines</ENAMEX>. Everyone named in the scandal has denied
allegations of this kind.

            Ezer
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weizman</ENAMEX>'s TV address to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> announcing his refusal to resign as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>, despite the launch of a criminal investigation into his
admitted receipt of cash gifts from a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> former business <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">associate</ENAMEX>, was
badly received by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX>. Writing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maariv</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">commentator Amnon Dankner</ENAMEX> attacked <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weizman</ENAMEX> for revealing nothing except his
determination to stay in office. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidency</ENAMEX> is mainly a symbol," he wrote.
"A presidency under criminal investigation that keeps its mouth shut in the
face of serious public accusations tramples the symbol into the mud and has no
more value. ... To use a metaphor from the world of flying, of which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weizman</ENAMEX> is
so fond, he should have operated his ejection seat <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three weeks ago</TIMEX>. He didn't
do so, and now he hovers over us with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> burnt-out engines and a broken <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wing</ENAMEX>,
shortly to crash on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heads</ENAMEX> of us all."

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yediot Aharonot</ENAMEX> was more indulgent. It described <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weizman</ENAMEX> as "a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">courageous</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">fighter</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">courageous statesman …</ENAMEX> a warm <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> among cold <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, a
sensitive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> among the insensitive, a brave <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cowards</ENAMEX>." But it said
his TV appearance "did not bear witness to public courage or sensitivity to
public discomfort." It went on, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weizman</ENAMEX> seemed to sense this. That may be why,
when he said 'I look you in the eye,' his eyes were searching the paper in
front of him." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yediot Aharonot</ENAMEX> said that, after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50 years</TIMEX> of public
service, it was implausible for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weizman</ENAMEX> to claim that he acted innocently on
the advice of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>. "The correct conclusion from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weizman</ENAMEX>'s appearance
last night may be that he is too naive to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>."

            In
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ha'aretz</ENAMEX> , military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ze'ev Schiff</ENAMEX> reported that "various
circles in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>" had been "stunned" by the huge sums requested by
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> in security aid to follow its eventual withdrawal from the Golan
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Heights</ENAMEX>. After <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protests</ENAMEX>, the demand was trimmed from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$17.4 billion</NUMEX> to
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$16.9 billion</NUMEX>, partly through cuts in requested intelligence funding. Then
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> surprised the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> again by almost doubling the number of
Tomahawk cruise <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX> it said it needed.

            As the
government stood accused by a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> TV <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> of claiming <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">less than a tenth</NUMEX>
of the real number of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> killed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chechnya</ENAMEX>, the latest issue of
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> military <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nezavisimoye Voyennoye Obozreniye</ENAMEX> said the
official "numbers game" about casualties is losing any relation to reality.
Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chechens</ENAMEX> are wildly exaggerating each other's losses.
If <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figures</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chechen</ENAMEX> losses were to be believed, there would be almost
no resistance to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> attempts to take <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grozny</ENAMEX>.

            In an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">op-ed</ENAMEX> article <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">London Evening Standard</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity Fair</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Hitchens</ENAMEX> said that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> presidential election
campaign owed its dreariness in part to manipulation by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX>. "The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Hampshire</ENAMEX> are microscopic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX> on the margin of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> society as it actually is," he wrote. "Nobody can remember how they
got to take the first whack at weeding the field of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>, and no sane
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">system</ENAMEX> would ever have granted them the permission. But this time not even
their rural <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cussedness</ENAMEX> can impart any drama to a race in which dollars and
polls have done their work before any 'real' vote is counted." 

         
      
   
