
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Horace</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Epistle i.</ENAMEX><NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX>

            Vala,
what's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the winter</TIMEX> like at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Velia</ENAMEX>?
Tell me about the climate at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salerno</ENAMEX>.
What are the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like? Are there good <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX>?
Musa, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX>, has seen to it that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baiae</ENAMEX>'s
Absolutely out of the question for me
And furthermore he's seen to it that I'm
Extremely unpopular there, now that he makes me
Pour <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice water</ENAMEX> over myself in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the middle of winter</TIMEX>.

            
Naturally <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Baiae</ENAMEX> grumbles because its groves
Of myrtle are now no longer what one resorts to,
And its sulfur hot <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">baths scorned</ENAMEX>, so celebrated
Once upon a time for being good for
Everything that ails <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, and they're miffed
By <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">invalids</ENAMEX> who go away to put
Their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heads</ENAMEX> and shoulders under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clusium</ENAMEX>'s waters
Or else to plunge in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gabii</ENAMEX>'s frigid <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">baths</ENAMEX>.

            So I
have to change my route and drive right past
The old familiar places. "Where are you going?
This isn't the way to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baiae</ENAMEX> or to Cumas"-
That's what the rider's going to say to his <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horse</ENAMEX>,
Angrily trying to make him go the old way,
But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horse</ENAMEX> has the bit in his mouth and won't be turned.

            Tell me, what <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> down
there is the best for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>?
Do they have fresh <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> there, flowing from springs
The whole <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> round, or do they have to use

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rainwater</ENAMEX> collected in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">tanks</ENAMEX> and saved for the purpose?
No point in even asking about the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX>.
At <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> I'm used to putting up with whatever;
But when I go away I want to have
Something a whole lot nicer, smooth and mellow,
Infusing hopefulness into the heart and veins,
Good for banishing care and promoting a flow
Of eloquence to make some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> think
That I'm still young when it's perfectly clear I'm not.
Which town down there is better for serving rabbit,
Which for wild boar, which one is better for <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX>,
So I'll come back home as fat as a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Phaeacian</ENAMEX>?
Write me a letter; you're my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authority</ENAMEX>.

            Maenius
with great spirit squandered all
The inheritance he had from his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>,
And so became an extra <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> and sponger,
A parasite with no fixed place of his own,
Who when he needed a dinner would gladly dine out
On vicious scandal he spread with impartial justice
About both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foe</ENAMEX>. And when he wasn't
Able to wangle an invitation he lived
On dishes of cheap gray <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">lamb</ENAMEX>, inveighing against
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gluttons</ENAMEX> and prodigals, saying they ought to be branded.
But when he ate well he ate it all up and said,
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">My heavens</ENAMEX>, this ragout of quail is simply delicious."

            I'm
just like that. When there isn't a lot to be had,
I'm very good at praising moderation;
But when there's something better and richer offered,
Why then I'm very good at praising how
You rich <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> live and dine in your splendid <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
