
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">372</NUMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Stakes Sauce</ENAMEX>"

             

             

             

            

               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>'s contests determined that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tennessee Titans</ENAMEX> will face the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Louis Rams</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Super Bowl</ENAMEX> XXXIV. Inevitably the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayors</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nashville</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louis</ENAMEX> will wager well-known local products on the big game. What's their bet?
(Question courtesy of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jon Delfin</ENAMEX>.)
               
            

             

            Send
your answer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.

             

             

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>'s
Question (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 371</ENAMEX>)-- "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Measured Response":</ENAMEX>
            

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Eight</NUMEX> feet, pondered <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Breyer</ENAMEX>. What <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about 3 feet</NUMEX>? asked
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Rehnquist</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">inches</NUMEX>, or even <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">an eighth</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">an inch</NUMEX>,
considered <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Antonin Scalia</ENAMEX>. At <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> session, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justices</ENAMEX> were quite concerned with the size of something. What?
            

            "The
distance from a homeless shelter that a family of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> must remain if both
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> have been unemployed for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than six days</TIMEX>."- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Kahn</ENAMEX>
( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Amoros</ENAMEX> had a similar answer.)

            "They
were pondering the ideal distance from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> should be when
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> spits on him."- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marshall Efron</ENAMEX>
            

            "How
wide a jail <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> has to be before it constitutes cruel and unusual
punishment."- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis Heaney</ENAMEX>
            

            "The
space allotted for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abe Rosenthal</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily News</ENAMEX> column."- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sullivan</ENAMEX>
            

            "Could
you please not stand so close to me when you ask that? And get out of my way.
I'm deliverin' <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PIZZA</ENAMEX> for chrissake."- <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan E. Snow</ENAMEX>
            

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cruel</ENAMEX>, dim, and out of
touch with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> life-no, not the evil <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bastards</ENAMEX> who killed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Charles</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schulz</ENAMEX>-the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U. S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>, at least that's how they look to quiz
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">participants</ENAMEX>. Scorn for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> has been a consistent theme of quiz
responses; that's one of the things I've learned as we near the second
anniversary of the quiz. (Yes, there will be a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>; yes, gifts are
appropriate; and yes, my clothing sizes and preferences in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">porcelain</ENAMEX> figurines
[drunken belligerent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clowns</ENAMEX>] will be posted as soon as those lovable bumblers
at <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Shining Path</ENAMEX> get the site up and working.) A <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> thing I've learned is
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schulz</ENAMEX> is actually alive; apparently they just beat him so badly that he
can no longer draw. And <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a third</NUMEX> observation is that, judging by the higher than
usual number of responses, quiz <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> love an invitation to a penis
joke. So here's a gift for you, a question I didn't run <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1949</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harry</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Truman</ENAMEX> did it <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">88</NUMEX> times; in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> did it <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">545</NUMEX> times. What? (See
below.)

            
               If <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">You Can't Harass</ENAMEX>
From <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Feet You Don't Deserve To Be Called a Religious Fanatic Answer</ENAMEX>
            

            As I understand the law, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> was considering
how big a distance might be maintained between a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> going to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> and
a shrieking <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> wishing to intimidate her.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> (No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">98</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1856</NUMEX>) challenges a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX> law establishing a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">100-foot</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">zone</ENAMEX> around the entrance to any health-care
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX>. Within that zone, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> may not, without consent, approach anyone
within <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">8 feet</NUMEX> to engage in "oral protest, education, or counseling" on a public
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sidewalk</ENAMEX>.

            Anti-abortion <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX> say this abridges free
speech. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Colorado</ENAMEX>, supported by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX> other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>,
says that at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> feet one can speak in a normal tone of voice and be clearly
heard, and thus the law does nothing to curb "uninhibited debate on all
topics." It merely allows a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> to go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> without someone screaming
in her face.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACLU</ENAMEX> has filed a
brief on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">plaintiff</ENAMEX>'s behalf.

            
                
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Singer</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amtrak Slogan Ongoing Extra</ENAMEX>
            

            The commuter <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">train</ENAMEX> I ride from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each day</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">MARC</ENAMEX>, is having a contest.

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amtrak</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">MARC</ENAMEX> take the safety of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX>
very seriously. Almost <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customer</ENAMEX> is injured while boarding or
getting off of a train. They slip on the stairs or fall between the gap between
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">train</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">platform</ENAMEX>, etc., etc. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amtrak</ENAMEX> and its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commuter Division</ENAMEX> try
very hard to raise Safety awareness of its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Passengers</ENAMEX> by using simple, short
Safety Slogans such as 'Walk, Don't Run,' 'Watch the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gap</ENAMEX>' or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">'Stay Alert</ENAMEX>, Stay
Alive,' etc., etc. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amtrak</ENAMEX> would like our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Commuter Customers</ENAMEX> to help us find
some new slogans."

            I'd like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Quiz</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> to provide those
slogans.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reponses</ENAMEX> will run
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> and be forwarded to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amtrak</ENAMEX> for a shot at the big <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prize</ENAMEX>, a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one-month</TIMEX>
free pass on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">MARC</ENAMEX>.

            
               Answer to Bonus
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Penis Joke Question</ENAMEX>
            

            Sent goons over to beat
the hell out of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Schulz</ENAMEX>.

            
               Actual Answer to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bonus Penis Joke Question</ENAMEX>
            

            Gave speeches.

            
                
            

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX> hearings nostalgia.

         
      
   
