
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vietnam&nbsp</ENAMEX>;

            A year
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ago</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX> faced a daunting challenge in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX>. Each man
was up against a well-financed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">front-runner</ENAMEX> who could marshal interest groups
and local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> to bring out a big vote on <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">caucus night</TIMEX>. Each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> had
taken a principled position during his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> career-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> against ethanol
subsidies, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> against <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Midwestern</ENAMEX> flood relief funded by federal
borrowing-that could be used against him in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> decided to go into
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> anyway. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> decided to stay out. That difference says a great deal
about where each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> comes from and where he goes from here.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> is an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">idealist</ENAMEX>. Unlike the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">technocrats</ENAMEX>, party <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hacks</ENAMEX>, and angry
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past three decades</TIMEX>, he echoes the valor and innocence of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 1960s</TIMEX>.
The class warfare of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Gephardt</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Harkin</ENAMEX> is as foreign to
looks instead to the programs and principles of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Frontier</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Society</ENAMEX>. He preaches faith, boldness, and big solutions to national problems.
He sees distrust of government not as educated skepticism but as uneducated
cynicism. He calls for a new war on poverty. He wants to outlaw anti-gay
discrimination by reopening the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1964 Civil Rights Act</ENAMEX>. He speaks constantly of
"racial unity" without defining it, as though the very concept were as
controversial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> as it was then. His campaign slogan distills the idealism
of that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">era</TIMEX>: "It can happen."

            The
case against that idealism is that it didn't happen-that big government
solutions failed or backfired, that the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">War</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Poverty</ENAMEX> was lost, and that the
racial equality that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> promised in law remained frustrated by cultural
and economic factors they had thought government could easily overcome. These
setbacks brought discredit to the whole idea of government activism, converting
practical failure into political failure. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Liberalism</ENAMEX> became a dirty word.
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>, banished from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>, learned to temper their ambitions.
The courage of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore Sr.</ENAMEX>, who lost his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> seat to a liberal-bashing
campaign in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1970</TIMEX>, gave way to the caution of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore Jr.</ENAMEX>

            But
caution can be frustrating. Why not guarantee health insurance for all
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>? Why not outlaw all cheap handguns? Why not ban soft money and fund
elections publicly? This is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s inspiration and message: He's tired of
"timid" <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> who "nibble around the edges." With confidence and principle,
he argues, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> can create "a world of new possibilities, guided by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">goodness</ENAMEX>," in which all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">obstacles</ENAMEX> can be surmounted. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s entrenched assets
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> seemed just another obstacle. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> didn't flinch. He joined the
battle on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s terrain. He poured <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">millions of dollars</NUMEX> into the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. He
offered a vision of a better world, confident that he could win over the hearts
and minds of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iowans</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> witnessed that kind of confidence in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>: the courage to fight on
unfamiliar terrain, the will to spend freely, the faith in hearts and minds. He
spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> in a prison <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> paying the price of those ambitions. He learned
the skepticism of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldier</ENAMEX>. Like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> is an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">idealist</ENAMEX>. But unlike
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>, he came away from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1960s</TIMEX> chastened by nobility's limits. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">McCain</ENAMEX>
sees a world not of "new possibilities, guided by goodness" but of threats
abroad and hubris at home. To those who believe gun control will cure school
violence, he replies that the Internet is full of Web sites illustrating how to
build pipe bombs. To those who promise big tax cuts based on projected
surpluses, he replies that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> must first pay off its debts and
trust funds.

            Having
experienced war firsthand, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> respects prudence more than bravado. He sees
the battles before him as tests not of manhood but of strategy and discipline.
His objective is to get the job done. He saw that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> was a quagmire. He saw
that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Hampshire</ENAMEX>, with its open primary and penchant for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mavericks</ENAMEX>, was more
favorable terrain. The book on presidential politics says a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> must
compete in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> to be taken seriously. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> throw out the book all the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>. So <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> spurned <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX>. He gambled that he could raise enough money and
drum up enough support in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Hampshire</ENAMEX> polls to guarantee his credibility
until the primary.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s mantra is that he's willing to fight. "I am not afraid," he repeated
over and over in his announcement speech <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last fall</TIMEX>. But his strategic advantage
is the opposite: Having proved his courage as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldier</ENAMEX>, he can get away with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ducking</ENAMEX> fights as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>. No one who avoided the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> draft by signing
up as an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Air Guardsman</ENAMEX> can call a POW a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coward</ENAMEX>. So
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> gave him a bye on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX>. And just in case anyone in
the press corps thought of accusing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> of chickening out, he framed his
evasion of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> as a sacrifice he had to endure for his principled opposition
to ethanol subsidies.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">McCain</ENAMEX>
got <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5 percent</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> vote in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> last night. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> got <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">35 percent</NUMEX>
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> vote. Yet the media consensus is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> is ready for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Hampshire</ENAMEX>, while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> has suffered a grievous blow and faces the
likelihood of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conclusive</ENAMEX> defeat <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX>. Front pages and TV <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> now
speak of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> in the past tense while bubbling with excitement over a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Granite State</ENAMEX> showdown for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Forbes</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>. "<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Tonight</TIMEX>,
I have a little more humility, but no less confidence that I can win and do the
job," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> conceded as the unhappy returns came in. The confidence may well
be warranted. But the humility may have come too late. 

         
      
   
