
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Downsizing Hell&nbsp</ENAMEX>;

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan.</TIMEX>
31
            

            The
cover
piece regurgitates the conventional wisdom on the presidential
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> is running on a "goodness <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">platform</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>
"believes <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> were put on earth to cut taxes," etc. … An
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX>
argues that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> has crippled his campaign by spending too much money and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX>. … An article
on the hyped-to-<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the-hilt</TIMEX> launch of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oxygen</ENAMEX> notes the obstacles to the women's
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cable</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX>'s success. Despite the promise of an <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oprah Winfrey</ENAMEX> show, a yoga
program, and Web tie-ins, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX> will debut in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 10 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> and
faces a powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitor</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Lifetime</TIMEX>.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan.</TIMEX>
31
            

            The
cover
story says that vitamin E, estrogen, and anti-inflammatory drugs reduce
the risk of developing <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Alzheimer's disease</ENAMEX>. Pharmaceutical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> are also
rushing to develop <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medications</ENAMEX> that will stall the disease by slowing the brain
plaque formation that causes <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Alzheimer's</ENAMEX>. … In an essay ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maureen Reagan</ENAMEX> reveals that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX> is losing his motor skills and can no
longer put his thoughts into words. … A profile
describes how <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lyor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cohen</ENAMEX> became "the most powerful executive
in hip-hop." Clever street-marketing techniques and "all-out advocacy of his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX>" earned him the loyalty of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">superstar</ENAMEX> rappers such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jay-Z</ENAMEX> and Foxy
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brown</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX> &
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Report</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 31</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover
story predicts that hell will survive, despite its downsizing. Pope
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Paul II</ENAMEX> envisions hell as a state of perpetual angst rather than as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fiery</ENAMEX> pit. Most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> agree that the netherworld is merely "an anguished
state of existence." … A piece argues
that prosperity and nationwide effervescence have "softened the political
culture." Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> are advocating a blend of tax cuts and social
investment.

            
               
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> ,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 31</TIMEX>
            

            A
profile portrays <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> driven by the desire to avenge his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> and to best the intellectual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elite</ENAMEX> who bugged him in college. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> is
the last of the silver-spooners, born to privilege before meritocracy ended
easy access to elite <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX> and golden-ring jobs. "He'll come to the
presidency with a lighter <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">résumé</ENAMEX> than anybody has in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at least a hundred years</TIMEX>."
… An article weighs <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Hockney</ENAMEX>'s ingenious theory that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ingres</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caravaggio</ENAMEX> used refracting technology to trace the outlines of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hockney</ENAMEX> argues that the assured lines in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ingres</ENAMEX>' sketches are optical evidence
that his work was "lens-assisted." There is no known documentary evidence to
support <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hockney</ENAMEX>'s claim.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Business Week</ENAMEX> ,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 31</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover story describes how <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> is cultivating its high-tech economy. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Ireland</ENAMEX>
is the world's <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>-largest software <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exporter</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Barcelona</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> for
e-startups, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Strasbourg</ENAMEX> is sprouting biotech <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX>. Monetary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX> and
relaxed fiscal policy are sparking the boom. … An article applauds a new
commercial artificial-vision system. For <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $50,000</NUMEX>, the blind can have a
circuit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> inserted in their brains that will stimulate the visual cortex
and produce grainy black-and-white images out of optical data captured through
a tiny camera. The product could make the blind more independent.

            
               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> ,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 31</TIMEX>
            

            The

cover story calls for renewed dedication to planetary exploration. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mars Polar Lander</ENAMEX> disaster threatens to cripple <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASA</ENAMEX>'s space exploration
program, which has struggled since the "national psychic letdown that followed
the moon landings." Colonizing other worlds would be "the ultimate
adventure."

            
               
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nation</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb.</TIMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>
            

            An
editorial
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> the redistribution of political power through a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100-$200</NUMEX>
campaign-contribution tax credit. (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>, contributions to political campaigns
are not tax-deductible.) A tax credit would increase public confidence in
government by enabling ordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> to participate in the political
process. … The cover story blames
public apathy on the professionalization of politics. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Polling</ENAMEX> has whittled
politics into a science, and money has monstrously deflated the importance of
grassroots support.  

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX> ,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 31</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover
story applauds <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX>'s ideological apostasy. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> opposes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">orthodoxy</ENAMEX> on campaign-finance reform and tax cuts. Unlike <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> preaches fiscal conservatism, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> universal health insurance, and
refuses to divert public school funds to private voucher programs. His
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">candidacy</ENAMEX> has started a healthy debate within <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ranks</ENAMEX>. … An
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX>
blasts the latest campaign-finance abuses. Although <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> accepted the
single biggest bundle (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$209,500</NUMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goldman Sachs</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> is "the undisputed
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bundling king</ENAMEX>." (
                  Slate
               's "" explains why bundling corrodes
democracy.) … A piece
mocks the anti-campaign <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> is waging in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX>. To lower expectations for the
upcoming caucus, his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> deny they are even organizing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan.</TIMEX>
22
            

            The
cover
editorial argues that the level of debt in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
leaves the world's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> biggest economies vulnerable to economic crises.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> should raise interest rates to discourage further borrowing.
… The cover
story warns that the next debt crisis is likely to occur in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> or
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>'s stimulus packages have widened the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s debt
to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">128 percent</NUMEX> of GDP. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Inordinate</ENAMEX> government borrowing discourages private
investment. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s private-sector debt was <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">103 percent</NUMEX> of
personal income. Soaring private debt will "amplify any economic downturn."
… An article
condemns former <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chancellor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helmut Kohl</ENAMEX> for harboring secret party bank
accounts and refusing to divulge the names of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX>. Corrupt party financing
"strikes at the heart of democracy." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kohl</ENAMEX>'s misdeeds have earned him the name
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Don Kohleone</ENAMEX>."

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rolling Stone</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Feb. 3</ENAMEX>
            

            The
cover story reveals that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Crosby</ENAMEX> fathered the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> of Melissa
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Etheridge</ENAMEX> and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julie Cypher</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crosby</ENAMEX> gave his <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sperm</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Etheridge</ENAMEX> and
her longtime <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX> because he wanted to encourage lesbian parenting.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crosby</ENAMEX> comments, "I think everyone will understand, except maybe the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coalition</ENAMEX>."  

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Magazine</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 23</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover story chronicles <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>'s remedial education in politics. The early
incompetence of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> campaign forced the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> to eschew his
ambivalence about politicking and come "to terms with his outer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX>."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s political performances often "reek of the greasepaint he rightly
scorns," but there are signs "that he can make a style of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">substance</ENAMEX>." …
An article champions former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> publisher <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Otis Chandler</ENAMEX>'s
decision to speak out against the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s current management. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chandler</ENAMEX>'s
protest against the crude commercialization of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> has made him "a
latter-day <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> to many newspaper <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX>." (
                  Slate
               's ""
criticizes the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chandler</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cult</ENAMEX>.) … A piece ridicules "fauxhemians"--rich
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> who dress up conspicuous consumption "in the artfully tattered guise of
the downscale and democratic." Example: the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VW Beetle</ENAMEX>.
(
                  Slate
               's "" laments the decline of genuine <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> bohemians.) 


             

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harper</ENAMEX>'s ,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 2000</TIMEX>
            

            An
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">excerpt of Oval Office</ENAMEX> recordings <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">captures</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Nixon</ENAMEX>'s most hateful
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ravings</ENAMEX>. On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicanos</ENAMEX>: "They're dishonest, but … [t]hey don't live like a bunch
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX>, which the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Negroes</ENAMEX> do live like." On <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Catholicism: Popes</ENAMEX> "were layin'
the nuns; that's been goin' on for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">centuries</TIMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">… A George W. Bush</ENAMEX>
cover story argues that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s record of crony capitalism is a poor omen for
his presidency. Despite "catastrophic losses," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s oil <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> was
repeatedly bailed out by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">businessmen</ENAMEX> who hoped to profit from his influence. By
hiking his share in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Rangers</ENAMEX> from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1.8 percent to 12 percent</NUMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cronies</ENAMEX> helped him realize a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2,400 percent</NUMEX> return on his investment.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">appointees</ENAMEX> used their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state power</ENAMEX> to benefit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
