
   
   
      
         
            No.<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">373</NUMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Courtier</ENAMEX>"

             

             

             

             

            
               On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> ruled in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Shrink Missouri</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Government PAC</ENAMEX> . Fill in
the blank as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Paul Stevens</ENAMEX> sums up the majority opinion: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Money</ENAMEX> is
property; it is not ___________."
                
            

             

            Send
your answer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.

             

             

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s Question
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 372</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Stakes Sauce":</ENAMEX>
            

            

               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>'s contests determined that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tennessee Titans</ENAMEX> will face the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Louis Rams</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Super Bowl</ENAMEX> XXXIV. Inevitably the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayors</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nashville</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louis</ENAMEX> will wager well-known local products on the big game. What's their bet?
(Question courtesy of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jon Delfin</ENAMEX>.)
               
            

            "Dolly
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parton</ENAMEX>'s breast implants against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark McGwire</ENAMEX>'s shrunken, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">steroid</ENAMEX>-ruined
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">testicles</ENAMEX>."- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brooke Saucier</ENAMEX>
            

            "If
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Louis</ENAMEX> wins, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tennessee</ENAMEX> drops all criminal charges currently pending against
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rams</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX>, and vice versa."- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Carlin</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Well</ENAMEX>,
given that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> grew up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Louis</ENAMEX> … wait, sorry, that would only be
funny if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> had grown up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tennessee</ENAMEX>."- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg Diamond</ENAMEX>
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarence Thomas</ENAMEX>' penis. Oh, crap. That was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s answer. Sorry."- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jon</ENAMEX>
Hotchkiss
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Beats</ENAMEX>
me. Does 'incest' count as a product?"- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Carvell</ENAMEX>
            

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
            

            To quiz <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX> that symbolizes <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nashville</ENAMEX> is, of course, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grand Ole Opry</ENAMEX>, and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX> that symbolizes <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Louis</ENAMEX> is the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">12-ounce</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Budweiser</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX> can-not
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arch</ENAMEX>, which was mentioned only a few times. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nashville</ENAMEX> has its own failed
attempt at a symbolic <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX>: None of you referred to the life-size model of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Parthenon</ENAMEX> located in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Centennial Park</ENAMEX> (or to the life-size model of a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jew</ENAMEX>,
so beloved by school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Natural History Museum</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">diorama</ENAMEX> is wonderful: The "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Torah</ENAMEX>" and "roasting <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX>" are incredibly
lifelike!). The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Opry</ENAMEX> succeeds where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arch</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parthenon</ENAMEX> fail because it is
not merely a tourist attraction but a vibrant part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s life, with a
genuine, if regrettable, purpose-as a performance space for country music-while
these latter <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> are self-conscious attempts to construct a symbol. So the
lesson is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Empire</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Building</ENAMEX>, good; <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Space Needle</ENAMEX>, bad. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monument</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln Memorial</ENAMEX>, and their ilk seem to be exceptions to this
rule, being evocative symbols of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX> but lacking apparent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">utility</ENAMEX>.
However the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln Memorial</ENAMEX> is not a cheap bit of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chamber of commerce</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">boosterism</ENAMEX>; it is a genuine attempt to honor the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">th president</ENAMEX>,
just as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Monument</ENAMEX> is meant to inspire penis jokes about
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">presidents</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX>, and former <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> eager to pick up a quick buck, and
so to unite a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>.

            
                
               Inadequately
Researched Answer
            

            I found no stories about mayoral wagering of local
products. I mourn the lost clichés of labored regionalism and my own inability
to figure out these "search engine" thingies.

            However, for traditional money <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gamblers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Louis</ENAMEX>
is an <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>-point favorite; the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over</NUMEX>-and-under bet is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">48 1/2</NUMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">About 80 percent</NUMEX> of the
action will be on which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> wins, but <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vegas</ENAMEX> bookmakers offer <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 200</NUMEX>
wagering options, including <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Player to Score First Touchdown</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eddie George</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Titans</ENAMEX>, is the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> favorite); the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Double Result</ENAMEX>, a bet on who's ahead at the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> and at the end (you can have <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tennessee</ENAMEX> at the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Louis</ENAMEX> at the
end at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">7-2</ENAMEX>); who scores <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> and who wins the game (you can take the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rams</ENAMEX> both
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ways</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5-6</ENAMEX>). What <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> gets arrested for a felony during the actual game
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marshall Faulk, Rams</ENAMEX>, is a long shot at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20-1</NUMEX>). The odds are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50-1</NUMEX> against this
last bet actually being offered in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vegas</ENAMEX>, although I once rented an <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Uzi</ENAMEX> not 100
yards from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Strip</ENAMEX>, so pretty much anything goes. And the shrimp
cocktail-huge! And virtually free. 
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caucus</ENAMEX>
Results <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Augmented Quotations Extra</ENAMEX>
            

            (Each final sentence added by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Quiz</ENAMEX>.)

            

               

                  "We've had a record-shattering victory, and I never
dreamt I'd be able to get such a high vote total. I have dreamt about
having sex with a gun, but that was before I stopped drinking and started
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">executin</ENAMEX>'; I'm better now."- G.W. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> is giddy with victory.
                  

               

               

                  "The power <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">brokers</ENAMEX> and the power elite are worried
because they have no hooks in me. Calm down, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX>, I'm on your side, and so is
my <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">gold-plated monkey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Popo: And</ENAMEX>, yes, that is a real diamond on his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ass</ENAMEX>."- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Forbes</ENAMEX> is giddy with defeat.
                  

               

               

                  "Don't let anyone convince you that the decent
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">heart of America</ENAMEX> is dead. It won't be dead until I crush it beneath my boot
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">heel</ENAMEX>."- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Keyes</ENAMEX> is just plain giddy.
                  

               

               

                  "The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> don't know any difference when you say
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Tyson</ENAMEX> was convicted of rape or got in a fight with a tourist. They just
want a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">famous guy</ENAMEX> to show them love and respect. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Celebrities</ENAMEX>-is there anything
they can't do?"- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Tyson</ENAMEX> is giddy with not actually running in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">caucuses</ENAMEX>.
                  

               

               

                  "If they really love him, they will come see him.
Obviously they don't love him. Instead of visiting <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Elián</ENAMEX>, his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmothers</ENAMEX>
should get in a fight with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Tyson</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">famous guy</ENAMEX>."<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">- Elly Carrera</ENAMEX>, a
Cuban-American, is giddy with keeping <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eli</ENAMEX>
                     á
                     <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">n</ENAMEX> from running in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> caucuses or from being reunited with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>.
                  

               

            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew Singer</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amtrak</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slogan Ongoing Extra</ENAMEX>
            

            I'm still seeking new safety slogans for the
Baltimore-Washington commuter line I ride to work. Actual slogans include
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Walk</ENAMEX>, Don't Run," <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Watch the Gap</ENAMEX>," and "<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Stay Alert</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Stay Alive</ENAMEX>" and feature
little mockery and derision. Damn government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bureaucrats</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reponses</ENAMEX> will run
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> and be forwarded to contest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> for a shot at the big <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prize</ENAMEX>, a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one-month</TIMEX> free pass on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">MARC</ENAMEX>, but no one will be forced to ride the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MARC</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>.

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anheuser-Busch</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
