
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">371</NUMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Measured Response</ENAMEX>"

             

             

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Eight</NUMEX> feet, pondered <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Breyer</ENAMEX>. What <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about 3 feet</NUMEX>? asked
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Rehnquist</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">inches</NUMEX>, or even <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">an eighth</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">an inch</NUMEX>,
considered <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Antonin Scalia</ENAMEX>. At <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> session, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justices</ENAMEX> were quite concerned with the size of something. What?
            

             

            Send
your answer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 p.m. ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.

             

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s
Question (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 370</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hot Spot":</ENAMEX>
            

            

               Using a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">helicopter</ENAMEX> equipped with a heat-seeking device, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Suffolk County</ENAMEX>
cops located <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">two cinderblock</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">warehouses</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Holbrook</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Long Island</ENAMEX>, and arrested
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> for theft of electricity. What was going on in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">warehouses</ENAMEX>?
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Industrial</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Light & Magic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wizards</ENAMEX> trying to make <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Costner</ENAMEX> hot
again."- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jon Hotchkiss</ENAMEX>
            

            "Ricky
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin</ENAMEX> was filming his triumphant return to the gay porn industry. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boy</ENAMEX>, that's
how rumors get started, isn't it?"- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael J. Basial</ENAMEX>
            

            "Oh,
some sort of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shelter</ENAMEX> for the poor. Don't worry, though; they put a stop to
it."- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Carvell</ENAMEX>
            

            "Since
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> had bolts sticking out of his neck, I'm going to assume that
someone was playing God."- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew Singer</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Davis</ENAMEX> had a
similar answer.)

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> outsourced its executions to the lowest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bidder</ENAMEX>, not knowing how the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contractor</ENAMEX> planned to keep the price so low."<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">- Maia Cowan</ENAMEX> (similarly,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katha Pollitt</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mark Wegener</ENAMEX> )

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
            

            It is difficult to give
a precise definition of electricity (particularly if you spent much of
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">seventh</NUMEX>-grade science class mooning over your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lab partner</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sally Gilbert</ENAMEX>), but
it seems to have something to do with the movement of electrons from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> part
of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Long Island</ENAMEX> to another. Electricity enters our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cinderblock</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">warehouses</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">copper</ENAMEX> wires, much as does <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBO</ENAMEX>, but electricity
generally keeps its blouse on even after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11 o'clock at night</TIMEX> (as did <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sally</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gilbert</ENAMEX>, at least to my adolescent knowledge). Apparently electricity has
something to do with lightning, as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Benjamin Franklin</ENAMEX> demonstrated in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1752</TIMEX> in a
famous experiment that no doubt proved something or other. This didn't make him
any less popular in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> where he was catnip to the ladies. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1768</TIMEX>, Luigi
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Galvani</ENAMEX> ran electric current through the legs of a freshly killed frog making
them twitch and no doubt contributing to the bad feelings most <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">frogs</ENAMEX> have about
their place in the sciences. Not that they were so happy about their place in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>. And so perhaps the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> things we can say with confidence about
electricity are that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) it's tough to be a frog  <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) unless you've been kissed
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sally Gilbert</ENAMEX>.

            
               Highly Potent
Answer
            

            Somebody was growing hydroponic pot.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Police</ENAMEX> charged <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Francisco</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dandraia</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Salinas</ENAMEX> with criminal possession of marijuana and stealing
electricity. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pair</ENAMEX> is accused of tapping into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Long Island Power Authority</ENAMEX>
electric lines for the current to run <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1,000-watt</NUMEX> high-intensity halide lamps
and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">carbon dioxide</ENAMEX> generators to stimulate the growth of pot <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> in
high-tech hydroponic <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">tanks</ENAMEX>. This system produces mature <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">four to six</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX> instead of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several months</TIMEX> required under ordinary growing conditions.
The excellent "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">connoisseur</ENAMEX>'s cannabis" sold for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5,000</NUMEX> a pound. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> spliced
into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LIPA</ENAMEX> power lines not to avoid paying for electricity but to avoid the
huge electric bills, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $50,000</NUMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13 months</TIMEX>, that would have called
attention to their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX>. But heat dispersal was their undoing.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cold Comfort</ENAMEX>
Extra
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> were invited to devise a photo caption
cliché of the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Winter Turns Cold; People Don Hats, Gloves</ENAMEX>" variety for any news
outlet.

            

               

                  
                     <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> -style: "After <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">freak</TIMEX> snowstorm, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angelenos</ENAMEX> in parkas walk past the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Staples Center</ENAMEX>(TM), the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s dynamic new sports, entertainment and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">convention palace</ENAMEX>, which can be
arranged in a variety of configurations for concerts (continued on Page
B2)."- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Hammett</ENAMEX>
                  

               

               

                  "It fits! Homeless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> beams as he tries on mitten
found in trash can."- Katha Pollitt
                  

               

               

                  "Juice in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Frozen Apple</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.J. Simpson</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">above</NUMEX>),
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">caught leaving Le Bernardin</ENAMEX>, looks bundled against the frigid <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">weather</ENAMEX>--but
denies it. 'I'm not cold,' the former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NFL</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> said. 'Some other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> is.'"
( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Daily News</ENAMEX> )- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellis Weiner</ENAMEX>
                  

               

               

                  "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Greenberg</ENAMEX>, one of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Quiz</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> not
to live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>, considers his latest response while enjoying a fish
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">taco</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ocean Beach Pier Cafe</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yesterday</TIMEX>'s high was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">71</NUMEX> with warm weather
expected to continue through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX> (story B3)." ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">San Diego</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union-Tribune</ENAMEX> )- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Greenberg</ENAMEX>
                  

               

               

                  "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> bundles up against the
frigid chill as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">first lady</ENAMEX> announces she will stay with him 'for the rest of
his pathetic, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">godforsaken days</TIMEX>.' "- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Yanosko</ENAMEX>
                  

               

               

                  "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Frosty the Frozen Pool of Ice</ENAMEX> wishes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX> would
just let him die instead of stringing him along with this damn melting and
refreezing over and over again."- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis Heaney</ENAMEX>
                  

               

            

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            Galvanizing dull
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>. 

             

         
      
   
