
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">369</NUMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Pig 'n' Pearl</ENAMEX>"

             

             

            

               "At <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX>, they called it 'throwing the pearls to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">swine</ENAMEX>,' " says
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Kling</ENAMEX>. What's it called off-campus?
            

             

            Send
your answer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s Question
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 368</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Baby, It's Scold Outside":</ENAMEX>
            

            

               On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> a distinguished <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitor</ENAMEX> lambasted a gathering: "Please join
the modern world. Why are you lagging behind? Why do you allow yourselves to be
regarded as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> without <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">talent</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> without a vision?" Who chided whom
for what?
            

            "As
much as I admire <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy Carter</ENAMEX>, I think he was being a little hard on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amish</ENAMEX>."- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andrew Staples</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX>
Gates taunted jury <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> for using <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1-month-old PalmPilot</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">models</ENAMEX>."- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis</ENAMEX>
Heaney
            

            "I
think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Jordan</ENAMEX> is beginning to get a bit frustrated with his new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cohorts</ENAMEX>
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Wizards</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">front office</ENAMEX>."- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aaron Schatz</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Geoff</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ward</ENAMEX>, goateed sophomore, chides each of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Canterbury Tales</ENAMEX>, for being written
during that <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Great Vowel Thing</ENAMEX> and for being 'boring and stupid.' "- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laura</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miller</ENAMEX>
            

            "All
right, so I lost my cool with those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hasid</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX> who come right up to
you and ask if you're <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX>. I don't see why you have to put it all over the
Internet!"- Katha Pollitt
            

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
            

            To
many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Case</ENAMEX> is the apotheosis of modernity, reason enough to
note that the salient feature of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL Time Warner</ENAMEX>-aside from its ability to
crush all before it like a mighty juggernaut-is its massive blandness. It's the
family <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> of media <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">conglomerates</ENAMEX>. A clue to the popularity of such
dullness can be found in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sports Illustrated</ENAMEX> swimsuit issue, the
innovative merging of journalism and soft-core porn that put that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> in
the black and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of frat <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> into a swoon. Why, in an era of readily
available pornography, does AOL thrive by blocking it and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SI</ENAMEX> by selling
it in so watered-down a form? Because it is undemanding. Passionate involvement
with sex, politics, or dinner can be exhausting. Each intense encounter demands
alertness, ingenuity, and a willingness to overturn old assumptions. Each
challenges. On the other hand, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald's</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SI</ENAMEX> swimsuits
are essentially reassuring. Their appeal is their familiarity. They comfort the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participant</ENAMEX>, reinforcing his preconceptions. That's the moneymaking way to
appeal to the timid, the plump, and the contented-i.e., to those who enjoy the
status quo. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald's</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">SI swimsuits</ENAMEX>: Each lulls. Like
a warm glass of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cheese</ENAMEX>.

            
               Averting an Even <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bigger</ENAMEX>
Catastrophe Answer
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nelson Mandela</ENAMEX> upbraided the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Burundi</ENAMEX>'s
warring <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">factions</ENAMEX> for bringing death and misery to their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>, shaming it
before the world.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mandela</ENAMEX> denounced their failure to stop the civil
war that has killed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200,000</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>. He
was especially critical of their not having included the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> of all armed
rebel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> in their negotiations.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burundi</ENAMEX>'s conflict is a
frightening echo of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hutu</ENAMEX>'s slaughter of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least 500,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tutsi</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rwanda</ENAMEX>,
its northern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX>. Recently the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Burundi</ENAMEX> ordered <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">350,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hutu</ENAMEX>
to leave their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> and move to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> camps to deter them from aiding guerrilla
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fighters</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cold Comfort</ENAMEX>
Ongoing Extra
            

            

               

                  "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helen</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ross</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inverness</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scotland</ENAMEX>, is covered with frost after cross-country skiing
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Stowe</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vt.</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Associated Press/ USA Today</ENAMEX> )

               

               

                  
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Passengers on the Staten Island ferry</ENAMEX>, left, were bundled up against the
bitter cold <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Dedario</ENAMEX>, above, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mate</ENAMEX> on the ferryboat, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herbert H. Lehman</ENAMEX>, said he was freezing." ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> )

               

               

                  " 'The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sopranos</ENAMEX>,' <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s greatest television series-no, make that the most
magnificent example of dramatic writing in the history of the world-continues
brilliant work despite current cold snap." ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> )

               

            

            Above, actual "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Winter</ENAMEX>
Turns <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cold; People Don Hats, Gloves</ENAMEX>" photo captions from various news sources
(except the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> one which I simply made up). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> are invited to
concoct similarly clichéd captions from photos that should run in any other
news outlet during the current meteorological unpleasantness. Results to run
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, if my hands aren't too cold to type and my scarf doesn't become
entangled in the keyboard, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isadora Duncan</ENAMEX>-style.

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            Modern <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Case</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
