
   
   
      
         
            Flat-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tax Flap</ENAMEX>

            
               Subject: Pampering
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wealthy</ENAMEX>? No, Fairness

            
               From: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andrew</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sullivan</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>: ""

            
               Date: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fri Jan</ENAMEX>
14

            It's a fair <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cop</ENAMEX>: I think all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX> should pay
the same rate of tax. I also think that equal treatment by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is a
useful idea in the resuscitation of liberalism. Go figure. But I'm not a
wealthy-pamperer. Because <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s punitive tax system means you pay
disproportionately more the richer you are, simply moving to an equal system
inevitably gives a break to the rich. I didn't hide this in the New York
Times Magazine piece. I said so explicitly. But that doesn't mean I give
the rich special favors. I give them the same favors as everyone else; and by
combining a flat tax with tax reform, take away large numbers of their goodies
for good measure.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Surowiecki</ENAMEX> is right in saying that technology makes
complicated things simpler to enforce; but it's also true that in our very
complicated world, the simple-is-beautiful <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mantra</ENAMEX> has increasing cultural
appeal. My point is not that the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40,000</NUMEX>-page tax code isn't easier to enforce
with technology. It is. My point is that the increasing cultural attractiveness
of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-click purchasing increases the cultural attractiveness of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-rate
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">taxation</ENAMEX>. A subjective impression, but a valid <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, I think. If Surowiecki
clambered out of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">paleo-liberal</ENAMEX>, redistributist mindset, he might get
it.

            
               (To reply, click
here .)
            

            
[ <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Sullivan</ENAMEX> is a senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX> and
contributing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Magazine</ENAMEX>.]

            
               Subject: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>:
Pampering the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Wealthy</ENAMEX>? No, Fairness

            
               From: 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Surowiecki</ENAMEX>
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>: ""

             

            
               Date: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mon Jan</ENAMEX>
17

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sullivan</ENAMEX> invokes the mantra of "equal treatment" as
if it's an argument-ender. But treating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> unequally when they're not equal
is, you might say, what social <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice</ENAMEX> is all about. Old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> get <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Security</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>. Poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> get <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX>. Young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> get <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Head</ENAMEX> Start
and free public school and free school lunches and, later, interest-free
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">college</ENAMEX> loans. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Workers</ENAMEX> at the bottom of the pay ladder are guaranteed a minimum
wage. Wage-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">earners</ENAMEX> are paid overtime, while salaried <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> are not.
Unemployed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> get unemployment insurance.

            Perhaps <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sullivan</ENAMEX> thinks all these, too, are
examples of paleo-liberalism. I'd say they're examples of liberal ideas that
enjoy the support of the vast majority of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>, as does the progressive
tax. Most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> believe that once you make a certain amount of money, each
additional dollar matters less, and therefore society has a larger claim on it.
Most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> think there's a difference between making <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50K</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> and making
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2 million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>, and that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> does well to recognize that difference.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sullivan</ENAMEX> doesn't think this, which is fine. He just shouldn't pretend that the
flat tax has anything to do with liberalism.

             

            
               (To reply, click
here.) 
            

            
[ <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Surowiecki</ENAMEX> writes "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moneybox</ENAMEX>."]

            
               (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">To</ENAMEX>
read an unedited version of the entire <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchange</ENAMEX>, click  and scroll to the
bottom of the page.)
            

            
               Subject: Culturebox
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Protects Us From Ourselves</ENAMEX>

            
               From: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Simon</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>: ""

            
               Date: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thu Jan</ENAMEX>
13

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Culturebox</ENAMEX> seems to have missed the glaring
inconsistency of her own position. Claiming that "we are products not just of
evolution, but also of what we imagine ourselves to be," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Culturebox</ENAMEX> decries the
classroom teaching of the evolutionary roots of rape (even as a prelude to
explaining the hows and whys of resisting those roots) on the grounds that
"[t]he <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> message to be drilled into boys' heads [would be]: We believe
you're genetically programmed to rape." The inevitable consequence: "criminal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> composing their genetic-determinist <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">defenses</ENAMEX> ... : Why, even the
state said he couldn't help himself! " Apparently, in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Culturebox</ENAMEX>'s eyes, if
"we imagine ourselves to be" rational, sensible <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">creatures</ENAMEX> capable of
distinguishing between biological drives and moral imperatives, it won't help
us one bit--we'll still be compelled by our natures to view objective
descriptions of those drives as moral justifications for giving in to them.

            Now, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Culturebox</ENAMEX> may well be correct that hungry
young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">males</ENAMEX> (or hungry old defense <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jurors</ENAMEX> of all ages and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">appetites</ENAMEX>) are incapable of resisting the temptation of "tout comprendre,
tout pardonner ." But if so, then it is hardly a triumph for her preferred
"willed culture" over the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animal</ENAMEX> model; rather, it is a subtler, richer
application of the evolutionary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychologists</ENAMEX>' fundamentally wise observation:
that social <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX> fail unless they treat <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX> as the instinct-driven
creatures they are, and avoid pretending that they are the self-defining
logical and aesthetic intellects that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Culturebox</ENAMEX> would like them to be. After
all, if we could truly will our culture to meet our ideals, then we could tell
our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Darwinian</ENAMEX> truth and the moral <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Truth</ENAMEX> without fearing that human
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nature</ENAMEX> will inevitably confuse the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>.

            
               (To reply, click
here .)
            

            
               Subject: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Culturebox Protects Us From Ourselves</ENAMEX>

            
               From: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judith</ENAMEX>
Shulevitz

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>: ""

             

            
               Date: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fri Jan</ENAMEX>
14

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Simon</ENAMEX> misses my point. I'm arguing
that by teaching <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> about the so-called evolutionary roots of rape we are
not teaching them the truth. We're teaching them a deliberately
diminished view of human nature that has been useful in helping <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX>
establish long-overdue connections between human and animal psychology--but
that is not the end-all and be-all of who we are, what we do, and why we do
it.

            In other words, evolutionary psychology is a
reductivist fiction, good at helping <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> point out a few interesting and
as yet not-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">well</NUMEX>-understood analogies between animal and human behavior.
Teaching a bunch of unsophisticated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> that this helpful little fiction is
the gospel truth, that "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> are driven to rape because their genes tell them
to," as if we really knew why some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> rape and others don't, as if we were in
possession of the complete truth about human motivation, as if we had the
information to say authoritatively, <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">X</ENAMEX> occurs because of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Y</ENAMEX> , is at best
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">naive</ENAMEX>, at worst arrogant and irresponsible.

            
               (To reply, click
here .)
            

            
               [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judith Shulevitz</ENAMEX> is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> and writes "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Culturebox</ENAMEX>."]
            

            
                
            

            
               Subject: The
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sopranos Are Jerseyites Before</ENAMEX> Mobsters

            
               From: Gerarld
Marzorati

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>: ""

            
               Date: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tue Jan</ENAMEX>
18

            I was a little disappointed you two didn't get
beyond the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mob</ENAMEX> and move on to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Jersey</ENAMEX>, which I think is close to the heart
of what makes <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Sopranos</ENAMEX> interesting. There is something about the
place that makes it special, and not only because I grew up there. It could be
its long multi-ethnic history--it was polyglot even in colonial times. It could
be its strange and thick class co-mingling, wherein somebody in "waste
management" gets to live in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> with country-club types. Where, come <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX>,
everybody heads to the shore. (And can we get the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sopranos</ENAMEX> to the shore for an
episode or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> please?) But whatever the explanation, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Jersey</ENAMEX> is a place
where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> wear their ethnic identity (but lightly), and where the working
class has created such a strong pop culture of its own--the football <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Giants</ENAMEX>,
the all-night <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">diners</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Springsteen</ENAMEX>, the boardwalk at the shore--that even those
with money continue to cling to it, rather than embrace elite culture. (They
don't go to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Vineyard</ENAMEX>; they just get a bigger <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">shore</ENAMEX>.) So what I'm saying is that <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Sopranos</ENAMEX> is as much about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jersey</ENAMEX>
as it is about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mob</ENAMEX>, and if you don't like it--hey, who fuckin' asked you
anyway?

            
               (To reply, click
here .)
            

            [ <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerald Marzorati</ENAMEX> is
the editorial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Magazine</ENAMEX>.]

         
      
   
