
   
   
      
         
            Power, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet Money</ENAMEX>

            The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time I saw <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">AOL</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Case</ENAMEX> was at the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House Correspondents Dinner</ENAMEX>, the annual sniff-and-scratch status
party for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX> media. Case was standing on the patio sipping a drink when a mob
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> bull-rushed past him and descended on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX>. Case watched
this spectacle, expressionless. The moment crystalized the (non)relationship
between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Old Establishment Washington</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Washington</ENAMEX>: My indifference is
greater than yours.

            At <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this spring</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondents</ENAMEX> dinner, reporters
will be swarming around Case. In buying <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Warner, Case</ENAMEX> has made himself the
biggest media <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mogul</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D.C.</ENAMEX> has known. A Case deputy, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Leonsis</ENAMEX>, has become a
local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrity</ENAMEX> by purchasing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Capitals hockey</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leonsis</ENAMEX> and
his <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> self-made zillionaire business <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partners</ENAMEX> will soon own the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBA</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Wizards</ENAMEX> as well. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leonsis</ENAMEX> recruited <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Jordan</ENAMEX> to run the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wizards</ENAMEX>.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Snyder</ENAMEX>, another new money <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tyro</ENAMEX>, just bought the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s most
precious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Redskins</ENAMEX>. And <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX> has suddenly noticed
that a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">34-year-old</TIMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Saylor</ENAMEX> has made <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $2 billion</NUMEX> running a
tech <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MicroStrategy</ENAMEX>.

            These are just a handful
of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> old <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> has never noticed, who live in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> exurbs old <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> could not find on a map (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herndon</ENAMEX>? Sterling?
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Merrifield</ENAMEX>?), who work for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> old <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> cannot understand ("data
mining"?), and who have made enough money to do whatever they want (which seems
not to include socializing in or with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgetown</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elite</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyists</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> has woken up and
realized-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>-thrilled, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">horrified</NUMEX>-that it is no longer the center of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>.

            Until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year or so ago</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Old Washington</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Washington</ENAMEX>
(which isn't even <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, it's <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern Virginia</ENAMEX>) shared nothing but mutual
disregard. Tech <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> have been congregating in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern Virginia</ENAMEX> (and, to
a lesser extent, suburban <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX>) for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three decades</TIMEX>. Most were defense
contractors--quiet, bureaucratic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> that churned punch cards for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> and had no social cachet. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telecom</ENAMEX> and satellite <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MCI</ENAMEX> set
up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '70s and '80s</TIMEX>. They were mostly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> who came to the
capital to be near <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">regulators</ENAMEX>. No one noticed as they wove seamlessly into the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyist</ENAMEX> fabric. The Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> that have emerged in the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past five years</TIMEX> are different: They are run by entrepreneurs, not <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>, and
they aren't near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX> because they need the blessings of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> established <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>'s
attitudes toward the new suburban techies. It didn't notice them. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX> did not
make the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> 's front page until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> and made it only infrequently
until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reliable Source</ENAMEX>," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> 's gossip column, mentioned
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX> only once before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 1999</TIMEX> -a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> item about Case's wedding. Insofar
as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> did notice, it was usually to point out <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX>'s (very real)
business problems: a plunging stock price, irritated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>, "harsh economic
realities." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> passed on chances to invest in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993, 1994</TIMEX>,
and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leonsis</ENAMEX> told me with relish.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kara Swisher</ENAMEX>, who covered
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid-'90s</TIMEX> and wrote the definitive book about the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, aol.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX> , says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> was "anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX>" because the paper
fixated on national politics. "All they cared about was who was going to be the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Department</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Interior</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">undersecretary</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX>. Meanwhile, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">20 miles</NUMEX>
away, these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> are becoming billionaires and affecting average <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> more
than any of these political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> ever will."

            The rest of elite <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX> followed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> 's lead.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> is a salary <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>, not an equity one. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elite Washingtonians</ENAMEX> can earn a
lot-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyists</ENAMEX> clear <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 million</NUMEX> or more <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>-but don't amass huge
fortunes. "Money has never been any criterion for success in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>,
because power is the criterion," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sally Quinn</ENAMEX>, the authority on
establishment <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>'s sociology. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rich</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> who have <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> cachet, such as
former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Rubin</ENAMEX>, acquire it by virtue of their power,
not their wealth. Homegrown fortunes have never impressed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">establishment</ENAMEX>.
Real-estate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">moguls</ENAMEX>, the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> who made real money in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX> until recently,
were shut out of power <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>-except for sports <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Kent Cooke</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abe Pollin</ENAMEX>.

            Establishment <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
also overlooked the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nerd</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">millionaires</ENAMEX> because the cultural clues are all
different. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, important <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of both sexes still wear dark suits
of conservative cut. In cyberland, you can't tell a senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX> from
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">janitor</ENAMEX>, at least not by his clothing. Nor is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> charmed by the
preening quirkiness of the tech culture. "We were weird. We had <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> putting up
chandeliers in their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> or lifting weights or watching <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hospital</ENAMEX> . This was not the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX> model," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mario Morino</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founder</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legent</ENAMEX> and godfather of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> technology industry.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Virginians</ENAMEX> reciprocated <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>'s indifference. Most
of the hot new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> are outside the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Beltway</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">20 miles</NUMEX> or more from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>. The techies labor like <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> on their suburban <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campuses</ENAMEX>, live near
work, and spend what social time they have with each other. They couldn't be
less interested in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol Hill</ENAMEX>'s machinations. They buy <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boats</ENAMEX>, play the stock
market, fiddle with software and gadgets. They buy <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mansions</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Great Falls</ENAMEX> and
Reston, not <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">townhouses</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kalorama</ENAMEX>, and rarely go into the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>. "They are
Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>. They could be <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">20 miles</NUMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2,000 miles</NUMEX>," says
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Arlen</ENAMEX>, who runs a local technology-research <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>. They are here almost by
accident. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX> is in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founder</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Kimsey</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washingtonian</ENAMEX>, and
he resisted efforts to relocate the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Silicon Valley</ENAMEX>.

            Most of the tech
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> are uninterested in politics (though Case is an exception). "They
don't see a need for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>. They can't imagine being a part of it. It is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">slow-moving</ENAMEX>. There is compromise. It does not involve the purity of starting a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Regardie</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> business magazine
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regardie's Power</ENAMEX> .

            But in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last year</TIMEX>, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elites</ENAMEX> have finally realized
they need each other. Most of the rapprochement is coming from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
establishment, which now understands that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Northern Virginians</ENAMEX> have ungodly
amounts of money, energy, and even glamour. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX> is succumbing to the money and
nerd fascination that has captured the rest of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> is
pouring resources into tech coverage. Scarcely <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a day</TIMEX> passes without a
front-pager on AOL or another local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Netrepreneur</ENAMEX> made good. When <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner</ENAMEX> merged, the entire business <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> and much of the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Style</ENAMEX>" section dived
on the story. The highest-profile <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">millionaires</ENAMEX> are becoming <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrities</ENAMEX>. "The
Reliable Source" now chronicles <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leonsis</ENAMEX>' exploits as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caps</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">owner</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Case</ENAMEX>'s
party visits, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saylor</ENAMEX>'s dating habits. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> packed its millennium
party with tech <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>. Nonprofits are courting the new plutocrats in hopes of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">scoring</ENAMEX> philanthropic <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX>.

            The tech <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">millionaires</ENAMEX>,
meanwhile, have realized they can use the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">establishment</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s disastrous
neglect of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> reminded AOL not to make the same mistake. Case
repeatedly says that policy will be more important than technology in shaping
his industry, and he is striving to become a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">player</ENAMEX>. He eats dinner with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katharine Graham</ENAMEX>, socializes with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Colin Powell</ENAMEX>, and even hammed it up with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Bennett</ENAMEX> at a benefit. Case hired <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Vradenburg</ENAMEX>, a high-powered
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyist</ENAMEX>, to represent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vradenburg</ENAMEX> is showering <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> with
attention: He estimates that he has brought <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX> campus for show and tell.

            Geek money is wedging into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> society through
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sports</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leonsis</ENAMEX> has been deluged with invitations from old <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> groups
since he bought the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitals</ENAMEX>. (Invitations he does not have time to accept: "I
have a job," he says.) Power <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> is miffed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Snyder</ENAMEX> doesn't think it
is important, but <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> still crave an invitation to sit in his Redskins
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX>'s box. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kimsey</ENAMEX> is campaigning to bring a baseball <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> to the area.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sally Quinn</ENAMEX> contends that
the nerd <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tycoons</ENAMEX> can only go so far in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>. "Money is not what we do
here. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX> that's what they do. But this is the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">power capital</ENAMEX> of the
world. No matter how much money you have, power is going to be the main event.
It is not like they are going to come in and usurp that."

            But perhaps money has never gone very far in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
because <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> has never really had money. This is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX> has
hosted large, successful <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX>. All the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">establishment folks</ENAMEX> I
spoke to admitted that they were fascinated by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Case</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">confreres</ENAMEX>. Money
hasn't supplanted power but may have matched it. An ambitious young lawyer
hungry for power used to join a big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>, make <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX>, schmooze <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX>, and
die happy. But <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saylor</ENAMEX> is holding <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mixers</ENAMEX> for young <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX> associates
and picking them off to work at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MicroStrategy</ENAMEX> with high salaries and stock
options. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tech</ENAMEX> venture <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">capitalist</ENAMEX> and former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Warner</ENAMEX> says
that his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician friends</ENAMEX> have been imploring him to get their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> jobs
at hot dot-coms.

            "In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '60s and '70s</TIMEX>, young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> came to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> because they were idealists and they wanted to change the world,"
says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner</ENAMEX>. "In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '80s</TIMEX> they came because they wanted to have power and make
a good living as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyist</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>. Now they are coming because they want to
do an IPO." After all, influence is hard to measure. Equity isn't.  

         
      
   
