
   
   
      
         
            Raskolnikov the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Handyman&nbsp</ENAMEX>;

            It
turns out that the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who looks as if he walked out of the pages of
Crime <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">and Punishment</ENAMEX> , and who for some unfathomable reason possesses the
only key to our new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>, is not <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> but <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX>. Even better: He claims
that he doesn't like <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>, which makes him as good as <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX>. As he opens
the door, I ask him if, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the three years</TIMEX> he says he's lived here, he's come
to know any of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>. He finds the question
amusing. "I prefer to keep to myself," he explains. "And so do they." Clearly,
we are the last thing he needs in his life: a bunch of eager <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> trying
to shoehorn information out of him about how to invent a life in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>.

            In any
case, our new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Raskolnikov</ENAMEX>, I'll call him--is a reluctant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX>. His
long awkward silences are punctuated only by unsettling smiles and chilling
anecdotes. We ask him if he knows where the nearest market is; he responds by
asking us if we know why there is so much calcium in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parisian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>. We say
we didn't realize there was calcium in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parisian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>. He explains that it
comes from the bones of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> Napoleon dug up from the cemeteries and
reburied under the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>. We laugh. He smiles in his strange, unsettling way,
and insists he is being serious. If we want to stay in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>, we must be
prepared to drink old <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> bones.

            In
flat tones, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Raskolnikov</ENAMEX> quickly explains to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> the perils of our new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>.
The old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> next door who leaves on her gas burners, and who will <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX>, he
insists, blow us all to <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">bits</NUMEX>, is just the start of it. There is also the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">French</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">handyman</ENAMEX> who does the work on our side of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> handyman"
strikes my <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> ears as oxymoronically as "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectual</ENAMEX>" probably
strikes <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> ones. But they do exist; ours is named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">M. Gautier</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A few months</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ago M. Gautier</ENAMEX> installed new lights in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Raskolnikov</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>. Not long after he'd
finished, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Raskolnikov</ENAMEX> began to receive electrical shocks while taking his bath.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">M. Gautier</ENAMEX> had grounded the wires into the tub.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Raskolnikov now</ENAMEX> pulls his hand from his <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">pea coat</ENAMEX>. It is one giant <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">black bruise</ENAMEX>.
A heater installed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">M. Gautier</ENAMEX> had exploded <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few nights earlier</TIMEX> and fired a
bolt like a bullet across the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> and into <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Raskolnikov</ENAMEX>'s hand. "I won't let
Gautier into my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">place</ENAMEX> again," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Raskolnikov</ENAMEX>. "If I were you, I wouldn't
either. He'll kill you."

            When
<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">Raskolnikov leaves</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tabitha</ENAMEX> wrinkles her nose and says, "I don't like it when I
don't know whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are joking."

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Discomfort</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disorientation</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anomie</ENAMEX>. Whatever you call it, that is the sensation
offered to us by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these first few weeks</TIMEX>. Clearly, we don't belong here. We
prove it many times <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each day</TIMEX>. Our simplest activities somehow become pitched
battles against an entire culture. Walking the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX>, for instance. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parisian</ENAMEX>
sidewalks are obstacle courses of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog shit</ENAMEX>. To make the game of avoiding the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog shit</ENAMEX> really interesting, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">locals</ENAMEX> turn it into a competitive sport. They
come at you in packs and refuse to yield ground, even when they clearly lack
the right of way. If you want to get anywhere on foot you have to at once leap
over the dog <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shit</ENAMEX> and burst heroically through oncoming hordes of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">French</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. Red <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rover</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Red Rover</ENAMEX>, send <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henri-Antoine</ENAMEX> right over!

            Here
we have next to no ability to determine what is normal and what is noteworthy.
Take the famous storms. They struck <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three days</TIMEX> after we arrived, without
warning, at least to us. Around <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 in the morning</TIMEX>, our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> began to shake. The
windows rattled madly. When I got out of bed to have a look outside, I found a
scene from the early part of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Wizard of Oz</ENAMEX> : plastic garden chairs
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">swirling</ENAMEX> in the air, huge planting pots crashing over, medium-size <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> bent
nearly in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>. I went back to bed, assuming that it must be just a typical
Parisian <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">The next morning</TIMEX>, we awakened to find huge <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> in the
street, shattered glass on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sidewalks</ENAMEX>, and cafe <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">awnings</ENAMEX> ripped in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>. We
stepped over all of it without giving it much thought. Oh, that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> weather!
C'est fou! It was not until we found a row of old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> peering through
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bars</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Luxembourg Gardens</ENAMEX>, mourning the death of their favorite old
<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX>, that we realized something was afoot. The highest winds in recorded
history had swept through <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>, and for us it was just <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">another night</TIMEX>. Such is
the curiously disoriented mentality of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newcomer</ENAMEX>. It's childhood all over
again.

            To my
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> is a problem to be solved. She's always been one of those people
who believe firmly in reading the instructions before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">assembly</ENAMEX>. For the past
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two months</TIMEX>, she's been poring over <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> or the other of our <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> books on how to
get along with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX>, from which she passes on to me the occasional tip.
For a while, I dismissed these with an almost <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gallic</ENAMEX> aloofness. Finally, she
became so insistent that I picked up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the books. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Foe</ENAMEX> , it
was called. Sure enough, it was filled with advice: Don't smile randomly. Avoid
being likable. When a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> says "Everyone likes him," what he really
means is "He's a failure." If you must cross your legs, do it carefully, as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">woman</ENAMEX> does who is wearing a short skirt, not sloppily, like a golfer at the
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">19 th</NUMEX> hole. Never bring <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers</ENAMEX> to a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> dinner <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>. If
you do bring <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers</ENAMEX>, make sure they are not yellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers</ENAMEX>, as a yellow flower
is the signal from a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guest</ENAMEX> to a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">hostess</ENAMEX> that her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> is
cheating on her. (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Subtle</ENAMEX>!) Above all, never use the toilet when you are out to
dinner. You might think that by now every <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Frenchman</ENAMEX> understands that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foreigners</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pee</ENAMEX> when they need to and will not think them barbarians for doing so. Not so,
apparently.

            On and
on it went. The general drift of the advice was that, with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> exception, if
you wanted to get what you wanted in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, you must exchange your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">warmth</ENAMEX> and directness for a cool and aloof manner. The exception was if you
wanted to have sex. They do that here, too, apparently. A long section of the
book was devoted to the sexually charged nature of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> public life. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">author</ENAMEX> explains that you can't walk down the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> without stirring
up vital <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">juices</ENAMEX> all around you. For instance, all polite <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frenchmen</ENAMEX> give the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> they approve of what the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> calls "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Look</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> describes
The Look thusly: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Look</ENAMEX> from a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stranger</ENAMEX>, maybe passing her on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> or
in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>, of an unmistakable intensity that lets her know that for that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>,
she's got it."

            I put
down the book and tell <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tabitha</ENAMEX> about <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Look</ENAMEX>. It probably won't come naturally
to an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">male</ENAMEX>, but, in an attempt to enter into the spirit of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">French</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> life, I will cultivate a Look of my own. "I will practice The Look on old
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ladies</ENAMEX> who are happy to have any old look at all," I say, "and then, as
I get the hang of it, move gradually into the big leagues."

            This
irritates her immensely. "Out of that whole book," she says, "all you came away
with is <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Look?</ENAMEX>"

         
      
   
