
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">374</NUMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Kids Tough</ENAMEX>"

             

             

             

             

             

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnny</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luther</ENAMEX>
Htoo, the chain-smoking <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">twins</ENAMEX> who lead the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> fundamentalist
rebel <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> God's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX>, made a horrible mistake <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>. How so?
            

             

            Send
your answer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.

             

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s Question
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 373</ENAMEX>)-"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Courtier":</ENAMEX>
            

            

               On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> ruled in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Shrink Missouri</ENAMEX>
Government <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">PAC</ENAMEX> . Fill in the blank as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Paul Stevens</ENAMEX> sums up the
majority opinion: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Money</ENAMEX> is property; it is not ___________."
               

               
            

            "An
animal!"- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jill Pope</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Davis</ENAMEX>
            

            
"Eligible to vote except by proxy."- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Anne Townsend</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael J.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Basial</ENAMEX> had a similar answer.)

            "For
everyone, that's why they're called 'have-nots.' "- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julie Anderson</ENAMEX>
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Snowing</ENAMEX>, is it? It is? Good lord! We'd better ditch work
immediately!"- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Radosh</ENAMEX>
            

            "The
contents of an overnight bag tossed on a bed which you roll in screaming, 'I'm
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rich</ENAMEX>! I'm rich! Now no one's gonna step on me no more! And that goes for all
you chicken-shit mugs with your <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Aqua Velva</ENAMEX> shaves and your <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Grecian Formula</ENAMEX>
comb-overs.' "- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marshall Efron</ENAMEX>
            

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
            

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yahoo</ENAMEX> search for
"money" turns up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">31</NUMEX> categories and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,750</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX>, confirming the notion that we
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> want a lot of information about it, and not just from pouty blond
financial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNNfn</ENAMEX>. Of course, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yahoo</ENAMEX> search for "sex" yields <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">46</NUMEX>
categories and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3,145</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX>, most of which expect you to hand over the money you
made applying what you learned from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">your first</TIMEX> search. (And I, for one, am
proud to live in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">46</NUMEX> categories of sex, most of which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orrin Hatch</ENAMEX>
objects to, but he's history, so the hell with him.) Euphoric with thoughts of
money and sex and the crushing defeat of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orrin Hatch</ENAMEX>, I'm sobered to learn that
these totals are surpassed by a search for "<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX>"-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">83</NUMEX> categories, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3,432</NUMEX>
sites-which I presume means that a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are spending a lot of money on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX>, and they expect something more than a handshake and the meowed suggestion
that "It's been such a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">lovely evening</TIMEX>; let's not spoil it." Perhaps the ASPCA
isn't screening quite as thoroughly as it should. You know, like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DNC</ENAMEX>. And
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RNC</ENAMEX>. And that intolerant loser, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orrin Hatch</ENAMEX>.

            
               Money Talks Slightly
Quieter Answer
            

            Money is property; it is not speech .

            Although it did not
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">overturn Buckley</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Valeo</ENAMEX> , the notorious <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1976</TIMEX> case that defined
political expenditures as speech, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> determined that political
contributions were not speech. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Antonin Scalia</ENAMEX> cast his <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> votes (his own and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarence Thomas</ENAMEX>') with dissenting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony Kennedy</ENAMEX>, who argued that the
decision might limit the influence of the very rich, or so I understand it.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Gerber</ENAMEX>'s
Cartographic Quibble
            

            I grew up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Louis</ENAMEX>, so I must say: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shame</ENAMEX>!
Shame! Shame! Geography aside, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Louis</ENAMEX> is part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East</ENAMEX>: It's more like
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX> than <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kansas City</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Midwest</ENAMEX>-which doesn't suck as much as,
say, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Queens</ENAMEX>-starts at the western edge of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Louis</ENAMEX>. I've lived on both sides
of the divide, so I know. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brrr</ENAMEX>. (I cannot defend <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nashville</ENAMEX>.)

            [ I believe I've seen
that on your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourist</ENAMEX> brochures: "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Louis</ENAMEX>: We're a lot like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX>!" and
so I stand corrected.-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed</ENAMEX>. ]

             
               More and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moira</ENAMEX>
Extra
            

            "My name is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moira Forbes</ENAMEX>. I am a junior at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Princeton University</ENAMEX>, and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX>, is running for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>, and I am an
alcoholic." So begins a "letter from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moira</ENAMEX>" touting Youth for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX>, except
for the part about her being an alcoholic. While it makes my head go all funny
trying to imagine a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> enthusiastic about the pudgy wealth-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inheritor</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moira</ENAMEX> says there are many reasons <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> should dig her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daddy</ENAMEX> the most, and now
that she's not drinking, perhaps we should pay attention to what she says.
Which of the following are among <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moira Forbes</ENAMEX>' reasons for youth to support her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>?

            

               

                  To show that young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> do, indeed, care about
the future of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>.

               

               

                  Just to piss off G.W.

               

               

                  We've been called lazy, apathetic, selfish, and
worse. I know better than that.

               

               

                  To find out just what worse things we've been
called. And by whom. And then go over to his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and kick the crap out of
him.

               

               

                  (To say) "yes" to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> who will protect our
fiscal future while cleaning up the moral mess of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.

               

               

                  To join in the moral mess of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.

               

               

                  Take it from me, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX>: Chicks dig <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> who say
"fiscal."

               

               

                  To make a real difference.

               

               

                  Free "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forbes Rules</ENAMEX>" bong to all registered
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>.

               

               

                  Another of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>'s embarrassing failures might cause
me to slip back into the alcoholic fog that marred my childhood, had any such
fog actually existed, which it did not.

               

            

            
               Answers
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1, 3, 5</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> are genuine.

            Read the rest of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moira</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX>' hip, hot, and happening letter to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX> here.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew Singer</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amtrak</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slogan Ongoing Extra</ENAMEX>
            

            He's still soliciting new safety slogans so he can
stuff the ballot box of a contest being run by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">MARC</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore-Washington</ENAMEX>
commuter line he rides to work. Already taken: "Cleaning up the moral mess of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reponses</ENAMEX> to run
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>.

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            Can't-or perhaps can-buy
me love.  

         
      
   
