
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">370</NUMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hot Spot</ENAMEX>"

             

             

            

               Using a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">helicopter</ENAMEX> equipped with a heat-seeking device, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Suffolk County</ENAMEX>
cops located <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">two cinderblock</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">warehouses</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Holbrook</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Long Island</ENAMEX>, and arrested
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> for theft of electricity. What was going on in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">warehouses</ENAMEX>?

            

             

            Send
your answer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s Question
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 369</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Pig 'n' Pearl</ENAMEX>":
            

            

               "At <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX>, they called it 'throwing the pearls to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">swine</ENAMEX>,' " says
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Kling</ENAMEX>. What's it called off-campus? 
            

             

            
"Dating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>."- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis Heaney</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan E.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Snow</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Colleen Werthmann</ENAMEX> had similar answers.)

            
"Speaking without an honorarium."- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Carvell</ENAMEX>
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Teaching</ENAMEX>. And what's so hurtful is not that they say that but that
they make those nasty little <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pig</ENAMEX> faces when they say it."- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jay D.</ENAMEX>
Majors 
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Freshman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Natalie Portman</ENAMEX> attending her first frat-house kegger."- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sullivan</ENAMEX>
            

            
"There's an off-campus? Do <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> live there? What do they do <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all day</TIMEX>?"- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dale</ENAMEX>
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Enmeshed in Harvard Final Exam Week</ENAMEX>" Shuger
            

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
            

             

            If you ran a Nexis
search or, like me, made up some data, you'd find that the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> nongovernmental
organizations most assiduously covered by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> are the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vatican</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX>. But while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> swoons before these cradles of
power, the general <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>-by which I mean my deadbeat <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>-disdains them
both, and it's not entirely jealousy. For <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> thing, within <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five minutes</TIMEX> of
meeting one of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> they inevitably let you know: I attended the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">College</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cardinals</ENAMEX>. Or the constant name-dropping: my old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">roommate</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Stinky</ENAMEX>, is the
papal nuncio. Or the vanity disguised as humility: Does this vestment make me
look fat? Or the way, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30 years later</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">40 years later</TIMEX>, some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> is still talking
about where he was an altar <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>. We hate that sort of thing around the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Penn</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Club</ENAMEX>. Puts us right off our scrapple.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Medically Necessary</ENAMEX>, or
So <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">My Accountant Tells Me</ENAMEX>, Answer
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liposuction</ENAMEX>.

            And eye jobs, tummy
tucks, tooth whitening, wrinkle removal, and other cosmetic procedures. These
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vanity</ENAMEX> treatments, once scorned around the med <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>, are now enjoying
increased respect because there's money in them. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Doctors</ENAMEX> weary of the
income-limiting effects of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMOs</ENAMEX> find it more lucrative to deliver unnecessary
medicine to rich <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> who pay for it themselves. "Now, in terms of survival,
it is what you do," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kling</ENAMEX>, who has a dermatology and cosmetic surgery
practice on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Park Avenue</ENAMEX>. "And of course by 'survival' I mean able to afford a
solid <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX> hat like the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> on my pet <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">monkey</ENAMEX>, over there in the Jacuzzi filled
with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">champagne</ENAMEX>," he did not add.

            
               Garden Statements
Extra
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 18</TIMEX>, was
the last day <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christine Todd Whitman</ENAMEX> could act on bills passed
during the legislative session that just ended. Which of the following did she
sign, and which did she veto?

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bills</ENAMEX>
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Police</ENAMEX> may stop <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX> for not wearing a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">seatbelt</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>.   "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Driving</ENAMEX> while black" reduced from felony to
misdemeanor.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Minors</ENAMEX> may be fined <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25</NUMEX> for purchase or
possession of cigarettes.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judges</ENAMEX> may require ignition locks on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> of
convicted drunk <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Springsteen</ENAMEX> named state <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>.   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Three-year</TIMEX> statute of limitations on parking
tickets.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>.   "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Rich Get Richer and the Poor Get Camden</ENAMEX>"
named state song.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>.   Underage drinking on private property
prohibited.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Cherry Hill Mall</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> tree because
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Springsteen</ENAMEX> is so damned sensitive.

            10.  "I'm Black and I'm
Proud, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Don't Shoot</ENAMEX>!" named new state motto.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitman Action</ENAMEX>
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>.   Signed.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>.   Not an actual bill.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pocket</ENAMEX> vetoed.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>.   Signed.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>.   Not an actual <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>.   Signed.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Camden</ENAMEX> too poor <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">to sing</ENAMEX>, can only
afford to hum.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>.   Vetoed.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>.   Ignored on flimsy grounds that no such bill
exists.

            10.  Ignored; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Police</ENAMEX> so damned sensitive about nonexistent bills.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Quote of the Day</ENAMEX>
for <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Days We Feel Like Having a Quote Extra</ENAMEX>
            

            "You don't see fancy
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">high-society types</ENAMEX> at a camel fight; look-it's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald Trump</ENAMEX>!"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">- Omer Demir</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX> fight <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> (as quoted in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> , except for the part
about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald Trump</ENAMEX>)
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cold Comfort</ENAMEX>
Ongoing Extra
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> are still
invited to devise a photo caption cliché of the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Winter Turns Cold; People Don</ENAMEX>
Hats, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Gloves</ENAMEX>" variety that should run in any news outlet. Results to run
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX> if my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">eyelids</ENAMEX> don't become frost-encrusted as I bundle up against
blustery <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Arctic</ENAMEX> winds and walk in front of a bus stalled by frigid air, then
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">stagger</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pavement</ENAMEX>, trip over a frozen <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX>, and break my spine.

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            Faculty disdain for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>; student disdain for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> at other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>. 

         
      
   
