
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angela</ENAMEX>'s Arses

            
               Movies
            

            

               
                  A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Map of the World</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First Look Pictures Releasing</ENAMEX>). Mixed reviews
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sigourney Weaver</ENAMEX>'s turn as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> stretched to the limit after a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> in
her care accidentally drowns. Some blast the film because it uses a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>'s
death "as merely the first manipulation of many meant to engender sympathy for
its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroine</ENAMEX>" and call it "fraudulent in every detail" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Morgenstern</ENAMEX>, the
Wall Street <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> ). Others deny these charges, saying the movie has
"an emotional depth and psychological acuity that place it in a category by
itself" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Holden</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ). Most concur in their
estimation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weaver</ENAMEX>'s work: "emotionally direct … lovely, warm" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Lisa</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schwarzbaum, Entertainment Weekly</ENAMEX> ). (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> 
here to read a review of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane Hamilton</ENAMEX> novel that was the basis of the
film.)

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angela</ENAMEX>'s Ashes
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paramount Pictures</ENAMEX>). The film's not bad, but it's
nowhere near the caliber of the beloved <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank McCourt</ENAMEX> memoir on which it is
based. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emily Watson</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Carlyle</ENAMEX> play <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Parker</ENAMEX>
( The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commitments</ENAMEX> ) directs. While the adaptation is respectful, it
"mostly misses the humor, lyricism and emotional charge of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank McCourt</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">magical</ENAMEX> and magnificent memoir" and unfortunately becomes "something resembling
a conventional tale of a gifted young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s struggle to lift himself out of
oppressive circumstances" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Todd McCarthy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Variety</ENAMEX> ). The harshest
complaint: It's just "<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two hours and 20 minutes</TIMEX> of beautifully photographed
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rain</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mud</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX>, lice, vomit, dead <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX>, and whining" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Owen Gleiberman</ENAMEX>,
Entertainment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly</ENAMEX> ). The more upbeat take: The movie is "a thinner
version of the novel, but you still get a drama that has you laughing and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">brokenhearted</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Desson Howe</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> ). (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to read an excerpt
from the book.)

            

               
                  Down to You
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miramax Films</ENAMEX>). Negative notices from all concerned
for this cutesy college romance. The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">leads</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Freddie Prinze Jr.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julia</ENAMEX>
Stiles, are "scrubbed, wholesome and bland," while the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer-director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kris</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isacsson</ENAMEX> "flees from anything that might involve real human emotion, or for
that matter any credible human activity other than looking good" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A.O. Scott</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ). "You keep waiting for a twist, a difficulty, a
dilemma, a single cleverness," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Hunter</ENAMEX> writes in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> . "Wait in vain, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX>." (The official
site includes a list of helpful dating tips, such as "Don't be afraid to
eat in front of your date.")

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Play It to the Bone</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buena Vista Pictures</ENAMEX>). This <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX>-cum-boxing
movie starring <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woody Harrelson</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Antonio Banderas</ENAMEX> is both trite and strange:
On <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> hand it "knocks the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rocky</ENAMEX> tradition on its ear by giving us two
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">boxers</ENAMEX> to root for in the same match" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Morgenstern</ENAMEX>, the Wall Street
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> ), but despite this departure from convention, it manages to include
"an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">assembly</ENAMEX> of ancient and familiar prizefight clichés" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Ebert</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Sun-Times</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Shelton</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bull Durham</ENAMEX> ) is a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veteran</ENAMEX> of successful sports movies, but this one lacks the "off-the-wall
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">larkiness</ENAMEX>" of his previous efforts (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jay Carr</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Globe</ENAMEX> ). The
film culminates in a gruesome fight between the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> that leaves several
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> bemoaning the confusion over whom to root for; others contend that the
scene's emotional conflict works in its favor. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to watch the trailer.)

            
               Book
            

            

               
                  Girl With a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pearl Earring</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tracy Chevalier</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dutton</ENAMEX>). This
"vibrant, sumptuous novel" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kate Flatley</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> ) is
dripping with slaver by the time <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX> finish with it. Set in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17 th -century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Delft</ENAMEX>, the "outstanding" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Denise Kersten</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> ) novel traces the singular life of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> working as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">servant</ENAMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">painter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jan Vermeer</ENAMEX>. The precocious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-ager</ENAMEX> ends up sitting for the
famous portrait that shares its title with the book. Something of an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">entanglement</ENAMEX> develops between the intelligent, artistically aware young girl
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">painter</ENAMEX>, but the book is in no way a conventional romance; it's "a
brainy novel whose passion is ideas" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Eder</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ).
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here
to look at the titular painting.)

            
               Television
            

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malcolm</ENAMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Middle</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:30 p.m.</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> pour the love on thick: "Fresh
as a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Twinkie</ENAMEX> right off the assembly line, more welcome than a power failure
during the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Union</ENAMEX> speech, fitfully 'Seinfeldian' in its pure,
crazed <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hilarity …</ENAMEX> [it] could very well be the best new sitcom of the season"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Shales</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> ). No laugh track, cinematic
single-camera shooting, and an appealingly daffy family all add up to a
fresh-feeling show. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newcomer Freddie Muniz</ENAMEX> plays <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malcolm</ENAMEX>, a gifted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9-year-old</TIMEX>,
and is "that rare thing, an uncloying <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child actor</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caryn James</ENAMEX>, the New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times</ENAMEX> ). Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> compare the show to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX>'s best-known <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">half-hour</TIMEX>
comedy, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Simpsons</ENAMEX> , saying it shares the same sense of the absurd
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> shaves <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s back at the breakfast table, etc.) with an
"undercurrent of love and gentle support" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ramin Zahed</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Variety</ENAMEX> ). (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX>
here to
find out more about the show at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX>'s official site.)

         
      
   
