
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft Kremlinology&nbsp</ENAMEX>;

            During
the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> entertained themselves with a parlor game called
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kremlinology</ENAMEX>. Every time a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> premier was ousted or a new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> joined the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Politburo</ENAMEX>, Western <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> spun fresh theories about who was up, who was down,
why the chairs were being rearranged, and what those wily old <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX> were up
to. The triumph of capitalism spoiled the old game but replaced it with a new
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>: corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kremlinology</ENAMEX>.

            The
most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kremlin</ENAMEX>-like of corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX>, in the eyes of many conspiracy
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">theorists</ENAMEX>, lies in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Redmond</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wash.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX>'s announcement by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX> that he is turning over his job to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">deputy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Ballmer</ENAMEX>-and
assuming the new post of "chief software <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX>" instead-has set
Kremlinologists abuzz. Here's how <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> is spinning the handover and how
cynics are reinterpreting those spins.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> is meeting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s challenge. At a press conference <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ballmer</ENAMEX> denied that the handover was prompted by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">America Online</ENAMEX>'s
merger with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Warner</ENAMEX>. Instead, they linked <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ballmer</ENAMEX>'s promotion to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s new strategy of focusing on "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Next Generation Windows Services</ENAMEX>,"
which are supposed to become the platform for all devices that communicate
through the Internet. "We have Bill now focused <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">100 percent</NUMEX> as chief <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX>
of this transformation," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ballmer</ENAMEX>.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cynics</ENAMEX>' translation: He's acknowledging <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s mess .
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Skeptics</ENAMEX> don't care whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> planned the handover before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX> merger.
They interpret the "next generation" strategy, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX>' assignment to it, and his
adversarial references to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX> as a belated concession that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX> was right about
the primacy of the Internet, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> was wrong about the primacy of the PC,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> now has to play catch-up. And why is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> going back to
supervising software development? Cynics figure that if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Capt.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kirk</ENAMEX> takes over
the engineering <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">room</ENAMEX>, it means <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scotty</ENAMEX> has botched his job.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> is doing what he does best. On the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> show, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> said
software architecture is "a job that draws on my strengths more." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff Raikes</ENAMEX> agreed that the new job puts <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> "in his element."
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s overall message is that the "next generation" project will
determine the industry's future and that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX> who can pull it
off.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cynics</ENAMEX>' translation: He's sinking back to his level of
competence . If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> is better at what he'll be doing next, then he
must have been worse at what he was doing before. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> link this point to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Principle</ENAMEX>, which holds that everyone rises to his level of
incompetence. They suggest that being <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX>' level of incompetence and
that he's going "back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">garage</ENAMEX>," where he belongs. They attribute all
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s missteps to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX>-bad <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PR</ENAMEX>, bad legal strategy, underestimation of
the Internet-and infer that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> must have been bad at everything <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ballmer</ENAMEX> is
good at: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>, finding new revenue <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>, and avoiding bad
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">investments</ENAMEX>.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> is psyched up. "I'm returning to what I love most-focusing on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">technologies</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX>'s promotion will allow me to
dedicate myself full time to my passion-building great software and
strategizing on the future." On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> said his new job would be
"more fun."

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cynics</ENAMEX>' translation: He's burned out . Again, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> invert
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s spin: If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> needs a new job in order to have fun, he must hate
his current job. Some say he lost interest because he made too much money and
has nothing left to prove. Others say the antitrust siege, the attendant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PR</ENAMEX>
damage, and constant media scrutiny have worn him out. A few offer the ultimate
macho corporate insult, speculating that he wants "more time to concentrate on
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>." But the condescension of these ill-wishers is trumped by the
contempt of those who say <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> is too coldblooded to put his family <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> is getting a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">puppy dog</ENAMEX>. The media always look for contrasts. Since
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> is a nerd, they've cast <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ballmer</ENAMEX> as a frat <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>. While <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> and Ballmer
stress their similarities, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">optimists</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ballmer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> spin the
nerd-frat boy dichotomy as a good thing: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Whereas Gates</ENAMEX> understands gadgets,
they suggest, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ballmer</ENAMEX> understands <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. He's "outgoing," "affable,"
"tactile," and "back-slapping." He's a "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">salesman</ENAMEX>" who can help <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> by
focusing on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>. He's a deal-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">maker</ENAMEX> who can break the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX>
Department <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">negotiators</ENAMEX> and settle the antitrust case. He's the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">puppy</ENAMEX> who can go
for a walk with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wag</ENAMEX> his tail, win over <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strangers</ENAMEX>, and help <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX>
make <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cynics</ENAMEX>' translation: He's getting an attack <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> . Sure, say the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ballmer</ENAMEX> is tactile and outgoing-like a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pit bull</ENAMEX>. They call him
"ruthless," "bombastic," "in-your-face," an "aggressive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hardliner</ENAMEX>," a
"bulldog," and a "hit <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ballmer</ENAMEX> played into this critique in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>'s
press conference, calling the notion of breaking up <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> "reckless and
irresponsible" and dismissing speculation about such a plan as "ludicrous."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Reporters</ENAMEX> deemed his tone "strident" and belligerent. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> isn't unleashing
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ballmer</ENAMEX> to make <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cynics</ENAMEX> argue. He's unleashing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ballmer</ENAMEX> to fight and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">intimidate Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX>.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> is taking a bullet for his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>. Despite <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX>' and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ballmer</ENAMEX>'s
insistence that the handover has nothing to do with the antitrust case, dozens
of market <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX>, legal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> suspect that it must. They
think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> is "stepping down"-contrary to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ballmer</ENAMEX>'s insistence that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> is
"stepping up" to his new job-in hopes of "appeasing" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">warriors</ENAMEX> who want <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>. Pro-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> spin this as a heroic
sacrifice, removing the "lightning rod" whose "seemingly disingenuous
testimony" has ostensibly driven the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOJ</ENAMEX> to the verge of demanding the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s breakup. Many attributed a rise in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s stock to optimism
that a freshly sated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOJ</ENAMEX> will back off the alleged breakup plan.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cynics</ENAMEX>' translation: He's playing dead . Anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX>
spin the same theory the other way: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX>, having been pulled over by the cops
for aggressive driving, is sliding into the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passenger</ENAMEX> seat" and giving the
wheel to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ballmer</ENAMEX>, whose record is clean, so that the cops will go easy on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ballmer</ENAMEX> is just a "student <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX>," and as soon as the cops leave,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> will retake the wheel. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> is just "putting a new face on the
company"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-a</ENAMEX> "kinder, gentler look"-to cleanse <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s corporate image and
soften up the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOJ</ENAMEX>.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>.
He's calling all hands on deck. At the press conference, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ballmer</ENAMEX> outlined
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s challenges and listed several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s "leadership
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">team</ENAMEX>" who would work with "chief <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> to "integrate" the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s
products and services. Having lost top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent months</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ballmer</ENAMEX> sought to convey that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> has divisional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> who can work
together to beat <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">rivals</ENAMEX>.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cynics</ENAMEX>' translation: He's manning the lifeboats . Conspiracy
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">theorists</ENAMEX> think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> is organizing his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commanders</ENAMEX> not to save the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ship</ENAMEX> but to
abandon it to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. "They are putting their affairs in order," said
tech <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guru</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff Eisenach</ENAMEX>. "If we are going to see the death of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> as we
know it and the creation of something new, then they would want to prepare
their most capable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> types of positions." The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>

               Times speculates that "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> would run the Windows operating system and
a new Internet operating system. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ballmer</ENAMEX> would take control of the applications
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">division</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Tribune</ENAMEX> agrees that with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ballmer</ENAMEX> at
their new posts, if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOJ</ENAMEX> breaks up <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>, "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baby Bill CEOs</ENAMEX>
will be in place."

            
Ballmer dismisses such talk as nonsense. But when a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> spends <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two decades</TIMEX>
impressing everyone with its ruthless practicality and wily resilience, it
can't easily brush off rumors of plots. "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> still can't escape the feeling
that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> knows something is coming and is positioning itself," said a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNNfn</ENAMEX> correspondent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> of the handover, alluding to a hypothetical
court-ordered breakup. "It thinks smartly, and this change is going to position
it for whatever comes down the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX>." On this, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> haters and worshippers
agree: The only thing of which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX> is incapable is coincidence. 

         
      
   
