
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		so how serious is the subject of crime in your area
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well needless to say here in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX>  this is the war zone
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh DC</ENAMEX> around here stands for drug <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX> or death capital
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		it's uh it's really bad here uh for example  the uh local high school uh they've already found <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> with sawed off shotguns
 	
 	
 		jeez
 	
 	
 		and they're starting to uh get these hand held metal detectors so they can inspect the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">every morning</TIMEX> when they come to school of all things
 		so it
 	
 	
 		well luckily it hasn't gotten that bad here uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Jose</ENAMEX> actually has a pretty good record in terms of being relatively low on violent crime
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh but it's on the uprise especially in a lot of the uh outlying agricultural <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> because you end up having a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gangs</ENAMEX> forming uh largely around the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic</ENAMEX> core
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh it seems to be that uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gang</ENAMEX> warfare follows very rapidly on the heels of  poverty conditions
 	
 	
 		uh-huh right that's how they uh they bind themselves together in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> i guess and uh  now the interestingly enough i don't think we have here a a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gangs</ENAMEX> but uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		only a couple uh of not a whole large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of them but uh just a few most of them centered around uh drug territory
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so they're protecting their  economic interests i guess and uh now nowadays the latest thing i've i've read about in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> here that they're doing as far as
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh crimes involving stealing <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> is that instead of stealing uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> like at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> breaking into them or whatever they will pick out a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> that they want and wait until you show up
 		and then as you get out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> they just uh step up and uh take the keys off of you and drive the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> away  and leave you standing in front of your house
 	
 	
 		oh well that's efficient
 	
 	
 		yeah that's the uh latest thing that way there's no damage to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> or anything they just wait for you to show up after they've picked out which one they want
 	
 	
 		they're decided they're completely unworried about being identified or anything of that sort
 	
 	
 		uh-huh right  just wait for you to drive to your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> you get out and they get in off they go with your car
 	
 	
 		
 
 		wow
 	
 	
 		so it's uh i think they call it car jacking around here
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah i'd heard that phrase
 	
 	
 		uh-huh yeah that's kind of the latest thing but  oh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX> area it gets progressively worse as far as the number of homicides so it's
 		uh it's unfortunate that we feel sometimes even that we have to bring our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> up in this area because we're not from around here we're from uh i'm from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and we've just come from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years</TIMEX> in the military and uh which is an entirely different environment so this is a whole new thing for  for us to to have to put up with and it's uh really scary sometimes
 	
 	
 		yeah there aren't that many places that are safe from that sort of thing nowadays
 	
 	
 		
 
 		right and it's pretty bad when they're using <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">metal</ENAMEX> detectors in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and uh of course the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> uh of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX> is having a real problem uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		trying to what do you do to to reduce crime in a in a major <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX> where it's a way of life for everybody it's uh
 		i would hate to have to wrestle with that problem i don't know what what the solution is uh there's no way they can stop the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> and that's what's causing all the killing
 	
 	
 		well uh  there's a couple of things that i've heard uh most of them are fairly uh radical in terms of what you'd have to do uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		course the  the reason that that these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> tend to to turn toward the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> and everything else seems seems to be just you know the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the the</TIMEX>
 		end results of of poverty and and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> that aren't doing any parenting and everything else because i mean you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> aren't making a living at anything
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right and they see all their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> uh
 	
 	
 		uh
 		and they're accidental <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> half the time anyway
 	
 	
 		yeah and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> are driving <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mercedes</ENAMEX> and so it's actually they grow up with that as their way of life and uh i think uh to a large extent they don't understand the concept that what they're doing is actually illegal because
 		this is the way they were raised
 	
 	
 		it's illegal but it's not wrong because all their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> do it
 	
 	
 		right  exactly so maybe it's the law that wrong in their eyes and they they say well it's
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it's the law that's uh got to be changed instead of their way of life so i don't know it's
 		i'm glad it's not the kind of problem i have to   come up with an answer to because it's not easy
 	
 	
 		well i think that the drug thing would actually be relatively easy to solve in terms of of an actual solution to the problem um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the the social the other social problems wouldn't wouldn't go away
 	
 	
 		right they've always been with us
 	
 	
 		uh
 		i mean there's there's been a lot of
 		and i used to think that this whole argument was completely bogus but then the more i thought about it the more sense it made is that uh <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> is as bad a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> as anything else
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and prohibition didn't stop it and didn't do anything really to slow
 	
 	
 		right
 		
 		
 	