
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay so what kind of luck you been having with buying and returning gifts products
 	
 	
 		uh not too bad really um i had a razor that i got for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> that i just i really didn't want it but i got it anyway and uh
 		it was a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Braun</ENAMEX> and they were real good about taking it back it wasn't a problem at all so uh i was able to get that back pretty easily
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh i don't know i really haven't returned a whole lot lately have you
 	
 	
 		i haven't had to it's uh the every so often i mean i i i'm almost pushing it myself maybe i'll buy a shirt from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">GI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX>'s and it shrinks too much and say well i should have known better i mean i bought it from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">GI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX>'s and it was probably made in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> by slaves
 	
 	
 		um  right
 	
 	
 		but uh  they uh most of the time  pretty careful shopping anyway i get pretty good stuff i think that uh aside from the fact all markets being internationalized and if you want to buy <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> it takes real extra work to find
 	
 	
 		
  
 		yeah
 		right like
 		exactly i was reading
 	
 	
 		and it's probably a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> or a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burmese company</ENAMEX> owning and hiring <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right i was reading something in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Consumer Reports</ENAMEX> tonight about that as a matter of fact they were talking about <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> issue just came out and about how yeah you'd like to buy an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> car maybe but uh you know the transmission may be made in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> or whatever
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um like i've got an <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford Ranger</ENAMEX> and and i know for a fact that the transmission is made by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mitsubishi</ENAMEX> you know so it's like what are you going to do you know
 	
 	
 		huh
 		yeah really
 	
 	
 		but uh that's the way it is i don't know i i personally feel that uh
 		uh if the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> are better and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> buy them you know that's the way it goes and you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> manufacturers <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> should get a clue and you know they should start making quality products and
 	
 	
 		yeah i think they're beginning to the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the days</TIMEX> of don't buy a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> made on a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> or a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> are pretty much going away and
 	
 	
 		that's what i thought too until i saw the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Consumer Reports</ENAMEX> issue uh they've got all the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> well all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> rated you know and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		essentially i haven't i don't see much of a trend i mean just like every other time that you look at it the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Honda Accords</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Civics</ENAMEX> are right up there there's nothing wrong with them
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and the same thing with most of the other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> but then again you look at a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX> or especially a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chevy</ENAMEX> and they're pieces of junk you know
 	
 	
 		oh know still at it hey
 	
 	
 		yeah that's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ninety</NUMEX> that's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty six</NUMEX> through <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ninety one</NUMEX> but uh i don't know maybe maybe they're getting better maybe they're starting to get a clue uh
 	
 	
 		wow
 		well they got a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three year</TIMEX> lead time it probably won't start really showing up until <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ninety four or so</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah that's just it technology that that comes in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">right now</TIMEX> is is probably not going to be implemented implemented until you know quite <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years</TIMEX> down the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> but uh
 	
 	
 		hm
 		the computer industry's where it's really dynamic especially for the consumer
 	
 	
 		oh yeah because technology is so uh you know volatile and changing all the time uh
 	
 	
 		and can you think of any other industry where in software they uh if the product is upgraded and a better version is put out you'll get a free version in the mail it's like here
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		or uh maybe they say well you we know you paid <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five hundred</NUMEX> bucks for this program so send us <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty</TIMEX> and we'll give you a really great upgrade
 	
 	
 		
  
 		yeah it uh they they keep up good with it pretty quickly and that's that's a real good thing i guess
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um i don't know
 	
 	
 		and the hardware well i mean all the chips that make up the hardware are a commodity and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Macintosh</ENAMEX> is about the only one that's going it's right forcing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX> and the rest of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOS</ENAMEX> world to follow along
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right they're kind of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> right now you know i used to see all those commercials for Windows you know and you're like oh gee they're reselling a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Macintosh</ENAMEX> under a different name
 	
 	
 		
 
 		really why don't they just say almost a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mac</ENAMEX> for half the price they could sell more if they were honest
 	
 	
 		yeah you know almost
 		exactly almost is the key word there too you know because i i really i've used both and i really don't see an advantage of Windows at all uh
 	
 	
 		yeah it it's only an advantage for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who had to use pure DOS
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah that's just it
 	
 	
 		i mean that's their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX> base
 	
 	
 		but uh i don't know i'm really i've gotten a little bit out of the the personal computer business just because i don't have one at home i i do use a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mac</ENAMEX> at work but uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh i really don't don't do much with it at home but uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple</ENAMEX>'s sort of making a  and they're ones were growling consumer
 		uh need to worry about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mac</ENAMEX> they're getting like if you bought a power book straight off a lot of them had to go back they issued a recall because of improper shielding or possibly other problems with the floppy drive
 	
 	
 		right uh-huh yeah you sound like you must uh work in the computer business
 	
 	
 		yeah i have one i do desktop publishing at work and i have a machine at home and i belong to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> and i i've been a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mac</ENAMEX> fanatic since they came out
 	
 	
 		yeah all right
 	
 	
 		but uh technically i'm not actually in the industry i don't work for a computer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> i'm an abuser
 	
 	
 		no
 		well that's that's all right
 	
 	
 		but it's sort of like surfing on the wave of future shock to you know keep up with the changes as they happen
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true
 		something that i find uncomfortable is you know you you want to buy something say you want to buy a personal computer
 		and you got to think about what kind of memory you want to get and what kind of technology that you want to go for you know let let's take the example of a modem for you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		okay what what what baud rate do you get well you know it used to be that you get a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">twelve hundred</NUMEX> baud
 		
 		
 	