
 
     		
 	
 		right uh actually i
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		lived over in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of years</TIMEX> i lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> and in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> they don't have the jury system what they do is they have uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> basically
 		and you get up there and the prosecuting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> presents his evidence and your defense <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> presents their evidence and those <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> take the evidence go off figure it out and then come back and say whether you're guilty or not
 	
 	
 		our our our judicial system is in such total chaos
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i think what they need to do is they need to somehow
 		take
 		the money out of it i mean when you have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> that's signed a
 		a a statement saying he's guilty we have a a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> called <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all day</TIMEX> family they were all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">murderers</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> signed confessions they went to a trial by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> they been trying these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> now for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty two years</TIMEX> ever since i was a child
 	
 	
 		wow
 	
 	
 		and what they've done is they've bought <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mercedes</ENAMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mercedes</ENAMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mercedes</ENAMEX> is what they've done has nothing to do with justice whatsoever
 	
 	
 		well you know it's it's one of those things i mean uh uh i would have to look at that if they did it with the uh
 		just the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> have to do a lot better job of making sure that their evidence is airtight
 		because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> sitting in that kind of stuff day after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX> they know all the procedures they know what's good and what isn't they'd be able to say i'm sorry you can't
 		use this as uh evidence you know because it was either illegally obtained or whatever and you know you wouldn't have this uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> theatrics where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> jumps up and presents it to the to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> and then the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> says oh no disregard disregard that come on any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX>'s not going to disregard the evidence you know
 	
 	
 		uh that's true i i i think our judicial system is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> welfare myself
 	
 	
 		that may very well be
 	
 	
 		i i hold it in the utmost contempt the uh
 	
 	
 		uh that's a
 	
 	
 		the the my favorite is
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">police department</ENAMEX>  they're not aimed at the criminal the judicial system is aimed at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> because you and i
 		we have work schedules we can be called at work we have <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> numbers they can trace us down we have telephones and we have checkbooks <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> have none of these things they're real difficult to catch and if they do catch them
 		they don't get any monetary gain out of it whereas us we write a check
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so where do you think they target their efforts
 	
 	
 		that's true you do have a
 	
 	
 		they target their efforts toward the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> not the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well how would you go about changing it
 	
 	
 		you know that's a i've nailed the problem down but i
 	
 	
 		leave the details up to somebody else huh
 	
 	
 		yeah i'm going to have to leave those details like what would you do about i think to begin with
 		you would have you would have like here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX> area our crime rate is just astronomical yet you go out on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> and they're giving speeding tickets
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i think somehow you have to separate the revenues from
 	
 	
 		well you know uh talking about the lawyers
 		you know what might very well do uh cause a uh a drop in the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> and things like that is to
 		set the fees for cases it's kind of like do it do it in the similar vein similar like uh VCR or television repair if you take your TV in
 		a lot of these TV repair <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">places</ENAMEX> will say well i'll repair your TV for a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">hundred dollars</NUMEX>
 		and if he gets in there and starts rooting around and finds something in there that's really tremendously wrong with it
 		then he eats it he he repairs it gives it back to you and takes your <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">hundred dollars</NUMEX> now if he comes in and says you know i'll repair your your VCR or somebody else's VCR for a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">hundred dollars</NUMEX>
 		gets in there maybe it's a blown fuse takes him <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two minutes</TIMEX> he fixes it he still charges you that <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">hundred dollars</NUMEX>
 		so maybe if we did that with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> so that you know whether it's a murder case or a you know a civil uh somebody suing somebody else you get <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">X</ENAMEX> dollars for that case and that's it none of this
 	
 	
 		now i i firmly believe in that because when you get the most
 		heinous of crimes have you ever noticed you always get the most renowned defense <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> and here's this bum that didn't have a job and he's got a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> that you and i could never afford
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		yeah
 		that's true yeah
 	
 	
 		who's paying for that
 	
 	
 		um yeah well you you know  you're talking to part of them that's paying for that
 	
 	
 		yeah and you're talking to the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> that's paying for it
 	
 	
 		that's right you know that's it it's it's amazing and and when you stop and look at it i mean the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> they're they're all former lawyers
 	
 	
 		yeah well that's another problem i think to really correct the judicial system you have to get the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> out of it
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i mean they're
 		they're totally and morally bankrupt without any ethics whatsoever and with that type <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> running it i mean you you could expect that you you could expect that you
 		
 		
 	