
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		topic today
 		there's a sound like a panel topic we're talking about uh what we can do to make uh
 		make uh our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> get a little more for it's money in other words
 	
 	
 		short and long long-term goals yeah
 	
 	
 		short long-term goals to be able to get
 		a better value
 		out of what we already pay
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i wanted to say something to you about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ross Perot</ENAMEX> are you familiar with the man
 	
 	
 		uh i've i've watched him yes he's  he's i've been told that that he uh well his ideologies won't work because he's too much of an authoritarian
 	
 	
 		
  
 		yeah but he does raise some interesting points like
 	
 	
 		he does i i i from just his speaking i i i hear a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a very</NUMEX> a strong tinge of integrity
 	
 	
 		uh-huh the uh
 		the the question he raised in my mind was uh he was speaking in front of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Press Club</ENAMEX> the other day
 		and he said  let's think of some wild and crazy things to do to wipe out the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">four hundred billion dollar</NUMEX> deficit that we've got
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um  remember we're thinking about wild and crazy things we'll throw anything out he said um let's say we take all the profits of the fortune <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">five hundred</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		for a year
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		not enough money
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only half</NUMEX> as much as we need
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so another words
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">hundred billion dollars</NUMEX> is hell of a lot of money
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and that's just he deficit <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">just this year</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		there's apparently <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred and eighty billion</NUMEX> dollars that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">controller</ENAMEX> will tell you is fault and mismanagement
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i think that would be the short-term goals
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		get rid of the fraud and mismanagement
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um apparently they have plenty of time
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">right now</TIMEX> for computer systems and other tracking methods to get rid of the fraud and everyone says well it's going to cost <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a billion dollars</NUMEX> to implement this <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">well</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a billion</NUMEX> stacked against <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred and eighty billion</NUMEX> sounds like a good investment to me
 	
 	
 		but are we what do you think are we talking about
 		the
 		the mechanical element you might say or are we talking about the human element i think it's the human element
 	
 	
 		it's a human element but the mechanical element of it can i mean mechanical meaning a computer could help
 	
 	
 		exactly yes
 	
 	
 		could help track
 	
 	
 		oh sure
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh and</ENAMEX> and find out what's going on you know statistical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cross-referencing</ENAMEX> and and uh you know the the pork barrel and all that other stuff that they uh you know
 	
 	
 		
  
 		
  
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they do to keep in office to stay in office uh
 		i think term limitations are a viable a viable way to cut the amount of money we spend in government
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um if uh you know we we say the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> can be limited to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> terms and we don't limit
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">congress</ENAMEX> critters at all
 	
 	
 		i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave</ENAMEX> i think one of the
 		another thing is that we have such a great disparity between the consumer and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> and that all reflects into the budget also
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we
 		we the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't have faith in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and they don't have faith in business
 	
 	
 		yeah especially now after this rubber gate thing you know they uh it's something that everyone can identify with and
 	
 	
 		exactly
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		and uh if they can't even balance their own check book how in the worlds are they going to balance a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">trillion</NUMEX> plus <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">dollar</NUMEX> budget
 	
 	
 		
  
 		well then you have you have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> going over to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> to try to do some wrangling over there to for the trade deficit and they send the send the top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GM</ENAMEX>
 		and they're they're making
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> times they're making <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">hundreds of thousands of dollars</NUMEX> a year
 	
 	
 		um oh that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GM</ENAMEX> is trying to market their products and is
 		that that's another way is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> just don't trust big business they just don't there's
 		so right there you have an element of of the political government you have an element of big business and you have the consumer watching and they're just going what's this
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah i think um it's
 		uh i've been studying some libertarian views
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i've been thinking more and more that maybe we need to get <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> out of
 		out of business and away from business and out of everybody's hair
 	
 	
 		you know i i i mean i agree with you to a certain extent but the problem is with democracy with you know our capitalistic government
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the almighty dollar doesn't have any ethical code with it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i it's just like how you know what would you do the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Exxon Valdez</ENAMEX>
 		you see what what are we just just say are we taking government out of it we need those controls because
 		the in the our capitalistic society it's just those controls it's just it's
 		the business it starts going and if they can its its the dollar that that dictates and if they can find someplace to dump something or their <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pollution</ENAMEX> and we're polluting something unfortunately
 	
 	
 		well
 		
 		
 	