
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cathy</ENAMEX> um do you keep a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">monthly</TIMEX> budget
 	
 	
 		well we we do of sorts it's not a it's not a family budget both my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and i work and what we do is basically treat each income as separate uh
 		partly we didn't want to fall into the trap of arguing over the family money oh yeah well you know i earned this much and therefore i have the right to spend that
 		and well you know you overspent the the total budget this way each of us knows what's in our own bank accounts
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so you can if you want to write a check for somebody's birthday present you don't have to worry about the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> seeing it that sort of thing
 		but uh what's unique is that uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> keeps a spreadsheet of uh the income and he submits a bill to me <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every month</TIMEX> an itemized bill and i pay that
 	
 	
 		wow
 	
 	
 		and then so he has track of both of our expenses i pay part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">utilities</ENAMEX> he pays part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">utilities</ENAMEX> it takes a little bit more work but it does work for us i mean it it really does work very successfully for us
 	
 	
 		hum
 		do you have any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes i'm i am juggling <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> right now on my lap
 		uh we have a uh almost one he he'll be one on on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX> second you can hear him and the one is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> and he's off taking a bath  so uh yeah we've got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		well i can hear him right there
 		so how does that work into your budget
 	
 	
 		uh well what
 	
 	
 		as far as planning for expenses and so forth
 	
 	
 		well in terms of of immediate expenses like clothing um i purchase those out of my income and i get reimbursed
 		<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">fifty percent</NUMEX> of that by my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> so again i submit bills to him  receipts to him uh for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> care uh what we do is actually take that directly out of my income
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> and my my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> has a uh a pretax medical deduction uh medical and uh child care uh all together so
 		um that that helps for for that planning
 	
 	
 		hum until they you wouldn't happen to work for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liberty Mutual</ENAMEX> would you
 	
 	
 		excuse me no no no a a biotech <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> as a matter of fact
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liberty Mutual</ENAMEX>
 		okay
 		that that's my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> and that's exactly what we have
 	
 	
 		yeah and it it works out it works out really well now in terms of long term like college expenses
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh right now we don't have something that's set up that's labeled college we have uh more along the lines of um uh sort of investment plans in each of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s names
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they were set up as as <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> birthday presents or or or even newborn presents from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX> just the the actually assembled and set up
 		uh all the investment decisions are are now ours
 		but in terms of retirement that's the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> area that that is is still a little sticky because you you you sort of have your retirement plans through your companies
 		and we spent so much time trying to to make sure that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> are okay  that
 		and you know for our own retirement there's not a whole lot actually organized but we do have uh the things through our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> so that's that's a start anyway
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah this is uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first year</TIMEX> that actually <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first month</TIMEX> that i've actually instituted a budget uh for my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and i
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the previous nine years</TIMEX> or so we've just pretty much let it slide um there really wasn't much problem as far as income versus expenses
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh things are getting a little bit tighter
 		uh we bought a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> we bought a new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicle</ENAMEX> things that which weren't a problem before have have all sudden noticed our cash flow is starting to decline a little bit
 	
 	
 		um
 		
 
 	
 	
 		you know with all the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">monthly</TIMEX> bills and uh
 		uh so far it's working out pretty well you know we're keeping an eye on what we spend <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each week</TIMEX>
 		but like i said being one of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first months</TIMEX> we really won't know for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few more months</TIMEX> down the road how well we're doing
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		but your plan where you you submit bills that's the most
 		itemized plan i've ever seen or heard anyone talk about as far as married couples
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well it's not it's not actually too bad once you get the spreadsheet the spreadsheet set out by my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> has categories for things like utilities uh you know other expenses
 	
 	
 		interesting
 	
 	
 		uh the rent and my contribution i don't make as much financially as he does
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so my contribution is prorated it doesn't come it doesn't come fifty percent out of my pocket when i don't make fifty percent of the income uh you know which is nice it's fair
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fair</ENAMEX> enough
 	
 	
 		uh so actually what it what happens is that we gather all the bills and then write them down and then uh
 		well uh after that it's just a question of putting them into the computer and the computer generates you know i mean it it takes the percentage that's necessary and he prints out a bill and i write a check and that's it
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> once it's set up it works it works reasonable well
 		so it it most of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> though when they find out about it they they they think your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> submits a bill to you that's that's that's weird  that's really weird but we don't i mean i
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	