
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so let's talk about the uh wonderful abuses in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State of Pennsylvania</ENAMEX> of personal property taxes whereby you can purchase something mail order
 		and after the fact the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State of Pennsylvania</ENAMEX> can find out about it and send you a bill for the sales tax appropriate to that item that you purchased as well as interest and penalties from the time that you bought it
 		what do you think is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX> kind of out of line there
 	
 	
 		well actually i don't think they're out of line <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Devil's Devil</ENAMEX>'s advocate possibly but it you are trying to avoid paying taxes and whether whether or not you agree with that law
 		it you're still circumventing it you are legal in in your circumvention of that law
 	
 	
 		what what if you're not doing it in order to circumvent the law though i mean what if you don't even realize that you're subject to paying um income tax on something that you purchase mail order
 	
 	
 		uh really i i i don't think that's a valid argument i think that most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are quite aware they're not paying that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">six percent</NUMEX> sales tax um some naturally some some things you just can't find in your local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KMart</ENAMEX> or or  um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bryn Mawr</ENAMEX> stereo dealer um but
 		then then then why not pay pay the sales tax to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> have to why should an individual just because it's just because the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> can't really find out about it be able to avoid paying sales tax
 	
 	
 		well i mean it seems to me that
 		generally at least in my own experience when i purchase something mail order it's not to circumvent paying sales tax to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State of Pennsylvania</ENAMEX> it's because
 		i'm sorry the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commonwealth of Pennsylvania</ENAMEX> uh it's because i i can't find the item that i want at a competitive price anywhere in my local area so i go outside the area for that
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		and i think that it's not my responsibility to police myself and pay <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX> what they believe they are owed
 		even though you know the revenue stream went to another state i don't i don't think that that's my responsibility as a as a conscientious consumer
 	
 	
 		i i'll agree it it's not your responsibility but
 		is but is it also legal
 		for you to do that what what from from what i understand from various various various net readings it it it the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is going to try to legislate a more aggressive enforcement of state
 		tax schemes um in into place in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next few years</TIMEX> it is it is a lost revenue stream right now and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> can can use all the revenue they can get with some with something like that will do your arguments still apply
 	
 	
 		well i think that if if policy is established and if a mechanism is put into place to promote the collection of taxes in this fashion
 		then i don't argue with it because it's not a burden on the consumer to remember that oh i bought this out of state i need  to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Xerox</ENAMEX> the receipt and make out a check for <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">six percent</NUMEX> and send it to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		which is exactly what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> do at the present
 	
 	
 		right but the point is is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> do that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> that you purchase the thing from is responsible for collecting the appropriate sales tax and forwarding it to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> in question that's a cost of doing business the burden shouldn't be placed on the consumer
 	
 	
 		and i i
 		i was actually talking about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> purchasing something mail order and then having having to pay sales tax on it
 	
 	
 		ah
 	
 	
 		that's my understanding of the way um the way it works usually the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> ordering it doesn't pay but the accounting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> will uh suck up all the bills at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the month</TIMEX> and realize how much they have to pay
 		and there reasons there are some some substantial nasty penalties um if you if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> try to avoid that
 	
 	
 		uh do you mean <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> from the point of view as of of selling things to a consumer and then being responsible for the sales tax
 	
 	
 		a as if
 		no <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> um if
 	
 	
 		or purchasing
 	
 	
 		purchasing things mail order if i if i'm a computer consulting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> and i see these this great deal on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">forty eighty six</NUMEX> motherboards uh from from say <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> um
 		i i might buy the motherboards from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> but then still have to pay some <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX> sales tax my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> accounting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> will at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the month</TIMEX>
 		uh i think that  i think that's the way things work in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX> and i know they work that way in uh say here in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah see i'm unfamiliar with that because i don't i never see that end of the business
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so my only experience has been from the point of view of a consumer
 		um but if that's the case if the business is responsible for policing themselves then i think some well defined mechanisms need to be in place so that
 		um the opportunity for to forget that you owe sales tax for something uh can be avoided
 	
 	
 		that's true is is a real a big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hole</ENAMEX> does exist right now uh in that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> can just say oh i i forgot that there there is no well defined mechanism at all and and that it is a  <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a</NUMEX> a loss i i think
 		is that the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> will try to establish a mechanism just just to do just that in order in order to gain the revenue that's being lost um and i i don't know if i agree with that but it but
 		
 		
 	