
 
     		
 	
 		so <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick</ENAMEX> you thinking about buying a new car
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah i am uh a truck
 	
 	
 		a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> uh <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i think i'm going to buy <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> this time
 	
 	
 		you you this time you had a you <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Japanese</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah i got a yeah we got a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toyota</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of them actually
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they uh they've always been real good <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> but it's just uh
 	
 	
 		they rust
 	
 	
 		well i actually haven't had any problem with them at all but um i i think it's probably pretty important to uh to buy <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> i've i'm coming to that conclusion
 	
 	
 		you know i it's like i'm i've been driving like foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> now for for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and i i'm actually thinking about buying a new car i i
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i'm sitting i'm sitting here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">right now</TIMEX> it's like my with a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">thousand dollars</NUMEX> worth of repairs on my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>  and uh i'm thinking about buying an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> also
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um i i think they're to the point now where they're just they're just as good as those foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i yeah i do too i i think uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i've i've had pickup <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trucks</ENAMEX> before and i've had uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chevrolets</ENAMEX> and they were pretty good but i i think uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX> um is is pretty much focusing on quality
 	
 	
 		that
 		that's the best uh actually uh a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> that like's in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next</TIMEX> office he uh he's thinking about buying a truck and he's looking at an F <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> fifty and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		he he he one thing that you find about the about the the F <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> fifties is that uh
 		they are every every the word is out that they are like the best truck uh especially like if you want to get like you know heavier than a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mini</ENAMEX> pick up and uh they weren't cutting too many deals
 	
 	
 		is that right yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		with uh with the prices on the F <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> fifties especially especially like in the in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> wheel drive models
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh i i i guess like all these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> can't be that wrong you know in terms uh of uh of how they how they are
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah i was looking in uh
 		it was uh i i forget the name of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> used to be Changing Times sort of like a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Consumer Reports</ENAMEX> magazine
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh they were saying that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford Ranger</ENAMEX> was the number one selling truck counting all
 	
 	
 		now the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ranger</ENAMEX> is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ranger</ENAMEX> is below the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> fifty it's like a it's like a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">three quarter ton</NUMEX> truck
 	
 	
 		yeah um-hum
 		yeah something like i believe something like that
 	
 	
 		and was is and the and the F <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> fifty is <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a ton and a half</NUMEX> or or i'm not sure where they sit
 	
 	
 		yeah i'm not sure i i i kind of think i'd like to go with uh something around a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a one</NUMEX> fifty i don't want a full size but i don't want uh one of those little uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mini trucks</ENAMEX> either
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		besides i probably would look at something uh maybe a a V <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		yep you geing to get a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">King Cab</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know  yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah that
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		that that  know do you have any any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> or anything
 	
 	
 		yeah i've got one little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> and and and a set of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">golf clubs</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		oh there you go yeah you you you  you got to have you got to have just that extra space
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 		yeah yeah that's it
 	
 	
 		it yeah
 		the uh the it's a a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buddy</ENAMEX> of mine he just he just bought a truck and uh
 		and and it was a thing was like it would there was no thought whatsoever about not getting the extra size cab even though you can't really use use that back area for a seat
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know unless you're some like some kind of contortionist
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		uh
 	
 	
 		but
 		you just need it because you do carry you do carry stuff that you you don't want to like just throw in the bed
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah i i kind of like the looks of a short bed but or the short cab but but uh you know like i say just you you just really need the extra space
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		either unless you have some sort of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cab</ENAMEX> you know  cover or something but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		you'd get air-conditioning because  you're down there it's pretty hot right
 	
 	
 		yeah um-hum
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> that uh
 	
 	
 		although uh i i notice you you you said rust right before that that we don't have that much problem down here but i know y'all have it up there i guess they salt the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		uh
 		oh boy i'll tell you that's like that's the number one car <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">killer</ENAMEX> up here is that is the is the rust you know it's like you're you're constantly car taking
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		about every other every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about every month</TIMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the winter</TIMEX> you know the smart thing to do is to go to like one of those uh
 		drive in car washes do it yourself and just fire a bunch of water underneath underneath you know up into your rocker <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panels</ENAMEX> and stuff
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh yeah</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		because uh it just like i said it it just eats the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> like right alive
 	
 	
 		yeah i guess i i as as was working with some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Buffalo</ENAMEX> here recently or actually it was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple years ago</TIMEX> but
 		they were they were saying you know a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> up there they got a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX> car and then a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> car you know
 	
 	
 		that my <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX>'s in the exact same situation situation it's like he uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		he has he has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> one of them is a is a a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mitsubishi</ENAMEX> you know uh uh i don't know what is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Starion</ENAMEX> or it's one of those hot <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		yeah um-hum
 	
 	
 		it's like come come <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX> when the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX> like start to get you know to get nasty the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Starion</ENAMEX> goes like into the into the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">garage</ENAMEX> then he closes it and locks it and then he
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		he throws he he pull he throws a tarp off of this beater that he's got in the backyard
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		out comes the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">sixty eight</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nova</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i think it's a it's actually like a
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		it's like an <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty two</NUMEX> no no yeah it's like an <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toyota</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Corolla</ENAMEX> you know
 	
 	
 		yeah uh-huh
 	
 	
 		and this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> goes through this like role you know this revert <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Doctor Jekyll and Mister Hyde</ENAMEX> revert
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	