
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		been about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years</TIMEX> since i graduated from high school i got a GED i was a drop out up until that point
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh as my memory serves me <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> was not that um
 		didn't achieve it's goals as being an educational <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX> very well and i would suppose that the trend in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is for things to get worse kind of like uh chaos and regular deterioration so i don't not having seen anything to
 		change my mind i would assume it's gotten worse in the meantime
 	
 	
 		yeah i graduated about the same time you did and um i graduated early only and i was lucky because i don't think i would have graduated at all
 		i was skipping and everything
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		up to that point and i just happened to have enough credit hours so i could get out
 	
 	
 		yeah i had really reached the point where i'd quit going entirely i was tired of it was off working somewhere
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		there was almost no challenge to it at all
 	
 	
 		i was on the college track doing all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classes</ENAMEX> and i was done
 	
 	
 		uh
 		um
 	
 	
 		it was boring
 		they weren't interested
 	
 	
 		yeah i had started in that uh that track but just got sick of it and turned into a juvenile delinquent instead
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		went off and joined the military and then uh came back to college it just the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">material</ENAMEX> was so repetitive it was stuff we already seen probably <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> a
 		who knows how many times before and it was just presented so dryly and i suppose that if um if you're going to pay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> the salary that they're paid that's that's the level of education that's going to be presented
 	
 	
 		that's true we have to pay our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> more and give them more incentive to interest the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um yeah i really  i really believe the same thing i mean here i am now just now  finishing up college it took me that long to get interested to go back
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		you know and but i find college a whole different ball game
 	
 	
 		yeah absolutely
 		it's a stress test
 	
 	
 		it is but it's so stimulating i mean
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> really are at least mine of course i'm in nursing so
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		
 
 		ours is a lot of life threatening but um
 		i it it isn't i i don't miss classes i love it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah i agree it's a whole another class of everything the level of education the uh excitement and the the interesting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">instructors</ENAMEX> their level of understanding the material everything's different
 	
 	
 		maybe we ought to um
 		offer this kind of enrichment to our high school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		now how would you recommend doing that
 	
 	
 		well
 		if somehow we could make give them a certain amount of independence
 		cause that's part of college
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		right um and then simply say this is up to you to achieve this
 	
 	
 		sounds a lot like the um what do they call let's see uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fire fox Foxfire</ENAMEX> method
 	
 	
 		i haven't heard about that
 	
 	
 		that's the one where uh some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> it's here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgia</ENAMEX> north <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgia</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several years ago ten twenty years ago</TIMEX>
 		walked into a class <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> and they the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> retained <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">command</ENAMEX> and he just kind of threw up his hands and said basically do what you want to do
 		and developed this uh program where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> pretty much did what they wanted to do
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> was just there to kindly loosely kind of loosely guide them um along and to make sure that they weren't getting
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		getting off into weird senseless subject areas and stuff like that and i think there was some kind of sociology <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> along the lines of um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		what did they do they went out and collected stories and culture of the area in southern <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Appalachian</ENAMEX> uh mountains
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and published a bunch of books and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>'s real famous now and in fact i just read recently that some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> here in north <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgia</ENAMEX> decided to completely um adopt the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foxfire</ENAMEX> method all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classes</ENAMEX> are that way
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		and they say that the results are just tremendous it's a whole another um magnitude of improvement over regular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> schools
 	
 	
 		
  
 		see and that and it works
 	
 	
 		yeah i wish there had been something like that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> when we were younger
 	
 	
 		me too i wish they had computers
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah they've made a an amazing change
 	
 	
 		i think i think elementary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> is educational is stimulating for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and i think we lose them somewhere
 		between junior high and high school
 	
 	
 		a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> here in town just recently helped a um <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grader</ENAMEX> with his science fair project  and he was describing some of the interaction
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh between the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> there and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> there and himself and other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like him
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and was really disturbed with the uh
 		mentality of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> there they treated him like uh he was one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> you know they had their little domain
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		i remember he brought up a story about how he needed a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">desk</ENAMEX> to set up the  uh the science fair project that he and this other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> worked on
 		and they couldn't find one anywhere and they found <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">instructor</ENAMEX> there was really possessive of it and wouldn't let him use it
 	
 	
 		oh you're kidding
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		well then that goes to maybe not having the funds for things
 		
 		
 	