
 
     		
 	
 		why what would you tell someone
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 		well i think first thing is they need to talk with their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> to  their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> talk to their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> and find exactly what they want
 		to do why are they're going why are they going to college instead of doing something else
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		once you find out why they want to go to college then you can get a better idea of
 		uh what range of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX> they should go to
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh obviously if they want to learn trade skills you wouldn't send them to an academic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">center</ENAMEX> and vice versa
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and um beyond that i think you need to consider the uh range of expenses of going to college that would probably narrow your ranges down even further
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and if you want to go something beyond what you can afford then you need to start investigating scholarship and other things
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so i think you start out with something broad like that and then narrow your range as you you know as you find out more about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> and what the their uh needs are and what they want to do
 		how about you
 	
 	
 		well i guess i would agree somewhat i mean in terms of finding out first why they want to go to college if they do want to go to college a lot of times it's the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> who want them to go to college rather than themselves
 	
 	
 		
 
 		that does happen yes
 	
 	
 		um but uh i think it's probably the the studies have been done looking at uh
 		how well you are and what you do when you end up whether or not you uh have a degree or not uh makes a big difference later on in your life
 		and um  you know it'd be good to even to start as early as possible to understand what what you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> would desire
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and and determine a goal some point uh before like the last moment
 	
 	
 		well
 	
 	
 		and but you know you never know they always a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> go to college because they don't know what else is better to do
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		it seems like it's my experience
 		but uh i guess that once they've decided they wanted to go to college
 		i think that's that's also that's something  uh important but uh
 		you know have them go through the i guess they have like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Barron's</ENAMEX> books and various other books that describes
 		all the different <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX> that they are in terms of competitiveness and things like that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they could also narrow it down that way other than just the economic things
 		though it's probably more so now than used to be
 		um but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you know you want to try to match their needs as best they can and then if
 		you know you could always shoot for those places that don't have you know are  that might be considered out of your range but sometimes you might be able to get a scholarship or whatever have you so i wouldn't rule them out on the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> cut
 		uh i would try to get them to to find the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX> they think that are
 		you know best fit their needs in terms of the size the college the kinds of course offerings the reputation they have in those areas
 		um you know whether a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> wants to be closer or away how far away they want to be from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> there's a lot of different other aspects to it you know
 	
 	
 		that does enter into it all
 	
 	
 		yeah and uh i think there's things like student uh faculty ratios and and uh
 		all that kind of stuff how well endowed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> is sometimes you that's important because if it's not well endowed school
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh then a you know a lot of times they're just they uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> go from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year to year</TIMEX> based on just the enrollment
 		and uh if that's what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>'s doing then um it may not be around <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the following year</TIMEX> especially these times
 	
 	
 		yes
 		
  
 	
 	
 		you know they're not as economically sound  right
 	
 	
 		well i have a a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> now who is
 		a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">junior</ENAMEX>  who is looking at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's interesting uh there were a lot more choices <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> when i went to college
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		she is is going through the process much like what you're you know you've described and i've described described so
 		how far away do they want to go what do they want to do how important is whether it's a private or a public school
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		what are the chances for scholarships
 		and uh a lot of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">mid</NUMEX> range smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> that
 		are actually easier to get into if you have pretty good grades of course it's not quite so comparative to say the Ivy League schools
 	
 	
 		oh yeah uh-huh
 	
 	
 		and um
 	
 	
 		yeah they also tend not to be as well endowed and they also have
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		lots of other uh good and bad points sometimes the offerings that they have is better than
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know some of the Ivy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> that's for sure uh
 		but there's also other problems too
 		um you know they tend to they all admit all sorts of people
 		
 		
 	