
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		go ahead
 	
 	
 		oh okay yeah the uh subject is child care and how to determine child care and
 		that's uh an interesting one for me to talk about since i have no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> but i did run a child care <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> for a while
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		and uh have some
 	
 	
 		well you should've you should have some opinions on that then
 	
 	
 		i do have some thoughts on that yeah and it's uh an interesting experience to be a surrogate <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">parent</ENAMEX> for or a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> for a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> there
 		and um  it's also very interesting in terms of how <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> choose  the child care facilities
 	
 	
 		well i guess if i were going to choose i mean my first consideration would be safety
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		my second consideration would be uh
 		um
 		health
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and uh i guess my <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> consideration would be uh
 		warm
 		environment warm personal environment
 	
 	
 		well right um in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> we have to meet certain state standards in order to operate  on a at an institutional level and at a like a small <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> level so
 		you meet the standards  but then after that there's there's a lot more i think it's important as the safety and health and that kind of stuff is qualification of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who work there
 		and in hiring <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who would work at the uh day care the child care <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> was very difficult to find qualified people
 		um in terms of not just just because somebody has a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> or uh likes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> doesn't really mean that they're qualified to give the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> the kind of supervision and training that
 	
 	
 		oh absolutely  as a matter of fact i believe that the safety and and health uh issues uh depend in a very direct way on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are working with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that uh
 		exactly and that was the most difficult thing of all to find the the right <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> the qualified people
 	
 	
 		and it's the most difficult thing of all for a parent
 		judge uh because a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> can be very nice and warm and loving but if he's a space <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cadet</ENAMEX> and doesn't watch the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and be aware of what the safety hazards are
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh exactly and the other thing that's difficult in uh an institutional setting like a day care <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> is to find the right program of enrichment
 		for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> because you don't wanna just warehouse the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> and i didn't want to run an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX> where that was the case where all we were doing were warehousing because the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four or five years</TIMEX> are so important
 		and you have to have the right kind of enrichment and that that includes uh an atmosphere in which the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> is safe and
 		and he's watched and his physical needs are cared for but also his uh developmental needs are cared for too
 	
 	
 		maybe the right thing to do is to um
 		when a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> has a child
 		then they should both take you say the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four or five years</TIMEX> are the most important and i think i would agree with that they both take <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four or five years</TIMEX> off and devote to parenting
 	
 	
 		that would be lovely
 	
 	
 		get rid of all these child care centers
 		at least for young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> below the age of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> and then of course to make up for that um the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> would have to work in their <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later years</TIMEX> longer in in other words they probably would not work
 		may not end may end up not working at all in the twenties
 		oh
 	
 	
 		well that's an interesting thought because
 	
 	
 		but they may have to work from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age thirty</TIMEX> or or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">forty</NUMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age seventy</TIMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty or ninety</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		that would be okay  that would that would help on the other end too
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		in in terms of not warehousing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and letting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> be productive for as long as they can be
 	
 	
 		right well you know the uh uh the world is changing from uh uh uh uh
 		from institutional from uh industrial uh base to uh information <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">base</ENAMEX> and so what that means is you don't have to be physically powerful to work
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		that's exactly right
 	
 	
 		all you have to do is have a sharp mind and i believe that uh mental <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">acuity</ENAMEX> is
 		easy to sustain maintain if you just simply continue to exercise your mind
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		so i think a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> could work  uh into the seventies eighties even nineties for that matter if they didn't have to do a lot of physical uh labor they could maintain maintain uh a
 		
 		
 	