
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		are you there
 	
 	
 		i sure am
 	
 	
 		well i guess it sounds like you have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in the background there
 	
 	
 		yes i do
 	
 	
 		yeah what kind of child care have you found for them
 	
 	
 		uh we're military so we take him to a military day care
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um i'm enrolled in a school right now a nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and it's just about the only thing i can afford
 	
 	
 		i see
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> it is expensive
 	
 	
 		it is and
 	
 	
 		what what kind uh through the military what kind of prices do you pay for child care there
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">forty five</NUMEX> a week
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">forty five</NUMEX> a week i'm from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bay area</ENAMEX> and uh just not even um well known <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> in child care here <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are paying <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two hundred two hundred</NUMEX> fifty a week
 	
 	
 		yes
 		oh my goodness you're kidding
 	
 	
 		no i don't know how they do it i'm i stay at home i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> i stay at home with <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX> but i know that it's uh really expensive here
 	
 	
 		oh that is outrageous
 	
 	
 		what types of things have you looked for when you're um when you were looking in for to the child care there
 	
 	
 		well i've had several different kinds of day care
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> taking care of him and that doesn't work
 	
 	
 		it doesn't
 	
 	
 		no um your your beliefs are different and i i guess they become you you can't um make demands that you can when you're paying for it
 	
 	
 		uh-huh i understand that
 	
 	
 		and i'm i'm not talking severe demands i'm talking things like i have to have you on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> you know what i mean
 	
 	
 		uh-huh right
 	
 	
 		i have an exam i must have you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> sit
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		um i've had home health care that i've gotten through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> and things like that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah well have the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies agencies</ENAMEX> sent you some good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> or
 	
 	
 		uh no no they're they're usually badly educated
 	
 	
 		no huh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		probably poor <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> that's what you find here in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bay area</ENAMEX> a lot of times
 	
 	
 		yes
 		yes and i'm i'm just not willing to expose my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> to that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i mean i i want him to be i want him to be stimulated and interested
 	
 	
 		yeah does does through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX> does the day care do they have things like oh craft projects and learning numbers is it is it kind of like a a preschool it is
 	
 	
 		yes
 		preschool <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only half</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a day half a day</TIMEX> is kind of geared toward those kind of things
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every week</TIMEX> is divided like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> they're doing spring and then <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX> they may do kites and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all week</TIMEX> they'll have things about this
 	
 	
 		i see
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		not only they talk about kites they talk about the different colors on kites they talk cultural aspects the shapes
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hm</ENAMEX> or
 	
 	
 		uh you know it's wonderful
 	
 	
 		well it sounds like a good school you know i'm uh being at home with mine um if if i do go back to work it you know it worries me to death the thought of uh the child care you hear so many things about
 	
 	
 		it is frightening
 	
 	
 		oh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> being oh Shaken <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Child Syndrome</ENAMEX> being <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> being molested i mean it's it's so hard to say say you know even with even with credentials whether you can trust them with your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert</ENAMEX>'s day care has um close camera watch on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> you know what  i mean so it's monitored
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh that's good
 	
 	
 		plus they have um this is military so they have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> come in and do checkups on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		what <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> are you in
 		oh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> my
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort Worth</ENAMEX> um-hum
 	
 	
 		oh huh yeah
 	
 	
 		and and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dentists</ENAMEX> come over <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> social work comes over uh family services comes over
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i mean it's a continual rotation of resources
 	
 	
 		oh well that sounds like a really good it sounds like a good place to to rear <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> it sounds like you're in a good good situation with the military
 	
 	
 		it is and they don't change day care <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> at all i mean my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> has been in there now a year and he has the same teacher
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		see that's
 		that's a problem with the day care here my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister-in-law</ENAMEX> has everyone i know in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bay area</ENAMEX> except me have their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> in day care and
 	
 	
 		and you know why they keep these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> they pay them more
 	
 	
 		um-hum exactly yeah the military i mean they just take care of their own i mean
 	
 	
 		they do
 	
 	
 		these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">um sister-in-law</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> have been in day care and they've switched i mean from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> care to another and those poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh i know they need they need um
 	
 	
 		they don't know what's going on
 		consistence consistency
 	
 	
 		yes they need and they need this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> is taking care of some of those things that i can't give my child
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		now i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> so i'm i'm home a lot
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i mean he's not like one a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight to five</NUMEX> job where i'm gone all the time
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but he he these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parent people</ENAMEX> are these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> are mothering my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> to a certain degree that's so important
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		it is really important well you're so lucky you know that
 	
 	
 		i am
 	
 	
 		that you have such a good opportunity with um the through the military especially
 	
 	
 		very lucky i have to admit i don't know what i'd do without it
 	
 	
 		yeah my um i guess uh i was surprised to hear the prices of the day care here um
 	
 	
 		oh i know
 	
 	
 		being <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two two</NUMEX> and i'm sure even in some of the nicer i'm not i'm talking uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Jose</ENAMEX> area the nicer areas <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paolo Alto</ENAMEX> more as it gets more expensive
 	
 	
 		oh no
 	
 	
 		you probably pay them i would assume you pay them more just because they're overhead in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> you know their renting in these day care places
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know the overhead for the for uh you know just paying their rent in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX> and she has the most wonderful home health care
 	
 	
 		oh does she
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> who does this for a living so she has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> that's all she can have by law
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and
 		
 		
 	