
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i actually just got back from uh U2 uh last week
 	
 	
 		yes
 		they were in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX> uh recently
 	
 	
 		yeah they they started down in the south and then they headed up the coast
 	
 	
 		how many shows did they play um
 	
 	
 		they played well we saw them in Wister
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		and they played once in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wister</ENAMEX> and once in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Providence</ENAMEX> and then <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saint Patrick</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Day</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i see i see so you you just caught one show uh
 	
 	
 		yeah um  the way they rigged things where you had to call an <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight hundred</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">number</ENAMEX> and and you know <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> tickets <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> tickets per a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		yes
 		oh i see
 	
 	
 		there there where <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two million</NUMEX> call attempts in in an hour to get the tickets so it was like by the time we got through there i mean we had separate <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">seats seats</ENAMEX> but we lucked out we got a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> and a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> row seat
 	
 	
 		really
 		yes
 		how about that
 	
 	
 		yeah so we were we were pleased
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah um uh so so um specifically um that's the sort of music you like
 	
 	
 		well i mean it it's more my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fiance</ENAMEX>'s tastes um i go more into <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Celtic</ENAMEX> music um <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Celtic Celtic</ENAMEX> folk uh
 	
 	
 		i see
 		really that's interesting
 		sort of new age stuff
 	
 	
 		well Still <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">I Spin and Silly Wizard uh Fair Port Convention</ENAMEX> you know kind kind of folk rocky kind of stuff but with a strong Celtic element
 	
 	
 		yeah i i
 		i see
 		i see
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh</ENAMEX> also Tangerine you know all sorts of pseudo new agey stuff <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tangerine Dream</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Micheal Field</ENAMEX> and and anything semi electronic
 	
 	
 		yes
 		is um so the appeal of that music is the  quality you know the relaxing quality to it
 	
 	
 		well i i like the harmonies and <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">and and</ENAMEX> and the sounds of of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Celtic</ENAMEX> music and i like like the uh
 		um the uh the the uh i'm trying to remember the name of it Tin Whistle the the variety of songs tone you can get out and i find the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singers</ENAMEX> tend to be better less screaming and more more uh
 	
 	
 		yes
 		melodic uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">melodic</ENAMEX> and attention to phrasing and and hitting the notes rather than you know just belting them out
 	
 	
 		yes
 		i see i see
 	
 	
 		uh sound you sound like you probably are down in the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and western belt there
 	
 	
 		i yeah well uh well you see um uh down here there is a big you know there's a huge Country <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Western</ENAMEX> influence um particularly what <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">i like um the Blues</ENAMEX> and uh you know various forms of um
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		you know of uh <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">um Delta Blues</ENAMEX> and uh getting back to um really elemental forms
 	
 	
 		well i i find i prefer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Delta Blues</ENAMEX> to like you know what a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> think the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Blues</ENAMEX> are because i find you know kind of the more
 		the the more uh conventional as where blues i i find kind of repetitive and unmelodic
 	
 	
 		well it um you know i can see that argument but and as far as the emotion and the feeling that comes out you know even though it might be repetitive um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the the emotion that comes out of it i really think is a lot of it you know it you know where as the  quality of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Celtic</ENAMEX> music seems appealing the raw power and you know whether
 	
 	
 		um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah well it it's a very it's a very minimalist form because you've got duh duh duh duh or something like that you've got a very simple base line with
 	
 	
 		uh yeah
 		uh uh
 		just a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">one four five progression</NUMEX> over and over again yeah
 	
 	
 		right yeah i think i was singing like my <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX>  yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah i mean i i think with that the quality kind of it it's much more based on you know how much the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> can impart i mean i've heard some <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Blues</ENAMEX> that it's like you you know did not strike me as
 		as anything special because it's like yeah okay you know life's been tough to me too and you know there's just so much you can hear of that
 	
 	
 		right
 		so uh so so perhaps the connection with it wasn't there uh
 	
 	
 		yeah i i mean you know well i've heard some Blues i really liked where they're imparting more than just you know i'm yet another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who got treated bad
 	
 	
 		yes
 		yes
 	
 	
 		i'm trying to think whether there was something interesting or unique because i think it depends a lot more on the actual message being imparted it it certainly certainly you're not listening to it for its lifting melodies
 	
 	
 		right
 		right  right right um i also like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jazz</ENAMEX> and um you know how do you think the two um
 		you know complement each other do do right
 	
 	
 		well uh
 		Jazz is is a much more i i i think you've got to be a much more uh spontaneous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> to be playing Jazz you know you've got a long time to think about that next verse in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Blues</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes
 		right
 	
 	
 		where as in Jazz you know it just is is moving and um
 	
 	
 		and create a flowing in different directions
 	
 	
 		right i mean and you've got to be very i mean in many ways <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Jazz and Celtic</ENAMEX> if you ever go to like a
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		um it's very much like a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a a an extemporaneous</NUMEX> or a uh
 		uh you know just a a jam session Jazz because you know there may be a basic pattern you know if you're playing a reel or a jig you know that's the basic melody of the jig but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are just going off and doing their own things and these are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who may have never played
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		uh uh never played together and uh never there uh apparently in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Celtic</ENAMEX> is there any set form that um
 	
 	
 		right
 		um there is to some extent i mean you know there's the basic tune of the jig or the real
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		but you know someone will just come in and you know who's going to who's going to you know take lead on this verse who's going to you know it you know i want to uh there's a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> called  which is an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	