
 
     		
 	
 		so do you your privacy being invaded at any time
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well one of the things that uh
 		that i found to be uh an invasion is when i pay for something with a credit card and they ask me to put my telephone number on the
 		on the uh credit card bill
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		that is something that is not required and in fact uh
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		it is actually prohibited but it doesn't stop many  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from uh from doing it
 		and it's
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the things that it's used for primarily is for demographic uh research and to get the your your phone number on uh
 		uh lists for phone solicitations
 	
 	
 		yep
 		yep there's a lot that you you can still yeah i have always done that i started once i found out that that's really
 		not necessary or legal then i just refuse and i say what are you gonna do
 		you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gonna</ENAMEX> say you don't wanna sell me this product then that's fine i'll just buy it somewhere else or not buy it at all
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then ultimately they say no you don't have to put it down
 		but uh really it's part of this compliance thing
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh the thing i don't like i know that certain <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> actually sell their uh their lists like uh motor <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicles</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that really burns me because
 		hey you're required you have to do that
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and
 		nowhere does it say you have asks you whether you have permission or not to sell your name or information regarding that to anyone
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i think that's it it's one thing  voluntarily give it because someone asks you can always refuse but it's another thing where it's required by law and then they go ahead and take that information and sell it to somebody
 	
 	
 		right uh that
 	
 	
 		you know i don't think i don't think they have the right to do that
 	
 	
 		i agree with you there that's something that uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have seen oh here's an easy way to make some money
 		but uh  i don't know if that's been challenged in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> or not i've i've heard
 		fairly recently uh
 		some talk about that in this in in my <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> ah the budget problems up here are are pretty tense and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are looking for
 		alternate ways of uh you know enhancing revenue is the uh phrase they use and they were talking about selling the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DMV</ENAMEX> lists and there was a lot of uh
 		a lot of uh
 		consternation about that and the last i heard they'd backed down from that idea
 		but
 		it really makes you wonder what other lists you're on that have been made uh public that you don't know about
 	
 	
 		well that's easy whenever you donate money to someone
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they you become  put on something like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sucker</ENAMEX> list and you start getting <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of calls or
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">solicitations</ENAMEX> and then you start  it kind of makes you feel deeded from doing it again like uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Public Radio</ENAMEX> or
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		any of these the public uh stations you know i i i i think i sent in in money for
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		once
 		to uh to public uh TV
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i started getting calls from all sorts of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diseases</ENAMEX> and syndromes and everything you could imagine i it's like
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		and it just started soon after i had done that once and i just said this is this is terrible
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> and that's also happened to me where as i've given money to my old <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Alma Mater</ENAMEX> in college
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh it's one thing they don't sell the list but the thing that makes me mad is uh
 		then they start getting uh other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> do these phonathons and they call you up
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and they actually happen to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are graduated in your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> or something like that and they say oh we we know you you uh had uh contributed <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">X</NUMEX> amount <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> can you do better this year
 		and you know like hold on here who how do you know that why why you even telling me this
 	
 	
 		how do you know that
 	
 	
 		is it any of your business i mean it's one thing that i and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX> knows that that's just our business there's no need for someone who's soliciting should know it all
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		just uh and that was very offensive too
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lotus Development Company</ENAMEX> the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that puts out <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One Two Three</NUMEX> was planning on marketing a uh cd-rom
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peoples</ENAMEX> names sorted by
 		number of different criteria
 		
 		
 	