
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		the only experience i have i don't have any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> but i've um
 		i was a babysitter in high school and then just recently after we were married i babysat for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dentist</ENAMEX> while she worked and i just
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah that's the only thing i've ever done also is babysit but um i've heard <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that i work with talk about you know child care especially i guess it's even harder on single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		is it
 		oh yeah the expense
 	
 	
 		yeah having to pick up the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> by you know <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">six o'clock</TIMEX> or it's <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five dollars</NUMEX> for every <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minute</TIMEX> you're late and stuff like that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		which is understandable i mean these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> can't you know
 		stay there till <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">eight o'clock</TIMEX> because somebody has to work late but
 	
 	
 		just sit around
 		that's true see the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> i did it for that's why she picked picked me is because i would go to her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> so she wouldn't have to get her little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> up so she could sleep in
 		and um then she could be at home and then i'd bring her to my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a couple of hours</TIMEX> if i wanted too or whatever but um
 		she paid i think it was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two or three</NUMEX> it was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about two</NUMEX> fifty <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">three dollars</NUMEX> a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">hour</NUMEX> and by the time i paid taxes on it it i was getting like <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">eighty cents</ENAMEX> and that wasn't counting <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> or
 	
 	
 		oh no
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas</ENAMEX> or anything
 	
 	
 		yeah it's hardly worth your time
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah that's pretty bad the only time i babysat was in high school and it you know of course you don't have i didn't pay taxes on that so
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		it was easy you know go over to some um it was these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that lived in our neighborhood and
 		i'd just go over there <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> they went to the theater they had permanent tickets and they'd give me it was supposed to be <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">two dollars</NUMEX> an hour for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> but they would usually give me more like <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five dollars</NUMEX> more at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the end of the night</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh wow
 	
 	
 		and i mean they'd you know it was great i'd go over there and there would be like
 		uh you know there's we have these videos over here watch whatever you want and there's some <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Oreos in the in the cupboard</ENAMEX> and there's some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coke</ENAMEX> and you know just help yourself to anything so it was it was you know the best that was a long time ago and that was only for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years</TIMEX> just once a week
 	
 	
 		
 
 		wow
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but
 		i don't know
 	
 	
 		i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that treat their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby sitters</ENAMEX> like that get a lot better <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby sitters</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah that's true
 	
 	
 		and they stick around for longer because i mean after i figured out i was getting eighty <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">cents</NUMEX> an hour i said bag it and i quit you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i was just like but i'm wasting my time
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i really liked the little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> and everything but i thought
 	
 	
 		she does take up and they do take up a lot of your time that
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah i
 	
 	
 		they're very demanding
 	
 	
 		uh-huh  well and she was really spoiled they didn't make her eat anything she didn't want or anything so basically they fed her <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cookies</ENAMEX> for breakfast and lunch
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dentist</ENAMEX> and i was just like we've got to quit this  and she's like no i don't want her to starve but i don't want to make her eat something she doesn't want to eat
 	
 	
 		oh shoot my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> would be like
 	
 	
 		like
 		
 
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		eat this or
 	
 	
 		eat it or don't eat anything that's right
 	
 	
 		
 
 		so i can see the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX> on what different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> want because some i mean you know if i was setting up a day care there would be so many needs you would have to
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		customize your service to
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> won't put up with anything where others would
 	
 	
 		i think yeah i think the best way to go would just be to to be able to do it out of your basement
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and just have like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> at the most like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and all from maybe <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that you know type of thing instead of trying actually to set up a day care where you don't know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> coming in and
 	
 	
 		no
 		that's true i i'd love to do it but i just don't trust <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> now there's too many lawsuits
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i just i think it's a bigger risk than
 	
 	
 		more than what it's worth
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it would scare me with i don't know because i'm sure some of them have good reason to sue but i think a lot of them are just
 		you know they're negligent and they get happy about money and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		they just want to sue you
 	
 	
 		well yeah that's yeah exactly when you have like a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kindercare</ENAMEX> or something set up and they when they get greedy or whatever that's when they have maybe one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assistant</ENAMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">twenty</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> or something
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		and that's just you know you can't watch <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> that many little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> getting into things at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time
 	
 	
 		that's impossible
 	
 	
 		you know you never know what they're going to get into
 	
 	
 		i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX> that works at a day care and she takes her little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> with her and
 		i mean she told me <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about half</NUMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that they hire and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of them she'd like to turn them into the state
 		and that's the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are working there you know and then she would like to turn in half of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> that drop their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> off because of the condition the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are in you know
 	
 	
 		oh that's horrible
 	
 	
 		like they'll be in the same clothes they were <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> before the same diaper
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		you know just awful things and
 		so i don't know i don't have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> but i always think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> i just don't know if i could trust anybody
 	
 	
 		um
 		yeah that's the the yeah that's a hard thing about it if i mean
 	
 	
 		i mean you just don't know
 	
 	
 		i don't i can't foresee myself getting married but if you know if i ever wanted to have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> how could i work i mean i don't think i could trust somebody with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> either unless it was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> that you know did it in their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> that i knew well
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		that's true
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i just i couldn't do it i don't think
 	
 	
 		it would just rip me apart i think  i don't know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah just besides the fact that you know your when your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> gets out of school at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three o'clock</TIMEX> and then has to wait
 	
 	
 		not knowing
 		
 		
 	