
 
     		
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		
 
 		okay you go first
 	
 	
 		well i have um <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one seven</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one five</NUMEX> and um they're in a public school here in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tyler</ENAMEX> and um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i'm happy with it i'm happy with their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> it's great good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> good curriculum
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um they learn a lot they have no problems um but i do live in the better
 		and well in the best part of the city though i live in you know the real richy part i guess i'm not but everybody around me is and um but the i have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> that live in the other the
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		less fortunate or whatever you wanna call it part of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> and their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> are kind of rundown and
 		um older and they don't really
 		offer as much i don't know as uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> are in i don't really think that's fair you know um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but you know i'm happy with what they're in so
 		go ahead
 	
 	
 		well yeah it it's it's pretty much what i was  going to say is there's a lot of disparity between different neighborhoods and what sort of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> go in
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um i grew up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> and um the place or not <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> upstate <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		wow
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i went to uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City of Rochester School District</ENAMEX> and so a lot of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> were in one of the neighboring suburbs
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it wasn't we weren't too far removed geographically from each other but
 		the difference in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> i think was pretty substantial and uh one of the things that probably would have been better if is if the entire <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">county</ENAMEX> had had had just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> school system
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		and that would result in some um could result in more equitable distribution of money because what was happening was you know all the very rich <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> went out to the move out to the suburbs
 		and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> had a very low tax base so they didn't have a lot of money to work with
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		as a result the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> were rundown there wasn't as many you know the nice supplies in science class that we would have liked there wasn't as many advanced placement courses uh when i was a senior as some other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> had
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh it it so i you know i think that one of the things one of the ways to to to help <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> in general uh and get them all to a minimum level of
 		of of competency almost would be to expand the size of school districts so you get a wider variety of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and the the problem with that is then then then <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> will either the rich <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> will either pull their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> out of the public school and put them in private schools
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		or they'll move farther away  to get better <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> so you know it it's kind of you end up chasing like a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> chasing its own tail sort of
 	
 	
 		right
 		also um the the family environment
 		you know you can come to south <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tyler</ENAMEX> where i live and you have got room <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> in every room you've got art <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> you've got <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every every holiday</TIMEX> there's parties
 		all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> have these really supportive really supportive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> always up there for something you can go to north <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tyler</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> might not could even tell you what their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX>'s name is
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know um
 		that has a a whole lot to do with it you know as far as their learning i mean if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> aren't um
 		you know willing to go with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and find out what they're learning and if they're learning
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know they really don't have much of a chance at all and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		why is that
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		why is that
 	
 	
 		oh  why are you  you just they just don't i mean i mean i'm i'm up there at my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>'s school
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i know what they're learning and if they're up i call and find out you know is she having problems does she need help with anything no she's doing fine okay you know um
 		and i i know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> that their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> could really give a rip and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are not motivated
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 	
 	
 		they have no motivation from home so they just go to school and you know eh you know i'll get through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> and um bring homework home and there's nobody to to sit them down and say you're going to do this
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		um just you know they they take a notion to do it they do and um that doesn't work either you know they have to have guidance and um they can't just have it at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and then come home and there's nothing
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah  yeah i know that that that was a big factor for me i ended up coming out of of the public school system very well you know with very good education
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i ended up getting some scholarships to go to college and which has been you know which is really nice and i think the difference for me was that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> were
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know they were definitely they were always there was like well yeah of course you're going to study and do well i mean that's the way of course are you know
 		
 		
 	