
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i uh get a lot of my news driving <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> from work listening to All Things Considered on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Public Radio</ENAMEX> uh that is one of my big
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> for current events information
 		i i really like that coverage my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> uh on the other hand is home most of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> and she watches a lot of the cable news network
 		have you seen uh
 		have have you uh
 		ever heard of All Things Considered
 	
 	
 		no we don't have the uh national public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">radio</ENAMEX> in in my area i can hear it at the um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh oh the college <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> nearby when i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stillwater</ENAMEX> which is <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about an hour</NUMEX> away but the FM signal doesn't reach this far
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh i listen to shortwave quite a bit it gives you a whole different perspective on the news uh when you hear it from say a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> point of view or from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> of origin
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh i agree with you too on the um
 		uh the cable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Headline News</ENAMEX>
 		um i'm not too satisfied with our local newspaper uh which is why i rely on shortwave and and then the cable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		i'm uh interested in the in the shortwave aspect of it uh how do you find that the the coverage from other places in the world
 		uh compares with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> coverage of
 		how do you think that uh
 		the viewpoints differ
 	
 	
 		i think a lot of it is just um the fact that in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> you're so far removed uh in a lot of cases from say conflicts or
 		or it's not happening in your backyard so it's it's more of a
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's not as a personal uh the news isn't as personal in what we receive domestically than than what's on the shortwave it's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BBC</ENAMEX> is um
 		oh i don't know the right word is is almost um
 		they almost take all emotions out of it when they report it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it just they seem to give more just the facts than opinions
 	
 	
 		do you think then that uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> is presenting an opinion along with their facts
 	
 	
 		uh very much so very much so and i i think a lot of it is um
 		especially TV news
 		they don't really have the time and a lot of them don't have the education and the background to um
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		oh to really decipher the news and to really explain it i mean i you know i think it's important to interpret it but a lot of times the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> doesn't have the experience to to do the interpreting
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		which uh
 		which approach do you find to be um more useful the the interpretive approach or the straight reporting
 	
 	
 		oh i like the straight reporting um and then i i hope to be able to form my own opinion of it it's it's nice to hear someone's interpretation of it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um i always think it's humorous when when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> gives the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State of the Union</ENAMEX> and uh for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX> and then for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an hour and a half</TIMEX> you hear different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentators</ENAMEX> explaining what you just heard
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and a lot of times i don't hear exactly what they what they write into it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so i overall i think i would rather hear just straight reporting
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the things that i found interesting <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> during the uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gulf</ENAMEX> conflict
 		was a sentiment against uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Arnett</ENAMEX> who had stayed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> and was
 		presenting uh some of the things that were available uh there was a
 		there was uh a piece where he was showing a bombed out
 		building where there was obviously a crudely uh a hastily erected sign saying baby <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factory</ENAMEX> and while he was
 		being severely uh censored and could not make any judgment call on this it was fairly obvious that it was a piece of propaganda but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were really down on him
 		for reporting the fact that this you know this isn't a baby milk factory how could he say it was uh and i think that that to me showed that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> were really getting used to having
 		the not just the facts but also the conclusions and opinions spoon fed to them
 	
 	
 		yeah i i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have that opinion they they wanna sit down in front of the TV and um or at a read a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> and read in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> paragraphs
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh and</ENAMEX> and find out every
 		
 		
 	