
 
     		
 	
 		yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan</ENAMEX> uh you you say you say it's near and dear to your heart buying a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> is uh something you're contemplating i take it
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> fantasizing about can't do it right now our situation is that we're a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> car family
 	
 	
 		ah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mini van</ENAMEX> we bought <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years ago</TIMEX> it's got a uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five year</TIMEX> loan so that's still got <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple years</TIMEX> to run
 	
 	
 		uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and the car i get to drive is a uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nissan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Sentra</ENAMEX> that's gonna be <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years old next month</TIMEX> so
 	
 	
 		wow  you get
 	
 	
 		i think about uh sprucing that up in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple years</TIMEX> when i can
 	
 	
 		uh-huh what do you think you'll uh what kind of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> do you think you'll buy next
 	
 	
 		well  since i just turned forty i'm thinking about a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">forty year</TIMEX> old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>'s something uh something real sporty but uh realistically with uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the need to take the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> to school probably have to have something that uh wouldn't wind up putting their knees in their throat when they sat in the backseat something a little seating room
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		how about you
 	
 	
 		well i think the next <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> we get will probably be a  well i i like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buicks</ENAMEX> we have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buick Century</ENAMEX> now it's a nineteen <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty seven</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh whatever i get i wanna have uh air bags uh both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX>'s and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passenger side</ENAMEX> and a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> door because
 		it's much more convenient if you're carrying anybody to you know rather than have them stoop down to get over so i think the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> door is probably a major requirement and other than that uh you know reasonable cost and
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		safety and uh as much economy as you can get out of a car
 		uh
 		you know i'm not looking for one with a great big engine uh something that'll carry it around safely i guess is best best way to describe it
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		right now we've got a V-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> in it and that seems to be just fine i know they said they're coming out with some <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">V-8s</ENAMEX> now and i think that's probably a little overkill for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this day</TIMEX> and age
 	
 	
 		yeah i'm surprised to hear that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">V-8s</ENAMEX> are coming back uh they've got some pretty powerful 6s
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">V-8s</ENAMEX> seem to be a return of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the days</TIMEX> of you know <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">twelve miles</NUMEX> a gallon
 	
 	
 		right
 		i uh i drive a a truck a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX> truck i i like <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trucks</ENAMEX> because they're spacious and
 		it's handy to haul things uh it's not related to my business i just you really use it basically for transportation but there's so many occasions when i've had to
 		move some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> or do this or that it's it's handy to have a truck and not have to borrow one
 	
 	
 		sure
 		is uh traction much of an issue for you up there terms of
 	
 	
 		traction uh not really um you know it's a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> wheel drive truck and i figure if it's so bad that i need a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> wheel drive i probably ought to be home anyway
 	
 	
 		actually uh pretty good way of looking at it yeah we uh we had a small accident with our <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mini van</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		wow
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years ago</TIMEX> a case where there was a sort of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">freak ice</ENAMEX> storm and we weren't aware of it and just slipped on some black <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX> and went into another car and
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		this is a rear wheel drive model so we got some monster studded snow tires after that haven't had any problem since
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		what kind of what make is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mini van</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mazda</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mazda</ENAMEX> i see
 	
 	
 		and uh we're pleased with it in terms of comfort and uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">driveability</ENAMEX> fuel economy isn't great being a minivan but uh it's real nice for carrying around our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and others and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		it's uh got some nice features in terms of being able to remove seats and flip them around so we've been able to do some real creative uh load hauling when called upon
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX> has a a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plymouth</ENAMEX> uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">van</ENAMEX> or you know uh uh that same type of thing the Voyager i guess
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		and uh they have a a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> that's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years old</TIMEX> and it's really handy for hauling him around and and their stuff and of course as he gets <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> i'm sure that'll
 		be even handier so i know if we were if we had <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> still at home we're in our fifties now but if we had <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> still at home we'd certainly have to seriously consider a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">van</ENAMEX> just for their functional value
 	
 	
 		yeah i think that we're gonna be uh owning a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mini van</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">some years</TIMEX> to come probably till the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are out of uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">high school</ENAMEX> anyway
 	
 	
 		uh what about uh all wheel drive is that something that you'd be interested in or is that a not an issue
 	
 	
 		uh  i'd be satisfied with a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a good</TIMEX> front wheel drive <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> when it comes time to replace the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Sentra</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and even as <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">as light as</NUMEX> that is with uh the small tires it's it's done pretty well in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX> uh again like you if conditions are are that bad i probably don't wanna be driving anyway
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		so i know i'd be happy with a a reasonable uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> door you know again we've we've got the same issue with getting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> into the
 		
 		
 	