
 
     		
 	
 		well uh does the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> you work for test for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		actually um they just recently started a policy of testing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> which was kind of interesting because when when i went to work for them um they didn't do that but uh since then they've they've started a
 		drug testing policy not because of their own um convictions but because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> of our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> are requesting that we do that
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		how about you
 	
 	
 		uh no we're not being tested for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> at all uh
 		our policies and procedures manual uh the furthest it goes about <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> is in the kind of the miscellaneous section or it's reasons for immediate dismissal it says use of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">narcotics</ENAMEX> on company premises
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		hum
 	
 	
 		so  that's pretty general but um i work for an environmental management <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>  and i'm an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineer</ENAMEX> there but i do go on a lot of hazardous waste <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> but i don't operate any machinery
 	
 	
 		okay
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		now <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> for our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that do operate machinery like drill <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rigs</ENAMEX> and things like  that are under a a medical monitoring program because they're
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		at a higher risk of exposure and blood screening is part of that and i i think that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> they do test for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> in that capacity but it's not their exclusive it's just part it's just something that turns up in the other parameters that they test for
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but i think it's got a little more relevance since they are around dangerous equipment and things like that and do have to exercise some quick judgment in the field what is the nature of your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s business
 	
 	
 		well it's actually uh we do oil well services so a lot of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> are oil <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> big oil <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> and they go out to
 		we have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineers</ENAMEX> who uh go out to the oil <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">well</ENAMEX>  to the to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">client</ENAMEX>'s oil <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">well</ENAMEX> and and work with a lot of heavy equipment and put tools down the oil <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">well</ENAMEX> and stuff so the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> are very concerned that
 		you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineers</ENAMEX> who go out there are adhering to their drug policy because they're on their their you know territory and everything but
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		the thing that's interesting is that i work i'm an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineer</ENAMEX> and a software <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineer</ENAMEX> and i work in the software uh <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and everybody there you know are all software <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineers</ENAMEX> they've never you know they never go out to the the oil <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rigs</ENAMEX> or anything and
 		yet we're getting we're subjected to this policy you know the same one that uh the all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineers</ENAMEX> have to to well a little different actually but um you know we have to go through the same thing and it's
 		but it's uh it's a little different i guess than than a lot of drug policies in our case it's like when you hire on they'll test you and then if you get injured on the job if you like trip and fall or something uh they give you a drug test right away
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		other than that they don't have random testing or anything like that but a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were really upset with the policy at first particularly like um we have a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> and stuff where they serve <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> and that they didn't find any problem with that you know but
 	
 	
 		right  we that's been an a an issue uh
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		in our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> even though we don't have the random or even regular drug screening in fact they'll  have these little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> will just get i mean i've my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> lives near where i work and i have many a time called him to come get me you know and um
 		uh but you you know they don't think twice about serving
 		beer by the keg you know but um i think drug testing and i i don't know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i guess i can i think it's got some relevance but i think its relevance is pretty limited i mean i think you know in your case i don't think that
 		you should necessarily be subjected to drug testing i think that's an interesting policy your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> has about testing immediately after an on the job accident
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah it's really it's really bizarre
 		uh particularly like where we are you know i there was a story of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> who who actually did slip on the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX> and and like sprained her ankle and she she was a personnel <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> and she  had to get tested
 		and i don't know i'm ambivalent about the whole thing i you know i have a lot of mixed feelings about on the one hand it's like if
 		you know they're they should be able to make it as a condition of employment in some sense and you know it's like you're i mean employments are contractual by nature anyway
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but um
 		i had an experience when i was interviewing for a job that where i had to um uh do a drug test and and it's it was kind of a long story but it was it was just an incredibly humiliating experience what i went through and it amounted to
 		um going in uh before any of these interviews i'm not even working for this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> i'm going in for like interviews and they flew me out to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> and and uh before i went in to any of the interviews uh they took me to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> to give me a physical they said it was going to be a physical you know
 		and um actually because beforehand they told me they were going to uh do drug screening
 		but i had forgotten about that and so basically i'd already peed off in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">that morning</TIMEX> and
 		and when i got in there i didn't i wasn't like able to give a full sample and so they made me sit and wait for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">forty five minutes</TIMEX> drink a whole ton of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> before  i went to any of the interviews
 	
 	
 		oh
 		right
 	
 	
 		and go in there again and the and the the procedure is utterly humiliating you go in there with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> he makes you take off all your clothes and then he examines you
 		
 		
 	