
 
     		
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX> uh with the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">election year</TIMEX> and whatnot coming up do you think we ought to cut taxes raise them or or or what do you think
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well that's  that's a really hard question i do know that uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> always talking out of both sides of their mouths um
 		i let's example uh our our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> right now says no new taxes we should and especially if anything be cutting taxes now because of the recession and at the same time the budget he sent to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> has
 		tax and fee increases so uh i know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> uh aren't aren't straightforward now in in terms of economics i'm not it's hard hard to call it really is
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		see i never thought really it's uh
 		i never really thought that that the the question really had to do whether or not we're paying too much or too little i i always that the the real question was is are we getting a reasonable return on on investment
 		for instance like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> tax or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social</ENAMEX> uh i mean that's that's tax we're paying money and and supposedly this money is going into some kind of fund so that when it comes our turn to retire the money will be there for us
 	
 	
 		hm right
 	
 	
 		that's yeah you know when i when i see that money taken out of my paycheck each <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each week</TIMEX> i or each every other week i i really think that money's history
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and you know so as far as return investment that's not that's nothing and we're not even going to get the exact same number of dollars back
 	
 	
 		yes uh
 	
 	
 		uh someone was telling me that there is a uh uh there's still an office in uh you know staffed with with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> there and in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX> that are researching to find a cure for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">polio</ENAMEX>
 		which i may be wrong but i believe that the cure for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">polio</ENAMEX> is already founded but but supposedly once you have an office in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX> or you know and and staff it with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> it's really tough to close it down and and they just haven't yet
 	
 	
 		well yeah i'm not exactly sure uh about <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">polio</ENAMEX> in particular i know we have a <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">polio</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vaccine</ENAMEX> which will prevent somebody from getting polio i'm not sure if we know what to do in terms of curing some who has already gotten polio
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well that might be the difference i don't know uh the other thing that uh i remember seeing on TV lately is uh had to do with
 		it's like seventy <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">five percent</NUMEX> of the historical <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> are in the home districts of very powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> politically
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		that that historical for some reason historical <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> with you know the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the full</TIMEX> federal money and everything
 		seem to appear as as almost as like political favors to to very strong politicians
 	
 	
 		yeah it's it's it's funny because uh it was one of the things that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> is been trying really hard to get ahold of is the line item veto where uh you know <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> is able to attach all kinds of
 		uh funny amendments for individual uh congressional congressional districts to the to the main budget proposals and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> has has to uh either accept or reject the whole thing
 	
 	
 		so it sounds like you uh you think that that we'd be able to save some money by uh passing the line item veto
 	
 	
 		uh
 		i i think the line item veto is not not is not necessarily a bad thing assuming that the uh
 		the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> uh uses it to get rid of uh this kind of waste on the other hand uh
 		uh it it assumes that you have lots of confidence in your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> not to veto important things
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		right and just to get rid of the unimportant things and whenever there's that kind of subjective judgment
 		there's always going to be a dispute as to uh where the exactly where the boundary between waste and and necessity is
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so i'm not i'm not sure that that that will help solve our problems but there definitely is is a problem with uh i forgot there's a political term for this stuff pork barrel or something
 	
 	
 		yeah pork barrel politics
 	
 	
 		uh pork barrel politics there there there has to be some way to do it i know state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governors</ENAMEX> usually have line item vetos and uh
 		well i i lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX> for a while and uh when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dukakis</ENAMEX> vetoed certain things there was a big uproar and wasn't necessarily so popular
 	
 	
 		yeah but <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX> wasn't when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dukakis</ENAMEX> was there anyway wasn't in that great shape financially
 	
 	
 		but at least at the end
 	
 	
 		uh-huh i mean i don't know i
 	
 	
 		yeah i i they were very good at <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> they were in very good financials at <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> and uh that's part of the reason he became a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominee</ENAMEX> is because things went so well and then of course the bottom fell out
 	
 	
 		
 
 		it's uh i mean it's it's tough i mean there's there's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> ways you can kind of go to get out of tough financial situations i guess you can like raise taxes and then create like job programs and whatnot
 		or you can hope that if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> keep their money that they'll spend more and create jobs and and whatnot
 	
 	
 		and spare the economy yeah it's really it's a hard balance it it definitely is even not for government even just say for a small business um i know some
 		
 		
 	