
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX> uh what are the capital punishment laws down in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they have the electric chair i believe remember <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Bundy</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh that's right
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">couple years ago</TIMEX> they were all down there saying fry him
 	
 	
 		oh so the laws are still intact then
 	
 	
 		oh yeah they yeah they use that all the time well not all the time is
 		you know it it it's always backlogged it usually takes a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> usually a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> sits on death row for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three or four years</TIMEX> at least before they put him you know in the actual actual electric chair
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		and i imagine that costs a small bundle too
 	
 	
 		yeah he always gets all these appeals and everything
 	
 	
 		go through the court process
 	
 	
 		he gets all these appeals and everything uh as far as it being a deterrent to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i don't think it's a deterrent a deterrent
 		uh i think it's i think it's more for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> more than anything the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> probably get some justification out of it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh as far as it deterring anybody from committing murder or something like that i don't think it really does
 	
 	
 		no but i think it does serve a valuable purpose in the sense that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> get some sort of satisfaction the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> doesn't pay for the burden of having a
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> can
 	
 	
 		a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoner</ENAMEX> in jail for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's right
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		you know and having to supply them with a color TV and
 		um books and education so forth
 	
 	
 		right i mean what is it how much is it a year to keep a prisoner it's like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty thousand a year</TIMEX> to food and clothe a prisoner
 		some ridiculous price
 	
 	
 		and i imagine it probably costs
 		a great deal amount of money to to even go through the process of trying to electrocute someone
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> proceum i mean it tying up <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX>'s time uh times the court system
 	
 	
 		yeah i don't know how many appeals <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Bundy</ENAMEX> had
 		uh they just keep appealing it and appealing it to the next higher next higher you know just keeps they keep going higher and higher up
 		and uh
 		you know it does take a long time it takes money of course to do that so and it's a public <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defender</ENAMEX> most of the time so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well how do you feel about that do you
 		are you in favor of capital punishment as a
 	
 	
 		yeah yes i am i am in favor of it but as far as it being an actual deterrent to crime i don't think it is like i said it's mostly for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> benefit i think or the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh the you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>
 		do you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> have it up there where where'd you say you were from
 	
 	
 		yeah i'm from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Hampshire</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">okay New Hampshire</ENAMEX> they have it up there
 	
 	
 		yeah as far as i remember we don't have it um
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		i know there hasn't been anyone executed up here probably in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about thirty forty years</TIMEX> which is ironic because we come from very conservative state
 		uh very strong on on punishment and crime
 		um it uh during <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> thing we don't really have that that much crime up here when we do have a celebrated case like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pamela</ENAMEX> Smart i don't know if you heard about that
 	
 	
 		that's the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">schoolteacher</ENAMEX> one
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		i saw the movie about that
 	
 	
 		yeah that's a case where um she's probably guilty
 		i don't think there's enough evidence there to convict her i mean to uh
 		execute her
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i think if because once you execute someone the the the decision the decision is final you can't really reverse the process um
 	
 	
 		well that is the bad thing about it and i'm i'm sure that back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the old days</TIMEX> they
 		they put to death a couple innocent ones during the process but they're but they're uh opinion was well if you got few few innocent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have to die to protect the majority then that's okay you know i don't i don't necessarily agree with that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah i don't agree with that either i think if you
 		kill someone who's innocent that's uh
 	
 	
 		it screwed up the whole thing in my opinion yeah i agree with you there
 	
 	
 		somebody you can't even live with if they
 		you you really need to you know case where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Hinkley</ENAMEX> tried to assassinate the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> uh
 	
 	
 		that's pretty obvious that's open and shut isn't it
 	
 	
 		right and if he had succeeded uh uh without a doubt he should be executed executed
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		uh whether he's insane or not
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		same thing with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dahlmer</ENAMEX> i mean he killed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seventeen</NUMEX> people
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh it's it's a shame that we're gonna have to pay for him
 	
 	
 		now
 		in his case now is that that's <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota</ENAMEX> right
 	
 	
 		what's that
 	
 	
 		is that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i think  uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michigan</ENAMEX> or somewhere somewhere around there
 	
 	
 		or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wisconsin</ENAMEX> or ah maybe it's <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wisconsin</ENAMEX>
 		yeah they they might have capital punishment the thing with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like that they like to take and study them put them in jail and do studies on them like that so that's they can try to get a profile of his personality i think
 		you know and
 		i guess in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> where they don't have capital punishment that's the kind of stuff they do but i think in his case they will put him to death because all the all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> you know all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> and stuff aren't going to tolerate it
 	
 	
 		yeah but i thought he he received his sentence um
 		remember maybe what the what the final turnout was
 	
 	
 		what is the final uh is he still going to trial for that
 	
 	
 		i thought he went to rehabilitation rehabilitation mean they they were going to put him in
 		rehabilitation for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years</TIMEX> then <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> for the rest of his life
 	
 	
 		that's right because he's definitely insane i think they proved that he was insane and maybe that's
 		maybe that was uh what got him off or made him uh not get the death penalty because they can prove that he's insane then i i don't think you get the death penalty
 		but the the but the uh prosecution was trying to uh
 		say that he was sane when he committed them so they could but they they were going for the death penalty i think that's what they were trying to uh i mean the they knew he did it that he was guilty it was just a matter of was he going to get the death penalty or life in prison
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah i think the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> wanted him to get death
 	
 	
 		yeah i think that's a a case where there really needs to be some change in the laws to allow for flexibility i think if <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> kills another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> out of
 		
 		
 	