
 
     		
 	
 		do you feel about the issue of uh random or spot drug testing
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well i'm i'm for it based upon my experience uh in taking
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> tests my uh my past experience in the military
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		plus uh my current <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">occupation</ENAMEX> working uh for a defense <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contractor</ENAMEX> here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX>
 		uh i feel that it's uh
 		there is some opinions whereas the uh uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of the mind that uh it's a right to privacy that
 		you know it's a it's a bodily function involved and that um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">um people</ENAMEX> should have a right to protect themselves and so forth but i don't agree i think that
 		um it's important particularly for some jobs and some jog occupations job occupations
 		that um <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> can be screened for uh should be screens for uh for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> through uh drug testing
 	
 	
 		yeah i i tend to believe that that it's it's important for those jobs where uh
 		where the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> has the safety of other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> uh in their own hands or within their control then i think it should be mandatory
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know the the airline industry the transportation industry um you know the uh
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		the defense and military you know any any application like that i think it should be mandatory
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		so i think we're in agreement that that uh uh that it's a good uh it's a good idea in some circumstances the one reservation i have though in that from my experience i've taken many urinalysis many drug tests
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		some of them random some of them um scheduled
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and every time you take one of those tests you know when you're submitting a sample
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		there's always in the back of your mind well how are you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> conducting the test
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">labs</ENAMEX> that are performing the test how adequate uh are those <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> and uh is is always it is it always a chance i know that what they call um the i think it's called the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX> of custody
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		of the uh the specimens themselves i know in the military in the military particularly they there's a they go to great lengths at protecting the samples before they get to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">labs</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		but my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> is and i think that that that what needs to be further investigated
 		is the uh the standardization and to have some <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundred</NUMEX> percent insurance that the test that's given
 		uh the the the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lab</ENAMEX> that performs the uh the analysis is uh validated in some way you know some standardization because i've heard some horror stories
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know
 	
 	
 		yeah you you you know you can easily envision the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one one</NUMEX> mistake could you know ruin a a career that couldn't be uh you know couldn't be resurrected
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Sixty</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Minutes</ENAMEX> did an article on this whole subject subject a few uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years ago</TIMEX> and there was a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force Captain</ENAMEX>
 		who uh you know took the test and it came up positive  and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> swore on a stack of bibles
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		now in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX> for a for a staff <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> NCO which is a a noncommissioned <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> but it's a certain rank above i don't know if you're familiar with military military rank structure
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		it's a it's a high level of enlisted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> for those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who show up positive on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> drug test they're immediately discharged
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		now for certain ranks and below like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sergeant</ENAMEX> and below if you're found positive or come up dirty in a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> on a on a drug test
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you can be reduced in rank forfeit your pay or if it's a repeat repeat offense uh offense
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		then they can discharge you
 		but there's this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> this this
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Captain</ENAMEX> he swore up and down that he didn't do anything
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		
 
 		and they went back and you know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">few months later</TIMEX> to try to investigate the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lab</ENAMEX> and the sample that he had given was destroyed
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right
 	
 	
 		so i i think you got to be careful with stuff like that that's that's my only concern about the whole issue i think
 	
 	
 		huh
 		yeah definitely
 		yeah i don't really feel like you know for any any of the
 		just routine jobs that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> should be subject to that kind of invasion of privacy
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um
 		only for the only for the ones where it's critical
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		uh yeah because there's a big thing in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">in the in the</TIMEX> here on the east coast the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Police Department</ENAMEX> uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Policemen's Association</ENAMEX>
 		took the uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Police Department</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> because they were uh trying to institute drug tests for the cops here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 	
 	
 		and um they won the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Police Department</ENAMEX> the the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Police Association</ENAMEX> won
 		
 
 		and it it was a right to privacy type deal that they approached it and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> agreed
 	
 	
 		yeah i i guess i would feel that the you know police
 		
 
 		uh that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> should be one of those public uh safety issues where you know mandatory drug testing where it would be favorable
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh yeah
 		definitely well you know the thing is is in all these transportation accidents this
 	
 	
 		uh
 		
 		
 	