
 
     		
 	
 		so what do you think
 	
 	
 		okay
 		well that's a pretty loaded topic  well here in um
 	
 	
 		absolutely
 	
 	
 		hang on just a second the dog is barking
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX> we just went through a uh major educational reform we're uh that was a hot topic
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh part of the problem had been there wasn't enough spent on education the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classes</ENAMEX> were too large
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and we recently well we're we're through a proposition now where they're limiting class size to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about twenty two</NUMEX> i think and they've increased salaries and just done a major revision
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah are your um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> paid for primarily with your real estate tax
 	
 	
 		yes yeah it's just about all
 	
 	
 		yeah what for a typical middle class house uh what kind of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> tax do you pay
 	
 	
 		oh well actually the actually it isn't just  i i said yes and it really isn't we
 	
 	
 		well i know it's split federal and so forth
 	
 	
 		we also well no we have a uh an excise tax on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> our <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> tags are very expensive average taxes are very low on real estate probably in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">six hundred dollar</NUMEX> a year range
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		they are
 		oh okay okay because um over here
 		um you could pay <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">between four and eight thousand dollars</NUMEX> a year
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and um
 		i'd be surprised if we're getting something that was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> times as good as what you're getting
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		matter of fact i'll bet it's not as good
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		um my feeling is that
 		there you know while there are certain problems where
 		you know being able to buy a new set of books or a new piece of equipment may be valuable by and large that correlation between the amount of money you shovel in and the quality of education doesn't seem to be that strong
 	
 	
 		yeah i i do have to tend to agree with you the only other problem with that is that it's difficult to attract <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> into the teaching profession
 	
 	
 		well again i don't know what it's like on your side of the fence um over here
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		um <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX>' salaries aren't bad uh they're not executive type salaries although if you're a
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> whose been at it for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fifteen</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years</TIMEX> uh you can retire  when you when you reach the top level it's not bad at all it's quite good
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah i think that's that's the other thing here the benefits are  very good for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> where
 	
 	
 		um
 		yeah
 		thing is there are nonfinancial there there should be nonfinancial benefits to teaching that i think we've managed to squash out of the system
 		um it used to be <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty years ago</TIMEX> being a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> was a uh position of respect you were educating the young
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		um now it seems that you know now the the joke of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> is you know those who can't teach
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and um you know so something went wrong somewhere along the line and i think it's felt both by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the educational profession and those outside
 		there's a wonderful book by a fellow named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Murray</ENAMEX>
 		called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">In Pursuit of Happiness</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and he discusses what he feels is wrong with the educational system
 		and um
 		he even offers some suggestions for improvements uh one of the points he makes is he feels that any attempt to fix the problems
 		uh whatever the nature of the reform is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> of the reform will be captured by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX> and rendered ineffective
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		in other words if you decide that you're gonna pump another <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> percent money in it'll right eventually filter down it filters it's way around to the most firmly entrenched <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> with no regard to their skill level um if you provide other benefits
 		they'll eventually work their way around to more firmly entrench the problems not to resolve them
 		i'm not sure i agree with him completely but he makes some interesting points
 	
 	
 		yeah that does i i think though you hit the the nail on the head  when you when you said it's the attitude more than anything of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> profession the teaching profession um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and that that's something you really can't change even with money
 	
 	
 		well it did change the thing to do is find out uh why um because uh
 		you know there was a time when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> was a respected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> and something changed um and intrinsically intrinsically the ideas you know um training our
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> to be uh mature productive responsible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> is potentially a uh
 		a very um what's the right word
 		um it's potentially a very rewarding not rewarding but uh it should be a respected profession so the question about asking is not why does no  why isn't it but well it should be what's preventing it from being respected
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right
 		right it's a it's a pretty big responsibility i mean to to teach
 	
 	
 		now
 		absolutely absolutely i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> who substitute teaches and um she brings home some interesting stories uh but the thing that you know i i hate falling into the trap of back when i was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh i'm just saying that but the thing that changed is
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um
 		back when i was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> you know maybe hated the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> maybe you didn't do your work but you respected or at least feared the teacher
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	