
 
     		
 	
 		your turn
 	
 	
 		
 
 		okay uh i don't think they should abolish it
 		i think it's i think if they put it into force more often they wouldn't have as many problems as they've got
 	
 	
 		but not for petty theft
 	
 	
 		right no no for major things like
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">premeditated</ENAMEX> murder mass murders uh you know that type of thing i don't think it should just be used
 		loosely
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well it should be used as a deterrent do you think
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well
 	
 	
 		or should it be used uh as to prevent further uh crime like
 	
 	
 		yes yeah prevent these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from ever getting out on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> by you know some technicality and they go down the line <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years</TIMEX> and then on some little technicality they get out and they're on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> again doing the same they they did before
 	
 	
 		hm
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and you know you know that's about the only thing and like for petty for theft and and stuff like that or manslaughter you know i don't think they should do that
 	
 	
 		well you know there's this old um <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> is it saying about an eye for an eye and a tooth for a tooth
 	
 	
 		oh well well i guess if i if it was someone in my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> i'd probably feel that way
 		you know i've never had anybody in my immediate family uh murdered and so i really wouldn't know but but i feel like if i did i probably would feel that way
 	
 	
 		uh one of the things i was thinking about is uh you know from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">society</ENAMEX>'s point of view if you put a value on each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> what you want to do is to maximize the end game value
 		so if you have someone that that destroys that value
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh then what you want to take steps to uh minimize the loss of course you have to also put value on the criminal
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		so if you terminate him that's a loss of value
 		so you know if you weight everyone equally
 	
 	
 		well that's true
 	
 	
 		then you have to say well the likelihood of not terminating him if if you don't terminate him the likelihood is expected value of loss of life is greater than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> in other words you'd have to you'd have to murder <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than one</NUMEX> other person
 	
 	
 		besides him
 	
 	
 		uh in order to justify taking his life
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		another way you could do it is weight this value by uh the value to society of the people
 		uh which is pretty uh
 		delicate thing to do but one way of doing it is uh by income
 		so  if this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> doesn't make a great deal of money which is often times the case then
 	
 	
 		
 
 		his life isn't worth very much then
 	
 	
 		then he's obviously not worth very much and so uh the likelihood that you know maybe expected expected murders by him is is um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">integrated</ENAMEX> over the income of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> uh that he murders is maybe you know a loss of
 		who knows <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">eight hundred thousand dollars</NUMEX>
 		uh but if he only uh integrated you know integrated income over the expected expected remainder of his life is um
 		small less than <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">eight hundred thousand dollars</NUMEX> then you terminate him of course one of the things that happens if you use that algorithm is you find that it's more easy it's easier to uh to uh
 		uh terminate older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> than younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> since the uh uh integration of their income over the rest of their lives is going to be less
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		which means well i suppose you could say well that has something to do with potential for rehabilitation
 	
 	
 		potential
 		i mean that's the that's the key right there potential
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		now are they are they rehabilitative or or not
 		huh
 	
 	
 		now that's all fine and well and and uh good philosophically but if you're involved yourself personally
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh i know i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> whose
 		uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> was murdered
 		on on <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night</TIMEX> before his sixteenth birthday
 		and let me tell you uh i i knew them personally uh not intimately but quite well and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you're talking about real trauma i mean trauma that extends beyond the counting of bodies
 	
 	
 		i can imagine
 	
 	
 		uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> you know of of course
 		um a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> losing a teenage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> is about as bad as it could possibly get i think in terms of psychological impact
 	
 	
 		yes yeah
 	
 	
 		um
 		
 
 	
 	
 		was he murdered did they find out who killed him
 	
 	
 		and
 		oh yes they found him and he is on trial for capital murder
 	
 	
 		hm
 		so it hasn't been a long time ago just recently
 	
 	
 		uh well actually he i'm i'm sorry he uh was convicted uh and of course now you know and you go through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two or three hundred years</TIMEX> of appeals process but
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 		yeah that appeals process i mean it's what you know really
 		you know just drags out and out and out my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother-in-law</ENAMEX> here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 		his by marriage my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband husband</ENAMEX>
 		his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> was murdered down here by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> in in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">well</ENAMEX> actually in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX>
 		and uh he would
 		
 		
 	