
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay
 		so
 	
 	
 		i guess
 	
 	
 		what kind of experience do you do you have then with child care
 	
 	
 		i think um
 		i wonder if that worked
 	
 	
 		does it say something
 	
 	
 		i think it usually does you might try um
 		i don't know hold it down a little longer
 	
 	
 		okay
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well
 	
 	
 		okay i
 	
 	
 		does it usually make a recording or something
 	
 	
 		well i don't remember it seemed like it did but it might not i guess i guess
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		we can start um
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		no i don't i don't have any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> i um my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> has a she just had a baby he's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about five months old</TIMEX> and she was
 		worrying about going back to work and what she was gonna do with him and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the different do you have kids
 	
 	
 		i have three
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yeah i do
 		yes um i don't work though but i used to work and when i had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i work off and on just temporarily and usually find <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> to babysit but
 		i don't envy anybody who's in that situation to find day care
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but does your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> live in a big community
 	
 	
 		um yeah she lives it's a it's a fairly large <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> she um got real lucky though she had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> who um moved into a larger office
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and she's able to take her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> to work with her
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		and it's a small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> that she works in
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and um
 		it's a it's a legal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm office</ENAMEX> and it's just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> and so she's the only one really that takes care of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> there's no one else that works there
 	
 	
 		um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so they have an extra <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> and everything for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> so it works out pretty good for her
 	
 	
 		wow
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		how lucky
 		i i know a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> around here sometimes have like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmothers</ENAMEX> that take care of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> i'm in is not a real large one so there are a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who babysit in their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> that you know you either know them or know somebody who knows them  to get
 	
 	
 		yeah so it's fairly safe
 	
 	
 		to yeah to get references and that so
 		but um
 		i i don't
 		don't feel comfortable about leaving my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> in a big day care <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> but
 		simply because there's so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and so many
 		
 
 	
 	
 		worried that they're not going to get enough attention
 	
 	
 		yeah and um you know colds and things like that get spread real easy and things but and they're expensive and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		course there's a lot of different types of day care available too you know where they teach them academic things
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		or they just watch them and let them play and things like that but
 		take a long time to find the right place
 	
 	
 		yeah and you and you don't always even know if it's it's
 		gonna be the right place or not
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		anything i guess could happen
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because after
 		i guess after he you know gets to a certain age she's going to have to take him to a day care
 	
 	
 		um-hum when he starts toddling around and stuff yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah when when he's not when she can't
 		keep control of him and he starts crawling that's
 	
 	
 		um-hum it would be hard i think it would be kind of stressful it would be nice to have him around
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but um seems like you know golly what if he cried at the wrong time or the phone rang or
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		you know at the wrong time  but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i think she has problems with that too
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well when you have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> will you work
 		do you work now
 	
 	
 		i don't know that's something i've considered um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i always kind of think it would be neat to
 		be able to watch them and be there for them all the time
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		is that what you do
 	
 	
 		um yeah uh actually i teach my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> at home
 		so i'm here all the time
 	
 	
 		oh so they don't go to school is it like um
 		oh what's that called it's a
 		correspondence school they do it at home
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		that's interesting do you have to have any special training
 	
 	
 		so
 		not it depends on the state you live actually some laws
 		absolutely prohibit it some <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states um</ENAMEX> say that you have to be a certified <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> in order to do that our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> doesn't yet
 		
 
 		say that and i'm not a certified <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> i went to college but i
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know but my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are only elementary grades levels right now
 		and so
 	
 	
 		so they haven't been to public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> at all
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of them was for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of years</TIMEX>
 		and so you know my oldest
 		he was and then my youngest <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> have never been
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		so
 		anyway but we don't
 	
 	
 		so you've never had
 		
 		
 	