
 
     		
 	
 		huh um do y'all have a budget
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">okay</ENAMEX> thanks
 		well um  yeah we we do um we've been married for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty three years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and we have um <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> teenage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX> and you know they're very expensive so um  uh we yeah we have somewhat of of a system um
 		it's it's kind of um
 		you know it's it's kind of hard to explain we've actually gone uh just recently to you know having having <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> checking accounts we always had just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and now we're having two
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um it's kind of hard to talk about this because to me it's very personal
 	
 	
 		yeah it's um
 	
 	
 		so i have to be that's that's kind of the way i feel about it you know
 	
 	
 		yeah i usually uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> handles a lot of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX> finances and of course we're the like everybody like a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> we just scramble through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">month to month</TIMEX> you know and uh
 	
 	
 		yes
 		do you have a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> or one income
 	
 	
 		uh we have a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> income uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> she also works
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh but she she enjoys it you know and and she's good at it um if it's if it's i am kind of uh
 		uh i'm i'm pretty bad about procrastinating and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one one</NUMEX> of these days i am gonna do something about that but you know  you know how that goes but uh uh if but she she handles it pretty well she uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		she writes all the checks you know once a month
 	
 	
 		so your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>
 		yes
 		is that what her is is her career uh related to to finance or accounting
 	
 	
 		um sort of on a peripheral she's an annuity annuity annuitity <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">administrator</ENAMEX> and so she uh she works for an insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> but but she enjoys it she likes keeping track of all that stuff and uh
 	
 	
 		oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah so that's sort of related to her field a little bit
 	
 	
 		yeah sort of and we you know we've experimented with with uh budgets you know from time to time uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but if you know you have to keep up with them so a lot of times we just uh just kind of play it by ear we try to keep our um
 		our retirement and our savings kind of automated so we never see that money just like taken directly
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		it's just taking it out right right yeah yeah we do the same thing
 	
 	
 		yeah and that that's kind of handy yeah because if you don't see it you don't miss it and uh you don't spend it
 	
 	
 		yeah if if you have something to take it out that's exactly what we've always done and we've had uh they've always had um where they match your funds you know sometimes if you if you save so much then they'll match it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um that you know we've done that too but my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> works for an insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> and he he has now for about oh gosh how long has it been <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years</TIMEX> i guess
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but he was with another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> before that but we have we have i i work also but i only have a part time job
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i get paid very little but um you know i try to use that money for food money <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jim</ENAMEX> gives me a certain amount money
 		you know we just transfer it into my account and then i use that for food household expenses and then i add my own check to that and then with that i try and handle
 	
 	
 		yeah um-hum
 	
 	
 		you know some of the clothes that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> need and and things like that but the expenses that we need around have around the house
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah so sounds like y'all pretty much do it the same we do just kind of
 	
 	
 		so
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		play it by ear but but keep the the deductions you know  coming on
 	
 	
 		yeah we well <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim has Jim</ENAMEX> has a budget i mean he works it out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every month</TIMEX> and writes it all down
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um you know i'm given so much money money <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX> so i am supposed to kind of get the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> out of that so i try not to you know we don't
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know i don't ask for more i mean i just try and make it on that because i think when you go to the grocery <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> you can just you can go crazy with all the choices that you have
 	
 	
 		um-hum yeah
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh you can buy you can really waste a lot of money that way so um well how long have you been married
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about five years</TIMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		oh yeah so you're just really getting started  so do you have a family too
 	
 	
 		yeah uh i've got one little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> she's like uh nineteen months
 	
 	
 		oh yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		so uh she's she's not uh
 	
 	
 		she hasn't affected your budget yet really
 	
 	
 		not not really not too bad uh
 	
 	
 		no no not like she will later on you'll you'll see that because all of a sudden you're paying you're trying to decide whether you are going to do you know soccer and piano and all these choices that they have of activities to do
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah when
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then you really have to start saying okay now what can we afford you know what can we do here and then you have to really sit down and plan some more and uh but i think when we were back at your age we didn't have much of a budget
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and then as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> got older i think we we did more and more of that you know more budgeting as as they got older
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um but um
 		but what do you do do you
 	
 	
 		i'm uh i i work for i'm an electronic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">technician</ENAMEX> i work at uh for a university uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Georgia Tech</ENAMEX> uh research
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 		oh well good good
 	
 	
 		as a so i just uh
 	
 	
 		well we just have yeah we have a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> that's about to move to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX> i guess we're not supposed to talk about those things i better get back to the subject but um budgeting i found you know i feel a lot better you know we used to work out of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> checkbook
 	
 	
 		oh well
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it would be very hard for me because i wouldn't have i wouldn't have any idea of how much money i was spending in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one month</TIMEX> now i have know exactly what i'm spending and it is so much
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 		
 	