
 
     		
 	
 		what what's your uh you are you into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cowboys</ENAMEX> or what
 	
 	
 		uh so
 		oh God no
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh no i i'm not i haven't been i grew up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> but i'm still not a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cowboys</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> i like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Philadelphia Eagles</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah that's my favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> so uh now <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randall</ENAMEX>'s coming back <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next season</TIMEX> i hope they'll be do a little bit better they didn't do too bad <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last season</TIMEX> but i hope they can do better how about yourself
 	
 	
 		that's all right
 		yeah
 		well i don't know i kind of go back and forth uh
 		depending on whose really hot and whose not i guess i'm kind of a fair weather <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> in a lot of respects but uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i guess if i have uh my druthers  i'd probably go for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seattle Seahawks</ENAMEX> i kind of like them
 	
 	
 		oh  yeah that's another one of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">favorites</ENAMEX> they're not they're not my favorite totally but i do like them i like
 	
 	
 		yeah they're kind of
 	
 	
 		yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seahawks</ENAMEX> are good they now that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Largent</ENAMEX>'s gone i kind of lose a little bit for them but you know he
 	
 	
 		you
 		yeah to be honest with you i i probably watch uh college a little bit more than i do pro yeah i kind of like college actually quite a bit
 	
 	
 		really
 		huh
 		yeah that's kind of that's kind of strange it's too much running for me in in college <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> i like i like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pros</ENAMEX> they do you know it's more high tech more you know players <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> are apt to act a little bit different when they when their jobs and their when it's a job and not just
 	
 	
 		is it
 		
 
 	
 	
 		you know when you getting paid <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> to do it you actually i think they take it to another level but i can see it's more you know
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah that could be
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		grunted out run the ball type college <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> it's a little bit different but
 	
 	
 		yeah you probably wouldn't like my favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> in college then
 	
 	
 		who whose that  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Notre Dame</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		no i root for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nebraska</ENAMEX> quite a bit
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nebraska Nebraska</ENAMEX> yeah there's a running <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> yeah that's that that's boring for me i i'll take the passing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">any day</TIMEX> but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 		yeah well i can see i can see definitely how you could get into that i to be honest with you i find that that too much running gets pretty boring as well and
 	
 	
 		yeah it just it's <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">four yards three yards eight yards</NUMEX> tackle that's it you know it gets kind of monotonous after awhile i i prefer forty i've asked forty yard flea <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">flicker</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every now and then</TIMEX> just just to juice it up a little bit and
 	
 	
 		right
 		sure
 		well i think they're starting to realize that a lot of the like the big <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> that used to run so much i think they're starting to realize that they just can't compete anymore
 	
 	
 		but
 		yeah it's high dollar you know it's all it's all money now even <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> is all can we get on TV so
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah yeah so uh what's a this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World League</ENAMEX> is coming in uh that's getting ready to start up right have you followed that very much or
 	
 	
 		that's that
 		right yeah
 		uh not really i i don't think anything will ever take over the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NFL</ENAMEX> i think
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it's basically you know it's it's an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX> it's like if we try to start
 		something to take over major league <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> it's just i just you know i mean it it it can be
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it can take over part of it but it's never gonna be the next
 	
 	
 		right it can take over a small market share but nothing really
 	
 	
 		yeah it's yeah it's gonna take a little bit some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are gonna watch it but it's not gonna be wide spread <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Super Bowl</ENAMEX> and every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">mourning afternoon</TIMEX> or anything you know it's just it's never gonna reach that that standard but
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah i think i agree with you it's it's kind of interesting to see uh
 		to see their claim of you know like world football but when in reality it's really <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> playing somewhere else you know
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah it's kind of
 		kind of strange huh i guess we're the only ones who take it that far everybody else still nuts over soccer but
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah actually uh i kind of like soccer i've never really played it but uh i like the idea it's it's an interesting game to watch that and rugby i like to watch rugby every now
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 		yeah or <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australian</ENAMEX> rules football that's some
 	
 	
 		yeah whatever you wanna call it there
 	
 	
 		yeah that's some brutal stuff there that's that's worse than football as far as violence i think golly those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> kill each other out there rugby something else
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 		yeah there's an element of there's definitely an element of stupidity in there somewhere
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah that's just wild that's why it's a good big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> thing
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rugby</ENAMEX>'s definitely big in college because it's something a bunch of fraternity <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> can get together and get a good beer buzz going and do
 	
 	
 		right exactly  yeah that
 	
 	
 		
 
 		so yeah i could see the feel for that but it's it's pretty it's fun to play i'll give it that it is fun to play if you don't value your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> very much but you know uh i don't think rugby will ever be professional but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		you've played it then
 		no i doubt it you know not least not in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> anyway
 	
 	
 		it's it's it's
 		no you can't stay healthy and do that that's a rough game
 	
 	
 		yeah it is
 	
 	
 		but
 		uh i don't know i i don't know how my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eagles</ENAMEX> are gonna do this year so you the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">the Seahawks</ENAMEX> are an up and down kind of team yeah i my my it's it's kind of odd my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">roommate</ENAMEX> that i live with here he's uh he's
 	
 	
 		
 
 		they really are yeah
 	
 	
 		lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennock Minnesota</ENAMEX> you know where that is it's it's it's a small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> it's <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about two hours</TIMEX> it's in like central <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota</ENAMEX> it's <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a couple of hours</TIMEX> uh west of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minneapolis</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh no i don't to tell you the truth i'm
 		okay to tell you the truth i'm not even really from here
 	
 	
 		but uh
 		you just live there now
 	
 	
 		yeah i'm i'm up here for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> on an internship but i i actually live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh-huh well he's
 		live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> like the Seahawks
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well you know i
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		hey i've i've i've i've only been to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX> twice and i you know i i still like
 	
 	
 		i mean who who
 		who the heck is gonna root for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tampa Bay</ENAMEX> right
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		really really
 	
 	
 		i mean i guess i could go for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miami</ENAMEX> but i don't know i'm from i root for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nebraska</ENAMEX> so i'm i don't have a real love for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miami</ENAMEX> anyway but i don't know i like i said i i get into pretty much any game that's out
 	
 	
 		yeah but i don't
 		
 
 		
 
 		
 		
 	