
 
     		
 	
 		community i'll start we have a lot of uh we we've started doing some and uh in in uh we live in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">suburb</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		recycling has become somewhat in vogue we've always had recycling <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> around where you can take in newspapers and bottles and things and put them in the right bin
 		but it's totally voluntary and basically only the ecologically minded would go to such pains places because it's it's a drive out of your way to take things to these
 		but recently we started a program i think is getting encourages a lot more participation which is uh you have to now pay for each trash bag that that the garbage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> picks up you have to pay a dollar and a half
 		and we uh you have to buy a sticker uh and it costs <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a dollar</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a half</NUMEX> and you have to put the sticker on your trash bag and if you don't have that sticker on there then the garbage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> won't pick it up
 		now that's that that's for regular trash if you have recyclable trash
 	
 	
 		i would
 	
 	
 		like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> or right now it's limited to i think the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> and plastic bottles plastic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk</ENAMEX> bottles then they'll pick that up for free
 		so there's the motivation basically your regular garbage you have to pay to get picked up and recyclable stuff if you put it in a recyclable bin
 		or recyclable uh container they they give you one of these then that that doesn't cost anything so that encourages <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to participate
 	
 	
 		well that's makes sense ours seems really crazy because well we've had the places all the shopping <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> i mean the local shopping <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> where there's a grocery <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 	
 	
 		a you know drug <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> and so on have bins around where you can leave <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> or aluminum cans
 		that type of thing for uh oh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kiwanis</ENAMEX> or some sort of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> pick them up and make money for their causes and those are fairly popular and work fairly well
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and you can also take your own stuff to a recycling <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> and you know get the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">few pennies</NUMEX> you get for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> or cans
 		i know some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who do that but to me that too much trouble for the few cents
 		the uh so i just drop it off at the local place when i go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> and let them
 		you know some good <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> make some money off of it what little they get and uh that works for me but now as i understand it from reading the paper the system seems totally backwards
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh they are starting a thing where all of our garbage bills are going up like a dollar and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a half</NUMEX> a month
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and that's because they will give us containers you know certain colors of bins and stuff to put cans and papers and so on in that all makes sense
 		but if you don't want to recycle you can say i don't want to recycle and save a dollar and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a half</NUMEX> a month
 	
 	
 		oh no
 	
 	
 		which the theory is that if you don't want to recycle with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> who actually has a private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contractor</ENAMEX> do it
 		uh if you don't recycle with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> then you're going to take it yourself and you know make your money off of your paper and cans
 		somehow it seems to me like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> will just say i don't want to pay the buck and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a half</NUMEX> and i'll throw it in the garbage
 		so
 	
 	
 		so like somebody messed up
 	
 	
 		it sounds to me like it's messed up but they've had
 	
 	
 		a strategic miscalculation on their part
 	
 	
 		i guess so we'll have to see what happens they're just supposed to start distributing these blue plastic containers for cans and bottles and different kind different colors for different things
 		uh
 	
 	
 		so it's totally voluntary even if you pay your dollar and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a half</TIMEX> you don't you you can still put everything in the trash
 	
 	
 		you still could so it doesn't make a lot of sense to me and i think i understand it pretty well from both the paper and TV and we'll see what happens
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		any idea how many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are going to do it are going to do it
 	
 	
 		oh supposedly the majority are
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		it's pretty ecologically conscious here
 	
 	
 		so some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> will go along with it anyway
 	
 	
 		oh i think so plus a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> will probably just pay the buck and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a half</NUMEX> and not even notice the difference or care
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but uh
 		it seems strange now at the the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX> where i work it's uh strange too because they have places you can leave cans and some campus <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> recycles them
 	
 	
 		well
 	
 	
 		and uh there is a campus recycling bins not bins but like i work in a library
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		and there are barrels where we can recycle <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> and different types of things but they're in staff areas
 		but we have wanted to have specially marked trash cans next to all the copy machines
 		
 		
 	