
 
     		
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX> i'm kind of in favor of capital punishment how about you
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i am i yes and uh
 		uh what was the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> part of the uh subject that you
 	
 	
 		well uh do you think it should just be restricted to certain crimes
 	
 	
 		oh i i basically do i think uh
 		other than murder uh the probably uh i don't think there's a need for it if uh if it's not if the case is doesn't involve murder
 		i don't see any need for it in anything else any other circumstances
 		i guess it's an eye for an eye
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well there are those that say it's not a deterrent to others but i think it certainly deters the one that uh
 	
 	
 		oh
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		gets the capital punishment
 	
 	
 		well yeah i guess the other argument is that you might execute the wrong <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> but uh
 		i don't know i just think the chances of that happening are pretty slim of course it's  it's not reversible uh obviously but uh i just think the way the system is set up uh
 		the chances of the wrong <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> being executed are are really very small uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh i've served on a few <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">juries</ENAMEX> and they take a they seem to take a lot of care to make sure they've got the uh the right <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> whatever for the conviction levied
 	
 	
 		that's
 		that's true well certainly <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		as a state believes in capital punishment i don't know i wonder if we execute more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> than other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> or
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		i don't know you every once in a while if you hear  if there's some who's fairly famous or notorious being executed in another state you read about it or hear about it but uh
 		i don't know how we rank up there with the other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> but uh i think it's a deterrent i i don't i mean it wouldn't be a deterrent for everybody obviously but i think uh if it uh
 		if it saves <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s life it may be worth it uh if <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who was going to kill somebody thought otherwise because of the uh possibility or a possibility of capital punishment it uh it may be worth it
 		but i think it's a deterrent
 	
 	
 		yeah i think so too uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and and we fail so miserably in rehabilitating any kind of criminal
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right and
 	
 	
 		and i i don't know i wonder if there are other crimes uh a repeated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rapist</ENAMEX> for example or
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 		uh i don't know kidnapping of course is a
 		capital crime
 		but i
 	
 	
 		well
 		is that uh is that punishable by death in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> or is that up to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> to decide or the judge
 	
 	
 		i doubt that
 		i
 		i don't know
 	
 	
 		i never thought about that but is that is that a capital crime
 	
 	
 		don't know
 		i think so but maybe not maybe not i could be confused what do i know
 	
 	
 		huh
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		don't hear much about don't hear much about kidnapping anymore kidnaps uh
 	
 	
 		i'm not a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kidnapper</ENAMEX>
 		well there've been a few over in
 		in i guess i not recently i guess
 	
 	
 		but the uh the whole judicial system is a mess like you said there's no rehabilitation in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prisons</ENAMEX> and so they get out of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> and they're they're back to doing what they were doing before they went to prison
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		they haven't learned a lesson
 	
 	
 		well i certainly don't agree with a with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">murderer</ENAMEX> getting a sentence of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years</TIMEX> and being out in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> or whatever it is
 	
 	
 		um-hum yeah
 	
 	
 		i think that's just totally inappropriate
 	
 	
 		yeah well like you said rape uh that there's a possibility there for uh capital punishment and that that's a serious enough crime that uh it maybe warrant capital punishment
 		but what gets me is the uh i may be getting off the subject somebody might get forty <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX> for stealing i mean for robbing something
 		of course that i think to get that they'd have to be a repeat <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offender</ENAMEX> that'd be more than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one or two</NUMEX> cases involved
 		but the the whole judicial system seems to be lopsided messed up
 	
 	
 		yeah you don't uh so you don't think that capital that capital punishment is appropriate for repeated robber or
 	
 	
 		no no i really don't uh
 		no murder and again rape possibly a repeated uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rapist</ENAMEX> may be uh
 		a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> for capital punishment but uh the really serious stuff i don't this burglary and robbery and
 		uh that sort of thing even if they're multiple <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offenders</ENAMEX> or repeat <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offenders</ENAMEX> i i wouldn't condone capital punishment for that
 	
 	
 		no uh
 		yeah
 		i i don't know what the consensus in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> is i know it was it was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years ago</TIMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> struck down capital punishment didn't they didn't they tell the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> to go back and review the circumstances
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah that uh it was it was uh there was no capital punishment for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time</TIMEX> there i don't know fifteen <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years</TIMEX> maybe
 	
 	
 		something like that they
 	
 	
 		and uh i know when i was growing up there was uh there were a lot of uh
 		electrocutions up in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sing Sing</ENAMEX> up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> upstate <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> and then uh they did away with like you said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> outlawed it and then it came back on a state by state basis
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but uh
 		
 		
 	