
 
     		
 	
 		well i guess uh
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		start off by saying that i am very much in favor of space travel but i think we're going about it all wrong
 	
 	
 		okay with that
 	
 	
 		what are your thoughts
 	
 	
 		
 
 		uh i'd like you to expound on that a little bit but uh i am very much in favor of it too and i think that we need to take the approach that
 		so much technology is advanced out of the uh space program that it's amazing to me that we don't
 		put more money into it
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well i am uh kind of disappointed by the way things have been going
 		uh basically we've been out this at this for what about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty five years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh well yeah well it depends on what you're saying yeah that i guess
 	
 	
 		from the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> experimental
 		well first experimental vanguard type stuff uh i think that was called the first uh the modified B twos and things like that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		okay
 	
 	
 		that was late fifties i believe so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and um if you
 		look at the progress that was made at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the turn of the century</TIMEX> in aviation in a period of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty five years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		in my assessment it was spectacularly better
 	
 	
 		well there's no doubt about that
 	
 	
 		and um i don't think that's because the complexity of the task i think that's because it's being handled by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bureaucracy</ENAMEX> now
 	
 	
 		well you so you're saying you thought uh that well that that implies to me that you would you should've felt like it should've been uh turned over to a commercial market
 	
 	
 		well i'm excited about these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fellows</ENAMEX> who are experimenting commercially i'm excited about uh the commercial end of satellite operations
 		um there seems to be some spectacular progress happening there and uh
 	
 	
 		well i think that uh satellites now that is a that is a market where there's a a valid
 		reason for commercial uh when it comes to research i'm not sure i agree with that
 	
 	
 		well what would be what would be the reasons for prohibiting commercial research
 	
 	
 		oh no reasons i just don't think that uh a commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> could successfully uh uh make it profitable for them
 		uh i mean  and besides the fact it it also would be extremely limiting as to which research it'd be be whichever one happened to bring in the dollar
 	
 	
 		well they have some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> out there with some fairly deep pockets and uh i think that
 	
 	
 		but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US</ENAMEX> is notorious for not spending any money on research
 		uh our commercial market uh our commercial percentages are much lower than uh most most of the other major <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> as compared to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> compared to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> compared to uh most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Scandinavian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah well maybe
 	
 	
 		the amount of money uh put towards research is is minuscule and had minuscule and has been decreasing over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last few years</TIMEX> that so i'm not so sure that that would be
 	
 	
 		well you go ahead
 	
 	
 		i i i agree that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bureaucracy</ENAMEX> in most cases is something which it should be avoided and we have we have entirely too much government and bureaucracy and it and it seeps over in a lot of different ways
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		now uh in space i don't think you could do it any other way uh well i'd say fact my opinion is what we ought to do is we ought to get all these all the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> involved in these things and in fact
 	
 	
 		um
 		go ahead
 	
 	
 		oh well because i mean we have um resources across the world i mean i i we're coming out to a global global economy anyways
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so why aren't we using the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> technology why aren't we using the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> technology why aren't see
 	
 	
 		well
 	
 	
 		see space travel is a world issue it's not a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> issue and and our our our kind of elitism attitude we had in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the sixties</TIMEX> about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> uh love it or leave it  and you know actually we still have it but that whole
 	
 	
 		
 
 		it's not as effective <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> as it was then
 	
 	
 		right um that the the the concept of beating the other uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> i think is somewhat
 	
 	
 		
 
 		it may be obsolete
 	
 	
 		yeah it's somewhat obsolete  and i think
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah you know i uh what do you call it um
 		i think it's important that it happened i think that ultimately it will happen
 		um i think that the way things are going on now may be an impediment and that by that i mean
 		you know i don't know about i'm not going to speculate about research across the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> but let's suppose um you were the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that could possibly have benefit from some space research
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and you're <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three or four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX> and you're debating whether to um
 		throw a couple of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billion dollars</NUMEX> into it over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next twenty years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but it's going to be a real long term uh play
 		or whether you're just going to sit back and watch television and um
 		when you look when you see that your primary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitor</ENAMEX> is um a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> with very deep pockets that's going to give the fruits to your competitors
 		the obvious correct decision is to sit back and wait for them to give it to everybody rather than doing it yourself
 		so i think the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> getting involved in that tends to reduce the amount of uh private uh effort put into it
 		uh with regard to myself personally i think that if ever if i ever in my lifetime do stand on the surface of the moon it's going to be uh on a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ship</ENAMEX> with a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> flag
 	
 	
 		i would say that i have absolutely no
 		
 		
 	