
 
     		
 	
 		uh well  uh having sort of recently gone through the school system i seem to be younger than most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who who talk on this thing i'm i'm just graduating college
 		graduating from college uh i didn't really perceive much of a of a problem with the school system however when you compare it to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school systems</ENAMEX> like
 		they have in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> and again you can compare just about everything thing to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> and we look like we we don't have anything
 		um it seems to be not difficult enough for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> not challenging enough and just not generally competitive enough
 		um however i if it weren't for our needless uh  competition with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> i i'd i'd think that that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school systems</ENAMEX> system works at a pretty good pace
 	
 	
 		i don't know um i haven't it's been um well seventy <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> since i was at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> at high school and um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i've seen things change
 		i don't know if i've seen things change enough that i can actually because i wasn't really like listening to the world go by back then so it's hard to compare you know what i mean
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but um
 		it seems like  when i lived i lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> i've i've lived down here i hear the dropout rates from the schools
 		and i certainly see how much i pay in real estate taxes every year
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and i begin to wonder if i'm really getting my money's worth
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		i mean i i've seen so many different things
 		so so many different bad reports coming out of the school system and i recognize that there are good <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> out there i mean somebody's getting getting a good education because we continue to employ people
 	
 	
 		right
 		
 
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but um
 		i don't i don't understand the um
 		i don't understand i guess why the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> don't seem to have such a high dropout rate in the big cities
 	
 	
 		uh well i i don't pretend to understand that either uh but i'm not quite sure that it's the kind of thing that ought to be blamed on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> but then again i'm not quite sure where the blame ought to be put
 		um because the the dropout rate is
 		in those areas it's it's high in those areas where also there's poverty and and crime and they all seem to go together and it seems like if you could eliminate <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of of the parts of that circle
 		whether wherever you have the dropout rate and crime and you know general poverty kind of conditions
 		that things ought to get better so uh and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">the other two</NUMEX> all oh they're all <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> social issues and could be addressed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> in anyways and clearly to me is a kind of government thing to
 		to fix but it's just like i i don't expect them to know which which which part is best to fix just like i don't know it's it's a complicated issue i i still don't think i would directly blame it directly on the school
 	
 	
 		i don't know if i blame it on the school i think i think i blame it i think i blame it on a couple of different things i think i blame it on the school system
 		um
 	
 	
 		well that's what i meant when i said the school
 	
 	
 		yeah  i don't blame it on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> in the school i although i think that i do know for a fact that some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> that i know personally get paid an awful lot more than
 		well  they do quite well for themselves
 	
 	
 		hm well that that's odd because i don't think the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> in my school district uh were well paid
 	
 	
 		no not all school districts are well paid but there are some school districts out there that are very well paid i mean i know one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> that's got they're both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX>
 		and they both have like <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> jobs that they work in the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoons</TIMEX> they both work <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all summer</TIMEX> full-time and from their teaching job alone they pull in forty grand each
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah well it it
 	
 	
 		i mean that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> is making <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over a hundred</NUMEX> grand and i'm i mean okay okay yes i agree that teaching our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> is important
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		however these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who only work <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">eight hours a day</TIMEX> at it from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> and they only work <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nine months a year</TIMEX> and they get an awful lot of breaks in between
 		and that's my tax dollars that i'm spending on that and i don't even have kids
 	
 	
 		yeah well well well that's true but that there's you can always play games with uh talking about whoa look at this my tax dollars are paying for this this is wrong
 		but when you're talk  and there's really not much you can directly do about that i think that that if if there is a problem with the school system
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> from my it's been my perception that the school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> and school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> are not that well uh
 		uh paid that perhaps that might be one area that that could be improved uh where you have other professional jobs and this this is a profession and as a matter of fact it's a pretty big influence on on
 		
 		
 	