
 
     		
 	
 		do you think should be done for the the uh huge budget we have
 	
 	
 		
 
 		uh uh well i think the first thing that every every time they talk about it they they say well we can't cut this or we don't need to cut this out of the budget because it's such a small amount in comparison to the overall decifit deficit
 		but
 		i think they need to start doing it i mean
 		the taxes are going to grow so high there's no way we'll ever pay off what we owe now our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> is going to pay it
 	
 	
 		yeah i know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Graham Krugman</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Krugman</ENAMEX> was it uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grudman</ENAMEX> he's  he's not going for
 		we elected him for that uh again and he said that he didn't think that we'd ever be able to have uh balanced budget
 	
 	
 		i don't think so they had an article in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX> about
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh
 		the interest alone in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year two thousand</TIMEX>'s going to be more than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Kennedy</ENAMEX>'s entire budget
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and when it's it's gone ridiculous now i don't know what's going to happen
 	
 	
 		we'll be like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> soon right
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		or what or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		bankrupt
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yep totally
 		everything yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year two thousand</TIMEX> that uh we'd be totally dependent on foreign capital
 		and
 	
 	
 		i think so like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh
 		i don't know if that's such a bad thing
 		one so
 		once <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> becomes
 		if we're dependent on them they're most certainly dependent upon us i don't think that the world market would
 		would be as possible for them with out us i mean i don't think <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> is consumer oriented as we are
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		they more or less have to sell to us whether where else would you sell that many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Toyotas</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Hondas</ENAMEX> and stuff it'd have to be here
 	
 	
 		well  you go were the money is and if you don't have the money anymore
 		then that's that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		i don't know i think the first thing we could do is uh
 		i'd like to see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>  attached to the decifit or you know or
 	
 	
 		performance right
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		attach performance
 	
 	
 		yeah performance calls like you might have at work or or i might have too
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		certainly do
 	
 	
 		you do
 		i do too uh it's uh
 		i don't know why they should be uh
 		unregulated and and
 		over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last twenty years</TIMEX> we've strictly gone down hill and the salary's gone up
 	
 	
 		well actually their  well that's one thing but we also got to change the voting stuff and the uh special interest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> and all that stuff
 		you know we we take a lot of the blame for it we have to start voting we have to start talking we have to start uh doing something about it but we're so apathetic it's almost ridiculous
 	
 	
 		well for one thing uh
 		we've got lives to live
 		i mean for us to uh to stay knowledgeable on all these issues it's a full time job
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i mean i go to work <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> just like you do i don't i can't sit down and keep up with all of this that's why we elect them
 	
 	
 		oh i understand that but we have to go to vote
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		we have to uh participate in political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> or something uh
 		those kinds of things and we don't even do that
 	
 	
 		no i i don't even think uh participation would have  as far as <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">democrats</ENAMEX> and republicans go it'd have to be a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> party
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh still i mean we have the right to do it we don't do it that's the whole problem we don't exercise those rights
 		i don't know i think part of the things is maybe a value added tax like what they have in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> i mean
 		um
 		that would definitely cut down on the consumerism  and which really pushes
 		a lot of the uh you know it'd be a good way of getting revenues and all so bring in line towards <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">savings and</ENAMEX> and putting money into uh instead of spending into investment
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		you know  do you sometimes think it's got to a hopeless position now that there's nothing we could do to reverse it
 	
 	
 		well i don't know i think if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> put their minds to it they can do it it's just a matter of mobilizing
 		uh you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that do it it's a very difficult task i'm not saying that any of this is easy
 	
 	
 		you know we're we're talking about numbers that i can't even comprehend
 		the numbers were too large for me
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well think about the wars the nuclear situation and all that talking about the numbers of atomic bombs and how many times you can bomb the world over and how incredible that was and now
 		you you know that's coming to a point where that's less likely less and less likely
 		right economic ruling brought that down
 		
 		
 	