
 
     		
 	
 		you're uh can you tell me what you think of capital punishment
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		um i'm against capital punishment um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i i guess there's a cliche that
 		um for every <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousand</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> let free if one innocent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> is uh killed that that's a terrible thing for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> to be doing and i agree i remember watching a a documentary film <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of years ago</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i've forgotten the name of it now but it was about a killing in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> where somebody was sentenced i think it may have been just to life imprisonment but in any event it may have been capital punishment but uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		this documentarian documentarian or whatever you wanna say um he uh interviewed all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> involved and basically got another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> to admit that he had been the one who had committed the murder i don't know
 	
 	
 		was that the rape murder of that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixteen year</TIMEX> old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> in a school
 	
 	
 		um no i don't think so it was a i don't remember the circumstances actually i i just remember
 	
 	
 		there was something like something like that on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sixty Minutes</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about two years ago</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		no no this was documentary um
 		it was a a you know in released in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theaters</ENAMEX> i saw it on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> finally i guess um but any event it was it was very interesting and it
 	
 	
 		um-hum hm
 		hm
 	
 	
 		you know i guess  they say that you look for views in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> that support your own and  maybe maybe that's the bias here
 	
 	
 		i don't find very many  that support mine
 	
 	
 		well what's your um perspective on capital punishment
 	
 	
 		well actually i mean not not with regard to capital punishment i mean just in general the media um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh they take the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the the the</TIMEX> the average <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> is far more liberal than the average <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> in the rest of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and so
 		uh views that are more conservative just don't get adequately represented in the mainstream <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> that's been documented by a number of studies but on capital punishment look that's an exception i'm not conservative on that i'm sort of middle of the road i i lean against capital punishment but
 		i i wouldn't be an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activist</ENAMEX> on it cause there's so many more important things i think i mean i admit that some innocent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> get killed and i believe you're correct that has been documented it happens occasionally and it's very that that that's that's quite unfortunate
 	
 	
 		and there's also the factor that
 		that there's obviously racism in terms of even though certain <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minorities</ENAMEX> might commit a higher percentage of crimes than they are represented in the overall population they are also convicted convicted of capital crimes
 		and sentenced to capital punishment at a higher percentage than they're represented even among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> so that's
 	
 	
 		hm well that last <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">caller</ENAMEX> actually i i  this is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time i've ever spoken about a topic for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> time but the last <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">caller</ENAMEX> that i discussed it with didn't
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		didn't say you know even that even the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the fraction</TIMEX> that would be represented among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> are convicted more often
 		and in fact i just asked him the question is it is it true that isn't it true that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minorities</ENAMEX> you know from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in general <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from lower socioeconomic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> tend to commit more violent crime and so wouldn't you expect them to be committed to to be convicted more often
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		now i do think i recall seeing some statistics to to the effect that that you that you mentioned um
 		i don't know that you know maybe it was a report a news report i heard or something where i couldn't check it out very carefully where i couldn't i i always tend to read over these things you know
 		especially if you have an interest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> that comes up with a study that supports their own position if they did the work i always tend to be a little suspicious of it and that might've been the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern Poverty Law Project</ENAMEX> or something that did that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 		i think
 		i don't know
 	
 	
 		and so i don't know whether i necessarily  whether i wanna give credence to that without looking into it but i do remember hearing that yeah
 	
 	
 		um-hum i think some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar associations</ENAMEX> um a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar associations</ENAMEX> are against capital punishment and um this is one area where perhaps they've done some of the work i'm not sure
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah well i'm i mean i i i agree i think that that the problem with capital punishment is that it's irrevocable
 		if you find out you put somebody in jail wrongly you can just let them out if you find out that you you killed somebody wrongly there's nothing you can do to bring them back to life so
 		so that's definitely a problem and um you know  well  we're supposed to talk about our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> i guess according to the synopsis at the beginning so <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX> has capital punishment well
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		if if <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX> didn't have capital punishment i wouldn't try and institute it it it does have capital punishment i don't see that it does any good
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they might convict somebody wrongly sometime that's unfortunate but um  you know farther
 		the fortunate thing really is that that it occurs so rarely uh i think we have about uh maybe one execution or a little bit less a year in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX> now i
 	
 	
 		is that so
 	
 	
 		i know there're some <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> like i think <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> is probably the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> i'm not sure of that but i think it may be is that right
 	
 	
 		i'm not sure i think
 		that sounds right offhand but i'm not positive i i have only recently moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kentucky</ENAMEX> so i'm not even sure what <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kentucky</ENAMEX>'s law is my guess is it's probably legal but probably similar to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Carolina</ENAMEX> that it's not used very frequently
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		hm
 		yeah i think that that you know most southern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> tend to have capital punishment more than northern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota</ENAMEX> for example i don't know but i'd be almost sure that they don't have capital punishments <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wisconsin Wisconsin</ENAMEX> the same way
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 		right i was living in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX> before here and i'm virtually certain that they didn't have it or if they did have it it was never used
 	
 	
 		hm
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	