
 
     		
 	
 		well um
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i guess the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> question is uh what um
 		what do do you have any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> at all to begin with
 	
 	
 		well i work with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> um i don't have any right now uh myself um
 		but we definitely do want to have um <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and i work in the medical field so i work with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> quite a bit
 	
 	
 		pediatrics
 	
 	
 		um well i have worked in family practice which in large part was pediatrics
 	
 	
 		i
 	
 	
 		so i'm
 		well aware of
 		child care problems and needs
 	
 	
 		oh are you um what are you a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurse</ENAMEX> are you a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> uh
 	
 	
 		i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physician</ENAMEX> assistant
 	
 	
 		is an attendant a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX> assistant
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i see so
 	
 	
 		have you ever heard of that
 	
 	
 		i've no well i mean there's all kinds of things i haven't heard of so i i haven't heard of that no not particularly what what do you do exactly
 	
 	
 		hum
 		um well we're train to diagnose and prescribe and
 		um in some <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> anyway their prescribing laws are different and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		in the particular job that i recently left um
 		i was functioning
 		as a family practitioner and
 		just seeing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> of all varieties whatever you'd see in normal family practice
 		pretty much what i did and i saw <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> a lot
 		they liked to see me because i wasn't an intimidating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man doctor</ENAMEX> i guess
 	
 	
 		um-hum hum hum
 	
 	
 		so they appreciated that
 	
 	
 		oh boy
 	
 	
 		but
 		so do you have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no i do not none that i'm aware of anyway as they say um
 		no i uh no i do not have have any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> i'm very i'm mostly happily single
 	
 	
 		hm  none that you're aware well that's our topic right
 	
 	
 		uh
 		yeah i i it is i i um
 		uh i don't know i have i have my own opinions on the on the subject it's kind of
 		for me this particular question is is is uh reminiscent of uh answer yes or no have you stopped beating your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh um it pre supposes something that isn't necessarily that isn't necessarily true <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of all that you think that child care should be done by other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> besides the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> having the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but um i'm i'm a little like i don't know i've i've got my own views on that i
 	
 	
 		well what are your views
 	
 	
 		well uh
 	
 	
 		you can tell me i've
 		doesn't matter if i agree or not oh
 	
 	
 		hey there you go
 		um i don't know i i tend to think that child care is kind of overused i think there's a
 	
 	
 		kind of what
 	
 	
 		kind of overused in a sense it's the idea is that you can have a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and nothing is going to be changed you know the idea of quality time over
 		over quantity of time spent with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> which i think is nonsense
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		that's the reason one of the reasons i think that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> are doing so badly is so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> look at them as a just a just a tax <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">payer</ENAMEX> financed babysitting service
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know but anyway that's just me
 	
 	
 		well i agree with you there i i guess
 		um
 		i i suppose
 		you know you could call me a career <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> but i i do feel that i want to be at home with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> mainly because i see that as such an important thing um
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		that
 		also i know of what a job takes out of me
 		and i wouldn't have anything left over for my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and i wouldn't want to do that to myself you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i mean these are human beings that we're trying to raise and help them be constructive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of society
 	
 	
 		there's a good phrase
 	
 	
 		so
 		so i i'm with you there on the other hand i have a lot <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> who are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> and work full time in their careers and i wouldn't
 		you know i
 		their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are darling too and i i would hate to give them the impression that i judge am judging them
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah oh yeah i i understand that
 	
 	
 		yeah but on the other hand there some that are sacrificing their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> for the sake of their jobs and you know
 		i'm sure their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> would be much better served if
 	
 	
 		if somebody would at least  i don't know it's it's rough and i think that there's a
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		well there a
 		giving an example my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX>'s uh sister
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		is um marry married a uh
 		married a uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychologist</ENAMEX> and where they're living he they can they can afford for her not to work
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		which she has not been doing since they since they've had uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 		and especially i i think it would be ultimate really impossible because she just had <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">twins</ENAMEX> not very long ago
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and uh
 	
 	
 		yeah there's no way
 	
 	
 		and uh they
 		you know they tell me that there's they get together and
 		
 		
 	