
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well here in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Logan Utah</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		we got a nice little valley here and it's like crystal clear all the time except for during the winter
 		when the inversion sets in and then we get a little bit of pollution in the valley
 	
 	
 		hm
 		well here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX> uh it's giving the air's getting more and more polluted to where uh we're in kind of a basin
 		and uh
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seattle</ENAMEX>'s on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Puget Sound</ENAMEX> which is a
 		inland <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">waterway</ENAMEX> between <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> mountains
 		and uh there's been a lot of lot of growth population growth around here
 		and uh it's uh it's getting worse  i think most of it is from <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah definitely here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX>
 		up along the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wasatch</ENAMEX> front along the
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">western</ENAMEX> side of the of these <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Rocky Mountains</ENAMEX> here where a lot of the big <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Salt Lake</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ogden</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Provo</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Logan</ENAMEX>'s up in the valley a little bit further north
 		we get a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pollution</ENAMEX> and it's like seventy percent of it's from <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		it always really hits hard during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the winter</TIMEX> when we get the  inversion and when we get
 		get cold air down in the valleys and warm air up <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">above</NUMEX> and it just sits and sits and sits and we're starting to hit <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pollution</ENAMEX> levels now on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wasatch</ENAMEX> front which match that of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LA</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years ago</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-oh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's not it's almost sad because when i grew up here it was just always the crisp air up in the mountain <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">valleys</ENAMEX> and now it's not in the mountain valleys
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah i live in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX> district and uh
 		uh it's supposed to have about the worst air pollution
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i think probably due to uh a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> going back and forth to school
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		and i'm we're right next to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Interstate 5</ENAMEX> also
 	
 	
 		they're getting serious about things like uh mandatory well they've already passed laws where you have to get your <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> checked for pollution if you're in certain <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">counties</ENAMEX> emissions
 	
 	
 		oh yeah oh yeah they started doing that yet
 	
 	
 		yeah they've actually started doing it down along the not in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Logan</ENAMEX> up here because we're doing a lot better we have a lot <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>'s a lot lighter up here
 	
 	
 		we have that here and uh they're they're expanding it to uh more <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">counties</ENAMEX> here um as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> spreads out
 		and i think they're also gonna be making it uh
 		mandatory for more <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> there there was uh
 		something in the law about if you're <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> was over a certain age like over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years old</TIMEX> you didn't have to get it done anymore and i think they're eliminating that uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yep they're getting eliminating that out here
 	
 	
 		that loophole yeah
 	
 	
 		they're also talking very seriously about the thing called a dirt gun
 		where they're uh looking at the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">emissions</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> using basically a spectrometer and looking at the
 		basically how much of what is coming out the exhaust kind of like a radar gun
 		and yes
 	
 	
 		oh really they make you do that remotely
 	
 	
 		yeah do it remotely just looking at the what they do they do several different types of things sometimes they put a source light
 		and they look at the source light and then as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> goes by you can see the exhaust pipe and the source light behind it and you can look at the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">emissions</ENAMEX> actually
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hm</ENAMEX>  now where does the source light go
 	
 	
 		and
 		like across the street they'll set up like a trap or something that add in some sense and they're also looking at uh
 	
 	
 		oh i see
 	
 	
 		other
 		you know ways of monitoring this and because they found out something basically that uh
 		and a poorly tuned <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> can emit something it's an incredible amount it was like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four hundred</NUMEX> times as much
 	
 	
 		jeez
 	
 	
 		um
 		of certain <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pollutants</ENAMEX> and it was like unburned hydrocarbons
 		then a a properly tuned <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and and the idea being that if you just tuned up
 		all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> well if you tuned up this <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> percent of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> that were producing like fifty percent of the
 		the pollution then
 		you know you'd it be one way to cut the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pollution</ENAMEX> in half
 	
 	
 		yeah that's neat
 		
 
 		but it's also been uh
 		oh you know everybody is talking about using more mass transient here but
 		it uh
 		it's tough you know like i've i've looked into riding the bus to work and
 		i can drive to work in uh
 		and get there in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty to twenty five minutes</TIMEX> over a very congested corridor which goes over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lake Washington</ENAMEX> on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the floating bridges
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but if i uh
 		
 
 		if i take the bus it requires several transfers
 		and it takes over an hour
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yeah and they're
 	
 	
 		so it it's it's not hard to see why i why i keep driving and you know i feel guilty because i'm driving a
 		
 		
 	