
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		uh well <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX> do you take your entire uh family camping
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well we really haven't been camping per se here but we've camped in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wyoming</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well you have do you take the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> with you
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah i got a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> he's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years old</TIMEX> when we go camping uh we normally have to round up another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> to keep him occupied
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		otherwise otherwise he drives us nuts
 	
 	
 		yeah well that that's basically the same way with us but we we kind of play games and stuff with him when we're camping
 	
 	
 		do you do you wilderness camp
 	
 	
 		uh yeah i have before before i uh got married i haven't since i've been married though
 	
 	
 		your your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> doesn't like that wilderness camping does she
 	
 	
 		well she she likes to go camping but we just haven't really had a chance to really go camping
 	
 	
 		yeah my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> thinks <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holiday Inn</ENAMEX> is wilderness camping
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		she uh she got to have a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bathroom</ENAMEX> and showers we live on the lake uh there's a very large lake here it's called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Lake Laniers</ENAMEX> in north <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgia</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> is on the lake so
 		there's a lot of places to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> around around here where the they have rest <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> and showers and stuff like but the lake's really crowded so we normally go the mountains we found some nice little places in the mountains
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		there's a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> run <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp sites</ENAMEX> now this they're charging us now do they charge you in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i'm not sure if they do or not it's uh i think uh some of the privately owned places do but i'm not sure about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> owned
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh they do here they they uh
 		you pay taxes to support it and then uh you pay to get in too
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know like a user fee i think they call them now so now do y'all do you <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> and go camp do you take a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> or
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well no not really we just usually kind of go camping and tent and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cook</ENAMEX> and
 		and just fish off the shore
 	
 	
 		yeah it uh do you uh load the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> down till <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the springs</TIMEX> are dragging the ground
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		we do we yeah we we got uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> is putting tables and chairs
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		got to have the comforts of home huh
 	
 	
 		oh yeah it we have a hard time getting the uh recliners bolted on high on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> too
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well it takes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three days</TIMEX> to load the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three days</TIMEX> to unload it and we camp for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a day</TIMEX> and a half
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah i i can understand that
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but we really don't
 		when we go we kind of plan everything out and
 		we don't uh take a lot of stuff with us so
 	
 	
 		do you know  how old are your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh we just got a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five year</TIMEX> old
 	
 	
 		a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five year old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> that's rough to camping in when they're <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> it'n it
 	
 	
 		well not really he's pretty good you know he  when he when we ask him to do something he usually does goes and does it
 	
 	
 		well when when uh ours is like i say is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years old</TIMEX> and
 		i think they might be a little bit more hard to handle too
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you got to keep them occupied and then plus you end up with a fish hooks in your ears and stuff like that
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well i kind of i kind of got a  got him to where he's uh just got a weight on the end of his right now so
 		he really doesn't know what catching <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> is like so he just kind of practice casting right now
 	
 	
 		well that's all they care about anyway
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		casting that's all my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> cares about
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		seeing how for he can throw it i've tried to explain to him fish can swim
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		he don't believe me
 	
 	
 		but before i came in the service my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> always took us camping in the Bighorns
 		in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wyoming</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so we did a lot of that just about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		it was
 	
 	
 		we drove we drove through there and looked that looks like it'd be beautiful out there
 	
 	
 		oh yeah it is well <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one one summer</TIMEX> we went in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX> and went camping and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one morning</TIMEX> we got up there's snow on the ground
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		sort of
 	
 	
 		it kind of surprises you you know
 	
 	
 		yeah i don't know if i could take that last time we went camping i went with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and
 		we went up the on top of this mountain it was a little narrow road
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it takes it's <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">just eighteen miles</NUMEX> but it takes like a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hour and a half</TIMEX> to get up that road it's a rough road
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so we get up there and we sit around and we get ready to get ready for the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> that <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> and and they didn't bring the poles to hold their tent up
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so we're all had to cram this one little tiny tent and it rained <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">all night</TIMEX> long
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and i was stuck at the door and it just it just flooded me <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">all night</TIMEX> long this so that has been our last little camping experience
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but uh we enjoyed it if we if you don't get <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">pneumonia</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah it's it's pretty nice to get out and see the wilderness every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> and then you know
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well there's getting less and less of it
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		i think
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	