
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 		uh so uh what are your benefits like at your job and how do you feel about them
 	
 	
 		uh pretty good actually i work for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hewlett Packard</ENAMEX> and they have uh a pretty good uh benefits package in fact they're they're kind of known
 		uh for having good benefits the pay isn't fabulous although
 		i saw a survey recently and i'm actually making just about as much as you know i'm making making actually over average over the average for my career my experience and all that stuff which kind of surprised me so
 	
 	
 		oh that's good
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		what kind of a degree have you got
 	
 	
 		i've got a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bachelor's</ENAMEX> in electrical engineering so
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and i'm not like a hugely advanced degree or any of that stuff
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh anyway the our benefits are pretty good we've got stock purchase program and a that that's pretty generous although you have to hold the stock for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		before you get the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> contribution which is kind of a a pain but uh  there's a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> plan uh for uh sheltering some taxable income
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh there's
 	
 	
 		how long have you been with them
 	
 	
 		i've been with them for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh that's good
 	
 	
 		yeah and the best thing and a lot of the stuff the best thing is like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years or five years</TIMEX> it's pretty soon you're completely vested in the retirement plan and everything
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so uh it's not too but there's full uh there there's several medical plans to choose from uh that cover pretty much everything i don't get sick that often so i don't pay much of it but you know i pay <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five dollars</NUMEX> every time i visit the the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that you know for a checkup or whatever
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 		they don't cover eyes though and i i have contact lenses so that's kind of a pain
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but you know i i can live
 	
 	
 		but for for all practical purpose you are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">almost a hundred</NUMEX> percent covered
 	
 	
 		oh yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		so that you've got got small small things to gripe about
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		wow well that sounds like you must feel really good about it
 	
 	
 		and
 		yeah yeah and and the dental plan is fabulous the dental plan i pay absolutely nothing
 	
 	
 		wow
 	
 	
 		because uh i i guess they would charge a little bit if there was some orthodontia or something for one of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dependents</ENAMEX> or something like that but that's not the case so i  guess nothing it's fabulous
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		wow
 	
 	
 		uh the what about you
 	
 	
 		well i uh work in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Naval Research Laboratory</ENAMEX>
 		i also have a part time job at a law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> and i get no benefits from them at to the part time work although they pay better per hour
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		than my my sort of quote real job does uh and benefits through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> are uh really uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		they just uh they're not the greatest uh i before i i uh  uh got my degree i'm uh computer a computer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientist</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and before i got my degree i had uh done <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">paralegal</ENAMEX> work for law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		at that time i was in gravy city uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">law firms</ENAMEX>  in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> are not you know for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time</TIMEX> were just rolling in the dough in the early eighties and uh benefits were just amazing and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we had everything paid for and uh anyway with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> it's not uh quite that nice a deal uh but it's you know it's it's okay what we have to do is we have to pay uh <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about twenty percent</NUMEX> of our
 		uh uh our costs and it's deducted from our check <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each month</TIMEX> and that sort of thing and the plans that are available to us uh range from kind of mediocre to really sweet
 		and uh  so i i think i'm actually involved in a relatively good plan plan at this point um but uh it could be better that's for sure and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh  but you know there there are other things that you get when you work for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> i uh
 		in in terms of uh more relaxed atmosphere it's really nice to be for me anyway to be able to work in uh a research atmosphere uh where i don't have to uh
 		uh you know worry about uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">academics</ENAMEX> or anything like that and  so i'm i'm really kind of happy about that end of of things it's uh
 	
 	
 		yeah the one of the things with my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> is that they've uh got a reputation for a lot of job security and uh there's a lot of different
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		things that they do lot of different <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">divisions</ENAMEX> even this area in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">San Francisco Bay Area</ENAMEX> that they do so there's uh i myself have moved around quite a bit within the company
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it's and i and i haven't had to move my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">residence</ENAMEX> to do that you know i still live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Jose</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		wow that's fabulous you see now that's that's interesting because i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX> whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> works for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hewlett Packard</ENAMEX> up in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX> area he he lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andover</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah it
 		oh yeah
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh the work that he he's uh specifically an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineer</ENAMEX> and and does work with uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hewlett Packard</ENAMEX> machines that do uh  uh sonographic imagining
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and uh i've been over to see his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> over there and it's amazing it's it's all ecologically designed and and uh he seems really really happy with the the set up
 	
 	
 		um
 		yeah yeah in fact i know a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who works at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andover</ENAMEX> who used to work who i used to work with out here and he moved his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> back east <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years ago</TIMEX> to to take that position
 	
 	
 		and
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		kind of interesting um uh anyhow
 		
 		
 	