
 
     		
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		okay so what kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> do you want to buy next
 	
 	
 		uh well i don't that's a tough decision um at the moment i probably should go for something that's that's more on the practical side of things
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		um so i don't know right now i drive a uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Volkswagen Golf GTI</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> and that's a great little <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> for me because it's it's fun to drive plus you can fold the backseats down and and it's got a lot of storage room
 	
 	
 		well do you have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are you married
 	
 	
 		no huh-uh i'm single
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well i am um divorced just just like in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three days</TIMEX> i'll be divorced and i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> and um i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pontiac</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">six thousand</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh wow
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and um that's worn out and and if i would have had the money to go buy a car i would probably get a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toyota</ENAMEX> just because
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 		really
 	
 	
 		that's what everybody says i should get when i get a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toyota</ENAMEX> they supposed to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">just last forever</TIMEX> you know and um if i had my choice i'd want a minivan
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh probably a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plymouth</ENAMEX> Voyager one of them other ones you know one of them that's what i would want  lots of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		
 
 		right right
 	
 	
 		have room for them <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> to you know move around and not get cramped up and fuss you know so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		plenty of room for all the toys and everything
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but i would probably you know want something with really good gas mileage because i'm cheap  you know so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		that would probably be my choices <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> choices
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah i always try and go for something a little more sporty just because i don't have the
 	
 	
 		well you're single and you know
 	
 	
 		yeah i don't have the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> to worry about it's just me selfish me
 	
 	
 		yeah have them <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> look at you in that sports <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> driving  oh goodness
 	
 	
 		well true true  i'm sure it doesn't hurt
 		but uh yeah actually um i don't know you know that brings up the the question about uh <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> versus imports
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know there's a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> saying buy <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> again you know but obviously uh neither of us would if we uh  had the option um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		no i wouldn't no i wouldn't
 	
 	
 		i guess yours is based on previous experience then maybe
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well we had a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Honda</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Accord</ENAMEX>
 		and um an older <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> it was a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty one</NUMEX> and um it just you know lasted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">forever</TIMEX> it was a really good car
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and um so i like them
 		but um i have a couple of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> that have <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Toyotas</ENAMEX> and and they have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred and fifty two hundred thousand</NUMEX> miles and not a thing goes wrong with them
 	
 	
 		wow
 	
 	
 		get great gas mileage and they still just run run run and i've got this poor pitiful <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pontiac</ENAMEX> and thing breaks down every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">other day</TIMEX> so you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so i don't know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i don't know it's it's it's interesting um
 		you know i don't
 	
 	
 		so if you were married and had <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> what would you want to buy
 	
 	
 		oh jeez if i was married and had <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> uh do i have a budget or not
 	
 	
 		of course you have a budget you're married and have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 		it depends are you a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> or a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> then you don't have a budget or you just have a bigger one
 	
 	
 		yeah no no not yet
 		
 
 		yeah yeah i guess everyone has a budget more or less um yeah i don't i don't know that's a good question um
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		i actually really like uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jeep</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Cherokees uh</ENAMEX>-huh
 	
 	
 		ooh i do too i like them
 	
 	
 		yeah they're the problem is they're pretty expensive um
 	
 	
 		they are well all  just about everything is expensive now i mean you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">minivans</ENAMEX> are way on up there you know they're real expensive and
 	
 	
 		true
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so you know
 	
 	
 		yeah but i don't know a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a</NUMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Cherokee</ENAMEX> would be nice uh or or a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Wagoneer</ENAMEX> uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		or gosh i don't know uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">station wagon</ENAMEX> of some sort you know that that be an an alternative i'm i'm not too sold on the minivan idea uh
 	
 	
 		you don't you don't like them
 	
 	
 		well you know i've never driven one so i can't really criticize them fairly but
 	
 	
 		i like riding in them
 	
 	
 		do you
 	
 	
 		i love them i think they're just great <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> have them and they're great they're i really like them
 	
 	
 		they uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		hm
 	
 	
 		um i rode my one of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> has a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dodge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Caravan</ENAMEX> and one has a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Plymouth Voyager</ENAMEX> and i liked the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Plymouth Voyager</ENAMEX> the best
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		hm
 	
 	
 		you know it was a little bit fancier
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know  they haven't had a bit of problem with them
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		they ride ride real smooth and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> have room and
 		you know i like them
 	
 	
 		right
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so
 		anyway
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah um i don't know i always like to to look for something a little with a little more power that's that's that's my main complaint against um like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toyota</ENAMEX> is because i think they always under power their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		do they
 	
 	
 		yeah um you know i mean they're they're great if if you're really looking for maximum uh
 		
 		
 	