
 
     		
 	
 		okay so i guess it starts recording now
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		i don't know really know that much about the recycling in this area that we're in we live in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Saginaw</ENAMEX> area
 	
 	
 		Saginaw
 	
 	
 		um-hum and i'm not real familiar with uh anything that i in fact the far as i know the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> doesn't have any kind of programs or anything out here and uh or the grocery <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">story</ENAMEX> or anything in this area yeah
 	
 	
 		really
 		the recycling we live in Plano
 		and
 		they started off recycling by
 		um
 		putting the i think at each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wal-Mart</ENAMEX> they had some recycling
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dumpsters</ENAMEX> and things like that which it now i guess the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> has has bought these
 		big green trash cans and uh
 		we they have a recycling truck that comes around now
 		and you separate your <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glass</ENAMEX> and
 		paper
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh aluminum
 		and you set it out and they pick it up and it it works real neat they seem to be having a real good response
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		but
 	
 	
 		that is pretty good i'm we're originally from another <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> and i know in the state we were from that they did that type similar type thing the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> brought out
 		you know separate trash separate trash cans and you separated your stuff and you put it in there and they took it you know
 	
 	
 		did they
 		did they like on bottles did they give you a
 		so many cents back for
 	
 	
 		i don't really know i don't really know they they started after we moved down here and so i i'm not really familiar i just know that and my in-laws up in up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX> that's how they do you know they pick it up but i don't know if they get a
 	
 	
 		for cans even i've seen that in
 		really
 	
 	
 		get anything back on it or do you get money for it
 	
 	
 		no i've just i noticed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> like that it's a nickel
 		per aluminum can
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		so you don't see too many thrown out around the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		even bottles you know all kinds of bottles they they
 		they really charge <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to uh i guess when you purchase them and and then when you turn them back in
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		i know i remember <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the old days</TIMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> where
 		a bottle was <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a nickel</NUMEX> and
 	
 	
 		right and now now most of them are the throwaway
 	
 	
 		
 
 		right so maybe that's one thing they could do to
 	
 	
 		and yeah i think now they're a lot more expensive than that um
 		i bought some Cokes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX> the little bottles
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know and i think the bottles were like
 		i know they were <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">at least ten cents</NUMEX> apiece i was trying to figure out how i was like God how much were those bottles you know and it was they come in like uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> and and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> packs you know
 	
 	
 		well that's
 		right
 	
 	
 		instead of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> packs and uh and they were like it was like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> dollars and something for the bottles you know i was like God Almighty costs more for the bottles than it did for the Cokes
 	
 	
 		that was my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> job in a grocery <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> he was in the bottle area
 	
 	
 		we're gonna bump our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heads</ENAMEX> what a job
 	
 	
 		it's pretty dangerous out there you know when they fall over but but it's uh
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		it's quite they say that the green glass now that there's a big glut
 	
 	
 		oh really

 	
 	
 		of green
 	
 	
 		of green glass
 	
 	
 		with the green glass yeah it's amazing
 	
 	
 		uh well out in this area they really don't have anything now i know that like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Minyard</ENAMEX>'s
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and places like that around like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arlington</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort Worth</ENAMEX> and a lot of those grocery <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> they have like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> different bins out front
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		yeah different colors for different things and
 		and things like that but i i did know some of these places were doing that and they discontinued them because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> coming and dumping their trash in them
 	
 	
 		right yeah it's i notice the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">plastics</ENAMEX> have sort of
 		faded away the milk jugs it it's
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> just they they really don't uh there's too much labor involved i guess to separate the stuff
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah it's i don't know it it can be it's not as easy
 	
 	
 		more than it's worth
 		
 
 	
 	
 		collecting you know clean junk as they say
 	
 	
 		right right well who wants to clean their junk before they throw it away
 	
 	
 		that's right that's right
 		it's like washing the dishes before you put them in the dishwasher
 	
 	
 		right i know
 	
 	
 		we all do it
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		well it was nice talking to you
 	
 	
 		it was nice talking to you i have no idea how long this is supposed to last or anything
 	
 	
 		well i think i think <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three minutes</TIMEX> is fine and yeah
 	
 	
 		it is that it okay well it was nice talking to you and i i guess i'll do this for i was doing this from actually i was gonna do it for my son
 		so that he could uh he he's in high school so that he could uh make some money
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and but then it has my name on it so i'm like okay i'll sit down here and call it
 	
 	
 		oh we're doing it for a church <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">choir</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		oh are you
 	
 	
 		yeah so
 	
 	
 		oh that's interesting that's nice well thank you good-bye
 	
 	
 		well thank you bye bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	