
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		actually to tell you the truth i think uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> selection is a uh prime
 		uh discussion topic in terms of possible improvements on uh
 		uh finding of uh guilt
 	
 	
 		hm i certainly can't argue with that definitely does need some improvements uh and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> can throw <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> out for no reason whatsoever just because they want to
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah i think there's a limit on that the uh the uh peremptory challenges are limited to i don't know how many but you can
 	
 	
 		i think it's
 		it's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four or five</NUMEX> i can't remember which i was on a jury trial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> only i got kicked out
 		as uh the last selection
 		that the uh defense got
 	
 	
 		hm
 		yeah i it seems to me i'm always challenged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peremptorily</ENAMEX> also when i go to these things i think i have a severe demeanor or something
 	
 	
 		hm  that uh
 	
 	
 		uh
 		but typically you know basically uh typically
 		uh everyone gets involved in uh the jury process and
 		i suppose an elitist might say well you really want someone who's well educated to be able to to winnow the facts from the from the prejudice
 	
 	
 		right but it still has to be a group of your peers
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		see
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		so if it's your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peers</ENAMEX> and you're not educated
 	
 	
 		so if you're a nincompoop on trial you'd you'd have to have nincompoops to uh
 	
 	
 		then
 		you want you want a nincompoop <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> because they'll sympathize with you a bit
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		as well as hopefully being honest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and do their best to comply with the facts as they were presented to them so that's why the defense is there
 		picking through them whereas at the same time the uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> sitting there picking through them because he wants somebody who will give him uh a guilty verdict if the facts warrant
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so uh i think the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> selection process is pretty neat but i don't think that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> ought to be the ones picking the punishment
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		afterwards i think that should be left up to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who have some knowledge in the subject and more knowledge than a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> would have i mean you're talking about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s already been found guilty
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right and many times i've seen on trials they have on TV the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> will make a recommendation as to leniency or as to the death penalty or whatever but i think that it should be up to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> and the uh lawyers
 		to make the decision as to what the actual penalty will be
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		maybe just the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> because they're the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who know what the system is and what it's all about and believe in the system
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		hm
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and i think that would provide a more fair sentencing procedure
 	
 	
 		well i suppose you may be right on that
 	
 	
 		as opposed to an emotional sentencing procedure also may be a more consistent sentencing procedure
 	
 	
 		as a matter of fact i've heard that
 		i've heard that some of the information uh is prevented from reaching the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> like uh mitigating circumstances or or preceding uh criminal record or things of this nature that
 	
 	
 		well preceding criminal record according to the judicial process has nothing to do with the current crime
 		but when it comes to uh sentencing for punishment of course if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s never done anything bad before according to the judicial system
 		then they're going to lean towards a slightly more lenient side and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX>'s supposed to be notified of criminal records when it comes to sentencing by jury
 	
 	
 		oh is it oh i didn't realize that okay
 	
 	
 		at least in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> they're supposed to be not during the trial during the trial as to whether they're guilty or not has nothing to do with their background
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but when it comes to what kind of sentence you're going to lay down
 		i think that uh that they should
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i don't i don't know that they always have because i never sat all the way through a jury trial they get too boring
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		so you're what you're saying is if if this is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offense</ENAMEX> then you execute them
 	
 	
 		well if it's a second offense the punishment should certainly be more severe than a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offense</ENAMEX> because obviously the rehabilitation process did not work the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so you got to give them either more time in the system or a different process that'll hopefully work better
 		uh
 		when it comes down to things like alternative sentencing i'm all for that
 		for uh small crimes infractions and misdemeanors or parking tickets or traffic tickets that have gone to warrant you give them the option of working off their time doing civil service sort of things
 	
 	
 		what about uh white collar crimes like uh theft of trade secrets
 	
 	
 		i think those ought to be punished a whole lot worse than they are
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		like what
 	
 	
 		well uh say embezzlement right you get a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> down the street
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		who comes up uh carrying a knife
 		
 		
 	