
 
     		
 	
 		so have you heard about Saturns
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i've heard some about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saturns i</ENAMEX> don't know
 		a lot about them i haven't been over uh to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealer</ENAMEX> to look at them although i did see something in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX>'s paper that said that their uh reliability is rated to be equal to that of the i guess the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		ooh that's great actually that's kind of the type of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> that i i'm thinking about
 		we might get Saturns you can't go to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealer</ENAMEX> unless you go to a a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Saturn</ENAMEX> dealer
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah this this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offshoot</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GM</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh supposedly they've got great customer
 		
 
 		satisfaction from what things i've heard
 	
 	
 		hm yeah i've heard a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like them uh
 		yeah i don't know whether whether i would buy <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Saturn</ENAMEX> or not at this point i'm kind of
 		my card and uh
 		desires tend to be pretty picky and so uh
 	
 	
 		well like what
 	
 	
 		well let's see i like i like <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> that are
 		designed with with human beings in mind and that's not just the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passenger</ENAMEX> but that's the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> whose working on it because i do almost almost all my own maintenance
 		and uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		those types of things and i found that while you can find some <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> that are comfortable to ride in uh
 		finding a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car car</ENAMEX> anymore that's that's fairly easy for me to work on it just not very easy it's not very
 		almost unlikely at this point
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh
 	
 	
 		yeah i've got a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixty five Mustang</TIMEX> and i and i do the work on most of the work on that myself
 	
 	
 		
 
 		ooh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and when i look at modern <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> and stuff like  i just say i will never do that with the modern <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> it's not worth my time you can't get in there you can't do anything
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and it's so complicated too i look at it and i say <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> you know i i'd have to almost
 		go take a class or something like that
 	
 	
 		well i've got an <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saab</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh i find that for a normal you know everyday things it's really very easy to work on and so uh
 		now i'm kind of spoiled i used to have an old uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chevy</ENAMEX> uh with a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> fifty in it and uh i really liked working on it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		
 
 	
 	
 		ah cause it was pretty easy too it was about a nineteen seventy
 		so i'm kind of uh
 		biased in that and you know i want a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> that i can work on because i think it just costs too much even to get the oil changed anymore
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and that's kind of that's that's probably one thing i'd look at i think another thing i'd look at is safety
 	
 	
 		yeah that's one of the things that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and i have thought about actually the car
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> we'd most like to get would be the new <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ninety one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Taurus</ENAMEX> because they're actually one of the cheaper <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> that have dual side air bags
 	
 	
 		hm
 		that's a real nice <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> i think
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i've driven some uh
 		Tauruses over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last couple of years</TIMEX> when i've been on business trips uh as rental <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> and i've always been very impressed
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tauruses</ENAMEX> it's a really nice <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> i think it's very
 		it's a stylish car both inside and out it's comfortable to drive
 		uh
 		reasonable performance and this is out in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>  where where they don't make a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> that's got reasonable performance anymore
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh i've been real impressed with that you you and i didn't realize that they were putting dual uh air bags in that car now
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ninety</ENAMEX> yep then or excuse me the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ninety two</NUMEX>'s the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ninety two</NUMEX>'s had dual air bags this newest <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX> you could get them with duals
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well i think that
 		that's excellent that's excellent because
 	
 	
 		yeah but the thing is is that it's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty thousand</TIMEX> dollars actually my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and i are actually thinking contemplating buying a new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> in the next
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year and a half</TIMEX> or so so we're actually been looking around and thinking about things we'd like to get like a
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		oh i don't know what do you call it a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealer</ENAMEX> return type thing on a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ninety two and ninety three</NUMEX> or something like that you know year old <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ninety two</NUMEX> or something like that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		sure
 	
 	
 		see if we can
 	
 	
 		those are yeah that that'd be a good deal to go with
 	
 	
 		and the other thing we're looking at is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saturns</ENAMEX> too because they looked really nice
 	
 	
 		okay
 		um-hum what do you what do you looking for in in those what attracts what attracts you to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saturns</ENAMEX> or or or of course we've already talked you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Taurus</ENAMEX> is safe but what what kind of things are you looking for
 	
 	
 		well the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">the Saturns</ENAMEX> you can get air bags in them i don't think you can get dual side air bags but one of the things the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> things that i'm really
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i'd say the most important thing is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> that's not gonna fall apart that doesn't have problems
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you set down you look at consumer reports we been pouring over consumer reports and you just get so depressed for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> auto
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">makers</ENAMEX> when you do that because you see the reliability and the types of problems they have and
 		and the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> that apparently are close to that that actually have high reliability the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Taurus</ENAMEX> is one of the highest <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and the other one is are the Saturns
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so those <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> things and then you know
 		we kind of want a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> door
 	
 	
 		okay
 		
 		
 	