
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		kind of like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mitre Corporation</ENAMEX> only uh uh we work mainly with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX> in terms of satellites
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">alright</ENAMEX> and um so um in other words your your <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">butter</ENAMEX> comes from the federal government
 	
 	
 		the the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> yes uh
 	
 	
 		right so your your uh your life sort of follows it's  flow
 	
 	
 		that's correct
 	
 	
 		so um how are the benefits set up are they set up like they are in the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> or are they
 	
 	
 		uh actually no um it turns out that uh we are a non profit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> so the the benefits are different um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i mean basically you get you know the the health care coverage uh one of the big pluses for this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> was you would get um
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three weeks</TIMEX> of vacation to start normally in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> when you work for one of the defense <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contractors</ENAMEX> they give you <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three weeks</TIMEX> to start but all of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> shut down <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between Christmas</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">New Year</TIMEX>'s so you end up
 		in essence only getting <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks</TIMEX> of voluntary vacation and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one week</TIMEX> of involuntary vacation is you want to look at it that way
 	
 	
 		sure i see what you're saying
 	
 	
 		uh where as in our uh for our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> they did not have until very recently a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> shutdown between <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">New Year</TIMEX>'s
 		uh the idea is that you've got the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three weeks</TIMEX> and you can take it whenever you want it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so that was a big plus benefit for this company
 	
 	
 		and that's just recently been taken away from you
 	
 	
 		uh well <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past couple of years</TIMEX> because of uh cut backs and and whatnot they uh basically have put down and told <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that you either take a week of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">vacation between Christmas</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">New Year</TIMEX>'s or take a week of no pay
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		uh the it's up to you you have the choice and so the the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> does shut down <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between Christmas</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">New Year</TIMEX>'s i don't believe that this is a long term
 		solution that they're going to use but uh they have been doing it for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past couple of years</TIMEX> and they may do it for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> more
 	
 	
 		development yeah
 		well um you say now you say you get your health benefits is this a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one hundred</NUMEX> percent coverage
 	
 	
 		uh
 		uh-huh no i don't think any of unless of course you go with an HMO
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh the thing is that they also do not have uh eye glass coverage so if you need eye glasses you're on your own uh they also do not provide uh well they do provide dental if you go with an HMO though you lose the
 		um the choose choice of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> if you take their you know they have one of these <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cafeteria</ENAMEX> plans so you you either choose the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMO</ENAMEX> or you choose the
 	
 	
 		ability to choose
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um i guess blue cross and blue shield is who they have now and the idea there is that if you go with one of their associated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> they'll pay eighty percent if you go with a non associated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> they pay seventy percent
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so that that  i have to admit i mean when i <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> started out you were covered completely and it was not a um
 		an HMO type of thing i i when i <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> started out in engineering i worked for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RCA</ENAMEX> back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid seventies</TIMEX> and uh they just covered everything
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		sure
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but uh you know i've watched this slowly erode erode erode until the point where now um i figure that the next thing is going to be uh you're going to have to pay big bucks and they're only going to pay cover certain certain uh diseases
 	
 	
 		well that's it certainly looks the way things are headed right now if uh something isn't done at the i guess at the federal level or
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		or something i don't know about this but it's uh i um worked for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a number of years</TIMEX> as support <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> in law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">law firms</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Area</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i kind of had exactly the same experience uh law the especially during the seventies and eighties law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> were just rolling in the money
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh it's a little bit less that way now the recession has even hurt a lot of the big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">law firms</ENAMEX> in this area but um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the result uh was during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that period</TIMEX> that not only did we get <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one hundred</NUMEX> percent benefits in terms of health care and so forth but they were rather extravagant plans that we were
 		party to with with uh full dental and
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		uh you know optical stuff stuff for our eyes and uh and so forth and i have to confess i had a couple of real bad health scares during that time and found that it really came in handy the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMO</ENAMEX> idea
 	
 	
 		uh-huh right
 		wow
 	
 	
 		appeared on the scene i guess in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid eighties</TIMEX> and i tried a couple of them out
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and in fact have eventually settled on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of them i've change jobs now but this the same HMO is still available in my current position and and um
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		it's it's uh i the interesting thing they've done some interesting things with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMO</ENAMEX>'s in this area where you there are a number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> and you can choose amongst the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> that are available in fact uh
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of them that's run by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudential</ENAMEX> has essentially signed up a bunch of private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX> in the the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Area</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	