
 
     		
 	
 		i guess i'll give my opinions here first okay uh in terms of taxes here i guess uh i feel like we are paying an awful lot of them uh and getting apparently very little for it
 	
 	
 		
 
 		okay
 	
 	
 		uh especially since uh the things that i think that our taxes are going for are i i guess in my opinion not the uh appropriate necessarily appropriate things
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i think that uh uh we should be emphasizing uh things like more like education and less on on programs which are permanent black holes which will never
 		do anything but continue to be uh uh
 		sponges for money
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i mean we need to do uh programs which are more on the concept of
 		uh
 		well like one of the concepts they had before was trying to renovate the housing
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but uh then turning the housing over that now see i i agreed with that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and i'm not very often into those kind of those kind of programs but that one made sense
 		help these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to fix their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> to improve their their environment i mean uh uh projects projects were the most idiotic concept in the world
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you had they had no sense of ownership no sense of responsibility
 	
 	
 		like a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">warehouse</ENAMEX> almost
 	
 	
 		it well it was like it's just a place for you to stay and you had no uh feeling of of responsibility ownership concern uh in fact it was insulting it was it was almost insulting it was embarrassing it was so embarrassing
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that i you know i i i i don't know exactly what the motivations were but basically they were destroyed they were they uh you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would strew feces across the uh
 		uh rooms you know just incredible the abuses that occured it was obviously a failed concept okay  so yes i think we do have problems with taxes
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well  uh-huh
 		well the uh unfortunate truth is that
 		no matter what sort of a program or whatever that uh gets put out there and made available by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX>' money
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		there is going to be someone who will abuse it they will find a way <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are very creative especially those that are on the public dole and want to be there
 		uh they can be very creative in their in their abuses and not surprisingly some of the worst <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offenders</ENAMEX> are the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are inside the system
 		and are in a position to know exactly where the red flags would be what they can get away with
 		uh i happen to work for an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assemblyman</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time and i saw abuse of power there uh really subtle
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but it was still there okay uh the man
 		was not a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">millionaire</ENAMEX> uh however he could have never gone to work again and lived comfortably
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh he owned a lot of low income housing for which he got considerable government aid
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		refurbish it and
 	
 	
 		and it was all legal
 	
 	
 		oh sure
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and oh doing a public service and like like i say you're right in that we're paying an awful lot well not really comparatively to
 	
 	
 		right
 		other countries
 	
 	
 		uh other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> especially <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> they pay a larger percentage than we do but the things that they get in return are more tangible
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		to the common <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> national health care uh education systems that you know that's one of mine own pet <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">peeves</ENAMEX> is how can how can our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> be so damn efficient
 	
 	
 		well if it's nothing okay
 	
 	
 		that they can teach our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred and eighty</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> what it takes <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two hundred and forty days</TIMEX> to teach you know how can they be that good come on  come on
 	
 	
 		right
 		well i uh then what it really comes down to the fact that uh uh
 		we don't have enough balls to actually make these programs work
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh well part part of the symptom symptom of a democratic system system is that it it kind of uh freezes itself up
 		you very seldom able able able able to do anything that's strong on either side whether it be left or right
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i mean i mean sometimes i say you know even though i tend to go with the with the conservative line i sit there and i say you know at least if we did something
 		
 
 		it would be better than what we do now
 	
 	
 		oh yeah um who it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ross Perot</ENAMEX> was speaking in front of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Press Club</ENAMEX> and he was talking about how <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> say well you know we've got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">eighty billion dollars</NUMEX> in fraud and mismanagement okay
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">hundred eighty billion dollars</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> just sort of going out of window and why don't they do anything to stop it well it'd cost <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a billion dollars</NUMEX> to track all the fraud and mismanagement well guess what i think that's a really good return on investment don't you
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billion</NUMEX> versus <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred and eighty billion</NUMEX>
 		
 		
 	