
 
     		
 	
 		well i think that there's uh a few things i would like to see um in the work environment that could improve things and number one is um
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		health benefits things like uh insurance for number one but another would be like <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">um  facilities</ENAMEX> or the ease some easy way to go out and exercise or something like that if you felt like it in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the middle the day</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		i i definitely agree on that um i'm working for a law firm right now the benefits are not bad the only thing i think that they're desperately missing is we have no dental plan whatsoever
 	
 	
 		um yeah same here
 	
 	
 		um
 		but as far as what i'd really like to see is i live close enough to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> that i would be able to bicycle in if i could
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		if there was some sort of provided provided <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> for that um maybe a locker area a shower area to change to take a shower before work
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and some place to lock the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bicycles</ENAMEX> up
 		and i've heard of a lot of other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> providing that
 		that would be something to look forward to
 		um
 		
 
 		let's see
 	
 	
 		another one i'd like to see would be in flexible scheduling of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		well a lot depends on the job though
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		what do you do
 	
 	
 		well right now i'm still in school i'm still a student but the ability to
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		you know kind of have a little bit of freedom over that to schedule your work from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">from week to week</TIMEX> so every once in a while you can slip in a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three day weekend</TIMEX> without having to use a day vacation or or just something like that
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		feel like taking a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> and you just come in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX> for a while or something like that
 	
 	
 		yeah that would be nice
 	
 	
 		and
 	
 	
 		i suppose that does depend on the type of job type of environment you're in
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um  i'm right now also a full time student
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and uh but i work in the evenings for the law firm
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so it's a rather yeah it's a rather interesting uh
 		rather interesting interesting set up  work full time go to school full time
 	
 	
 		yeah that can be rough
 		yeah i did that for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a year</TIMEX> and had my fill of that
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		swore to never do it again
 	
 	
 		but
 	
 	
 		i think another thing um would be nice i guess this is more of an overall really nebulous kind of thing would be consideration of
 		um  like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> in some in somebody's in the way that somebody relates to the work place
 	
 	
 		how so
 	
 	
 		um well an example would be in the military they give a whole lot of allowances for family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> they even get paid more
 		they get um allowances for
 		um you know have being married or having <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> i don't really think that that is fair i think uh equal work equal pay for equal work ought to be applied in that case
 	
 	
 		well they do
 	
 	
 		but um they get housing and stuff like that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah i have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> that are in the military and they do get quite a lot of perks
 	
 	
 		and other considerations as well you know their the duty is a little bit different and stuff like that
 	
 	
 		right right
 	
 	
 		but that you know recently there was some kind of documentary on some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">station</ENAMEX> i don't know what and some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> was on there he was a middle level <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> and he was talking about how
 		you know here he'd spent all these <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> putting in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">fifty hour</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX> um you know for these various places he'd worked at now you know here he was totally unemployed and been unemployed for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nine months</TIMEX> and it got him absolutely nothing
 		some kind of consideration there would be nice as well
 		i don't know what would be the solution i suppose uh
 		not foolishly giving an extra <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ten hours</TIMEX> a week to some place
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		if they're just gonna <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pork</ENAMEX> you in the end
 	
 	
 		um what a lot what a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> do is far as far as their health benefits are concerned the insurance provides um coverage for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouse</ENAMEX> and or family
 		in a lot of cases i know that's the case in my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> at least
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		they'll provide minimum benefits for your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouse</ENAMEX> and dependent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">codependent children</ENAMEX> not like the case applies to me but um
 		it is nice that they offer it
 	
 	
 		yeah it's a good consideration for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>
 		that's absolute necessity in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s world and price
 	
 	
 		definitely and health insurance costs
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> they're getting so expensive
 		right now i don't have any health insurance it's kind of disturbing unless you
 	
 	
 		you you're not still covered under your parents
 	
 	
 		no i'm gonna be <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty this year</TIMEX> but
 	
 	
 		oh wow  when you said you were going to school full time
 	
 	
 		and yeah i'm working on my PhD
 	
 	
 		oh that's different
 	
 	
 		it's a long road  but the insurance they have at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> is kind of uh they've got a really minimum plan and it'll cover you you know and as a student you don't need a whole lot if
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		if you lose a leg or something like that you just need the skin folded over you know you know just something to keep you alive till you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduate</ENAMEX> and make some money and i suppose can go out and get it fixed then
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 		right
 		what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> is this
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Georgia Tech</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh wow
 	
 	
 		but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> it is just uh really expensive <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years ago</TIMEX> it was <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">two hundred dollars</NUMEX> for the basic uh major medical and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next year</TIMEX> it was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four hundred</NUMEX> you know it doubled in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> like that
 	
 	
 		wow
 	
 	
 		and so this this is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that year</TIMEX> that was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four hundred</NUMEX> i just wasn't prepared to pay for it i'm not too sure what i'm gonna do about that right now there's still another <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six months</TIMEX> to go and it's not a pleasant feeling worrying about that
 	
 	
 		right now
 		right now the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that picks up the insurance they pay i think it's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> dollars a month
 		so that'll be at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three sixty a year</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		and that's basic uh group health coverage
 	
 	
 		is there any deductible with that or anything like
 	
 	
 		no
 		
 		
 	