
 
     		
 	
 		well um as far as the as far as spending goes
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		the way um the way i see it in the in the last article i read was that i think <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> ought to spend the same amount of money that we're spending but i think the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> need to take advantage of it more than they are
 		because i know the article i read stated that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> had um what was it like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven million</NUMEX> not <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a million</NUMEX> but like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred and ten thousand</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		offered to it or more than that and it didn't take advantage of all the money that it was offered
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> that i'm in has is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> largest in <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> cases
 		and it's just not taking advantage of the money that's being provided
 	
 	
 		i wasn't aware that there was a very large uh gay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well there's well well we have we have our own you know that we have i guess a fair share um and it's it's
 		spreading outside of of the homosexual community
 	
 	
 		interesting
 		yeah and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX> is sort of the homosexual capital of the Southeast so we have quite a few cases here and of course we here a lot about it because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Centers for Disease Control</ENAMEX> is located here
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh my feeling on the funding issue is uh
 		uh proportion in proportion to the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are dying of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX>
 		uh compared to uh other diseases like <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> and heart disease
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we're spending many many times more on <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> research than we are for these other diseases
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i think a lot of it's just due to political clout and pressure
 	
 	
 		well also because it's so new
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> and such doesn't spread as readily to other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> as it does as <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> does
 	
 	
 		that well yes that's true but also uh we haven't learned enough about cancer to be able to prevent it but it many ways <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> is completely preventable through uh behavioral changes
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i do think that uh part of the reason that we haven't made as much progress in <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> research and the reason we're spending so much money on it is that it's almost all of the research is in the hands of the government
 		and we all know how efficient the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is uh the way i look at it is if uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		if all the internal bickering between in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center for Disease Control</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Institutes of Health</ENAMEX> health uh over who's going to get credit for solving it were to be set aside
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and if private industry just through the profit motive more than anything else were set loose to go off and find uh
 		a cure with the promise that they'd be able to get the financial rewards from it uh i feel that we'd find a cure really quick
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh but as it is it's just being the whole program is just being mismanaged by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bureaucrats</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and it's real disappointing uh
 		you know so many of the other uh major advances that we have <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> are are done by private industry but for some reason in this case no one's really willing to give them a chance
 	
 	
 		that's true
 		i hadn't i hadn't thought about that
 	
 	
 		uh
 		course you know i'm a big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocate</ENAMEX> of the free market anyway and uh it seems to me that so much of what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> gets involved in
 		just just goes to pot
 		uh but
 		uh i
 		uh i do want there to be a cure
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 		uh
 		but like so many other things i think the way just the way that we're going about it is not the best way
 	
 	
 		well um i i think
 		a lot of a lot i mean this is a this is a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a an</NUMEX> a totally new experience we haven't come really ever come across at least not in my like time that you know where we've come across a disease that has spread this rapidly
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> and that we've you know is is changing i know just in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last three months</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDC</ENAMEX> has come back and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">redefined AIDS</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		you know and so i mean it's it's very difficult to put a cure on something that you keep expanding
 		and we keep you know and all the new um you know things that we keep finding you know that you can be <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX> positive for you know now what have they bumped it up to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> now
 	
 	
 		uh it's a long time
 	
 	
 		yeah you know
 	
 	
 		and it's interesting that there are there do seem to be a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX> positive but who never get the disease
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it seems to me that it's it's likely that there's some other uh it's not just the virus that causes it but it's something else in your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> that the virus triggers
 		uh that causes it and if they can find whatever that other that other trigger
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	