
 
     		
 	
 		well <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen</ENAMEX> do you think that uh all our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> are totally dishonest or are they just making mistakes like their uh banking business
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i think some of them are dishonest and some of them are probably honest mistakes
 		it's hard to me to imagine that somebody's going to overwrite uh what what was the largest amount of checks and write out a check for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five thousand dollars</NUMEX> and not know they're overdrawing their account
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but on the other hand somebody you know making a couple of overdrawing checks probably isn't a major phenomena i think they're under a lot of pressure especially when there's money involved
 		and it's hard to keep them honest when they're there for a long time
 	
 	
 		oh i think so too and i think that's just about the only thing you can do to to clean up <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> or clean up the political side of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is to kick the bums out periodically limit the terms
 	
 	
 		well that bothers me because again we ought to have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> where we can choose who we want and when you you know limit terms and you say well even if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> want this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> they can't have them
 		which is kind of a hard situation too
 	
 	
 		yeah but but the longer they stay i'm and i'm  assuming we're just talking about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> i don't know that much about the state government i figure it's pretty rotten too
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i mean even the city council's are a little weird if you look at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		or a lot weird
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah but but
 		have you been to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		have have you watched those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> in action i mean i visited the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> and sat there in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">gallery</ENAMEX> and watched those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> up there pontificating to a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> of no one
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and and it it  their their posturing their
 		i don't know i it it's like their not in the real world or something and maybe that's why they have
 		have trouble drawing lines as to what's illegal and what's not
 	
 	
 		well i mean the other problem is is that they're always up for reelection
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		so that they're always not making the right decision but the politically correct decision
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and it it i think that's hard for them
 		plus when you you put the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyist</ENAMEX> back there i wish somehow we could limit lobbyist
 	
 	
 		well
 	
 	
 		i think that's a greater problem because they're constantly trying to
 		use their influence in not always the most positive ways
 	
 	
 		yes that's true i i think they do things that make it easier for our elected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> to have to live the good life
 	
 	
 		
  
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i mean if you if you just look at at what goes on in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> don't live the same way i do anyway
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		it's almost that they're royalty of some sort and i think that's why they forget sometimes that laws apply to them too
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh</ENAMEX> seems to me somehow if they could draw a straight salary and not have any other benefits
 		and you know i don't know what the salary ought to be but i think that would decrease somewhat the the need for the kinds of things that sometimes happen
 	
 	
 		yeah but aren't they making something like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred and ten thousand</NUMEX> a year
 	
 	
 		well i was shocked i was happened to be reading the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters guide</ENAMEX> in the last election and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senator</ENAMEX> a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a</NUMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Representative</ENAMEX> makes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred and</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty</TIMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">nine thousand dollars</NUMEX> a year
 		which kind of blew my mind  yes yes i'd like to make that much
 	
 	
 		that's more uh
 		that's a lot more than i make  huh huh
 		well run for office
 	
 	
 		uh no thanks
 	
 	
 		yeah they i i what gets me is when they pass laws and they always manage to exempt themselves from them
 	
 	
 		or raise they give themselves raises when they're trying to cut government expenses
 	
 	
 		oh yes but i mean is it no wonder that there's not a balanced budget when they can't even handle their own checking accounts
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i don't know
 	
 	
 		and the other problem is you know one of the other questions it asked is is is there someway we can make all unethical things illegal and i'm just convinced you can't legislate common sense
 	
 	
 		no probably not
 	
 	
 		and that seems to be something that a lot of them are missing
 	
 	
 		that's right i they get caught up i think in the
 		the glamour and the power and whatnot and probably make bad decisions bad choices sometimes
 	
 	
 		and i think part of the other problem is is because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> has such a bad reputation <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who might really do well in it
 		tend to avoid it
 		because of all the negative uh
 		feelings about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> you may have some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who could be do a really good job but they just kind of stay out of it because they don't want
 		to be associated with that kind of thing
 	
 	
 		that's true
 		that's true i wonder i wonder if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ross Perot</ENAMEX> would get elected how he would behave
 	
 	
 		i don't know little nervous about that one too
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i i think he's an honest person
 	
 	
 		yeah i think he definitely is
 		i don't
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and he and he certainly has no need to have his hands in anybody else's pockets
 	
 	
 		i'm just wondering how he would cope with the fact that he can't just do you know sort of looking at the as an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">outsider</ENAMEX> at the way he ran his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> you either did what he said or you were out
 		and i'm not sure as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> you could ever run it that
 		
 		
 	