
 
     		
 	
 		so how do you uh so it so it sounds like you've got a television going on there so i can assume that you probably watch TV news is that
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i almost never watch TV news  i get most of my news driving back and forth to work listening to the radio
 	
 	
 		really wow
 		
 
 		uh what what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">station</ENAMEX> do you listen to
 	
 	
 		uh it's a local radio station it's called uh
 		KLIF cliff
 	
 	
 		cliff i see so um it's not affiliated with anything is it not not a network <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">station</ENAMEX> okay yeah because i i listen to uh public radio a lot and they have
 	
 	
 		no no
 	
 	
 		they have KCRW which i i i saw a thing recently they may be trying to start their own uh cable TV outlet i guess they're getting a little getting a little feisty now
 	
 	
 		well this has this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">station</ENAMEX> has a lot of just ongoing news
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		and occasionally in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX> i'll pick up something like uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> or that but i hate watching the like <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ten o'clock</TIMEX> news or
 	
 	
 		yeah so you have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> or something or
 	
 	
 		yeah we have a local well we have uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dallas Morning News</ENAMEX> which is the big paper in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> we read it i read it pretty much
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		from cover to cover
 	
 	
 		how do you like it it's been  it's been a while since i read the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> news i uh
 		fact last time i read the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas Dallas</ENAMEX> news i was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX>
 		uh
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times Herald</ENAMEX> went out of business here
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		and so we really only have one <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> and one <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort Worth</ENAMEX> newspaper
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well that must be pretty bad
 		so
 		how did that happen anyway
 	
 	
 		uh financial trouble
 	
 	
 		no not how i mean when did it when did they  yeah
 	
 	
 		oh when did it happen
 		i guess they closed down <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about three months</TIMEX> ago
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		so how do you keep up
 	
 	
 		oh me i um  good grief i read the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> there's uh
 		quite a task if you've ever run into one they're uh specially
 	
 	
 		yes they're very voluminous
 	
 	
 		yeah they're thick um
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		if there's something you want to know it's it's in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> and then in in detail
 		um
 		they uh we we used to have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> and then the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herald Examiner</ENAMEX> collapsed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about two years ago</TIMEX> because of
 		oh i don't know just just nobody was buying it really
 	
 	
 		so there really is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> now
 	
 	
 		yeah pretty much um there used to be in fact i think there still is the uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily News</ENAMEX> which runs out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Fernando Valley</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and um they're not bad as far as a uh you know as far as a local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> goes in fact it was kind of weird because i met the uh i met the i met the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>
 		uh while i was on uh while i was doing jury <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Monica</ENAMEX> one time it was like we just sat around and talk about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> and stuff he was a really cool guy
 		um you know went to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia University</ENAMEX> and all this stuff
 		and uh it's it's a pretty good <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> but um you know it's not the it's not the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		although i see you know i'm starting to see some of their um there's there's a daily new
 		uh news rack right around the corner from where i live which means that they're they're expanding i guess
 		but uh and and occasionally i i pick up like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time magazine</ENAMEX> or something i think uh if they've got an interesting lead story but
 		you know it's i i don't have time
 	
 	
 		i used to read <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time magazine</ENAMEX> a lot but i don't read it much anymore
 	
 	
 		yeah that's that's kind of a problem for them there's a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who fall into that category
 	
 	
 		and then we have a local rag here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> that i pick up periodically and read just to see what's going on in our little community
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		i see
 	
 	
 		because we don't get an awful lot of coverage in the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dallas Morning News</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah  the big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dailies</ENAMEX> don't like to don't like to step much out of their uh out of their home turf i have to admit the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> is kind of provincial too
 		it's basically anything that's south of downtown they don't bother to cover
 	
 	
 		now they have started here running a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three day</TIMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> Plano section
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it's just sort of a you know <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four or five</NUMEX> pages that covers what's going on in Plano
 		but it's still not an awful lot of news
 	
 	
 		yeah i know
 		i uh
 		it was it was a big discovery when when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> found out there was a place called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Orange County</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i mean  the way they i mean the way they've been handling it before they practically they practically acted like their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> needed shots to go south of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">LA county</ENAMEX> border
 	
 	
 		oh i would imagine in uh you know  in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> they have plenty happening in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> to cover that it gets hard covering all of the suburbs suburbs and
 		of course they tend to cover the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">county</ENAMEX> and we're not in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">county</ENAMEX> so they tend to ignore places outside of the county
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh really
 		yeah yeah i i i find that attitude kind of arrogant though it's like you're taking our money but you're not bothering to cover things that are interesting to us
 	
 	
 		
  
 		yeah
 		
 		
 	