
 
     		
 	
 		hi um the most experience i know about that is just when we had my grandma and
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		she lived with us when i was a little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about three or four years</TIMEX> and then we had to put her in a rest <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> because you couldn't take care of her anymore huh
 	
 	
 		yeah she had to have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurses</ENAMEX> care
 	
 	
 		yeah that's rough isn't it
 	
 	
 		and yeah it was a really hard decision because i she had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and they had all decided that between the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> of them they could keep her at their home
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		wow
 	
 	
 		but uh her health just failed so much that they couldn't do that she needed an <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IV</ENAMEX> and things
 	
 	
 		yeah that's really hard my grandma is uh
 		just turned ninety
 	
 	
 		oh wow
 	
 	
 		and she's still on her own
 	
 	
 		oh my goodness
 	
 	
 		and she's down in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Phoenix</ENAMEX> and i don't know what we'll do when she can't take care of herself her her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> is dead
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and she has a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>  my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aunt uh</ENAMEX> who lives in another <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> but uh
 		she has
 	
 	
 		and then there's just the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandkids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh well i'm like the uh yeah i'm my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> and i are the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandkids</ENAMEX> are her only grandkids
 	
 	
 		oh wow
 	
 	
 		so i don't i don't know what's going to happen with her but she's amazingly strong uh
 	
 	
 		yeah that's what's neat is when they don't have to go into a rest <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> or anything
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		but i don't know i guess uh  most of us uh probably end up there sooner or sooner or later
 	
 	
 		yeah my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandpa</ENAMEX> lived to be <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ninety four</NUMEX> and
 	
 	
 		oh my gosh
 	
 	
 		his grandma or his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> was uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years</TIMEX> younger than him and she kept him at home his uh about the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last two years</TIMEX> of his life she had him in a hospital bed
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and you know the port a potty and stuff she he couldn't get up or anything but she threatened that she'd never put that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> in a rest <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> and she never did
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> that's amazing that's a lot of stress
 	
 	
 		oh yeah uh she has osteoporosis  i don't know how to say it
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		anyway where their back bends and stuff and the bones deteriorate and it really did a toll on her lifting him and stuff but she
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		hm
 	
 	
 		she would have died before she let anyone put him in there in a rest home
 	
 	
 		amazing
 	
 	
 		but when my grand when my <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> grandma that did go in the rest <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> we found a really nice <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> the you know we'd go visit <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">every night</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">every night</TIMEX> wow that's dedicated
 	
 	
 		and she only
 		well she was only there for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a month</TIMEX> and she was really bad we you know we knew it was coming
 	
 	
 		oh i see
 	
 	
 		and i you know we felt really bad for putting her there and stuff she was unconscious and so
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i don't know a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> say she didn't even know she was there but
 		still it was nice to be with her and stuff
 	
 	
 		yeah it's a tough emotional uh issue
 	
 	
 		well nowadays the expense is going so crazy i mean some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> they need it but they can't afford it and those are the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> i feel so bad for
 	
 	
 		yep
 		yeah that's tough
 	
 	
 		you could lose your whole retirement or whatever just
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		taking and you know nowadays a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are taking care of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> you know because they can't afford a rest <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> or whatever
 		and that does a double toll on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i don't know if i could ever put my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> in a rest <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> but
 		i don't know how we would afford it either
 	
 	
 		i remember <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time i was uh
 		i was in a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh i i was sitting alone in this <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">booth</ENAMEX> reading and eating and i overheard some  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> in the next <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">booth</ENAMEX> who i think some of them worked at the restaurant they were
 		a little younger than me and they were talking about the differences between i don't know whether they were from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> or or but they were you know definitely <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin American</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they were talking about the differences between uh how uh our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> cares for old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and what it was like back home
 		and they were just appalled that anybody could  put somebody in a you know in a rest home
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		yeah they weren't course they weren't talking about uh where you know you're absolutely unable to care for them but it was it you know they would come from large extended families
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		where you know the the old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were uh were at home
 	
 	
 		living all together weren't they
 	
 	
 		yeah and uh most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't want to live that way <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>  in this country
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i don't even know if i can handle living with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> let alone three generations
 	
 	
 		yeah  God
 		yeah i don't know i and i've been single so long i don't even know if i could handle living with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that is a challenge
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i'm probably  incorrigible you know
 	
 	
 		that and you know a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> say it's good for the elderly because they can be with you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with their same interest and their same age and stuff but i don't know i i would never want to be in a rest home
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i really don't think i'd want to
 	
 	
 		well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandma</ENAMEX>'s in a retirement <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> now and uh
 		seems to like it there a lot and stays really active and
 	
 	
 		does she have a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> or an apartment
 		
 		
 	