
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well
 	
 	
 		so uh what do you think about uh
 		uh how trials in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> are right now with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> or twelve do you think that's fair
 	
 	
 		well um i believe a trial by twelve uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peers</ENAMEX> is fair i don't think the need for a unanimous vote is fair
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		nothing in our world seems to be by unanimous vote
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		except that
 		hm we're too uh diverse a cultures i believe to make a
 		complete agreement
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		so you think that um majority rule majority rule is good enough for um deciding on a verdict of guilty or not guilty
 	
 	
 		i do
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i really do
 	
 	
 		um something that's kind of interesting is uh i lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> for a while and um in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> they don't have trial by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> they have trial uh by
 		usually <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		and uh i've discussed with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and it's it's kind of interesting uh kind of an interesting concept it sounds strange at first not to have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> by your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peers</ENAMEX> but then um the argument for it
 		is that
 		um you know
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> off the street really don't know much about law
 	
 	
 		i agree with that
 	
 	
 		and yeah and and then uh
 		i guess the argument is that they're easily influenced you know by by tricks by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> you know who dos do more psychology than trying to teach them what's right and wrong and the law they they use uh
 		you know techniques to sway their feelings whereas
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">professional</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX>
 		um
 		you know know the ins and outs of the system better
 	
 	
 		i agree i think that's very true i'm um concerned that when we uh sentence a uh a criminal to for a certain amount of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> that we don't really know what that means
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years</TIMEX> may mean <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one year</TIMEX> in reality
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and i don't think that most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are aware of that
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know i i wouldn't couldn't tell you if we sentenced someone <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX> how long he'd actually be in jail
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		could you
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		me either
 	
 	
 		no couldn't
 	
 	
 		and i think they kind of depend on that these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah definitely i don't know i think the that the um alternative is something interesting to look into uh
 	
 	
 		but it
 	
 	
 		if you you know instead of
 		instead of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">juries</ENAMEX> just by by uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh</ENAMEX> peers <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">juries</ENAMEX> by professional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um but i guess uh
 		that would take a major constitutional change here
 	
 	
 		definitely would but i see where they would be experts
 	
 	
 		right um i mean i see also how they were you know when they made the constitution they were uh afraid of that kind of thing that you know that um if the
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		government has all the power to decide who's guilty and who's not they wanted to make checks and balances against that
 	
 	
 		right it could really throw the checks and balances out of whack
 		what if one of them is corrupt
 	
 	
 		right exactly
 	
 	
 		and he is the the decision the the main decision maker
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know the the they're split either way
 	
 	
 		yeah it's uh does carry an implicit danger with it that way
 	
 	
 		it does but
 		that's kind of goes like our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> in a way
 	
 	
 		right  that's true too you know how does how does that work
 	
 	
 		
 
 		and who gets to point those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		
 
 		so they get to make the decision not the people
 	
 	
 		exactly i think it was i think it was more of a danger you know in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seventeen hundreds</NUMEX> when um really you know like the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">King of England</ENAMEX> could decide who's guilty and who's not guilty i could see how they would
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		wanna protect against that so i think the danger is less <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> would be less of a risk of you know uh corrupt <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> forcing
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 		you know someone to to be guilty for uh even though they're not or vice versa you know um but it's definitely something that would have to be watched very closely if they decided to do it that way
 	
 	
 		that's true i think a good start would be maybe some uh simple basic education into how the process really works for  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		exactly
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		on up i mean i know i know that we all learned but i really don't see it where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are learning it nowadays
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		they think it's a big game and you know
 	
 	
 		right and and um you know what what does jury duty mean not not many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> really
 	
 	
 		are are you willing to take off from work and lose <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a day</TIMEX>'s pay or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX>'s pay
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		is your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> willing to let you
 	
 	
 		right that's that's a really interesting issue too and um you know most people
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		another interesting thing is you know most most most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> try and get out of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> duty right
 	
 	
 		oh definitely
 	
 	
 		so the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that actually become <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">juries</ENAMEX> are it's not really just a random sampling of the
 		
 		
 	