
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		shall um
 		actually actually i've had i've had very good luck on consumer products lately
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 		you know just about  i've i've uh
 		gotten recently it's been a new mother <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> for my computer and that's working fine
 	
 	
 		uh a new motherboard
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		because my my other one bit the dust after after a power failure
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so i i got a you know a very inexpensive motherboard from someone in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> very happy we were very fast
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		other other than i'm i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> conservation  buying anything
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		how about you
 	
 	
 		i'm not buying much in terms of consumer products these days
 		uh
 		i prefer to travel rather than buy things so
 	
 	
 		yeah i i hear you there the i i guess you know given a choice most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are kind of holding off on
 	
 	
 		uh right
 	
 	
 		getting anything um i'm trying to think back in mind if there's ever been anything anything i got
 		you know the the things i've been most disappointed with is that when you go those time share gimmicks
 	
 	
 		exactly yes
 	
 	
 		and and you get you get like the the quality luggage which is like yes you too can have vinyl  you know wallet
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		right or from the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sidewalk</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">vendors</ENAMEX> that are supposed to be the real thing
 	
 	
 		
 
 		right you know i i find there's that you just have to be really careful
 		because like especially if you watch TV there's like all such of scams going on where you know like uh you you really have to listen to what they're selling you i mean there's a lot of things like um
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		God you you like you know yes you can get whole sacks of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beef</ENAMEX> you know delivered fresh to you if you buy our thousand dollar refrigerator
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		or um
 		you know all all these multilevel marketing things
 	
 	
 		all of the  well have you noticed even the the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> coupons do that
 	
 	
 		they they're tying them in now
 	
 	
 		you know
 		right  you can get fifty <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five cent</NUMEX> off if you buy <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> and something else
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and  not anything that you want
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		so
 		i mean if you use the coupon you're just falling for the gimmick and there you are
 	
 	
 		like you know we've i'm getting married <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this summer</TIMEX> and we're going to like <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">wedding expos</ENAMEX> and things to get fashion and half the thing's like yes we'll give you a free makeover  we're <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Kay</ENAMEX> cosmetics and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know once  your name on you our mailing list you know you're damned for life because
 	
 	
 		oh that's right that's right
 	
 	
 		or or you you know or all these little
 		i really think multilevel marketing is undermining
 		the quality quality of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> business because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> getting so focused on the progress other than the products
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know it's it's like well you know i could get <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two hundred</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">distributors</ENAMEX> on to me each selling <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">one dollar</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> and i'll be rich but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh all those pyramid schemes
 	
 	
 		yeah that's what multilevel
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amway</ENAMEX> and uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Williams</ENAMEX> insurance which i guess is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Primerica</ENAMEX> now
 	
 	
 		and
 		right and
 		even somewhat is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Kay</ENAMEX> you know she's a local girl
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Kay</ENAMEX> you know they they're something
 		yeah oh do oh we we have <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> to blame for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Kay</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah i'm afraid so  sorry
 	
 	
 		
 
 		but yeah i i i find that you know the place where uh i i think the the the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">place</ENAMEX> were we uh you know consumer price i did fairly well i was leading electronics industry
 	
 	
 		yeah except that i was with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> we had his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Macintosh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and he had taken it back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> for repair
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and  the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">vendors</ENAMEX> are not living up to the contracts that they get with you for so i mean this is a this is an expensive piece of equipment
 	
 	
 		too expensive in my opinion but
 	
 	
 		yeah well whatever but it's what he wants because he's an animator
 	
 	
 		
 
 		right
 	
 	
 		and he's using all of those tools and he's having a really difficult time with the hardware
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">vendor</ENAMEX> that he bought it from  gave it back to him <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> charged him <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">forty five dollars</NUMEX> and told him that it was a software problem
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 		oh no not that
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		oh actually actually you know it it's like i have yeah i've  i've got a VCR and recently it kind of just capped out on me
 	
 	
 		
  
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and you know i typically when your VCR breaks what you have to do you have to like give it to these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and then eventually they'll get get it back to you but i happen to know this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who i met met recently he just like took it down to his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">basement popped</ENAMEX> off the cover you know took a couple of things off so okay this is just junked up cleaned it out it's working fine didn't charge me anything
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		you know i think that the service the really where the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> consumer products uh kind of failing is is in the customer service
 	
 	
 		oh exactly and and you know
 		there was no reason that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike</ENAMEX> should have had to pay <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">forty five dollars</NUMEX> for somebody to run a diagnostic that he had already run
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and he already knew that it wasn't a software problem
 	
 	
 		right i i mean the best example  i guess i guess there's some really it's not um
 		uh the the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX> the some really luxurious uh department uh department store in in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	