
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		drug testing hey
 	
 	
 		yeah um my opinion uh
 		is not quite well enough formulated for for real debate but above all i really really believe
 		that uh <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are innocent until proven guilty and secondly that there in some sense there's a sort of sanctity of the body issue in that i don't
 		really believe that other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would have the right for someone to under go a blood test without their explicit consent
 		so i think that pretty much clearly leads me to my conviction conviction that i i do not believe that uh spot drug tests or required drug tests should be should be
 		you know mandated however they could be done with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s consent
 	
 	
 		i'm a little bit more uh against it than that because i see this as an absolute parallel to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCarthy</ENAMEX> witch hunts when anybody who held
 	
 	
 		um
 		
 
 	
 	
 		liberal opinions or supported civil rights was considered an evil <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">satanic agent</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		quite often i mean there's the legitimate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are too stupid
 		not to use <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemicals</ENAMEX> that impair can impair their behavior in a job
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		where they better be on top of things like running <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trains</ENAMEX> flying <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX> or uh driving buses
 		and also uh the uh strictures against driving uh unimpaired while impaired should apply to any chemical of any kind whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> has authorized the use of that chemical or not
 	
 	
 		
 
 		okay  well i maybe i should qualify <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX> and and mention of course there are some legal parameters that need to be observed as well
 		and uh in the case of driving it's not a it it's a privilege to drive
 		and there's certain things that go along with it but even then they don't force you to take any kind of test if you simply don't take the test then you just you know
 	
 	
 		and they take your license on the assumption that you're guilty which makes sense but this is not the issue here
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right in that case because it clearly clearly endangers someone in that case
 	
 	
 		it's not the issue in question though because what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is trying to do is to truly impose thought control they are saying there are things you cannot do to your mind and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> because we have not authorized to do it
 		and further more if we think that you are
 		uh we're going to make sure that you can't get a job or that you'll be fired from your job if you are engaging in this behavior
 		now blood tests aren't really being called for what they're doing is calling for piss tests which technically it's leaving your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> but whatever it is they shouldn't even have the right to ask
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they shouldn't have the right to prohibit these chemicals what they should have the right to prohibit is misuse of anything
 	
 	
 		oh i see you're you're a much more baser at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">at</TIMEX> at the issue of uh of the drug issue than i am apparently uh
 	
 	
 		yeah i think that it's just a witch hunt and that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> being hit the hardest are the ones that cause the least impact something like eighty percent
 		of the tests and the positive tests and the arrests contain <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> marijuana the only commonly used <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> that has no traceable deaths from overuse none even aspirin kills thirty <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> a year
 		and if by all standards that can be compared potential for abuse uh general impact on society physical impact on the individual this <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> should not be outlawed but the right wing does not want to hear talk like that
 		and so on top of that goes the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> drug testing uh intervention and control of your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> attitude
 		an interesting side note of this is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Motorola company</ENAMEX> lost <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eighteen months</TIMEX> of development on the oh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> oh chip because they instituted drug testing and the entire development <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> for that chip left the company
 	
 	
 		ah wow
 	
 	
 		and that's why it took this long for the oh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> oh to get out they scuttled their own <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> and cost themselves <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">millions of dollars</NUMEX> for that
 	
 	
 		well uh as as far as i i'm not sure you you sort of seem to be kind of saying that you have the right to uh pursue any kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">substance</ENAMEX> that you'd like except for in certain
 		circumstances like driving is that what you're trying to say
 	
 	
 		i'd say it's pretty much it's uh right to privacy the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> can do whatever they want as long as they don't negatively impact other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> it is then that negative impact that should be looked at
 		not the uh not the direct cause of it it's under those grounds that we don't have alcohol prohibition or tobacco prohibition
 	
 	
 		
 
 		right
 		well not having alcohol tobacco prohibition and and uh tobacco prohibition uh i think those are more historical artifact of uh
 		the link between the business and the government though because there
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true too especially with tobacco
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> they did try to ban it they failed utterly they failed miserably and led to the creation of the modern day <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mafia</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well hey they were successful
 	
 	
 		and that's pretty much what's happen that's pretty much what's happened with other with the the current prohibition
 	
 	
 		well i'm i guess we should get back to to the the drug testing issue
 	
 	
 		to tell yeah that we are getting a stray
 	
 	
 		yeah um well i'm trying to think of of more coherent thought it's kind of difficult to have a debate
 		
 		
 	