
   
   
      
         
            Brit Noir

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Amis</ENAMEX> has long evinced
his fascination with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> culture, so it should come as no surprise that he
has brought out an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> novel. Or, anyway, a simulacrum of an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
novel. The work is, of course, an hommage to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX>-procedural genre
for which <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> are principally known overseas. This is true of most
entries in the fiction <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wing</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX>-culture simulacra produced
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX>. Like most items in the music <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> of the same phenomenon, it
is a riff.

            Some
might glance at the book and decide that it is meant to be <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amis' Elmore Leonard</ENAMEX>
moment, recalling his praise for that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX> of fibrous plots and low-key
sociology. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Night Train</ENAMEX> is light on plot and nearly <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Martian</ENAMEX> in its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sociology</ENAMEX>, so it might better be seen as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amis</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Knopfler</ENAMEX> moment. Like the
lead <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guitarist</ENAMEX> of the erstwhile <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Dire Straits</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amis</ENAMEX> is a stolid, middle-class
New Briton blessed with considerable <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chops</ENAMEX>, torn between worldly cynicism and a
certain <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nostalgie</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">de la</ENAMEX> boue , whose wish to get down and dirty is
undertaken professionally but stops a bit short of conviction. They are both
smart enough to notice you noticing this, and their answers are identical: more
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sixteenth</ENAMEX> notes! In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amis</ENAMEX>' case, what this entails is cascades and arabesques of
language.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Night Train</ENAMEX> is a monologue, delivered by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Detective</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike</ENAMEX>
Hoolihan, a physically intimidating, seen-it-all, tough-but-tender <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veteran</ENAMEX> of
every rotten assignment in the police <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">precincts</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anytown</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hoolihan</ENAMEX> is
also a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>, as she reminds the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> no more than once per paragraph. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Police</ENAMEX>
salaries being what they are, she lives in a comically tilted slum flat down by
the railroad tracks, where deep in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night</TIMEX> the titular conveyance roars by
and sets the coffee cups a-rattling. She shares the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dump</ENAMEX> with her latest in a
series of hulking morons, or so she alleges. She only alludes to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tobe</ENAMEX>, failing
to introduce him to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX>, who is tempted to conclude that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tobe</ENAMEX> belongs to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">race</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">6-foot-tall</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rabbits</ENAMEX>.

            On this
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">day</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike</ENAMEX> has got her worst job yet. She has to notify next of kin in a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">suicide</ENAMEX>, and not just any suicide. The corpus delicti was once <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockwell</ENAMEX>, who was both bodacious gorgeousness personified and the essence of
braininess, an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">astrophysicist</ENAMEX>, in her day job. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike</ENAMEX> has known <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer</ENAMEX> since
the latter was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tyke</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer</ENAMEX> was a sprout of the local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cop</ENAMEX> dynasty, the only
one not to wear the blue herself. All her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> are cops, and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> is
such an overwhelming <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cop</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cop</ENAMEX> they made him a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colonel</ENAMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Colonel Tom</ENAMEX>," as he
is called throughout, has taken <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike</ENAMEX> under his capacious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wing</ENAMEX> and seen her
through detox and depression and all the rest of it, as if she were another
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> of his.

            
So <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike</ENAMEX>'s heart is heavy, but she is still a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX>, as she likes to put it. She takes a quick look at the situation and her
analytical mind snaps to. In addition to beauty and brains, the deceased had
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">charm</ENAMEX>, wealth, and a fulfilling love-machine relationship with a fellow double
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dome</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor Trader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Faulkner</ENAMEX>, a roguish but loyal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wearer</ENAMEX> of tweed jackets
with leather patches on the elbows. Does that sound like a recipe for
self-offing? Not to our <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike</ENAMEX>, who starts investigating pronto, although the
field of potential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">murderers</ENAMEX> is as thin as the motive directory. At length her
researches lead her into terrain that is nearly spiritual or something. Could
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer</ENAMEX>--who apparently managed to put <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bullets</ENAMEX> into her lovely
brain--have killed herself because of the absurdity of the simultaneously
expanding and contracting universe?

            Don't
count on finding out. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amis</ENAMEX>' game is sixteenth notes or, in this case, a run
through the candy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> slang. Like the blues as played by suburban
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">virtuosos</ENAMEX>, the story itself is little more than a structural excuse for a show
of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wizard dexterousness</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike</ENAMEX> is the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>. Background noise is
supplied by other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>, but they are cut and pasted from a
vague memory of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Barney Miller</ENAMEX> . After <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Faulkner</ENAMEX>'s cameo, he presumably
returned to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Folgers Crystals</ENAMEX> commercial from which he was borrowed. Most
others, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tobe</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Col.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom</ENAMEX>, are flickering wraiths. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MacGuffin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockwell</ENAMEX>, might occupy center stage as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">corpse</ENAMEX>, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> doesn't believe
in her previous existence for a minute. She joins the parade of other scarily
perfect, not remotely credible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">objects</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amis</ENAMEX>' fiction, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicola</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Six</TIMEX>, who plots her own murder in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">London Fields</ENAMEX> .

            Is <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Night Train</ENAMEX> intended to be the record of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hoolihan</ENAMEX>'s dt-induced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hallucinations</ENAMEX>? You tell me. What is certain is that it
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">represents Amis</ENAMEX>' tabulation of his own verbal pink <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">elephants</ENAMEX>. He would
experience them in this form anyway, since here, as elsewhere in his
oeuvre , he appears curiously absent of any visual sense. He wallows in
Americaness, especially <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cop</ENAMEX> talk. He likes the idea of hollow cant being
delivered in clipped cadences by a broad, especially <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> under emotional
strain. Sometimes you don't know whether he did his research by letting himself
be washed by television for endless stretches, or whether he went so deep he
knows expressions you've never heard (or haven't heard since <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX> grade: Do
cops ever refer to a perp as a "hoody"?).

            He savors verbal dandruff
("state-of-the-art," "parameters") and jargon (the verbs "to badge" and "to be
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rigored</ENAMEX>"), but mostly he likes the rhythm, the tattoo, of fuck s and
shit s and excuse me s. This doesn't prevent him from dishing out
the fine writing, though; he has <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike</ENAMEX> get pretty fancy, to the point of
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">spouting Latin</ENAMEX>. Anyway, the language business is the only conceivable motive
for this book. Perhaps <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foreigners</ENAMEX> will thrill to the exotica, as a sort of
high-lit gloss on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Springer</ENAMEX> territory. Otherwise, it goes nowhere, for no
reason, has no friction and no ending. A pint of the "fortified <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX>" that
shares the book's name would make a better investment.

         
      
   
