
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eden</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX>

            Klansmen were not the only
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who resented integration. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-Americans</ENAMEX> who lived as serfs in the
deep <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX> saw <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Brown vs. Board of Education</ENAMEX> in a favorable light. But
those who had thrived in functional black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> with strong <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and
civic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>--doing just fine without white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX>--were understandably
ambivalent about desegregation. Their misgivings rarely reached the mainstream
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">media</ENAMEX>. A notable exception was the black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novelist</ENAMEX> and anthropologist Zora Neale
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hurston</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1901-1960</TIMEX>), who had grown up in the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pure Negro Town</ENAMEX>" of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eatonville</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fla.</ENAMEX>, which boasted a charter, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">marshal</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">council</ENAMEX>, plenty to eat--and
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> so peaceful that there was no <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">jail</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hurston</ENAMEX> wrote that she was too busy
eating well and sharpening her oyster <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">knife</ENAMEX> to feel victimized by racism. Black
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> attacked her bitterly when she described the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX> decision as
an insult to black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> like hers, which had educated their own just
fine.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Toni</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morrison</ENAMEX> has been praised for using magical realism in the style of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gabriel</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">García Márquez</ENAMEX> and for the literary black feminism she established almost
single-handedly in novels like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Bluest Eye</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1970</TIMEX>), Sula
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1974</TIMEX>), and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Song</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Solomon</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1977</TIMEX>). But magic and feminism are only
surface features of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morrison</ENAMEX>'s work. Her novels are an archaeology of strong
black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> like the ones she and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hurston</ENAMEX> were born into. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morrison</ENAMEX> was
born in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lorain</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX>, a stone's throw from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oberlin College</ENAMEX>, a stop on the
underground <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">railroad</ENAMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morrison</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX>, the region would have been heady
with this heritage, filled with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">descendants</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> who felt themselves equal
if not superior to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX> and who had made self-reliance into a religion.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Communities</ENAMEX> like this one faded with desegregation, which
sent middle-class <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> scurrying to white suburbs. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1960s</TIMEX>, even the
memory of flourishing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hurston</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eatonville</ENAMEX> had been erased, replaced
by crime-ridden ghettoes that '60s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">radicals</ENAMEX> tried to palm off as the only
legitimate black experience.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morrison</ENAMEX> reconstructed those
lost <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> magnificently in her early novels. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sula</ENAMEX> is my
hands-down <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">favorite</ENAMEX>, a crystalline work about the bond between a pair of
girlhood <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>, the timid conformist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nel</ENAMEX> and the rebel <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sula Peace</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sula</ENAMEX> is a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> of nature, the alpha and omega of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>. After an absence of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 years</TIMEX>,
she returns accompanied by a plague of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">robins</ENAMEX> who coat the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> in shit and
fall dead from the skies. The novel strikes a creative balance between
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morrison</ENAMEX>'s affection for magical reality and the need to tell a straightforward
story of small-town pettiness, jealousies, and affections.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morrison</ENAMEX>'s
novels since then have revealed a growing tension between the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paradise</ENAMEX> finds that tension more pronounced than ever. The novel has a
difficult, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Faulknerian</ENAMEX> style--with twists, turns, and ghosts. There is
beautiful writing here. ( to read a sample.) But the historical events that
inspired the novel remain submerged and inaccessible, except to those of us who
know them well.

            
Paradise focuses on the fictional <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruby</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Okla.</ENAMEX>, founded by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> who came West to escape the horrors of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Reconstruction</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morrison</ENAMEX> has given the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founders</ENAMEX> a biblical stature. But they are almost
certainly based on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founders</ENAMEX> of a very real <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Langston</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Okla.</ENAMEX>,
settled by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Negroes</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1890</TIMEX> and named for the black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">educator</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Reconstruction</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">congressman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John M. Langston</ENAMEX>. (He graduated from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oberlin College</ENAMEX>, was <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX>'s
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>, and would have been a familiar figure in the local history
to which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morrison</ENAMEX> was exposed as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>.) Long before it became a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">territory</ENAMEX> and a haven for runaway <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">slaves</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Langston</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">founders</ENAMEX> convinced <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 2,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Negroes</ENAMEX> to settle there. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> shrank
dramatically when the proud <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Negro residents</ENAMEX> had exhausted their savings with no
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> of making a living. With prospects dwindling, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founders</ENAMEX> themselves
decamped for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guthrie</ENAMEX>, the territorial capital.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paradise</ENAMEX> recounts a similar move for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who eventually founded
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruby</ENAMEX>, but attributes the migration to the fact that an earlier settlement had
become too worldly and corrupt. In <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruby</ENAMEX>, founding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> control the local
bank and mete out justice as they see fit. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> is lavishly prosperous,
sharing food and resources and money such that need is unknown. The nearest
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">municipality</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">90 miles</NUMEX> away, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">outsiders</ENAMEX> are profoundly unwelcome. (A white
family that happens through <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> ends up trapped in a blizzard and is eaten by
buzzards come <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the spring</TIMEX> thaw.) <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> leading <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen</ENAMEX> criticizes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAACP</ENAMEX> as a
bunch of "stir-up Negroes" for bringing desegregation suits in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> evaluate prospective <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouses</ENAMEX> on the basis of skin color, and only the
blackest of the black are welcome. Mulattoes are despised as mongrels.

            The isolation pays off in immortality, for no one dies in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruby</ENAMEX>. But inbreeding brings sterility and spiritual rot. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>'s first
family reaches the end of the line when neither of its scions produces an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heir</ENAMEX>.
Such <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> as there are grow troublesome during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '60s</TIMEX>, when they rebel
against tradition. Vexed by discord, the founding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> find a convenient
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scapegoat</ENAMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">colony</ENAMEX> of single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> that springs up at a ruined <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> home
for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> girls <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">15 miles</NUMEX> away.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morrison</ENAMEX>
has always regarded the impulse to murder as part and parcel of love,
particularly a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s love for her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beloved</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX>), for
example, an escaped <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slave</ENAMEX> slits her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">infant</ENAMEX>'s throat to prevent its capture by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slave hunters</ENAMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sula</ENAMEX> , a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> douses her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> with kerosene and burns
him alive after he becomes a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">heroin addict</ENAMEX> and petty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thief</ENAMEX>. Through murder, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> deliver their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>--and sometimes themselves--from evil.

            
Paradise reiterates these themes. Before
running away from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Newark</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.J.</ENAMEX>, to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> home--known locally as
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Convent</ENAMEX>--for instance, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mavis</ENAMEX> allows her twin <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">infants</ENAMEX> to
smother to death in the family <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mavis</ENAMEX> believes the deaths are accidental,
but circumstances suggest that the act was at least unconsciously volitional.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mavis</ENAMEX> has dreamt of an incubus (clearly a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>) taking her <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX>. She is
frightened to death of her remaining <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, whom she suspects of plotting to
murder her.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Convent</ENAMEX>'s other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX> from bad marriages or abuse of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> kind
or another. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">place</ENAMEX> also serves as a haven for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruby</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> who need a break
from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>'s claustrophobic sameness. An influential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">townsman</ENAMEX> takes a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lover</ENAMEX>
there. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> driven mad by caring for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">disabled child</ENAMEX> recovers there. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Convent's</ENAMEX> spiritual life revolves around <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Consolata</ENAMEX>, a benevolent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witch</ENAMEX> who uses
her powers to bring a dying townsman back to life. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stallions</ENAMEX> who run
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruby</ENAMEX> see the place as purely evil. To them, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> represent the danger and
disorder that must be expunged if the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> is to survive. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> attack,
murdering some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and scattering others to the winds. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> do not go
quietly, extracting a toll on their way out.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morrison</ENAMEX> uses both <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruby</ENAMEX> and its opposite, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Convent</ENAMEX>, to
critique the utopian ideal as dangerous, stultifying, and illusory. The moral
of the story, simply put, is: Till your garden where you are; good and evil
exist in similar quantities almost everywhere.

            This, of course, is a drastic
simplification of a complex book that tells its stories from several
perspectives, each in its own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapter</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morrison</ENAMEX> thickens the ambiguity by
avoiding literal references to history and even physical descriptions that
might fix <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> in time and space. These omissions blur the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> and
allow them to operate at the level of myth. But the absence of workaday and
historical detail keeps the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> at a distance; many of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morrison</ENAMEX>'s characters
are impenetrable to the mind's eye. The lack of literal historical context also
allows us to leave <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Paradise</ENAMEX> without learning about the black Western
settlements that sprang up during <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Reconstruction</ENAMEX>, or the so-called "exodusters"
who left the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX> to seek their fortunes on the frontier. The history is so
little known--and so fascinating--it could easily have served as this novel's
point of departure, or the spine of a novel all its own.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morrison</ENAMEX> certainly has earned
the right to be as idiosyncratic as, say, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Gaddis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Pynchon</ENAMEX>, or
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Faulkner</ENAMEX>. But I would love to see her talents turned to a cultural
history of the eras and places she treats so compellingly in her novels. She
has recaptured those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> beautifully in fiction. It would be even more
rewarding to see her write about them in fact.

         
      
   
