
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX> Follies

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 1962</TIMEX>, after the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union</ENAMEX> stationed nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fidel Castro</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">F. Kennedy</ENAMEX> called upon <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dean Acheson</ENAMEX> for advice. With typical self-assurance,
the grand old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX> bellowed his recommendation at a meeting of
the so-called <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">ExComm</ENAMEX> of top <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kennedy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX>: a swift <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> airstrike to take out
the nukes. When asked what the result would be, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Acheson</ENAMEX> replied that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX>
would then destroy a cache of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX>. Then what? he
was asked. Under our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> obligations, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Acheson</ENAMEX> said, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> would have to
attack a nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">base</ENAMEX> within the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> itself. And then? Acheson paused.
"That's when we hope," the magisterial wise <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> said, "that cooler heads will
prevail, and they'll stop and talk."

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mercifully</ENAMEX>, the end of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX> has brought an end to this type of
hair-raising <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchange</ENAMEX>. But those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> looking to remember <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the bad old days</TIMEX>
can find this sort of thing, and plenty of it, in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Aleksandr Fursenko</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Timothy Naftali</ENAMEX>'s important new book on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cuban</ENAMEX> missile crisis, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">One Hell</ENAMEX>
of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gamble</ENAMEX> ." It would be nice to report that their account packs
the pleasure and thrills of a spy novel, but that's not exactly the case. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spy</ENAMEX>
novels induce a frisson of tension that's enjoyable because the reader
knows nothing is really at stake. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fursenko</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Naftali</ENAMEX>'s book, while it
will leave <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>' knuckles white, is no fun at all to read, because the
events it describes are so frightening.

            Their impressive account is one of the best of a flood of
new books about the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX>, triggered by the end of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">superpowers</ENAMEX>' long
struggle. These have ranged from the triumphalist (such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jay Winik</ENAMEX>'s On
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brink</ENAMEX> , a hagiographic account of the Reagan-era <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> he sees as
the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX>'s victors) to the tendentious (say, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Schweizer</ENAMEX>'s simplistic
Victory , giving all the credit, again, to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>) to the thoughtful
(such as We Now Know , by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dean</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historians</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Lewis</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gaddis</ENAMEX>). "One Hell of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gamble</ENAMEX>" belongs in the last category. Fursenko
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Naftali</ENAMEX> resist the urge to gloat or sermonize, and instead let their
research speak for them. It has quite a bit to say, little of it soothing.
Fursenko, a leading <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Academy of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sciences</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Naftali</ENAMEX>, a fellow in international-security studies at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale</ENAMEX>, add
much to what we know about the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">coldest days</TIMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX> from careful
digging in newly opened <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> archives.

            In
particular, the popular image of the missile crisis as a triumph for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JFK</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">diplomacy</ENAMEX> gets badly dented. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> began his term hoping to establish a new
detente with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX>, but he also sought to rid the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Western Hemisphere</ENAMEX> of
communism by ousting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Castro</ENAMEX>. These goals soon proved incompatible. In his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1960</TIMEX>
campaign, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> talked up a fictional missile gap in order to show up the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>
as flaccid on communism. During the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eisenhower</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Castro</ENAMEX> had begun
moving deeper into the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> orbit out of fear of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> invasion; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX>'s
failed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bay</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Pigs invasion</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1961</TIMEX> aggravated <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Castro</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">anxieties</ENAMEX> and gave him
a rallying cry for a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">pro-Soviet</ENAMEX> tilt. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nikita Khrushchev</ENAMEX>, fearing
the loss of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX> for a new path of socialist development, got mischievous.
"Why not throw a hedgehog at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Uncle Sam</ENAMEX>'s pants<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>" he asked, and decided to move
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX> into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX>. The gambit would, at a stroke, deter <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> from invading
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX>, cement <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX>'s alliance with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Havana</ENAMEX>, and shift the world strategic
balance. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> would learn to live with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Khrushchev</ENAMEX> figured,
just as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX> lived with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX> on its <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX> frontier.

            
But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> had no intention of doing so.
Instead of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Acheson</ENAMEX>'s airstrike, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ExComm</ENAMEX> chose to blockade <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX> with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">warships</ENAMEX>. After several harrowing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khrushchev</ENAMEX> blinked and agreed to remove
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX> in return for an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> pledge not to invade <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX> and a secret
pact to remove the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">superpowers</ENAMEX> subsequently entered a
brief era of eased tensions, installing the famous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kremlin</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> hot line
and signing a nuclear test ban treaty. " 'One Hell of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gamble</ENAMEX>,' "
writes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arthur Schlesinger Jr.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Camelot</ENAMEX>'s court <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX>, shows "an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> doggedly bent on the avoidance of nuclear war." Actually, it shows
that mixed politics send mixed signals. True, the planet was not destroyed, for
which we should be grateful, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX>'s maladroit foreign policy helped
create the conditions for the crisis. The world was brought to the verge of
nuclear catastrophe because of a missile gap that did not exist, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX> that were not supposed to be there, and an invasion that was not
coming.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khrushchev</ENAMEX> doesn't come off looking any better. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fursenko</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Naftali</ENAMEX> offer a
wealth of new details about <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cuban</ENAMEX> motives, including the most
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">comprehensive</ENAMEX> picture yet of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Havana</ENAMEX>'s slow entry into the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> orbit. We also
get a better look at the roots of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khrushchev</ENAMEX>'s decision to back down. In the
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">X</ENAMEX>" article, the landmark <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1947</TIMEX> essay that spelled out the fundamentals of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX> strategy, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Kennan</ENAMEX> argued that "the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kremlin</ENAMEX> has no
compunction about retreating in the face of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">superior force</ENAMEX>. And being under the
compulsion of no timetable, it does not get panicky under the necessity for
such retreat. ... [<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">I</ENAMEX>]f it finds unassailable barriers in its path, it accepts
these philosophically and accommodates itself to them." Sure enough, confronted
with such a barrier in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1962</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khrushchev</ENAMEX> decided to give way. He retreated as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">philosophically</ENAMEX> as he could, although he described his reaction to the setback
in rather less elegant language. There was no need for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kremlin</ENAMEX>, he said, to
"act like the czarist <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> who farted at the ball and then shot
himself."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fursenko</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Naftali</ENAMEX>'s book is full of this type of
gripping new detail, including the book's biggest, scariest revelation. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kremlin</ENAMEX>, we learn, had decided to use tactical battlefield nuclear weapons
against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> invaded <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX>. Had <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> not opted for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">blockade</ENAMEX>, it's clear that the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> combat use of nuclear weapons since
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nagasaki</ENAMEX> could have prompted a terrifying cycle of escalation. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cuban</ENAMEX>
missile crisis, it seems, may have been even worse than we had thought.

            Facing a more complex world,
some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">diplomats</ENAMEX> and conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX> seem to long nostalgically for the era
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mutual Assured Destruction</ENAMEX>. "One Hell of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gamble</ENAMEX>" comes as a welcome
corrective. Bad as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s global uncertainties may seem, the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX> system
always had an even more dangerous potential for getting out of control. Even
after the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">superpowers</ENAMEX>' <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1962</TIMEX> showdown led to an easing of tensions, the planet
still had a series of nuclear scares, such as the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 1973</TIMEX> nuclear
alert--which happened on the detente-minded watch of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Kissinger</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Nixon</ENAMEX>. The inherent problem with <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX> brinkmanship, as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">theorist Thomas C. Schelling</ENAMEX> has noted, is that it could elicit concessions
only if one's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponent</ENAMEX> didn't know exactly where the brink was. "One Hell of
a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gamble</ENAMEX>" reminds us just how terrifying that game could be. "Any fool
could start a war," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Khrushchev</ENAMEX> used to like to say. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1962</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Khrushchev</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Castro</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> almost did.

         
      
   
