
   
   
      
         
            Uncool

            If you've been watching
television recently, you might have seen an ad featuring the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Pentium</ENAMEX> computer
chip. This little morality play contrasts a ragtag <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of aging flower
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> with a gathering of young, glamorously dressed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX>. When the
'60s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veterans</ENAMEX> try to play some pitiful music, they are quickly drowned out by
the frantic brainstorming of their corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">descendants</ENAMEX>. The words "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Make</ENAMEX>
Money, Not War" flash at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewer</ENAMEX>.

            These
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX>, it hardly raises an eyebrow when yet another <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">'60s</TIMEX>-style slogan enters the
corporate lexicon. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Politicians</ENAMEX> might fault <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the decade</TIMEX> for its legacy of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">permissiveness</ENAMEX> and the pursuit of too much happiness, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Apple</ENAMEX> blithely urges
us to "think different," while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fruitopia</ENAMEX>'s graffiti-strewn magic bus rolls
merrily across the screen.

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Conquest of Cool</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Frank</ENAMEX> offers an
indignant explanation of this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of affairs. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank</ENAMEX>, the '60s
pageantry of rebellion was welcomed--and in some respects, anticipated--by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">marketers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX>. The real legacy of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Woodstock</ENAMEX> era, Frank
believes, was an all-embracing ethos of "hip capitalism" that holds us in its
paisley thrall to this day. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Had Dustin Hoffman</ENAMEX> known how cool these plastics
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were, he would never have been so confused about his future.) The world
has been made safe for stylish nonconformity, and the prospect of genuine
dissent has been banished.

            Though
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank</ENAMEX> says he aims to illuminate the entire world of "business culture," his
book actually concentrates on the image-conscious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> of the advertising
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>'s-clothing industries. The story begins in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early '60s</TIMEX>, when a small
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">band</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Madison Avenue</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">radicals</ENAMEX> launched the "creative revolution." Advertising
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '50s</TIMEX> had been a timid, stifling business. <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Admen</ENAMEX> populated their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">creations</ENAMEX> with lab coats and graphs and prided themselves on the scientific
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">precision</ENAMEX> of their work. Detailed rule books expounded the doctrine of the
"unique selling proposition"--a clear, simple message that would establish the
superiority of a given product over its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX>. (Wonder <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX> "helps build
strong bodies twelve ways.") The results were humorless and hectoring, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tedious</ENAMEX>, nonstop barrage that was better suited to a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mad</ENAMEX> magazine satire
than to the subtle task of infiltrating the wary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumer</ENAMEX>'s mind.

            
By the end of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eisenhower</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">advertisers</ENAMEX>
were eager to shake up their industry and address the public's alienation. If
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> were unhappy with the gaudy, chrome-plated excess of '50s
consumerism, if they resented the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">crude</ENAMEX> ministrations of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Madison Avenue</ENAMEX>, then
this was something that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">advertisers</ENAMEX> needed to know, and to act upon. The trick
was to make the middle class's pervasive dissatisfaction with commercialism,
cheap goods, and planned obsolescence into an instrument of consumerism
itself.

            The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> and most
influential trickster was an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adman</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bernbach</ENAMEX>, whose famous campaign
for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VW Beetle</ENAMEX> began in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1960</TIMEX>. Bernbach satirized the grandiose claims of
'50s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">advertisers</ENAMEX> by making a virtue of modesty: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VW</ENAMEX> urged its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> to
"think small." Another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">client</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Avis Rent A Car</ENAMEX>--boasted, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">We're No. 2</ENAMEX>!" The
style caught on: Perhaps the most memorable example of commercial diffidence
was a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1961</TIMEX> ad for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Fina gas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX>, which humbly suggested, "If ... you need
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas</ENAMEX> or something, please stop in."

            All this
self-mockery was typically accompanied by a subdued design; the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">consumer</ENAMEX>'s
suspicions would be disarmed with light humor and quiet sophistication. But the
message was plain and clear: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Individualism</ENAMEX> and nonconformity could sell a
product. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bernbach</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> had discovered, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank</ENAMEX> puts it, "the
magic cultural formula by which the life of consumerism could be extended
indefinitely, running forever on the discontent that it had itself produced."
When the counterculture burst on the scene, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">advertisers</ENAMEX> simply found a new,
much brighter "palette" for the presentation of already established messages.
Before long, a sea of psychedelic ads flooded the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>, urging <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> to
"break away from the silent majority" or even to "impeach <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miss America</ENAMEX>."

            The marriage of counterculture and capitalism is hardly a
new subject, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank</ENAMEX> does provide a refreshingly unsentimental look at it. He
does not believe that sinister <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">advertisers</ENAMEX> were simply trying to capture or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> an idealistic--and burgeoning--young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>. Rather, he argues,
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Madison Avenue</ENAMEX> was sincere in its "cosmic optimism" about youth culture:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Marketers</ENAMEX> didn't want to contain countercultural energies so much as to release
them into the world at large. Ads with aggressively youthful themes were just
as likely to appear in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ladies' Home Journal</ENAMEX> or Look as in the
underground <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX>. And those ads often hawked products that only the prosperous
and middle-aged would be able to buy. The point was not to sell to the young;
it was to create a vague but attractive image of rebellion for all to
enjoy.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank</ENAMEX> is a
young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">academic</ENAMEX> who is best known as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founder</ENAMEX> of a lively cultural criticism
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'zine</ENAMEX> called the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baffler</ENAMEX> . For a renovated dissertation, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Conquest</ENAMEX>
of Cool is blessedly free of academic throat-clearing and professional
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">jargon</ENAMEX>. There isn't a dull page in the book. Unfortunately, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank</ENAMEX>'s frequent
generalizations about "the world of business and of middle-class mores" are far
less convincing than the particular stories he has to tell. The advertising and
fashion industries, after all, are not representative of "postwar <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
capitalism." If there were any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">businessmen</ENAMEX> who didn't welcome youth culture,
they don't appear here. (We are told that the sales of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>'s hats fell
dramatically <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 1964 and 1970</TIMEX>--did hatters enjoy <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the decade</TIMEX> too?) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Frank</ENAMEX>
also ignores a more sober aspect of '60s revolt: the consumer movement.
Responding to public pressure, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Trade Commission</ENAMEX> banned cigarette
advertising on radio and television in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1970</TIMEX>, and established tough regulations
on "truth in advertising" shortly thereafter. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralph Nader</ENAMEX> may not have been
"hip," but he was definitely a '60s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>.

            
When it comes to the present, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank</ENAMEX> paints with
particularly broad strokes. At his best, he deftly skewers the inanities of
corporate-sponsored dissidence. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Details</ENAMEX> is quoted as
asking himself, "How is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> rebelling <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>?") But the antinomian antics of
some <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Madison Avenue</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> and glossy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> hardly establishes that "rebel
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX> culture" is "the cultural mode of the corporate moment." It may be fun to
say, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank</ENAMEX> put it in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baffler</ENAMEX> , that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William S. Burroughs</ENAMEX>'
"inspirational writings are boardroom favorites, his dark nihilistic burpings
the happy homilies of the new corporate faith." But what does it mean? Chances
are that when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nike</ENAMEX> put <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burroughs</ENAMEX> in one of its ads, none of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> had even heard of him. As for "middle-class mores," a culture eager
to embrace the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">V-</ENAMEX>chip surely subscribes to other beliefs besides the
desirability of transgression at any cost.

            In fact,
there is no dominant style to contemporary consumerism. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Advertisers</ENAMEX> frequently
urge us to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebel</ENAMEX>, and they frequently urge us to conform. They encourage us to
indulge ourselves, and they exhort us to worry about our competence at work.
They appeal to patriotism and then to anarchism. The same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychographers</ENAMEX> who
identify a lucrative market of rugged individualists in one study will turn
around and identify an equally lucrative market of "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neo-traditionalists</ENAMEX>" in the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Marketers</ENAMEX> will do anything that seems to promise a momentary fit with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">elusive Zeitgeist</ENAMEX> , or at least a surge of attention.

            Rather than distinguish these varieties of consumer
experience, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank</ENAMEX> stuffs everything into the boxes of "square" and
"hip"--receptacles that were already full back when the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">'60s</NUMEX> dawned. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank</ENAMEX> is
hardly the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> to note that the tastes of a "hip" bohemian <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elite</ENAMEX> have spread
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masses</ENAMEX>, or to argue that the results of this cultural migration are
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">deleterious</ENAMEX>. Both the observation and the complaint are virtually as old as
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 th -century</TIMEX> cultural criticism itself. Click to read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leslie Fiedler</ENAMEX>
on the subject in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1960</TIMEX>, and to read <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theodor Adorno</ENAMEX> discussing it in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1947</TIMEX>.)
Wherever the image of nonconformity appears, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank</ENAMEX> spies the ascendant force of
rebel <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumerism</ENAMEX>. Is there really a common sensibility that unites the
inspirational homiletics of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nike</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Just Do It</ENAMEX>" and the remorseless irony of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s "You can talk to your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> anytime" campaign? When <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Delta Air Lines</ENAMEX>
promises to be "ready when you are," is that an instance of untrammeled
individualism, catering to the whims of the impulsive <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">jet</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">set rebel</ENAMEX>? Or is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Delta</ENAMEX> merely trying to soothe the nerves of the anxious business <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traveler</ENAMEX> who
hopes to arrive at the next meeting with his clothes unwrinkled? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank</ENAMEX>'s
categories are too crude to answer these questions. All these advertisements
may be insulting to one's intelligence or taste; but they don't add up to a
single coherent message--much less to a dissent-dissolving "magic cultural
formula" that can explain capitalism's survival and success.

         
      
   
