
   
   
      
         
            History Lite

            If you want your history
books to be entertaining--full of anecdotes about the lives of the rich and the
famous--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Johnson</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> for you. A prolific <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist-historian</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> of many popular books, including
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Modern Times</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A History</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>), which
explore the past in large sweeps. More opinionated than academic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historians</ENAMEX>
tend to be, he is also skilled at offering <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> sketches and at spinning
out stories. While this ambitious and lengthy history of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> people
gets bogged down here and there, it manages, for the most part, to move ahead
at a lively pace. It covers developments from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">15 th</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">century</TIMEX>
explorations of the New World to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid-1990s</TIMEX>, but you can open the book
almost anywhere and have a good read.

            You will
also encounter a host of superficial and slanted judgments. Some of these
reflect thin research--hard to avoid entirely in a book of such scope. Others
expose a sourness about modern <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> politics and culture that becomes
increasingly <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> moves toward <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the present day</TIMEX>. Particularly in the
sections devoted to the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1929</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> has trouble containing his
conservative political and cultural agenda. He is better when he keeps things
light.

            This is not to say that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> dislikes what he discovers
about the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. Far from it. Indeed, if he may be said to have an
overall interpretation, it is one that is fairly conventional: that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">English colonies</ENAMEX> (there is little here about <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">colonies</ENAMEX>) were
settled by extraordinarily adventurous and idealistic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">North</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> continent until well into the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19 th century</TIMEX> was a fantastic
land--an "economy of plenty" that rewarded bold and ambitious dreamers. Early
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anglo</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> had the "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> virtues of pragmatism, fair-mindedness, and
honorable loyalty to each other." The founding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fathers</ENAMEX> were "the most
remarkable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> in history--sensible, broad-minded, courageous, usually
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">well-educated</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gifted</ENAMEX> in a variety of ways, mature, and long-sighted, sometimes
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">lit</ENAMEX> by flashes of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX>." Their <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> during the revolutionary
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">era</ENAMEX>, by contrast, included "boobies" such as the royal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ministers</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Townshend</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lord</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Germain</ENAMEX>, as well as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George III</ENAMEX> himself, "a
young, self-confident, ignorant, inflexible, and pertinacious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>."

            When
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson</ENAMEX> turns to the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19 th century</TIMEX>, he continues to reward us with
lively prose and well-crafted sketches of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>--mostly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidents</ENAMEX> and big
business <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> such as the steel magnate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Carnegie</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">J.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pierpont Morgan</ENAMEX> (this is decidedly a top-down history, in which the poor, labor
union <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>, and minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> receive far less attention than in most
scholarly histories <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson</ENAMEX>, a shrewd <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">observer</ENAMEX>, often needs
relatively few words to convey his opinionated judgments. Thus, on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Adams</ENAMEX>
as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>:

            [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX>]he historian warms to
this vain, chippy, wild-eyed, paranoid, and fiercely patriotic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">seer</ENAMEX>. But,
whatever they think, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidents</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> should not publicly
proclaim their detestation of democracy and equality. That leaves only
fraternity, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adams</ENAMEX> was not a brotherly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> either. He was much too good a
hater for that.

            On <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ulysses</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grant</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> writes simply:

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grant</ENAMEX>,
the great general, turned out a political and administrative booby. He wished
to run a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> time but his party was not having it. ... He then went on a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two-year</TIMEX> tour of the world, during which he got spectacularly drunk and
committed many enormities.

            
If there is a sexual bit to be found in a
story, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> usually contrives to slip it in. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dolley Madison</ENAMEX>, he explains,
controlled her diminutive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and "launched the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>'s first
'drawing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>' receptions which, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">her day</TIMEX>, were celebrated--the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> in 'black
or blue coat with vest, black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">breeches</ENAMEX> and black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stockings</ENAMEX>,' the ladies 'not
remarkable for anything so much as for the exposure of their swelling breasts
and bare backs.' " <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woodrow Wilson</ENAMEX> was "fond of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, highly sexed, even
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">passionate</ENAMEX>, and capable of memorable love-letters. His <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellen</ENAMEX>, was a
proto-feminist, and their marriage was a grand love-affair. But it did not
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">prevent Wilson</ENAMEX> striking up, in due course, an acquaintance with a frisky <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">widow</ENAMEX>,
whom he met in his favorite vacation haunt, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bermuda</ENAMEX>. This developed into a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">liaison</ENAMEX>, which led in time to a bit of genteel blackmail." <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Readers</ENAMEX> can guess
what is in store when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> yanks back the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> curtains during the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy years.</ENAMEX>

            Well
before then, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX>'s political agenda moves to front and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX>, best
revealed in a lengthy section lauding the minimalist economic and political
philosophy of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Calvin Coolidge</ENAMEX> (perhaps his favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>) and in
another passage concerning <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman Rockwell</ENAMEX>, whose representations of the
"magnanimity of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle America</ENAMEX>" send <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> into raptures: "It is now possible
to predict his [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockwell</ENAMEX>'s] emergence as an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Old Master</ENAMEX>, like the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX> genre
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">painters</ENAMEX>, especially <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jan Steen</ENAMEX>, or the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">moralist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Hogarth</ENAMEX>."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alas</ENAMEX>, there is not much else about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s recent past
(save <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Truman</ENAMEX>'s decisive stance during the early <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>) that
appeals to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franklin Delano Roosevelt</ENAMEX>'s New Deal gets short shrift;
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> is "a kind of pyramid fraud, played on youth." Worse, FDR
"tended to give <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stalin</ENAMEX> what he wished, thus making possible the immense
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">satellite</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">totalitarian states</ENAMEX> in eastern <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>." Lyndon
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> adds, threw money at problems--so much so that one might
conclude that "the whole of the Great Society program was unconstitutional."
Citing conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Brown vs. Board of Education</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson</ENAMEX>
seems to agree that it was an "unprincipled decision" that "turned out to be a
prelude to a major step backward in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> race relations." Affirmative
action programs, he adds, are "based on illegality."

            Nothing distresses <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX>, a
distinguished <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX>, more than the behavior of the liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> news
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">media</ENAMEX>, which are described as having abused enormous power in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fidel Castro</ENAMEX> climbed to power, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> informs us, on the back of adulatory
news stories in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> have developed an
insatiable passion for "witch hunts," such as the one that badly distorted <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Contra</ENAMEX> stories during the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. We are asked to feel especially sorry
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Nixon</ENAMEX>, who endured vilification from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> that was "continual, venomous, unscrupulous, inventive,
and sometimes unlawful."

            Statements such as these add
a great deal of spice to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX>'s ambitious History . No one can accuse
him of waffling. Sometimes he seems mainly to be having fun--whacking away at
everything from Marxism to contemporary political correctness offers him happy
sport. All too often, however, such statements are zingers, as if whipped out
from the comfort of his easy chair or dashed off for the op-ed page of a
conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX>. Popular history need not come at the expense of
thoughtful reflection and serious research, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX>'s zingers are too often
substitutes for those qualities. This is a pity, for his caustic tone and
shallow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">glosses</ENAMEX> undermine what is a bold and worthy effort: to write a readable
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-volume history of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
