
   
   
      
         
            Folie ࠎ

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> with high <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">IQs</ENAMEX> tend to
be nearsighted. This is not because they read a lot or stare at computer
screens too much. That common-sense hypothesis has been discredited by
research. Rather, it is a matter of genetics. The same genes that tend to
elevate IQ also tend to affect the shape of the eyeball in a way that leads to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">myopia</ENAMEX>. This relationship--known in genetics as "pleiotropy"--seems to be
completely accidental, a quirk of evolution.

            Could
there be a similar pleiotropy between madness and mathematics? Reading this
absolutely fascinating biography by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sylvia Nasar</ENAMEX>, an economics <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> , I began to wonder. Its subject, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Nash</ENAMEX>, is a
mathematical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX> who went crazy at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the age of 30</TIMEX> and then, after several
decades of flamboyant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lunacy</ENAMEX>, was awarded the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nobel Prize</ENAMEX> in economics for
something he had discovered as a graduate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX>. (He is now about to turn
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">70</TIMEX>.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nash</ENAMEX> is among the latest in a long and distinguished line of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mathematicians</ENAMEX>--stretching back to that morbid paranoiac, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isaac Newton</ENAMEX>--who
have been certifiably insane during parts of their lives.

            Just in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last 100 years or so</TIMEX>, most of the heroic
figures in the foundations of mathematics have landed in mental <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">asylums</ENAMEX> or have
died by their own hand. The greatest of them, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kurt Gödel</ENAMEX>, starved himself to
death in the belief that his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> were putting poison in his <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>. Of the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pioneers</ENAMEX> of game theory--the field in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nash</ENAMEX> garnered his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nobel</ENAMEX>--one,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ernst Zermelo</ENAMEX>, was hospitalized for psychosis. The other, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Von Neumann</ENAMEX>, may
not have been clinically insane, but he did serve as the real-life model for
the title <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanley Kubrick</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Strangelove</ENAMEX> .

            So maybe
there is an accidental, pleiotropic connection between madness and mathematics.
Or maybe it isn't so accidental. Mathematicians are, after all, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who
fancy that they commune with perfect <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Platonic</ENAMEX> objects--abstract spaces,
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">infinite</ENAMEX> numbers, zeta functions--that are invisible to normal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX>. They
spend their days piecing together complicated, scrupulously logical tales about
these hallucinatory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX>, which they believe are vastly more important than
anything in the actual world. Is this not a kind of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">folie à n</ENAMEX> (where
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">n</ENAMEX> equals the number of pure mathematicians worldwide)?

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ABeautiful Mind</ENAMEX> reveals quite a lot about the
psychic continuum leading from mathematical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX> to madness. It is also a
very peculiar redemption story: how <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three decades</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">raging schizophrenia</ENAMEX>,
capped by an unexpected <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nobel Prize</ENAMEX>, can transmute a cruel shit into a frail
but decent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">human being</ENAMEX>.

            As a boy
growing up in the hills of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Virginia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nash</ENAMEX> enjoyed torturing <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> and
building homemade bombs with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> other unpopular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youngsters</ENAMEX>, one of whom was
accidentally killed by a blast. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Given Nash</ENAMEX>'s childhood keenness for explosives
and his later penchant for sending odd packages to prominent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strangers</ENAMEX> through
the mail, it's a wonder the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> never got on to him as a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Unabomber</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suspect</ENAMEX>.) He
made his way to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carnegie Tech</ENAMEX>, where he was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classmate</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andy Warhol</ENAMEX>'s, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">thence</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Princeton</ENAMEX>--the world capital of mathematics at the time--at the age
of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX>.

            In sheer appearance, this cold and aloof <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Southerner</ENAMEX> stood
out from his fellow math <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prodigies</ENAMEX>. A "beautiful dark-haired young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>,"
"handsome as a god," he was <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">6 feet 1 inch</NUMEX> tall, with broad shoulders, a heavily
muscled chest (which he liked to show off with see-through <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dacron</ENAMEX> shirts), a
tapered waist, and "rather limp and beautiful hands" accentuated by long
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fingernails</ENAMEX>. Within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> of entering <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Princeton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nash</ENAMEX> had framed and proved
the most important proposition in the theory of games.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mathematically</ENAMEX>, this was no big deal. Game theory was a somewhat fashionable
pursuit for mathematicians in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">those postwar days</TIMEX>, when it looked as if it might
do for military science and economics what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newton</ENAMEX>'s calculus had done for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">physics</ENAMEX>. But they were bored with it by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 1950s</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economists</ENAMEX>, after a
few <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX> of hesitation, picked it up in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '80s</TIMEX> and made it a cornerstone
of their discipline.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agame</ENAMEX> is just a conflict situation with a bunch
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX>, or "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> could be poker <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pals</ENAMEX>, oligopolists
competing to corner a market, or nuclear powers trying to dominate each other.
Each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> has several strategy options to choose from. What <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nash</ENAMEX> showed was
that in every such game there is what has become known as a "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nash equilibrium":</ENAMEX>
a set of strategies, one for each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX>, such that no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> can improve his
situation by switching to a different strategy. His proof was elegant but
slight. A game is guaranteed to have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nash</ENAMEX> equilibrium, it turns out, for the
same reason that in a cup of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX> that is being stirred, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> coffee
molecule must remain absolutely still. Both are direct consequences of a
"fixed-point theorem" in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">branch</ENAMEX> of mathematics known as topology. This
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">theorem</ENAMEX> says that for any continuous rearrangement of a domain of things, there
will necessarily exist <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> thing in that domain that will remain
unchanged--the "fixed point." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nash</ENAMEX> found a way of applying this to the domain
of all game strategies so that the guaranteed fixed point was the equilibrium
for the game--clever, but the earlier topological theorem did all the work.
Still, for an economics theorem, that counts as profound. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economists</ENAMEX> have been
known to win <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nobel Prizes</ENAMEX> for rediscovering theorems in elementary
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">calculus</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nash</ENAMEX>'s
breakthrough in game theory got him recruited by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rand Corp.</ENAMEX>, which was then
a secretive military <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">think tank</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Monica</ENAMEX> (its name is an acronym for
"research and development"). However, the achievement did not greatly impress
his fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mathematicians</ENAMEX>. To do that, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nash</ENAMEX>, on a wager, disposed of a deep
problem that had baffled the profession since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 19 th century</TIMEX>: He
showed that any <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">Riemannian manifold</ENAMEX> possessing a special kind of "smoothness"
can be embedded in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Euclidean</ENAMEX> space. Manifolds, one must understand, are fairly
wild and exotic <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">beasts</ENAMEX> in mathematics. A famous example is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Klein</ENAMEX> bottle, a
kind of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">higher-dimensional</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Moebius</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">strip</ENAMEX> whose inside is somehow the same as
its outside. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Euclidean</ENAMEX> space, by contrast, is orderly and bourgeois. To
demonstrate that "impossible" manifolds could be coaxed into living in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Euclidean</ENAMEX> space is counterintuitive and pretty exciting. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nash</ENAMEX> did this by
constructing a bizarre set of inequalities that left his fellow mathematicians
thoroughly befuddled.

            That about marked the end of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nash</ENAMEX>'s career as a
mathematical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX>. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>, he was expelled from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rand</ENAMEX> as a security
risk after local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> caught him engaging in a lewd act in a public <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Muscle Beach</ENAMEX>. At <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MIT</ENAMEX>, where he had been given a teaching job, he
hardly bothered with undergraduates and humiliated graduate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> by solving
their thesis problems. He carried on affairs with several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mistress</ENAMEX>,
who bore him a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> he refused to lift a finger to support. His cruel streak
extended to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> he married, a beautiful physics <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alicia</ENAMEX> who
was awed by this "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX> with a penis." Once, at a math department picnic, he
threw her to the ground and put his foot on her throat.

            All the
while, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nash</ENAMEX> was showing an intense interest in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>--often a
sign of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">incipient insanity</ENAMEX>, at least in a non-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jew</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Geniuses</ENAMEX> slipping into
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">madness</ENAMEX> also tend to disrobe in public (I learned this from a volume on chess
prodigies, who have a proclivity for disrobing on public <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">buses</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nash</ENAMEX> showed up
for an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MIT</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">New Year</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eve</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">party</ENAMEX> clad only in a diaper. And then, of course,
there was the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> , that old mainstay of psychotic
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">delusion</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nash</ENAMEX> thought <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX> were sending him encrypted messages through its
pages (come to think of it, that could explain the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> ' odd
prose).

            
When the big breakdown came, it was properly
mathematical. Fearing his powers might be waning as he approached <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nash</ENAMEX>
decided he would solve the most important unresolved problem in mathematics:
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Riemann Zeta</ENAMEX> conjecture. This bold guess about the solutions to a certain
complex-valued infinite series (made by the incomparable <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bernhard Riemann</ENAMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1859</TIMEX>) would, if true, have far-reaching implications for the structure of the
most basic of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX>, the natural numbers. Before an eager <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> of
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of mathematicians at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia University</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1959</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nash</ENAMEX> presented his
results: a farrago of mathematical lunacy. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nash</ENAMEX>'s talk wasn't good or bad,"
said one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mathematician</ENAMEX> present. "It was horrible." <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Some weeks</TIMEX> before, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nash</ENAMEX> had
declined a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Chicago</ENAMEX> offer of an endowed chair on the grounds that
he was scheduled to become the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">emperor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Antarctica</ENAMEX>.

            Such
ebullitions of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">insanity</ENAMEX> continued for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three decades</TIMEX>, becoming more rococo. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Nash</ENAMEX>
went to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> to form a world <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, attempting repeatedly to renounce
his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizenship</ENAMEX>. He did stints in tony asylums, hanging out with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lowell</ENAMEX>, and in dismal state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX>, where he was subjected <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin-induced comas</ENAMEX>. He believed himself to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugee</ENAMEX> called
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C.O.R.P.S.E.</ENAMEX>; a great <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shogun</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">C1423</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Esau</ENAMEX>; the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prince</ENAMEX> of peace;
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">l'homme d'Or</ENAMEX> ; a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX>. As <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nasar</ENAMEX> observes, his delusions were weirdly
inconsistent. He felt himself simultaneously to be the epicenter of the
universe--"I am the left foot of God on earth"--and an abject, persecuted
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">petitioner</ENAMEX>.

            He returned to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Princeton</ENAMEX> area in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1970s</TIMEX>, where he
was taken care of by the long-suffering <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alicia</ENAMEX>, now his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ex-wife</ENAMEX> (she supported
him partly through computer programming, partly on welfare). He haunted the
campus, where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> began to call him "the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Phantom</ENAMEX>." They would come to
class in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX> to find runic messages he had written on the blackboard at
night: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mao Tse-Tung</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Bar Mitzvah</ENAMEX> was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13 years</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13 months</TIMEX>, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13 days</TIMEX> after
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brezhnev</ENAMEX>'s circumcision."

            Then, in
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">'90s</NUMEX>, inexplicably, the voices in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nash</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> began to quiet down. (Nasar
gives an interesting account of just how rare such remissions are among those
diagnosed with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">schizophrenia</ENAMEX>.) At the same time, the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nobel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Stockholm</ENAMEX> was deciding it was about time to award the prize in economics for
game theory. Dare they make a known <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">madman</ENAMEX> into a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">laureate</ENAMEX>? What might he say
to King <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gustav</ENAMEX> at the ceremony? Nasar shows her mettle as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> here by
penetrating the veil of secrecy surrounding the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nobel</ENAMEX> and revealing the
back-stage machinations for and against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nash</ENAMEX>'s candidacy. He did fine at the
ceremony, by the way.

            
Indeed, he has evolved into a "very fine
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>," according to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ex-wife</ENAMEX>--humbled by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> of psychotic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">helplessness</ENAMEX>,
buoyed up by the intellectual world's highest accolade. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nobel</ENAMEX> has a
terrible effect on the productivity of many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX>, paralyzing them with
greatness. For <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nash</ENAMEX> it was pure therapy. Then, too, there is the need to take
care of his son by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alicia</ENAMEX>, who--pleiotropically?--inherited both his
mathematical promise and his madness. (His older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>, the one born out of
wedlock, got neither.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nobel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">money</ENAMEX> bought a new boiler for the little
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bungalow</ENAMEX> across from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Princeton</ENAMEX> train <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX> inhabited by this shaky
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">menage</ENAMEX>. (When <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity Fair</ENAMEX> published an excerpt of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Beautiful</ENAMEX>
Mind , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nash</ENAMEX> probably became the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> ever featured in that magazine
to live in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> clad in "insulbrick.")

            The eeriest thing I
discovered while reading this superb book was that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nash</ENAMEX> and I came within a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">couple of years</TIMEX> of crossing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">paths</ENAMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> mental <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX>. I was actually
working there, but psychiatric <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX> pick up so many mannerisms of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> that it's hard to tell the difference after a while. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A few years</TIMEX> after
that I found myself in a mathematics Ph.D. program. You'll be glad to know that
I'm in remission.

         
      
   
