
   
   
      
         
            Gone With the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wind</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cold Mountain</ENAMEX> is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sincerely</ENAMEX> plausible. It is a solemn fake. You will not hear this from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> who have helped make <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Frazier</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Civil War</ENAMEX> tale
probably the most popular novel about that period since Gone With the
Wind . (Since its publication in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cold Mountain</ENAMEX> has sold more
than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a million</NUMEX> copies; in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX>, it won the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">National Book Award</ENAMEX>.) The book
is so professionally archaeological, so competently dug, that one can mistake
its surfaces for depth. But it's like a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cemetery</ENAMEX> with no bodies in it. All the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">records</ENAMEX> of life are there, the facts and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figures</ENAMEX> and pocket histories, pointing
up out of the ground, but what's buried there was never alive.

            Most
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't want novels to be, in the deepest sense, unreal. They want them to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">obey</ENAMEX> the conventions of current realism. Thus <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Berendt</ENAMEX>, author of
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Midnight in the Garden of Good and Evil</ENAMEX> , has said of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold Mountain</ENAMEX>
that it is "utterly convincing down to the last detail." And he's right. But
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cold Mountain</ENAMEX> is utterly convincing in an unreal way.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Frazier</ENAMEX> has written a stirring story of bloody simplicity
and epic power. As a storyteller, he hardly ever errs. This is a remarkably
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tremorless</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> novel. It is the story of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Inman</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Confederate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldier</ENAMEX> who is
wounded in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1864</TIMEX> and briefly hospitalized, and who then deserts to find his way
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>. He travels raggedly from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tennessee</ENAMEX> to the mountains of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX>
where he had grown up. There, near <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Cold Mountain</ENAMEX>, waits his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sweetheart</ENAMEX>, a woman
called <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ada Monroe</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> of an upper-class <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charleston</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">S.C.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX>
who has died just before the book begins, she is struggling to make her old
farm profitable. The novel alternates <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Inman</ENAMEX>'s story and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ada</ENAMEX>'s story. She waits;
he travels.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Inman</ENAMEX> is
silent, good, and strong--one must imagine a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Confederate Clint Eastwood</ENAMEX>. He is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">metaphysically</ENAMEX> alone, as the conventions of adventure dictate: "He wished not
to be smirched with the mess of other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>." But messes just keep on
smirching him. He goes through a shower of picaresque trials: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> set on
him (he single-handedly beats them off); he saves a pregnant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> from death,
and another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> from a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">band</ENAMEX> of renegade federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX>; various <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> try to
recapture him; he is seduced by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>, discovering the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX>,
tries to shoot him. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Inman</ENAMEX>'s conversation, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late-20 th -century</TIMEX>
writing-school style, is intelligently starved ("It is still a cloudy matter to
me if I did the right thing, letting you live"), and his inner life is
carefully rationed. He is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Homeric</ENAMEX> foot <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldier</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frazier</ENAMEX> has said he had
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Odysseus</ENAMEX> in mind--and quite unreal. The novel's unreality flows from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Inman</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">unreality</ENAMEX>.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cold Mountain</ENAMEX> rolls the brougham of itself from
episode to episode, until <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Inman</ENAMEX> reaches home. A puff of sentimentality is
exhaled at the end of the book: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Inman</ENAMEX> is reunited with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ada</ENAMEX>, only to be shot
down at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the last minute</TIMEX>. But the tragic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> was permitted a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> of
passion, and a moist epilogue shows a happy little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>, the product of this
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">union</ENAMEX>, frolicking with her mother <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">some years later</TIMEX>: the happy end of a happy
ending.

            Frazier
is a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>: calm, for the most part unsentimental, often rich. But the
novel is a refined exercise. It is worth bearing in mind that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frazier</ENAMEX> was,
until recently, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>, although the jacket copy omits this
fact, preferring us to believe that he and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> merely "raise horses" in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Raleigh</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.C. Cold Mountain</ENAMEX> is in fact a willed pastiche of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crane</ENAMEX>--that is, modern prose with occasional attacks of nostalgia. "There was
not moonlight nor the prick of lantern light from some welcoming <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>. The town
of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold Mountain</ENAMEX> was ahead, but they knew not how far." Or this, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Inman</ENAMEX>
battles the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thieves</ENAMEX>: "[H]e eventually smote the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> down to their knees
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dirt</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> so they looked like those of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Romish</ENAMEX> faith at
prayer."

            Such prose, if not quite antiquarian's dust, is the carbon
of something once fiery. It is not a living <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">19 th</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-century</TIMEX> prose, or a
living contemporary prose, but rather a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">20 th</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-century</TIMEX> reduction,
living off the alms of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19 th century</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Frazier</ENAMEX> does the opposite
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Melville</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woolf</ENAMEX>, who historicize the language by shaking
its roots. Linguistically, he is not in search of the historically rejuvenating
but the historically plausible. But most great historical fiction--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eliot, Stendhal</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tolstoy</ENAMEX>--is not written in "historical" prose. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crane</ENAMEX>, in
The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Red Badge of Courage</ENAMEX> , wrote in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1895</TIMEX> about the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Civil War</ENAMEX>, but it
would not have occurred to him to write in anything but the living language of
his own age (which, admittedly, was closer to the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX> period's than
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Frazier's</ENAMEX> is).

            To compare
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crane</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Frazier</ENAMEX> is to compare a genuine, fibrous style with academic tissue.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Frazier</ENAMEX> controls all his similes so that they stay ruly. His similes--there is
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> per page--are either trimmed for historical plausibility (like the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thieves Romishly</ENAMEX> at prayer) or, more frequently, made to involve an <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animal</ENAMEX>, the
idea perhaps being that in simpler times, a homely, rustic simile would have
come to mind. So we have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s tongue "grey as the foot of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">goose</ENAMEX>"; a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">catfish</ENAMEX> "the size of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">boar hog</ENAMEX>"; a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who gets ready to take a blow "like a
cowed <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX>"; a night as dark "as the inside of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cow</ENAMEX>"; an old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> whose dugs
"hung down like those on a sow hog"--an entire farmyard of likenesses. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crane</ENAMEX>,
by contrast, lets his similes go everywhere: In battle, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> has a shoeful
of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX>: "He hopped like a schoolboy in a game." A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">corpse</ENAMEX> is seen, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crane</ENAMEX>
describes the dead <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s beard moving in the wind "as if a hand were stroking
it."

            
In short, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Frazier</ENAMEX> sacrifices aesthetic life to
historical life. The result is that while <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> continues to believe <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold</ENAMEX>
Mountain on the surface, one stops believing it at any deeper level. There
is a false consciousness to a late <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 th -century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>'s efforts to
evoke a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">19 th</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> in a language that belongs to neither. When
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Inman</ENAMEX> is seduced, for instance, he places his hand on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>'s leg, high up.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frazier</ENAMEX> writes, of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>'s genitals, that to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Inman</ENAMEX> they "seemed
extraordinarily fascinating though it was but a mere slot in flesh." The reader
realizes instantly that a deserting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldier</ENAMEX> would never think like this--that
he would never use these upholstered words. The private language of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> like
that would be both simpler and more strange, more original, than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Frazier</ENAMEX>'s
ecclesiastical <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>. Instead, we have <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frazier</ENAMEX>'s fancy, plausible idea of how
a vagina might have been described in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1864</TIMEX> had this been written down .
But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Inman</ENAMEX> is not writing anything down--he is being seduced, he is speaking to
himself. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> sees that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Cold Mountain</ENAMEX> is condemned to be a literary
approximation of an already literary idea of reality.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry James</ENAMEX> complained to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarah Orne Jewett</ENAMEX> in a letter of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1904</TIMEX> that the historical novel had "a fatal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cheapness</ENAMEX>." Although the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novelist</ENAMEX> might be able to render well all sorts of
facts and dates and general furniture, she could never truthfully render the
"old consciousness." The great historical novels are always about contemporary
consciousness. This inability to convey the "old consciousness" was not a
matter of inaccuracy but of bad faith. It would always be the new consciousness
imagining what the old consciousness was like--forcing it to be "old." "And
even then," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James</ENAMEX> added, "it's all humbug." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cold Mountain</ENAMEX> is advanced
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">humbug</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
