
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monkey Business</ENAMEX>

            It was a bit weird, reading
and thinking about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>'s young literary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">phenom</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Will Self</ENAMEX>, just as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>'s
death and its aftermath were flooding the airwaves. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newscasters</ENAMEX> spoke of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Flower Revolution</ENAMEX>, of the possibility that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> might at last stop clinging
to ancient protocol and allow its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> to display the normal range of human
emotion. But as I read <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Great Apes</ENAMEX> it occurred to me that stiff-lipped
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reserve</ENAMEX> hasn't been the sole <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enemy</ENAMEX> of emotionally demonstrative English
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">do-gooders</ENAMEX>. Other hallowed traditions are just as allergic to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">touchifeeliness</ENAMEX>--consider the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s fascination with turds. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Generations</ENAMEX> of
Britons have reveled in scatological humor; poop features quite prominently in
some of their great literature, even. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gulliver</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Travels</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hero</ENAMEX>
closely observes insect droppings and the stinking evacuations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cows</ENAMEX>, while
the horrible <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yahoos</ENAMEX> pelt him with their dung. These passages are funny, but
also deadly serious. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shit</ENAMEX> is made to stand for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s essential viciousness, his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">brotherhood</ENAMEX> with base <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX>. And <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s brotherhood with base <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> would
seem to point to the futility of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>-style attempts at emotional
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">communion</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Self</ENAMEX> has
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">long</ENAMEX> declared his admiration for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Swift</ENAMEX>, and in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Great Apes</ENAMEX> he
makes the homage explicit. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Self</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simon Dykes</ENAMEX>, starts out as a successful
but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">disillusioned painter</ENAMEX> living in contemporary <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simon</ENAMEX>'s milieu is the
much-hyped "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Swinging London</ENAMEX>"--the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> in the throes of a
fashion-artistic-musical-culinary renaissance that has made the covers of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity Fair</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Self</ENAMEX>, thankfully, is less of a booster.
His <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> is more like a cesspool. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simon</ENAMEX> goes out to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">nightclubs</ENAMEX>, where he
takes unholy quantities of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> and sneaks off to have sex with his hot,
vacant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX>; this is as sickening to him as "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> skeletons copulating in
a wardrobe." As for the art world, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simon</ENAMEX> is so bored by its worthless wannabes
that, while talking to them, he disassociates, turning one woman's "anatomy
inside out, sockwise," imagining what life looks like from up inside her
butt.

            It's a convincingly icky portrait, so we're relieved when
Self picks <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simon</ENAMEX> up and sends him on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Swiftian</ENAMEX> journey. <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">One morning</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simon</ENAMEX>
wakes up to find that his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX>, a petite blonde, has turned into a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">beast</ENAMEX>
that walks on its knuckles. Worse, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simon</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> at this turn of events is
interpreted as <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">insanity</ENAMEX>. He's hospitalized by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chimp paramedics</ENAMEX>, and held for
observation by a trendy, controversial chimp <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychiatrist</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Busner</ENAMEX>.
Slowly, via grunting and sign language, his furry new caretakers explain that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simon</ENAMEX> is a chimp, that he has been a chimp all along, and that his humanity has
been an illusion. Moreover, chimps are the civilized ones, while <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX>--slow,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">clumsy</ENAMEX>, embarrassingly hairless--are a primitive joke.

            To help us
picture these tony chimps, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Self</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publisher</ENAMEX> has helpfully supplied cover art
showing a low-browed, large-nostriled male <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">creature</ENAMEX>. The face has an obviously
simian <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cast</ENAMEX>--yet the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">creature</ENAMEX> sports a tweed coat and spectacles and parts his
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">silver hair</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">side</ENAMEX>; he bears a distinct resemblance to the late <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burns</ENAMEX>. It's a mesmerizingly gross notion and, for a while, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Self</ENAMEX> dazzles us with
the ramifications. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Self</ENAMEX>'s cleverest invention is probably the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chimps</ENAMEX>' language:
They convey words to each other by signing and touching each other's fur, and
they add emotional inflection with grunts like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">euch-euch</ENAMEX> (irritable) and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hooograa</ENAMEX> (friendly, inclusive). Another feature of chimp land is that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">monogamy</ENAMEX> has flown out the window. When a female goes into heat she thrusts out
her "swelling," and any male in sight, from the sweet old local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dad</ENAMEX>, is invited to partake. As for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">males</ENAMEX>, they all want to be the alpha,
the top <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX>. Every encounter is either a challenge or a sniveling suck-up.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Self</ENAMEX> has the chimps <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">spray shit</ENAMEX>, get crumbs of
it stuck in their fur and, in the case of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> odious academic, drink it--which
more than meets the fecal humor quota for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>. But, pretty soon, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Self</ENAMEX>'s
imagination begins to sputter. He gives us dexterous word painting, like this
description of a decrepit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> in which "the ghosts of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> long
departed recline on skeletal neststeads and the broken <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">spirits</ENAMEX> of long gone
junior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> toe-tap mournfully over the linoleum." He gives us elaborate
descriptions of chimp <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>, which looks much the same as human <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>, only a
few sizes smaller. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Self</ENAMEX>, it's surprising to discover, is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">painstaking realist</ENAMEX>.
And much of what he describes is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dully</ENAMEX> familiar: There is a chimp Noam Chomsky
and a chimp <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Liam Gallagher</ENAMEX>, and upper-class chimps read The 
               New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yorker</ENAMEX> .

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> often praise <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Self</ENAMEX>'s
cerebral rigor, his sharp satiric grip on our foibles--and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Great Apes</ENAMEX>
does occasionally gesture in this direction. He inverts intellectual history,
tracing <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">18 th</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chimps</ENAMEX>' fascination with savage
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Swift</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Yahoos</ENAMEX> being a prime example--and the delusional arrogance with
which "Western Civilization ... had projected itself towards divinity on the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">up</NUMEX>-escalator of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Chain</ENAMEX> of Being." He also pokes fun at evolutionary
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">biologists</ENAMEX>, who so confidently ascribe all our behavior to genetic programming.
But these ideas aren't developed; they remain on the level of rhetoric. As for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">insight</ENAMEX> into any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> other than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simon's</ENAMEX>, here are a few of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Self</ENAMEX>'s pearls,
which he delivers with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">I</ENAMEX>-don't-really-mean-it, yes-I-do exhibitionism of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard Stern</ENAMEX>. There are <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chimps</ENAMEX> with big "nasal <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridges</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">females</ENAMEX> in
the novel tend to be dumb and nymphomaniac, and one is an especially miserable,
laughable <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fool</ENAMEX>. There are also black-furred <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">monkeys</ENAMEX>, or "bonobos"--huge
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">creatures</ENAMEX> who excel at sports and love to have sex and to dance.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Swift</ENAMEX> was just as merciless,
of course. So why is he timeless, while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Self</ENAMEX>'s sendups of PC already seem
dated, as if he'd jotted them down in a fit of childish pique in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>? I wonder
if it's that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Swift</ENAMEX>, for all his pessimism, was deeply engaged in the events of
his day. He was a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Whig</ENAMEX>-turned-fervent-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tory</ENAMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activist</ENAMEX> cleric, a staunch
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defender</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anglican Church</ENAMEX>. Much of the power of his bilious attacks comes
from a righteous <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> sense of sin. <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">Self strains</ENAMEX> to carry on the
tradition, but the world has changed since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1726</TIMEX>. He preserves <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Swift</ENAMEX>'s rage
without his certainty. His <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">attacks</ENAMEX> seem less illuminating than pointless;
they're out of it, and unnecessarily cruel. A little like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royal Family</ENAMEX>, it
occurred to me <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX>. It will be interesting to see what happens if the
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Flower Revolution</ENAMEX> extends to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> literature.

         
      
   
