
   
   
      
         
            Apocalypse Imminently

            Let me make one thing clear,
before I cruelly attack this book: I admire <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Davis</ENAMEX>. His <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX> jeremiad,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">City</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quartz</ENAMEX> , was a classic of well-directed rage. In macho prose,
with obsessive reporting, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX> all but predicted the date and street address
of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> riots. He attacked the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Police Department</ENAMEX>, the corporate
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boosters</ENAMEX>' whitewashing of city history, the absurd and isolating layout driven
more by greed than geographical logic. He displayed a rare awareness of Latinos
in the region, both past and present. (I'd love to know what he thinks of
Bulworth , with its literally black-and-white take on racial strife.)

            Above
all, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX> was humane. He was fascinated by the abstract weirdness of
contemporary <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>, but he didn't get off on it like some silly French
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">postmodernist</ENAMEX>. Instead, he got angry. Sometimes too angry, seeming to argue
that all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reformers</ENAMEX> were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elitists</ENAMEX>, all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX> closet racists.

            Over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past eight years</TIMEX>, that anger has mushroomed into
panic. It's hard to describe <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX>' new book, since it flits among several
genres. At its best, it's a sequel to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">City of Quartz</ENAMEX> , using the
environment as a window onto <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>' social problems. At its weirdest,
it's a diatribe shot through with millennial overtones, so that its reach is
much larger than just the environment--it's about the ultimate doom of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mankind</ENAMEX>,
or something like that. And then there are whole <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapters</ENAMEX> that smell like old
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">articles Davis</ENAMEX> wrote a while back in the alternative press and recycled to fill
out a volume.

            The book
shuttles back and forth in a wacky dialectic. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thesis No. 1</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>'
ecological system is more likely than any place on earth to suffer earthquakes,
volcanoes, floods, fires, grizzlies, rabid squirrels, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">killer bees</ENAMEX>. Even
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tornadoes</ENAMEX>, which are generally thought to prefer the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Midwest</ENAMEX>, spin
threateningly on the horizon. But, of course, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angelenos</ENAMEX>, world champions of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">denial</ENAMEX>, are ignoring the situation. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fools</ENAMEX> assume that the aberrant
quiescence of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past 50 years</TIMEX> is the norm. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thesis No. 2</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angelenos</ENAMEX> are
excessively paranoid. Natural disaster is all they think about--it's their
guiding legend, muse, and inspiration, as well as a great way to avoid thinking
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about</NUMEX> race and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX>.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Davis</ENAMEX> believes both <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Thesis No. 1 and Thesis No.</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>, though they seem to contradict each other. Take the following dance:
"Middle-class apprehensions about the angry, abandoned underclasses are now
only exceeded by <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">anxieties</ENAMEX> about blind thrust faults and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">hundred-year</TIMEX> floods.
Meanwhile, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caltech</ENAMEX> seismologists warn that the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pacific Rim</ENAMEX> is only beginning
its long overdue rock and roll: the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kobe</ENAMEX> catastrophe may be a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">3-D</NUMEX> preview of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>. And waiting in the wings are the plague squirrels and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">killer bees</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First Davis</ENAMEX> accuses the bourgeoisie of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">misdirected anxieties</ENAMEX>,
then he urges them to wake up and worry.

            The
disconnect here seems to represent a conflict basic to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lover</ENAMEX> of nitty-gritty facts rubs up against the acolyte of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Frankfurt</ENAMEX>
School. At <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX> borrows <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter Benjamin</ENAMEX>'s melancholy idea that
history is a dialectical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fairy</ENAMEX> tale--a bunch of contradictory stories people
tell about themselves, "linked together by strange ironies." Attempts to put
such notions into practice send <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX> off the deep end.

            He's much more persuasive as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>. A great
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mini</ENAMEX>-chapter on the history of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> floods shows how at a critical
moment city <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> rejected the idea of zoning to avoid floods. Instead
they went with the notion of flood control, which gave them a nice pork barrel
budget for public works and allowed rich <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> build a house wherever they
damn well felt like it. A rather heartbreaking section argues that similar
greed-based zoning has endangered the lives of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">firefighters</ENAMEX>. Unable to use
their usual firefighting techniques for fear of endangering the property next
door, they're forced into a futile house<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">-by-</NUMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> battle in what is essentially
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> huge firetrap. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Davis</ENAMEX> tells you more than you ever thought you wanted to
know about the hunting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lobby</ENAMEX> and security at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Calipatria State Prison</ENAMEX>, where
a surrounding <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">fence</ENAMEX> is rigged to zap human beings but welcome cute little
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">squirrels</ENAMEX> and birdies. And he has an eye for grotesque detail: In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX> of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>, swarms of writhing snakes washed up on beaches from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tijuana</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santa</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara</ENAMEX>. It isn't clear what this fact proves, but it's alarming and
memorable.

            Plus it
has biblical resonance, and there are biblical implications to the story <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX>
is telling. The ecosystem in the world that most resembles <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>' is the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mediterranean</ENAMEX>, he tells us--and the best natural history of the ancient
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mediterranean</ENAMEX> is found in the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Davis</ENAMEX> seems to think that the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">horsemen of the Apocalypse</ENAMEX> will arrive via the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pacific Coast Highway</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Chapter 3</ENAMEX>
is titled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"The Case for Letting Malibu Burn</ENAMEX>." I fear that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX> really wants
this to happen. Maybe a good fire will shake things up, his thinking seems to
go--take the rich <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> out of their game. It'll accomplish what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Angeles</ENAMEX> riots and all the striking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX> and political protests in the world
failed to do: It'll bring on a revolution.

            
There's despair in this notion, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">frivolity</ENAMEX>--it's a good <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">20 minute</TIMEX> riff at a cocktail party but not the stuff of
a book. Even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX> seems to realize this. He runs out of gas <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about two-thirds</NUMEX>
of the way through and turns into an armchair academic. The last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">few</NUMEX> chapters
are truly disappointing--slack, dated, and filled with tired ideas. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Davis</ENAMEX>
surveys disaster stories set in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>, but he's an insecure literary
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX>, and his emphasis on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fairy</ENAMEX> tale aspect of natural disaster
undermines the facts that have gone before. His argument appears to be that
fictional disasters stand in for racism. He appears to have missed the Will
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX> phenomenon, whereby a masculine and not deracinated black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> repeatedly
saves the world.

            Upon finishing this book, I
was seized by a deep feeling of stuckness. "The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">1990s</NUMEX> in particular have been a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">funereal decade</TIMEX>, interring many of the hopes and fantasies of the earlier
twentieth <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">century</TIMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX> intones. Funereal, indeed. I'm not saying <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX>
should stop complaining and suck it up, but <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this decade</TIMEX> has seen the birth of
new fantasies, and he fails to take them on. There's no mention of the Internet
here, though surely it must have some effect on the way <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> define their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">loyalties</ENAMEX> and civic duties. Ecology of Fear reads like a book written in
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">middle of the 1992</TIMEX> recession. There's no sign of an economic boom or
increased optimism (whether justified or not) about technology.

            Also, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX> needs to get
over his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">exceptionalism</ENAMEX>. Segregation on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South Side</ENAMEX> is as
vicious as it is in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Compton</ENAMEX>, and if you're talking about criminalizing the poor
and turning public space over to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>, then <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudolph Giuliani</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>
would seem to be the current industry <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>. Scary rodent-borne viruses are
making a comeback across the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, not just in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Southern California</ENAMEX>. And what
about floods in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Dakota</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> or fires in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oakland</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Daytona</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beach</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fla.</ENAMEX>? Maybe <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> isn't the scariest place on earth after all.

         
      
   
