
   
   
      
         
            Out of the Past

            <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Forty</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX>, when
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> still believed in progress, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">revolutionary</ENAMEX> young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">composers</ENAMEX> named
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luciano Berio</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Krzysztof Penderecki</ENAMEX> undertook a musical purge. <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX>
was over, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> wanted to scrub off its history, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Berio</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Penderecki</ENAMEX>, an
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pole</ENAMEX>, were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of the music world's most ruthless and effective
slate-cleaners. Berio disassembled traditional techniques of playing,
instrument by instrument, in a series of solo pieces called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sequenze</ENAMEX> ,
the most famous of which was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sequenza III</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1966</TIMEX>) for unaccompanied
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">voice</ENAMEX>--<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">eight minutes</TIMEX> of theatrical giggling, clicking consonants, and heavy
breathing. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1960</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Penderecki</ENAMEX> exploded the lyrical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX> of the string
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">orchestra</ENAMEX> in his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Threnody</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Victims</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hiroshima</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">52</NUMEX> stringed
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">instruments</ENAMEX>, a brutal piece commemorating an act of violence.

            Both of
these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">composers</ENAMEX> came to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX>. Berio, accompanied by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">technicians</ENAMEX>
from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Centro Tempo Reale</ENAMEX>, his electronic-music <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florence</ENAMEX>, and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Orchestra della Toscana</ENAMEX>, performed his work-in-perpetual-progress,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ofanim</ENAMEX> . <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">The following week</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Penderecki</ENAMEX> conducted a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> Philharmonic
performance of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Threnody</ENAMEX> and gave the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> premiere of a recent
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">symphony</ENAMEX>-- <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">No. 5</NUMEX> , written in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Berio</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">72</NUMEX> now, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Penderecki 64 and</ENAMEX>, like revolutionaries
everywhere, they belong to a generation that has fallen into disrepute. Many
young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">composers</ENAMEX> view musical modernism with distaste, much as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Berio</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Penderecki</ENAMEX> and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peers</ENAMEX> viewed late <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Romanticism</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">their day</TIMEX>. These <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>,
along with the rest of their generation, are often charged with having reduced
music to a set of games, making it schematic and emotionally barren. The
decades of modernism, however, produced music that was vehement (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Crumb</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Black Angels</ENAMEX> ), haunted (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elliott Carter</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Night Fantasies</ENAMEX> ),
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">humorous</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Berio's Sequenze</ENAMEX> ), dazzling (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wijtold Lutoslawski</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Les</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Espaces du Sommeil</ENAMEX> )--not to mention music that wasn't modernist at all. If
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audiences</ENAMEX> came to believe that the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">compositions</ENAMEX> of their time were mechanical,
it is largely because they listened less to the music than to what the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX>
said about themselves.

            "I wrote
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Threnody</ENAMEX> thinking only about structure [and] architecture," Penderecki
once said. "I don't really care much about emotions." The music preceded the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">title</ENAMEX>, he insisted, and it would be wrong to hear nuclear-age despair in the
clangor of bows being bounced and scraped on the strings, of fingers tapping on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">wood</ENAMEX>, or of the siren wails produced by floods of sliding glissandi. Wrong,
perhaps, but inevitable. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Threnody</ENAMEX> is expressive in spite of itself.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Berio</ENAMEX> also denied his passions. In an interview
he gave in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985</TIMEX>, he described an early encounter with opera, when he was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX>.
"The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">radio</ENAMEX> was carrying <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">La Bohème</ENAMEX> ," he recounted, "and I suddenly found
my eyes filling with tears. So, to hide them, I dropped a spoon on the floor.
... <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anyway</ENAMEX>, I soon got over the emotional excitements of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Bohème</ENAMEX> ."

            His music suggests
otherwise. Ofanim , a long biblical cantata for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> matched <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">ensembles</ENAMEX> of
wind, brass, and percussion; <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> choirs; female voice; and computer; is a
highly operatic piece of the sort <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Puccini</ENAMEX> would have understood. At the New
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">York</ENAMEX> performance, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Esti Kenan Ofri</ENAMEX> spent most of the time
shrouded in drapery and darkness at the foot of the podium, slowly rising and
writhing only for the keening solo that ends the piece, a recitative redolent
of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Middle Eastern</ENAMEX> rites. An earlier trombone cadenza was a modernist echo of
the ram's-horn blast that ushers in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jewish New Year</TIMEX>.

            There
were plenty of "emotional excitements." The music rolled like a wave through a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dozen</ENAMEX> episodes, each of them based on a passage from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ezekiel</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Song</ENAMEX> of
Songs. (The title, which means "wheels" in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Hebrew</ENAMEX>, refers to an apocalyptic
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vision</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ezekiel</ENAMEX>.) It crested on choruses of screaming <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy sopranos</ENAMEX> and
furious churning from the instruments, then abated to quiet intonations and
still chords, filigreed by a solo clarinet. It may just have been heat or
hunger that caused <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> chorister to faint as if on cue as soon as the last
chord faded during a rehearsal that <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>, but it was easy to believe he had
been felled by the music.

            The real problem with the most innovative music of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">postwar</ENAMEX> era is not so much that it is dry as that it can sound dated.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Penderecki</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Threnody</ENAMEX> is a good example. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the decades</TIMEX> since it was
composed, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">orchestras</ENAMEX> have been asked to make noises that sound much worse than
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Penderecki</ENAMEX>'s squeaks and blurts. In the meantime, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Penderecki</ENAMEX> has been trying to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">recast</ENAMEX> himself as a grand old symphonist in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brucknerian</ENAMEX> mold. His
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Symphony No. 5</ENAMEX> lasts <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">only 35 minutes</TIMEX>--no longer than a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mozart</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">symphony</ENAMEX>--but it has the feel of something weighty, sprawling, and epic. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great</ENAMEX>
blasts of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brass</ENAMEX>; a fugue built on a long, solid cable of a theme; climaxes that
follow each other with the deafening regularity of an artillery barrage; horns
that blare from the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">balconies</ENAMEX>: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nearly every moment</TIMEX> seems calculated to matter.
When <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19 th -century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">composers</ENAMEX> wanted to be solemn, they invoked the
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Baroque: Thick counterpoint</ENAMEX> and a good old passacaglia--variations over a
repeating bass--never failed to sound lofty. Penderecki <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cranks</ENAMEX> up
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19 th -century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baroque</ENAMEX>-style rhetoric into something both stentorian
and shrill. His passacaglia sounds less like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bach</ENAMEX> than like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruckner</ENAMEX> imitating
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bach</ENAMEX>. He has come a long way from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who once proudly claimed to have
"destroyed normal harmony and notation."

            
Berio, on the other hand, hasn't needed to
rediscover history. In a landmark <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1968</TIMEX> work, the wryly named <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sinfonia</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Berio</ENAMEX> made a musical palimpsest, thickly layering his new music and a jumble of
spoken words over the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundation</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mahler</ENAMEX> symphony. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ofanim</ENAMEX> , Berio
has combined his search for new technologies with a reverence for rituals and
ancient theater: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Microphones</ENAMEX> picked up sounds from the stage and computers
tossed them to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speakers</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">balconies</ENAMEX> and back again, letting chords and
passages hang in the air like incense.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sacramental</ENAMEX> feel of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ofanim</ENAMEX> is both apt and ironic, for both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">composers</ENAMEX> came to fame for
bringing down temples. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Four decades later</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Penderecki</ENAMEX> has joined the ranks of
those who renounce the achievements of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Berio</ENAMEX> remains
unabashedly highbrow and staunchly atonal, a true avant-gardist. When the next
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">modernist</ENAMEX> revolution comes around, he'll be ready.

         
      
   
