
   
   
      
         
            The Conformist

            I'm not a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, so I'm not
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> who hailed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nick Hornby</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> novel, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High Fidelity</ENAMEX> ,
as the ultimate exposé of the contemporary male psyche. What I do know is that
the story made for a fun read: A <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">35-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Londoner</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rob</ENAMEX> with the
maturity level of a high-school junior dumps his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX> and retreats to his
pathetic job in a music <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX>. He fetishizes his record collection until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX>
he realizes that it's just a stack of plastic discs, not a fulfilling life
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX>.

            Hornby
writes with awesome fluidity. His musings on the destructive beauty of pop
culture, the way it merchandizes melancholy to vulnerable young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, at
times achieve something like philosophical depth. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> for an example.) The
book's unapologetic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> with personal happiness even lent it a classical
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">grace</ENAMEX>. You could almost see it as a throwback to the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18 th century</TIMEX>,
before the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Novel</ENAMEX> got confused with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Art</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novelist</ENAMEX>'s job was to write
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">clean</ENAMEX> prose, trot out a few moral guidelines, and make the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> laugh. My
only complaints with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High Fidelity</ENAMEX> were with a few cloying Growth
Moments and the cute <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">epilogue</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> at which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rob</ENAMEX> plays <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DJ</ENAMEX> and every
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> in the novel appears to issue a happy farewell. The finale is
reminiscent of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of those <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Pollyanna</ENAMEX>-ish endings on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beverly Hills</ENAMEX> 90210
such as when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donna</ENAMEX> gets out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> after an attempted rape, and the
whole <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">gang</ENAMEX> gathers at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peach Pit</ENAMEX> for a supersupportive celebration.

            If you had to quantify it, the brilliant-to-annoying ratio
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High Fidelity</ENAMEX> would probably be about <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">4-to-1</ENAMEX>. Maybe it was inevitable
that in a new <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hornby</ENAMEX> effort, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">number</ENAMEX> would decline. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rob</ENAMEX> was immature,
but his desperate clinging to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX> placed him inside a world of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rock</ENAMEX> trivia
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hornby</ENAMEX> described in beautifully specific detail. By comparison, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Will</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">About</NUMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boy</ENAMEX> , is an abstraction, the sort of handsome cipher you
see in magazine ads for khakis. He's inherited a nest <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">egg</ENAMEX>, so instead of
working he sits at home and watches <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> television. All signs to the
contrary, he thinks this shallow bachelorhood is glamorous. His joys in life
are dressing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">well</ENAMEX> and going "clubbing." In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>, apparently, this makes him
an archetype of male cool.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Will</ENAMEX> wants
to sleep with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, but he doesn't want to get involved, so he comes up with a
plan. He'll pursue beautiful single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> and pretend he has a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>, too.
This will trick his girlfriends into thinking he's capable of depth and caring.
Then, before things get too heavy, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> will realize her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> comes first
and break up with him. "Great sex, a lot of ego massage, temporary parenthood
without tears and a guilt-free parting--what more could a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> want?"

            
In other words, the premise of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">About</NUMEX> a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boy</ENAMEX> is as thin as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Handi Wipe</ENAMEX>. It's like something a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> of TV
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> might dream up for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Costanza</ENAMEX> on a lesser episode of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seinfeld</ENAMEX> . But after a few implausible episodes in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Will</ENAMEX> tries out
his ruse, he finally embarks on a challenging relationship. It's not with a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> at all, but with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marcus</ENAMEX>, a geeky <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Will</ENAMEX> meets the poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>
when the woman <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Will</ENAMEX> is currently attempting to date drags the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> along on a
picnic as a favor to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>'s flaky <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>. Will <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">resents</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marcus</ENAMEX> and finds him
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">weird</ENAMEX>, but when he drops him off at home, they find the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> passed out in a
failed suicide attempt, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Will</ENAMEX>'s sympathy is engaged. Sort of. Actually,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marcus</ENAMEX> fixates on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Will</ENAMEX> as a potential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> figure and starts appearing at his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">house</ENAMEX> uninvited. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Will</ENAMEX> feels guilty, lets him in to watch television and slowly,
very slowly, begins to get involved.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marcus</ENAMEX> is a complex and
touching creation, and his growth arc easily beats out <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Will</ENAMEX>'s for interest. A
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> of the modern parental tyranny of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hippie</ENAMEX> idealism, he doesn't watch
television, eat <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX>, or know how to dress, and his music-listening at home is
tragically restricted to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joni Mitchell</ENAMEX>. He misses the cultural references kids
throw around at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>. The bullies in his class sense this and pounce, like
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">hyenas</ENAMEX> on a limping gazelle. Meanwhile, his well-meaning but narcissistic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother mopes</ENAMEX> around the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, so his only example of adult behavior is
hopeless isolation.

            In his
clueless search for companionship, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marcus</ENAMEX> gets a crush on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ellie</ENAMEX>, a
troublemaking older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> (she's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX>) obsessed with the pessimistic lyrics of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kurt Cobain</ENAMEX>. Here you can see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hornby</ENAMEX> straining hard to live up to his
reputation as an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">interpreter</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zeitgeist</ENAMEX> . The novel is set in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>,
and the climax cleverly dovetails with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cobain</ENAMEX>'s suicide. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hornby</ENAMEX> clearly means
to revisit a <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Defining Cultural Moment</ENAMEX>, with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ellie</ENAMEX> symbolizing the peril of
taking rock 'n' roll angst as a model for life.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> of problems with this strategy: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) It's too early
to look back on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid-'90s</TIMEX> with clarity, let alone nostalgia. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) As wise as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hornby</ENAMEX>'s warning against overwrought adolescent feeling is, the alternatives
aren't very appealing. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marcus</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classmates</ENAMEX> abuse him, his mother ignores his
needs, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ellie</ENAMEX> is insane. That leaves him with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Will</ENAMEX>. But what does Will know
how to do? Buy records and clothes, be selfish, and not take anything
seriously. In all the obvious ways, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">About</NUMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boy</ENAMEX> feels like a
continuation of the themes in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High Fidelity</ENAMEX> . But where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fidelity</ENAMEX> argued against too much coolness, the new novel is about the
benefits of fitting in.

            It's almost brave, this
defense of conformity. It certainly defies the standard tropes of writing about
young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>--all that stuff about how it's OK to be yourself, even if you're
different. Brave or not, though, it's still shallow. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the great things
about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High Fidelity</ENAMEX> was the way it made emotional epiphanies function as
plot. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rob</ENAMEX>'s painful realization that he was lonely was as thrilling as the
naming of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">murderer</ENAMEX> in a whodunit. In <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">About</NUMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boy</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> go
through the motions of growing up without conducting the necessary internal
search. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Will</ENAMEX>'s maturity simply arrives <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX>, like a piece of mail: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Will</ENAMEX>
couldn't recall ever having been caught up in this sort of messy, sprawling,
chaotic web before; it was almost as if he had been given a glimpse of what it
was like to be human. It wasn't too bad, really; he wouldn't even mind being
human on a full-time basis." As for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marcus</ENAMEX>, under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Will</ENAMEX>'s sartorial influence,
"[h]e had flattened out and become as robust and unremarkable as any
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">twelve</NUMEX>-year-old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>." The message is that there's a right way to dress and a
right set of music to listen to and that hippies, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">geeks</ENAMEX>, angry <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-agers</ENAMEX>, and
other marginal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would make life easier for themselves if they'd just get
with the program.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hornby</ENAMEX> still writes with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">warmth</ENAMEX> and charm. In fact he renders his message in such appealing, facile
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">strokes</ENAMEX> that one wants to believe he just panicked after the success of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fidelity</ENAMEX> and turned out a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">callow</ENAMEX> rush job. More depressing is the
possibility that he means it.

         
      
   
