
   
   
      
         
            All <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Men</ENAMEX>

            Shortly after he won the
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pulitzer Prize</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Parting the Waters</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>), which chronicled the first
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">decade</ENAMEX> of the civil-rights movement, author <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Taylor Branch</ENAMEX> told a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> that
he would probably complete his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> and final volume by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the fall of 1990</TIMEX>,
"when the money runs out." <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Eight years</TIMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">746</NUMEX> pages <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later</TIMEX>, he has, in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pillar of Fire</ENAMEX> , covered roughly <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">26 months</TIMEX>, from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the beginning of 1963</TIMEX>
through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early 1965</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">A third</NUMEX> volume is promised. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Branch</ENAMEX>, who now knows better,
hasn't predicted when it will be done.

            
               Pillar
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fire</ENAMEX> 's sprawl doesn't come from the kind of notebook-emptying
self-indulgence that often clogs up journalistic histories. Rather, the book's
breadth reflects <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Branch</ENAMEX>'s enthusiasm for his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subject</ENAMEX> and his appreciation of
its epic dimensions. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> he covers here were the high-water <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> for the
movement. There were previously unthinkable triumphs: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protests</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Birmingham</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Selma</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ala.</ENAMEX>, that helped topple <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Crow</ENAMEX>; a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">quarter-million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Americans</ENAMEX>
gathering in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> to demand racial equality; black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northern</ENAMEX>
white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteers</ENAMEX> registering hordes of black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>; a civil-rights act
outlawing racial discrimination, passed despite a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three-month</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>
filibuster.

            And yet, there were also appalling setbacks: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAACP Field</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Medgar Evers</ENAMEX> was assassinated. Freedom Summer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteers</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goodman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Chaney</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Schwerner</ENAMEX> were murdered. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic</ENAMEX>
Party spurned <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mississippi</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freedom Party</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">delegation</ENAMEX>, seating a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bloc</ENAMEX> of
segregationist <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX> instead. Fissures widened within and among the leading
civil-rights <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>, in some cases irreparably.

            A
magisterial storyteller, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Branch</ENAMEX> ranges confidently over these peaks and
valleys, but he also stops along the way to explore a slew of seemingly less
significant tales. The great strength of this book is the way <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Branch</ENAMEX> zooms in
on the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of local skirmishes, from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenwood</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miss.</ENAMEX>, to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Augustine</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fla.</ENAMEX>, through which the movement's shock <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> waged their nonviolent
campaigns. He returns again and again to these chosen locales, lingering over
them, patiently narrating their miniature dramas: a march by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">schoolchildren</ENAMEX> to
get library cards, a black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s fatal decision to attend a white <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">theater</ENAMEX>. At
breaks in the action, he will inconspicuously cut away to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>, or
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Luther King</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX>. But though he amply covers
the higher-stakes political events, he never allows them to eclipse his larger
story: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sharecroppers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dentists</ENAMEX>, prying their freedom
loose from the grip of segregationist <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX>--and in so doing stripping away
the racist restrictions that had always made the achievements of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
democracy ring hollow.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Branch</ENAMEX>'s most powerful scenes are his unflinching
descriptions of the horrors endured by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX>, from the
"medieval privations of ," to barbaric beatings by , to the arson and murder
committed by . When TV cameras covered events like these, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> was
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">riveted</ENAMEX>, but often these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> sacrifices went unnoticed by reporters
swooning over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX>. At <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point in his account of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mississippi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freedom</ENAMEX>
Summer voter-registration drive, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Branch</ENAMEX> describes the release from a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenwood</ENAMEX>
jail of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">111</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protesters</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the same day</TIMEX> King arrived in town.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Foul-smelling</ENAMEX> and haggard from a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six-day</TIMEX> hunger strike, ... some of them
briefly mistook the commotion downtown as a welcoming ceremony for them.
Unfamiliar <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> prowled with clipboards and camera equipment, wrote
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">volunteer Sally Belfrage</ENAMEX>, who noted that "for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Negroes</ENAMEX> there hardly seemed to be
anyone who wasn't rushing around looking for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX>, cooking for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX>, talking of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX> as if they couldn't find him, and thinking of him as if there was no one
to talk to."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Branch</ENAMEX> does place <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> at the center of his history, but
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pillar of Fire</ENAMEX> is far too broad to be labeled a biography of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>.
Nor is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> here the mythic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figure</ENAMEX> who has become our only undisputed
contemporary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX>. Branch restores to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> his human dimensions.

            That King
was fallible was almost forgotten in the mad rush to immortalize him during his
own lifetime. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1963</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> named him <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Man of the Year</ENAMEX>, praising his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Birmingham</ENAMEX> desegregation protests that made him "the
unchallenged voice of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Negro</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>--and the disquieting conscience of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX>." The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>, he won the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nobel Peace Prize</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX>'s prominence
turned out to be a mixed blessing. Whipsawed between the need, on the one hand,
to preserve good relations with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> as it cautiously pushed the
landmark civil-rights bill and, on the other, to placate the fiery young
methods suited to his stature as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prince</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Negro</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX>." He backed away
from protests (such as a "stall-in" at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York World</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fair</ENAMEX>) as often as
he led them. He frequently emerges from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Branch</ENAMEX>'s narrative as indecisive,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">feckless</ENAMEX>, even weak. At <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point he states that his own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> was
"standing still, doing nothing, going nowhere."

            
Unknown to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX> was also hemmed in
by blackmail threats from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J. Edgar Hoover despised King</ENAMEX>, whom he
genuinely believed to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist</ENAMEX> and further resented for assailing the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bureau</ENAMEX>'s sometimes laggard enforcement of justice in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">lawless South</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hoover</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> received special commendations for such petty deeds as getting
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marquette University</ENAMEX> to withdraw an honorary doctorate it had planned to award
King. Worse, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bureau</ENAMEX> tapped <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX>'s phones and shadowed his every move,
hunting for any damaging secrets.

            On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6, 1964</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> installed microphones in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">King</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>, hotel room
and turned on the tape recorder. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> who heard the tapes,
King that night betrayed his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coretta</ENAMEX>--not for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> or the last
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>--shouting, amid his most private activities, "I'm fucking for God!" and
"I'm not a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Negro</ENAMEX> tonight!" <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Later that year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">agents anonymously</ENAMEX> shipped <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX> "a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'highlight</ENAMEX>' recording of bugged sex groans and party jokes" along with a letter
warning him: "You are done. There is but one way out for you. You better take
it before your filthy, abnormal fraudulent self is bared to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>." They
called it the "suicide package."

            While <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King vacillated</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malcolm X</ENAMEX> seized the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s
attention with his calls for retribution, tempting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> weary of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">King</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nonviolence</ENAMEX> and sending <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX> into a panic. Throughout <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pillar of Fire</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malcolm</ENAMEX> upstages <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX>'s speeches may seem like part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
political canon now, but in the despair of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early '60s</TIMEX>, they could appear
toothless next to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malcolm</ENAMEX>'s rhetorical <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">daggers</ENAMEX>. "Anyone can sit," the angry
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">preacher sneered</ENAMEX>, belittling the transformative techniques of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protesters</ENAMEX> for desegregation. "An old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> can sit. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coward</ENAMEX> can sit. ... It
takes a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> to stand." When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malcolm</ENAMEX>, rejoicing over a plane crash that killed
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">120</NUMEX> white <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Atlantans</ENAMEX>, chalked the disaster up to "our God" and hoped that "every
day another <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> falls out of the sky," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX> could only reply, feebly, "I
would certainly disagree with him." Privately, too, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX> brooded over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malcolm</ENAMEX>'s
jibes about "my being soft and ... my being a sort of polished <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Uncle Tom</ENAMEX>."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Branch</ENAMEX>
interprets the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malcolm-Martin</ENAMEX> choice not, as the press did, as a simple
contrast between violence and gentleness, but as a contest between democracy
and its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Branch</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">King</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">theologian</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> way. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">King</ENAMEX>'s
letter from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Birmingham</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">jail</ENAMEX>, where he languished for a week in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 1963</TIMEX>,
he "pulled up hope in paired phrases of secular and religious faith,"
repeatedly invoking "constitutional and God-given rights" in a
"characteristically <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> ... notion of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">divine sanction</ENAMEX> for democratic
values."

            
Where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> invoked <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s promise, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malcolm</ENAMEX>
underscored its betrayal. "It was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who advocate democracy who sold us
like <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cotton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cows</ENAMEX> from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plantation</ENAMEX> to another," he told a gasping crowd
at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City College</ENAMEX>. "It was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who advocate democracy who had black
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> lynched from one end of this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> to another. ... All the hell our
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have ever caught in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, they have caught in the name of
democracy." As <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Branch</ENAMEX> notes, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX> and the movement's established leaders
sounded ponderous against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malcolm</ENAMEX>'s avenging swagger." And yet, for the wider
public, black and white, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malcolm</ENAMEX> was also a helpful foil to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX>, whose
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">munificence</ENAMEX> looked noble and whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">radicalism</ENAMEX> looked moderate in contrast.

            But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pillar of Fire</ENAMEX>
isn't a study of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> charismatic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> any more than it is a biography. Its
lasting impression is of a portrait <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">gallery</ENAMEX> of inspiring <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> just
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> among many. I think, for example, of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">June Johnson</ENAMEX>, who joined
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Moses</ENAMEX> and his "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troublemakers</ENAMEX>" (as her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> called them) in an excursion
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Selma</ENAMEX>, only to wind up beaten by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Winona</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miss.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">jail</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> never imagined that history would remember them. But
quietly, compellingly, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Branch</ENAMEX> shows how they forced <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">America</ENAMEX> to rethink what it
means to be a democracy, achieving with their deeds what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> so brilliantly
articulated with his words.

         
      
   
