
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hipness Is All</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">People</ENAMEX>
make a mistake in supposing "hip" to mean "stylish." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hip</ENAMEX> is a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">self-consciousness</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nathanael West</ENAMEX> offered an example of it in his short novel
The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dream Life of Balso Snell</ENAMEX> , by writing this:

            An intelligent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> finds
it easy to laugh at himself, but his laughter is not sincere if it is thorough.
If I could be <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hamlet</ENAMEX>, or even a clown with a breaking heart 'neath his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jester</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">motley</ENAMEX>, the role would be tolerable. But I always find it necessary to
burlesque the mystery of feeling at its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX>; I must laugh at myself, and if
the laugh is "bitter," I must laugh at the laugh.

            But
that's not all. He also laughed at the laugh at the laugh, and so on, unto
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">eternity</ENAMEX>. The self-burlesquing quality in the truly hip is relentless, which
means that hip is a tragic condition. From this point of view, life must have
been hard for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nathanael West</ENAMEX>. But it is true that hip is amusing.

            West wrote <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only four</NUMEX> novels before dying in an auto crash
at the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age of 37</TIMEX>, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1940</TIMEX>. The last of those novels, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Day of the</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Locust</ENAMEX> , was filmed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1975</TIMEX>, which makes it the most famous of his titles
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. But the key to understanding him lies in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of his novels, The
Dream <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Life of Balso Snell</ENAMEX> , which took <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX> to write, from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1926</TIMEX> to
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1929</TIMEX>, and ended up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">49</NUMEX> pages long. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dream Life</ENAMEX> is wild. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX>
climbs into the anus of the wooden <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Trojan horse</ENAMEX> and goes wandering through its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">intestines</ENAMEX>, having adventures. He meets a little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>, who shows him his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">writings</ENAMEX>, and he meets his old writing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX>, Miss <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McGeeney</ENAMEX>, who shows him
her writings. The little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>'s writings turn out to be by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miss McGeeney</ENAMEX>, and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miss McGeeney</ENAMEX> end up having sex. And so forth--with the effect
being, exactly as promised by the manifestoes of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Surrealism</ENAMEX>, a work of total
realism.

            For you
feel, in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Dream Life</ENAMEX> , that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">West</ENAMEX> has filmed a jerky-camera record of
his own dream life, and that each new, ridiculous scene represents a further
unfolding of an altogether real and plausible personality. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personality</ENAMEX> is
nervous, fearful, sexually frustrated to the point of hysteria, terrified of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, and perhaps mildly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homosexual</ENAMEX>. But it is also too rigidly imprisoned in
sardonic literary references, or in the movies, or in popular clichés, ever to
penetrate its own deepest emotions--which, in any case, are too shameful to be
acknowledged. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personality</ENAMEX> is not unlike <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kafka</ENAMEX>'s, except with less
intellectual intensity, which is too bad, and with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inflections</ENAMEX>, which
is wonderful. Perhaps there was something <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> in the style--though <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">West</ENAMEX>, who
went to the trouble of changing his name from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weinstein</ENAMEX> (which in those days
was a good idea from a career perspective, even in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>, where he wrote
his screenplays), might not have appreciated the ethnic emphasis.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">T>he Dream Life of Balso</ENAMEX> Snell seems to have taught
him the rudiments of literary form, and in his next <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> novels, Miss
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lonelyhearts</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">1933) and A Cool Million</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1934</TIMEX>), he funneled this
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>-hysterical personality of his into some reasonably disciplined yet fully
grotesque story lines--in the case of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miss Lonelyhearts</ENAMEX> , the noir daily
life of a cynical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian</ENAMEX> advice <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX>, and in the case of A Cool
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Million</ENAMEX> , the adventures of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Horatio Alger</ENAMEX>-type <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>. I suppose that
Miss <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lonelyhearts</ENAMEX> should count as <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West</ENAMEX>'s masterpiece, due to the
fantastic procession of importuning advice-hounds that traipses across its
pages--a procession of battered <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wives</ENAMEX>, crippled cuckolded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husbands</ENAMEX>, syphilitic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, rape <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>, and deformed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-agers</ENAMEX> whose sufferings could break
your heart--except that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">West</ENAMEX>'s demeanor makes the whole thing slightly funny,
as in a sick joke. There's much to be said for the tone of comic-book violence:
"He buried his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">triangular</ENAMEX> face like the blade of a hatchet in her neck."

            But A
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cool Million</ENAMEX> is, in its modest way, the most perfect of his books. The
novel is strictly a sendup of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> patriotic inspirational literature. A
young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> sets out to earn his fortune and save his aged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> from eviction.
He passes through every <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX> of the uplift narratives: He meets a beneficent
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">banker</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patron</ENAMEX>, falls in love with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> next door, traverses the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>. Every word in the novel plunks the tinkly piano keys of a dime novel.
But the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">land</ENAMEX> of opportunity that goes reeling by in the background
turns out to be a nightmare of free-floating violence and organized fascism
(brilliantly imagined, by the way), until the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">America of A Cool Million</ENAMEX>
has outdone in scariness even the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kafka</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amerika</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> loses his thumb, his teeth, his leg, his scalp, and his nose; and the
creepier his sufferings become, the funnier is the book, sad to say.

            It's hard to imagine that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">West</ENAMEX> could ever have written a
conventional novel with any success. He tried in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Day of the Locust</ENAMEX>
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1939</TIMEX>), with its more or less realistic story of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> down and outs, but
mostly he succeeded in placing a veneer of hard-boiled literary conventions
over his manias about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and sex, which makes him seem just as crazy as in
his other books, but less aware of it, therefore less entertaining. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Library</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> edition of his writings, edited by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sacvan Bercovitch</ENAMEX>, includes, in a
spirit of thoroughness, random essays and stories that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> never
finished; some screenplays; and a few letters to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">F. Scott Fitzgerald</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edmund</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilson</ENAMEX>, and other literary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figures</ENAMEX>. These have their points of interest. "My
dear Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fitzgerald</ENAMEX>, You have been kind enough to say that you liked my novel,
Miss <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lonelyhearts</ENAMEX> . I am <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">applying for a Guggenheim Fellowship</ENAMEX>."

            But those <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> novels
show us everything that is appealing about <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West</ENAMEX>. He had the kind of neurotic,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sardonic</ENAMEX>, satiric, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">manic</TIMEX>, and generally -ic personality that I imagine was not
so common <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">60 years ago</TIMEX> (for who else was like him in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> letters? I can't
think of anyone), only to become mandatory <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. So he was prophetic, too. The
test of time has never been an accurate gauge of literary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX>. Greater
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> than <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West</ENAMEX> have been doomed to fade with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> does tell us
something, though. In the case of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nathanael West</ENAMEX>, it tells us that earnestness
ages and hip is ever fresh.

         
      
   
