
   
   
      
         
            For <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Viewers Like You</ENAMEX>

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early '70s</TIMEX>, even a
novice channel surfer could tell when he had landed on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>. There'd be a
cheerful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chef</ENAMEX> butchering a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cornish</ENAMEX> hen, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Muppets</ENAMEX> singing songs about friendship,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professors</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">moderator</ENAMEX> seated in a bare-bones studio discussing race
relations, a helmeted fat <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> singing, a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Third Worlder</ENAMEX> criticizing the First
World in a documentary, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">lions</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Serengeti</ENAMEX> stalking an impala
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">herd</ENAMEX>.

            But after
the many-tendriled <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">beast</ENAMEX> of cable TV conquered the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>, the mélange
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chefs</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Muppets</ENAMEX>, TV talk, and prowling <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">lions</ENAMEX> came to define not <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> but the
act of channel surfing itself. Of course, video vaudeville wasn't the goal of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>'s early <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architects</ENAMEX>, the culture shapers at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carnegie Commission</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foundation</ENAMEX> who dreamed that an infusion of federal funding would make the "vast
wasteland" of television bloom. How their dream cracked up, resulting in the
pablum of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>, and how <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> became <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>'s most politically
skittish <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>, is the subject of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Ledbetter</ENAMEX>'s brief history,
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Made Possible By ...:</ENAMEX> 
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Death of Public Broadcasting</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> .

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public TV</ENAMEX> was the runt of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">post-World War II</ENAMEX>
telecommunications litter. But it was planned that way. Commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">broadcasters</ENAMEX>
licenses and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">162</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UHF</ENAMEX> licenses nationwide for public-TV <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">broadcasters</ENAMEX>, but they
did so out of self-interest. Each frequency assigned to a noncommercial owner
meant <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> less competitor selling advertising. For the same reasons, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX>
pledged a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1-million</NUMEX> grant for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>'s debut <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX>, but the industry blocked at
every turn the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> model of a full-fledged public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> financed with a
hefty tax on televisions.

            Ledbetter
argues that public broadcasting's independence was tainted from the get-go by
the "military-communications complex." Military-industrial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">types</ENAMEX>, he reports,
had been loitering in the vicinity of educational broadcasting <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> before the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> decided to fund a government-supported system: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Officials</ENAMEX>
from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GE</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Atomic Energy Commission</ENAMEX> sat on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Education Television</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford Foundation</ENAMEX>-sponsored <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> precursor.
Defense <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contractors</ENAMEX> were recruited to explore the then-novel idea of networking
the new system with satellites. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> who midwifed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> included
<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Vietnam War</ENAMEX> escalator <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McGeorge Bundy</ENAMEX> and former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General</ENAMEX>
Dynamics <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Pace Jr.</ENAMEX>

            
While I'd love to be able to tell you that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>
was born in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a Seven Days</TIMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX> -type coup, and that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julia Child</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mister</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rogers</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Lehrer</ENAMEX> have been slipping us subliminal military propaganda
since the beginning, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ledbetter</ENAMEX> doesn't develop his idea that the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold Warriors</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">co-opted PBS</ENAMEX>. When the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> starts any new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enterprise</ENAMEX>, it always taps the
made <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX>--not the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herbert Marcuse</ENAMEX>. In fact, had the establishment
not been present at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>'s creation in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1967</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX>--a commercial
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">broadcaster</ENAMEX> himself (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lady Bird</ENAMEX> owned broadcast <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>)--would never
have green-lighted it.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> took
the public broadcasting handoff from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford Foundation</ENAMEX>, which, along with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carnegie Commission</ENAMEX>, had long exhorted the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> to start a public
system. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford Foundation</ENAMEX> seeded the public-TV idea with <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$300 million</NUMEX> worth
of grants <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 1951 and 1976</TIMEX> in the hope that the feds would completely
underwrite it thereafter (just as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> routinely assume responsibility for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">museums</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">libraries</ENAMEX> once <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">philanthropists</ENAMEX> found them). In the expansionist
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> of the Great Society, the idea of a government-financed TV <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> devoted
to education, culture, and politics wasn't that wild. Looking back, one
imagines that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> could have evolved into an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American BBC</ENAMEX> and secured the sort
of government funding that didn't require the scrutiny of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> congressional
appropriations. All this would have required was that its founding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bureaucrats</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) make the product seem as innocuous as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> exhibit and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) block the
election of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Nixon</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1968</TIMEX>. They failed on both counts.

            Instead, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early years</TIMEX> of the public-TV experiment,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> (which launched in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1969</TIMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NET</ENAMEX> (which received no federal funds) aired
the provocative programming they thought was their mission. These unflinching
documentaries of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Vietnam War</ENAMEX>, shows devoted to militant black politics, and
Naderesque consumer programs (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nader</ENAMEX> even hosted a show) sealed public TV's
reputation as "left-dominated, elitist, minority-radical," as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ledbetter</ENAMEX> puts
it. Nothing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> has aired since comes close to the daring stuff of the first
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hated PBS</ENAMEX> no more than he did the commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX>, but his veto over <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">funding</ENAMEX> and his power to appoint <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> to the Corporation for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Broadcasting</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">overseers</ENAMEX>) gave him a direct outlet for his hate. He
defunded, jawboned, and intimidated the fledgling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">broadcaster</ENAMEX>, and had he not
been distracted by <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX>, he surely would have dismembered it.

            
Reduced by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> to a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">well-trained dog</ENAMEX> that sometimes chews on the furniture, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> steered a moderate
programming course into <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '70s</TIMEX>. But to remind its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masters</ENAMEX> that it can still
bite--and reinforce conservative prejudices that it's pink--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> periodically
aired blasphemous dramas ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steambath</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1973</TIMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mao</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">symp</NUMEX> travelogues
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shirley MacLaine</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Other Half of the Sky: A China Memoir</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1975</TIMEX>),
politically provocative docudramas ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Death of a Princess</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX>), lefty
attacks on agribiz ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hungry</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Profit</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985</TIMEX>), homoerotica ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tongues</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Untied , 1991</TIMEX>), and brazen assaults on logical thinking ( The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Panama</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deception</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>).

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">broadcasting</ENAMEX>'s big transformation came in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid-'70s</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ledbetter</ENAMEX> finds, when
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> stepped in to fill the financial gap for the underfunded
network. (Yes, underfunded: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.5 billion</NUMEX> doesn't go very far on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">350</NUMEX> public-TV
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">stations</ENAMEX>.) Dumping their tax-deductible loot by the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Archer Daniels</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Midland</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GE</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mobil</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Exxon</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chevron</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dupont</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metropolitan Life</ENAMEX>)
encouraged the sort of shows only a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Business Roundtable</ENAMEX> could
love: centrist news programs, conservative talk shows, Wall Street advice
shows, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">lions</ENAMEX>-of-the-Serengeti documentaries, and historical dramas that set all
human conflict in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late-19 th -century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>.

            No wonder, then, that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">right-wingers</ENAMEX> think of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> as liberal
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lefties</ENAMEX> regard it as a corporate/conservative tool. It's neither and both.
Conflicted over what its true mission is, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> simultaneously whores for
corporate money and aggressively gathers data on how poor, uneducated, and
blue-collar its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> is. It accepts its role as an elite medium and then
panders for larger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audiences</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yanni</ENAMEX> specials. ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yanni</ENAMEX> specials? ) It
runs advertisements for its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> at the top of shows and strikes business
deals with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MCI</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCI</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>, but still insists it's not commercial. It
shares hit shows like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Nye</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Science Guy</ENAMEX> with commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX>.
And when it stumbles onto a good subject for a series, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Burns</ENAMEX>' history
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX>, it turns the show into a seminar on racism and labor relations,
not the hit-and-run and the spitball.

            At book's
end, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ledbetter</ENAMEX> issues his clarion call for reform, demanding that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> clock
be turned back to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '50s</TIMEX>, when the philanthropoids first imagined <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
public broadcasting. His policy prescription includes reducing corporate
influence, liberating the system from presidential control, democratizing local
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">stations</ENAMEX>, serving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minorities</ENAMEX>, decentralizing the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>-centric service,
and increasing accountability.

            
What <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ledbetter</ENAMEX> misses is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>'s time--if it
ever had one--has come and gone. The Internet facilitates the sort of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">communications</ENAMEX> and activism that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fords</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carnegies</ENAMEX> prayed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> would
spark. Commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX> pour programs down from the heavens that match or
surpass the products of the public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">broadcasters</ENAMEX>, who are too cowed to produce
anything as homo-proud as the new <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellen</ENAMEX> , as racy as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brooklyn</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South</ENAMEX> , or as culturally subversive as <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Larry Sanders Show</ENAMEX> . I ask
you, what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">newsman</ENAMEX> out-wings the liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Jennings</ENAMEX>?

            Oddly, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX>-led
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sallies</ENAMEX> against public broadcasting, which consume many pages of Made
Possible By , have only enhanced its chances of survival. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> is now viewed
as a federal public-works project, a dispenser of political and cultural pork
to liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> and conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army Corps of Engineers</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rural Electrification Administration</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amtrak</ENAMEX> have lasted a lot longer
with a lot less going for them.

         
      
   
