
   
   
      
         
            The Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Makeover</ENAMEX>

            To call Ms. a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Media</ENAMEX>
Event sounds less invidious than obvious. Isn't that what all journalism is, by
definition, and what even serious activism aspires to nowadays? Most
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">single-issue</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> can only dream about the eye-catching niche that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gloria</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steinem</ENAMEX> and her fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> carved out for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s first glossy feminist
publication <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25 years ago</TIMEX>. With the glamorous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Steinem</ENAMEX> at its helm--and
intermittently on its cover-- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ms.</ENAMEX> was just the promotional vehicle the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">feminist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">movement</ENAMEX> needed to go mainstream.

            But
Inside <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ms.</ENAMEX> , as you might expect of an "authorized" account of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">magazine</ENAMEX>, prefers to think of it as a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Historic Event</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Thom</ENAMEX> is herself a
staff <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veteran</ENAMEX>, who arrived as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researcher</ENAMEX> at the very start and went on to
serve as executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> under <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Editor</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin Morgan</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1990s</TIMEX>. Thom
touts her reliance on "oral histories of many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founders</ENAMEX> and long-time staff
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>." It is clear that she aspires to a down-in-the-trenches record of a
pioneering endeavor that, in her opinion, transcended the ordinary boundaries
of journalism. As such, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thom</ENAMEX> requires unconventional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>, daunting
circumstances, and heroic goals, all of which she does her best to supply.

            Hence <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gloria Steinem</ENAMEX>, one among a large <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cast</ENAMEX> of
path-breakers struggling to fulfill an unorthodox dream. Hence the many pages
devoted to the uphill battles on the business end. Unsurprisingly, bold
determination prevailed, and a new kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> was born. "Ms. seems
more like a social movement than a national <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thom</ENAMEX> writes. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX>
were both "a publishing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enterprise</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> for activism." Ms.
"represent[ed] a state of mind." Ms. was a "feminist mecca." A flood of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> were eagerly greeted--and vetted--as potential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recruits</ENAMEX> to the cause.
Funds flowed out from the coffers of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ms. Foundation for Women</ENAMEX>,
giving fledgling feminist projects the boost they needed.

            Such an
epic saga of political activism may have been what <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Thom</ENAMEX> meant to write, but
soon enough she settles down into the blander form of the press release. Hers
is not the book to read for a serious assessment of the ideas in the many
articles she makes sure to mention by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>. (Her former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX>, she is
well aware, will head straight for the index.) She rehearses the main
criticisms leveled against the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>: that it was politically conventional,
emphasizing male-dominated electoral politics and skirting controversy; that it
was sentimental about sisterhood, forever holding up individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> as
inspirational role models. But her reply to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> consists of providing
an exception or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> to each of the complaints and then moving swiftly on. She
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dutifully</ENAMEX> describes the big dramas that got <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ms.</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> all riled
up--the crusade for and defeat of the ERA; the smear campaign in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1975</TIMEX> by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">radical Redstockings</ENAMEX>, who attacked <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steinem</ENAMEX> for work she'd done <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a decade</TIMEX> earlier
on behalf of a liberal cause that had <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> backing; the nationwide women's
conference in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1977</TIMEX>. What may have been the larger philosophical
questions behind these contretemps? Here is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thom</ENAMEX>'s idea of an answer: "Then as
today, feminism was not an ideology set in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">stone</ENAMEX>, but rather an adaptable set
of attitudes and beliefs."

            
And yet, bromidic and blurry though this
public-relations job is, it is in its way not inaccurate. For <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steinem</ENAMEX> never was
an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of the sharp, analytic variety; she was a repackager. Her aim was not
to subvert the women's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> but to give it a makeover, to translate
feminism into something familiar to the middle class. Go back and reread the
Ms. of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1970s</TIMEX>, and you rediscover how psychological how-to-ism for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> at home became consciousness-raising for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> newly out in the world.
Confessional narrative became first-person testimonial about the choices and
changes in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s lives. In the coping-with-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> department, the message
changed from advice to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> on, say, avoiding "<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">martyr complexes</ENAMEX>," to advice
on lobbying for child care and avoiding gender stereotypes with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX>. Soft-focus messages about sexuality--the importance of pleasing your
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>--became pointed discussion of abortion rights and the myth of the vaginal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">orgasm</ENAMEX>.

            By the
1980s the positions had grown predictable ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ms.</ENAMEX> was pro-abortion, pro-day
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">care</ENAMEX>, pro-ERA, pro-welfare rights, pro-clitoral orgasm). But it is no small
tribute to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ms.</ENAMEX> that most of the issues it raised over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> are
still around. Ms. was among the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> to run pieces
about sexual harassment, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spousal</ENAMEX> abuse, breast <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">implants</ENAMEX>, the economic impact of
divorce--all based on real reporting. The formula was not original and didn't
pretend to be--"soft" personal stories, plus "hard" facts, with some
prescriptions for action. It was service journalism, and its depth and quality
were uneven, as it generally is with service journalism. Ms. also relied
a great deal on book excerpts, hardly a sign of bold editorial
entrepreneurship. As for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ms.</ENAMEX> ' political coverage, crusades heavy on
symbolism preoccupied the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1970s</TIMEX> (the ERA, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX>
conference). If the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> followed electoral politics a little doggedly, it
participated in gestural politics a little overenthusiastically. In "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cracking</ENAMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Women's Movement Protection Game</ENAMEX>" in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1978</TIMEX>, a staff <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> was honest enough
to acknowledge the journalistic--and political--pitfalls of such boosterism.
(She had puffed pro-ERA forces although they were in complete disarray.)

            Ms.' radical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> were right. It was not in the business
of making sustained ideological arguments or issuing eccentric <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">polemics</ENAMEX>. Few
distinctive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> emerged from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>, though over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> many
contributed to it. From the choice of name onward, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ms.</ENAMEX> ' real specialty
was promotion--above all of a usable, salable symbolism. It probably didn't
hurt this larger endeavor that fellow founding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Letty Cottin Pogrebin</ENAMEX>,
the author of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">How to Make It in a Man's World</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1970</TIMEX>), had a career as a
high-powered <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">publicist</ENAMEX> behind her. But it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steinem</ENAMEX>'s inspirational role at
Ms. that was the model for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ms.</ENAMEX> ' role with its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>. She was
not a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">theorist</ENAMEX>. She was an icon, a catalyst, plugged in to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> via
the lecture circuit, and to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">establishment men</ENAMEX>, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boyfriends</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Nichols</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mortimer Zuckerman</ENAMEX>, via the social circuit.

            It's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fitting</ENAMEX>, then, that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thom</ENAMEX> perks up whenever she's describing a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>, a gala, a
television show, a promotional tour. This was the true <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ms.</ENAMEX> "state of
mind," and there were many such events to boast about. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">premier</ENAMEX> issue in the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">spring of 1972</TIMEX> got a plug from <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The David Frost Show</ENAMEX> , on which Steinem
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">others</ENAMEX> appeared. Then there was a big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Public Library</ENAMEX>
to celebrate. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX> "the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>'s own birthday ... was the occasion
of larger gatherings, several of them aboard a chartered <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Circle Line</ENAMEX> boat."
"Everything we did," <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> recalled, "got a tremendous amount
of attention." It would all sound narcissistically frivolous were it not so
earnest. And so ineffective financially; the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> was all but broke from
the start, and stayed that way.

            
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX>, "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Ms.</ENAMEX> ," which had
been granted not-for-profit educational status, launched a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campus</ENAMEX> issue to
attract younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>, but a hectically busy <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Steinem</ENAMEX> was devoting less
editorial energy to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>, and it showed. (You can sense a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>'s
desperation when it tries to generate hoopla on both its <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">10 th</NUMEX> and
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">15 th</NUMEX> anniversaries.) In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1990s</TIMEX>, after being sold and resold,
Ms. lost its spark, but it still carries on. Its covers are as flashy as
ever, though an arid cleanliness reigns within; it resembles nothing so much as
an alumnae <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>. ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ms.</ENAMEX> has been ad-free since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>.) Inside the
current issue you will find, what else, an excerpt from <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Inside Ms</ENAMEX> . On
this <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">25 th</NUMEX> anniversary, there is no gala. Instead, there's a book
that reads like a genteel obituary.

             

         
      
   
