
   
   
      
         
            Consulting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stars</ENAMEX>

            Just after <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War I</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Motors</ENAMEX> asked a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> of industrial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineers</ENAMEX> from outside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> to
survey its business and recommend strategies for the future. After careful
study, these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pioneer</ENAMEX> management <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultants</ENAMEX> advised <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GM</ENAMEX> to rid itself of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chevrolet</ENAMEX> because it "could not hope to compete in its field." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX>
somehow saw their way clear to disregarding this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> and, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15 years later</TIMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chevy</ENAMEX> was the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s most popular <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>.

            This is a
good story. So too is the one about consulting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Booz Allen & Hamilton</ENAMEX>'s
recommendation in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1960s</TIMEX> that gasoline <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> not sell <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> in their
stations for fear of annoying local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX>. In fact, the history of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">consulting</ENAMEX> is full of tales like these, showcasing the hubris,
shortsightedness, and one-size-fits-all attitude of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McKinsey</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Deloitte & Touche</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andersen</ENAMEX>. If, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James O'Shea</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Madigan</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Tribune</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dangerous Company</ENAMEX> ,
you feel "a growing sense of unease" about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authority consultants</ENAMEX> enjoy in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s business world, finding evidence to feed your anxiety won't be a
problem. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Deloitte & Touche</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisers</ENAMEX> who promised to turn a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> into
"a world-class <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 to 12 weeks</TIMEX>" while remaining unable to
explain what "world-class" meant; the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Andersen</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultants</ENAMEX> whose fee was set by
how many jobs they eliminated; the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bain</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultant</ENAMEX> who got himself appointed
controller of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> he was counseling--they're all here, and they're all
preposterous.

            The history of management consulting, though, is more
complex than these horror stories would suggest. The profession originated in
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early years of this century</TIMEX> with the application of the principles of
scientific <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> to production lines. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> consulting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> sprang up
after <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War I</ENAMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultants</ENAMEX> were regarded primarily as "efficiency
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX>." In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 1950s</TIMEX>, consulting came into its own. The corporate need
to understand the burgeoning consumer market, a more general faith in the value
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> advice, and the demands of an unprecedentedly strong economy created
a market for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Booz Allen</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McKinsey</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last two decades</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultants</ENAMEX> have benefited from <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">anxieties</ENAMEX> about profitability and foreign
competition. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Corporations</ENAMEX> looking to reinvent and downsize themselves have made
consulting the new hot profession.

            
Unfortunately, little of this history makes its way into <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dangerous</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Company</ENAMEX> , which is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> real study of consulting since business
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">journalist Hal Higdon</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1969</TIMEX> work The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Business Healers</ENAMEX> . Instead, the
book is constructed--unintentionally or not--as a series of case studies that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">echo</ENAMEX> the teaching methods of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard Business School</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime consultant</ENAMEX> training
ground. Each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapter</ENAMEX> is meant to illuminate a larger truth about consulting in
general. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapter</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Deloitte & Touche</ENAMEX> shows how willing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultants</ENAMEX> are
to assume absolute power, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapter</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andersen</ENAMEX> how readily they chop heads,
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapter</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gemini</ENAMEX> how successful consulting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> are at selling
themselves. In , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O'Shea</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Madigan</ENAMEX> paint a bleak picture of corporations
dazzled by snake-oil <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">salesmen</ENAMEX> operating with "a blind and sometimes fatal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">certainty</ENAMEX>," and of long-term financial health sacrificed to short-term
thinking. But while the picture is bleak, it isn't sharp or convincing. Instead
of a serious analysis of the evolution of consulting or a discussion of the
differences and similarities between consulting and traditional corporate
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX>, we get argument by anecdote.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O'Shea</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madigan</ENAMEX> take this approach,
ultimately, because they have no thesis to offer. To be sure, they want to
persuade us that the work <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultants</ENAMEX> do is too often not in the best interests
of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>, and they do reveal how often hubris and open checkbooks have
been recipes for disaster in the past. But they have remarkably little to say
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about</TIMEX> why they think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultants</ENAMEX>--as opposed to any other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> with
power--are particularly dangerous. Nor do they explain why consulting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX>
continue to enjoy the authority they do in the business world. For the
underlying tenets of consulting--faith in the value of a disinterested
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rationality</ENAMEX>, the idea that what works in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">place</ENAMEX> will work in another--have
given way since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX> to the idea that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with vested interests in a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> are the best-equipped to run it. (That's why stock options, for
example, have become a preferred form of executive compensation.) So why have
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultants</ENAMEX>, who are asked to help <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> in which they have no financial
stake, survived?

            These are
serious questions, and answering them would tell us important things about the
transformation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> economy in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the postwar period</TIMEX> and specifically in
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last two decades</TIMEX>. Instead, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dangerous Company</ENAMEX> often reads like a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">self-help</ENAMEX> book for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> who just can't stop picking up the phone to call
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arthur Andersen</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James O. McKinsey</ENAMEX>. The last chapter even ends with a
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>-point checklist of things to keep in mind when dealing with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultants</ENAMEX>.
"Never give up control," we're told. "Value your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>," and, "Beware of
glib talkers with books."

            In a way, though, the sheer banality of this advice points
up the lockhold that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultants</ENAMEX> have over the corporate mind. After all, no
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> would need to be told to "never give up control" unless there were
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> all too willing to cede authority in a crisis. Nor would "value your
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>" be necessary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> unless <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> were routinely putting more
stock in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">outsiders</ENAMEX>' analyses than in the intelligence of their own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. One
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">thing Dangerous Company</ENAMEX> does show convincingly is how quick companies
are to look outside for solutions, especially when these come with the
imprimatur of a major consulting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>.

            And yet, looking outside
isn't necessarily a mistake. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Executives</ENAMEX> are often too close to problems or too
hidebound in their thinking to produce new solutions. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> business, in
fact, has a long history of bringing in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">outsiders</ENAMEX> to transform <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>,
though these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">outsiders</ENAMEX> haven't always been called <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultants</ENAMEX>. Taylorization,
for example, shaped the auto industry assembly line even though <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frederick</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Winslow Taylor</ENAMEX> developed his theories by studying carters. Later in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">century</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX> was saved by the so-called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Whiz Kids</ENAMEX>, a group of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX>
(including <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert McNamara</ENAMEX>) who came to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Detroit</ENAMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX> from the
Army. More recently, outside <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEOs</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harvey Golub</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Express</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lou</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerstner</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX>--both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McKinsey</ENAMEX> alums--have forced fundamental changes on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> seemingly stuck in long-term ruts. As many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> have
fallen apart listening only to those inside as have collapsed from bad advice
from those outside.

            Besides, blaming consultants
for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>' failures seems, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX>, to be beside the point. No one
forced <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AT&T</ENAMEX> to pay <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$450 million</NUMEX> in consulting fees over the course of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. That doesn't mean <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AT&T</ENAMEX> was stupid to do so, but it does suggest that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ma Bell</ENAMEX> is the one responsible for its woes. It also suggests that the real
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">riddle</ENAMEX>--and one that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O'Shea</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madigan</ENAMEX> don't thoroughly investigate--is why
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> call in management <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultants</ENAMEX> to begin with. The answer probably has
something to do with the needs of corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>--the need to pass off
responsibility, the need to appear to be on the cutting edge, the need to
believe that every problem has a ready-made solution. <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dangerous Company</ENAMEX>
levies a powerful indictment against management consulting, but in doing so it
confuses a symptom with the disease. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Consultants</ENAMEX> aren't the real problem. The
needs they're asked to fulfill almost certainly are.

         
      
   
