
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hail</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX>

            It's a fine time to be
writing a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Victorian</ENAMEX> novel. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> has been one of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane Austen</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">brightest; PBS</ENAMEX> and cable TV have given fresh life to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hardy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott</ENAMEX>, and all
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">Brontës</ENAMEX>; even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dickens</ENAMEX> got a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">makeover</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this winter</TIMEX>, his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great</ENAMEX> 
               Expectations transported from <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Kent</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>. We have renewed our fascination with the close spaces of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19 th -century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>, and it is with those close spaces, the dim
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hallways</ENAMEX> and yellow glooms, that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novelist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Carey</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jack</ENAMEX>
Maggs reacquaints us.

            Already a
best <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">seller</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maggs</ENAMEX> marks <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carey</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> foray
into Victorian <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>. His <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Booker Prize-winning Oscar</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucinda</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>), is now a major motion picture. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carey</ENAMEX> specializes in the
picaresque, in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-man novels about larger-than-life social <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">misfits</ENAMEX> who must
cope with rotten childhoods, loveless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>, hideous disfigurements, and
secret shames. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Orphans</ENAMEX> with tics and dwarfs without lips or teeth ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jack</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maggs</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Unusual Life of Tristan Smith</ENAMEX> ), <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10-year-old</TIMEX> parricides
and sexually abused <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-agers</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Illywhacker and The Tax</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inspector</ENAMEX> )--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carey</ENAMEX> documents their stories in exhaustive, loving detail.
There is plenty of humor in his books, some of it sharp and much of it just
plain funny; and bizarre bits of magic that, though not always comprehensible,
compound a real sense of menace.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Maggs</ENAMEX> offers many of these <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Carey staples</ENAMEX>. It opens
with the return to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> of its eponymous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX>, and uses a combination of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">linear</ENAMEX> narrative and flashback to tell a story that spans <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several decades</TIMEX>. In
broad outline, it echoes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great</ENAMEX> 
               Expectations , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dickens</ENAMEX>' story of
Pip the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">waif</ENAMEX> who is befriended by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Magwitch</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">convict</ENAMEX>, though <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carey</ENAMEX>'s book is
also partly a reflection on how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dickens</ENAMEX>' novel came to be written. There are
quite a few correspondences between the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> novels, of which the play on names
is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX>. Like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dickens</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abel Magwitch</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Maggs</ENAMEX> has been exiled to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australian</ENAMEX> backwaters. Both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> have protégés: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maggs'</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Phipps</ENAMEX>, a much
younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who we think may be his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>. Maggs returns from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New South Wales</ENAMEX>,
where he is now a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen</ENAMEX> of good repute and considerable wealth, to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>,
where he is still a wanted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, to find <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phipps</ENAMEX>, whose foppish lifestyle he has
long subsidized. It is with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maggs</ENAMEX>' search for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phipps</ENAMEX> that the story begins.

            Soon after
his return, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maggs</ENAMEX> encounters <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tobias Oates</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novelist</ENAMEX> and self-styled
"cartographer" of the "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Criminal Mind</ENAMEX>," of which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maggs</ENAMEX> is soon forced to become
the hapless embodiment. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oates</ENAMEX> cuts a deal with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maggs</ENAMEX>: He will help the convict
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">find Phipps if Maggs</ENAMEX> will agree to undergo a series of experiments in
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mesmerism</ENAMEX>." Their terrible sessions (click for a sample) anchor the tale and
provide a framework for its telling. Through them--plus a cache of
invisible-ink letters <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maggs</ENAMEX> writes to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phipps</ENAMEX> in order to acquaint the protégé
with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protector</ENAMEX>--we look into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maggs</ENAMEX>' tortured <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soul</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX> an <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oates</ENAMEX> in
all but tumescent pursuit of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maggs</ENAMEX>' life story, which he will exploit for his
next best seller.

            
Though there is much that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carey</ENAMEX> takes from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dickens</ENAMEX>, he manages to separate his story from its archetype quite easily.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carey's</ENAMEX> is a metanovel-- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great</ENAMEX> 
               Expectations , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Australian</ENAMEX>
version--that takes on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX> and his work by <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> tenderly tucking them
into its pages, then slowly exposing their vulnerabilities. What we end up with
is a sharp postcolonial critique not just of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> but of novel-writing as
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a whole</TIMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Carey</ENAMEX>
lays his trap by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hewing</ENAMEX> close to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dickens</ENAMEX> in style and mood. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maggs</ENAMEX> '
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dickens</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>, only darker: a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> whose humanity has long since
run dry and whose juveniles--the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Twists and Dorrits and Chuzzlewits and</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maggses</ENAMEX>--are forced into lives of crime. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">The year</TIMEX> is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1837</TIMEX>--that of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Victoria</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">accession</ENAMEX>--but we get a sense not of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire</ENAMEX> or of politely crumpeting tearooms
but of decay and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX>, of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more</NUMEX>-Dickensian-than-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dickens</ENAMEX> underside of
rapid industrialization and urban growth.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carey</ENAMEX> does an impressive job as time <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traveler</ENAMEX> and tour
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">guide</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maggs</ENAMEX> is delightfully atmospheric and full of peel-away details,
shit-rimmed cobblestones and stinking . The quaintly elaborate names--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Percival</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarence Buckle</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mercy Larkin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sophina Smith</ENAMEX>--are a lively match for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dickens</ENAMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Uriah Heeps</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Augustus Snodgrasses</ENAMEX>. And the quaintly elaborate
capitalization--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buckle "</ENAMEX>found his way into ... the sleepy arms of his Good
Companion"--takes you further back, to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richardson</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pamela</ENAMEX> , as does
this priceless request: " 'Turn over my pretty one, and raise your sweet white
bottom in the air.' " But it is through the portrait of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oates</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>,
hypnotist, and all-round selfish <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bastard</ENAMEX>, that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carey</ENAMEX> brings his novel into its
own. For <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oates</ENAMEX>' pretensions--his impassioned defense of abused <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>; his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">overassiduous</ENAMEX> note-taking; his obsessions with criminality, mesmerism, and his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">parrot Dickens</ENAMEX>' own well-documented preoccupations. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maggs</ENAMEX> is arching its brow at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dickens</ENAMEX>' vaunted causes, making them
potentially smelly. And where a literal-minded parodist might have bound the
narrative to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dickens</ENAMEX> and his doings, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carey</ENAMEX> gives the novel and its themes a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">full</TIMEX> life outside them. If you've read the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Victorian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>, you get your
insider's chuckle. If not, you still get a good yarn.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carey</ENAMEX>'s
careful separation of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">19 th</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> from modern-day anywhere
may be the key to our appreciation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Victorian</ENAMEX> world, but it is his
portrait of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maggs</ENAMEX> that allows you to collapse that distance and to really
settle into his novel. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carey</ENAMEX> gives us the flawed, utterly romantic anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> of
high Victorian fiction--<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">absurdly</NUMEX> tall, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">absurdly</ENAMEX> shy, absurdly proud, absurdly
trusting, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maggs</ENAMEX> is a sighted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Edward Rochester</ENAMEX>, a kinder <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heathcliff</ENAMEX>. His scarred
back and missing fingers, his tragic isolation from those around him, however,
also make him identifiably <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Careyesque</ENAMEX>. Of course, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carey</ENAMEX> isn't the first author
to use castaways to dramatize a world gone wrong. If anything, he makes a
remarkably unsubtle play for your sympathies.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carey</ENAMEX>'s cheerful <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ham</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fistedness</ENAMEX> turns out to be
just what is called for to correct <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dickens</ENAMEX>' lugubriousness. Suffice it to say
that when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carey</ENAMEX> rewrites <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dickens</ENAMEX>' ending--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maggs</ENAMEX>, unlike the late lamented
Magwitch, does not die a miserable death--it is a perfectly delightful
solution. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maggs</ENAMEX> is given an out. In fact, all the sympathetic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> in the
novel are given outs. They are allowed to transcend their particular
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">poverties</ENAMEX>--of class, gender, or nationality--in a way <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dickens</ENAMEX> granted precious
few <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Micawbers</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carey</ENAMEX> even reclaims that slighted continent, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX>. It isn't
just a convenient dumping ground for convicts, he tells us, with the ticklish
pride so typical of the expatriate (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carey</ENAMEX> lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Maggs</ENAMEX>'
burgeoning dignity and the choices he makes at novel's end give
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19 th -century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX> the bourgeois stature it lacked in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dickens</ENAMEX>'
novel, allowing the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> to become a place of hope rather than of exile. By
the same token, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Maggs</ENAMEX> ' triumphal march burnishes the literary
moment to which its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> lays proud claim, restoring the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19 th -century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> novel, that much-maligned instrument of
colonial oppression, to a well-deserved place in the sun.

         
      
   
