
   
   
      
         
            Up in Smoke

            When <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Tobacco</ENAMEX> agreed to
the previously unimaginable <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>--severe marketing restrictions on
cigarettes and a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$368.5 billion</NUMEX> payout to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> and the federal government
over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next 25 years</TIMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-tobacconists</ENAMEX> pouted instead of cheering. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Lung Association</ENAMEX> dismissed the restrictions as "a mere inconvenience"
to the industry. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Food and Drug Administration</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Kessler groused</ENAMEX> that
the agreement would block the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">feds</ENAMEX>' right to regulate nicotine levels in
cigarettes for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12 years</TIMEX>. And the , who had dragged <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Tobacco</ENAMEX> into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> with
dreams of winning <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$18 billion</NUMEX> in fees, protested that the deal cheated them.
Even after <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ariz.</ENAMEX>, proposed increasing the payout to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$506</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">billion</ENAMEX> and adding new regulations to the bill, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-tobacconists</ENAMEX> still
complained. (To read why the "deal" keeps flying apart, click .)

            Two
questions: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) What made the once-invincible <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">makers</ENAMEX> capitulate? <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) How
many <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">trillions</NUMEX> does it take to make an anti-tobacconist smile?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Pringle</ENAMEX>'s ticktock of the legal battle, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cornered</ENAMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Tobacco</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bar of Justice</ENAMEX> , answers the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> question: The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">plaintiffs</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys general</ENAMEX> proved indefatigable;
incriminating documents were leaked from inside the big tobacco <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>; an
important industry <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientist</ENAMEX> defected; and, most importantly, Wall Street,
fearing a bottomless payout, signaled the industry to submit.

            As Pringle
reports, the trial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> filed their class action suits in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early '90s</TIMEX>
after having tapped out the conventional product liability market: <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">asbestos</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IUDs</ENAMEX>, and silicone implants. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> general, also primed by asbestos
settlements, joined in with a new legal argument that held the industry liable
for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX> bills of all <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco</ENAMEX>-damaged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>--an argument that has
proved persuasive in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>. Joining this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">coalition</ENAMEX> were anti-smoking
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kessler</ENAMEX>, who thinks of smoking as a "pediatric <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX>" and
regulation as the cure.

            
Against them stood the united front of Big
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tobacco</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">R.J. Reynolds</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Philip Morris</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lorillard, Brown & Williamson</ENAMEX> (a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">division of B.A.T.</ENAMEX> Industries), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Liggett & Myers</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Tobacco</ENAMEX>. It
wasn't until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 1996</TIMEX>, after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four decades</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courtroom sparring</ENAMEX>, that a jury
finally ordered the industry to pay damages to a smoker for ruining his health.
The tobacco <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cartel</ENAMEX> also fractured in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> when the runt of the litter, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Liggett</ENAMEX>,
sensed the power shifting and cut a separate deal. What may have caught
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liggett</ENAMEX>'s eye were: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First</ENAMEX>, newly purloined documents from industry archives
that revealed the magnitude of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Tobacco</ENAMEX>'s deceit about <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco</ENAMEX>'s role in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">addiction</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX>; and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>, the fact that a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">B&W</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientist</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeffrey</ENAMEX>
Wigand, had gone over to the other side. The new information to be gleaned from
the documents and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wigand</ENAMEX> could conceivably persuade <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">juries</ENAMEX> in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">300-plus</NUMEX>
tobacco-liability suits then pending to award <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">hundreds of billions</NUMEX> in
damages.

            If the legal levee was about
to burst, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liggett</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett LeBow</ENAMEX> figured, why shouldn't he let the flood
lift him to greater glory? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Portraying</ENAMEX> himself as a "whistleblower," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LeBow</ENAMEX>
simultaneously surrendered to the anti-tobacconists, with whom he hoped to
settle for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a few million</NUMEX> and some marketing restrictions, and launched a
takeover bid for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RJR</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LeBow</ENAMEX>'s hope, which ultimately proved false, was that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RJR</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> would welcome a takeover if it would allow <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RJR</ENAMEX> to share in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Liggett</ENAMEX>'s
lenient settlement. This would give <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RJR/Liggett</ENAMEX> a huge competitive edge over
industry <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">giant</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Philip Morris</ENAMEX>, which would presumably face tougher terms.

            Wall
Street initially recoiled at the idea of a settlement but then bid Big
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tobacco</ENAMEX>'s stocks up at nearly every mention of an impending deal. What sweet
irony: The specter of unlimited legal liability was a bigger threat to the
industry's well-being than a straightforward settlement. And the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$368.5 billion</NUMEX>
deal was affordable for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, especially considering the tax benefits
of a payout and the time value of money. These economic truths reunited Big
Tobacco behind a settlement on the industry's terms. Having won the public
relations war by agreeing to a settlement, the industry continues to use its
leverage to win a sweeter deal. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Just last week</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RJR</ENAMEX> led <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Tobacco</ENAMEX> in
declaring its opposition to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> bill.

            Which brings us to Question <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. When <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Tobacco</ENAMEX> was finally
brought to the bargaining table, why didn't the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-</ENAMEX>tobacco <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX> rejoice?
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Sullum</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">For Your Own Good: The Anti-Smoking Crusade and the Tyranny</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public Health</ENAMEX> surveys <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five centuries</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco abolitionism</ENAMEX> and
concludes what tobacco's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foes</ENAMEX> want more than money: They want to see the last
butt snuffed out.

            Sullum
reaches back to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James</ENAMEX> I's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1603</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-</ENAMEX>tobacco tirade, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A Counterblaste</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tobacco</ENAMEX> , to prove that the is nearly as old as the smoking habit itself.
The campaign has grown so successful that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> think cigarettes are
more deadly than they really are. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sullum</ENAMEX> cites a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economist</ENAMEX>'s
survey in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">respondents</ENAMEX> guessed that the average smoker forfeits <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11.5 years</TIMEX>
from his life span, when the "true" loss is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">between 3.6</NUMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7.2 years</TIMEX>. So much
for the idea that more "education" will deter <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco</ENAMEX> use.

            
Adequately warned, why do <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> persist
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sucking</TIMEX> cancer-causing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tars</ENAMEX> into their lungs? Anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tobacconists</ENAMEX> insist that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nicotine</ENAMEX>'s addictive powers explain it all. But when the industry attempted to
create , the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX> protested again, declaring the "safer" cigarette
evil because it would encourage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">smokers</ENAMEX> to continue their habit. As it turns
out, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Tobacco</ENAMEX> was ambivalent about the safe-cigarette <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">projects</ENAMEX> because they
exposed the industry to an uncomfortable double bind: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Making a</ENAMEX> "safer"
cigarette is tantamount to confessing that regular cigarettes are dangerous
when taken as directed, something the industry had spent <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billions</NUMEX> denying.

            As the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">endgame</ENAMEX> approaches for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Tobacco and Congress</ENAMEX>, one is tempted to sympathize
with the anti-tobacconists. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Tobacco</ENAMEX> has lied at every step, denying the
addictive properties of nicotine and the causal link between <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco tar</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>. A wealth of circumstantial evidence indicates that they've threatened
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> and committed criminal fraud by illegally withholding subpoenaed
documents.

            But consider the evil done to the truth by the "good"
anti-tobacconists. Their propaganda has exaggerated the health dangers of other
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco products</ENAMEX>--pipes, cigars, snuff, and chew--all of which are . Thanks to
their accomplices in the press, the beyond recognition. And they've distorted
the health costs that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">smokers</ENAMEX> impose on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sullum</ENAMEX> cites convincing
statistics showing that the cost of smoking probably more or less equals the
benefits, if you factor in the exorbitant taxes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">smokers</ENAMEX> pay and recognize that
by dying early they save us a bundle on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>.

            How wise is it to endow the
state with powers to force us into wellness even if we prefer risk? Now that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-tobacconists</ENAMEX> are on top, will they too know no bounds?

            
               If you
didn't click through to all the internal links, fire up a menthol and read at
your leisure about behind the litigation and the for why the settlement deal
keeps collapsing. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kessler</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Everett Koop</ENAMEX> didn't invent tobacco repression,
as informs us. Proving that they knew tobacco tars caused <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">lung cancer</ENAMEX>, the
industry did develop a couple of "" cigarettes. Click to learn what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harm</ENAMEX>
Reduction movement could teach the anti-tobacconists and for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Environmental</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Protection Agency</ENAMEX>'s own estimate of how dangerous secondhand smoke really
is.
            

         
      
   
