
   
   
      
         
            What <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">We Have Here Is a Failure to Communicate</ENAMEX>.

            Few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> enjoy wider name
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">recognition</ENAMEX>, or a smaller core <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readership</ENAMEX>, than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gertrude Stein</ENAMEX>. Even avid
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> tend to know only the two easiest of her <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX>-odd books, the experimental
but accessible <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Three Lives</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1908</TIMEX>) and the gossipy Autobiography of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alice B. Toklas</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1933</TIMEX>). After that, she's remembered as the queen scene
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">maker</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Modernist Paris</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patron</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Picasso</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matisse</ENAMEX> and
later <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hemingway</ENAMEX> who turned out cryptic, quotable phrases such as "a rose is a
rose is a rose" and "there's no there there." Her celebrity image is both
frivolous and terrifying: Imagine the souls of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fran Lebowitz</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yogi Berra</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mingling</ENAMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who looked like an ancient statue, with a huge, flat face
and dark little dots for eyes.

            Of
course, that image underestimates what an amazingly innovative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stein</ENAMEX>
was. Luckily, or so you'd think, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Library of America</ENAMEX> has galloped to the
rescue with a gigantic new edition to tout her worth. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catharine Stimpson</ENAMEX> and independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholar</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harriet Chessman</ENAMEX>, have
done a perfectly fresh job assembling both canonical and neglected pieces to
trace the evolution of this oddest of minds. Most of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stein</ENAMEX>'s phases are here:
the pioneering "continuous present" tense she invented in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Three Lives</ENAMEX> ;
the abstract sketches of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>; the barely performable plays that she
compared to landscapes; the difficult holistic theory of literature that made
her a surprising star on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> lecture circuit late in life. All very
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">magisterial</ENAMEX>--but, at the daunting <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-volume length of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,900</NUMEX> pages, something
of a backhanded compliment. Other prolific <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry James</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mark</ENAMEX>
Twain usually get their stuff sorted into <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early period</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late period</TIMEX> and
released in dribbles. The way the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> has handled <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stein</ENAMEX> may make a
statement about her importance, but it certainly doesn't help in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reader</ENAMEX>-friendliness <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>.

            There are some neat things here, starting with the novella
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Q.E.D.</ENAMEX> , which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stein</ENAMEX> wrote when she was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">29</NUMEX>. (It was never published in
her lifetime.) This was in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1903</TIMEX>, shortly before she moved to bohemian <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> and
not too long after she studied psychology at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Radcliffe</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William James</ENAMEX> (the
subject of her thesis, still relevant as ever, was how undergraduates
experience fatigue during final exams). The style is naturalistic; the plot is
your basic love triangle, with a lesbian twist: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Adele</ENAMEX>, whose butch
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">forthrightness</ENAMEX> makes her an obvious stand-in for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stein</ENAMEX>, falls for a frustrating
coquette, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helen</ENAMEX>, who returns her love but can't commit because she's already
beholden to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mabel</ENAMEX>, a rich, withered-spinster type.

            Since
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stein</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> tend to fetishize all things experimental, this straightforward,
painfully autobiographical book (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stein</ENAMEX> was hurt by a failed love affair the
summer she wrote it) has generally been dismissed as wooden, of interest only
for its lesbian subject matter. But its hyperintelligence is underrated. It is
proof that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stein</ENAMEX> started out writing with perfect clarity, which means that her
later bizarre style was a choice, not the natural expression of a loon. Also,
the angry portrait of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helen</ENAMEX> shows that, all feminist claims on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stein</ENAMEX>
notwithstanding, she was as capable of misogyny as any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Biographies</ENAMEX> tell
us she was fascinated at the time by the ideas of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Otto Weininger</ENAMEX>, a morbid
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Viennese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">philosopher</ENAMEX> who believed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> were stupid and corrupt banshees.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ludwig Wittgenstein</ENAMEX> was another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX>.)

            
Dominance in relationships, the question of who
has the upper hand and why, turns out to be one of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stein</ENAMEX>'s favorite themes. "In
friendship, power always has its downward curve," she writes in Three
Lives , her famous portrait of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">servant women</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Readers</ENAMEX> have been
conditioned to study this groundbreaking work for its pioneering
technique--still beautifully readable, but eerie and fractured. Each sketch is
also a cool study of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> and weak, grasping <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">followers</ENAMEX> in love. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> for
an excerpt.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stein</ENAMEX> is shamelessly fascinated by power, and in Three
Lives she begins to dictate the terms by which we read her, even <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.
Since <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">portraits in Three Lives</ENAMEX> were based on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> she
actually knew and the celebrated middle section "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Melanctha</ENAMEX>" is a rehash
(brilliant, daring, but a rehash nevertheless) of the same love affair that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Q.E.D.</ENAMEX> was based on, you could even argue that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stein</ENAMEX> invented a
revolutionary new literary technique in order to disguise a weakness--her own
inability to make up a story.

            What
imagination she had was almost entirely theoretical. Watching young <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cubists</ENAMEX>
bring the techniques of painting to the forefront, she assigned herself to
write "portraits" of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> that did the same thing for literature. Soon
she'd forgotten all about her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX> and begun inquiring into the very nature
of composition. Deciding that the normal rules of punctuation and grammar
promoted old-fashioned sentiment, she came up with new rules of her own
(question marks and exclamation points <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">verboten</TIMEX> ; evocative nouns and
adjectives dangerous; adverbs excellent, because they're about nothing more
than the relationship between words). She believed you could repeat the same
word over and over without risking boredom, because each time it appeared it
was like new. She even tried to work out a literature without fake beginnings,
middles, and ends--a literature that enters directly into the flow of
experience. (From an alleged essay, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Acquaintance With Description</ENAMEX>": "If it and
this is wild from this to the neatness of there being larger left and with it
could it might if it not if it as lead it lead it there and incorrectly which
is at this time.")

            All this exploration makes for some heavy going, and I
certainly wouldn't recommend that anyone read these volumes straight through,
as I had to for review. Taking in too much <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stein</ENAMEX> too fast can provoke a numb
panic, a clog in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>. At times, I felt as if I'd inhaled highly caloric
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> and, just when the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sugar</ENAMEX> coma hit, entered a long line at the department
of motor <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicles</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stein</ENAMEX> is far more amusing when she forgets her rules and
gets drunk on the music of words. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> for an excerpt from "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lifting Belly</ENAMEX>," a
witty unpublished love poem she wrote to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alice B. Toklas</ENAMEX>.) She's much more
stimulating when she remembers that she's <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> and foremost a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thinker</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX>
for her arbitrary, brilliant take on literary history.) In fact, much of her
imaginative writing seems to me a mere preparatory sketch for her real work of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">genius</ENAMEX>, which is the self-promoting--but undeniably original--criticism that
explicates it.

            As for the rest, her idea
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about</NUMEX> starting over and over--halting a phrase before it evokes an image, God
forbid, or reaches the dead end of clarity--is a fascinating mistake. Starting
over and over again doesn't mean you've entered the flow of experience. It
means you're starting over and over again, with all the stop-and-go frustration
this implies. : Writing deals in meaning, images, false renderings of time, and
devices to hold the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX>'s attention. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stein</ENAMEX>'s attempt to show otherwise is a
landmark in literature, a unique episode in the history of thought. Whether
you'll want a keep a copy by your bedside to thumb through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">lovingly year</TIMEX> after
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> is a choice best left to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX>. My guess is a regretful no.

            
               If you
missed the links within the review, click to read a passage from , another
from "," or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">an</NUMEX> .

         
      
   
