
   
   
      
         
            Autopsy Gothic

            Who is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s leading
conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novelist</ENAMEX>? <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patricia Cornwell</ENAMEX>, the best-selling
mystery <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> based in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Richmond</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Va.</ENAMEX> A pert blond <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dynamo</ENAMEX> who could be <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Molinari</ENAMEX>'s big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>, she's also got the credentials. Her <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> book wasn't a
mystery but a loving biography of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruth Graham</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rev.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Billy</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>. She's an
advocate for tougher law enforcement and was a public supporter of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> former Gov. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Allen</ENAMEX>. A few novels back, she even based a
fictional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orrin Hatch</ENAMEX> and paid tribute to him as a brave soldier
fighting for truth. Her latest is dedicated to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara Bush</ENAMEX>, "with love."

            On the
other hand, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cornwell</ENAMEX> doesn't always fit the conservative bill. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Allied</ENAMEX> with men
who prefer their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> dutiful and demure, she herself has a macho side. She
flies a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">helicopter</ENAMEX> and makes statements about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> surviving in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>'s world
that could be confused with feminism. Her novels argue that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> must pay
for their actions--no forgiveness, no rehabilitation, no excuses
whatsoever--but she's also admitted to bouts with childhood <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">molestation</ENAMEX>,
bulimia, and bipolar mood swings, and she has asked that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who suffer such
traumas be given a little <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TLC</ENAMEX>. There are hints that she has a most un-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Billy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Graham</ENAMEX>-like lifestyle. In a bizarre episode <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of years ago</TIMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX>
claimed he was driven to attempt to murder his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cornwell</ENAMEX> was having
an affair with her.

            In work and in life, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cornwell</ENAMEX> screams ambivalence, which
may explain why she's so popular and so queasily interesting. At a time when
most pop best sellers seem dumbed down to please a focus <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cornwell</ENAMEX> is a
rarity: a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> with a vivid, at times even freakishly messy, personality. She
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">condemns America</ENAMEX>'s moral decline with the smugness of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlton Heston</ENAMEX>, but
her narcissism and button pushing skills give the early <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madonna</ENAMEX> a run for her
money.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroine</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cornwell's</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> mysteries is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kay Scarpetta</ENAMEX>. She's
middle-aged but still damned good looking, tough but vulnerable, and other
assorted mystery cliché traits. What's special about her is her job, chief
medical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">examiner</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>, which allows her to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX> more gruesome sights
than one could dream of. During <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cornwell</ENAMEX> worked in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">coroner</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>, and now she specializes in clinical descriptions of autopsies,
explaining in graphic detail how to analyze the vaginal swab of a raped corpse
or how to test skin ripped off a tortured <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>'s buttock. As if that weren't
bad enough, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cornwell</ENAMEX> has also given <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scarpetta</ENAMEX> problematic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX>. There's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pete Marino</ENAMEX>, a bigoted and emotionally stunted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cop</ENAMEX> who eats and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drinks</ENAMEX> too
much, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benton Wesley</ENAMEX>, an older <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WASP FBI</ENAMEX> profiler with whom she eventually
strikes up an affair.

            
In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Postmortem</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scarpetta</ENAMEX>'s
impressive debut, the tone was grim and graphic, focused on the nitty-gritty of
crime detection and the challenges faced by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> entering this mostly male
business. Scarpetta was the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counterpart</ENAMEX>, in a way, to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Detective</ENAMEX> Chief
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Inspector</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane Tennison</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> TV series Prime Suspect . As sales
skyrocketed, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cornwell</ENAMEX> hired a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> to help work up her autopsy
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">nightmares</ENAMEX>. The details are now more rigorous and even more clinically
rendered. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> to read the latest tour de force, in which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scarpetta</ENAMEX> boils a
dead <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>'s bones.) But the plots have evolved to an abstract level--a kind of
metaphorical mist--and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scarpetta</ENAMEX> has acquired <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> archenemies: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Temple Gault</ENAMEX>, an
evil-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX>, white-trash skinhead, and his accomplice, an attractive young
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">psychopath</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carrie Grethen</ENAMEX>. After several tries, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scarpetta</ENAMEX> finally
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">defeated Gault</ENAMEX>, murdering him in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">subway tunnel</ENAMEX>. But in the new
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">installment Grethen</ENAMEX> escapes from a mental asylum and goes after her.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Characters</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gault</ENAMEX> and
Grethen are the basis of the standard praise for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cornwell</ENAMEX>, which is that she
has a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dickensian</ENAMEX> grasp of evil. Don't believe it. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Temple</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carrie</ENAMEX> are cartoon
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">meanies</ENAMEX> who hate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scarpetta</ENAMEX> for no apparent reason; they're about as Dickensian
as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">satanic clown</ENAMEX> doll named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chuckie</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cornwell</ENAMEX>'s plots are getting weaker, and
I won't claim too much for her prose, either. Lacking the self-monitoring skill
that's crucial to a really good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>, she projects ugly <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fixations</ENAMEX> onto
Scarpetta, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">remarking</ENAMEX> constantly--and with embarrassing, naked approval--on her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">blond</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Teutonic</ENAMEX>" looks.

            My
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">favorite Cornwellian</ENAMEX> clunker is a cheap bid for sinister atmosphere, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scary</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Noun</ENAMEX>. That's when she drops the article before some harmless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inanimate</ENAMEX> object,
lending it a kind of pseudohuman <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>. Examples include "<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rain</ENAMEX> was slanted and
flying down like nails," and "rocks were black beneath stars," and--frightening
enough to make you shiver--"windshield wipers dragged across glass." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> for
more reasons to dislike <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cornwell</ENAMEX>.)

            So why do we all keep reading? Voyeuristic slumming, in
part. You wait with bated breath to see which hot social issue <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cornwell</ENAMEX> will
take up and handle oddly. In the latest novel she addresses race--sort of--in
the form of a rich, power hungry, sexually overactive but ultimately humane
black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activist</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">publisher</ENAMEX>. Point of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Origin</ENAMEX> also further develops
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cornwell</ENAMEX>'s most loaded theme, lesbianism, by way of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scarpetta</ENAMEX>'s niece, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucy</ENAMEX>. A
little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> when the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">series</ENAMEX> began, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucy</ENAMEX> is now a brilliant young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scarpetta</ENAMEX> is turned off by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucy</ENAMEX>'s lesbian lifestyle and convinced that that
awful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pervert</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grethen</ENAMEX> seduced <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucy</ENAMEX> into it. At the same time, she's moved to
rather suspect erotic awe by the nubile beauty of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucy</ENAMEX>'s perfect young
body.

            On such issues, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cornwell</ENAMEX> is
hilariously confused but not without insight. The increasing abstraction of her
plots allows her to do what she does best: write about the job. The most
poignant parts of her books detail the pressures <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scarpetta</ENAMEX> faces as an
executive who's responsible for the welfare of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subordinates</ENAMEX> but under
ruthless pressure to deliver results; the impossibility of sorting through
overwhelming floods of information and straining for an educated guess; the
sadness of a life lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">helicopters</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX> rather than in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX>; the
inadequacy of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> who function like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> but aren't. So what if
Cornwell perks up these not so uncommon problems with a backdrop of
unadulterated, almost supernatural evil? She conveys, somehow, a genuine grief.
Call it millennial, if you must, or simply modern-professional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gothic</ENAMEX>. "The
pain is out there," could be her slogan. At the end of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Point of Origin</ENAMEX> ,
someone Scarpetta cares about meets a fate so gross and far-fetched it made me
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">giggle</ENAMEX>. It was also sad enough to remember for a while.

            
               If you
missed the excerpt from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Point of Origin</ENAMEX> , click , and are more reasons to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dislike Cornwell</ENAMEX>.
            

         
      
   
