
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX>

            It started innocently
enough. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bobby Kennedy</ENAMEX>, gearing up in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the fall of 1959</TIMEX> to manage his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>'s
upcoming presidential run, visited <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lyndon Johnson</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ranch</ENAMEX> to inquire
after the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">majority leader</ENAMEX>'s presidential ambitions. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson</ENAMEX> assured the
younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> that he had none. Then, as was his wont, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> took his guest
hunting. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bobby</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vet</ENAMEX> who never saw action in <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX>, fixed a deer
in his sights, squeezed the trigger--and landed flat on his back from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">recoil</ENAMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Son</ENAMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX>, helping him up with a smirk, "you've got to learn
to handle a gun like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>." He went on to break his word by giving <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jack</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bobby</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> never forgave <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> the slight, loathing him to the end. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson</ENAMEX>, for
his part, never gave up trying to knock <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> on his ass. And while their
feud may not have defined <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a decade</TIMEX>, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff Shesol</ENAMEX> claims in this wonderfully
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">entertaining</ENAMEX>, original, and exceptionally researched book, it certainly makes
for a hell of a gripping yarn.

            It is hard to imagine <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> more opposed in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">temperament than Lyndon Baines Johnson</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Francis Kennedy</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> was
supremely self-confident and unyielding. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson</ENAMEX> was self-pitying and prone to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">blackest paranoia</ENAMEX>. (For his <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">paranoia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> owe the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">36</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> a debt. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson</ENAMEX> recorded just about every telephone call he ever
placed, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shesol</ENAMEX> deploys impressive documentary gifts to knock the resulting
transcripts into one of the most intimate portraits of the inner life of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> yet committed to print.) The kinds of things <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> reveled
in--locker-room talk and stiff belts of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">whiskey</ENAMEX>, the "muted grays" of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>'s well-turned compromises, even his own hard-earned influence and
wealth--were the kinds of things against which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX>-educated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kennedy</ENAMEX>
defined his very identity.

            Indeed,
one senses that nothing less than the deepest matters of personal identity
fueled their intense and bitter rivalry. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bostonian</ENAMEX> must have sensed that,
compared with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Texan</ENAMEX>, he came off as snobbish, petulant, and obtusely rich.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> certainly made <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> feel like a wheedling country <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bumpkin</ENAMEX> who was
unable to pick out the right suit jacket. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX>, who cherished his very own
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">LBJ voodoo</ENAMEX> doll, called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> "mean, bitter, and vicious--an <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animal</ENAMEX> in many
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ways</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson</ENAMEX> found <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> a "little shitass" and a "grandstanding little
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">runt</ENAMEX>." It is not surprising that they didn't care to be in the same place at
the same time.

            
But circumstances forever conspired to place
them in the same place at the same time: namely, in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John F. Kennedy</ENAMEX>'s shadow.
Their enmity began in earnest at the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">1960 Democratic National Convention</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Angeles</ENAMEX>, where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JFK</ENAMEX> decisively turned back <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last-minute</TIMEX> bid for the
nomination. Not, however, before <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX>'s reckless attempt to derail him by
reminding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">delegates</ENAMEX> of rumors that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Kennedy Sr.</ENAMEX>, while he was ambassador
to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>, had appeased <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>. Now protocol demanded that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JFK</ENAMEX> offer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson</ENAMEX>
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> spot on the ticket, and honor demanded that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX>, given that he
had insulted the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">turn Kennedy</ENAMEX> down.

            Instead,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson</ENAMEX> accepted. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bobby</ENAMEX> was given the unenviable job of marching into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson</ENAMEX>'s
hotel <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">suite</ENAMEX> to talk him out of it. To make a long story--it takes up the
greater part of a gripping chapter--short: The dust lifted with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lyndon</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice</ENAMEX>-presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">loathing</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bobby</ENAMEX> for plotting against him (here was
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lyndon</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">paranoia</ENAMEX>, or maybe his ability to spot the hustle); and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bobby</ENAMEX>, the
campaign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">loathing Lyndon</ENAMEX> for having the audacity to take a job for
which he knew he wasn't the first choice (here was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bobby</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Coast</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">arrogance</ENAMEX>, or maybe his idealism). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thither</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>, where Attorney
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX>, whose only previous public service had been as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committees</ENAMEX>, earned from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> the label "assistant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>" for
his ubiquity at the highest levels of executive influence; while <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson</ENAMEX>, who practically ran the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> from his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">chamber</ENAMEX> in the
1950s, found himself so insignificant that he was only informed of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX>
meetings <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five minutes</TIMEX> in advance.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JFK</ENAMEX>'s assassination changed everything but the feud, which
only intensified as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">martyr</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shadow loomed</ENAMEX> ever larger. In his grief, each
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">man</ENAMEX> blamed the other for the tragedy. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bobby</ENAMEX> had been point <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> for the
administration's <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cuban</ENAMEX> counterinsurgency program--whose activities, Lyndon
insisted privately, had certainly brought on the assassination as an act of
revenge from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Castro</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Q.E.D.</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bobby</ENAMEX> killed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX>. And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lyndon</ENAMEX>, thought <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bobby</ENAMEX>, was
responsible for his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>'s being in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> at all--to heal a wound in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Democratic Party</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lyndon</ENAMEX> should never have let fester in the first
place. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Q.E.D.</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lyndon</ENAMEX> killed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX>. The executive branch clearly wasn't big
enough for the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of them, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kennedy</ENAMEX> wisely decamped for his successful
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> run. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson</ENAMEX>, for his part, seriously considered dropping out of the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1964</TIMEX> election altogether, foreshadowing his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1968</TIMEX> decision not to seek
re-election.

            Up to this
point, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shesol</ENAMEX>'s book is nearly flawless (though <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Texan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> might be forgiven
for wondering whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shesol</ENAMEX> doesn't tip his evidence a little to favor <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>
over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX>). When the chronicle enters <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the second half of the '60s</TIMEX>, however,
it loses a little of its aplomb. This is the period when a single
issue--<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>--came to trump all others in establishing the political order of
battle. With <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX>'s Great Society sluicing off <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">up to $2 billion</NUMEX>
per month in expenditures on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> being elevated, for
better or for worse, to the role of standard-bearer for a generation repulsed
by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s imperial presumptions, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">antagonists</ENAMEX> became symbols for opposing
forces larger than either <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> could discern. By the time they faced each other
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">back-room atmospherics Shesol</ENAMEX> excels in reconstructing.

            
This is perhaps why the lesson that Shesol
draws from the denouement of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> feud feels so unsatisfying. He
claims that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> is the archetype of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">New Democrat</ENAMEX>." This is not a
completely untenable proposition, since, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shesol</ENAMEX> demonstrates, toward the end
of his life <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> began to experiment with some uncannily Clintonesque
gestures, such as financing urban renewal through market-based public-private
partnerships. It is, however, hard to square <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bobby Kennedy</ENAMEX>, whose
characteristic response to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX>'s poverty proposals was that they didn't go
far enough, with the end of welfare as we know it. And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shesol</ENAMEX> overlooks a far
more abiding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">division</ENAMEX> in contemporary politics than those that divide <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>. Like so much that polarizes us <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX>, it is more cultural than
strictly political.

            Take a
remarkable statistic that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shesol</ENAMEX> cites but lets pass relatively unexamined. In
May <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1967</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gallup</ENAMEX> found that the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who said they "intensely
disliked" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RFK</ENAMEX>--who was also probably more intensely liked than any other
practicing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX>--was twice as high as the number who intensely disliked
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX> of the increasingly unpopular war in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>. Exactly
who reviled the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX> to such a degree is not broken down further. But
it is easy to guess. Consider the results of another poll, this one from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1964</TIMEX>,
in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louis Harris</ENAMEX> found that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RFK</ENAMEX>'s presence on a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> ticket would
gravely hurt the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>'s chances in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX> and border <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>, among
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">businessmen</ENAMEX>, and among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fence-sitters</ENAMEX> in both parties.

            That is a rough description of what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Phillips</ENAMEX> later
called the emerging <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">majority</ENAMEX>: the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> whose voting habits were
molded by the act of detesting the likes of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bobby Kennedy</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> who
never worked a day in their lives, who were eager (so the perception went) to
oppress the plain <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folk</ENAMEX> with burdensome taxes in order to fatten the undeserving
poor, eager to sell out <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s military supremacy out of some guilt-ridden
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">moralism</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Politicians</ENAMEX> who seemed not to know how to handle rifles like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>. By
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1968</TIMEX>, that annus horribilis when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> cracked from the pressure of
mediating an increasingly centripetal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic Party</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> fell to an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">assassin</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bullet</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> political ideal-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">types</ENAMEX> had solidified: a "silent
majority" who supported <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX>'s war on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> and voted in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Nixon</ENAMEX>,
and a "new class" of liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX> who supported <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX>'s
war on poverty but detested everything <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Nixon</ENAMEX> represented.

            
               This is the mutual
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">contempt</ENAMEX>, hinted at but not developed in this valuable book, that haunts us
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.

         
      
   
