
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood Babylon</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dominick Dunne</ENAMEX> is a
ridiculous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, but in an interesting way. He is not, in the conventional
sense, a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>. His prose lacks even the hasty, spasmodic felicities to
which we are resigned in the age of word processing. Here is a sentence from
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> page of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.J. Simpson</ENAMEX> novel, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Another City</ENAMEX>, Not <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">My Own</ENAMEX> :
"That book [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dunne</ENAMEX>'s own <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Season</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Purgatory</ENAMEX> ], the miniseries of which he
was watching, had brought <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gus Bailey</ENAMEX> and the unsolved murder in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greenwich</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Connecticut</ENAMEX>, which, to avoid a libel suit, he had renamed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scarborough Hill</ENAMEX>, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">great</ENAMEX> deal of notoriety at the time of its publication, resulting in the
reopening of the murder case by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX>." Have we lost you? In this
sentence, "its" cries out for its parental noun like a little <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">duckling</ENAMEX> left on
the wrong side of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX>. "That book" is the referent, but other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nouns</ENAMEX> rush
to and fro like big, scary <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">buses</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miniseries</ENAMEX>, murder, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greenwich</ENAMEX>, libel suit,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scarborough Hill</ENAMEX>, notoriety.) Almost magisterial, almost artistic, is the way
this sentence begins to go haywire with the words "the miniseries of
which"--and yet not.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dunne</ENAMEX> can
be ridiculed not merely for his aimless, dribbling style. What he calls a novel
is hardly deserving of the name. Another <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">City</ENAMEX>, Not <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">My Own</ENAMEX> reads like a
conflation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>'s first-person columns for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity Fair</ENAMEX> , the
sole difference being the substitution of "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gus Bailey</ENAMEX>" for "I" throughout, as
if by universal search-and-replace. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gus Bailey</ENAMEX> goes to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courtroom</ENAMEX> and
watches the trial everyone already knows by heart. Then he goes to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> and talks up <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each day</TIMEX>'s events with an air of tragic foreknowledge.
That's it. The tone is uneven: Dunne jerks from moralistic pronouncements on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.J.</ENAMEX>'s guilt to smarmy name-dropping with the ease of an evangelical hack. The
litany of show-business and upper-crust names in the book is staggering. On
Pages <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">218</TIMEX> through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">221</TIMEX>, we find the following: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army Archerd</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kate Capshaw</ENAMEX>, Uma
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thurman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carrie Fisher</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roddy McDowall</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Taylor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Crowley</ENAMEX>,
Nazimova, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Natalie Wood</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Clavell</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sue Mengers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore Vidal</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Nicholson</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnny Mathis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy Reagan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marje Everett</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Merv Griffin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Princess</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prince Charles</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Travolta</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Suzanne Childs</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray Stark</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betsy Bloomingdale</ENAMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Greisman</ENAMEX> ("who used to be married to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sally Field</ENAMEX>"). I've omitted names
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> directly connected with the case--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marcia Clark</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Darden</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ito</ENAMEX>--although <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dunne</ENAMEX> has a way of making their names sound dropped as well.

            So why is one inclined to forgive this book's faults? Dunne
is nothing if not charming. The flair for gossip that got him into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of
dinner <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> also wears down the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resistance</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX>. He is seductively
forthright about the failures in his life, about the fiasco of his career and
marriage in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1960s</TIMEX>, and he is aware of the conditional,
codependent quality of his fame. He knows that his A-list aura at the time of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.J.</ENAMEX> trial owed everything to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.J.</ENAMEX> himself. He admits to being a "terrible
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">name-dropper</ENAMEX>." (Rather like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.J.</ENAMEX> admitting that he had his problems with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicole</ENAMEX>.) The act has more than a bit of camp about it--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">America</ENAMEX> attends to the
stern judgments of a male socialite. One has to smile at the role played in
this book by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Cunanan</ENAMEX>, whose scenes are the only ones here that seem to
spring from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dunne</ENAMEX>'s imagination. Cunanan shows up at a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> dinner party
hosted by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray Stark</ENAMEX> and populated by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kirk Douglas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Geffen</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marcia</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gus Bailey</ENAMEX> notices <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cunanan</ENAMEX> right away, and asks <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stark</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>, "Who's
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Latino</ENAMEX> staring at your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Monet?</ENAMEX>"

            At the end
of the book, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gus</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cunanan</ENAMEX> meet again, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gus</ENAMEX> dies. It's a loopy little
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">fantasy</ENAMEX>, belonging in the same genre as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dunne</ENAMEX>'s classically overworked
meditations on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Menendez</ENAMEX> case in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity Fair</ENAMEX> . (For example: "If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jose</ENAMEX>
did stick needles and tacks into his son's thighs and buttocks, didn't <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erik</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bleed</ENAMEX>? Didn't <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erik</ENAMEX> have scabs on his rear and thighs? I tried sticking a
thumbtack into my buttocks and I bled.")

            
I got a kick out of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Another City</ENAMEX>, Not My
Own . I devoured it in the proverbial single sitting. But the book is
ultimately compromised and rendered stupid by the obliviousness of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dunne</ENAMEX> had the best seat at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the great comic cultural cataclysms of recent
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, and he produced a weak, chatty book rather than a good, vicious <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. He
relishes a few absurdities as they glide past--the accidental meeting of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heidi Fleiss</ENAMEX> in a hotel <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lobby</ENAMEX>, or the sight of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">servants wincing</ENAMEX> in the background as beautiful white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> call <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.J.</ENAMEX> the scum
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">earth</ENAMEX>. He writes this nifty dialogue for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anne Douglas</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kirk</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>) and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara Sinatra</ENAMEX>: " 'I suppose everyone has said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX> word at some time or
other,' said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anne Douglas</ENAMEX>. 'Frank said it <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX>,' said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara Sinatra</ENAMEX>."
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dunne</ENAMEX>'s own rage at the black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, however, goes unexamined. Ultimately, his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">frothing</ENAMEX> is indistinguishable from the others'. That <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dunne</ENAMEX>'s own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> was
killed by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who later went free is not a sufficient distinction--victimhood
does not confer rectitude.

            In his
own life and in the larger spectacle, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dunne</ENAMEX> flubs the bigger ironic notes. Take
this exemplary passage from a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity Fair</ENAMEX> piece: "Sometimes you have to
separate yourself from the trial and go back to real life. I left <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX> early on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 11</TIMEX> so that I could get to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eva Gabor</ENAMEX>'s funeral on time."
Does Dunne mean to make himself ridiculous, or is his sense of "real life" so
far gone? You're never sure. I'm afraid that regular attendance at the funerals
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gabors</ENAMEX> is this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s idea of keeping it real.

            So, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Another City</ENAMEX> is a borderline case. It is a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">shoddy</ENAMEX>, daffy piece of work, but it provides <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four or five</NUMEX> fine vignettes of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> bedlam in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1990s</TIMEX>. Fortunately, there is another novel that renders
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dunne</ENAMEX>'s quite superfluous: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gary Indiana</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Resentment</ENAMEX> , published earlier
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Doubleday</ENAMEX>. It is, for the most part, a novelization of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Menendez</ENAMEX> case, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.J.</ENAMEX> nonsense shadows it, and the whole incompetent <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.J.</ENAMEX>
prosecution <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> seems to have been flown in for a last-ditch battle with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> of billable evil. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana</ENAMEX> has composed not just an autopsy of Los
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Angeles</ENAMEX> trial spectacles but also a satire-before-the-fact of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dunne</ENAMEX>'s
novel--possibly the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> such pre-emptive strike in literary history.
Resentment is narrated, like <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Another City</ENAMEX> , by a grumpy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> who
lives at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Chateau Marmont</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX>; at the same time, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dunne</ENAMEX> himself appears as
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>, as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist-novelist</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fawbus Kennedy</ENAMEX> who is variously
called "the kind of nothing this culture has been moving toward for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX>," a
"third-rate middlebrow Depends ad," and a "pompous mediocrity of a type
unprecedented and decidedly unwelcome in this kind of grave proceeding." The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">diatribe</ENAMEX> goes on and on and on, and it's funny precisely because it won't let
up. As <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dunne</ENAMEX> makes nice with the truly rich and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">famous</ENAMEX>, compliments the likes
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Taylor</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy Reagan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Spielberg</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX> holds
nothing back, burns all <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridges</ENAMEX>, settles scores with those who have merely
irritated him from afar.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>,
an on-and-off <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novelist-playwright</ENAMEX> and a longtime <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Village</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Voice</ENAMEX> , has accomplished more than the obliteration of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dominick Dunne</ENAMEX>.
Resentment also sends up urban gay novels and unravels the tangle of
reality and fantasy surrounding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> abuse. But it's the precision of his take
on high-minded gutter journalism that makes Resentment the one post-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.J.</ENAMEX>
book likely to survive the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">remainderer</ENAMEX>'s abattoir. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana</ENAMEX> manages
simultaneously to reproduce and cut to pieces the bad faith and false
consciousness surrounding these trials. He serves up in full the swiftly
rotting texture of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">,</ENAMEX> , the way every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">observer</ENAMEX> is drawn into the general inanity
and loses face in the act of . (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> on the underlined phrases for samples of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana</ENAMEX>'s vicious analysis.)

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dominick Dunne</ENAMEX>, in his book, tries to find the
meaning of events in relation to his own life and can end only with a scene of
queasily erotic murder-suicide. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana</ENAMEX> finishes with a general shudder, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">random</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> earthquake, a "shallow-focus event unaccompanied by volcanic
activity." My God, someone has finally summed up the whole shebang.

         
      
   
