
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Muddled Middle</ENAMEX>

            The right and the left have
been quarreling about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> middle class for at least
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three decades</TIMEX> now. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX>' populist version, the common-sense
morals of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Middle Americans</ENAMEX> are under attack by libertine <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elites</ENAMEX> and a decadent
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">media</ENAMEX>. The left conjures up a heartland full of racists, misogynists, and
religious maniacs. Both pit a morally hidebound <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">middle</ENAMEX> against a culturally
permissive overclass.

            But neither of these
overwrought images of fierce <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">division</ENAMEX> captures <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s more complex reality.
The truth of the matter is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> have won the culture wars. Maybe
not as thoroughly as they would have liked and maybe with much of the looniness
removed, but they won them, and we are a more tolerant, egalitarian, and
unified <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> because of it.

            It is the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">prime</ENAMEX> virtue of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Wolfe</ENAMEX>'s new book, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">One Nation, After All</ENAMEX> , that it
grasps the contours of what he calls this "mature" middle class. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolfe</ENAMEX>, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> of sociology at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston University</ENAMEX>, and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assistant</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria Poarch</ENAMEX>,
conducted interviews with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in each of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>. The locations
ranged from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rancho Bernardo</ENAMEX>, a gated retirement <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>; to
Medford, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mass.</ENAMEX>, home to police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">firemen</ENAMEX>; to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Broken Arrow</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Okla.</ENAMEX>, on
the buckle of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bible Belt</ENAMEX>. What intrigues <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolfe</ENAMEX> is not the regional
peculiarities of these places but the overlap among them. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> of Dekalb
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">County</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ga.</ENAMEX>, turn out to have much in common with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brookline</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mass.</ENAMEX>;
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">constituents</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Cobb County</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ga.</ENAMEX>, bear a basic resemblance to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Latinos</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asians</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastlake</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif. Hence</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>. (The "after all"
that completes the title is wry, not just as in "surprise, surprise" but also
"after all the cultural upheavals of the last <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX>.")

            These suburbanites, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolfe</ENAMEX> finds, are wary of both
right-wing preachers and bleeding-heart <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX>. They "long for a sensible
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">center</ENAMEX> and distrust ideological thinking." They're hardly heroic in their
virtues; there's none of the grandeur of, say, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Protestant Ethic</ENAMEX> here. But
neither is there much of the demonic. There's no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>-swapping or
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">anti-Semitism</ENAMEX>.

            Their
morality might be described as nonjudgmental pragmatism. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolfe</ENAMEX> finds them using
few words such as "sin," "moral rot," "decay," or "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Satan</ENAMEX>." Middle-class
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> don't deem <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of other faiths as wanting or immoral. They're
"reluctant to pass judgment on how other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> act and think." They don't
hanker for the old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> order or want to put <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> back in ancient
strictures, but neither do they endorse the left's "anything goes" morality.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolfe</ENAMEX> describes these <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Middle Americans</ENAMEX> with the term "ambivalent," which I
don't think is quite right, since it suggests they're unsure of their own
views. Rather, I'd call them syncretists, who draw on the values of both moral
obligation and modern self-expression. They wish to preserve the freedoms
brought by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> working, sexual enlightenment, and feminism, even as they also
worry about the fragility of family life and the dangers their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
face.

            
The same <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mix</ENAMEX> is evident on public policy issues
such as race, welfare, and immigration. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolfe</ENAMEX>'s interviewees draw sharp lines
between the deserving and undeserving poor. When they think about riven
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> and social pathology in the inner <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, they generally blame "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s
lack of personal responsibility." But such sentiments aren't necessarily
racist. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolfe</ENAMEX>'s suburbanites have sympathy for unwed ghetto <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX>, believe in
giving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> chance, and know that the safety net is a moral, not
just a practical, necessity. And if they don't like feeling swamped by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who want <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> placed on a par with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX>, they have
come to value different ethnic and racial traditions--so long as those
traditions don't trump one's identity as an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX>.

            At almost
every turn, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolfe</ENAMEX> affirms a sensibility of the serene. The concepts he
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">invokes</ENAMEX>--"quiet faith," "mature patriotism," "ordinary duties," "morality writ
small," "soft multiculturalism"--proclaim a preference (both his and his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX>') for the middle way. Against hotter images of a churning id of rabid
racism or dangerously aggrieved <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Middle Americans</ENAMEX>, he restores to the middle its
claims of reason and morality. We do not have to fear them.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolfe</ENAMEX>'s approach has its limitations. His interviews tend
to focus on the more educated, affluent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">segments</ENAMEX> of the middle class, segments
that may more easily slip into genteel euphemisms and present themselves as
"enlightened." And the brevity of the sessions<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">--90 minutes to 120 minutes</TIMEX> to
cover a lot of ground--can permit the breathless clutter of quick responses to
keep at bay deeper and darker sentiments. Moreover, by contrasting his central
metaphor of "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>" against the alternative vision of culture war, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wolfe</ENAMEX>
makes his own position seem moderate and attractive. Were he not constantly
playing off a notion of a fiercely divided society, one might discover other
questions and thus other important qualities of the middle class.

            Finally,
in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> case I suspect <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolfe</ENAMEX> is incorrect. He sees homosexuality as something of
a grand exception to his larger thesis: Only a small percentage of his
interviewees are willing to admit its legitimacy as a lifestyle. But the vast
majority of them have come to accept <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homosexuals</ENAMEX> as worthy of rights and even
of respect, if not of admiration. Measured against the historical baseline of
great fear and misunderstanding, this tolerance may actually vindicate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolfe</ENAMEX>'s
larger argument.

            
Still, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolfe</ENAMEX>'s portrait captures an essential
truth. Despite the huffing and puffing, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">divisions</ENAMEX> have been closing in gender,
in notions of patriotism, and even in some dimensions of race. Religious
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fundamentalists</ENAMEX>, who once declaimed against fornication, now seek simply to
hold the line at gay marriage. Meanwhile, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">party</ENAMEX> have
been publicly embracing the idiom of hard work and personal responsibility.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolfe</ENAMEX> also throws down an
implicit challenge to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX>. At <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point he imagines this middle-class
plaint: "By dismissing our fears about declining morality out of hand, you fail
to recognize that middle-class morality is not necessarily opposed to the
values of inclusion and equality that you currently profess." <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Liberals</ENAMEX> have
been like the pre-<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Civil War Whigs</ENAMEX>, at least as rendered by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louis Hartz</ENAMEX> in his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">classic Liberal Tradition</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whigs</ENAMEX> kept seeing the proles
through the lens of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>'s old feudal societies, imagining that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s
lower orders wanted to seize property rather than acquire it. Rebuffing these
lower classes when they could have beguiled them, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whigs</ENAMEX> made potential
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> into <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX>. The post-1960s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic Party</ENAMEX> has come close to making
the same mistake. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolfe</ENAMEX> reminds us that for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>, "taking back the
middle" doesn't have to mean craven opportunism or a betrayal of its beliefs.
Rather, it can simply mean rediscovering the common ground that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> have
long shared with the middle class without even realizing it.

            It might be argued that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolfe</ENAMEX>'s portrait of the middle's muddle will be shocking only to a rarified and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dogmatic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ideologues</ENAMEX>. But that's the virtue of this calm and sensible
book. It doesn't aim to dazzle with flashy but misleading <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rubrics</ENAMEX> like
"backlash." <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nation</ENAMEX>, After All is full of the very qualities its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author imputes</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>: ordinary virtue, mature patriotism, and quiet
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">faith</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
