
   
   
      
         
            Second-Class Symphonies

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">composers</ENAMEX> have
usually found it easier to earn money than respect. In the rarefied world of
concert music, film <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">composers</ENAMEX> were always thought of as versatile and skilled,
but with nothing crucial to say. Those who had started out writing for the
concert <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stage</ENAMEX>, as most in the studio heyday had, were assumed to have
sacrificed their art to mammon. The likes of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erich Korngold</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Adventures</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin Hood</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony Adverse ) and Bernard Herrmann</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Citizen</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kane</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Psycho</ENAMEX> ) never stopped pressing their noses to the windows of
the concert <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hall</ENAMEX>, bitter at the unwritten dictum, "No movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hacks</ENAMEX> need
apply."

            All that
has changed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX>, and the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> releases of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nonesuch Film</ENAMEX>
Series amount to a certificate of intellectual chic. The scores of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eden</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spartacus</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jules</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dodes'kaden</ENAMEX> , and a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX> of other classic films, whose music we have heard mostly squeezed stingily
out of tinny television <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speakers</ENAMEX>, have been sumptuously rerecorded. To hear
them this way--loud, full, warm, and three-dimensional--feels rather like
watching the movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> walk off the screen and into the "real" world in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woody Allen</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Purple Rose</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cairo</ENAMEX> .

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Uncharacteristically</ENAMEX>, the generally visionary <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nonesuch</ENAMEX> is
scrambling to catch a trend with this one. More typically, the label has
outclassed the competition. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> of the featured <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">composers</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>'s Georges
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Delerue</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toru Takemitsu</ENAMEX>--come from the artier world of foreign film,
and even the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scorers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leonard Rosenman</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alex North</ENAMEX>, wrote
music with a stronger bite than the bloated tone poems full of sopping strings
that had become the studio standard by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1940s</TIMEX>. For his first film, A
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Streetcar Named Desire</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1951</TIMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">North</ENAMEX> wrote <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>'s first jazz
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">soundtrack</ENAMEX>, the musical embodiment of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Orleans</ENAMEX>' moist, hot <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nights</TIMEX>. Rosenman
even dipped into the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX>-tone techniques revered by the very high <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">priests</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">modernism</ENAMEX> who thought his profession was debased.

            Takemitsu
was the only one of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> to have been a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> in good standing of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">avant-garde</ENAMEX>, partly because he wrote for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cinema</ENAMEX> , rather than the
movies, and partly because his film music was so abstract and his concert works
so cinematic. A long (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">15-minute</TIMEX>) excerpt from his score for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rikyu</ENAMEX> braids
together fitful phrases of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Renaissance</ENAMEX> string music, ominous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asian</ENAMEX>
pluckings, and electronic reverberations into a tapestry that is more hazily
eerie than narrative. At the same time, water <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courses</ENAMEX> through many of his
concert pieces (which have titles like "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Rain Tree Sketch" and "Towards the</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sea</ENAMEX>"), and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Takemitsu</ENAMEX> was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX> at painting rain, waves, and rivulets in
sound.

            
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Delerue</ENAMEX> CD is a box of bittersweets: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-
or <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three-minute</TIMEX> cues that deftly evoke a mood or a quick pang, and then move
on. From <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jules</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim</ENAMEX> there are the plucked, fragrant melodies that
stop brilliantly short of cloying, the spasm of frantic neo-Baroque fiddling
from <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Day for Night</ENAMEX> , and the tangy sounds of an out-of-tune barroom
upright from <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Shoot the Piano Player</ENAMEX> . In these eclectic sketches--which
capture an image but have no emotional arc of their own--the irony of this
project comes into focus: the contradiction of championing film music by
cleaving it from film.

            Those who
agitate loudest to get the soundtrack recognized as the great modern genre--the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">conductor John Mauceri</ENAMEX>, for example--betray a prejudice toward music that is
independent, nonreferential, and pure. "Once you take away the picture,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mauceri</ENAMEX> has said, "the inherent ambiguity of the music takes over." Strip the
battle scene from a cue written for a battle scene, and you get not mere
descriptive battle music but an abstract shard of symphony. The tension between
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">descriptive</ENAMEX> and abstract forms of music goes back to controversies of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19 th -century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>. In one corner, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brahms</ENAMEX> and his acolytes held
that music's highest aspiration should be internal perfection and
self-sufficiency. Opposing them, behind <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wagner</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Liszt</ENAMEX>, were those for whom
music was a lubricant for literature, art, or drama--just one component of a
synthetic artistic experience.

            These recordings would like it both ways. The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cream</ENAMEX> of film
scorers, they imply, are consummate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">collaborators</ENAMEX>, able to fuse notes and
images so that each inflames the other. But the very act of issuing them on CD
suggests they should be able to stand alone. If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wagner</ENAMEX>'s operas can be
excerpted for concert performance, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stravinsky</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ballet scores</ENAMEX> have a life
of their own, why can't the soundtrack jettison its celluloid ballast and
soar?

            Because it
doesn't work that way. Take <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">North</ENAMEX>'s celebrated score for <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Streetcar Named</ENAMEX>
Desire : The score's <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">brilliance</ENAMEX> lies in the way the languorous <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Orleans</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">jazz</ENAMEX>, redolent of sin, plumes out of the dive up the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kowalskis'</ENAMEX>, curls along the block, and squeezes itself through a radio. As we
watch, we can never be sure whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> are hearing the same music
we are, and as the music seeps into the lives of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanley</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stella</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blanche</ENAMEX>,
it does what jazz and the movies have always done best: It makes the squalid
glamorous. But surround the soundtrack with silence and mount it in a frame of
its own, and you have a stylish, silky knockoff of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duke Ellington</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Creole</ENAMEX>"
style: a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">makeover</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northeastern</ENAMEX> version of raucous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Orleans</ENAMEX>
jazz.

            
In a sense, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nonesuch</ENAMEX> film-music series is
like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cloisters</ENAMEX>, the hodgepodge of medieval sculpture rescued from crumbling
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">monasteries</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX> all over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> and patched together in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">City</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Fort Tryon Park</ENAMEX>. There is something perverse about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cloisters</ENAMEX>' demand
that the essential quality of a work of art remain intact, even when it is
dropped into an alien habitat. Like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cloisters</ENAMEX>, these discs contain
ravishingly crafted bits and pieces extracted from their intended setting;
restored, reassembled, and asked to keep right on glowing exactly as they did
before.

         
      
   
