
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Emperor</ENAMEX> of Ice-Cream

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Wallace</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stevens</ENAMEX> needs to be read in isolation. His poetry makes little sense in
conjunction with anyone else's. Like many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, I was baffled when I first
read his poems in high-school anthologies: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Emperor of Ice-Cream</ENAMEX>" sounded
like antique mumbo jumbo in comparison with the up<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">-to-the-minute</TIMEX> adolescent
angst of "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Love Song</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J. Alfred Prufrock</ENAMEX>." Only when I began to read the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">1954 Collected Poems</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wallace Stevens</ENAMEX> did I come to terms with him.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stevens</ENAMEX> eludes the anthologists because no one poem is the great <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. It's the
total book that counts. You can pick up the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Library of America</ENAMEX> edition,
turn to any page, and sink yourself into the unconditional, unfootnotable
splendor of the voice. I am not sure if this edition is the ideal packaging of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stevens</ENAMEX>, even though it includes more of his work than any previous collection
did. It may include too much--the words look smaller, the margins thinner. For
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> as worshipful of words as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stevens</ENAMEX>, these slight differences
matter.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stevens</ENAMEX>' rough chronological equivalence with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joyce</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eliot</ENAMEX> has created a mistaken notion that his poems are rich in complexity.
Blessedly, they are not. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stevens</ENAMEX> offers a double liberation: <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> from
meaning, then from modernist meaninglessness. His world is separate,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">immaculate</ENAMEX>. You do not need a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dublin</ENAMEX> map or a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> phrase book to travel in
it. Academic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">interpreters</ENAMEX> have failed to meet the challenge posed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helen</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vendler</ENAMEX> in her landmark study <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">On Extended Wings</ENAMEX> --to give up the search
for intellectual subject matter and to treat <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stevens</ENAMEX> as "pure sound." Vendler
herself sometimes fails to meet that standard. She offers ingenious paraphrases
and elaborations, but she imposes a false order on a genially chaotic world.
She looks for process and argument in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX> who excels at sudden revelations
in miniature. She and others have also promoted the idea that the greatest
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stevens</ENAMEX> is to be found in his ambitious long poems. But it is in those
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">poems</ENAMEX>--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Notes Toward a Supreme Fiction" and "An Ordinary Evening in New</ENAMEX>
Haven"--that his language is driest, his images dullest. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stevens</ENAMEX> came closer to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Fiction</ENAMEX> in short forms, in fragments.

            Rather
than try to launch a new exegesis, I want to name a few simple technical
devices with which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stevens</ENAMEX> makes his verbal music. More often than not, he
writes in iambic pentameter, the antiquated base rhythm of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> poetry. Take
the famous opening line of "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Idea</ENAMEX> of Order at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Key West</ENAMEX>": "She sang beyond
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX> of the sea." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> for a longer sample.) He chooses the sounds with
great care. In this line, the vowels almost rhyme: "ee ah, ee aw, eh ee, yuh
oh, eh ee." <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Only two</NUMEX> words have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than one</NUMEX> syllable: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stevens</ENAMEX> follows to
extremes the old schoolhouse rule that short words work better than long ones.
Like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX>, he loved the heave and ho of a line in which each beat has
its own word. (A lot of classic oratory also relies on monosyllables: "The only
thing we have to fear is fear itself"; "Ask not what your <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> can do for
you.") In <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stevens</ENAMEX>, monosyllables run riot, sometimes saturating several
consecutive lines, as in the vertiginously beautiful climax of "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Esth√</ENAMEX>©tique
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">du Mal</ENAMEX> ." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> .)

            
"The Idea of Order" culminates in another
highly monosyllabic line: "And when she sang, the sea,/ Whatever self it had,
became the self/ that was her song, for she was the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">maker</ENAMEX>." But as the language
grows ever more chiseled and incisive, the picture grows more vague. That woman
singing on the beach is dissolving into abstraction. It seems as though some
principle is being preached. At this point, if you read the poem in high school
or college, you may remember deadly questions intruding from the poetry
anthologies: "Does the sea represent language? Is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX>?" Any
question about meaning in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stevens</ENAMEX>, whether well or badly formed, ruins the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">trance</ENAMEX>. His words are a dream melody of language, bells from nowhere. You can
hear as much in tapes of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stevens</ENAMEX> reading aloud; he is so intent on keeping an
even, magisterial tone that he occasionally loses himself in the convoluted
syntax on which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vendler</ENAMEX> expends such analytic energy. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stevens</ENAMEX> fashioned a new
oratory free of meaning; he wrote a surreal, agnostic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Bible</ENAMEX> culled
from dilettante philosophy, dated chinoiserie, and picture-postcard
Americana.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stevens</ENAMEX>' grandeur is <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">an inch</NUMEX>
away from absurdity, if not in the thick of it. This is by intention. He liked
to deflate solemnity with silliness. His humor is his least noticed attribute,
probably because it is so widespread. Even his titles--"The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Revolutionists Stop</ENAMEX>
for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Orangeade</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"The Emperor of Ice-Cream</ENAMEX>"--undercut their own pomposity.
Sometimes I think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stevens</ENAMEX> was a collegiate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prankster</ENAMEX> who never gave away the
joke he played on literature. He comes close in some of the offbeat writings
that appear toward the end of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Library of America</ENAMEX> edition--especially in
such nonsense aphorisms as "A poem is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cafe</ENAMEX>," "A poem is a pheasant," and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">All</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">murderers</ENAMEX>." <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">More than a few</NUMEX> of the poems, I think, are self-parodies,
although it's hard to say which. (A good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> is "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Of Hartford in a Purple</ENAMEX>
Light": "A long time you have been making the trip/ <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">From Havre</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hartford</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Master Soleil</ENAMEX>,/ Bringing the lights of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Norway</ENAMEX> and all that.") <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stevens</ENAMEX>, securely
employed for much of his adult life by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hartford Accident</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indemnity Co.</ENAMEX>,
could afford to laugh aloud at the pretensions of the poetry business.

            The
closeness of the sublime and the ridiculous, of the daft and the grand, is
central to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stevens</ENAMEX>. The poem that sets it out most clearly is "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Man on the</ENAMEX>
Dump," in which he writes: "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> sits and beats an old tin can, lard pail.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">/ One</ENAMEX>
beats and beats for that which one believes." The monosyllables are the meaning
of the poem--the acting-out of a literary philosophy, which is to hammer new
beauty from well-worn words and modern bric-a-brac. The poem goes on to ask
these questions about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX>'s task:

            Is it
to sit among mattresses of the dead,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bottles</ENAMEX>, pots, shoes and <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">grass</ENAMEX> and murmur
aptest 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">eve</ENAMEX> ;Is it to hear the blatter of grackles and
say Invisible 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">priest ;</ENAMEX> is it to eject, to pullThe day to pieces and
cry stanza my <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">stone</ENAMEX>?
            

            Yes it is; this is what poetry is. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stevens</ENAMEX> frames his
manifesto in questions, as if uncertain. I think he's pointing up a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">contradiction</ENAMEX>. The poetry that he imagines being murmured on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dump</ENAMEX>--"aptest
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">eve</ENAMEX>," "invisible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">priest</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"stanza my stone"</ENAMEX>--is not in itself distinguished; by
intention, it's a bit ridiculous. The sublimity comes in the way those
fragments of a Romantic vision glide together with artifacts of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ordinariness</ENAMEX>--bottles, pots, shoes, <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">grass</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">poem</ENAMEX> performs its theme; it is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">self-sufficient</ENAMEX>, it runs on its own power.

            It is the purity of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stevens</ENAMEX>'
language that makes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Library of America</ENAMEX> edition--edited by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Kermode</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joan Richardson</ENAMEX>--seem a bit "off." Not only do the poems look better in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Collected Poems</ENAMEX> (which, to be sure, omits great ones early and late);
they are also unencumbered by comparison with the "uncollected poems," which
include a lot of mystifying mediocrity. It's good to have all the poems in one
place, and also the published prose and a smattering of letters. But it's also
distracting and, occasionally, misleading. You can't find the real <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stevens</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">voice</ENAMEX> in the early poems, but you can find it in early letters not printed
here. In one, the teen-age <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stevens</ENAMEX> writes a dead-on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stevensian</ENAMEX> description of a
motley village <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX>--"the piping of flamboyant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">flutes</ENAMEX>, the wriggling of
shrieking fifes with rasping dagger-voices, the sighing of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bass-viols</ENAMEX>, drums
that beat and rattle, the crescendo of cracked <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">trombones</ENAMEX>." <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Eight years later</TIMEX>,
the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> writes flamboyantly to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fiancee</ENAMEX>, "I believe that with a bucket
of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sand</ENAMEX> and a wishing lamp I could create a world in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">half a second</TIMEX> that would
make this one look like a hunk of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mud</ENAMEX>." For all its omissions, Collected
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Poems</ENAMEX> is the better picture of that awesome world.

         
      
   
