
   
   
      
         
            Suits Me

            Up until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few weeks ago</TIMEX>,
the presidential campaign was marked by a deliberate effort at restraint--no
insults, few attacks, an unvarying tone of stern politesse. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>'
clothes followed suit, which meant, of course, suits. No T-shirts or zipper
jackets on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX>; no cowboy hats or tank <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">helmets</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>. Just the
careful hair of each (unconvincingly dark for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>, unconvincingly gray for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>), the contrasting hair of their running <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mates</ENAMEX> (soberly dark for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>,
youthfully gray for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kemp</ENAMEX>), and similar suits on all the very different
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX>.

            Not that they haven't
lapsed. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX> have each momentarily given in to the populist urge and
appeared in leisure wear or rough gear; but that's always been a mistake.
Clothes like that are supposed to show the public <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> in private, the regular
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">guy</ENAMEX> with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guard</ENAMEX> down, but they usually just make him look childish.

            It is one
of the paradoxical effects of suits that, instead of concealing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> under
a bland exterior, they enhance it. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX> are more visible in
their smooth, dark envelopes than they are in the multicolored, bunchy stuff
required for <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">golf</ENAMEX> or hiking, picnics or beaches. Such exposure may not always
be flattering, but it does let the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voter</ENAMEX> sense the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> behind the slogan. Dole
may be trustworthy, but in a suit he comes across as withheld and static. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Kemp</ENAMEX>
is youthful and beefy, but he takes his coat off to jump around, which, like
his exuberant faith in quick fixes, seems a little bit foolish. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is
plump, bouncy, and optimistic. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> is solid, but sedate. And for once, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> look like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heads</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> before they've even taken <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>, clad in
the same somber <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outfit</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Yeltsin</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
Karimor of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Uzbekistan</ENAMEX>--a very dark suit, a pure white shirt with starched
spread or pointed collar, and a tie with a generous but disciplined
pattern.

            This is the costume, not of "power," as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people woozily</ENAMEX> say,
nor of rigid conformity and unimaginative conservatism, but of classic and
flexible modernity. Suits are the dress of civility itself. They aim to avoid
embarrassing or intimidating others, either with display--of bare skin or
startling color--or with a show of personal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX>. Instead they mean to
suggest, with self-respecting reticence, the idea of a strong but adaptable
order in things. This is the look we want in our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>--the look of unlosable
cool in shifting circumstances.

            This campaign has featured a
nicely symmetrical ensemble of youthful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gaffers</ENAMEX> and aging <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youngsters</ENAMEX>, each team
starring <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> brown, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">one</NUMEX> thick <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> and one thin, one mobile
frame and one stiff. But what this civilized sartorial <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">theater</ENAMEX> underscores more
clearly than anything else is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> is sexy and the others are
not. In breathing, tailored life, they are stiffs, except for <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Bill</ENAMEX>. He's the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> you want to hug, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> carrying his flesh with obvious pleasure,
ready to share it with others. Images of him with his tailored arms across the
shoulders of other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> seem reflections of genuine impulse, all the more
poignant in the context of sober modern dress. No wonder he's ahead in the
polls.

            It is
instructive to contrast the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicos</ENAMEX> who don't obey the
fashion rules. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Morris</ENAMEX>, for one, can't hide his unpalatable stump of a body
behind the trappings of genial sensuality. He may wear a soft collar, a suit
with wide lapels, and a brilliant yellow tie covered with yellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">sunflowers</ENAMEX>, or
a button-down collar with a glen plaid suit and a brilliant magenta tie, but it
only emphasizes his lack of bodily self-possession.

            
In <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> life, a dark suit is a given; it is
a costume generated out of modern <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s honorable and heroic past, particularly
his political past. When it comes to suits, we are all, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>, still in thrall to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Great Emancipator</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ultimate Public</ENAMEX>
Figure, whose great black suit merged his great <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soul</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> into
such a forceful image of physical appeal and high principle. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Candidates</ENAMEX> might
usefully remember that there are no photos of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> in fishing gear or
country clothes. His presidential suit alone created his special blend of
personal attractiveness and public statesmanship, a blend our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> are
always being urged to emulate. There were, moreover, no attempts to carve
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> in the nude with drapery, as there had been with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, no efforts
to heroicize him out of his trousers, just as there were none to popularize him
with comfy sportswear.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> sits forever in his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">monument</ENAMEX>, his marble words glowing high up on the walls behind him and beside
him. His marble sleeves and pants legs break into noble tailored folds around
his endless <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX> and legs, his marble <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lapels</ENAMEX> lie gravely along his chest, his
marble buttons, watch <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX>, necktie, and collar points create small episodes
along the front of his lean <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX>, over a marble shirt and waistcoat that create
a stately sequence of carved wrinkles.

            The statue enshrines <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX>
and his tailoring along with him, a suited beacon for all future political
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generations</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jefferson</ENAMEX> in their antique knee pants can't hope to
compete; neither can <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Teddy Roosevelt</ENAMEX> in his boots and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX>, nor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> in his
cowboy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outfit</ENAMEX>, nor, frankly, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> in their exercise clothes. In
their expressive self-effacement, suits make grown-up politics possible. It's
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the things they were invented for.

         
      
   
