
   
   
      
         
            Tales of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred Siegel</ENAMEX>, a senior fellow
at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic Party</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Progressive Policy Institute</ENAMEX>, has written a scathing
attack on urban liberalism. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Siegel</ENAMEX> blames liberal ideology for most forms of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">urban</ENAMEX> decline--for welfare dependency, spiraling crime rates, inefficient
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">services</ENAMEX>, and failing public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>. It is not New Deal liberalism that is at
fault, either. No, he says, "[t]he problems plaguing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> are the product of
policy choices produced in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1960s</TIMEX>."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Siegel</ENAMEX>
supports his argument with case studies of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>; and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>. He chose those <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>, he says, because they "shaped not
just the urban but also the national agenda. Politics and policy in these
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> represent liberalism and big <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> to the rest of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>." The
critical moments in the history of those <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>, he says, are the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
riots of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1965 and 1992</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Lindsay</ENAMEX>'s attempt to forge a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
Deal liberalism by expanding welfare and creating multicultural <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York</ENAMEX>'s fiscal crisis; and the collapse of municipal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> under
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marion Barry</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> "lived in the shadow of the riot ideology," he writes,
and it is in the name of "the riot ideology" and of righting the wrongs of
racism that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> went on to justify the violence of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1960s</TIMEX> and its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminal</ENAMEX> aftermath. The power to disrupt became a way of "extracting money from
the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>," he says.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Siegel</ENAMEX> clearly wrote this book out of a frustration, which
I share, with a general failure to face up to the shortcomings of the policies
of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1960s</TIMEX>. Yet <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Siegel</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cooper Union</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> of several
respected books, is too good a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> not to know that he has produced an
incomplete, one-dimensional account of the decline of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>. There
are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> serious problems with his argument--<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>, an analysis that gives
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">urban</ENAMEX> liberalism an unconvincing degree of importance in accounting for this
decline; <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>, a methodology that picks out <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> that are not really
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX>; and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>, an oddly unbalanced account of urban history that
places ideologically motivated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayors</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberal intellectuals</ENAMEX>, and radical black
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX> center stage.

            Was the so-called liberal
ideology really responsible for the deterioration of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Siegel</ENAMEX>
barely considers other explanations. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth T. Jackson</ENAMEX> argues in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crabgrass Frontier</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Suburbanization</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> , central
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> began to degenerate, and suburbs to boom, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">as early as the 1920s</TIMEX>, when
many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> started buying <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Federal Highway Act of 1916</ENAMEX> and the
Interstate <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Highway Act of 1956</ENAMEX> produced the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX> that enabled this
middle-class flight. A series of well-intended federal mortgage and loan
programs developed during the New Deal led to policies of "redlining": the
wholesale branding of certain--often, black--neighborhoods as greater credit
risks. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Housing Administration</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">GI bill of 1944</ENAMEX> ensured
long-term mortgages for home construction and sale, which made it cheaper for
the white middle class to buy new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> in the suburbs than to rent (or even
modernize) older <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX>. Meanwhile, many areas in the aging central <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> were
declared ineligible for loan guarantees. Add to these disastrous policies a
segregated public-housing program that concentrated affordable housing for the
poor in central <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>, and you see why, by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1950</TIMEX>, the suburbs were growing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
times faster than the central <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>; and why, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1960</TIMEX>, not a single one of the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">82,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Levittown</ENAMEX> was black.

            At the
same time, the manufacturing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">base</ENAMEX> of the inner <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> eroded. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Between 1958</TIMEX> and
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX>, most of the older central <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> lost <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of their manufacturing jobs.
suburbs were the principal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> of employment in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> largest metro
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">areas</ENAMEX>.

            
Clearly, these long-term trends and federal
policies left <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> besieged and impoverished. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Siegel</ENAMEX> doesn't just
undervalue these trends; he also gets his chronology--and therefore his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">causality</ENAMEX>--wrong. The wrenching loss of manufacturing jobs (the source of
low-skill jobs at decent wages) and the flight of the white middle class to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">suburbs</ENAMEX> began before the riots. While the so-called riot ideology might
have exacerbated these trends, it certainly could not have been held
responsible for them. The decline in urban economies occurred in almost every
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, even in those without the legacy of 1960s riots--like the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Belt</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Phoenix</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX>, whose economies actually
grew in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1960s and 1970s</TIMEX> before falling off in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '80s</TIMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Siegel</ENAMEX>
also fails to grasp certain key political facts of urban life. Simply put,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayors</ENAMEX> can't afford to be raving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ideologues</ENAMEX>. They are practically the lowest
living things in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s political food <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX>. Both <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> and federal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> can mandate programmatic spending without providing the funds.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> limit the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s legal authority to raise revenue through taxes and
debt, while the federal system forces <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> to compete with one another for
tax revenue. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Siegel</ENAMEX> fails to address the basic problem of a federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">system</ENAMEX> that
makes local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> dependent on their local tax base to fund basic
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">services</ENAMEX>, infrastructure, and education. Wealthier jurisdictions will always do
better than <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> with high concentrations of poverty.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Siegel</ENAMEX>'s choice of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> to study also presents a
methodological problem. In social scientific terms, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Siegel</ENAMEX> selects cases that
don't offer the opportunity to "test the null hypothesis." He stacks the deck.
This is really a book about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">District of Columbia</ENAMEX>
are invoked only insofar as they can support his claims about riot ideology.
But if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Siegel</ENAMEX>'s theory is correct, then <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> where "riot ideology" did not
inform local policies should have had different outcomes in terms of fiscal
policy, the quality of the public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>, and the condition of the local
economies. But this is not the case. Moreover, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> is never used in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">urban</ENAMEX> literature as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX> of anything other than itself--its history,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">governance</ENAMEX>, and economy are understood to be unique.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the
recurring themes in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Siegel</ENAMEX>'s book is that urban <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> were mau-maued by
black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">militants</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Siegel</ENAMEX> argues that funds from the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community Action</ENAMEX>
Program, a neighborhood-based anti-poverty program, were used to buy peace from
the black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">militants</ENAMEX>, allowing them to develop their own neighborhood-based
patronage <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX>. This was supposed to have been particularly true in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York</ENAMEX>, where white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lindsay</ENAMEX> were easily guilt-tripped. Here's where
a broader selection of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> would have made a big difference. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1973</TIMEX>,
political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Greenstone</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Peterson</ENAMEX> examined the Community
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Action Program</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Detroit</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX>--and found that it worked differently in each place. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Daley</ENAMEX> retained complete control over the federal funds and
distributed them to black neighborhoods through his <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> machine. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lindsay</ENAMEX> used them to augment a scheme for political decentralization that
began in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1950s</TIMEX>, under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Wagner</ENAMEX>. More importantly, all these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayors</ENAMEX>
went to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> for funds, and of them only <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lindsay</ENAMEX> would be considered a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberal reformer</ENAMEX>. No doubt, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayors</ENAMEX> who took these funds did try to use them
to consolidate their political bases. They were operating in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">great</ENAMEX>-urban-machine tradition of buying support.

            In <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the last few</TIMEX> lines of his book, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Siegel</ENAMEX> waxes strangely
optimistic:

            [E]ven after being taken
down a notch or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>, [<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>] will remain, by virtue of their concentrations of
energy and intellect, at the center of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> political imagination.
These great <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> will continue to shape our future.

            But if <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ideologically</ENAMEX> driven
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayors</ENAMEX> and radical black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX> have taken over, then the future of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> should be bleak. It isn't, of course. Across the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, immigrant
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">groups</ENAMEX>, faith-based <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX>, and bootstrap <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayors</ENAMEX> are reinvigorating
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, for example, where <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than half</NUMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s current
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">population</ENAMEX> is foreign-born, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> have helped renew neighborhoods: <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Koreans</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> have revitalized <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flushing</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Queens</ENAMEX>; as have <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian Jews</ENAMEX> Brighton
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beach; Caribbeans Flatbush</ENAMEX>; and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dominicans</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Irish Washington Heights</ENAMEX>. Each
of these stories is more important to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>'s future than those that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Siegel</ENAMEX> chose to tell.

            What's more, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>'s
current renaissance is happening because there is something to come back to.
The "overspending" that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> engaged in during the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Depression</ENAMEX>, which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Siegel</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">decries</ENAMEX>, may be contributing to the current rebirth of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s economy,
which centers on tourism, culture, financial services, and information
technology. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> there is, at least, an infrastructure to rebuild,
cultural <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX> that draw <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX>, and a wealth of human capital with
technical and creative energy. Were it not for <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">LaGuardia</ENAMEX>'s grand vision of
public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX>, public transportation, and affordable
housing, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> might have just been another <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Newark</ENAMEX>. In a recent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gallup</ENAMEX>
poll, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> was identified as the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> would most like to
live in. Nothing in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Siegel</ENAMEX>'s work could explain this perception.

         
      
   
