
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Empress' New Clothes</ENAMEX>

            The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">other day</TIMEX> I put my hand
on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> full, ankle-length skirts at the back of my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">closet</ENAMEX>, one tweed and one
black velvet, with the idea of finally getting rid of them. After <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two decades</TIMEX>
of nonwear, they seemed overripe for removal. But then, in a sudden fit of
prescience, I stayed my hand. I thought, like many others have lately, of Eva
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Per√≥n</ENAMEX>.

            What
brought her to mind was the advance hype for the movie, starring <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madonna</ENAMEX>, of
the musical <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evita</ENAMEX> , because a lot of that hype is about clothes. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madonna</ENAMEX>,
like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Evita</ENAMEX> before her, conveys personal power through bodily presence. Garb
matters a great deal to her, as it did to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evita</ENAMEX>, and it matters twice as much
when they are brought together. Given the movie's period flavor, this means
that the modes of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late 1940s</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early 1950s</TIMEX> are in for a determined
revival.


recent exhibition in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> featuring <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Per√≥n</ENAMEX>'s wardrobe in original magazine
photographs dating from her rise. These shots, from both <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> and French
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">publications</ENAMEX>, concentrated on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Evita</ENAMEX>'s patronage of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian Dior</ENAMEX>, fashion's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Man</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Hour</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 1940s</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inventor</ENAMEX> of the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">New Look</ENAMEX>" and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">savior</ENAMEX> of the
war-wounded <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> couture. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Evita's</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dior</ENAMEX>'s moments of prominence were
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">simultaneous</ENAMEX>, and they did make a stunning <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">duo</ENAMEX>--her daringly potent public
beauty, his daringly rich and ultrafeminine fashions. The alliance was short,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1950</TIMEX> marking the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pinnacle</ENAMEX> for each. Evita was dead in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1952</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dior</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1957</TIMEX>. Both,
however, proved enduringly compelling after death.

            Dior
arrived on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> fashion scene after <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX>, just in time to do away
with the enforced practicality of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s wartime clothing--usually refurbished
old clothes, or military uniform--and to revive Romance. The designs of the war
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> had been stamped with a certain gallant jauntiness and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">comic quirkiness</ENAMEX>,
expressed in restricted amounts of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fabric</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dior</ENAMEX>'s new insistence on elegance
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> was an inspired move toward a whole world of pleasure and languor
that had been suspended and nearly forgotten.

            
Whittled waists and prominent breasts were
shaped by exquisitely cut and fitted jackets that curved over flaring hips,
while sleek coils of hair supported delicately feathered hats. Crisply
radiating pleats and sumptuously layered folds of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fabric</ENAMEX> were deftly
manipulated into sweeping skirts, draped <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shawls</ENAMEX>, billowing bows--a universe of
precious textiles, often embroidered or sequined, to spread out from the
hourglass torso. When skirts did not sweep, they molded the figure to well
below the knee; dashing cuffs, collars, and stoles did the sweeping. Feet
emerged at the bottom, delicately shod. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coats</ENAMEX> swung out like the mantles of
Venetian nobleman.

            The whole
effect evoked the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">French Second Empire</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a century earlier</TIMEX>, the lush, moneyed
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">social</ENAMEX> world presided over by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Empress Eug√©nie.</ENAMEX> Dior was clearly creating
himself in the image of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Frederick Worth</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> of haute

               couture , dressmaker to the empress and her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>, and to the whole
affluent world. Dior was proposing to make empresses out of an emerging
international <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clientele</ENAMEX>, and to re-establish <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>'s pre-eminence as the
source of serious fashion, just as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empress</ENAMEX> had done. Per√≥n was the ideal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX>, an upstart with huge drive, deep pockets, and great beauty--as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eug√</ENAMEX>©nie
had been in her time.

            There has been a great deal of cant in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past 30 years</TIMEX> to
the effect that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dior</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">era</TIMEX> forced helpless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> into a posture of submission
with its fussily constructed garments, cumbersome skirts, cinched waists, and
rigid hairstyles, crippling their feet in high heels and imprisoning their
hands in white gloves. It looks as though we're now meant to forget that quaint
line of thought, and to regard such fancy trappings as appropriate to the
ruthless fight for political ascendancy. Call it the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dictatorial Mode</ENAMEX>.

            The
historic models for that notion are the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Renaissance</ENAMEX> queens--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth</ENAMEX> I of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">England</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Catherine de' Medici</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>. Plotting with or against their
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">statesman</ENAMEX>, courting the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populace</ENAMEX>, negotiating treaties, or ordering executions,
those formidable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rulers</ENAMEX> never failed to appear ostentatiously clad in vast
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">padded</ENAMEX> and jewel-encrusted dresses, their torsos boxed in whalebone, their hair
glued into smooth rolls upholding pearls and plumes.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Submissiveness</ENAMEX> clearly had no part in such
dazzling feminine armor, which not only fails to hamper but actively enlarges
female power. Modern <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, weary of expressing strength of mind and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> via
sports clothes and messy <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hair</ENAMEX>, may be ready to look again at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dior</ENAMEX>, to see how
he helped create <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Evita</ENAMEX>'s remarkable triumphs and to ponder how similar effects
could enhance theirs. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Costume Institute</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metropolitan Museum of Art</ENAMEX>
certainly thinks that we're ready, at least in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institute</ENAMEX> is
mounting an exhibition of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian Dior</ENAMEX>'s work, to coincide with the opening
of the movie and demonstrate the superiority of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dior</ENAMEX>'s vision by displaying the
actual clothes. After all, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madonna</ENAMEX> wore reconstructions in the film, and they
won't really look like the real thing.

            One
reason for this is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madonna</ENAMEX>'s pregnancy during shooting required her Dior
finery to mask her thickening midsection, whereas photos of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Evita</ENAMEX> in the
clothes show that her slimness and tiny waist--maintained both by will and by
deteriorating health--were a strong focus of her visual appeal. In the early
stages of her career, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evita</ENAMEX> was fleshier and raunchier and blended better with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madonna</ENAMEX>'s present persona.

            Pregnancy aside, what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madonna</ENAMEX> has that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evita</ENAMEX> didn't is
visible muscles and strong shoulders. The postwar Romantic look involved
sloping shoulders, a very straight spine, delicate bones, and no muscles
whatsoever. In fact, the sicker and physically weaker <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evita</ENAMEX> became, the more
the fashions became her. Her dominating will was all the fiercer, her grip on
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, too. The whole point of the fashion was the tension between the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> of female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personality</ENAMEX> and the delicacy of the feminine <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX>.

            In fact,
the sloping shoulder was the noticeable feature of the new clothes of the Dior
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">era</ENAMEX>, coming as it did immediately in the wake of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joan Crawford</ENAMEX>/Rosalind
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russell</ENAMEX> period and its vigorous shoulder padding. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Garbo</ENAMEX>'s characteristic
hunched posture of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid-1930s</TIMEX> was wholly obsolete. We had fallen under the
spell of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grace Kelly</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Audrey Hepburn</ENAMEX>, whose shoulders curved with easy
finesse, and whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heads</ENAMEX> sat high atop swanlike necks, just waiting for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">crowns</ENAMEX>.

            
A straight spine is something <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evita</ENAMEX> did have
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madonna</ENAMEX> and most others now either lack or choose not to show off. Ever
since we gave up posture for fitness, big square shoulders with a tendency to
hunch are no longer a disgrace but the appropriate sign of strength, especially
if worn with strong biceps. A hint of hulk is apparently not unwelcome in the
modern <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>'s image, and a slightly humped back, spinal curve, and
forward-thrusting neck go well with that. They look very good on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madonna</ENAMEX>, not
to mention <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Demi Moore</ENAMEX>; they add a thrilling touch of masculinity to female
chic. But they don't go so well with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dior</ENAMEX>.

            Modern <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> love to be
thin, but they also want their strength to look physical, not just emotional or
mental, in the Romantic vein. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dior</ENAMEX> style went with the kind of physical
force that is masked like a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">ballerina</ENAMEX>'s. In classical ballet, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>'s
greatest feats of bodily discipline and endurance must look effortless, and her
elasticity, miraculous. The emphasis is on expressive power--on imaginative and
spiritual range. Her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX>'s mechanical power is just as great or greater, but
it's there to support the interpretation, not to show itself off. That's for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gymnasts</ENAMEX>.

            It's possible that women
would still rather look like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gymnasts</ENAMEX> than ballerinas. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madonna</ENAMEX>/Evita/Dior
combination may generate only token changes in fashion, with small details
making the period allusions (hairstyles and makeup, hats and gloves, collars
and cuffs) on top of the present basic shapes. We may not be ready to hide the
female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX>'s true strength, to celebrate feminine charm with luxury and high
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">artifice</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Women</ENAMEX> may have to get more used to their real power in the world
before they can afford to look as if they practiced the discipline of elegance,
not that of the gym. But, in case we do arrive at that point, I'm straightening
my back and keeping my long, full skirts.

         
      
   
