
   
   
      
         
            Why <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Saddam Gets Away With It</ENAMEX>

            Why have <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arab</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">allies</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Operation Desert</ENAMEX> Storm been so skittish about a sequel? <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arabia</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> say they won't let the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> use combat <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">jets</ENAMEX> stationed
in their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> in raids against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al-Ahram</ENAMEX> , the main state-owned
newspaper of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX>, recently warned the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> that any strike would be
"coercive, aggressive, unwise, and uncaring about the lives of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iraqis</ENAMEX>." The
most outspoken <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponent</ENAMEX> of renewed bombing has been <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>'s arch-rival.
Even the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gulf emirates</ENAMEX> are nervous.

            You'd
think they'd all be more accommodating. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Just eight years ago</TIMEX>, with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kuwait</ENAMEX>
occupied and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> massed along the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Saudi</ENAMEX> border, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saudis</ENAMEX> asked for
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> help. That unprecedented request, enlisting <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Western</ENAMEX> aid in an intra-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX>
war, seemed to mark a turning point in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> politics, triggering a regional
reconfiguration of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alliances</ENAMEX>. So why are <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partners</ENAMEX> balking?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fouad Ajami</ENAMEX> helps explain this riddle--and many others--in
his new book, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Dream Palace</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arabs</ENAMEX> . Ajami, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Lebanese Shiite</ENAMEX>
who now heads <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> studies at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johns Hopkins University</ENAMEX>, offers a
haunting portrait of a generation of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX> forced to come to terms
with the West. All too often, he finds, they have failed to do so, preferring
the invocation of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> unity and anti-Western defiance to dealing with the
political realities of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX>.

            This is
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> reason <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s threat to bomb <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> is provoking such <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resistance</ENAMEX>. Meddling
by the West is still widely unpopular in many parts of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> world, even
among those who don't relish the thought of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX>'s chemical and
biological weapons. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> intervention smacks of the old Western habit of
arranging <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> affairs to suit Western convenience. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arabs</ENAMEX> would rather
relive the glory days of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1956</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Suez</ENAMEX> crisis, when the great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arab</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">nationalism</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gamal Abdel Nasser</ENAMEX>, withstood an invasion by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>. Ajami empathizes with the frustration engendered by Western
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">inconsistency</ENAMEX> and arrogance. But he knows that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX>'s brand of nationalism is
as much of a dead end as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nasser</ENAMEX>'s proved to be, and he worries that so many
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX> seem not to mind being taken for another ride.

            
Ajami, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Arab</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Predicament</ENAMEX> , the classic <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1981</TIMEX> intellectual history of modern <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> political
thought, is probably the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> most influential <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> public
intellectual. Pride of place goes to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia University</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward Said</ENAMEX>, who is
no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ajami's</ENAMEX>. In his groundbreaking <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1978</TIMEX> study, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Orientalism</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Said</ENAMEX>
accused previous generations of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX> of peddling a view of an exotic,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">backward</ENAMEX>, savage <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Orient</ENAMEX>, the intellectual justification for colonizing or
manipulating the region. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albert Hourani</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dean</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historians</ENAMEX>,
once put it, in a stroke Said changed "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Orientalist</ENAMEX>" from a legitimate academic
specialty into an insult.

            Some of
Said's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">admirers</ENAMEX> refer to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ajami</ENAMEX> by the ugly term "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Uncle Abu"</ENAMEX>--a play on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Uncle</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom</ENAMEX> meaning, in this case, an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> Orientalist. They will note that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ajami</ENAMEX> takes
his new book's title from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">T.E. Lawrence</ENAMEX>, the arch-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Orientalist British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colonel</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War I</ENAMEX> fame, and they will accuse him of imperialist sympathies. But
Ajami, a scrupulous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentator</ENAMEX> with a rich sense of irony, is using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lawrence</ENAMEX>
to make a subtler point. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arabs</ENAMEX> did not build the "inspired dream <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palace</ENAMEX> of
their national thoughts" that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lawrence</ENAMEX> sought to give them; they tried to build
a dream <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palace</ENAMEX> of their own, "an intellectual edifice" influenced by the West
but not of the West. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ajami</ENAMEX> is invoking <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lawrence</ENAMEX> knowingly, to underscore
what he views as the central <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> quandary. To <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ajami</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lawrence</ENAMEX> represents both
the good side of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West</ENAMEX>--its ideas of democratic governance, its support for
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> sovereignty--as well as its bad side: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Orientalism</ENAMEX>, meddling. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lawrence</ENAMEX> and
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heirs</ENAMEX>, the colonial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masters</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, left the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Middle East</ENAMEX>
with a complicated legacy of attraction and repulsion.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ajami</ENAMEX> begins his book with a bang: the suicide of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Khalil</ENAMEX>
Hawi, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Lebanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX> who shot himself on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day in 1982</TIMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> invaded
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beirut</ENAMEX>. Hawi, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mount Lebanon</ENAMEX> turned big-city <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">academic</ENAMEX> whose
often political poetry had once made him an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> nationalist <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX>, despaired
over the wider <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> world's abandonment of his beloved <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lebanon</ENAMEX>. The weakest,
most fractured <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> had become the front line for an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli-Palestinian</ENAMEX>
war that other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> wanted kept far from their borders. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawi</ENAMEX> had also
come to detest the willingness of his fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thinkers</ENAMEX> to become rented
mouthpieces for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lebanon</ENAMEX>'s myriad <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">militias</ENAMEX>, to cheer as the country
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">imploded</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawi</ENAMEX> saw <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lebanon</ENAMEX>'s dirty war as a meaningless blood bath rather than
as another glorious confrontation with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>. Through the tragic figure of
Hawi, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ajami</ENAMEX> mourns the tolerant, graceful, cosmopolitan <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beirut</ENAMEX> of his youth and
decries the factionalism that led to its ruin.

            Ajami
complains that many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> prefer simply not to deal with the
cruel realities of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> today: the gap between petrodollar wealth in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gulf</ENAMEX> and uninspiring economic growth elsewhere; the persistence of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">autocracy</ENAMEX> and the failure to develop accountable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX>; the debilitating
enmity with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>; the legacy of foreign rule; the influence of Western
political ideas and the sheer power of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. And so they have fled
into pan-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arabism</ENAMEX> instead.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pan-Arabism</ENAMEX> dates back to the collapse of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Ottoman Turks</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War I</ENAMEX>, which paved the way for what the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek Orthodox</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Antonius</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1938</TIMEX> famously called the "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> Awakening"--the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">prospect</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> self-rule. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pan-Arabists</ENAMEX> sought to unify all <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arabs</ENAMEX> across the
artificial borders drawn by the Western empires, hearkening back to the
glorious <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> caliphates. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, who vanquished <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX> in the war,
had other ideas, and the emergence of real <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> was deferred. But by the
1950s and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1960s</ENAMEX>, the awakening seemed underway, led by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nasser</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX>.

            The
problem was that it didn't work. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> that arose were uninspiring
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">monarchies</ENAMEX> or autocracies, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nasser</ENAMEX>'s grand dream of a united pan-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> state
that included <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Palestine</ENAMEX> came crashing down with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arabs</ENAMEX>' ignominious defeat
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">1967 Six Day War</ENAMEX>. But despite <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nasser</ENAMEX>'s humiliation, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">die-hards</ENAMEX> still
cling to his legacy and excoriate those who dare doubt its ultimate triumph.
Having seen pan-Arabism bankrupted in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1967</TIMEX>, more and more <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arabs</ENAMEX> are seeking
solutions from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past</TIMEX>--in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> fundamentalism, which seeks to remodel
Muslim societies along the lines of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arabia</ENAMEX> under the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prophet Mohammed</ENAMEX>. This
path has been smoothed by the nihilism of those <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX>--including
Said--who prefer utopian dreams to a view of politics as the art of
compromise.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> predicament is most painfully evident in what
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ajami</ENAMEX> calls "the orphaned peace" with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectual guardians</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> nationalist <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">orthodoxy</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Said</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Syrian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nizar Qabbani</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Egyptian</ENAMEX>
cultural <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saad Eddin Wahbe</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Egyptian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundit</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mohamed</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heikal</ENAMEX>--have never accepted the fact of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>; they cannot envision a world
without the rallying cause of anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Zionism</ENAMEX>. Nothing could have been more
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">infuriating</ENAMEX> to them than the sight of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yasser Arafat</ENAMEX>, the embodiment of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> nationalism, shaking hands with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yitzhak Rabin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>'s late prime
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX>. They never forgave <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arafat</ENAMEX> for bowing to what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ajami</ENAMEX> calls "the logic
of brute, irreversible facts." To them, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1993 Oslo accords</ENAMEX> meant settling
for a sadly truncated form of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> self-rule without extracting an
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> admission of wrongdoing. Indeed, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Said</ENAMEX> and other rejectionists showed a
perverse glee when <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>'s dovish <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor Party</ENAMEX> was defeated by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Benjamin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Likud</ENAMEX>. Here, again, was a world they could understand. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Men</ENAMEX> love
the troubles they know," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ajami</ENAMEX> witheringly observes.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ajami</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroes</ENAMEX> are figures
such as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novelist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Naguib Mahfuz</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">academic</ENAMEX> Sari
Nusseibah, and the tragic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawi</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> of integrity imbued with "the old,
confident spirit" of cosmopolitanism and an openness to the Western ideas that
led to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> awakening in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place. But they are under siege.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mahfuz</ENAMEX>'s secular liberalism so enraged <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Islamists</ENAMEX> that one fanatic
knifed the old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, paralyzing his writing hand.

            "The political culture of
nationalism reserved its approval for those who led ruinous campaigns in
pursuit of impossible quests," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ajami</ENAMEX> writes. Campaigns do not come much more
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ruinous than Saddam</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX> invasion of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX> or his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">occupation</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuwait</ENAMEX> a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decade later</TIMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX>, for all his strategic blunders, is deft at posing as
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heir</ENAMEX> to the tradition of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> nationalism. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> ratchets up
the pressure on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baghdad</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX> will inevitably bellow Nasserite defiance.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ajami</ENAMEX>'s book is an indispensable guide to why anyone in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> world still
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">listens to it.</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
