
   
   
      
         
            In God He ...

            Press <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mavens</ENAMEX> wring their
hands when news <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> are caught being brutal or irresponsible. But the
truth is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> were at their ballsiest and most outrageous 100 years
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ago</TIMEX>. Anything they dared to print <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> would seem panty-waisted in comparison.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Newspapers</ENAMEX> that once policed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> have been absorbed by the same
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> and have lost the taste for bare-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fisted</NUMEX> combat. In some places,
stories that might threaten <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">advertisers</ENAMEX> no longer see the light of day.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Reporters</ENAMEX>, once cast as ink-stained paladins, have morphed into banker
look-alikes and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrities</ENAMEX>. As news <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> have waned, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX>
have waxed, hiring fleets of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> who shape the news, often by spoon-feeding
lazy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX>.

            This
scenario owes a great deal to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John D. Rockefeller Sr.</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1839-1937</TIMEX>), sire of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard Oil</ENAMEX> monopoly, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patron saint</ENAMEX> of the modern <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporation</ENAMEX> and, in his time,
the most detested <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockefeller</ENAMEX> hired <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the first
corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">flacks</ENAMEX> to counteract the blistering hostility generated by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">muckraking</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ida Minerva Tarbell</ENAMEX>, who laid out in detail how <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX>
conspired to help its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">allies</ENAMEX> and ruin its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockefeller</ENAMEX>'s flack did
a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">yeoman</ENAMEX>'s job of placing warm stories about this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scourge</ENAMEX> of the corporate high
seas. But the irony that emerges from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Chernow</ENAMEX>'s hefty new biography,
Titan , is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockefeller</ENAMEX> helped create the modern corporate relations
department too late to help himself. After <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX> of fire from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McClure's</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tarbell</ENAMEX> had painted a bull's-eye on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX>'s back.
By the time the flack was in place, hordes of attorneys general and
trustbusters were closing in for the kill.

            Why did <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockefeller</ENAMEX> wait so long to return <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tarbell</ENAMEX>'s fire?
The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> reason is that he underestimated <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s hatred of his corporate
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">octopus</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard Oil</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> and most illuminating reason is that he
thought God was on his side. If you've got God, why on earth would you need a
public relations <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>?

            Inside
every fat book is a slender one struggling to get out. The fat book here
surveys the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds of</NUMEX> books and articles already written about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockefeller</ENAMEX>
and re-examines transactions, business <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partners</ENAMEX>, and supporting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> in
skillful--though excessive--detail. The slender book dispersed throughout the
fat one is a fascinating meditation on the monopoly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">capitalist</ENAMEX>'s moral
life--and the role that evangelical Christianity played in it. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockefeller</ENAMEX>'s
harsh <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Baptist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">upbringing</ENAMEX> made him the perfect instrument of the marketplace,
but it also set up a tortured cycle inside him. He coveted cash as his
God-given right; felt sinful about wanting it so badly; and was desperately
compelled to give it to charity, which he did with anguish. In wealth, as
elsewhere, religion was his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scourge</ENAMEX>.

            
The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Protestant</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Reformation</ENAMEX> provided divine
sanction for making money, earning profits, and engaging in commerce.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockefeller</ENAMEX> extended this sanction to collusion, secret agreements, corporate
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">spying</ENAMEX>, bribery, and extortion. Simply put, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">rivals</ENAMEX> were told that if they did
not sell out to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockefeller</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> would bankrupt them with a pricing war.
"The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX>," as he called it, used this strategy <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> in the "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cleveland</ENAMEX>
Massacre" of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1872</TIMEX>, wielding a contract with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">railroads</ENAMEX> that promised
preferential rates and taking over <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">26</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX> in the blink of an eye.
Then it marched like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sherman</ENAMEX> through the rest of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>. Before he was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockefeller</ENAMEX> controlled all but a pittance of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX>. His brutality
and success led directly to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Sherman Antitrust Act of 1890</ENAMEX>, which was
created specifically to dismember the Standard system of interlocking
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> that disallowed genuine competition. Standard resisted until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1911</TIMEX>,
when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> approved the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s plan.

            As usual,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockefeller</ENAMEX> laughed last. The stock soared when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s newly created
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">subsidiaries</ENAMEX> appeared on the market, making the richest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> in the world that
much richer. The deluge of cash angered <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Teddy Roosevelt</ENAMEX>, who had
hoped the break-up would bring the monopolists only pain. But it is a testament
to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockefeller</ENAMEX>'s skills both as an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">industrialist</ENAMEX> and as a deal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">maker</ENAMEX> that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offspring</ENAMEX> dominated both <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> and world oil for the rest of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">century</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offspring</ENAMEX>'s names, by the way, are <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Exxon</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mobil</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amoco</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chevron</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conoco</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Titan</ENAMEX> saw nothing wrong with bankrupting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> that
resisted his advances. He viewed the process of smothering the weakest
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> and swallowing those that remained as a thoroughly <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian</ENAMEX>
activity. While trustbusters called him the devil, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockefeller</ENAMEX> looked upon
himself as a saver of corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">souls</ENAMEX> who consolidated an unruly <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> and
did away with redundancy. This was true of the kerosene market, where
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockefeller</ENAMEX> turned a crappy, unreliable product into one that was consistently
good--and cheaper, to boot. But in so doing, of course, he drove his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX> out of business.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Reviewers</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Titan</ENAMEX> have found it impossible to speak of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockefeller</ENAMEX> without
referring to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft Corp.</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX>, especially since the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX> began scrutinizing charges that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> employs predatory
practices to maintain its monopoly on computer operating systems and to push
its own Internet browser. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s questions are legitimate, but the
comparisons between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockefeller</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> are less precise than they could be.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockefeller</ENAMEX> cornered the market on a natural resource simply by wrenching it
out of other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s hands. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> are selling intellectual
products that they thought up and that could eventually be eclipsed by others.
The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> are similar, however, in that both severely misjudged public
sentiment. Like <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Rockefeller</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">100 years ago</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> came to the national attention
with a pugnacious, imperial style that irritated government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> who needed
no provocation to do what they were hired to do.

            
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later years</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockefeller</ENAMEX> was rebuked
for his tyrannies, he sang the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">monopolist</ENAMEX>'s equivalent of "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Onward Christian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Soldiers</ENAMEX>": "It was right before me and my God. ... If I had to do it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX>,
I would do it again the same way--do it <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred</NUMEX> times." This messianic
corporatism originated in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockefeller</ENAMEX>'s childhood in western <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>.
His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Avery Rockefeller</ENAMEX>, sometimes called <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Devil Bill</ENAMEX>, was a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">flimflam</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bigamist</ENAMEX> who left his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> alone for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> at
a time while he fleeced the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populace</ENAMEX> with bogus medical cures. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockefeller</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mother, Eliza</ENAMEX>, reacted to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Devil Bill</ENAMEX>'s criminality by putting the fear of God
in her threadbare <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, whom she marched to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> with unfailing
regularity.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockefeller</ENAMEX> grew up ashamed of both his poverty and his ne'er-do-well father
and obsessed with the twin themes of frugality and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>. He kept a
personal ledger in which he recorded all the money he spent, even the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$118</NUMEX> he
paid for his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s engagement ring, which he listed under "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sundry Expenses</ENAMEX>."
He wanted mightily to accumulate money, but he worried constantly about
breaking the moral code against covetous behavior. Worth <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billions</NUMEX>, he reviewed
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">every</TIMEX> grocery bill and prowled the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hallways</ENAMEX> turning out lights. He bit the head
off a streetcar <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conductor</ENAMEX> who once charged him two fares thinking the
distinguished gentleman was paying for his traveling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> as well.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockefeller</ENAMEX> was deeply conflicted about giving away money.
He recognized a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> duty to charity but was gripped by a fear that his
charity would be wasted, thereby incriminating him in sin. He overcame this
fear enough to give away <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">billions</NUMEX> (more by far than even <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andrew Carnegie</ENAMEX>) and
created the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Chicago</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockefeller University</ENAMEX>, and his own
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">foundation</ENAMEX>. But giving drove him near to nervous collapse. This story is told
well in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chernow's</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapter</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Captains of Erudition</ENAMEX>," which describes the hellish
wrangling between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockefeller</ENAMEX> and the free-spending <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Rainey Harper</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockefeller</ENAMEX> wrote to an associate:

            I am in trouble, Mr.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX>. The pressure of these appeals for gifts has become too great for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">endurance</ENAMEX>. ... I am so constituted as to be unable to give away money with any
satisfaction until I have made the most careful inquiry as to the worthiness of
the cause. These investigations are now taking more of my time and energy than
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard Oil</ENAMEX> itself.

            Chernow
attributes this attitude to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockefeller</ENAMEX>'s "uncommon respect for the dollar."
But what we see is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> caught between the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> imperative to give
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">generously</ENAMEX> and a near-pathological cheapness. The tension between the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> drove
him to distraction. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chernow</ENAMEX> attributes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockefeller</ENAMEX>'s poor relations with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harper</ENAMEX>
to the fact that the college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> was a spendthrift. But building a
university from scratch is far from cheap. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockefeller</ENAMEX> wanted a great <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX>,
and he went to great trouble to lure <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harper</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale</ENAMEX> to the nascent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>. With <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harper</ENAMEX> in place, one gets the sense of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockefeller</ENAMEX> seizing up
on the issue of money, eventually forbidding <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harper</ENAMEX> to even discuss it in his
presence. This is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockefeller</ENAMEX>'s double bind. The sight of his money flowing
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">liberally</ENAMEX> unnerved him deeply, even when it flowed to something he valued.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockefeller</ENAMEX> was caught up in this anguished
giving when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Avenging Angel Tarbell</ENAMEX> began to rend his flesh in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McClure's</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tarbell</ENAMEX> had grown up in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX> oil <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">regions</ENAMEX> and saw firsthand what
happened when the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cleveland Massacre</ENAMEX> rolled east. Her religious <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">upbringing</ENAMEX> was
easily a match for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockefeller's</ENAMEX>, but it manifested itself in a substantially
different way. Her <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19</NUMEX>-part series was an enormous undertaking that still stands
as the signal work on the Standard monopoly. The series maintained an even,
almost clinical tone. But a final, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-part profile was unvarnished opinion at
its most brutal. Few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> had seen <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockefeller</ENAMEX> up close until Tarbell
ambushed him at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX>. She found him leprous and reptilian and saw in him
"concentration, craftiness, cruelty and something indefinably repulsive."
Painting a harrowing portrait of the age-ravaged face, she wrote, "Mr.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockefeller</ENAMEX> may have made himself the richest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> in the world, but he has
paid. Nothing but paying ever ploughs such lines in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s face, ever set his
lips as such a melancholy angle."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chernow</ENAMEX> argues with Tarbell
throughout this book, crediting her work and pointing out her mistakes and
emotional lapses. Tarbell was occasionally over the top. But she was also a
passionate and hard-driving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> who spoke a sometimes crushing truth to
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the most powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> in the world. Deal-hungry <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">monopolists</ENAMEX> will be with
us always. But with journalism fixated on gossip and entertainment, there may
be no <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ida Tarbells</ENAMEX> to bring them down.

         
      
   
