
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Smiley</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">People</ENAMEX>

            One thing you have to admire
about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane Smiley</ENAMEX>, no matter what you think of her fiction: She puts her money
where her mouth is. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Two years ago</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Smiley</ENAMEX> published an essay in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harper</ENAMEX>'s --a manifesto, really--claiming that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> have been conned
into seeing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huckleberry Finn</ENAMEX> as the "definitive" <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> novel when
it's actually a mess and a moral disaster. Among her charges was the claim that
the bond between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Huck</ENAMEX> and the escaped <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slave</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim</ENAMEX> was an evasive white fantasy.
Twain, she says, doesn't care what happens to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim; Jim</ENAMEX> is just a dumb sidekick
and the novel a precursor to the kinds of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buddy</ENAMEX> movies in which a sweet black
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cop</ENAMEX> played by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danny Glover</ENAMEX> stands aside while a white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> played by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mel Gibson</ENAMEX>
saves <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>.

            What's
more, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smiley</ENAMEX> wrote, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> have always sensed that the happy ending is slapped
on, a cop-out; probably the book would have dropped out of sight if certain
self-promoting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> hadn't started talking it up <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early in this century</TIMEX>.
These literary bullies--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">T.S. Eliot</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ernest Hemingway</ENAMEX>, and later on, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lionel</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trilling</ENAMEX>--were invested in a single, skewed view of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> writing. They
believed that its great theme was the struggle of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> wandering
alone in the wilderness, and they turned <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Huck</ENAMEX> into a mascot for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lonely</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Searching Man</ENAMEX>. What made <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Smiley</ENAMEX> especially angry was how these canon-builders
dismissed all the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19 th century</TIMEX> novels that didn't conform to this
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">guy</ENAMEX>-in-nature pattern (unless the novels were written by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry James</ENAMEX>). They
decided that the once-beloved social novel--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smiley</ENAMEX>'s prime example is <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Harriet</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beecher Stowe</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Uncle Tom's Cabin</ENAMEX> --was a weepy, feminine waste of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>.

            Iremember reading <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smiley</ENAMEX>'s article at the time and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">blanching</ENAMEX>. One hates to use a sexist's favorite word, but she came off as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">shrill</ENAMEX>. On the other hand, if you set aside her excessive loathing of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Twain</ENAMEX>,
some of her points are hard to argue with. She's , for instance, that until
recently, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> who wrote about alienation stood a decent chance of being taken
seriously by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>, while a whole genre of social novels written by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> got
pooh-poohed as earnest and sentimental.

            Is it possible, or even
desirable, to revive the lost tradition of social fiction? In <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The All-True</ENAMEX>
Travels and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adventures of Lidie Newton</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Smiley</ENAMEX> has supplied a test case.
It's set in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kansas Territory</ENAMEX>, shortly before <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">the Civil War</ENAMEX>, when the area
was an anarchic battleground between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northern</ENAMEX> abolitionists, poor pro-slavers
from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Missouri</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speculators</ENAMEX> out to make a buck.

            The
eponymous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroine</ENAMEX> was born and raised in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Quincy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ill.</ENAMEX>, and orphaned, just as
the novel opens, at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the age of 18</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lidie</ENAMEX> is tall, homely, a tomboy--and
somewhat anachronistically aware of all the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19 th century</TIMEX> clothing
and marriage <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">customs</ENAMEX> that infantilize <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>. She's a burden to her extended
step <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, so when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX>, a serious-minded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX>, passes
through <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> on his way to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kansas</ENAMEX>, she marries him within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX>. She knows
he's running <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> for abolitionists (blond, effeminate, and brave, he's the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northern</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counterpart</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Gone With the Wind 's Ashley</ENAMEX>), but she's totally
unprepared for the hardscrabble life she's chosen. The first few <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapters</ENAMEX> are
gripping re-creations of the hideous journey to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kansas</ENAMEX> and the daunting task of
building a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cabin</ENAMEX> from scratch while drunken <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strangers jeer</ENAMEX> at you and threaten
you with rifles.

            
From her diatribe in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harper</ENAMEX>'s , you'd
think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smiley</ENAMEX> was out to revive Stowian melodrama, with its coincidences,
angelic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, and neat distinctions between good and evil. Wrong. At every
point, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Smiley</ENAMEX> upsets the usual expectations. Coming from the no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s land of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX> instead of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">North or South</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lidie</ENAMEX> represents the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">realist</ENAMEX>'s take on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">slavery</ENAMEX>--in her heart she's against it, but she finds the abolitionists smug,
intoxicated by their own abstract words. Instead of love at first sight,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lidie's</ENAMEX> romance with cold, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fussy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX> is slow and confusing, and halfway
through the book, just as she's prepared to investigate the possibility that
they're in love, he's suddenly murdered. (I might not have revealed this plot
point if it weren't announced on the book jacket.)

            Here the
story turns into a kind of absurd picaresque: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lidie</ENAMEX>, driven by rage at her
loss, disguises herself as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy reporter</ENAMEX> in hostile <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Missouri</ENAMEX> and sets out to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">find Thomas</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">killers</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smiley</ENAMEX> blocks her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">path</ENAMEX> with various obstacles, until
Lidie ends up broke and dying on the side of a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX>, and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slave</ENAMEX>-owning family
takes her in. Unwilling to give up the notion that she has a mission, she
embarks on a final escapade: She tries to liberate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lorna</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>'s angry,
put-upon <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slave-maid</ENAMEX>.

            At which point, it becomes obvious that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Smiley</ENAMEX> isn't
writing a traditional "social novel" at all. She's writing a sendup of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huckleberry Finn</ENAMEX> . The parallels are obvious. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lidie</ENAMEX> equals <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Huck</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lorna</ENAMEX> equals <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jim</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lidie</ENAMEX> even has a mischievous young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX> who's a stand-in
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Sawyer</ENAMEX>--and the whole point of the book is to shine the harsh light of
reality on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Twain</ENAMEX>'s irresponsible fantasy. Unlike <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huck</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adventure</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lidie</ENAMEX>'s ends
in disaster. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lorna</ENAMEX> is caught and sent down the river to a violent fate in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South</ENAMEX>. And <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lidie</ENAMEX> learns, learns, and learns her lesson: She's been selfish and
. Desperate to escape the plantation where she's been recuperating but lacking
the willpower, she has selfishly accepted the defenseless Lorna "as my reviver,
felt the cool, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> sensation of her hand on my neck as a promise."

            The ending of Lidie
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newton</ENAMEX> is quite stunning as parody. But for someone so bent on unmasking
pieties, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Smiley</ENAMEX> is not above her own kind of sanctimony. In its curious, modern
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX>, this novel is a sermon. It attacks sentimentality, ideology, and piggish
male heroism, preaching ambiguity in their place. "No one could describe what
was true in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kansas</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Missouri</ENAMEX>," the newly mature Lidie announces at the end.
The message is deep--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smiley</ENAMEX> may be the subtlest didact ever to write a novel.
But was it worth taking down <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huckleberry Finn</ENAMEX> for? Only if it serves as
a building block to a better <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smiley</ENAMEX> novel in the future, one in which her
brilliant lessons of disillusionment fly faster, because they're spurred on by
a bigger, warmer imagination. This would be the real coup: to unite <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Smiley</ENAMEX>'s
cold, corrective realism with the joy--still unmatched--of that increasingly
misunderstood <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Twain</ENAMEX>.

            
               If you
missed the links within this review, click for the of how <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> dismissed a
"whole genre of social novels written by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> ... as earnest and sentimental."
And 's a comparison between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lidie Newton</ENAMEX> and an early <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smiley</ENAMEX> novel,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Duplicate Keys</ENAMEX> .
            

         
      
   
