
   
   
      
         
            Like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Water</ENAMEX> From a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stone</ENAMEX>

            It may sound odd to hear the
name <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McPhee</ENAMEX> in the same sentence as the phrase "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cult writer</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McPhee</ENAMEX>'s
career developed smack in middle of the literary mainstream, in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yorker</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '60s and '70s</TIMEX>. In many ways he, along with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joan Didion</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman Mailer</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Wolfe</ENAMEX>, helped define contemporary <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> writing,
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">elevating</ENAMEX> journalism from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">journeyman</TIMEX>'s status to something like literature.
What's more, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McPhee</ENAMEX>'s work is uncultishly genteel. Unlike his fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Journalists</ENAMEX>, he rarely stoops to the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>. Where his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peers</ENAMEX> wrote
frenzied accounts of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> and racial strife, he gravitated toward tamer
subjects--the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX>, for example, and canoes.

            In this
era of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX> overkill, it's not surprising to find a cult of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> as
restrained as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McPhee</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Didion</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mailer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolfe</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">et al.</ENAMEX>, have become somewhat
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">overexposed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McPhee</ENAMEX>'s influence may have narrowed since his heyday, but he
remains the ultimate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>. In creative writing programs, his focused
prose and reverence for facts are touted as the great model for literary
journalism. Among my acquaintances in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> publishing, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McPhee</ENAMEX> has better
word of mouth than any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> I know.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This month</TIMEX> his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> should be moved to even greater awe by
a giant new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">opus</ENAMEX>. Annals of the Former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World</ENAMEX> is vintage <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McPhee</ENAMEX>--it
represents <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 years</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> pieces and books, reworked for the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time into a unified whole. All the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">craftsman</ENAMEX>'s flourishes are on view.
Sentence by sentence, this book has more finely tuned prose than anything I've
read in ages. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> for an excerpt.) Which is, as it turns out, its main
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">shortcoming</ENAMEX>. Things written sentence by sentence often lack a larger energy.
One could even call <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McPhee</ENAMEX> boring--except that the real problem is weirder than
that.

            Here is a
key fact about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McPhee</ENAMEX>: He was born in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Princeton</ENAMEX>, went to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Princeton</ENAMEX> and, with a
few exceptions, has lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Princeton</ENAMEX> all his life. The obsessive travels he's
recorded in prose are balanced by a level of stability almost unheard of for a
contemporary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>. His working life is just as consistent. He knew at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX> that
he wanted to write for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> . By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the age of 34</TIMEX> he was on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>,
enjoying wonderful privileges--salary and benefits, huge word counts,
permission from his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> to do whatever he wanted. This is freedom the likes
of which <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> may never see again.

            
Early on, he specialized in admiring portraits
of successful young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> as a star college <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thomas</ENAMEX>
Hoving at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metropolitan Museum of Art</ENAMEX>. It's hard to appreciate how
influential these <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pieces</ENAMEX> were, since their meandering narrative--a leisurely
stream of details set off by sharp, dramatic scenes--helped define the modern
magazine profile. What stands out about them <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> is how positive they are
about their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> has a great work ethic and uncommonly good
manners. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hoving</ENAMEX> is a shining <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">art bureaucrats</ENAMEX>, so talented that every
major <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX> would swap favors with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Satan</ENAMEX> to hire him. It's
refreshing to read a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> who doesn't snoop around for hints that his
subject ever did anything sordid. Yet the pieces are also suffused with a
strange self-satisfaction. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McPhee</ENAMEX> lays out a picture of young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> who happened
to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Princeton</ENAMEX> and to possess gifts (a good eye, discipline) not unlike his
own. Then, moving in to eat his <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cake</ENAMEX>, he asks us to applaud their modesty.

            As time
went on, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McPhee</ENAMEX> began to focus more and more on the structure of a piece. Each
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX>, he believes, has an organic shape. He finds it by sorting his ample
research into subtopics, writing the name of each subtopic on an index card,
and playing around with the cards till he finds the right order. To an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">outsider</ENAMEX>, the results of this search can seem specific to the point of
absurdity. An introduction to the collection <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Literary Journalists</ENAMEX>
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1984</TIMEX>) reports that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hoving</ENAMEX> profile was shaped like a capital <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Y</ENAMEX>, in which
"the descending <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">branches</ENAMEX> finally joined at a moment of an epiphany during
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hoving</ENAMEX>'s college career at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Princeton</ENAMEX>, and then proceeded along the bottom stem
in a single line." In some sense that I struggled to understand but eventually
gave up on, another famous piece, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Travels</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgia</ENAMEX>," was apparently shaped
like a lower case e.

            His sense of shape may explain why he was drawn to geology,
a science that interprets rocks and gashes in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">earth</ENAMEX> and weaves these
interpretations into a story of how the world grew. Annals of the Former
World began in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '70s</TIMEX> with a piece for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> 's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Talk of</ENAMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Town</ENAMEX>" on road cuts around <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McPhee</ENAMEX> knew he was onto
something bigger. Again, the form preceded the content: He imagined a book that
would journey in a straight line across <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Interstate 80</ENAMEX>. He began traveling
around the world interviewing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">geologists</ENAMEX>, journeying with them to outcrops,
looking and learning. The result is a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">majestic</ENAMEX> book, filled with fascinating
facts, memorable profiles of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX>, and a profound grasp of the fact that
we human beings are nothing but the merest specks.

            And yet, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Annals</ENAMEX> of the
Former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World</ENAMEX> numbs the brain. It makes you feel as if you'd been plucked
out of your own life and plopped down into someone else's repressed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>.
This <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>'s weird habits include, for example, assuming that when you see
something--a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>, a mountain, an empty <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">soda</ENAMEX> can--the appropriate response is
not to decide how you feel about what you see but to think of tautly composed
phrases in which to describe it. The family belongs to the passive-aggressive
school of communication. Its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> hint at what they're thinking and expect
you to read their minds.

            To be fair, this last
neurosis extends beyond <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">McPhee</ENAMEX>. This book may be the grandest embodiment of the
principle that guided <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> through its glory days under
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Shawn</ENAMEX>: that it is the role of good writing to arrange facts artfully
and discreetly, and not much else. Out of self-interest, I'm as nostalgic as
anyone for the era of big word counts and editorial carte blanche. But
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Annals</ENAMEX> is a good antidote. For all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McPhee</ENAMEX>'s expertise at crafting a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">narrative</ENAMEX>, it feels unnecessarily bloated; for all his famous humility, there's
a mild vanity in its fussy perfectionism. Above all, there's a sense of
strain--of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McPhee</ENAMEX> working hard to make all these facts sing. And for what? A
well-curated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> exhibit backed by a few smart CD-ROMs could, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a day</TIMEX>,
drill you in most of the geology <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McPhee</ENAMEX> has to teach. We could get upset about
this, and worry that technology is about to replace fine writing. I say bring
on the CD-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ROMs</ENAMEX>--and free the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> to do something else.

         
      
   
