
   
   
      
         
            Broken Mainspring

            If you're in the market,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Haruki Murakami</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Wind-Up Bird Chronicle</ENAMEX> will teach you how to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>)
kill with a bayonet (thrust deep under ribs, drag in slow, deep circle to
scramble organs); <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) skin a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> alive (slit skin at shoulder, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peel</ENAMEX> slowly down
right <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX>); and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) eliminate a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">zoo</ENAMEX> full of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">carnivores</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">snipers</ENAMEX> per tiger
best). It will steep you in the bizarre lives and roles of 30ish <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toru Okada</ENAMEX>, an
out-of-work law <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clerk</ENAMEX>, bent-tip-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">tailed</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX>, house <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>, toupee
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researcher</ENAMEX>, well dweller, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prostitute</ENAMEX>. It will titillate you with red-hatted
mind <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> and sexy phone calls, oozing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pols</ENAMEX> and hot dreams, ill-omened
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">houses</ENAMEX> and unwaveringly plastic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nutmeg and Cinnamon</ENAMEX>. Hanging
over the overwrought whole are an overcast sky and an elusive "wind-up"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bird</ENAMEX>--so named for its creeeak, creeeak song, which nauseates and dooms
the select few who hear it. Stripped of their powers of volition, they become
"no more than dolls set on tabletops, the springs in their backs wound up
tight, dolls set to move in ways they could not choose, moving in directions
they could not choose, ... most of them died, plunging over the edge of the
table."

            How
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dystopian</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murakami</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>, how sterile and subwayesque. Not for him the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">cherry</ENAMEX>-blossom viewings and golden pavilions of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yukio Mishima</ENAMEX>, the monarchist
who disemboweled himself in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1970</TIMEX>. No nostalgic ramblings, only details that
overrun the canvas and add up to nothing. A best-selling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> in his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murakami</ENAMEX>'s most recent work before <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wind-Up was Underground</ENAMEX> , a
mammoth exploration of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aum Shinrikyo</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cult</ENAMEX>'s sarin gas attacks on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tokyo</ENAMEX>
subway. Away at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Princeton</ENAMEX> when they occurred, he returned to examine <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>'s
fascination with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cult</ENAMEX> and its tubby, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>-blind <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>. Underground
describes a nation bored and isolated by its successes and its failures alike.
Wind-Up fictionalizes that world--but barely, and to less effect.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rootless</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lonely</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toru Okada</ENAMEX> plods across his
strenuously postmodern space. Until, that is, his spaghetti-cooking,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rossini</ENAMEX>-humming contentment is dissolved by the sudden departure of first his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">cat</ENAMEX> and then his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six years</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Noburu Wataya</ENAMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX>) returns about
halfway through the novel; of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kumiko</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, one is less sure. She works at
a health <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>, whose <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">strange hours</TIMEX> screen her infidelities from an
improbably credulous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouse</ENAMEX>. Leaving as if for work <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one morning</TIMEX>, she does not
return. She picks up her dry cleaning <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the following day</TIMEX>, however, and
eventually writes him a letter, in which she recounts earth-shattering orgasms
with other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>: "I'm sorry to have to tell you this, but the fact is that I was
never able to have true sexual pleasure with you."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toru</ENAMEX>'s
life <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">disintegrates</ENAMEX> following <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kumiko</ENAMEX>'s departure. Obsessed with finding her, he
takes off on a cinematic odyssey that collapses time and space. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murakami</ENAMEX> lays
several plot lines and, both consummate miniaturist and committed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pessimist</ENAMEX>,
appears to develop each carefully while keeping the mix unstable. And so the
pressure builds. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Toru</ENAMEX> reaches out to a pair of allegedly clairvoyant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX>
(as it turns out, to little result beyond a few crepuscular couplings that may
or may not be real). He meets a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veteran</ENAMEX> whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wartime</ENAMEX> experiences allow
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murakami</ENAMEX> to play anti-imperialist. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toru</ENAMEX>'s conversations with the lieutenant
yield an enduring image: a dry well, whose dark silences facilitate thought and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force people</ENAMEX> to confront their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">demons</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toru</ENAMEX>'s suburban <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alley</ENAMEX> offers convenient
access to such a well, and into its clichéd dankness he descends ("my body
began to lose its density and weight, ... my mind was dragging my body into its
own territory"). It is the perfect birth <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">canal</ENAMEX>, a magical anti-environment that
both suspends and exaggerates all sensation. For <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murakami</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX>, it conjures
up the excitement and terror, the white hots and the blue colds, of childhood
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">treks</ENAMEX> through a storm <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sewer system</ENAMEX>. For <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toru</ENAMEX>, who is drawn back to it
repeatedly, it is simultaneously <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> and release. It makes him face his
deepest fears (which puddle up in a stigmatic stain on his right cheek), then
allows him osmotic and healing passage to other worlds and narratives.
Mysteriously transported from the well to a mysterious <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Room 208</ENAMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tokyo</ENAMEX>
hotel, he taps into a labyrinth of stories that eventually reconnects him with
humanity.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murakami</ENAMEX>'s fiction before <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wind-Up</ENAMEX> was
less ambitious in scale and makes a compelling case for his return to a smaller
canvas. He is a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>, well read, well traveled, and keen-eyed. All
this makes for good documentary and great short stories: His book about the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cult</ENAMEX> sticks with the conventions of storytelling and delivers emotion,
analysis, and narrative; the many-splendored tales that interpolate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toru</ENAMEX>'s
story find <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murakami</ENAMEX> at his most engaging. Each plot is painstakingly tooled,
generates momentum, and invites you to share.

            But look at the whole, and
Wind-Up confirms the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman Mailer</ENAMEX> principle: The birth of a great
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> is often paralleled by the death of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novelist</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murakami</ENAMEX> lets the
narrative lines, so carefully laid, snap; you're suspended midair, your tender
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">attentions</ENAMEX> scattered to the winds. You gulp, tell yourself you can transcend
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aristotelian</ENAMEX> unities, and would move on if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murakami</ENAMEX> allowed you to. But he
does not. In what is either a belated acknowledgment of your investment--and
his own--or, less likely, a more directly subversive move, he starts reeling in
the lines <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 100</NUMEX> pages from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX>. The obvious is manfully recapped, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bows</ENAMEX> tied in tweet, tidy trills. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cinnamon</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX>, the nameless
veterinarian, and I had a number of unusual things in common--a mark on the
face, a baseball bat, the cry of the wind-up <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bird</ENAMEX>. And then there was the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lieutenant</ENAMEX> who appeared in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cinnamon</ENAMEX>'s story: he reminded me of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lieutenant</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mamiya</ENAMEX> [the war <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veteran</ENAMEX>]." And shortly thereafter, "Everything was intertwined,
with the complexity of a three-dimensional puzzle--a puzzle in which truth was
not necessarily fact and fact not necessarily truth."

            Back in Room <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">208 a few</NUMEX> pages
before the novel's conclusion, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Toru</ENAMEX> encounters a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> on the bed. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ping</ENAMEX> ,
goes the call button in his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>: "I think you are <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kumiko</ENAMEX>. Because then all
kinds of story lines work out." I'm tempted to give <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murakami</ENAMEX> the benefit of the
doubt--to say, even, that his pat machinations force his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> into his crowd
of wound-up dolls (of whom most died, remember, "plunging over the edge of the
table"). But I'll settle for this: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murakami</ENAMEX>'s story ran away with him. Too
little too late, his impulse to tidy resolution testifies more to his
discomfort with an expanded canvas than to his plug-and-socket skills.

         
      
   
