
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cheater</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Poker</ENAMEX>

            About
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two-thirds</NUMEX> of the way into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burn Rate</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Wolff</ENAMEX>'s sardonic tell-all
about his failed attempt to become an Internet multimillionaire, the author
pauses to ask himself a set of questions I had been wanting him to address for
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">150</NUMEX> pages:

            How many fairly grievous
lies had I told? How many moral lapses had I committed? How many ethical
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">breaches</ENAMEX> had I fallen into?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alas</ENAMEX>, it
only sounds like soul-searching. Wolff relishes the many deceits and
indiscretions he commits in his pursuit of Internet riches and, after this
brief hiatus, he redoubles his efforts to hoodwink the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">financier-partners</ENAMEX> he
believes are out to swindle him.

            Burn Rate, currently all the rage in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Silicon Valley</ENAMEX> and on
Wall Street and excerpted in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">June Wired</ENAMEX> to wide acclaim, deserves
our attention for its panoramic treatment of the Internet's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">boom years</TIMEX> and its
pus-ugly picture of the get-rich psyche. But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burn Rate</ENAMEX> will attract the
majority of its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> because its message--The Internet Has Failed
Us--panders to the current consensus. Didn't the last round of Internet initial
public offerings <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX>? Aren't the existing Internet stocks depressed? Isn't the
Internet really about technology and not content? Isn't the Internet like cable
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TV</ENAMEX>--all those Web sites and nothing on?

            The
Burn Rate saga begins in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolff</ENAMEX>, a respected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> and
publishing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entrepreneur</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">his 40s</TIMEX>, attracts the interest of several
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">heavyweight New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5 million</NUMEX> in financing. The money <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> want
to transform his little successes (a Yahoo!-like home page for the Internet
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masses</ENAMEX>--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Your Personal Net"--and the NetGuide</ENAMEX> series of books about
what's on the Internet) into the next Yahoo! As the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> and the
investment <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">banker</ENAMEX> prepare the foundation for an IPO--"There is no valuation.
There's only orchestration," intones the investment <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">banker</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolff</ENAMEX> imagines a
public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> worth <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">several hundred million dollars</NUMEX>. Meanwhile, his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s
"burn rate," the amount it spends in excess of income, soars. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>, many
meetings, industry conventions, threatening phone calls, and transcontinental
flights later, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolff</ENAMEX> flees from his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">creditors</ENAMEX> and the crocodile swamp of deals
and venture capital and legal disputes as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX> overtake his flimsy
concept. He decides he isn't a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">craven CEO</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Netrepreneur</ENAMEX>, or a deal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">maker</ENAMEX>.
He's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> (with this book in him). And the Internet is a big joke.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iowe Burn Rate</ENAMEX> a better synopsis, if
only to excavate the psychopathology that runs through it like a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sewer</ENAMEX>. But
beware of comparisons with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liar</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">Poker</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Lewis</ENAMEX>'
first-person account of his wild ride on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Salomon Bros.</ENAMEX> money-go-round and
his eventual escape. (In fact, beware of the flattering blurb by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burn Rate</ENAMEX> 's dust jacket.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charm</ENAMEX>, not malice, guides <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX>' odyssey
through a business gone similarly bonkers. Listen to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolff</ENAMEX>'s treacherous
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">heartbeat</ENAMEX> as he daydreams on his way to a business meeting with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CMP Media</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">multibillion-dollar</ENAMEX> computer-magazine <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publisher</ENAMEX>: "Would I get rich for being a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">visionary</ENAMEX>? Or would I get rich for being a charlatan?" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CMP</ENAMEX> wants to buy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wolff</ENAMEX>'s
Web sites database and license his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NetGuide</ENAMEX> name for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> about
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alison Anthoine</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolff</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX>, sizes up the deal with the
acumen of a confidence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>. "They know nothing about this. And you know next to
nothing," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthoine</ENAMEX> says. "It does appear, however, that we can sell them the
next to nothing we know for a lot of money."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wolff</ENAMEX>
gloats like a hyena when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CMP</ENAMEX> makes the purchase. "I genuinely believe they
thought that they were buying the Internet from us," he writes. "Just think ...
how many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stupid people</ENAMEX> there are in this world we can take advantage of." To
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolff</ENAMEX>'s all-knowing smirk, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CMP</ENAMEX> pulls the plug on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NetGuide</ENAMEX> concept a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">couple of years later</TIMEX>, after having dropped <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">tens of millions</NUMEX> on it.

            This sort of candor and cold-bloodedness abounds on every
page. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolff</ENAMEX> gratuitously singles out (by name!) <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> as having
"extreme body odor." He calls <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">America Online</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Leonsis</ENAMEX> "a fat <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>,
an ugly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, sweating like crazy." He labels his most dependable source of
investment capital a "wire-thin, almost feminized <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">JFK Jr.</ENAMEX> look-alike" and
quotes the look-alike describing their investment <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">banker</ENAMEX> as "a fat <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fuck</ENAMEX>." Of an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">old</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleague</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolff</ENAMEX> writes, "I admired him at the same time I made fun of him
(behind his back)"; he goes on to dismiss him as "a gay <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sammy Glick</ENAMEX>." He
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ridicules Wired</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founder</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louis Rosetto</ENAMEX> as a "lost soul" who wears
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sneakers</ENAMEX>. (Full disclosure: I'm acquainted with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rosetto</ENAMEX> and the "gay <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sammy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Glick</ENAMEX>.")

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wolff</ENAMEX>
heaps analogous abuse on the Internet industry. "In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cyber business</ENAMEX>, it
seemed that no one ever told the truth. Sometimes it seemed that there was no
truth. It was all bullshit." He calls <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX> "the most dysfunctional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>," adding that "every business AOL had ever tried had failed." The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">moronic Baby Bells</ENAMEX> are <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18 months</TIMEX> behind the curve. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> hasn't a clue.
(More full disclosure: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> publishes 
                  Slate
               .) The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> ? Ready for fleecing when it invests in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">NetGuide</ENAMEX> .
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolff</ENAMEX> admits <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> into his circle of virtue: Former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Warner</ENAMEX> new
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">media</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter Isaacson</ENAMEX>, who has since ascended to the editorship of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Isaacson</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX> was that he understood the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX>'s potential but
was smart enough to leave the new media <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">division</ENAMEX> early.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Delicious dish</ENAMEX>, but watch out for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">aftertaste</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolff</ENAMEX> exploits the human tendency to confuse frankness and cruelty
with truth-telling. And by repeatedly reminding the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> of what a dishonest,
scheming little shit he is, he seeks to inflate his credibility. A real liar
wouldn't tell you that he's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liar</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolff</ENAMEX> does, would he? The wealth of
verbatim quotations--constituting a good <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> of this book--also enhances
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burn Rate</ENAMEX> 's verisimilitude. But should it? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolff</ENAMEX> writes that he jotted
down <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">bits</NUMEX> of dialogue on his legal pads during meetings while others composed
to-do lists. Not to accuse anyone of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Glassism</ENAMEX>, but I'd love to see
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wolff</ENAMEX> post those copious notes on his promotional Web site, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">burnrate</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.

            As
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolff</ENAMEX>'s dreams of undeserved riches fade into a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mirage, Burn Rate</ENAMEX>
becomes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journal</ENAMEX> of a loser. And, like most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">losers</ENAMEX>, he fails to give the
winners their due. No Web startup except for Yahoo! appears to be making much
money, yet scores of insurgent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Excite</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Virtual</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vineyards, Auto</ENAMEX>-by-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">TheStreet</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">eBay</ENAMEX>, to name a few--continue to
massage the medium, attract serious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>, and lay the substructure for the
inevitable: an Internet economy. What's more, these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> believe in their
products--unlike <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolff</ENAMEX>--and back them with serious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX>, who, whatever
their other weaknesses, are fleet-footed and care about their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>. Given
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolff</ENAMEX>'s transparent contempt for his industry, his business <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partners</ENAMEX>, his end
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX>, and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX>--actually, everybody but his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Isaacson</ENAMEX>--it's
a miracle he got as far in the Internet business as he did.

            Has the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Wide Web</ENAMEX>, which only appeared in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>, failed
us? Can any 5-year-old fail us? Compare the breakneck growth of the Web with
that of any new medium of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past 150 years</TIMEX>: the telegraph, the telephone, the
motion picture, radio, television, cable TV, and the VCR. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Blithe investors</ENAMEX> toss
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> at the Web out of the conviction that it will subsume the other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>,
change the face of capitalism, and generate <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billion-dollar</NUMEX> payouts.

            They're right. But consider
yourself fortunate if you've never invested <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a penny</NUMEX> in this market. Any sure
thing attracts too many hackneyed ideas, like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wolff's</ENAMEX>, and too much foolish
money. For all his bluntness, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolff</ENAMEX> never concedes that the product he was
selling--essentially another set of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX> directories--wasn't that appealing.
Nor, judging from this book, was its primary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">salesman</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
