
   
   
      
         
            Long <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Division</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Horwitz</ENAMEX> has done
something remarkable. He has written a book about the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Civil War</ENAMEX> that will
interest not only war <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enthusiasts</ENAMEX> but also <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who find the subject a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vexation</ENAMEX> or a bore. Speaking as one of the latter, I discovered that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Horwitz</ENAMEX>
made me confront my aversion in a way that was both troubling and revealing.
Let me explain.

            I was
born in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southern</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> but raised mainly on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> posts,
curious nonplaces that, even when located in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX>, feel more like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX>
than like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alabama</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgia</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX>. Growing up on an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> post, we
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">brats</ENAMEX> looked at the civilian world with a wary eye, particularly in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX>,
where we were doubly different: not just <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">outsiders</ENAMEX> and transients but also
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goddamn Yankees</ENAMEX>.

            If we went off-post to school, we adjusted to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern</ENAMEX>
folkways, standing at football games for the "national anthem," as "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dixie</ENAMEX>" was
called, even though we knew that our anthem was the one heard at the
parade grounds on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekends</TIMEX>. More important, in those pre-integration <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX>, we
<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">attended lily</ENAMEX>-white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classes</ENAMEX> and witnessed racial barriers that were absent, or
at least being dismantled, back on the forts.

            Tied to
this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jim Crow</ENAMEX> order was a social reality that seemed as peculiar as any I had
experienced overseas. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Years later</TIMEX>, reading <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walker Percy</ENAMEX>'s superb essays on race
and civil rights, I had it spelled out for me: The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX>, at least the white
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South</ENAMEX> before integration, was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> big kinship lodge. And it was precisely
because the public realm was taken to be an extension of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> that white
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Southerners</ENAMEX> took any effort to bring <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> into it as a direct attack on their
most intimate social space.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Idimly</ENAMEX> sensed this whenever, as a boy, I
visited my <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southern</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> I barely knew talked to me--and "did for
me," as they say down there--as though I were their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX>. I was
touched by these kindnesses, but also suspicious: Why were they doing this?
What did I owe them? Beyond the suspicion lay a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Puritan</ENAMEX> sense that this was all
dreadfully wrong.

            That is
why this semi-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Southerner</ENAMEX> does not like to think about the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Civil War</ENAMEX>,
particularly about the way <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southerners</ENAMEX> fetishize the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lost Cause</ENAMEX> business.
It takes him back to memories that lie uneasily at the base of his identity. I
can't help but think that many white <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> share this queasy
ambivalence.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Horwitz</ENAMEX> turns out to be an oddly perfect guide for us
divided <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">souls</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">descendant</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian Jews</ENAMEX>, born and raised in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">North</ENAMEX> (to
the extent that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North</ENAMEX>), he would seem to have little reason for
interest in that war. But this is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, and when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Horwitz</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">great-grandfather</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Poppa Isaac</ENAMEX>, made his way from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">czarist</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> to the East
Side of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, one of his first purchases was a book about the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Civil War</ENAMEX>.
The interest was passed on, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Horwitz</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physician</ENAMEX>, kept his son up
late at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> reading from the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">10-volume Photographic History</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Civil</ENAMEX>
War . By <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> grade, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Horwitz</ENAMEX> fils was completing his own "highly
derivative" history of the war and commencing a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Sistine</ENAMEX>-scale project: a mural
of the war, pro-Rebel in slant, that would soon cover every inch of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">attic wall</ENAMEX>
space.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Horwitz</ENAMEX> soon put aside such
childish things. As a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>, he covered both the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gulf War</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX> and, returning to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">States</ENAMEX>, settled with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">shadow of Virginia</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Blue Ridge Mountains</ENAMEX>. There he lived in tranquil
expectation of their <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">band</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Civil War</ENAMEX> re-enactors
stumbled into their yard in search of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>.

            This
encounter with "hard-core" re-enactors--whose dedication to authenticity
includes camping out under thin blankets and huddling spoon-style to share body
heat--brought <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Horwitz</ENAMEX>'s curiosity about <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Civil War</ENAMEX> mania to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>. Where did it
come from? Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who were thus obsessed were so because, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Horwitz</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">notes</ENAMEX>, "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">roughly half</NUMEX> of modern-day white <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southerners</ENAMEX> descended from
Confederates, and one in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southern</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> of military age died in [it]." But
there was a greater prod to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southern</ENAMEX> memory: defeat. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Losers</ENAMEX> don't forget. Nor
do their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. The only <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southerners</ENAMEX> who want to blot it out are black
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Southerners</ENAMEX>, who wish that all the noise and symbolism would go away.

            
These are generalities, of course. The strength
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Horwitz</ENAMEX>'s book lies in his gift for fleshing them out through precisely
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rendered</ENAMEX> encounters with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southerners</ENAMEX> of all walks and all colors, united only
by the common <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southern</ENAMEX> compulsion to answer a question with a story. Such
meetings, spontaneous and arranged, punctuate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Horwitz</ENAMEX>'s zigzag journey through
the Old Confederacy, with stops at battlefields, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museums</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">redneck bars</ENAMEX>,
gatherings of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sons of Confederate Veterans</ENAMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Afrocentric</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>, and the
living <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> of countless affable <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southerners</ENAMEX>.

            If this
makes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Horwitz</ENAMEX> sound like a journalistic <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sherman</ENAMEX>, he wears his <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yankee</ENAMEX> bias
lightly. "Y'all always do the same," says the white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">60 percent</NUMEX> black
Selma, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ala.</ENAMEX>, at the end of their interview. "Come in here smiling and then go
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> and write a dig at us." Not only does <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Horwitz</ENAMEX> not do this, but he also
understands that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX>'s remark was the real point of the interview--that
and the jocularly aggrieved way in which he made it.

            What comes through repeatedly is not just grievance but
also the pride, vulnerability, and sometimes desperation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who see
their lives and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> predicaments as having been shaped by a cataclysm that
occurred <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than 130 years ago</TIMEX>. There's probably no staler chestnut than the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern</ENAMEX> alibi that it wasn't slavery's defense but honor and loyalty to place
that made most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Confederates</ENAMEX> take up arms to fight the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northern</ENAMEX> "aggressors."
Yet, in the mouths of the white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">townsfolk</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Salisbury</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.C.</ENAMEX>, it sounds
convincing. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Horwitz</ENAMEX> makes us see that the pinched circumstances of their lives
are not so different from the conditions of their ancestors, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dirt</ENAMEX>-poor yeoman
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX> who seldom saw, much less owned, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slave</ENAMEX>. For such <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, then and
now, a sense of place and community is not merely the most sustaining fact of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> life, it is the most dignifying.

            Not much
further into the book we are treated to a more worked-up, intellectualized
version of the alibi--<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> called the "neo-Confederate" ideology. But because
it is put forward by a fatuous <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charleston</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">S.C.</ENAMEX>, college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX>, we hear it
for what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Horwitz</ENAMEX> rightly calls it: "a clever glide around race and slavery,
rather like the slick-tongued defense of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern 'way</ENAMEX> of life' made by
antebellum orators, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">South Carolinians</ENAMEX> in particular." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Horwitz</ENAMEX> doesn't leave it
there. He's neither immune to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX>'s charm nor untroubled by what the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> says about the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern</ENAMEX> agenda: "a culture war in which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yankees</ENAMEX>
imposed their imperialist and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">capitalist</ENAMEX> will on the agrarian <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX>, just as
they had done to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scots</ENAMEX>."

            
Many moments in the book are indelible. There's
nothing but tragedy in the trial of a young black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who has killed a white
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> for driving on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Luther King Jr.</ENAMEX>'s birthday <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekend</TIMEX> with a Confederate
flag flying on his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX>, an incident that has thoroughly riven the once fairly
harmonious <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guthrie</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ky.</ENAMEX> Almost as unsettling is the conversation
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Horwitz</ENAMEX> has with the bright black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who founded an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Afrocentric</ENAMEX> alternative
school in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Selma</ENAMEX>, a conversation that soon breaks down in a venomous exchange
over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louis Farrakhan</ENAMEX>. "Don't tell us who our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> should be!" she snaps.

            Poking around the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Civil War</ENAMEX>
can lead both to such impasses and to bleak comedy. What more need be said
about the name given to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Selma</ENAMEX>'s all-black housing project, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nathan B.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forrest Homes</ENAMEX>, than what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Horwitz</ENAMEX> dryly observes: "an odd choice, given
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forrest</ENAMEX>'s notoriety as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slave trader</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Imperial Wizard</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KKK</ENAMEX>"?

            This is outstanding
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">journalism</ENAMEX>, artfully constructed and unfailingly vivid, as good a rendering as
I've seen of the mysterious pull at the heart of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> identity. Being
fascinated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Civil War</ENAMEX> is central to what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Penn Warren</ENAMEX> called "the
very ritual of being <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX>." If so, there may be no more fitting conclusion
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">than Horwitz</ENAMEX>'s tentative insight into his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">great-grandfather</ENAMEX>'s attraction:
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Poppa Isaac</ENAMEX> came from learned, rabbinical stock. Maybe he sensed that the
Civil <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">War</ENAMEX> was an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> Talmud that would unlock the secrets of his adopted
land and make him feel a part of it."

         
      
   
