
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">German Eye</ENAMEX>

            What makes a photograph
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">recognizably German</ENAMEX>? You'd think that photography, the most transparent of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">arts</ENAMEX>, would defy those pesky national stereotypes. It would stand to reason
that a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">eye</ENAMEX> and an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Egyptian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">eye</ENAMEX> and an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">eye</ENAMEX> and a Micronesian eye
would all be equally naked behind the lens. For the longest time, photography
didn't have enough of a history to promote any fixed notions of what a picture
should be or should show. But as you flip through the present volume, the
aggregate mass of images does look "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX>"--at least according to some
received notion of what that is. There's a precision, a prevailing cleanliness,
a crispness of focus, a strong use of light and shadow. The pictures tend not
to be pale, fluffy, indecisive or, for that matter, funky, gonzo, over the
top.

            But then,
when you go back and look systematically, it seems that the most "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX>" of
these images derive from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> period, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Weimar Republic</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1920s</TIMEX> and very
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early '30s</TIMEX>, and that most of them were made by left-wing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">modernists</ENAMEX>, many of
whom fled the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> came to power and not a few of whom were
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jewish</ENAMEX>. Take the stark cover image, for example, of crewmen repairing the Graf
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zeppelin</ENAMEX> in-flight over the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Atlantic</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1934</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> are silhouetted in a
vertical stack as they pull <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> lines across the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dirigible</ENAMEX>'s silvery skin. The
image is forceful and brooding, celebrates heroic labor, elides the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personalities</ENAMEX> of its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX>--and it was taken by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alfred Eisenstaedt</ENAMEX>, who was
soon to remove himself and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">talent</ENAMEX> to the safety of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> and
Life <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> photography took its time getting started. As one of
the essayists notes, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> for various reasons failed to produce its <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Nadar</ENAMEX> or
its <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew Brady</ENAMEX>. Few of the images herein predate <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the turn of the century</TIMEX> by
much. Crystalline architectural views of the sort that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nègre</ENAMEX> was making in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1850s</TIMEX> apparently did not get made in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">another 30</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. The most striking of the early works in the book are overwhelmingly
imitative of the style of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> pictorialists. The only things that look
distinctive at first are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Baron</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">von Gloeden</ENAMEX>'s and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilhelm Plüschow</ENAMEX>'s pedophilic
tableaux of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youths</ENAMEX> decked out in laurel wreaths.

            So <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> photography really
does seem to have begun where one might have thought it did, with the great
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">catalogers</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karl Blossfeldt</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1865-1932</TIMEX>) remains unrivaled for his close-up
depictions of the architectural forms of plant life. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">August Sander</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1876-1964</TIMEX>)
embarked on a study of human <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">types</ENAMEX> that was so evenhanded, unprejudiced, and
unflinching that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazis</ENAMEX> burned his books. And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albert Renger</ENAMEX>-Patzsch
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1897-1966</TIMEX>), drunk on the beauty of the visual world, recorded <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> thing after
another--<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX>, faces, machinery, and on and on, in foursquare
simplicity. His work is more influential <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> than ever; recent German
documentarians of a cataloging persuasion, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bernd</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hilla Becher</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Struth</ENAMEX>, are his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lineal descendants</ENAMEX>.

            Modernism
in photography was less a national than an international phenomenon, but the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> work was perhaps the most striking. Very loosely speaking, photographic
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">modernism</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">its grandest period</TIMEX> consisted of finding and framing the most
dramatic designs to be found in the accidental accretion of the world. László
Moholy-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nagy</ENAMEX> essentially invented the diagonal, for instance, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Umbo</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Otto</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Umbehr</ENAMEX>) shares credit with his <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleague</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aleksandr Rodchenko</ENAMEX> for
discovering the graphic power of the shadow as seen from a perpendicular
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">perspective</ENAMEX>. A lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> all over the world stumbled pretty much
simultaneously upon the smokestack, the double exposure, the multiple <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shadow</ENAMEX>,
the wall of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX>, etc.--although <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Munkàcsi</ENAMEX> deserves special mention for
his work on the last, and this book doesn't even reproduce my favorite picture
by him, a large scattering of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">schoolchildren</ENAMEX> lying on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">grass</ENAMEX>, seen from
above and looking like so many clothespins.

            
Of course, the wall of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX> was quickly
adapted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">modernists</ENAMEX>' natural <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Socialists</ENAMEX>. In place
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Munkàcsi</ENAMEX>'s wonderfully motley and individuated agglomerations, party
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">photographer Max Ehlert</ENAMEX> devised solid blocks of anonymous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">party</ENAMEX>-rally heads, or
a whole sheet of stiff-arm saluters blurred into human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coleslaw</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Nazi</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">photography</ENAMEX> was correspondence-school modernism, only scarier. The strangest
thing about it is how unseductive any of it seems as propaganda--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hugo Erfurth</ENAMEX>'s
portrait of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Capt.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hauffe</ENAMEX> is the quintessential depiction of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frankenstein</ENAMEX>, with the bolts sticking out of his helmet--but then what isn't
mystifying about that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX>'s allure?

            After the war things
happened in dribs and drabs. This collection does contain some staggering
portrait studies from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 1940s</TIMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karl Heinz Mai</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who seem to
have been emptied of everything but their outlines--some of them were in fact
taken as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ID</ENAMEX>-card photos. But otherwise there is some pleasant geometry, some
mostly unremarkable portraits, some jazzy fashion shots that culminate in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helmut Newton</ENAMEX>'s high-gloss simulated sadism. Most of the work from the 1950s
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">'60s</ENAMEX> has the slightly desperate air of much continental art from that time,
unsure whether to please or to shock, failing to remember how to do either one,
and seeming to evaporate as <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> looks at it.

            The book ends abruptly just
as things are picking up: with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bechers</ENAMEX>' zoological catalogs of workaday
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>, and some lively conceptual sequences by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johannes Brus</ENAMEX> and Sigmar
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Polke</ENAMEX>. Thus, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> interesting period in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> photography--the last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>--is almost completely omitted. Such is the hazard of arbitrary date
limits. But were it not for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1920s</TIMEX>, and for the historical value of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">East German</ENAMEX> documents, this collection might rival Ruritarian
Photographs of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Century</ENAMEX> , with its obligatory nods to every passing wrinkle
of fashion devised elsewhere, its dull portraits of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">statesmen</ENAMEX> unknown outside
the fatherland, its honorable but unexceptional petits maîtres . This,
from a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> which invented the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leica</ENAMEX>, comes as something of a surprise. But
since so many of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>'s great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">photographers</ENAMEX> died in exile--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Munkàcsi</ENAMEX>,
Eisenstaedt, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moholy-Nagy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lotte Jacobi</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herbert Bayer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Gidal</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Felix H.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Man</ENAMEX>--not to mention in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Auschwitz</ENAMEX> (the pioneering <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">photojournalist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erich Salomon</ENAMEX>,
for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>), we know whom to blame.

         
      
   
