
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sad Sack Superman</ENAMEX>

            Like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hermann Hesse</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steppenwolf</ENAMEX> and anything by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Antonin Artaud</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frederick Exley</ENAMEX>'s A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Fan</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Notes</ENAMEX> is one of those books that gets pushed on you by crazy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. I was
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Munich</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 1980s</TIMEX>, widening my horizons on a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Eurailpass</ENAMEX>, when it was
pushed on me. An aging <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">beatnik</ENAMEX> with a ragged knapsack plunked down next to me
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Haufbrauhaus</ENAMEX> and started raving about the "book of books." He brought
out a tattered paperback and thrust it at me, insisting that the volume was too
important not to be passed on. When I asked the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> what A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Fan</ENAMEX>'s Notes
was about, I expected an answer profound and mystical; instead, he fixed his
bright eyes on me and said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Gifford</ENAMEX>. It's all about this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who loves
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Gifford</ENAMEX>."

            
               A
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Fan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Notes</ENAMEX> , which is being canonized <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this month</TIMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Modern Library</ENAMEX>
edition and whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> is the subject of a new biography by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
Post <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Yardley</ENAMEX>, is actually more of a memoir than a novel,
and is only incidentally about the former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Giants</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">halfback</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gifford</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">First</NUMEX> published in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1968</TIMEX>, the book has been kept alive by zealous
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> who feel compelled to promote it, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amway</ENAMEX>-style, to everyone they meet.
Read a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapter</ENAMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> and you'll know why. Written by a self-pitying autodidact
for consumption by self-pitying autodidacts, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A Fan</ENAMEX>'s Notes divides the
world into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camps</ENAMEX>: tortured, bewildered <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">misfits</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Exleys</ENAMEX>) and serene,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fair</ENAMEX>-haired conformists (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Giffords</ENAMEX>). In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Exley</ENAMEX> implies--indeed, he
shouts it--a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> is either a suffering <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX> or a cheerful drone.

            I'm in pain, you're in pain. It's the classic invitation of
the memoirist, the ploy that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams reader</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> against the world, and
it's also the classic lament of the barroom, which is where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Exley</ENAMEX>'s painful
story opens. While watching a televised <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Giants</ENAMEX> game, indulging his overweening
passion for <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX>, he collapses from alcoholic exhaustion. The breakdown
occasions a jigsaw of memories: of an upstate <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boyhood</ENAMEX> dominated by a
local-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero dad</ENAMEX>; of doomed attempts to make it in the straight world of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX> advertising; of romantic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humiliations</ENAMEX> at the hands of perky
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">centerfold blondes</ENAMEX>; and, finally, of dreamlike interludes in sadistic mental
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX>.

            Where have
all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">anti-heroes</ENAMEX> gone? <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Literary dementia</ENAMEX> seems dated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX>, but there was a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> when a month in the funny <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farm</ENAMEX> was as <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">de rigueur</TIMEX> for budding
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> as an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MFA</ENAMEX> is now. To be sent away was a badge of honor, to undergo
electroshock a glorious martyrdom. "Was I, too, insane?" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Exley</ENAMEX> asks when he's
committed. "It was a difficult admission to make, but I am glad that I made it;
later I came to believe that this admission about oneself may be the only
redemption in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>." This notion was once a staple of big novels (see
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Catch-22</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">One Flew Over the Cuckoo's Nest</ENAMEX> ), and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Exley</ENAMEX> plays it
for all it is worth, ennobling himself through <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">nausea</ENAMEX>. A rosy-cheeked suburban
family seated next to him at a <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football game</ENAMEX> makes him want to "cut my
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">jugular</ENAMEX>." When he falls in love with a beautiful <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Midwestern</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>, her "milk
flecked with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">butter</ENAMEX>" complexion renders him impotent.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Exley</ENAMEX> is so over-rich in his descriptions of
all things wholesome and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX> that his disgust is infectious. His prose is
moist with lyrical revulsion. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Autumn days</TIMEX> are blinding in their goldenness,
pretty girls suffocating in their softness, young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> crucifying in
their crispness. Exley, as sensitive as a rotten tooth, can bear the world in
the smallest doses only, and any extended period of consciousness forces him
back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX>. In <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> chapter, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Journey</ENAMEX> on a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davenport</ENAMEX>," he
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tucks</ENAMEX> himself in on his mother's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couch</ENAMEX> and goes on a sort of existential
sit-down strike. "In a land where movement is virtue, where the echo of heels
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">clicking</ENAMEX> rapidly on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pavement</ENAMEX> is inordinately blest, it is a grand, defiant, and
edifying gesture to lie down for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six months</TIMEX>."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Exley</ENAMEX>'s
self-loathing is really self-love. His is an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Olympian</ENAMEX> degradation. His voice on
the page is a rummy baritone, fat and resonant but capable of a cruel
exactitude, as when he describes a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX>'s melting love for him. "[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX>]here
came a point when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bunny</ENAMEX> had a kind of terrifyingly loose and constant
moistness, the kind of totally loose submission <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> detects in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> he has
impregnated, the moist eyes, the warm moist hands, the loose moist breasts
beneath the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">cotton blouse</ENAMEX>." At other times <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Exley</ENAMEX>'s smoky eloquence turns blowsy
and verbose. "Thus it was that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the days</TIMEX> of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX> flew by like violently
clashing confetti." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Exley</ENAMEX> writes, in short, like what he was: a middle-aged,
unpublished <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novelist</ENAMEX> tuning up to write his magnum opus just as soon as
he finishes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> more drink.

            The amazing thing is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Exley</ENAMEX>'s postponement of his great
work inspired a great work about postponement, a portrait of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">procrastinator</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drunken</ENAMEX> bore of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">A Fan's Notes</ENAMEX> is never boring. He's
vibrant with resentment, alive with failure, a sad sack superman. When he gazes
up from his stool at fleet <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Gifford</ENAMEX> catching a touchdown pass, it's a
transporting thrill, a brief ascension. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Exley</ENAMEX> found consolations in his sloth,
among them an awe of physical transcendence. His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">talent</ENAMEX> for disgust and mockery
was saved by a paradoxical gift for praise.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Exley</ENAMEX>'s
life of splendid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">indigence</ENAMEX> didn't change when his book met with wide acclaim.
According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Yardley</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Misfit , Exley</ENAMEX> didn't become rich, just
somewhat famous, though this was enough to turn his alienation into an act, a
tiresome self-caricature. From the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Greenwich Village</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lion</ENAMEX>'s Head <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pub</ENAMEX>,
where he reigned as a sort of rumpled deadbeat <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buddha</ENAMEX>, he attracted a circle of
seedy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">admirers</ENAMEX> who kept him in cold <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX> and pocket change in return for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">recycled</ENAMEX>, embellished anecdotes concerning his hard-luck youth and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> of
wandering. He hectored <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publishers</ENAMEX> for money, repaid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s love
for him with cold neglect, and followed up on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">A Fan's Notes</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sequels</ENAMEX>, neither of which the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> deemed interesting. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yardley</ENAMEX>'s
affectionate yet dubious portrait of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> he knew only through rambling
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">late-night</TIMEX> phone calls, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Exley</ENAMEX> was a classic <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-hit wonder, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> who never
overcame his breakthrough.

            
The wonder, of course, is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Exley</ENAMEX> broke
through at all. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yardley</ENAMEX>'s book does little to solve the mystery of how a man
with no apparent self-discipline, minimal formal training, and colossally
self-destructive habits managed to write a contemporary classic on his first go
round. To make the job of reconstruction harder, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Exley</ENAMEX> wrote few letters,
rarely lived long at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> address, and wasn't given to intimate conversation.
When he died of a stroke in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> (too early to see his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adored</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Gifford</ENAMEX>
dragged from an athletic state of grace into the oily tabloid muck), he left
behind no significant paper trail other than the memoirs that made his name.
Yardley hunts in their margins for clues to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Exley</ENAMEX>'s inner life, with modest
results. He concludes, on the basis of a few short passages, that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Exley</ENAMEX> was
strangely obsessed with oral sex. On even less evidence he speculates that
Exley may have had homosexual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leanings</ENAMEX>, to which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> may feel entitled to
ask: Doesn't everyone?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yardley</ENAMEX>'s conclusions don't
add up to much in any conventional biographical sense, and he admits as much in
his prologue: "[<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Exley</ENAMEX>] lived on another planet, if not in another universe."
Still, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yardley</ENAMEX>'s book has value as a study of just how small and brief and
enigmatic certain <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>' lives can be once you've subtracted their work from
the equation. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Exley</ENAMEX> put all he had into his books, and what he had, besides his
talent, was shockingly little: a troubled heart, a bottle, an affection for the
home <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX>, and a cacophony of chemical imbalances. It's no wonder that crazy
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> love him: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Exley</ENAMEX> did more with less than any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> I can think of. His
failure will endure.

         
      
   
