
   
   
      
         
            We Do Understand

            "This is not another book
about civility," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deborah Tannen</ENAMEX> promises in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> sentence of The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Argument Culture</ENAMEX> . "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Civility</ENAMEX>," she explains, suggests a "veneer of
politeness spread thin over human relations like a layer of marmalade over
toast." Instead, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tannen</ENAMEX> has written something less: a book about other books
about civility. Quoting from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> media <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard Kurtz</ENAMEX>,
political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Sabato</ENAMEX>, and others who have studied the rise of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">belligerence</ENAMEX> in politics, journalism, and law, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tannen</ENAMEX> spreads their insights
thin over all human relations, painting a general theory of discord. The whole
is less perceptive than its parts and more pernicious.

            In her
previous books-- That's Not What I Meant! (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX>), You Just Don't
Understand (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>), and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Talking From</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9 to 5</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>)--<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tannen</ENAMEX> carved out
a niche as the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s pre-eminent intergender <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">translator</ENAMEX> and couples
the comparative study of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">male</ENAMEX> and female conversational patterns from a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">linguistic</ENAMEX> subdiscipline into a self-help movement. Until recently, though,
Tannen confined her analysis to conversations among dysfunctional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>.
(For an illustration, click .) But in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Argument Culture</ENAMEX> , she takes
her movement <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> step further, peddling the elixir of mutual understanding as a
remedy for the whole damned dysfunctional <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. This is necessary, she
argues, because "contentious public discourse" not only <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">poisons</ENAMEX> the political
atmosphere, it also risks infecting our most intimate relationships.

            Tannen, like some grandmotherly <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">creature</ENAMEX> from an Aesop
fable, admonishes us to recognize what is good in the work of others, and it is
only fair to extend her the same courtesy. Here's what's worth gleaning from
her book:

            Don't just quarrel; listen
and learn.

            Don't nit-pick other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s
ideas; build your own.

            Don't argue for the sake of
arguing.

            Truth and courage often lie
in the middle, not the extremes.

            Many issues are
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">multisided</ENAMEX>.

            Focus on the substance of
debates, not on strategy, theater, or the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX>' personal flaws.

            Don't fight over small
issues.

            Don't obstruct good ideas
just so you can win.

            If you
portray everything as a scandal, no one will care when something really is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">scandalous</ENAMEX>.

            
All this is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sage</ENAMEX> advice--for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couples</ENAMEX>, for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>, for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bosses</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>, maybe even for book <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX>. But when she
applies her precepts to our great national conversation, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tannen</ENAMEX> gets confused.
She conflates belligerence, divisiveness, polarization, titillation, jealousy,
incivility, aloofness, ruthlessness, cruelty, savagery, contempt, glibness,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cynicism</ENAMEX>, anomie, partisanship, obstructionism, and gridlock. She makes
culprits out of answering machines, electronic mail, campaign money,
malpractice litigation, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMOs</ENAMEX>, corporate takeovers, and the demise of house
calls by the family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX>.

            "When
there is a need to make others wrong," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tannen</ENAMEX> argues, "the temptation is great
to oversimplify" and to "seize upon the weakest examples, ignore facts that
support your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponent</ENAMEX>'s views, and focus only on those that support yours." In
her need to make the "argument culture" wrong, she succumbs to these
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">temptations</ENAMEX>. She blames the mainstream <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX>, not just the paparazzi ,
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">torturing Princess</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX> and driving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Adm.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Boorda</ENAMEX> to suicide. She
compares to the propaganda of "totalitarian <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>" (because falsehoods are
spread) and to the dehumanization involved in "ethnically motivated assaults"
(because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> hound <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>). She blames communications technology for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">obscene</ENAMEX> and threatening phone calls made by former university <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Berendzen</ENAMEX> and former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sol Wachtler</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tannen</ENAMEX>'s main mistake is failing to appreciate the
difference between <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> distinct social spheres: the sphere of snuggle and the
sphere of struggle. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>--say, your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouse</ENAMEX> or your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>--you should
snuggle with. Others--say, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX>--you shouldn't. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tannen</ENAMEX>'s antagonism
toward antagonism makes sense in the former case but not in the latter. Among
her illustrations of belligerence are <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Safire</ENAMEX>'s "kick 'em when they're
up" philosophy of journalism and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>'s use of war metaphors to describe
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Greenspan</ENAMEX>'s policies against inflation. To which one might sensibly reply:
Good for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Safire</ENAMEX>--and for us. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Reserve</ENAMEX>'s war on
inflation and the press corps' scrutiny of powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> safeguard the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. Some things are worth fighting for, and some things are worth
fighting.

            Vigilance
and combat are particularly essential to law enforcement and foreign policy,
which must deal with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thugs</ENAMEX> and tyrants, not thoughtless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husbands</ENAMEX>. Tannen
laments that cops and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> have been "trained to overcome their resistance
to kill" by trying "not to think of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> as human beings." She
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">neglects</ENAMEX> to mention that our safety depends on the ability of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> to
kill their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adversaries</ENAMEX>. Comparing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tannen</ENAMEX> focuses
strictly on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX>' social experience. In <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX>, she observes,
they trained, served, and went home together. "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>, in contrast, was a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'lonely</ENAMEX> war' of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> assigned to constantly shifting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year-long</TIMEX>
tours of duty." She ignores the more important difference: In <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX>,
they were fighting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tannen</ENAMEX> doesn't trust in the power of good
argumentation to keep society honest, much less correct itself, because she
rather shockingly insists "" that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> can distinguish lies from the truth.
Nor does she trust our competence to manage unfettered communication: "E-mail
makes it too easy to forward messages, too easy to reply before your temper
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cools</ENAMEX>, too easy to broadcast messages to large numbers of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> without
thinking about how every sentence will strike every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipient</ENAMEX>." Lexis-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nexis</ENAMEX> is
an equally unwelcome troublemaker: "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Technology</ENAMEX> also exacerbates the culture of
critique by making it much easier for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> to ferret out
inconsistencies in a public <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s statements over time."

            Given
this oddly paternalistic (or maternalistic) diagnosis, it's not surprising that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tannen</ENAMEX> should wish to cover our ears, filtering out strife, deception, and
debate. She assures us that all reasonable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> can agree that disseminating
birth control and sex education is the best way to reduce the abortion rate;
that stiff sentences for small <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offenses</ENAMEX> don't reduce drug abuse; that
global warming is producing "disastrous consequences." Partial-birth abortion
is "surely not" a "very important" issue, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> should not have let the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> "politics of obstruction" defeat <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s health care
proposal in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>, given the "broad bipartisan and public consensus that it was
desperately needed." The "view of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enemy</ENAMEX>" isn't worth
debating; it's just "another troubling aspect of the argument culture." Indeed,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tannen</ENAMEX> embraces a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleague</ENAMEX>'s claim that "right-wing talk radio" deploys
phrases "similar to verbal manipulations employed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">propagandists</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">era</ENAMEX>."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tannen</ENAMEX> finds it particularly unseemly that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> and
independent counsels treat the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s ultimate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> figure with such
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">irreverence</ENAMEX>. She complains that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> radio address "is followed
immediately by a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> response," which "weakens the public's ability to
see <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>." A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>'s skeptical question to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> "broke the
spell" of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruth Bader Ginsburg</ENAMEX>'s remarks upon being nominated to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme</ENAMEX>
Court, thereby injuring <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>' "sense of connection" to "our judicial
system." The investigation of former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agriculture</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Espy</ENAMEX> was
excessive, the campaign against former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Surgeon General Joycelyn Elders</ENAMEX> was
"cruelly unfair," and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitewater</ENAMEX> investigation--led by "a prominent
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> known for his animosity toward the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>"--is, in the words of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gene Lyons</ENAMEX>, "the result of the nastiest and most successful
political 'dirty tricks' campaign in recent <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> history." Is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tannen</ENAMEX> a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> apologist? She rules that criticism out of bounds. "The very fact that
defending our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s elected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> makes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suspect</ENAMEX>--an 'apologist'--is in
itself evidence of the culture of critique," she writes.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">First Amendment</ENAMEX>, in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tannen</ENAMEX>'s view, has often become "a pretext to justify the airing of just those
views that make for the most entertaining fights." As an alternative, she
offers <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">authoritarianism</ENAMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Disputation</ENAMEX> was rejected in ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> as
'incompatible with the decorum and harmony cultivated by the true <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sage</ENAMEX>.' "
Similarly, "the minimal human <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> is not the individual but the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX>." Instead of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> practice of having <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX> debate policy
questions on TV news programs, she suggests a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> format, which "typically
features a single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guest</ENAMEX>." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> to learn how she puts this into practice.)

            Tannen
even wants to protect us from the possibility of unpleasant confrontations in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courtroom</ENAMEX>. "The purpose of most cross-examinations" is "not to establish
facts but to discredit the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX>," she asserts, as though the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> objectives
were unrelated. Thus, "the adversary system ... is inhumane to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cross</ENAMEX>-examination." She simply assumes the very thing the trial is supposed to
prove and what cross-examination might disprove (if this is, in fact, the point
of the trial): that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX>. Conversely, she assumes
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defendant</ENAMEX> cannot be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX>. While objecting to cross-examination of
alleged rape <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> because "it is easy to distort events so that a rape can
appear to be consensual sex," she ignores the reverse implication--that it is
easy to make consensual sex look like rape. She complains that when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anita Hill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">accused Clarence Thomas</ENAMEX> of sexual harassment, "Framing these hearings as a
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-sides dispute between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX> allowed the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> to focus their
investigation on cross-examining <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX> rather than seeking other sorts of
evidence." Did the dispute not have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sides</ENAMEX>? Should <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hill</ENAMEX> not have been
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cross</ENAMEX>-examined?

            Instead of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> system, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tannen</ENAMEX> proposes
consideration of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">systems</ENAMEX>. Under <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> law, after
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Princess</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>'s death:

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">photographers</ENAMEX> were
held for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two days</TIMEX> without charges being filed and without being allowed to
confer with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>. ... The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> do most of the questioning; though lawyers
can also ask questions, they cannot cross-examine <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX>. Guilt ... need not
be established 'beyond a reasonable doubt' but simply by ... the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>'s
intimate belief, or deeply held sense, of what happened.

            Likewise,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tannen</ENAMEX> recalls the trial of a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who had denied the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defendant</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> interrogated concentration camp <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">survivors</ENAMEX>, asking whether
they had seen their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> gassed. The adversarial system permitted such
questions to be asked and answered--admittedly a vexatious experience for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">survivors</ENAMEX> but one that does entail an airing of the facts of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX>.
Tannen, however, treats it only as a display of the "cruelty of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cross</ENAMEX>-examination." She raises no objection to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX> hate-speech ban
under which the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defendant</ENAMEX> was prosecuted. Would <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tannen</ENAMEX> argue that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> should adopt such a law, along with, say, a ban on the cross-examination
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">accusers</ENAMEX>? If so, she'd be wrong. But hey, so far, it's still a free
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>.

            
               If you missed the links
within the review, click to read: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) an illustration of ; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tannen</ENAMEX>'s that
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> journalism is just like propaganda from totalitarian regimes, plus
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Saletan</ENAMEX>'s disclosure that "several of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">propagandists</ENAMEX> now infest
Slate "; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) the for her contention that there is no evidence that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> can distinguish lies from truth; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4</ENAMEX>) and an example of how <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tannen</ENAMEX> from a
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-guest format on TV and radio talk shows.
            

         
      
   
