
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Folk Jews</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bernard Malamud</ENAMEX> was a writer
with a real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX> for evoking the cosmic and the transcendent; but reading his
Complete <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Stories</ENAMEX> makes me think that transcendence has its limits.
Malamud was born in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brooklyn</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1914</TIMEX> (and died in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX>), and he grew up in the
kind of immigrant environment in which little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, because they are the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">native</ENAMEX>-born <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of a foreign-born neighborhood, are obliged to shield their
vulnerable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elders</ENAMEX> from the contempt of the outside world. It was a background,
as I imagine it, that led naturally to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Malamudian insight</ENAMEX> that visible life
is a veil, behind which can be glimpsed, by means of sympathetic insight, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vaster</ENAMEX> and more beautiful reality.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroes</ENAMEX> of his early stories, from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1940s and '50s</TIMEX>, tend to be poor,
inarticulate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shopkeepers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">tailors</ENAMEX>, grocers, shoemakers,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">census</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">takers</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malamud</ENAMEX> almost always identified his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> by profession,
in a bow to the proletarianism of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '30s</TIMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> mostly, whose rough
outer appearances suddenly fall away to reveal inner <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">souls</ENAMEX> of the purest
lyrical passion. Or else he writes about strange, grief-stricken, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lonely souls</ENAMEX>,
perhaps <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>-mad, who seem to have been picked up like leaves by some
inexplicable wind and blown around the world until they attach themselves
randomly to the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">unlucky person</ENAMEX> who comes their way. Sometimes the author
himself seems to float upward on a gust of wind, into the airy zones of fable,
which seem to have been his instinctive <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>.

            In "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Jewbird</ENAMEX>," a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">melancholy black bird</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schwartz</ENAMEX>
lands on the balcony of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and insists on being taken care of--a
sad nuisance of a talking bird, fleeing God knows what tragedies (the bird
says, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gevalt</ENAMEX> , a pogrom!" and complains about "anti-Semeets"--to which
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> replies, "What kind of anti-Semites bother a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bird</ENAMEX>?").
A "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Talking Horse</ENAMEX>," in the story of that name, turns out to be a half-man or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">centaur</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abramovitz</ENAMEX>, cruelly disguised as an <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">authentic horse</ENAMEX> and forced to
entertain circus <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audiences</ENAMEX> with pathetic jokes. The fabulist images are
wonderful and mysterious precisely because, in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malamud</ENAMEX>'s hands, they seem
perfectly believable, an effortless demonstration that the grotesqueries of
workaday existence are merely masks.

            He
sketches his stories usually with a few bold colors and fewer details, as in a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Raphael Soyer</ENAMEX> painting. His language is notable mostly for the
oniony taste of <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Yiddish</ENAMEX>, when it is appropriate: "Who comes on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> to
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> that he has <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX>, to spoil him his supper<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>" But you come away from
these colors and tastes with the feeling that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jewishness</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Malamud</ENAMEX> is more
than ethnic, that the weird little events in his tales correspond to unseen
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">doings</ENAMEX> in the cosmos of an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Old World</ENAMEX> folk-Judaism. In one of his later stories,
"The Silver Crown" from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1972</TIMEX>, a high school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> visits a raggedy
wonder-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rabbi</ENAMEX> in the rundown <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bronx</ENAMEX> who builds a miracle crown for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">nearly $1,000</NUMEX>.
And though the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">schoolteacher</ENAMEX> concludes that the wonder-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rabbi</ENAMEX> is a con <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>,
we ourselves, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>, are not so sure. The talking <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jewbirds</ENAMEX> and centaurs,
the wonder-rabbis and the magic silver crowns--all seem to hint at larger,
transcendent truths.

            
But where can these larger truths be found?
Sometimes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malamud</ENAMEX> pointed to art, especially to painting and sculpture, which
he elevated into an ideal. He devoted a number of his later stories to an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fidelman</ENAMEX> who goes to live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>, which move occasions all kinds
of theorizing about art and its meaning. But the effect is gassy:

            "Form may be and often is
the content of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Art</ENAMEX>."

            "You don't say."

            "I do indeed."

            Other times, he looked to
love and tried to put a little flesh on his spiritual creations, in an effort
to endow his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poor</ENAMEX>, suffering <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least a few</NUMEX> shreds of a romantic
life.

            But in
these stories, especially the later ones, he seems to have been unable to get
beyond his own commonplace fantasies about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prostitutes</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1960s</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">miniskirts</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fidelman</ENAMEX> takes up with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prostitute</ENAMEX> in "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Pimp's Revenge</ENAMEX>," a student confesses
her hooker past in "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Choice of Profession</ENAMEX>," a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> trails after his
streetwalker <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> in "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">God's Wrath</ENAMEX>," a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> imagines his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX> as a
"semi-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prostitute</ENAMEX>" in the story "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">In Retirement"</ENAMEX>--it gets to be a little much.
The writing leers, for want of any better way to conjure a sexual attraction.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Malamud</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janna Malamud Smith</ENAMEX>, has just now brought out a book called
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Private Matters</ENAMEX>: In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense of the Personal Life</ENAMEX> , in which she says
that, coming across a sexual scene in one of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s novels, she put the
book down in embarrassment, out of daughterly modesty. But even a nondaughter
could feel that way. I reached a point in reading <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Complete Stories</ENAMEX>
where the arrival of a new young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> in any given story made me roll my
eyes--not because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Malamud</ENAMEX>'s masculine reveries are particularly scandalous, but
because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reveries</ENAMEX> seem scandalously inadequate to the cosmic hintings of his
other stories.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of his first stories of love, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The First Seven Years</ENAMEX>,"
from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Partisan Review</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1950</TIMEX>, strikes me as nearly perfect, though. A
poor immigrant <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jew</ENAMEX> works as an assistant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shoemaker</ENAMEX>, patiently waiting for the
master <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shoemaker</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> to grow old enough to marry. The assistant
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">shoemaker</ENAMEX> is another of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Malamud</ENAMEX>'s weirdly insistent, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lonely souls</ENAMEX>--impelled,
who knows why, to devote himself to a hopeless love; still wincing from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">horrors of Europe</ENAMEX>, which he has not entirely escaped; inarticulate, yet
bursting with passion, if only his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX>, the master <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shoemaker</ENAMEX>, will deign to
listen.

            "You are crazy," the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX>
says to him about his love for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>. "She will never marry a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> so old and
ugly like you." But she will, of course, which is going to be too bad. The
story is moving. It arouses wonder. Biblical overtones--the tale of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Laban</ENAMEX>--bubble up from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Malamud</ENAMEX>'s simplicity. In his introduction, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Giroux</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Malamud</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>, quotes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cynthia Ozick</ENAMEX>, who said of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Malamud</ENAMEX>: "Is he an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX>? Of course." Which is right--sometimes.

            It was inevitable that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Malamud</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> would bring out a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Complete Stories</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Completeness</ENAMEX> is not
always a virtue, though. The lesser stories in the Complete edition cast
a wrong light on the greater ones. Malamud, the true <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX> Master, wrote, in
my estimation, a volume slightly different from <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Complete Stories</ENAMEX> ,
and the name of that slightly different volume ought to be, more cautiously,
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Selected Stories</ENAMEX> .

         
      
   
