
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Piano Forte</ENAMEX>

            The tell us a lot about this
recording: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First</ENAMEX>, a superbly voiced E-flat major chord with every instrument
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">audible</ENAMEX>, the winds biting through the string sound, the timpani crisp yet
viscerally forceful. Then, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soloist</ENAMEX> begins his famous heroic surge up the
keyboard. Except that he doesn't sound heroic; he sounds tinkly. His finger
work is impeccable, his phrasing elegant, his stance as swaggering as one could
wish, but the sound of his instrument--a fortepiano, an earlier, less powerful
version of our modern-day piano--is irreconcilably at odds with his
intentions.

            The
original instrument movement is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several decades old</TIMEX>, and has moved so far
beyond mere novelty that in some repertoires, it might even be considered the
new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">orthodoxy</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bach</ENAMEX> performance in the style of those old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grand</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Teutons</ENAMEX>--conductors like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Furtwängler</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Klemperer</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">von Karajan</ENAMEX>--has fallen
out of fashion and favor, and massed <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Victorian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">armies</ENAMEX> raising the rafters as
they belt out The 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Messiah</ENAMEX> now seem quaintly anachronistic.

            In music of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19 th century</TIMEX>, though, the use of
original instruments is still controversial. Do they reveal the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">composer</ENAMEX>'s
intentions, or merely demonstrate the practical limitations against which he
struggled? Keyboard music poses the question in its starkest terms: Was the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19 th -century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">concert grand</ENAMEX> developed in response to the music being
composed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beethoven</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contemporaries</ENAMEX>, in order to realize its potential
more fully, or was the Romantic style of keyboard writing itself a response to
the sound of these new instruments?

            These
aren't idle questions. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beethoven</ENAMEX> was sent a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Broadwood</ENAMEX> grand as a gift from
its <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1818</TIMEX> (he maneuvered to avoid paying import duties,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">incidentally</ENAMEX>), he was delighted--with both the gift and the instrument. It's
not unreasonable to assume that he considered it a superior medium for the
performance of his music, even music composed before he received the gift.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Levin</ENAMEX>, the fortepiano <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soloist</ENAMEX> on this
recording and a respected musical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholar</ENAMEX>, assumes otherwise. As he makes his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> through the cycle of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beethoven</ENAMEX> concertos, he plans to use different
instruments for the different pieces, determining the compass of each
instrument he employs by the range of notes each piece demands. He believes, as
he put it in a conversation with me recently, that "no matter the size of the
room, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beethoven</ENAMEX> always insists on banging his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> on the ceiling and stubbing
his toe on the floor." This is elegantly put and close to inarguable: If
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beethoven</ENAMEX> had a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five-and-</NUMEX>a-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> octave instrument at his disposal, the music he
wrote for it probably would demand the highest and the lowest notes of that
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>-and-a-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> octave <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">span</ENAMEX>. But does it necessarily follow that the instrument
available to him on any given occasion produced the ideal sound he heard in his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>?

            This
question is more pointed for the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Emperor " concerto</ENAMEX> than it might be for
its <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">predecessors</ENAMEX>. Although not the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> grandly heroic piano
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">concerto</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mozart</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K.</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">503</NUMEX> arguably merits that description--the
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Emperor</ENAMEX> " proclaimed its grandeur in an especially aggressive way, and
in so doing, became the model for concertos of the Romantic era. The drama
inherent in concerto performance--valiant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soloist</ENAMEX> vying with and defying the
mass of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">orchestra</ENAMEX> with his eloquence and virtuosity--is the very essence of
the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Emperor</ENAMEX> ." <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> would think it requires an instrument that can
challenge the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">orchestra</ENAMEX> in volume and power. To play the piece on a fortepiano
seems almost perverse.

            That said, it must also be said that no other performance
could have offered a better opportunity to decide whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Levin</ENAMEX> is right.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gardiner</ENAMEX>'s conducting is so good (his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beethoven Symphony</ENAMEX> cycle is, to my ears,
the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to own, and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mozart</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Handel</ENAMEX> performances are exemplary); <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Levin</ENAMEX>'s
playing is so dexterous, intelligent, and ardent; and the recording is so
technically splendid (there are felicities of scoring, such as a solo cello
line in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> movement I'd never noticed before) that, whatever its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">peculiarities</ENAMEX>, this release at least qualifies as best of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">breed</ENAMEX>.

            And how does it fare? In the
lyrical <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sections</ENAMEX>, it works superbly (most of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> movement, say, and the
beautiful B minor/C flat major section of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> movement's second subject,
projected with supple delicacy by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Levin</ENAMEX>). In the filigree figures accompanying
transitional passages in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> movement, or the dialogue with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">French</ENAMEX>
horns near the end of the same movement, it's close to a revelation. This, I
found myself thinking, must be the precise blend <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beethoven</ENAMEX> intended.

            But in the
heroic passages that define the work, it doesn't succeed for me at all. The
cadenza that opens the concerto sounds wan and unassertive; its even more
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">extravagant recapitulation</ENAMEX> tries harder while achieving less. The great
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>-against-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> contrary-motion chromatic scales, one of the most thrilling
virtuoso passages in the literature, are bland in spite of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Levin</ENAMEX>'s awesome
execution. And in the battle of block chords toward the end of the development
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">section</ENAMEX>, the piano comes off as strident rather than imperial as it attempts to
rival the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">orchestra</ENAMEX>.

            
This performance contains <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> other oddity
worth noting. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Levin</ENAMEX> accompanies the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">orchestra</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">continuo</TIMEX>-style, during the tutti
sections--passages when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soloist</ENAMEX> is normally silent. This is a controversial
practice even in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mozart</ENAMEX> concertos, and unheard of in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19 th -century</TIMEX>
works. In his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">liner</ENAMEX> notes, and more elaborately in our conversation, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Levin</ENAMEX>
claims the manuscript score makes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beethoven</ENAMEX>'s intentions unambiguous on this
point. His argument is persuasive, but the conclusion is so
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">counterintuitive</ENAMEX>--why should the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soloist</ENAMEX> meekly accompany the orchestra when he
isn't defying it?--that I remain unconvinced. His contributions in these
passages are largely unobtrusive--and in a medium without a visual component,
not especially bothersome--but the choice nevertheless seems eccentric.

            The other piece on the
recording, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Fantasy</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pianoforte</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chorus</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Orchestra</ENAMEX> 
               in C
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Minor Op</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">80</TIMEX>, a hastily written occasional composition with amusing
premonitions of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Symphony No. 9</ENAMEX> , is not one of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beethoven</ENAMEX>'s more inspired
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">creations</ENAMEX>. But the performance is splendid; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Levin</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gardiner</ENAMEX> are powerful
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> for a work whose position in the repertory has historically been
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tenuous</ENAMEX>.

            It's impossible to arrive at
any general conclusions about what sorts of instruments are right for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beethoven</ENAMEX>'s keyboard music. It's true that different pieces benefit from
different treatment; the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Op</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> sonatas, for example, don't need a sound source
identical to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hammerklavier</ENAMEX> . And the coming original-instrument
performances of the remaining concertos from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Levin</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gardiner</ENAMEX> promise to be
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">revelatory</ENAMEX>. But--and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Levin</ENAMEX> is likely to find this praise more infuriating than
any criticism--had he chosen to play his "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Emperor</ENAMEX> " on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steinway</ENAMEX> or a
Bosendorfer, he might have given us one of the greatest recordings of the piece
ever put on disc.

         
      
   
