
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Strange Case</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Ruddy</ENAMEX>

            On the
off chance that you haven't followed every twist and turn of the case, there
are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> ways to reassure yourself that former Deputy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House Counsel</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vincent Foster</ENAMEX> killed himself in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Fort Marcy Park</ENAMEX>. One is to read Whitewater
Independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Counsel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>'s just-released report on the subject--a
briskly efficient <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">114</NUMEX>-page document that makes an already overwhelming case for
suicide about as close to airtight as you can get. The other is to read
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Ruddy</ENAMEX>'s new book, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Strange Death of Vincent Foster</ENAMEX> .
Ruddy, of course, is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Inspector</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clouseau</ENAMEX> of the Foster case--a determined,
if bumbling, former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Post</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> who has virtually
single-handedly spawned a cottage industry of conspiracy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buffs</ENAMEX> dedicated to the
proposition that a foul and monstrous cover-up surrounds the circumstances of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Foster</ENAMEX>'s death.

            Financed by a cranky right-wing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">philanthropist</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mellon Scaife, Ruddy's</ENAMEX> repeated bromides about the Foster case have been
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">republished</ENAMEX> in newspaper ads across the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>; his sheer persistence has led
some casual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">observers</ENAMEX> to conclude he might be on to something. The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Strange</ENAMEX>
Death , published by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Free Press</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">division</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simon & Schuster</ENAMEX>, is
endorsed as "serious and compelling" by former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Sessions</ENAMEX>.
In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Book Review</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Review</ENAMEX> senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Brookhiser</ENAMEX> chides political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> for failing to pursue <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ruddy</ENAMEX>'s
many "unanswered questions" about the case.

            Don't
worry, when it comes to how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Foster</ENAMEX> died, there aren't any--or none that matter.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ruddy</ENAMEX>'s book--and the entire movement he has helped create--is utterly
preposterous. Turgidly written and dense with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">534</NUMEX> footnotes and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX>
appendixes, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ruddy</ENAMEX>'s plodding book repeatedly confuses the evidence and chases
after scores of imaginary holes in the official verdict--without ever positing
an alternative scenario that makes the least bit of sense.

            
To fully understand why the "debate" over
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Foster</ENAMEX>'s death is so phony, it helps to review a few of the raw,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">incontrovertible</ENAMEX> (you would think) facts. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Foster</ENAMEX> left his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> office
for the last time at around <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 p.m.</TIMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 20, 1993</TIMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">About five hours later</TIMEX>,
his supine <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> was discovered by a secluded <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Civil War</ENAMEX> cannon near the Potomac
River, a bullet wound through his mouth, his right thumb trapped in the trigger
of an antique <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.38</NUMEX>-caliber revolver, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX>-shot <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">residue</ENAMEX> on his hand, and blood
oozing from the back of his head. There were no signs of a struggle; his sports
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">jacket</ENAMEX> was later found folded over the front seat of his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Honda</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Accord</ENAMEX> in a
nearby parking lot. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the days</TIMEX> that followed, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> members
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">described Foster</ENAMEX> as distraught over the demands of his job and suffering from
clear signs of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">depression</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> adds new details: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Just four days</TIMEX> before his
death, he reports, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Foster</ENAMEX> broke down in tears over dinner with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and
talked of resigning. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> before he died he phoned his family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> in
Little <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rock</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ark.</ENAMEX> According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX>'s typewritten notes, published in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s report for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Foster</ENAMEX> complained of stress, anorexia, and
insomnia, and received a prescription for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Desyrel</ENAMEX>, an antidepressant.

            It is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ruddy</ENAMEX>'s contention that none of this should necessarily be believed; the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">widow</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Park Police</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> that found the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coroner</ENAMEX> who performed the autopsy--all may well be "complicit" in a
cover-up. But why? As far as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Park Police</ENAMEX> goes, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ruddy</ENAMEX> argues, they
mistakenly rushed to the judgment that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Foster</ENAMEX>'s death was a suicide and are
concealing the fact that they failed to follow proper police procedures by
considering alternatives, such as murder and/or the possibility that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foster</ENAMEX>
died somewhere else and his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> was "moved" to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort Marcy</ENAMEX> by an unidentified
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX> of secret <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conspirators</ENAMEX>. The argument begs certain questions, such as: Who
were these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conspirators</ENAMEX>? What possible motive would they have had? Why deposit
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Foster</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> in a public <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX>? (At least the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mafia</ENAMEX> drops its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> in
rivers.) And most curious of all, how exactly could this dastardly crime have
been carried off? Consider: There were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least a half-dozen</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> known to
have visited the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> that <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX>. It was broad daylight. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Foster</ENAMEX> was <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">6 feet</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">4 inches</NUMEX> tall and weighed <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">200 pounds</NUMEX>. To have transported the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">deputy</ENAMEX> White
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX>'s lumpy dead body <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">200 yards</NUMEX> from the parking lot to the cannon
and have nobody notice would have been quite an achievement. Wouldn't they have
at least waited until nightfall?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ruddy</ENAMEX> makes no stab at guessing who the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> are. But
as he plows his way through <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds of</NUMEX> pages of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX> statements, he thinks
he has discovered what they were wearing: orange <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">vests</ENAMEX>! This is actually not a
joke. Ruddy dwells ominously on the equivocal testimony of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fairfax County</ENAMEX>
rescue <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Todd Hall</ENAMEX>, who initially told the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> he thought he might
have seen someone in an orange or red vest in the woods. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hall</ENAMEX> later conceded it
may have been nothing more than a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> in the distance. Still, Ruddy
smells a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX>. He speculates darkly that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hall</ENAMEX>'s possible sighting was evidence
of a suspicious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of orange-vest-clad body-movers in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> that day
masquerading as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Park Police</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteers</ENAMEX>."

            There is,
of course, much more about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ruddy</ENAMEX>'s book that is equally absurd--or simply
wrong. Like his fellow conspiracy nuts, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ruddy</ENAMEX> argues that there was too little
blood in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort Marcy</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foster</ENAMEX> to have been killed there. In fact, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>
makes clear, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Foster</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> was turned over, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Park Police</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX>
reported a pool of blood underneath his head and new, wet blood pouring out of
his nose. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Fiske</ENAMEX>, is chastised for failing
to identify supposedly mysterious white carpet <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fibers</ENAMEX> found on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Foster</ENAMEX>'s
clothing. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> has: The carpet <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fibers</ENAMEX> are the same as those found in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foster</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ruddy</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> have questioned where the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.38</NUMEX>-caliber revolver
found in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foster</ENAMEX>'s hand came from. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s report, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Foster</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">widow</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> recall that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Foster</ENAMEX> inherited a similar handgun
from his late <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX> and that he took it to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years later</TIMEX>,
keeping it in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedroom closet</ENAMEX>. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lisa Foster</ENAMEX> ran upstairs to look for it on
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night</TIMEX> of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s death, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapon</ENAMEX> was missing. Are they all
lying?

            
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the days</TIMEX> before his death, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Foster</ENAMEX> was
obsessing about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> travel-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> affair, and apparently feared
continued investigations would focus attention on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX>'s role in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">firings</ENAMEX>. That almost certainly helps to account for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> stonewalling
over the documents left behind in his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>--an action that did much to fuel
suspicions about what secrets <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Foster</ENAMEX> might have known. But that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> killed
himself is beyond dispute. It would be comforting to think that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">report</ENAMEX>--reaching precisely the same conclusion as <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> previous government
investigations--will finally end the matter. Of course, it won't. On his
continually updated Web site, the indomitable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ruddy</ENAMEX> charges on, picking away at
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s report and darkly suggesting that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitewater</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX>, with his
impeccable <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> credentials, has joined the cover-up. It must be heady
stuff taking on such giant conspiracies--and frightening too. Can <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruddy</ENAMEX> be sure
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> with orange <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vests</ENAMEX> won't soon be coming for him?

         
      
   
