
   
   
      
         
            Not-<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">So-Plain Jane</ENAMEX>

            We know virtually all there
is to know about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane Austen</ENAMEX>'s life, and at least on the surface, it's pretty
tame stuff. She was born in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1775</TIMEX>, in a tiny <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hampshire</ENAMEX>. As a young woman
she went to a few balls. She flirted with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> dashing boy, but she had no dowry
to speak of and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> got worried and made him move away. Later she
agreed to marry <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a very</NUMEX> tall, very ugly younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, but she changed her mind
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the next morning</TIMEX>. Beginning in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">her late 20s</TIMEX>, while packed into a snug cottage
with her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>, her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>, and a pockmarked spinster friend, she revised some
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">juvenilia</ENAMEX> and wrote a series of freakishly perfect novels. Then she got sick,
we now think of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Addison</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX>, and died at the unfair age of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">41</NUMEX>.

            Given the
material, it's not surprising that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane Austen</ENAMEX> should now be seen as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">literature</ENAMEX>'s beloved old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">maid</ENAMEX>: modest, retiring, more comfortable darning socks
by the fire than out in the big bad world, something of a gossip but basically
sweet. But <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biographies</ENAMEX> argue that while the outline of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Austen</ENAMEX>'s life is
pretty much what we thought, posterity has colored it in all wrong, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Austen</ENAMEX>'s own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> are largely to blame. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">First</NUMEX> there was her overprotective
older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cassandra</ENAMEX>. After <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane</ENAMEX> died Cassandra burned <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several years</TIMEX>' worth
of letters, and edited all the zest out of what remained. A <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">half-century later</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Austen's</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">great-nephew</ENAMEX> wrote a classically priggish memoir that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cast</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane</ENAMEX> as the
perfect Victorian <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX>, a superwoman of piety and self-denial. Perversely, it
wasn't until this <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">crude</ENAMEX> sanitization that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Austen</ENAMEX>'s popularity really took off.
Even <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Austen</ENAMEX>'s biggest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> meet to re-create <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> quadrilles and
to go over the changing fashions in bonnets, they're dealing with this cleaned
up, adorable, and essentially false <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane</ENAMEX>.

            If these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> books got together, their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offspring</ENAMEX> would be a
near-perfect biography. As it is, each is flawed but useful. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Claire Tomalin</ENAMEX> has
written a smart, terse, mildly feminist summary of every fact in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austen</ENAMEX>'s life
she could get her hands on. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Nokes</ENAMEX> has made a bold, provocative, and
sometimes messy attempt to write <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Austen</ENAMEX>'s life as if it were a novel whose
outcome we didn't already know--"a biography written forwards," he emphatically
declares in the introduction, which unfolds "as it was experienced at the time,
not with the knowingness of hindsight." Though less original and not as fully
realized, these books reminded me of a pair of recent literary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">appreciations</ENAMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hermione Lee</ENAMEX>'s mammoth biography of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Virginia Woolf</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alain de Botton</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">idiosyncratic</ENAMEX>, obsessive <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">How Proust Can Change Your Life</ENAMEX> . <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">All four</NUMEX> books
share a playful disregard for the rules that usually govern high-minded
"intellectual" biographies. They move beyond overarching <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Freudian</ENAMEX> thematizing.
Most of all, they share an almost fetishistic desire to re-create a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>'s
life sight by sight and smell by smell. So we learn that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane</ENAMEX> drank from
her mother's breast (before being farmed out to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurse</ENAMEX> with the eye-catchingly
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">contemporary</ENAMEX> name of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Movie</ENAMEX>); that, while growing up, she may have tasted spicy
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">condiments</ENAMEX> shipped to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hampshire</ENAMEX> by her <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Uncle Tysoe Saul Hancock</ENAMEX>, who was
stationed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calcutta</ENAMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">East India Co.</ENAMEX>; and that she probably began to
menstruate at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the age of 15 or 16</TIMEX>.

            Her family
looms large--much more than is usual in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>'s biography--because she never
managed to win independence from it. Little information survives about her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>. But how much does this matter? We've been reminded in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX>--by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> as disparate as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Sulloway</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Bly</ENAMEX>--that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">siblings</ENAMEX> can be just
as crucial as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> in determining a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s development, and the brilliant,
loyal, competitive <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Austen</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clan</ENAMEX> is a perfect example. Nokes, anachronistically
but suggestively applying <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">20 th</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-century</TIMEX> standards of family unity,
argues that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane</ENAMEX> was traumatized by a separation from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of her <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX>.
Luckless, mentally challenged <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX> was packed off to a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> and never
mentioned again. On a brighter but no less arbitrary note, childless
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">aristocrats</ENAMEX> picked genial <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward</ENAMEX> as their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heir</ENAMEX>; he changed his name and became
a snobbish <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">landowner</ENAMEX>, kind to his less glamorous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">siblings</ENAMEX> but also
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">condescending</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> left behind were the cleverest, which was just as
well, because among them, they had next to no money. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stiff James</ENAMEX>, the oldest,
wanted to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> (he ended up a curate) and spurred <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane</ENAMEX> to compete.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charming</ENAMEX>, flaky <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry</ENAMEX> started a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> that eventually went belly up; Tomalin
brilliantly places him in the volatile context of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regency London</ENAMEX>, a magnet for
striving nouveaux riches <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hustlers</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brave Frank</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles</ENAMEX> went to sea, writing
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">West Indies</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> and other places that the quaint fantasy
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> has been assumed to know nothing about. And how's this for exoticism:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane</ENAMEX> was nearly as close as a sister to her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eliza</ENAMEX>, who was probably the
illegitimate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren Hastings</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor-general</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>. His
trial, on charges of corruption and cruelty, was the most gossiped-about
scandal of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>.

            
These <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX>, and not <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>, were the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane</ENAMEX> depended on for survival once it became clear she wouldn't marry.
They were solicitous. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry</ENAMEX> helped her publish, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward</ENAMEX> made sure
she had a roof overhead. But they had total power over her, deciding where she
lived, how big an allowance she got, and when and where she could travel.
Meanwhile, for companionship and reaction to her work she was utterly dependent
on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cassandra</ENAMEX>. Their love for each other ran deep. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A few years ago</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholar</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Terry Castle</ENAMEX> even suggested in an attention-grabbing essay in the London
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Review of Books</ENAMEX> that it was more than sisterly. This is a cheap, ludicrous
claim, and I'm happy to say that both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nokes</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tomalin</ENAMEX>, for all their
determination to explore the hidden <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Austen</ENAMEX>, basically ignore it. Still,
Cassandra may be the most frustrating sibling in literary history. Nokes, in
particular, believes that for all her very real devotion, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cassandra</ENAMEX> was
something of an underminer, constantly urging <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane</ENAMEX> to hide her identity as an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>. Her "plump, dumpy" watercolor portrait of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane</ENAMEX> shows an unremarkable
woman utterly lacking in energy. And after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane</ENAMEX> died, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cassandra</ENAMEX> stressed her
goodness more than her wit or her bitter eye for human failings. With perfectly
good intentions, she ended up stifling "the restless spirit of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who
said of herself: 'If I am a wild <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">beast</ENAMEX>, I cannot help it. It is not my own
fault.' "

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cassandra</ENAMEX> is also
responsible for destroying the letters that would fill us in on the crucial
period in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1801</TIMEX>, when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> moved from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> to the fashionable spa
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">town</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bath</ENAMEX>. Family legend has it that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane</ENAMEX> fainted away when she heard of the
move, terrified of leaving all that was dear to her for such a den of iniquity.
By this point <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Austen</ENAMEX> had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> rough drafts of novels under her belt, but all
she wrote during the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bath</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> was The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Watsons</ENAMEX> , a stiff fragment of a
novel that she never returned to. Her silence has always been attributed to a
deep depression. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Nokes</NUMEX> points out that our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX> for her fainting is
unreliable--<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">70 years later</TIMEX>, a niece who wasn't alive at the time thought she
remembered hearing something to that effect. What if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane</ENAMEX> was tougher than
this? What if she had found <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bath</ENAMEX> stimulating? What if she had failed to write
there not because she was desolate and dried up but because, for a few active
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, she actually had a life? There is simply no evidence, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nokes</ENAMEX> writes,
"that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane Austen</ENAMEX> considered the curtailment of her former literary pastimes,
in favour of visits to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pump Room</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Assembly Rooms</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sydney Gardens</ENAMEX> or the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">theatre</ENAMEX>, as any form of sacrifice." We'll never know if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nokes</ENAMEX> is right--in the
end, the record on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Austen</ENAMEX> is just too scanty to go beyond speculation. But it's
a sobering idea. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> does always have the sense with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Austen</ENAMEX> that she values
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">equilibrium</ENAMEX> and happiness over suffering. She was a born <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>, but she wasn't
pretentious enough to regard writing as her only possible destiny. It's sad to
imagine her returning to her manuscripts <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years later</TIMEX> in a state of
irritable, impoverished resignation. It's especially sad to think that we might
not have these happiest of novels if it weren't for her lowered hopes.

         
      
   
