
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Right To Be a Boor</ENAMEX>

            With the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> case
and the sexual harassment debate wearing thin, a new crisis looms on the
employment horizon demanding our urgent attention. According to a recent called
Diversity in the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Power Elite: Have Women and Minorities Reached the</ENAMEX>
Top? , highly placed corporate white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> are fretting over the slow but
steady rise of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Latinos</ENAMEX> to elite positions in the workplace.
Are they worried that these new arrivals will take away their jobs? No.
According to the study, what they fear is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minorities</ENAMEX> won't be
good at playing <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">golf</ENAMEX>.

            OK,
accusing a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">golf</ENAMEX> anxiety isn't quite the same as alleging that he lowered
his pants in front of a subordinate and requested service. But far from making
a trivial point, the diversity study shows that the prosecutorial way we think
about gender in the workplace may not always be helpful. During <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past few</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>'s limitless pursuit of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has caused sensible people
to wonder if we've let the battle against sexual harassment turn into a witch
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hunt</ENAMEX>. I agree that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> aren't equipped to resolve many issues of gender on
the job--not because the results are unjust but because they're unsubtle.

            How could the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> possibly deal with golf <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">anxiety</ENAMEX>?
Surely a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> has every right to converse with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> who play <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">golf</ENAMEX>.
Surely he also has a right to assume that a new employee doesn't play <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">golf</ENAMEX>.
Likewise, he's entitled to appear shy or unfriendly around her, and perhaps
unintentionally hamper her ability to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, and even then
assume she lacks initiative and give her a mediocre job evaluation. But such
obtuse behavior, even if legal, causes suffering, and it's worth talking about
away from the blunt, guilty-or-innocent logic of the law.

            Arriving
as it does on the tail end of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> disaster, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frances K. Conley</ENAMEX>'s
memoir of sexism at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stanford</ENAMEX> may encounter a kind of sexual-conflict fatigue
and miss the attention it deserves. It's a treasure trove of messy, not always
courtworthy gender-job dilemmas that nevertheless need to be explored. Conley,
the first tenured woman <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> of neurosurgery in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, tells how she
left <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stanford University School of Medicine</ENAMEX> back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>, after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25 years</TIMEX> of
contented teaching and research. Traditionally, of course, neurosurgery has
been the elite macho pinnacle of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX>--its <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Navy SEALs</ENAMEX>. So at <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> glance,
when you consider how steely <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Conley</ENAMEX> had to be to rise in the field, the event
that provoked her to leave sounds pretty innocuous: A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleague</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerry</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Silverberg</ENAMEX> got promoted to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of the program. Conley, who'd worked with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerry</ENAMEX> since they were in medical school, thought he was a jerk.

            
Sounds so far like a depressing but routine
power contest. Where did sex come in? Stirred by her anger, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conley</ENAMEX> eventually
began to face facts about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerry</ENAMEX> that she had suppressed over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two decades</TIMEX> in
order to concentrate on work. She recalled how in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years past</TIMEX>, during training,
he made a juvenile habit of propositioning her in front of other male
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>--really propositioning her, thrusting his pelvis in her face and
saying how much she'd like it. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX>, he'd interrupted her during
complex brain surgery and shouted, laughing, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">How</ENAMEX>'s it going, hon?" All in all,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerry</ENAMEX> was a charmer.

            Conley
had to admit that while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerry</ENAMEX> had no <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">rivals</ENAMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pig</ENAMEX>, he was hardly alone in
his insensitivity. When she was a med <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX>, all but a couple of generous
male <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisers</ENAMEX> had told her, paternalistically, to give up her neurosurgery
dreams and stick with a nice female discipline like obstetrics. (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">One day</TIMEX> she
finally got the courage to knock on the door of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> chair and ask if
she could join the program. He answered the door with his pants-string undone,
and a glance at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couch</ENAMEX> indicated he'd been screwing his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX>.) As a
young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faculty member</ENAMEX> she attended <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> lunches because that's where the
networking action was. They were gross, childish stag affairs: In plain sight
of everyone, one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleague</ENAMEX> would caress her thigh, daring her to make him stop
and inviting all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> to giggle. Then the urologists at the
table would speculate about who among their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> could get it up.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> may ask why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Conley</ENAMEX> put up with this for so long. It's a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fair</ENAMEX> question. Until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the spring of 1991</TIMEX>, she says, she'd basically identified
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>. "Wrapped and totally immersed within the competitive cocoon of
academic medicine, living <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> at a great distance from the 'real' world,
I was all but oblivious to the fact that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">movement</ENAMEX> had started, and,
selfishly, had no idea how other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in my own world were faring." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conley</ENAMEX>'s
writing voice even has something of a macho swagger, and once in a while it
hits a false note, as if she were building her broad case against the medical
profession in order to get back at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerry</ENAMEX>, the vulgar meanie. At times, too, the
(cool expertise vs. righteousness, wit vs. no sense of humor) become almost too
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vivid</ENAMEX>, as if she weren't a real-life polemicist so much as an intriguing
fictional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>.

            But here's
where the case gets really fascinating. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Conley</ENAMEX> says she never intended to take
legal action. She just felt <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerry</ENAMEX> would make an intolerable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>, and when he
got promoted she impulsively resigned. Then she naively sent a rambling op-ed
piece to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">San Francisco Chronicle</ENAMEX> , outlining--in general terms,
naming no names--the sexist atmosphere at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stanford</ENAMEX>. The piece wasn't published
right away. Instead a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> called, wheedled an interview out of her, and
without informing her ran a front-page story about her claims.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nightline</ENAMEX> , <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20/20</NUMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NPR</ENAMEX>, etc., came along and ran stories
portraying her as a crusader against "sexual harassment"--a loaded phrase with
a specific legal import, which she had never used.

            
Now, all this happened <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">just a few months</TIMEX> before
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anita Hill</ENAMEX> announced to a TV <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarence Thomas</ENAMEX> had left a pubic
hair in her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coke</ENAMEX>. In retrospect, the media transformation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conley</ENAMEX>'s case
looks like a rehearsal for its circuslike approach to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hill</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conley</ENAMEX> had
hoped to spark a general discussion of sexism in the medical academic
profession. Instead the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> claim of sexual harassment reorganized the debate
into a contest of personal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adversaries</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stanford</ENAMEX>, as big and powerful
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX> tend to do, called for hearings. Conley, feeling that she should
see through what she had unleashed, returned to work in a <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX> atmosphere.
A <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two year</TIMEX> agony of fact-finding panels and legal actions ensued, with losers
both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">male</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">female</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Scapegoat men</ENAMEX> were singled out for behavior their
profession had never before discouraged; <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who told of being pressured for
sex found themselves alone, laughed at, or forced by the hostile environment to
leave.

            It took
ages to resolve, but in the end <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerry</ENAMEX> didn't get to be department chair (though
the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> are, somewhat horrifyingly, still <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX>). Conley, after becoming a
kind of national <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clearinghouse</ENAMEX> for complaints about sexism in medical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>,
traveled the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college circuit</ENAMEX> to discuss flaws in both theory and practice of
medical instruction. But often, she says, the resulting reforms have been
cosmetic--a token low-level <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bureaucrat</ENAMEX> assigned to "hear" problems, with no
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">forum</ENAMEX> to do anything about them. Which isn't surprising. Who would want to go
through this kind of divisive battle every time an allegation came up?

            That's one problem with our current approach to sexual
harassment. As we've just seen in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> case, it's exhausting.
Everyone gets tired of the ransacking of private lives, the cynical search for
ulterior motives, the weighing of imperfect evidence; after a while, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are
likely to say, "Just let it go." There's another problem, too. The focus on
legalistic descriptions of punishable human behavior ignores unconscious
behavior, the habits many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> are accustomed to that don't call for punishment
but are still harmful--what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Conley</ENAMEX> says occurs within "the reverberating
circuitry of maleness." The best parts of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conley</ENAMEX>'s book are about deep,
institutional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resistance</ENAMEX> to change: the way that otherwise admirable male
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professors</ENAMEX> understandably draw on their training of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 years ago</TIMEX>, which assumed
the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">70</NUMEX> kilogram male <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> as the human norm and left them totally ignorant of
female health problems; the way training in elite specialties like neurosurgery
still promotes a specific kind of cowboy bravado, which encourages <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> to
bail out for gynecology. On these issues, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conley</ENAMEX> raises difficult, important
questions. Unfortunately, crude history will more likely reduce her to another
role, as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pioneer</ENAMEX> of the he-said-she-said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">'90s</TIMEX>.

            
               If you
missed the links in the text, click to read more on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale University Press</ENAMEX>
study and for some samples of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conley</ENAMEX>'s conflicted prose style.
            

         
      
   
