
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Id饳 Fixes</ENAMEX>

            Bad things happen to the
ordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ian McEwan</ENAMEX>'s novels--things that initially seem bizarrely,
even comically, out of proportion with their lives. In <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Innocent</ENAMEX>
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>), a newly engaged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> comes home from a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> and goes to bed to make
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">love</ENAMEX>, only to discover that there is an intruder asleep in their wardrobe.
Panic-stricken, unsure of how best to get rid of him, they begin to argue. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">woman</ENAMEX> is smoking a cigarette, and she accidentally sets herself on fire. The
intruder wakes up. A terrible fight breaks out. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bones</ENAMEX> are broken, testicles are
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">crushed</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> bites through another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s cheek. And then things get a whole
lot worse.

            The scene
is vintage <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McEwan</ENAMEX>--in its suspense, its violence, and the sickening swiftness
with which it unfolds. But perhaps its most emblematic characteristic is its
ability to provoke a flustered and ambivalent response in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX>, a
horrified sympathy that alternates with a deep desire to distance oneself from
the nightmare at hand. Could this grisly encounter have been prevented? Was it
merely bad luck, or did the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> somehow bring it on themselves? And--most
important--could anything like this ever happen to me? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McEwan</ENAMEX> is a Freudian
with an Orwellian sense of decency, and his novels often trigger this sort of
unsettling examination of both one's unconscious and one's conscience. He's
also fascinated by the infectious nature of calamity: The success with which he
simultaneously analyzes and communicates its uneasy intimacy is his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Hardy</ENAMEX> was another great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX> of morality, psychology, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">circumstance</ENAMEX>, but his tragedies never make you nervous. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McEwan</ENAMEX> makes you
nervous.

            In his latest book, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Enduring Love</ENAMEX> , this struggle to
make sense of misfortune is an explicit enterprise, a contentious necessity for
the novel's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> main <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>. The worst, one senses, has already happened,
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">narrator</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Rose</ENAMEX>, is returning to his story's beginning, just as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reader</ENAMEX> might, in order to understand what went wrong. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX> is a science writer
who has made a successful career of elucidating complex phenomena (black holes,
chaos theory) for the general <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX>. His common-law <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarissa Mellon</ENAMEX>, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">beautiful Keats</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholar</ENAMEX> with whom he lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North London</ENAMEX>. Then, one
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX>, during a celebratory picnic in the countryside near <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oxford</ENAMEX>, they
hear a shout of distress: A middle-aged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> is entangled in one of the
anchoring lines of an enormous hot-air balloon while his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passenger</ENAMEX>, a terrified
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>, is unsuccessfully attempting to escape from the basket.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX>
instinctively sprints to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">balloonist</ENAMEX>'s aid, as do <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> who happen
to witness the event: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> farm <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">laborers</ENAMEX>; a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">motorist</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Logan</ENAMEX>; and Jed
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parry</ENAMEX>, a day-tripper from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>. In hindsight, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX>'s description of his
actions signals the undertow of bewildered culpability that will run throughout
the novel: "We turned to look across the field and saw the danger. Next thing,
I was running toward it." As it turns out, this altruistic instinct proves
fatal not for the narrator but for one of the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rescuers</ENAMEX>. After a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hair-raising</ENAMEX> and chaotic collective attempt to retrieve the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>, a sudden gust
of wind lifts the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> into the air; the others drop away, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Logan</ENAMEX>, a local
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>, holds on as the unburdened balloon shoots suddenly
skyward. <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">A few moments</TIMEX> later, he falls to his death as the others look on,
guilt-stricken and disbelieving. Which of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">survivors</ENAMEX> let go <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>, thereby
causing the rest to follow suit? How could they have managed it
differently?

            
When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Clarissa</ENAMEX> return to their apartment
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> they find themselves obsessively reiterating <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the afternoon</TIMEX>'s events
in an attempt to contain and absorb them. "We were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX> in a cell," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">remembers</ENAMEX>, "running at the walls, beating them back with our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heads</ENAMEX>. Slowly our
prison grew larger." They sit at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen</ENAMEX> table for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX>, "grinding the
jagged edge of memories, hammering the unspeakable into forms of words." By the
time they turn in for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night</TIMEX> they have already forgotten <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parry</ENAMEX>, the awkward
young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hiker</ENAMEX> who had wanted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX> to pray with him over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Logan</ENAMEX>'s shattered <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX>: He
has been relegated to an anecdote and dismissed. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parry</ENAMEX>, as it turns out,
has not forgotten <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX>. Quite the opposite, and just as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> is drifting
off to sleep, he phones <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX> to declare his undying love. ("I just wanted you to
know, I understand what you're feeling. I feel it too.") Rattled and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">disbelieving</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX> hangs up on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Parry</ENAMEX> and tells Clarissa it's a wrong number. And
from that moment on, their interpretations of events diverge, and their
relationship begins to crumble.

            In the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> that follow, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parry</ENAMEX>'s fixation intensifies, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">paranoia</ENAMEX> correspondingly
deepens, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarissa</ENAMEX> becomes increasingly alienated. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX> has done nothing to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">encourage Parry</ENAMEX>'s attentions, and yet, even before he realizes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parry</ENAMEX> is
stalking him, he feels apprehensive, hunted. It is almost as if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX>'s guilt
over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Logan</ENAMEX>'s death has brought Parry into being. Why doesn't Clarissa ever see
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parry</ENAMEX>, if he is stalking <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX>, and why did <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe erase all Parry</ENAMEX>'s messages
on the answering machine, instead of saving them as evidence? Before long, the
apartment is awash in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Parry</ENAMEX>'s letters and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clarissa</ENAMEX> has moved into the spare
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bedroom</ENAMEX>. And as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clarissa</ENAMEX>'s support for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX> is withdrawn, we, too, begin to have
our misgivings. To be sure, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX>'s narrative is intelligent and persuasive, but
then again, so are <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parry</ENAMEX>'s letters--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of which are included in the text for
our inspection--and we know that he's insane. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baffled</ENAMEX> and disoriented, we pick
our way among these versions of the truth, straining for a synthesis that would
permit some hope for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX>'s future. Meanwhile, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX> lurches from one
unnerving mission to the next: a trip to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oxford</ENAMEX> to meet <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Logan</ENAMEX>'s furious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">widow</ENAMEX>;
a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kafkaesque</ENAMEX> visit to the local police <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">station</ENAMEX>; a sinister expedition to buy a
gun from some aging <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hippies</ENAMEX>. And there is an expensive birthday lunch with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clarissa</ENAMEX> and her godfather, which begins with a lively discussion of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Keats</ENAMEX> and ends in a fine <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">spray</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the initial frustrations of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Enduring Love</ENAMEX> is
the eclipse of the balloon accident. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parry</ENAMEX>'s fixation feels like a blunt
instrument in comparison, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> begins to long for the delicate moral
complexity of the tragedy that produced him in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strangers</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">converging</ENAMEX> in the center of a field to save a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>, and killing a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> instead.
But that sort of balletic patterning is precisely what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McEwan</ENAMEX> is calling into
question. At <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX> muses that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dirac</ENAMEX>'s early theory of quantum
electrodynamics was slow to gain acceptance because it was aesthetically
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">unappealing</ENAMEX>--"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Acceptance</ENAMEX> withheld on grounds of ugliness"--and this phrase
could well serve as the novel's ironic motto, for its plot is littered with
examples of this prejudice. When the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">balloonist</ENAMEX> yells perfectly reasonable
instructions to his would-be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">helpers</ENAMEX> in the field, they all ignore him because
he appears incompetent. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> dismiss <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX>'s warnings about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Parry</ENAMEX> because
they have a neater theory. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Logan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">widow</ENAMEX> becomes convinced that her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> was
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">adulterous</ENAMEX> because, after his death, she finds a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>'s scarf in his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>. But
is the elegant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">embodiment</ENAMEX> of an idea ever the entire story? On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Keats' Grecian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">urn</ENAMEX> perhaps, or in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Einstein</ENAMEX>'s theory of relativity, or even in a love letter.
But real life, lived in real time, requires us to push a lot harder for the
truth, as does any love that--unlike <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parry's</ENAMEX>--evolves between <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. The
conclusion of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Enduring Love</ENAMEX> , appropriately enough, proves impossible to
foresee. Ingeniously rewarding and unusually contingent on the intellectual
curiosity of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX>, it offers a playful reprimand to anyone who assumes
that they know where the "real" story of this novel begins and ends.

         
      
   
