
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Glass Is Not Half Full</ENAMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> broad traditions
encompass commentary about race relations in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. One is
pessimistic, the other optimistic. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Jefferson</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pessimist</ENAMEX>, maintained
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX> "can never live in a state of equal freedom under the
same <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Government</ENAMEX>, so insurmountable are the barriers which nature, habit, and
opinion have established between them." Despite the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Civil War</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reconstruction</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Civil Rights Revolution</ENAMEX>, an appreciable number of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">observers</ENAMEX> continue to assert that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> is, and will remain, a
white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supremacist</ENAMEX> pigmentocracy. Hence the despairing talk about "the
permanence of racism," "the myth of black progress," and "the coming race
war."

            The
optimistic tradition includes such figures as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frederick Douglass</ENAMEX>, who, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1863</TIMEX>,
even before the destruction of slavery, averred that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> "the white and
colored <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> [would] be blended into a common nationality, and enjoy together
... under the same flag, the inestimable blessings of life, liberty, and the
pursuit of happiness, as neighborly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> of a common <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>." <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A century</TIMEX>
later, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Luther King Jr.</ENAMEX> affirmed that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> would someday "be able to
transform the jangling discords of our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> into a beautiful symphony of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">brotherhood</ENAMEX>."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Black</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">One Nation</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indivisible</ENAMEX> by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stephan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abigail Thernstrom</ENAMEX> is a highly publicized contribution to the
conversation on race relations that is, in certain respects, squarely within
the optimistic tradition. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephan Thernstrom</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> history
at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard University</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abigail Thernstrom</ENAMEX>, his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> a senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fellow</ENAMEX> at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Manhattan Institute</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">think tank</ENAMEX>. Their book offers a history of black-white
race relations since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 19 th century</TIMEX>; discusses racial
controversies in a wide array of contexts (employment, housing, social-welfare
programs, electoral politics, criminal justice); and prescribes a framework
within which to fashion policy.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thernstroms</ENAMEX> conclude that the story of race relations since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1940s</TIMEX> is one of
"amazing" and "enormous" change for the good. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Thernstroms</ENAMEX> claim,
is "no longer separate, much less unequal than it once was, and by many
measures, less hostile." The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> are critical of those who, in their view,
exaggerate the significance of white racism, the significance of the black
underclass, and the extent to which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> remain <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">outsiders</ENAMEX>. Instead, the
Thernstroms stress the reduction in racial prejudice openly expressed by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX>, "the rise of the black middle class," and the extent to which blacks
have become "major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">players</ENAMEX>" in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> politics.

            
For the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thernstroms</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> racial politics
took a wrong turn when the imperative simply to end discrimination ceased to
govern our policies. That bare obligation, they argue, was superseded by a
destructive insistence that racial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minorities</ENAMEX> be included in substantial
numbers (ideally, in rough proportionality) in all spheres of social life,
including the most competitive. Throughout <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Black</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">White</ENAMEX> ,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Thernstroms</ENAMEX> attack almost any initiative that steps beyond simple
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">anti-discrimination</ENAMEX>: affirmative action, race norming in testing (under which
black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">examinees</ENAMEX> and white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">examinees</ENAMEX> are ranked and judged separately),
majority-minority electoral <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">districts</ENAMEX>, busing, subsidies for purposes of
residential racial integration, and so on.

            The
Thernstroms synthesize a tremendous amount of information, cover a daunting
array of topics, and convey their findings and prescriptions in a vivid,
accessible style. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Black</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">White</ENAMEX> fails, however, to reach
the levels of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">insight</ENAMEX> and carefulness that its subject demands and the
expressed ambitions of its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> lead <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to expect. I say this
notwithstanding my affinity for their optimism. Indeed, perhaps it is partly
because I share this optimism that I am particularly disappointed by this
book's rather substantial flaws.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> try to place themselves at the vital <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">center</ENAMEX> of
racial politics: "We quarrel with the left--its going-nowhere picture of black
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> and white racial attitudes," but "we also quarrel with the right--its
see-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">no</NUMEX>-evil view." In actuality, however, they unremittingly berate "the left"
but rarely challenge the settled understandings of conservative or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">neoconservative</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thernstroms</ENAMEX> say they recognize that racial
discrimination, though dramatically diminished, continues to pose an obstacle
to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-Americans</ENAMEX>. Yet they say little about the large extent to which key
anti-discrimination provisions remain underenforced. Virtually the only sort of
current racial discrimination that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thernstroms</ENAMEX> treat at length is that
which is intended to help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> and disadvantages certain <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX> in the
process.

            Consider
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thernstroms</ENAMEX>' discussion of the controversy surrounding the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Civil Rights</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Restoration Act of 1991</ENAMEX>. The act involved, essentially, a congressional
override of several <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> decisions that had narrowed, in a number of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ways</ENAMEX>, the scope of earlier civil-rights statutes. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thernstroms</ENAMEX> mainly
disapprove; the "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> small bit of arguably good news" about the act, they
write, was that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> outlawed race norming. But was this really the
only good news? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Unmentioned</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thernstroms</ENAMEX>' account is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme</ENAMEX>
Court decision on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patterson</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McLean Credit Union</ENAMEX> that prodded
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> to take action. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Patterson</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> held that the
Civil <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Rights Act of 1866</ENAMEX> did not prohibit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> from racially harassing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>--e.g., calling a black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX> "nigger." In the act of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> rectified this problem, explicitly outlawing such racial harassment by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX>. I am certain that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thernstroms</ENAMEX> would view that aspect of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>' action as "good news." But it seems that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thernstroms</ENAMEX> were so
preoccupied with criticizing the legal system as overindulgent toward blacks
that they passed over entirely this key feature of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX> legislation--a
feature that sought to correct the very sort of anti-black bias they take pains
to underplay throughout their text.

            
I am not criticizing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thernstroms</ENAMEX> because
they fervently oppose affirmative action. I disapprove of most forms of public
affirmative action myself, on the premise that public <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> shouldn't be
permitted to allocate burdens and benefits on racial grounds in the absence of
an absolute emergency. But there is something dreadfully wrong with a study of
race relations in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> that places affirmative action at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">center</ENAMEX> of the drama. The imbalance is especially notable given that other
significant phenomena--such as the lingering effects of racial oppression in
the (recent) past, new eruptions of anti-black prejudice, and so-called
"rational" racial discrimination (by which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, without malevolent intent,
use black skin as a negative cue)--are relegated to the far margins of
discussion.

            The only time the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX>
attack passionately and in detail the privileging of whiteness is when such
practices are located safely in the past. But even then, the Thernstroms
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">equivocate</ENAMEX>. They do not clearly condemn as racist the actions, sometimes
violent, that white ethnics in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> resorted to in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1960s</TIMEX> to keep blacks
from moving into "their" neighborhoods. Rather, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thernstroms</ENAMEX> shift attention
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> who criticized these actions but didn't themselves live in the
contested neighborhoods. I do not object to their empathy for the white
ethnics, or to their point that affluent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folk</ENAMEX> often have been able to escape
the harsh dilemmas posed by racial conflicts. After the explaining is done,
however, judgments must still be made. It is striking, and troubling, how
reluctant the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thernstroms</ENAMEX> are to condemn white bigotry, especially in light of
their clear, consistent, and negative assessment of black bigotry.

            Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentators</ENAMEX> adopt a
stance of racial pessimism because they fear that making concessions to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">optimists</ENAMEX> will breed complacency and inhibit the efforts needed for still
further progress. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Black</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX> will nourish such fears
through its own embrace of laissez faire optimism. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thernstroms</ENAMEX> prescribe
little to end the harms wrought by past injustices, or even to fight latent
racism--except stopping affirmative action and kindred policies. This is too
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">passive</ENAMEX> a stance. Affirmative action in its current guises is unlikely to be
the best or even a good way forward; but the consequences of simply eliminating
such programs are sure to be mixed. What's more, such reforms will leave
untouched injustices that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">seed</ENAMEX> legitimate aggrievement on the part of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX>.
Through intelligent, self-conscious, collective action, we have changed much
for the better in race relations. But much remains to be done to create what
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jefferson</ENAMEX> wrongly perceived as impossible: an <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX>--and others as well--living in a state of equal freedom under the same
government.

         
      
   
