
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dying of the Light</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jamaica Kincaid</ENAMEX> is great at
describing rage. Her fictional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroines</ENAMEX> can name every indignity they've been
subjected to since birth, and because they are usually bright young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> from
troubled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> in poor <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island backwaters</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Antigua</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dominica</ENAMEX>, their
list of injuries is long. They've seen corrupt <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX>, sadistic
schoolmasters, domineering <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> who spoil their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX> but train their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX> to be selfless clothes-washers, and feckless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> whose only reason
for living is to seduce <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and then disappear. Sometimes, as in the case of
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protagonist</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucy</ENAMEX> , a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kincaid</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroine</ENAMEX> gets so fed up
that she moves to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> (as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kincaid</ENAMEX> did, at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17</NUMEX>)--but there she only
finds more <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fuel</ENAMEX> for her anger in the pitying stares of unconsciously racist
white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX>.

            Rage is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kincaid</ENAMEX>'s strength.
One senses it above all in her amazing control over words, which, while
extremely satisfying on the level of literary technique, also comes across as a
refusal to be vulnerable and a reply to anyone who would try to keep her
down.

            Still,
rage is only one shade on the spectrum of human experience. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kincaid</ENAMEX>'s new
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">memoir</ENAMEX> is more expansive than her fiction--and at times more moving--because in
it, she begins to explore some of the others.

            The story she has to tell is sadly simple: Her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Devon Drew</ENAMEX> died of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the age of 33</TIMEX>. The event was far from
unique, of course. Many <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> have died a similarly
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">frightening</ENAMEX>, needless death, and not a few memoirs have chronicled their last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX>. And anyway, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kincaid</ENAMEX> wasn't even all that close to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drew</ENAMEX>. He was the
youngest of three younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX>, all of whom shared a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> different from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kincaid's</ENAMEX>, and although he was sharp and curious as a boy, he threw away his
talents and made a fatal decision to glide through life on charm alone. After
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kincaid</ENAMEX> moved away, he grew up to become an irresponsible pothead <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rastafarian</ENAMEX>,
a boastful lady-killer, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gardener</ENAMEX> who toyed with becoming a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singer</ENAMEX> and gave
himself the stage name "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sugar</ENAMEX>." But <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the themes of My

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Brother</ENAMEX> is the overpowering gravitational pull of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>--even if
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">yours</ENAMEX> is so sick and infuriating and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doomed</ENAMEX> that you left the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> to escape
it. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kincaid</ENAMEX> finds out that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drew</ENAMEX> is ill (the news comes from a family
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">friend</ENAMEX>, since she and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> are in the middle of a months-long quarrel and
have stopped speaking), she flies to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Antigua</ENAMEX> to visit him and to offer
help.

            Critics
often praise nonfiction by saying that it reads like fiction, when all they
really mean is that it is absorbing and well written. In this case, the
comparison really does hold up. My 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Brother</ENAMEX> reads a little like a
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">lyrical</ENAMEX> mystery novel: It's clear from the very first sentence that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drew</ENAMEX> is
going to die, and what follows is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kincaid</ENAMEX>'s attempt to figure out what led to
such a waste of a life. She picks through childhood memories for a
foreshadowing of what was to come. There was, for instance, the ghastly
incident shortly after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drew</ENAMEX> was born, when he was lying in the arms of their
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mother</ENAMEX>, who was asleep, and red <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">ants crawled</ENAMEX> in through the window and nearly
ate him alive. And she adds a plot to her unfolding understanding of what
happened to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drew</ENAMEX> the adult. She plants clues--chance encounters with
acquaintances of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drew</ENAMEX>'s whose significance she doesn't grasp until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a hundred</TIMEX>
pages <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later</TIMEX>. As with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kincaid</ENAMEX>'s novels, what stands out is her obsessive
cataloging of subtly different emotional <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> in clear, looping, musical
prose. On a break from the bedside vigil, she returns to her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vermont</ENAMEX>
and wonders how she actually feels about her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Love</ENAMEX> always feels much
better than not-love, and that is why everybody always talks about love and
that is why everybody always wants to have love: because it feels much better,
so much better." With a scary honesty typical of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of her heroines, she
decides that her feelings for him are intense but probably smaller than love,
clouded by anger.

            
But this remains a piece of nonfiction, and
it's a handy reference point for anyone who wants to argue that the recent
ascendance of the memoir hasn't wiped out artful, ambitious writing. Far from
it. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kincaid</ENAMEX>'s favorite fictional themes show up in My 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Brother</ENAMEX> ,
and they gain from the real-life urgency. There's the messed-up sexuality of
Antigua, the way <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> are taught to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">virgins</ENAMEX> while <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> are encouraged to be
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">careless</ENAMEX> and promiscuous; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kincaid</ENAMEX>'s heroines have suffered from this sick
training, and here we watch it slowly kill her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>. And there is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kincaid</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>. The figure of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>--wronged by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> but stronger than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Atlas</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">selfish</ENAMEX> and prejudiced and quite possibly evil but once in a while capable of
infinite love--has dominated nearly all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kincaid</ENAMEX>'s stories and novels. In
My 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Brother</ENAMEX> we see the real <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCoy</ENAMEX> and she is, if anything, more
formidable than her various imaginary incarnations. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click for Kincaid</ENAMEX>'s
recollection of a childhood incident that remained buried in her memory until
hanging around with her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Drew</ENAMEX> died suddenly shook it loose.)

            
               My 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Brother</ENAMEX> is
a modest little book. And yet, although <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kincaid</ENAMEX> never says this so grandly, you
get the sense that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drew</ENAMEX>'s death somehow prompted her to look at life
differently, from a less narrow point of view, perhaps, and that the
discoveries this book relates might eventually spill over into her fiction.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kincaid</ENAMEX>'s stories so far have been about young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> of color born into a world
that absolutely fails to value them. Her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroines</ENAMEX> have been fierce and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">admirable</ENAMEX>, but their struggle to be acknowledged has necessarily entailed a
degree of self-dramatization--even, you might say, of selfishness. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroine</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucy</ENAMEX> rejects the meek role that life tries to assign her, announcing,
"I wanted to have a powerful odor and would not care if it gave offense." How
much rounder a note Kincaid strikes when she writes of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drew</ENAMEX>: "And I began to
wonder what his life must be like for him, and to wonder what my own life would
have been like if I had not been so cold and ruthless in regard to my own
family, acting only in favor of myself when I was a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>." After all
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these years</TIMEX>, she's still writing about survival. But as of this book, it looks
like she's made it to the other side.

         
      
   
