
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wild West</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> history is widely
interpreted as the pre-eminent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">refutation</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karl Marx</ENAMEX>'s social and political
theories. Ironically, though, it was in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 1890</TIMEX> and
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1915</TIMEX>, that something very close to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marx</ENAMEX>'s vision of class warfare
unfolded--not, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marx</ENAMEX> might have predicted, in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s industrial centers
or financial <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capitals</ENAMEX>, but in the mining and logging <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camps</ENAMEX> of the West. Lacking
a sizable middle class of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shopkeepers</ENAMEX> (who would arrive only after
<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War I</ENAMEX>), and undergoing intense and rapid capitalist development, large
portions of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nevada</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Idaho</ENAMEX> became sharply polarized along class
lines--"labor in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> in another, no in-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">between</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX>, with
government a football between the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>," according to the final volume of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">R. Commons</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">associates</ENAMEX>' venerable History of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> .

            Western
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">miners</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">loggers</ENAMEX> defended themselves and their jobs with rifles and dynamite.
They also created some of the most incendiary labor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> ever seen,
above all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Western Federation of Miners</ENAMEX>. Their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> were no less
violence-prone. Timber magnates and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> deployed armed <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Pinkertons</ENAMEX> and
strikebreakers as if they were baronial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">armies</ENAMEX>. When private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> failed,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> persuaded local and state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> to suspend due process of law,
arrest suspected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troublemakers</ENAMEX>, initiate mass deportations, and crush strikes
with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Guardsmen</ENAMEX>--using what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commons</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">associates</ENAMEX> called all "the
paraphernalia of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dictatorship</ENAMEX>."

            While writing Big Trouble , the late <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pulitzer</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Prize-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J. Anthony Lukas</ENAMEX>, who took his own life in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June this year</TIMEX>, may
have sensed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> in the conservative 1990s would resist being reminded
about these ferocious, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">long-ago</TIMEX> American upheavals. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lukas</ENAMEX>' penchant for epic
had served him well in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Common Ground</ENAMEX> , his account of racial turmoil in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '60s and '70s</TIMEX>. But, by all reports, he was depressed about
the prospects for a large tome about <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> class conflict.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>, after all, has been blessed (we are constantly told) with a dynamic,
egalitarian sort of capitalism, one that has always rewarded individual
initiative and confounded class distinctions. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lukas</ENAMEX>' book runs afoul of this
conventional wisdom in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> ways: <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>, by describing a world (as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woody West</ENAMEX>
complains in a dismissive review of Big Trouble for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> ) in which there was "no middle term" between plutocrats and wage
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">slaves</ENAMEX>; and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>, by appearing to ignore what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">West</ENAMEX> contends is "the most
remarkable fact of the capital consolidation of those <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, especially in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West</ENAMEX>: the permeable nature of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">'class'</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lukas</ENAMEX> knew better about such
pre-World <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">War I</ENAMEX> hellholes as the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Coeur d'Alenes</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">district</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Idaho</ENAMEX>; or Cripple
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Creek</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leadville</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX>; or the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Comstock</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mines</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nevada</ENAMEX>, as described
by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eliot Lord</ENAMEX>:

            View their work!
Descending from the surface in shaft-cages, they enter narrow <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">galleries</ENAMEX> where
the air is scarce respirable. By the dim light of their lanterns, a dingy rock
surface, braced by rotting props, is visible. The stenches of decaying
vegetable matter, hot foul <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> and human excretions intensify the effects of
the heat. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> throw off their clothes. ... Only <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a light breech</NUMEX>-cloth covers
their hips and thick-soled shoes protect their feet from the scorching rocks
and steaming rills of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>.

            In telling
of these <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> places, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lukas</ENAMEX> had to challenge some powerful reassuring myths
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about our past</TIMEX>.

            
He decided to focus on a particular story: the
murder, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1905</TIMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Idaho</ENAMEX>'s former <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">44-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steunenberg</ENAMEX>. Considered a moderate on labor issues, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steunenberg</ENAMEX> had been
elected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> by a wide margin in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1896</TIMEX>, with the support of the Populists
and organized labor. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Three years later</TIMEX>, however, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steunenberg</ENAMEX> approved the
deployment of black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> and the use of preventive detention "bull pens" to
squelch labor unrest in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Coeur d'Alenes</ENAMEX> mining <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">camps</ENAMEX>. Denied re-election in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1900</TIMEX>, he retired to his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">hometown</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Caldwell</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about 30 miles</NUMEX> west of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boise</ENAMEX>,
forgotten by most of his fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Idahoans</ENAMEX>--but not by the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">aggrieved</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">miners</ENAMEX>. On
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the evening</TIMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 30, 1905</TIMEX>, as he walked through his front gate, a bomb blast
blew him to pieces. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Idaho</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> immediately suspected that militant miners
were responsible.

            The job
of investigating the murder fell to the celebrated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pinkerton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">detective</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James</ENAMEX>
McParland, who had broken up the notorious <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Molly Maguire</ENAMEX> labor terrorist groups
in the anthracite fields of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30 years earlier</TIMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Caldwell</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McParland</ENAMEX> quickly apprehended a drifter and sometime <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">associate</ENAMEX> of various union
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">miners</ENAMEX> who called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">himself Harry Orchard</ENAMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Orchard</ENAMEX>'s hotel <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>, police
discovered materials for rigging up a bomb. After prolonged coaxing by
McParland, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orchard</ENAMEX> confessed to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steunenberg</ENAMEX>'s murder--and, with the clear
impression that he could save his own neck by naming others, he went on to
implicate <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Denver</ENAMEX>-based <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Western Federation of Miners</ENAMEX>,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of whom, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William D.</ENAMEX> ("<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Big Bill"</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Haywood</ENAMEX>, had co-founded an even more
notorious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Industrial Workers of the World</ENAMEX>.

            The arrest of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Haywood</ENAMEX> and the others in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> and their
removal on a secret <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">train</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Idaho</ENAMEX> (in what amounted to a legal kidnapping)
brought an outraged response from such relatively conservative labor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Samuel Gompers</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Federation of Labor</ENAMEX>, as well as from such
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">radicals</ENAMEX> as the socialist <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eugene Debs</ENAMEX>. The defense, in turn, acquired
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s most famous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarence Darrow</ENAMEX>. And after a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a half</NUMEX> of legal wrangling and nationwide protest demonstrations,
followed by a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three-month</TIMEX> trial, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Darrow</ENAMEX> won an acquittal for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Haywood</ENAMEX>, mainly on
the grounds that <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Orchard</ENAMEX>'s testimony was unreliable. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A few months later</TIMEX>,
another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> acquitted one of the other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WFM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, and charges against the third
were then dropped. Only the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">wretched Orchard</ENAMEX> wound up getting convicted, and
(following the commutation of his death sentence) he spent the rest of his life
in an <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Idaho</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">penitentiary</ENAMEX>.

            It's easy
to see what drew <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lukas</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Steunenberg</ENAMEX> episode: a tale of murder that is
still shrouded in mystery; along with a long-forgotten cause

               <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">célèbre</ENAMEX> populated by such larger-than-life <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Haywood</ENAMEX>,
Darrow, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">McParland</ENAMEX>; all wrapped around a history lesson about the class
bitterness of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a century ago</TIMEX>. Indeed, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lukas</ENAMEX> was so drawn to the story and its
details that he sometimes seems to have lost his bearings, trying to read
significance into every little shard of information that his research had
uncovered.

            
As a result of these huge authorial efforts,
Big Trouble is bigger than it had to be. It includes long digressions on
subjects ranging from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> origins of private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">detective</ENAMEX> work to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">gradings</ENAMEX> along the circuitous railroad route from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Denver</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boise</ENAMEX>. The major
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> receive ample biographical treatments, but so do <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of other
figures, famous and obscure, who had only fleeting links to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lukas</ENAMEX>' story. The
book certainly rewards <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> whenever it returns to the main story. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lukas</ENAMEX>'
mastery of historical events and contexts, and his ability to dramatize them,
was acute. But it is a shame, in an age of blockbuster publishing, that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lukas</ENAMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> either did not or could not prevail upon him to lighten up, on himself
and on his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Historians</ENAMEX> may also question
whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steunenberg</ENAMEX> affair, on its own, touched off, in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lukas</ENAMEX>' words, "a
struggle for the soul of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>." To be sure, the larger industrial conflicts
of the period amounted to such a struggle. And to his credit, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lukas</ENAMEX>, for all
his obvious sympathies with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>, was scrupulous in assessing the events
surrounding the murder. (In his epilogue, he offered compelling, albeit
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">circumstantial</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">bits</NUMEX> of evidence that strongly suggest that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Haywood</ENAMEX> and the
others actually were involved in an assassination plot.) But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lukas</ENAMEX> never fully
clarified why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steunenberg</ENAMEX>'s murder and its aftermath were as pivotal as his
subtitle implies they were. In fact, the immediate result of the trials was to
widen the breach between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Haywood</ENAMEX> (who became increasingly radical) and his more
cautious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WFM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">associates</ENAMEX> (who wound up pulling back from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">revolutionary</ENAMEX> IWW).
In this sense, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lukas</ENAMEX>' story may have been important as part of the struggle
over the future of organized labor, but less so as a struggle over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">soul</ENAMEX>, at least when compared with the truly momentous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Homestead</ENAMEX> and Pullman
strikes of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1890s</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Triangle Shirt Waist Co.</ENAMEX> fire of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1911</TIMEX>, or any of the
other more familiar set pieces of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">turn-of-the-century</TIMEX> labor history.

            Still, it is the rare author
who can re-create, with so much passion and exactness, aspects of our history
that most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> would just as soon forget. Anyone who knew <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Lukas</ENAMEX> even
slightly was deeply impressed by his boundless, open-minded curiosity about the
injustices of modern life, along with his stubborn reportorial integrity about
getting to the very bottom of any story as best he could. Its flaws aside,
Big Trouble is a brave book that exhibits those qualities bounteously.
And so its tale is truly tragic.

         
      
   
