
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">People's Hitler</ENAMEX>

            It is one of the paradoxes
of modern biography that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adolf Hitler</ENAMEX>, who came frighteningly close to
establishing his <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Thousand Year Reich</ENAMEX>, has seldom been taken seriously as a
political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>'s own day, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Churchill</ENAMEX> called him a "guttersniper";
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brecht</ENAMEX> parodied him in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arturo Ui</ENAMEX>, a buffoonish <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thug</ENAMEX>
implausibly thrust into power; and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neville Chamberlain</ENAMEX>--well, enough said about
Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chamberlain</ENAMEX>. Afraid of being branded revisionists, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biographers</ENAMEX>
have been largely reluctant to acknowledge his political talents. Thus have
they given us <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> as "psychopathic god" and "unprincipled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opportunist</ENAMEX>," but
never as "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">statesman"</ENAMEX>--a title that, even in the age of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kissingers</ENAMEX> and the
Pinochets, has lost little of its luster.

            But, as
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Lukacs</ENAMEX> underscores in his study The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> of
History , the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dictator</ENAMEX> was not simply <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the century</TIMEX>'s most murderous
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tyrant</ENAMEX>; he was one of its most brilliant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>. Lukacs, a distinguished
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> of modern <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, has reflected perceptively in previous books on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>'s hypnotic allure. In <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Hitler of History</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lukacs</ENAMEX> adopts a
more historiographical approach, examining, comparing, and correcting the
interpretations of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biographers</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lukacs</ENAMEX>' courtly prose can mask the
bold scope of his ambitions: Besides critiquing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> biographies, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lukacs</ENAMEX> is
also advancing his own reading of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>, says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lukacs</ENAMEX>, was a peculiarly modern demagogue.
More than any of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peers</ENAMEX>, including <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mussolini</ENAMEX>, he created an electrifying
fusion of aggressive nationalism and populist rhetoric. An early practitioner
of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">McLuhanesque</ENAMEX> politics who was "extraordinarily aware of his pictorial
image," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> "understood the popular effect of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cult</ENAMEX> of the 'star' " on
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX>, the ordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Germans</ENAMEX> who admired and even loved him. ("If only the
FÃ¼hrer knew!"--the cry of many ordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Germans</ENAMEX> who felt betrayed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX>
regime--suggests the depth of their affection.)

            Often
dismissed as a poor military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strategist</ENAMEX> intoxicated by quixotic ambitions,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> was in fact extremely adept at sizing up his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX>' weaknesses and
understood acutely the "supreme importance of land power" with the
"motorization of military movement." As a result, he succeeded, in less than a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decade</TIMEX>, in making himself the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ruler</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> from the gates of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX> to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">English Channel</ENAMEX>. Indeed, until his obsessive vision of cleansing <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> and conquering <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Russia</ENAMEX> overcame his pragmatic instincts, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> did
not make a wrong move. His victories emboldened him and his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Socialist</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">followers</ENAMEX> to visit untold misery upon their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lukacs</ENAMEX> writes, he "left
a more indelible mark upon <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the century</TIMEX> than any other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dictator</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lenin</ENAMEX> or a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stalin</ENAMEX> or a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mao</ENAMEX>."

            
Much of the writing about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> falls into the
category of "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitlerology</ENAMEX>," a form of insipid voyeurism similar to that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">surrounding Kennedy</ENAMEX> or, perhaps closer to the point, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack the Ripper</ENAMEX>. The
details about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personality titillate</ENAMEX>, but they rarely edify, even
though <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>'s fanatical devotion to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> does provide a rather chilling
rebuttal to a faith in family values.

            Lukacs
does not himself always resist the temptation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hitlerology</ENAMEX>. He tells of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>'s love of romantic poetry and "creamy <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Viennese</ENAMEX> cakes"--the only
exceptions, apparently, to his unyielding asceticism--and speculates, in
ponderous footnotes studded with citations from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kierkegaard</ENAMEX>, on the theological
nature of evil. (A <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lukacs</ENAMEX> whitewashes the record of the church
as "the least compromised and ... sometimes even inspiring" of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX>. If
so, why has the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> subsequently apologized for its cozying up to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>?)
For the most part, though, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lukacs</ENAMEX> concentrates on the disturbing specter that
has come to haunt <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> scholarship--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">admirers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defenders</ENAMEX>, open
and hidden." The most notorious <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> apologist is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British Holocaust</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">revisionist David Irving</ENAMEX>, who has worked tirelessly to exculpate the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FÃ</ENAMEX>¼hrer
while lashing out at his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adversaries</ENAMEX>. As <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lukacs</ENAMEX> observes, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irving</ENAMEX> has not
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">scrupled</ENAMEX> to invent "evidence" that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stalin</ENAMEX> planned to attack <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> before
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>'s invasion and that "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> again and again ordered the 'Jewish problem'
set aside until the war was won."

            Since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid-'80s</TIMEX>, a subtler but arguably more insidious
form of revisionism has come from such reputable <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ernest</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nolte</ENAMEX> and the late <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andreas Hillgruber</ENAMEX>, both leading <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> in the
Historikerstreit , a quarrel among <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historians</ENAMEX> over the uniqueness
and meaning of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX>. While rebuking <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> for declaring war against
the Western <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">democracies</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nolte</ENAMEX> offered an implicit justification of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holocaust</ENAMEX> as an anxious, reactive measure sparked by "the previous practices
and exterminations by the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Russian Revolution</ENAMEX>." For <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nolte</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stalin</ENAMEX> was the
original sinner. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hillgruber</ENAMEX> added his own provocative twist by proclaiming that
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historians</ENAMEX> were obliged to "identify" with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastern</ENAMEX> front who were protecting <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bolshevism</ENAMEX>. The thrust of such
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">interpretations</ENAMEX>, as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lukacs</ENAMEX> argues, was to rehabilitate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> as a German
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">patriot</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-Communist</ENAMEX>.

            Although
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lukacs</ENAMEX> has some--in my view, rather too much--compassion for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nolte's</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hillgruber</ENAMEX>'s "bitterness against [the] <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-</ENAMEX>nationalist consensus among German
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">historians</ENAMEX>," he concludes that "their explanations amounted to a kind of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">relativization</ENAMEX>" to the point of "defending <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>." And yet, that shrewd
critique of revisionism notwithstanding, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lukacs</ENAMEX>' own corrections to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>
history are idiosyncratic and often wrong. For instance, we are told that
"foreign policy was secondary [to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> unity] in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>'s intentions,"
although <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> saw these aims as inseparable--invoking, in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mein Kampf</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>'s need for "living space" ( lebensraum ) and her "moral right to
acquire foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">land</ENAMEX> and soil." Indeed, as the self-proclaimed imperial savior
of an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aryan Europe</ENAMEX> weakened by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> and socialism, he exalted the quest for
lebensraum as a struggle to the death. No less questionable is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lukacs</ENAMEX>'
claim that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>, for all his hatred of the inferior races, was not a
biological racist. Lukacs gleans this insight from a solitary remark by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>,
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1945</TIMEX>, to the effect that "from the genetic point of view there is no such
thing as the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">race</ENAMEX>." If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> was less a biological racist than an
extreme <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nationalist</ENAMEX>, as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lukacs</ENAMEX> asserts, this was a distinction without a
difference to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">the millions</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Germans</ENAMEX> instructed in such particulars of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Darwinist</ENAMEX> "science" as how to tell a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> skull from an Aryan <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>.

            
Why would Lukacs underplay <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> the racist?
Because he is more intent upon painting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> as a populist--a creature of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baleful</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age</TIMEX> that wrested authority from responsible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elites</ENAMEX> and enshrined
popular sovereignty. Lukacs, who came of age in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hungary</ENAMEX> while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> was in
power, has long described himself as a "reactionary"--not a Gingrichian
rightist but a partisan of the patrician mores of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">pre-World War I</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>.
Because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> took to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> and disregarded the niceties of bourgeois
politics, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lukacs</ENAMEX> considers him an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-bourgeois</ENAMEX> "revolutionary" and a friend
of the proletariat. While <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lukacs</ENAMEX> is right to point out that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> "was
contemptuous of [the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bourgeoisie</ENAMEX>'s] caution, of their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">thrift</ENAMEX>, ... of their
desire for safety," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> did not crush their political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> and send them
in droves to labor <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camps</ENAMEX>--this fate he reserved for the organized working
class. Nor did <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> try to abolish capitalism, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lukacs</ENAMEX> suggests, although,
like his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adversary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roosevelt</ENAMEX>, he did expand state supervision of private
industry. Despite his penchant for revolutionary rhetoric, his inspired use of
modern techniques of collective mobilization, and his willingness to strike up
a tactical alliance with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stalin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> remained a committed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foe</ENAMEX> of what he
called "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jew</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bolshevism</ENAMEX>," and indeed, of all leveling ideologies.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lukacs</ENAMEX> often writes as
though <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>, or rather <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitlerism</ENAMEX>, triumphed in the war. That's because, for
Lukacs, the horror of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hitlerism</ENAMEX> is simply an expression of the horror of modern
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">collectivism</ENAMEX>. "In <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> sense <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>'s vision survived him," notes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lukacs</ENAMEX>.
"During <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the twentieth century</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">compound</ENAMEX> of nationalism with socialism has
become the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly</NUMEX> universal practice for all <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> ... [w]<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">hether</ENAMEX> they call
themselves socialist or not. ... We are all national <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">socialists</ENAMEX> now." Does this
mean that the difference between, say, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Swedish</ENAMEX> social democracy and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> state
capitalism is less significant than the similarities? Or between <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Afrikaner</ENAMEX>
white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supremacism</ENAMEX> and post-apartheid multiracial democracy? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lukacs</ENAMEX> would not,
of course, go that far. But in using <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> to illustrate the threat of power
passing into the hands of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masses</ENAMEX>, he ignores an important distinction
between mass <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">societies</ENAMEX>: those ruled by charismatic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dictators</ENAMEX>, unchecked by
popular representation; and those governed by democratic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX>. With
some exceptions, we are all <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">democrats</ENAMEX> now. Perverse as this may sound, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>
is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> reason why.

         
      
   
