
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sexual Behavior</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Scientist</ENAMEX>

            In his fine <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX> book,
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bad Blood</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Jones</ENAMEX> exposed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX>'s most shameful
episodes: the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tuskegee</ENAMEX> experiment, in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> enlisted a group of black
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> with syphilis and, without their knowledge or consent, withheld treatment
so as to observe the natural progress of the disease. In this new biography,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> outs <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alfred Kinsey</ENAMEX>. He "lived with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> terrible secrets: He was both a
homosexual and a masochist." Everything else about him seems to follow. "The
answer" to why he worked so hard "lies in his private life." His "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">spring</TIMEX>-coil
vitality" was the product not of a naturally energetic constitution, or a
passion for science, or even old-fashioned ambition, but of "stupendous guilt."
He presented himself as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> of science but actually he was a "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crypto-reformer</ENAMEX>
who spent <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">his every waking hour</TIMEX> attempting to change the sexual mores and sex
offender laws of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>." (Not exactly. He also spent 15 years
researching gall wasps and was a serious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gardener</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hiker</ENAMEX>, and record
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">collector</ENAMEX>.)

            Others
may have had an inkling of his secret agenda but only now can the truth be
told. It is the following: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kinsey</ENAMEX> believed, in the words of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> informant, that
"if only he could get the facts to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> life would be a lot happier and less
guilt ridden." And moreover, "he was a great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">champion</ENAMEX> of tolerance and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">liberality</ENAMEX>." Apparently only a guilt-ridden masochistic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homosexual</ENAMEX> could be
driven by such <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suspect</ENAMEX> and cleverly disguised views. Kinsey fooled many. "The
irony, of course," is that many distinguished <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> who knew his work
intimately "were not able to see beneath the surface." "Incredible as it may
seem," the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX> and senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">premier</ENAMEX> medical publishing
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">house</ENAMEX> also "failed to question <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kinsey</ENAMEX>'s scholarly objectivity." Not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">perpetrator</ENAMEX> of all these deceptions may not have been
the "successor to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Darwin</ENAMEX>," as many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contemporaries</ENAMEX> thought, but he was arguably
the paradigmatic social <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientist</ENAMEX> of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who more than any
other made the study of human sexuality a respectable and legitimate field of
inquiry. The author of the groundbreaking best sellers <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Sexual Behavior</ENAMEX> in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Human Male</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1948</TIMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sexual Behavior in the Human Female</ENAMEX>
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1953</TIMEX>), he was the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pioneer</ENAMEX> in finding out what <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> actually do in bed and
with whom we do it. That <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kinsey</ENAMEX> had intense homoerotic relationships with his
graduate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> is certain. He was into group sex and he masturbated. His
sexual life unquestionably extended beyond the missionary position within
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">monogamous</ENAMEX> marriage, but then, as his--and much subsequent--research showed, so
does that of most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>. More than likely, he had "<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">orgasms</ENAMEX> derived from
homosexual contact." But he also had a long, loving, and complex sexual
relationship with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Clara</ENAMEX>, and found stimulation in heterosexual
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pornography</ENAMEX>. Whether he was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homosexual</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> can decide for
themselves.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>'
relentlessly hostile readings of the evidence, however, make this difficult.
When a graduate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> on a field trip writes about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kinsey</ENAMEX>'s "prick nibblin
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tent</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> suggests that "it is not hard to suspect that oral sex was going
on under canvas tops," because "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Berland</ENAMEX> was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who usually meant what he
said." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Berland</ENAMEX> also said that the retiring <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana University</ENAMEX> had
"shriveled balls," and worried lest he himself "be castrated for biting a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">coed</ENAMEX>'s tit.") <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kinsey</ENAMEX>'s assignment of "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">0</ENAMEX>" to the exclusively heterosexual and
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">6</ENAMEX>" to the exclusively <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homosexual</ENAMEX> in his famous scale leads <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> to comment:
"[H]ow interesting that he should assign this [<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">heterosexuality</ENAMEX>] no value." One
can only wonder what snide comment he would have made if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kinsey</ENAMEX> had flipped the
values.

            
The evidence for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kinsey</ENAMEX>'s masochism--mostly the
reports of anonymous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>--is much more difficult to assess. Consider <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pièce de résistance</ENAMEX> : On "one particular <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX>," in response to "his
inner <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">demons</ENAMEX>," and more specifically to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockefeller Foundation</ENAMEX>'s rejection
of a grant application, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kinsey</ENAMEX> allegedly hanged himself by the hand and balls
from an overhead pipe "long enough for this self-appointed <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Messiah of the</ENAMEX>
sexually despised to experience much pain and suffering, precisely as he had
intended." (Forget the mocking tone; it pervades the book. Any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reformer</ENAMEX> is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">invariably</ENAMEX> described as a "chronic" or "habitual" "do-gooder." Forget, too, the
absence of even the semblance of evidence for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kinsey</ENAMEX>'s inner <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> here as
elsewhere: Kinsey "must have felt" ambivalence about gardening because it
threatened his "fragile sense of masculinity.") A footnote reveals that the one
anonymous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX> for this episode of "self-torture" who is actually cited was
apparently not an actual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX> and that it can at best be dated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 1951</TIMEX>
and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1955</TIMEX>. In the note, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> also suggests that a "massive pelvic infection,"
which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kinsey</ENAMEX> suffered in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the fall of 1954</TIMEX>, may "pinpoint the most likely time"
and, of course, corroborate the incident. But back in the main text he says
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kinsey</ENAMEX> had an "infection in his pelvic region"--probably glomerular
nephritis , a different and more probable diagnosis--which would make the
public "cover story" (that a strep throat caused the problem) far likelier.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Readers</ENAMEX> can decide for themselves if they care.

            They may
not. Suppose <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kinsey</ENAMEX> were a card-carrying homosexual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masochist</ENAMEX>; it would
seem to have little bearing either on his commitment to tolerance or on his
scientific <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">practice</ENAMEX>. Even if his private life were relevant, once again <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>'
unrelieved disdain for his subject obscures any possible connections. Kinsey
never did anything for innocent reasons. Even when he tried to write
well he was "craft[ing] his prose with the care of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> for whom words are
weapons." He can't win. On <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> page he is charged with listening to music
analytically, in keeping with his general penchant to dominate, and on the next
with barely keeping from having an erection listening to the songs of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Hugo</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf</ENAMEX>.

            Whatever the problems with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kinsey</ENAMEX>'s data, they had nothing
to do with his sexuality. He manifestly did not, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> claims, "place a
meaty thumb upon the scales" so that he was "virtually guaranteed" that he
would find what he was looking for. Again and again <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> himself reports that
Kinsey was "surprised" at this or that result. If indeed--following common
wisdom--he really did disparage "the sexual capacity of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>," the volume on
the sexual response of the human female nonetheless contained all sorts of
things he was not looking for. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Twenty years</TIMEX> before <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Masters</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX>, for
example, he discovered that, contrary to the then-dominant view, the great
majority of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> experienced not vaginal but clitoral orgasm.

            Of course,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kinsey</ENAMEX>'s statistics were and are open to criticism. His is not a random sample
and it's not clear exactly what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> it represents. That said, a
blue-ribbon <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Statistical Association</ENAMEX> concluded that
the interviews themselves were remarkably probing and that, under the
circumstances, a random sample was impossible. Most of us would respond to the
phone call or knock on the door from a total <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stranger</ENAMEX> announcing that we had
been randomly selected to tell them when we started to masturbate or how often
we had been unfaithful to our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partners</ENAMEX> with a polite "no thank you, not
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>, of course, claims that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">statisticians</ENAMEX> was
manipulated into supporting <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kinsey</ENAMEX> and that his efforts to improve the quality
of his statistical work were merely cosmetic. The remarkable fact is that his
numbers have proven to be so robust and that the archive he assembled--of
sexual history and sundry other <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">material</ENAMEX>--remains unrivaled.

            
Finally, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kinsey</ENAMEX>'s insistence that there was no
such thing as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homosexual</ENAMEX>--a subspecies of humankind--but only an infinite
shading of variation, a continuum of practices, seems to have had more to do
with his training as an entomologist than with the nature of his own desires.
He inherited from his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduate</ENAMEX>-school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mentors</ENAMEX> a resolute anti-essentialism.
This is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who, before he collected <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18,000</NUMEX> sexual histories, spent 15 years
collecting <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">300,000</NUMEX> gall wasps in order to argue, as he would again <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later</TIMEX>,
against the ontological reality of established taxonomic categories.

            A
self-righteous tone suffuses this biography: The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> clearly feels he has
exposed the dirty secrets that inspired his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protagonist</ENAMEX>'s "crypto" agenda of
reform. In fact, there is nothing "crypto" about his agenda; writing about sex
for a lay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1940s and 1950s</TIMEX> was an openly revolutionary act. It
was still illegal under various <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">19 th</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-century</TIMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Comstock</ENAMEX>" laws to
disseminate information about birth control in many <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>. Kinsey, like every
other social <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientist</ENAMEX> since the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enlightenment</ENAMEX>, was simply obeying the central
tenet of his discipline: that the scientific study of society is possible; that
the results of such study are a better basis for policy than, say, the Mosaic
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">interdiction</ENAMEX> against homosexuality. Moreover, the fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kinsey</ENAMEX> had a sexual
life, however nonstandard it was, would not render him incapable of objectivity
in writing about sex. "Value-free" social science does not demand that its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">practitioners</ENAMEX> have no values. It means that they gather and interpret their
material fairly and argue about its interpretations rationally. By these
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">criteria Kinsey</ENAMEX> fares well. That he exaggerated the power of biology, failed to
deal with love, and perhaps overextended the protective umbrella of tolerance
is beyond doubt. But overinterpretation or even misinterpretation are not the
same as bias.

            It is distressing that in this time of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> it could still
be said that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kinsey</ENAMEX>'s passionate interest in human sexuality could only be the
product of perversion. The book's cynicism is even more distressing,
symptomatic as it is of a larger cynicism that seems to have gripped our public
culture. We seem to believe that all human action is motivated not by the
desire to know or improve the lot of humankind, but only by the basest motives
of greed, power, and self-aggrandizement. Kinsey was of another age. "How
characteristically <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX>," wrote <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lionel Trilling of Sexual</ENAMEX>

               Behavior in the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Human Male</ENAMEX> , in its "impulse toward acceptance and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">liberation</ENAMEX>, the broad and generous desire for others not to be harshly
judged."

         
      
   
