
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Jews You Can Use</ENAMEX>

            The following are fields in
which <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> are believed to excel: gastroenterology, the violin, political
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">consulting</ENAMEX>, the domination of world financial markets, and particle physics.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> field in which it is believed we do poorly, however, is beating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> up.
We are, the stereotype has it, lousy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fighters</ENAMEX>, and this rankles. Some of us
respond to this slander by embracing, in the words of the cultural critic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Boyarin</ENAMEX>, our "sissy heritage" and taking up, among other things, the
study of <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Yiddish</ENAMEX> (not for nothing is it known as "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">mama-loshen</ENAMEX> ," the
mother tongue). Others move in the opposite direction and join the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX>
army, where <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Yiddish</ENAMEX>, the language of our sissy exile, is most definitely not
spoken. Still others take up <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice hockey</ENAMEX>.

            And there
are those who steel themselves with memories of our gangster past. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Men</ENAMEX> with
names such as <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Kid Twist and Gyp the Blood</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phil</ENAMEX> once roamed the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> ghettos. These <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gangsters</ENAMEX> were as tough as the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> and as powerful as
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mob</ENAMEX>, and when I discovered this fact at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 12 or so</TIMEX>, it thrilled
me. This reaction is easy to understand: I was, at the time, facing the
oppression of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-Semitic</ENAMEX> schoolyard <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thugs</ENAMEX>, and in my revenge-fantasies, Bugsy
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Siegel</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gurrah</ENAMEX> Shapiro were lining up on my side, blackjacks in hand.

            Of course, all this was happening when I was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX>. By the
time I hit <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX>, my understanding of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gangsters</ENAMEX> had become substantially
more nuanced. Great nicknames and fists aside, I began to recognize these
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gangsters</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fools</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thugs</ENAMEX> who preyed on their own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX>, robbed
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poor</ENAMEX>, and murdered their own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rich</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cohen</ENAMEX>, author of a new book titled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tough Jews: Fathers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sons</ENAMEX>, and Gangster
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dreams</ENAMEX> , doesn't get this fact. For <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cohen</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rolling Stone</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">magazine</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gangsters</ENAMEX> are the purest expression of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> spirit
and the means through which he defines his own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jewishness</ENAMEX>.

            
There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> books here. One is a very bad
book of social history, defined by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cohen</ENAMEX>'s tendency to make up facts--"imagine"
is his word--when he doesn't know something: "I do not know what [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yasha</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Katzenberg</ENAMEX>] looked like," he writes, "but I have tried to imagine him. I see
his eyes as mirrors, reflecting not what he is looking at, but what he will
see: <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">mountains</ENAMEX>, rivers, wars. I imagine him tall and slender, wearing a hood,
taking his time--something long prophesied, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nomad</ENAMEX> who has crossed <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wastes</ENAMEX> to
get here."

            The
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> book is his attempt to portray himself as a spiritual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heir</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jewish</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gangsters</ENAMEX>. He does this by striking a tough <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> pose throughout, a pose that
fails to hide his sense of physical inadequacy, which he blames on his
Jewishness:

            When I
was growing up, any mention of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> would make me cringe. Other than my
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>, I really knew of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> type of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jew</ENAMEX>: cerebral bourgeois
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>-to-college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suburbanites</ENAMEX>. Do <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> get drunk? Do <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> trash hotel <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX>? Do
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> defend themselves? Questions I never thought to ask.

            His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> is different, he maintains, by dint of his
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brooklyn</ENAMEX> roots. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cohen</ENAMEX> writes affectionately and ad nauseam about his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> and
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s aging, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brooklyn-born</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">schemer-friends</ENAMEX>, who sit in delis blowing
hard about the glories of tough <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX>, and these passages are charming only if you believe that being in a room
with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> just like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX> would be charming.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cohen</ENAMEX>
believes his book is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">revolutionary</ENAMEX>, a violation of a taboo against speaking
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gangsters</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>, he writes, "have pushed aside the image of the
gangster: Forget. Forget when you were bullies. When I tell old <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> about this
book, ... the blood drains from their faces." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cohen</ENAMEX> is infuriated by this
purported tendency to suppress the gangster past and is even more angered by
attempts to make light of it. "I once heard a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">comedian</ENAMEX> refer jokingly to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jewish Mafia</ENAMEX>," he writes. "The mere mention of a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gang</ENAMEX> broke up the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>. ... Sometimes, when I see this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">comedian</ENAMEX>'s bit rerun on cable, I
imagine <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pep Strauss</ENAMEX>"--a hit <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> in the hit-man <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Murder</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inc.</ENAMEX>--"entering stage left and cutting him belly to chin."

            
I will put aside <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cohen</ENAMEX>'s bizarre dreams of
violence for a moment to address the idea that the memory of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gangsters</ENAMEX>
has been suppressed, which, of course, is not the case. Just because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cohen</ENAMEX>
didn't know about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Siegel</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schultz</ENAMEX> doesn't mean everyone else didn't.
The subject of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">gangsterism</ENAMEX> has been well mined in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX> by both
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historians</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albert Fried</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Rise and Fall of the Jewish</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gangster</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Jenna Weissman Joselit's Our Gang: Jewish Crime</ENAMEX>
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Jewish Community</ENAMEX>--<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1900-1940</TIMEX> are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> recent additions to
the nonfiction literature, and films such as Once <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Upon a Time in America</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bugsy</ENAMEX> feature <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> criminality. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cohen</ENAMEX> is not "imagining"
history, he rewrites other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s research, sometimes mangling quotes during
his copying, as he did when he took a quote from a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1951</TIMEX> book, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Murder, Inc.:</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Story of "the Syndicate</ENAMEX> ," by , also about <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gangsters</ENAMEX>. Even
the title of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cohen</ENAMEX>'s book and its cover art--a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brass-knuckled</ENAMEX> fist--are lifted
directly from a book published <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight years ago</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Breines</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tough Jews:</ENAMEX>
Political <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fantasies and the Moral Dilemma of American Jewry</ENAMEX> , which analyzes
the psychological underpinnings of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cult</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> toughness born after
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>'s victory in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">1967 Six Day War</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cohen</ENAMEX>
hits bottom when he compares the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gangster</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louis Lepke</ENAMEX>'s flight from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice</ENAMEX> to
the plight of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anne Frank</ENAMEX>, and when he compares his own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX> to a drug
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealer</ENAMEX>. "When I think of someone like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tolly Greenberg</ENAMEX>, I think of my grandpa
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben</ENAMEX>," he writes. "The same restless energy drove both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> toward invention. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben</ENAMEX>
worked in a diner and was tired of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">clunky sugar</ENAMEX> dispensers and so converted an
existing piece of machinery, a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tea bagger</ENAMEX>, creating the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> sugar packet.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tolly</ENAMEX> worked in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">narcotics</ENAMEX> and knew there was a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southern</ENAMEX> market for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> and so
converted an existing piece of machinery, creating the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> morphine pill. ...
I would like to say <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tolly</ENAMEX> was working for evil, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX> for good, but I
don't know if it's that simple."

            This is stuff that defies analysis. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cohen</ENAMEX> has written a
book that he undoubtedly believes extols <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroes</ENAMEX> and explains a suppressed bit
of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> history, but what he has done is expose the architecture of his own
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pathology</ENAMEX>. He wants desperately to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thug</ENAMEX>, because that is the only way he
knows to be <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX>. Instead of writing this book--and book-writing is surely a
job for sissies--he should have gone out and beat someone up or sold <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>.
Then his pathetic self-loathing might have been exorcised.

            I am not opposed to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jewish</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">toughness</ENAMEX>. Breines, in the original Tough 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> , argues that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holocaust</ENAMEX> disfigured the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soul</ENAMEX>, turning the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> of fascist
persecution into the fascist persecutors of another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX>.
But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Breines</ENAMEX> is avowedly anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>, and he sees any expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jewish</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">self-defense</ENAMEX> as a sign of nationalism gone awry. To my mind, though, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jewish</ENAMEX>
toughness of the sort that was in evidence in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Entebbe</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Uganda</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22 years ago</TIMEX>,
when armed <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> flew <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">thousands of miles</NUMEX> to rescue <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">innocents</ENAMEX> from death,
was one of the great moments in post-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Holocaust Jewish</ENAMEX> history--a statement to
the world that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> will no longer sit idly by and watch themselves being
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">oppressed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> toughness was seen in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warsaw Ghetto</ENAMEX> uprising against the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nazis</ENAMEX> and in the sacrifices of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Schwerner</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Goodman</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mississippi</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1964</TIMEX>. Also, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lou Reed</ENAMEX> is tough.

            The
presence of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bugsy Siegel</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Kid</ENAMEX> Twist in our recent history does not mean we
are a tough <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. At most, it means we are simply a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like any
other.

            
               If you
missed our link to a comparison of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> versions of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mob</ENAMEX> history--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cohen</ENAMEX>'s
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Turkus</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Feder's</ENAMEX>--click .
            

         
      
   
