
   
   
      
         
            Without Malice

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cynthia Gorney</ENAMEX>'s new history
of the conflict over abortion could serve as an advertisement for an imperiled
form of journalism: the long, meticulously researched narrative of ideas in
which unglamorous noncelebrities drive the action. If that sounds off-puttingly
worthy even to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">devotees</ENAMEX> of serious nonfiction, then too bad for us. Some of the
best journalism of the last quarter-century or so belongs to the same
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">genre</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane Kramer</ENAMEX>'s and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McPhee</ENAMEX>'s and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Finnegan</ENAMEX>'s work for The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> and nearly all the late <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony Lukas</ENAMEX>' writing. It is getting
harder to do for the very reasons it is worth doing: It can require years of
reporting, which doesn't sit well with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">keepers</ENAMEX> of our buzz-driven
publishing culture. It demands of its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">practitioners</ENAMEX> a quality of
listening--even, alert, self-effacing--that seems increasingly rare in this
first-person age. It doesn't sell a whole lot of ad space.

            None of
this is to say that narrative nonfiction is some sort of selfless or inherently
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">democratic</ENAMEX> form. It's not oral history; the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> is there on every page, as
enticed by vanity as any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> is--maybe more so, because his is the kind
of journalism that aspires most nakedly to the status of literature. But at
least these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> confer a kind of dignity on their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX>, if only by
attending so closely to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s own explanations of what they believe. And
when it comes to showing us the means by which everyday <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are taken up by
history, how they shape it and are in turn shaped by it, there is no genre more
accommodating.

            In this tradition and with scrupulous fairness, Articles
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Faith</ENAMEX> brings to life the arguments and experiences of sympathetic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> on opposite sides of a great moral divide. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gorney</ENAMEX>'s setting is
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Missouri</ENAMEX>, which, as a microcosm for the history of abortion and the opposition
to it over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last three decades</TIMEX>, is an arbitrary choice; she seems to have
chosen it mainly because her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> sent her
there in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 1980s</TIMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX>, though, the conceit works--partly because
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Louis</ENAMEX> was the site of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> sit-ins at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">abortion clinics</ENAMEX>; partly because
it was a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Missouri</ENAMEX> law restricting access to abortion that inspired one of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>'s most important post- <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Roe</ENAMEX> cases, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William L. Webster</ENAMEX> vs.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reproductive Health Services</ENAMEX> ; partly because we are primed to think of
almost any Midwestern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> as "typical" in a way that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>
is not; and mostly because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gorney</ENAMEX> found <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> such fundamentally appealing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> there.

            On one
side is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judith Widdicombe</ENAMEX>, an obstetrical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurse</ENAMEX> who <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteers</ENAMEX> at a suicide
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hotline</ENAMEX> and can't help noticing how many of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> calling in are
pregnant--and desperate about it. This is the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late 1960s</TIMEX>, abortion is illegal
and dangerous, and at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Widdicombe</ENAMEX> works she has seen women
bleeding and blue-white with shock in the aftermath of botched
abortions--terrified <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, dying <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>. And so <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Widdicombe</ENAMEX>, "a big, smart,
opinionated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>" with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX>, a sweet, shy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> who runs a
newspaper delivery route, and a modest little <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">pea</ENAMEX> green <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> in a nice
neighborhood, begins, systematically, to break the law. It is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Widdicombe</ENAMEX> who
eventually runs the abortion underground in pre- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roe</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Missouri</ENAMEX>, telling
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> where they can find somebody relatively clean and relatively safe to
terminate their pregnancies and sometimes smuggling them into her own spare
bedroom afterward to suffer the aftereffects of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX> in
clenched-teeth pain. And it is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Widdicombe</ENAMEX> who, in the wake of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Roe vs.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wade</ENAMEX> , opens the first abortion clinic in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reproductive Health</ENAMEX>
Services of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Webster</ENAMEX> fame. "This was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s business," is how Gorney
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">describes Widdicombe</ENAMEX>'s thinking about what she does. "And, if you were a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurse</ENAMEX>
who took care of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>--for that was how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judy</ENAMEX> thought of her work in labor and
delivery, the care of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>--you did what they needed you to do, you helped
them have the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> or not have the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX>, they came to you in crisis, and you
eased them to the next place. Either way, it was a kind of delivery."

            
On the other side is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Samuel Lee</ENAMEX>, a would-be
seminarian with a ragged beard and the look of "an <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Old Testament</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prophet</ENAMEX> or a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monk</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lee</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pacifist</ENAMEX> and an intellectually serious one. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1978</TIMEX>,
inspired by the civil-rights movement and his reading of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gandhi</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX> dreams up
and then organizes the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> sit-ins at an abortion clinic, and so helps to
steer the anti-abortion movement from its polite letter-writing phase to its
angry street-theater phase. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lee</ENAMEX> is convinced that no one has proposed a more
logical time for "the moment of an individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s beginning" than the
joining of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">egg</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sperm</ENAMEX> for the simple reason that there is no more logical
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>. He compares his moral duty to rail against abortion to his moral duty to
intervene if he saw a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> on the street beating his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX>. He is a
purist but not a fanatic.

            One
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">virtue</ENAMEX> of having chosen these particular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>--a gruff, empathetic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurse</ENAMEX>
instead of a polished, pro-choice <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyist</ENAMEX>; a thoughtful, vaguely leftish
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catholic</ENAMEX> as opposed to a fire-breathing evangelic--is that we can live with
them for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500</NUMEX> pages or so. But, implicitly, the choice serves a more didactic
purpose as well. Articles of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Faith</ENAMEX> makes it abundantly clear that even
the most decent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> both sides have to offer--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Widdicombe</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lee</ENAMEX> who will occasionally talk to each other instead of merely hurling
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">epithets</ENAMEX>--can find no real common ground on abortion. Whatever compromise
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> come to on abortion won't be the product of a warm and fuzzy dialogue
between pro-choice and pro-life <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX>. (It is more likely to emerge out of
what polls show most nonactivists on the issue believe, namely, that abortion
should be, as the slogan goes, "safe, legal, and rare." Call it muddled or call
it nuanced, but most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> seem to want to preserve the right to abortion,
pretty much unrestricted, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first three months</TIMEX>, and to allow <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> to
limit it sharply thereafter. They want abortion to be legal, but they think too
many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> seek it out for the wrong reasons.) As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gorney</ENAMEX> notes, the
well-meaning <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> known as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Common Ground Network for Life</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Choice</ENAMEX>, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">national</ENAMEX> project that brings pro-choice and pro-life <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX> together in
discussion circles and makes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mediators</ENAMEX> available to help resolve their
differences, has succeeded mainly in inflaming <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partisans</ENAMEX> on both sides while
producing "extremely modest tangible results."

            The other advantage of this sort of textured narrative is
that it inevitably turns <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">up bits</NUMEX> of the past that more ideological accounts
leave out. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gorney</ENAMEX> gives us a fascinating glimpse, for example, of the
involvement of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clergy</ENAMEX> in helping <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> obtain illegal abortions in the late
'60s. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Widdicombe</ENAMEX> herself worked for something called the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clergy Referral</ENAMEX>
Service, a network of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">some 1,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Protestant</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ministers</ENAMEX> across the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> who
decided it was their pastoral duty to shepherd unhappily pregnant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> to
underground <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> willing to perform abortions. (They took their lead from
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rev.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard Moody</ENAMEX>, a liberal and outspoken <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Baptist</ENAMEX> who occupied the pulpit
at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Judson Memorial Church</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Greenwich Village</ENAMEX>.) This is the kind of history
that pro-lifers don't care to discuss, because it suggests the existence of a
moral, as well as a political, dimension to abortion rights. The idea that some
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> of God might regard their commitment to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> housing a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fetus</ENAMEX> as more
important than their commitment to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fetus</ENAMEX> itself is anathema to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lee</ENAMEX>. And pro-choicers are likely to ignore the abortion-abetting ministers
because their own history of the movement puts feminist <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX> more or less
alone on center stage.

            There are drawbacks to any
journalistic genre that requires the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> to stick to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one or two</NUMEX> main story
lines. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gorney</ENAMEX> introduces us to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX>, but it is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Widdicombe</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX> who propel the narrative.) Since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Widdicombe</ENAMEX> is apparently so
much less given to moral casuistry than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gorney</ENAMEX> sometimes risks leaving us
with a vague impression of abortion-rights <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX> as tough <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pragmatists</ENAMEX> at a
loss for loftier arguments, and anti-abortion <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">philosophers</ENAMEX> with a
common touch. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lee</ENAMEX>, whose dedication to both nonviolence and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catholicism</ENAMEX> soon
marginalized him in a movement that had become increasingly dominated by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">militants</ENAMEX> and evangelical <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christians</ENAMEX>, is perhaps even less representative than
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Widdicombe</ENAMEX>. (For a thorough account of the anti-abortion movement's turn to the
right and the new militancy of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Operation Rescue</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>
can refer to the recently published <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wrath of Angels: The American Abortion</ENAMEX>
War , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Risen</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judy Thomas</ENAMEX>.) Moreover, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gorney</ENAMEX> ends her
book in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>, with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> ruling in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webster</ENAMEX> . This is hard to
justify since the decision marked neither the culmination of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>'s
thinking on abortion (the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Casey</ENAMEX> ruling in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> was at least as
influential) nor an obvious turning point in the abortion wars. It caps her
story simply because it caps <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Widdicombe</ENAMEX>'s battle with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gorney</ENAMEX> will probably be
praised for having drawn unusually nuanced portraits of abortion <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX> on
both sides--humanizing them and in so doing narrowing the gap between them. But
her real accomplishment is something like the opposite. The more
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">compassionately</ENAMEX> and conscientiously she reconstructs <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX>'s views and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Widdicombe</ENAMEX>'s views, the more irresolvable their differences seem. It may be
that only this sort of journalism, with its sympathetic attention to the
intricacies of its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>' thoughts, could do justice to these
differences.

         
      
   
