
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pop Fiction</ENAMEX>

            I started
picking up The 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> , back when I was a sprout, in order to
read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald Barthelme</ENAMEX>. I think what did it were those faux-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Max Ernst</ENAMEX> collages
with which he occasionally ornamented his stories, which appeared so much
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">wilder</ENAMEX> than my received notion of what that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> was like, and the stories
turned out to be even wilder than the pictures. His surrealistic short fiction
was about as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">avant-garde</ENAMEX> as you could get on the mass market in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">those days</TIMEX>. As
the present volume reveals, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Barthelme</ENAMEX> also occasionally contributed to "Notes
and Comment," at that time the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> section of "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Talk of the Town</ENAMEX>." There's
nothing earthshaking about those pieces, falling as they do into the
walking-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">around</NUMEX>-and-peering or flight-of-whimsy tendencies of that venerable
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rubric</ENAMEX>. Still, it's hard to feature them appearing in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s version of the
same <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>. "I remember exactly where I was when I realized that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post-Modernism</ENAMEX> had bought it. I was in my study with a cup of tequila and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Y</ENAMEX>'s new book, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One Half</NUMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Y</ENAMEX>'s work is, we agree, good-- very
good. But who can make the leap to greatness while dragging behind him the
burnt-out boxcars of a dead aesthetic? Perhaps we can find new employment for
him. On the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX>, for example." In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1975</TIMEX>, this, and not a celebrity or a
promotional motive anywhere in sight (do I need to point out that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">William Y</ENAMEX> is
an invention of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>'s?).

            The term "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Post-Modernism</ENAMEX>" turns up again and again in these
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">essays</ENAMEX> and interviews, and it comes as a surprise to find it applied a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">quarter-century ago</TIMEX>, not to metareferences in knowing television serials but to
the work of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Barthelme</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coevals</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Barth</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Hawkes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Coover</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Gass</ENAMEX>, etc. Who still reads <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Barth</ENAMEX>? Although when you think about
it, these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>, who came of age in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1960s</TIMEX>, were <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Post-Modern</ENAMEX> even then.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reading Barthelme</ENAMEX> may make you think of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Surrealism</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pop Art</ENAMEX>, of various
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX> of what used to be called bricolage, but what came to my mind,
revisiting his stories after a long absence, was <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">the mile</NUMEX>-a<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">-minute</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">channel</ENAMEX>-switching in the monologues of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin Williams</ENAMEX>. Like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Williams</ENAMEX>, Barthelme
was a master ventriloquist with a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dish antenna</ENAMEX> in his subconscious. From "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A</ENAMEX>
Shower of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Gold</ENAMEX>," circa <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1963</TIMEX>:

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Yesterday,</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peterson</ENAMEX> said
to the television <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>, "in the typewriter in front of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Olivetti</ENAMEX>
showroom on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Fifth Avenue</ENAMEX>, I found a recipe for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ten Ingredient Soup</ENAMEX> that
included a stone from a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">toad</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>. ... Coming home I passed a sign that said
in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX><NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">-foot</NUMEX> letters <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">COWARD SHOES and heard a man singing 'Golden Earrings' in a</ENAMEX>
horrible voice, and last night I dreamed there was a shoot-out at our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> on
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Meat</ENAMEX> Street and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> shoved me in a closet to get me out of the line of
fire. ... My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> was a royal virgin and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> a shower of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX>. My
childhood was pastoral and energetic and rich in experiences which developed my
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>."

            Actually,
you won't find much of this kind of machine-gun improvisation in
Not-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Knowing</ENAMEX> , at least once past the bracing title essay, the most fully
fleshed apologia <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barthelme</ENAMEX> achieved, which <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">barrels</NUMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Husserl</ENAMEX> to "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Melancholy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Baby</ENAMEX>" to the past-due bills on his desk in mock-peevish diatribe. You can
imagine the voice successively issuing from a pulpit, a bullhorn, an onionskin
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">page</ENAMEX>, a teletype, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Victrola</ENAMEX>--and then suddenly there's the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>, speaking
plainly as himself, "I suggest that art is always a meditation upon external
reality rather than a representation of external reality or a jackleg attempt
to 'be' external reality." Savor that word, "jackleg," a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">quarter-second</TIMEX>
visitation by the ghost of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Horace Greeley</ENAMEX> or someone like him. Such is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Barthelme</ENAMEX>'s power when he's operating at full throttle--his piano seems to have
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">888</NUMEX> keys.

            
Unfortunately, most of Not-Knowing
consists of leavings, marginalia, occasional pieces that do not show him at his
best. There are some book reviews, which are acceptable but not much more; some
movie reviews, which are pretty feeble, with that literalism that bedevils many
literary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> when they come to dabble in the form (viz., the collected film
criticism of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dwight MacDonald</ENAMEX>); and some art writing, considerably more savvy
although many of the pieces originated as catalog essays and thus sometimes
betray a rather forced enthusiasm. There is a transcription of a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1975</TIMEX> fiction
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">symposium</ENAMEX> in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barthelme</ENAMEX> says relatively little and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> is mostly
subjected to vast snowdrifts of abstraction courtesy of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gass</ENAMEX>. There are a few
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>-era op-eds that are musty period pieces now. And there is a passel of
interviews that vary greatly in quality and insight.

            The enthusiastic and
scholarly wish to preserve the entirety of a given <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>'s work is
understandable and even endearing to a point, but one of the frustrations of
this collection is its repetitiveness. Anecdotes are retailed in pieces and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">retold</ENAMEX> in interviews; the same citations crop up again and again; I lost count
of how many times <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Barthelme</ENAMEX> attests to his debt to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beckett</ENAMEX> and explains that
his writing not resembling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beckett's</ENAMEX> is a paradoxical measure of his thrall.
None of this is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barthelme</ENAMEX>'s fault, of course. If I were to publish your
collected table talk you would be appalled--only your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouse</ENAMEX> and your deity
know how many times you've told those same <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> stories. Had <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barthelme</ENAMEX> lived
longer (he died in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>, at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">58</NUMEX>), the majority of these items would not have
been reprinted for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">another 20 or 30 years</TIMEX>, and then probably in the usual
dead-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> package by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Winooski Press</ENAMEX>, for acquisition by
selected academic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">libraries</ENAMEX>. Don't get me wrong: This collection has its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pleasures</ENAMEX>, not least of which is the reminder of how strong and unique a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sensibility Barthelme</ENAMEX> possessed, which sent me back to the incomparable
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">anthology Sixty Stories</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1981</TIMEX>). But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Not-Knowing</ENAMEX> is not unlike a
dead-rock-star <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">memento</ENAMEX>, such as all those collections of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jimi Hendrix</ENAMEX>'s doodles
and backup sessions that seemed to come out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every Christmas</TIMEX> until his estate
finally clamped down. The impulse is partly commercial, partly sentimental,
partly a wish to uncover <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">just one</NUMEX> more unsuspected gem. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Barthelme</ENAMEX>'s case,
this kind of packaging seems oddly timed, since his influence on current
fiction is if anything at a low ebb. But maybe, just maybe, in some circuitous
and stealthy way, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Not-Knowing</ENAMEX> will play its part in revising that lapse,
prompting young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> in particular to seek out the best work of an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
original, part philosophe and part <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">banana</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
