
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grisham</ENAMEX>'s Homily

            It has never been hard to
understand the appeal of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen King</ENAMEX>. His is the fiction of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">subconscious: id-lit.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Clancy</ENAMEX> is just as easy. He stands at the vital
intersection of military documentary and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Popular</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mechanics</ENAMEX> . Only
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Grisham</ENAMEX>, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> in the troika of leading <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airport</ENAMEX>-bookstore brand names,
remains mysterious. What does he represent? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nominally</ENAMEX>, his genre is legal
fiction. But true legal fiction--the work of, say, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott Turow</ENAMEX>--organizes
itself around the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courtroom</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grisham</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courtroom</ENAMEX> scenes are lackluster. He
seems more comfortable with the before and after--with the back and forth of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">white-shoe</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> who never leave the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>--than with showdowns for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX>. Had Grisham written The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caine Mutiny</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Capt.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Queeg</ENAMEX> would
have settled.

            Nor is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grisham</ENAMEX> particularly good at the kinds of things you expect from a decent
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thriller writer</ENAMEX>. Compared to, say, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Baldacci</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Absolute Power</ENAMEX> ) or
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Finder</ENAMEX> ( The 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zero Hour</ENAMEX> ), his plotting is pedestrian. When
it comes to character, he can do hard-working, naive, up-from-the-middle-class
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">associates</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">their late 20s</TIMEX>. He can do brilliant, crusty octogenarian senior
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partners</ENAMEX>. And he can do public-interest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> last names. But
that's about it. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grisham</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protagonists</ENAMEX> tend to be more memorable in the movie
versions of his novels than in the novels themselves, which is remarkable
considering that the movie versions aren't terribly memorable to begin
with.

            So why is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grisham</ENAMEX> so successful? The answer, I think, is
that his books proceed from a perspective radically different from that of his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX>. Most legal fiction begins with the criminal and derives the law:
It's what enters at the end, deus ex machina like, to separate the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroes</ENAMEX>
from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">villains</ENAMEX>. Grisham, by contrast, begins with the law and derives the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminal</ENAMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grisham</ENAMEX>'s universe, it is not the felonious mind that shapes the
legal world. It is the legal world and its attendant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX> that shape
the felonious mind. (Of course, lots of other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> see the world this way
too. It's just that they tend to be political-science <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professors</ENAMEX>, not thriller
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>.)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grisham</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">achievement</ENAMEX> is to use this inverted narrative to create a sense of purpose in
his novels--to make them seem consequential. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chamber</ENAMEX> , for instance,
was a wonderful novel. But it was also an incisive and brilliant argument
against the death penalty. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Runaway Jury , Grisham</ENAMEX>'s penultimate book,
was an intelligent and compelling indictment of the tobacco industry that,
because it was sold in the fiction aisle, probably reached <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a thousand</NUMEX> times
more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> than every other tobacco-industry indictment combined. To reread
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grisham</ENAMEX>--in particular, recent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grisham</ENAMEX>--is to be struck by how completely he is
devoting his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrity</ENAMEX> to the articulation of a passionate and decidedly
unfashionable liberalism. This has never been more true, though, than in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grisham</ENAMEX>'s new book. In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Street Lawyer</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grisham</ENAMEX> sheds whatever
lingering attachments he may have had to the frivolity of his genre and emerges
as a moralist--a skilled and worthy practitioner of the largely forgotten art
of socially redeeming fiction.

            
The Street <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lawyer</ENAMEX> is the tale, in the first
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Brock</ENAMEX>, a young, naive, up-from-the-middle-class <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">associate</ENAMEX> at
a large, faceless corporate law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C. Brock</ENAMEX> is on track to
make <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> when a homeless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> carrying a gun takes him <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hostage</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>'s
plush conference <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>. He escapes, but the incident jars him. He begins a
period of soul-searching. He quits his job. He leaves his cold careerist <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>.
He moves out of tony <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgetown</ENAMEX> and into an <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> in the bad part of town.
He joins a tiny public-interest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> representing the poor and downtrodden. He
begins to investigate why the homeless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> was so angry at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brock</ENAMEX>'s former law
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> and uncovers--as have many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Grisham</ENAMEX> protagonists before him--a dirty little
secret that his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> has tried to cover up.

            The book
has a lean, linear feel to it. Things happen to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brock</ENAMEX>, and he does not stop to
ask why. He becomes involved with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>, a fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activist</ENAMEX>, but she appears
only fleetingly. ("She lifted the blanket and tucked herself next to me,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grisham</ENAMEX> writes, in the book's sole romantic moment: "I held her firmly; if not
she would've fallen onto the porch. She was easy to hold.") The moment when
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brock</ENAMEX> decides to leave his high-paying job to help the poor comes as he sits at
his desk comparing himself to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mordecai Green</ENAMEX>, the public-interest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> whose
legal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clinic</ENAMEX> he is about to join. This may be the most abbreviated epiphany in
modern literature:

            I helped my clients
swallow up <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX> so they could add more <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zeros</NUMEX> to the bottom line, and for
this I would become rich. He helped his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> eat and find a warm bed.

            I looked at the
scratchings on my legal pad--the earnings and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> and the path to
wealth--and I was saddened by them. Such blatant and unashamed greed.

            The
phone startled me.

            Grisham, it is clear, wants nothing to stand in the way of
his central point--that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who surrenders all his worldly <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">possessions</ENAMEX> to
defend the homeless is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX>. To have Brock agonize, to have him spend the
bulk of the book desperately weighing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pros</ENAMEX> and cons of his decision, would
be to have him act as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> normally act in novels. And The Street
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lawyer</ENAMEX> isn't a novel, exactly. It's a homily.

            It is hard
to understand how <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grisham</ENAMEX> pulls this off. His books aren't being sold
exclusively to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Upper West Side</ENAMEX>. He is preaching to the
kinds of middle <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> that liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX> long ago gave up for dead. But
he manages to present politically unpalatable ideas with grace and
understatement. The Street <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lawyer</ENAMEX> avoids the kind of self-righteousness
that usually accompanies homeless activism. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grisham</ENAMEX> is content with the simple
and compelling observation that as a society we fail to treat the homeless with
the dignity they deserve.

            
At <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point, early in the book, an entire
family of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> whom <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brock</ENAMEX> had befriended dies on a bitter <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, after
being turfed out of their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX>. He visits their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX> in the morgue,
pulling back the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sheet</ENAMEX>: "I closed my eyes," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brock</ENAMEX> says, "and said a short
prayer, one of mercy and forgiveness. Don't let it happen again, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lord</ENAMEX> said
to me." That moment--that prayer--sounds like a cliché. But a cliché is
something said over and over again. And these are things that, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this day</TIMEX> and
age, are rarely said at all.

         
      
   
