
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Accidental Writer</ENAMEX>

            No <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>'s name, not even
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shakespeare's</ENAMEX>, has the talismanic effect of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chekhov</ENAMEX>'s. Speak that name to any
intelligent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> or theatergoer and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">eye</ENAMEX> turns inward, though not away,
and his mouth drifts into a soft, private smile. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chekhov</ENAMEX> belongs to
everyone who knows him.

            Thus a
new serious biography has a commanding, basic importance. And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anton Chekhov</ENAMEX>:
A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Life</ENAMEX> does more than fulfill basics. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald Rayfield</ENAMEX>, who
teaches <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> literature at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of London</ENAMEX> and has previously
written two critical books on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chekhov</ENAMEX>, spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Russian</ENAMEX> archives
(going through, among other items, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5,000</NUMEX> letters written by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chekhov</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7,000</NUMEX>
letters addressed to him). These materials had not been thoroughly examined
even by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX>, because the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> had wanted to keep
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chekhov</ENAMEX> quasicanonized. The result of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rayfield</ENAMEX>'s research is a book that
amplifies much that we have known and adds much in color and facet that has
been omitted or only sketched up to now.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rayfield</ENAMEX>'s prose is of the packhorse variety, bearing along
its load of information sturdily but not with much grace. Like many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biographers</ENAMEX>
of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">our day</TIMEX>, empowered by new research technologies, he is reluctant to discard
any of what he has been able to harvest. He includes minor stuff merely because
he has culled it. (Do we really need to know the eventual fate of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shopboy</ENAMEX> who
once worked for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chekhov</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>?) But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rayfield</ENAMEX> gives us a more rounded
portrait of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chekhov</ENAMEX> than we have ever had, less sanitized, and he deepens the
flow of paradoxes that runs throughout.

            The first
paradox rests in the first facts: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chekhov</ENAMEX>'s origins. His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egor</ENAMEX>, was
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slave</ENAMEX>. (The usual term "serf" gilds it slightly.) In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1841</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Egor</ENAMEX> managed to
buy freedom for himself and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Egor</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pavel</ENAMEX> became a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shopkeeper</ENAMEX> in
Taganrog, struggling but free; and there <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pavel</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anton</ENAMEX> was born in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1860</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anton</ENAMEX> certainly never forgot his origins. He once described himself as a "young
man squeezing drop by drop the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slave</ENAMEX> out of himself and waking <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one morning</TIMEX>
feeling that real human blood, not a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slave</ENAMEX>'s, is flowing through his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">veins</ENAMEX>."

            
This grim self-knowledge begets contradiction.
The origins of some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> explain to a degree their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX> and styles.
Turgenev, the scion of elegance, reflected it in his work. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gorky</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> of
difficulties, wrote much about the wretched. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chekhov</ENAMEX>, out of a childhood
that one of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> called "crushing anguish," ranged the full field of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">society</ENAMEX>, and always with a delicacy that still makes the world gasp.

            Writing, the art of writing,
entered <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chekhov</ENAMEX>'s life tangentially. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1879</TIMEX>, aided by a grant from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taganrog</ENAMEX> city council, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chekhov</ENAMEX> went to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX>, where most of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> had
already moved, to study medicine. To help pay his way through medical school,
he began to write--sketches and stories for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX>. Within a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">very few years</TIMEX>, he was established as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1884</TIMEX> he qualified as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physician</ENAMEX>, and he never completely gave up <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX> as his short life raced to
a close. (He died in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1904</TIMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">44</NUMEX>.) But, paradoxically, what had started as an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">adjunct</ENAMEX> to his medical education became his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX> support--fairly handsome
support, too.

            The
stories ascended breathtakingly in quality and varied greatly in length, though
he never wrote anything in grand "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> novel" proportions. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rayfield</ENAMEX> says in
his preface, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Biography</ENAMEX> is not criticism," and he assuredly keeps his word.
Each of the major stories gets only a small identification tag from him, of not
much critical value. Possibly he deals more helpfully with them in his critical
books, unread by me. But this critical tagging becomes even less helpful when
he deals with the kind of writing that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chekhov</ENAMEX> came to in his last <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>:
drama.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chekhov</ENAMEX>'s major plays-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Uncle Vanya</ENAMEX> , The
Seagull , <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Three Sisters , and The Cherry Orchard</ENAMEX> --have links
with his antecedent stories, as well as with events in his life. Rayfield
clarifies these <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">connections</ENAMEX>. But he does not come near conveying that, in the
whole of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Western</ENAMEX> drama, there is no precedent for the style and texture of
these quietly towering plays. (For an exquisite illumination of these matters,
see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Gilman</ENAMEX>'s recent study, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chekhov</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Plays: An Opening Into</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eternity</ENAMEX> .)

            But,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">vividly</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rayfield</ENAMEX> presents the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>: tall, energetic, socially scintillating.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">famous</ENAMEX> sought him out. The venerable <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tolstoy</ENAMEX>, a secular saint in his time,
called on him more than once; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tchaikovsky</ENAMEX> contemplated writing an opera with
him at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Women</ENAMEX> pursued him feverishly. (Yet--another paradox?--he was a
frequent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patron</ENAMEX> of brothels.) Involved though he was with a literary life, he
never abandoned <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX> as long as his health permitted. He worked heroically
when a <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cholera</ENAMEX> epidemic struck the area of his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country home</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1890</TIMEX>, he spent
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">81 days</TIMEX> crossing <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Siberia</ENAMEX> to the penal <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">colony</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sakhalin</ENAMEX> so he could spend
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three months</TIMEX> there studying the health conditions, about which he wrote a very
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">full</TIMEX> report.

            
Another paradox, contradicting his broad
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">humanism</ENAMEX> and also contradictory within itself, is his attitude toward <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>, a
subject that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rayfield</ENAMEX> traces throughout this book. On the one hand <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chekhov</ENAMEX>
believed that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian Jews</ENAMEX> could never be truly <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX>; he categorized every
new acquaintance as <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jew</ENAMEX> or non-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jew</ENAMEX>; in his letters, he frequently used a
slurring term for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>. Yet <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of his dearest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> was a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">painter</ENAMEX> who
greatly influenced him aesthetically. When the Dreyfus case was raging, clearly
the result of anti-Semitism in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chekhov</ENAMEX>, then in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, was a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fiery Dreyfusard</ENAMEX>. He was even engaged for a time to a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>. Rayfield
assists us with these contradictions by saying that, "by the standards of his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chekhov</ENAMEX> was a "judophile."

            The overarching paradox of
his life, lucidly detailed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rayfield</ENAMEX>, is the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chekhov</ENAMEX>'s health and
his attitude toward it. By his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">middle 20s</TIMEX>, he knew that he suffered from
tuberculosis, and he coughed blood increasingly as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> went on. When he
married in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1901</TIMEX>, he and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Olga Knipper of the Moscow Art Theater</ENAMEX>) went
directly from the ceremony to a honeymoon in a sanitarium. Why did this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>,
himself a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physician</ENAMEX>, pay so relatively little attention to his <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX>? The
only comprehensible explanation is that the vocation that had burrowed in next
to medicine had taken control, had insisted. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1894</TIMEX> he said in a letter to a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">friend</ENAMEX>: "Not for a minute am I free of the thought that I must, am obliged to
write. Write, write, and write."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chekhov</ENAMEX> was an ingenious
phrase <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">maker</ENAMEX>, with many of the phrases scattered in his letters. ("<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">All</ENAMEX>
gynaecologists are idealists.") One line, unintended as an epigram, stings
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">unforgettably</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1897</TIMEX> he was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX>, staying at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great Moscow Hotel</ENAMEX>,
when he began to cough <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood profusely</ENAMEX>. He sent a note to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> he knew:
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bleeding, Great Moscow No. 5</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chekhov</ENAMEX>." The terseness, the immense taciturn
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gravity</ENAMEX>, makes the note truly <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chekhovian</ENAMEX>. In those circumstances, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Astrov</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Uncle Vanya</ENAMEX> might have written it.

         
      
   
