
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Love and Death</ENAMEX>

            So many <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">I.B. Singer</ENAMEX> novels
have been posthumously published in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last few years</TIMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scum</ENAMEX> , The
Certificate , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Meshugah</ENAMEX> ) that death is coming to seem like just
another problem of translation for the great <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Yiddish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Singer</ENAMEX>, who
died in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>, wrote so much and so well in his long career that it would be
wrong to conclude that his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publishers</ENAMEX> are cynically raking their way through a
justly neglected backlog. Shadows on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hudson</ENAMEX> , published in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>
for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>, was written in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1950s</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Singer</ENAMEX> was at the
height of his literary powers. He had emigrated to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> from
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Poland</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">some 20 years before</TIMEX>, and though his translated work was already
acquiring a following, he was a long way from becoming the puckish <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">purveyor</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Old World</ENAMEX> culture who charmed the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> and won the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nobel Prize</ENAMEX> for
literature in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1978</TIMEX>. He still inhabited his own liminal realm--a <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Yiddish</ENAMEX> writer
living in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> creating fiction in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Yiddish</ENAMEX>. Shadows
on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hudson</ENAMEX> , produced inside the intimacy of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> language and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">serialized</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jewish Daily Forward</ENAMEX> , has an unself-conscious energy
and honesty that gives it, even after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">40 years</TIMEX>, a shocking power.

            Set in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Upper West Side</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1947</TIMEX>, the novel follows the lives of a group of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX> linked by <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX>, friendship, sexual intrigue, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Old World</ENAMEX> ties. Many
are from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Poland</ENAMEX>, but assimilation and war have blown them through <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> until they fetch up, in various states of spiritual and
physical exhaustion, in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX>. They gather in the spacious <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central Park</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Makaver</ENAMEX>, who has rebuilt the wealth he lost in the war
and reclaimed the religious piety that his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">associates</ENAMEX> have mostly
abandoned.

            These are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who have lost <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX>, hopes, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wives</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">husbands</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, illusions. They sit and argue, between mouthfuls of
strudel, about communism, God, the destruction of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Judaism</ENAMEX>, the horrors of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> culture. "I know one thing, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Shloymele</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Makaver</ENAMEX> says to one of his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX>-educated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physician</ENAMEX>. "Our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fathers</ENAMEX> were <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>, we've become
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>, and our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are ... well, I'd better not say anything." The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX> are also <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> in love with death. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanislaw Luria</ENAMEX>, who lost his entire
family in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX>, speaks incessantly of torture and the dead, until
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anna</ENAMEX>, his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, cries out: "You're starting with the horrors again! Why
should anyone want to come up to our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> when you speak about such
things." <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shrage</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mathematician</ENAMEX> whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> died in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Warsaw Ghetto</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">devotes</ENAMEX> himself to psychic research, desperate to contact her.

            But if
these wounded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">souls</ENAMEX> are in some sense ghosts themselves, as we are meant to
think, they are nevertheless carnal ghosts. The plot is set in motion when
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anna</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> of the pious <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Makaver</ENAMEX>, decides to run off with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hertz Grein</ENAMEX>. Both
are married--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anna</ENAMEX> to the morose <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Luria</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grein</ENAMEX> to the long-suffering <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leah</ENAMEX>,
with whom he has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> grown <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> whom he regards with a kind of detached
disgust. Having raised his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> without the religious principles he long ago
rejected, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grein</ENAMEX> finds himself horrified by their alien, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> otherness.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grein</ENAMEX>'s hypocritical disdain for his own family
is the natural state of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Singer</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>, shaped as they are by multiple
cultures--<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Eastern European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">piety</ENAMEX>, radical secularism, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
self-invention. It is in part to drown out these competing impulses and to
squelch despair that his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lovers</ENAMEX> fling themselves into each other's <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX>. Grein
is the central consciousness of the book, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who, once a brilliant Talmud
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholar</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Poland</ENAMEX> and then a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> of secular philosophy, is now a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">half-hearted</ENAMEX> mutual-fund <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>. His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> is filled with biblical
and liturgical ruminations, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nietzschean</ENAMEX> doubt, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> optimism, and a loud
wail of self-diverting <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">lust</ENAMEX>--all of which is expressed internally in a jumble
of <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Yiddish</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Polish</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Hebrew</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Singer</ENAMEX> is very good at evoking
the palimpsest imprints of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>' layered lives in a way that gives
them more modernist complexity than his rather conventional conception of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> and plot might otherwise have allowed for.

            He is
also good at making their highly personal adventures seem the outgrowth of
historical and metaphysical circumstances. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Singer</ENAMEX>'s decision to set his novel
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1947</TIMEX> allows the book to spin on a historical axis--the aftermath of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holocaust</ENAMEX>, the creation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>, the birth of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holocaust</ENAMEX>, for instance, does not simply inspire the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>' large,
despairing gestures; it filters into their casual foreplay: "Do you remember
how we once turned on the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas</ENAMEX> and sat in the bathtub together?" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Esther</ENAMEX>, another
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grein</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lovers</ENAMEX>, reminds him breathlessly.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the bracing elements in the novel is the casual
darkness with which his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> discuss the world. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mickey Sabbath</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">irreverent</ENAMEX>, renegade <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Philip Roth</ENAMEX>'s apocalyptic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sabbath</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> , would hardly raise an eyebrow here. "Why should it matter to me if
they massacre <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">types</ENAMEX> like these or burn them in ovens<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grein</ENAMEX> thinks,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">disgustedly</ENAMEX> contemplating the coarse <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> who have snubbed him and his
new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lover</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anna</ENAMEX>. "The tragedy is that they destroyed the good ones and left
this trash behind." Asked what became of her <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>, a profligate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anna</ENAMEX> remarks matter-of-factly: "It was thought he was murdered by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazis</ENAMEX> but
what's the saying? <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Scum</ENAMEX> floats to the top." The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX>, when he does
miraculously turn up to embark on a successful <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX> career, admits he
destroyed his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s happiness as if it were the most natural thing in
the world: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Well</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hasidic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> of a wealthy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>,
came on the scene and I ruined her. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">those days</TIMEX>, I wanted to ruin everything.
It was a sort of an ambition with me." This is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who, seeing a full moon
rise beautifully in the sky, feels moved to announce, "Oh, if only I could piss
all over it!" That God himself might be a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> is a thought that several
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> comfortably entertain.

            It would be wrong to see in
all this merely the warping effects of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holocaust; Singer</ENAMEX> is chronicling
something larger and more complicated than that. Most of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>,
despite <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Orthodox</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">childhoods</ENAMEX>, began their rebellion against God before <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">II</ENAMEX>, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '20s and '30s</TIMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> were stepping out of shtetl culture
for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a thousand years</TIMEX>. This was true of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Singer</ENAMEX> himself, who
has a good deal in common with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grein</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> merely added a
horrible twist to their rebellion. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ernest Jones</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freud</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biographer</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">famously</ENAMEX> observed that <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hamlet</ENAMEX>, wishing his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> dead, was unable to survive
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s actual murder because he was so crippled by guilt. In other words,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prince</ENAMEX>'s real tragedy was that somebody fulfilled his fantasy for him. One
might say something similar about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Singer</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>. Having rebelled in their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX> against Judaism's commandments, having come to revile its
restrictions--having, in some sense, wished it dead--they were forced to watch
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazis</ENAMEX> fulfill their fantasy by actually murdering the thing whose
destruction they inwardly willed. No wonder so many of them feel implicated in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">evil</ENAMEX>.

            This peculiar double death
adds anguish and guilty energy to the book. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grein</ENAMEX> has the fundamentalism of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fallen Orthodox</ENAMEX>: He sees only the faith of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> or a full embrace of sin.
He cannot believe in a middle way. Ultimately, he becomes a penitent, fleeing
his sexual entanglements, his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, his responsibilities, and taking up
refuge in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Palestine</ENAMEX>. This stab at return is both unconvincing and at the same
time what makes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Singer</ENAMEX> and this novel so interesting. For what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grein</ENAMEX> comes to
resemble, in his selfish flight from the past, from responsibility, from moral
choices, is nothing so much as a <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Yiddish</ENAMEX> Huckleberry <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Finn</ENAMEX>. He isn't going back
to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Palestine</ENAMEX>, he's lighting out for new territory. He has become an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> at
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last</TIMEX>.

         
      
   
