
   
   
      
         
            Regarding <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>

            Finally, a
laugh-out-loud-funny book on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adolf Hitler</ENAMEX>! This useless blurb is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only half</NUMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">jest</ENAMEX>. Books about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> tend to be draped in solemnity--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> make us aware
that they are taking on the evil of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the century</TIMEX>. But it's difficult at this
stage of the game to take a bold moral stance against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Der Führer.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosenbaum, in Explaining Hitler</ENAMEX> , writes in quite a different tone--with
a mix of amused detachment and mildly off-kilter enthusiasm. It's the same
desktop-detective approach that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosenbaum</ENAMEX> brings to his triumphantly
idiosyncratic <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> column for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Observer</ENAMEX> , as he burrows
through such issues as the meaning of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dylan</ENAMEX>'s latest lyrics or the
inexplicable popularity of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seinfeld</ENAMEX> . He asks--as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seinfeld</ENAMEX> might--what
was the deal with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>? What was he thinking ?

            The book
begins with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> pictures, which are on the cover. With a not quite
solemn air, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosenbaum</ENAMEX> raises the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Problem of the Baby Pictures</ENAMEX>--the conundrum of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>'s humanity, his rosy-cheeked normalcy when he was young--and then quotes
the film <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Claude Lanzmann</ENAMEX>, who calls the baby pictures an "obscenity."
Here I laughed for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Baby</ENAMEX> pictures of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> are eerie, but
they're not obscene. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lanzmann</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Klaus Kinskiesque</ENAMEX> outburst is the first
instance of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> effect on contemporary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>: the tilt toward the
absurd. Explaining <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> is a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>-comic, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>-terrifying account of
the trouble that this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> still causes in the mind.

            At first, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosenbaum</ENAMEX> threatens to present his own startling
solution to the mystery of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>. He describes his research expeditions to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Munich</ENAMEX> and rural <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austria</ENAMEX>, his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">quixotic</ENAMEX> searches for long lost documents
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pertaining</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>'s ancestry and psychology. In his last book, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Travels</ENAMEX>
With <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dr. Death and Other Unusual Observations</ENAMEX> , he had taken up the rumor
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one-quarter</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX>. Here he goes into other shadowy corners of
the biography--the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1931</TIMEX> suicide of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>-niece <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Geli Raubal</ENAMEX>; rumors
about irregularities in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>'s sexuality and physiognomy (what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">biographer Alan Bullock</ENAMEX> calls the "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-ball business"); the endlessly debatable
question of when exactly <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> made up his mind to launch the Final Solution;
and, thorniest of all, the question of his sincerity, the degree to which he
believed what he said and believed in what he did. It soon becomes apparent
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosenbaum</ENAMEX> does not wish to answer these questions. He is interested in how
other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> answer them. At some point his search became, to quote from his
previous book, "an investigation of the investigation." The world of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>
Studies--as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don DeLillo</ENAMEX> called it in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">White Noise</ENAMEX> --is going to be treated
as a subculture, not unlike the world of JFK conspiracy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buffs</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosenbaum</ENAMEX>
has been chronicling since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '70s</TIMEX>.

            Even
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who follow the literature on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> may be taken aback at the mass of
absurdity patiently evaluated here. It has been variously supposed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>
did what he did because of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) psychological problems arising from the
aforementioned single testicle; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) physical or sexual abuse by his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>)
"epidemic encephalitis" contracted in the trenches of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War I</ENAMEX>; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>)
unforeseen aftereffects of a hypnosis session that restored his eyesight after
he was wounded in a gas attack in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1918</TIMEX>. There is a range of theories involving
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fatal</ENAMEX> encounters with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>, among them <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> who incompetently
caused the death of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> during cancer treatment; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> music
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> who seduced his <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>-niece and somehow incited her suicide; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prostitute</ENAMEX> who gave <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> syphilis (this is a pet notion of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hunter Simon Wiesenthal</ENAMEX>). The most insidious blame-the-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> concept locates
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>'s anti-Semitism in his own putative <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> ancestry (for which no
reliable evidence exists). Unfortunately, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Explaining Hitler</ENAMEX> seems to
have gone to the printers too late to take account of a loony new book by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australian</ENAMEX> amateur <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kimberley Cornish</ENAMEX>, in which the blame for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> falls squarely on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ludwig Wittgenstein</ENAMEX>, who went to school
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> to read about it.)

            
Alot of the dark humor of the book comes from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosenbaum</ENAMEX>'s straight-faced attempts to lay out the rival theories of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>
Studies <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. He has a way of coming up with a quick summary of complex
proposals that clarifies and nullifies them in one stroke. For example, he
examines the widely accepted notion that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> "radicalized" his ideas over
the course of his career. He started off as an ordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">right-wing politician</ENAMEX>
and then became extreme. The fact that this "radicalization" is seen to have
taken place at many different points of his career--after the suicide of
Raubal, after the allegedly "spontaneous" violence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kristallnacht</ENAMEX> ,
after the almost supernatural ease of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> victories on the Western front,
after the first defeats in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> invasion--is testimony to its weakness.
But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosenbaum</ENAMEX> deflates it completely by cataloging it under the rubric "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">No More</ENAMEX>
Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nice Guy</ENAMEX>." He similarly disposes of those who try to find psychosexual
explanations for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>'s actions by dividing them up into a "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Party of</ENAMEX>
Perversion" and a "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Party of Asexuality</ENAMEX>."

            The book
ceases to be funny--and becomes scary--when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosenbaum</ENAMEX> observes his subjects
mimicking their subject. Lanzmann, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shoah</ENAMEX> , comes off as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">petty</ENAMEX> totalitarian. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosenbaum</ENAMEX> recounts an event at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>, at which
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lanzmann</ENAMEX> accused a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">73-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Auschwitz</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">survivor</ENAMEX> of participating in
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">revisionist</ENAMEX> propaganda. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">survivor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louis Micheels</ENAMEX>, had taken an interest in
a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">film</ENAMEX> that explored the ambiguous attitudes of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Auschwitz</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> who
had worked behind the scenes to save the lives of some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inmates</ENAMEX>. Micheels
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">invited Lanzmann</ENAMEX> to a discussion of the film. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lanzmann</ENAMEX> arrived, "forbade" the
film to be shown (his own word), called it an "obscenity" (because it showed
more <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> pictures!), and implied that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Micheels</ENAMEX> wished to rehabilitate his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">torturers</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosenbaum</ENAMEX> himself approached <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lanzmann</ENAMEX>, was abused over minor
procedural matters, and was told that the investigation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> had
become superfluous because "it has been done. I did it." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> for more
examples of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historians</ENAMEX> behaving strangely.)

            Despite <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosenbaum</ENAMEX>'s skepticism about definitive
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">explanations</ENAMEX>, a "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosenbaum Hitler"</ENAMEX> does emerge: a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> bent on a <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> from
the outset, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> aware of the enormity of what he intended, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who
consciously disguised his responsibility and, finally, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who thrilled to
the deceptions he devised. This is more or less the picture advanced by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">scholar Lucy Dawidowicz</ENAMEX> in her controversial book The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">War Against the</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1975</TIMEX>). Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historians</ENAMEX>--particularly those enamored of what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosenbaum</ENAMEX>
calls the "great and grave abstraction," the systemic rather than biographical
explanation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX>--have resisted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dawidowicz</ENAMEX>'s thesis that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>
conceived of the physical annihilation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> early in his political
career, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between the years 1919 and 1924</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-Semitic</ENAMEX> speeches from
that period are among the most violent of his life. On <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">several</NUMEX> occasions he
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">explicitly</ENAMEX> described the killing of large numbers of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>, and his speeches put
the basic jargon of "removal," annihilation," and "destruction" in place.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dawidowicz</ENAMEX> also marshals an astonishing sequence of quotations from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>'s
speeches in the period <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1939-43</TIMEX>, in which he maps in coded terms the progress of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX>: Each time he makes reference to "the laughter of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>," and
each time he observes that more and more <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> have stopped laughing. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Rosenbaum</ENAMEX>
makes even more of these viscerally chilling sentences, which are buried in a
footnote in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dawidowicz</ENAMEX>'s book. He sees a simple transference in their imagery:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> is laughing at the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>, not vice versa.

            I am a
little uneasy with the "laughing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>." It comes too close to the purely
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">satanic Hitler</ENAMEX> that one finds in theologically flavored theories. The image of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">laughing Jews</ENAMEX> may signal something deep about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>'s mindset, but it may also
simply illustrate his insane consistency, his brutal economy of language. He
wrote in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mein Kampf</ENAMEX> that one attracts attention by saying the same thing
over and over and over again. This is the methodology not of the pliable
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX> but of the monomaniacal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>. The baroque rhetorical tricks buried
in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>'s most heinous utterances help us make the most difficult of
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">biographical</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">connections</ENAMEX>--the one between the mature <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> and the young <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>.
What happened to the earnest, apolitical, cultural <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX> described by his
boyhood <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">August Kubizek</ENAMEX>--the one who went to the opera every other night
and filled <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">his days</TIMEX> sketching and writing? Why and how did hatred swamp him? We
have to face the possibility that his love of art and his hatred of humanity
were inextricably related. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosenbaum</ENAMEX> does pursue this theme--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> as a
self-styled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX> who painted not on canvases but on others' minds--but in the
end he favors the more recondite picture of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> as diabolical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">comedian</ENAMEX>.

            After reading <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosenbaum</ENAMEX>, I went back to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Mann</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1938</TIMEX>
Esquire essay, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Man Is My Brother</ENAMEX>," the most convincing picture of
Hitlerism as an "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>-phenomenon":

            Mortifyingly enough, it is
all there: the difficulty, the laziness, the pathetic formlessness in youth,
the round peg in the square hole, the "whatever do you want?" The lazy,
vegetating existence in the depths of a moral and mental bohemia; the
fundamental arrogance which thinks itself too good for any sensible and
honorable activity, on the ground of its vague intuition that it is reserved
for something else--as yet quite indefinite, but something which, if it could
be named, would be greeted with roars of laughter.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">comedic quirk of Mann</ENAMEX>'s essay--written at a time when laughing back at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>
still counted for something--is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> is never named. He is simply "he."
It's as if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mann</ENAMEX> made him up. In fact, he did: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gladius Dei</ENAMEX>," an early story,
tells of a strange young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> raging in disgust and envy at pornographic art in
a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">gallery</ENAMEX> window and resolving to bring down a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">fiery sword</ENAMEX> on a rotten
world.

            
               If you
missed the links in the article, click to read about an amateur <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX>'s
account of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wittgenstein</ENAMEX>'s influence on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> and to read about the strange
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">world of Hitler Studies</ENAMEX>.
            

         
      
   
