
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Unraveling</ENAMEX>

            In the presidential election
of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1972</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> could choose from among <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Wallace</ENAMEX> was a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">segregationist</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George McGovern</ENAMEX> was so impolitic he favored <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> busing even
though <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">52 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> opposed it. <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Sixty percent</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">electorate</ENAMEX> judged
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Nixon</ENAMEX> the least of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> evils. But then, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX> didn't
know that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks earlier</TIMEX> the incumbent had detained a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> in the Oval
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Office</ENAMEX> with the question, "How about the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk</ENAMEX> money?"--and he wasn't talking
about his school-lunch program. The reference was to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2 million</NUMEX> in campaign
contributions solicited from the dairy <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lobby</ENAMEX> in exchange for federal price
supports for their industry.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Journalists</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX>, and special <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> have made sure that even the
most ill-informed among us knows that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>, this complex <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who invaded
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambodia</ENAMEX> while opening up <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> and invented racial preferences while singing
the praises of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Silent Majority</ENAMEX>, was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crook</ENAMEX>. But in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1974</TIMEX>, even the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme</ENAMEX>
Court couldn't have proved that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> knew about the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk</ENAMEX> money. Or that he
once ordered his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief of staff</ENAMEX> to "[b]low the safe" of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the bulwarks of
official <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brookings Institution</ENAMEX>. Or that he sold ambassadorships
at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$250,000</NUMEX> apiece. But we know now, thanks to <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanley</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kutler</ENAMEX>'s remarkable book of tape transcripts, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abuse of Power</ENAMEX> . This is a
book that tells <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> stories: of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Nixon</ENAMEX>'s fall and of the tapes that
brought him down.

            Both begin in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1971</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> had
just printed proof, leaked by a disgruntled <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Defense</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analyst</ENAMEX> named
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Ellsberg</ENAMEX>, that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> had systematically lied to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> about the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Vietnam War</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>'s statesmanlike response was to fund a
secret investigative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> to bedevil <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellsberg</ENAMEX> and anyone else whom <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>, in
his overweening <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">paranoia</ENAMEX> and narcissism, deemed a risk to "national security."
The most infamous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">escapade</ENAMEX> of these "plumbers" was their last: a failed
They were caught, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX> became <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suspects</ENAMEX> in a conspiracy.

            
Immediately the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oval Office</ENAMEX> confidants began scheming to
protect what they portentously referred to as "the presidency" (meaning
themselves) from revelations that would surely issue from any serious
investigation of their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>: where they got their <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk</ENAMEX> money, how
they used the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> as their own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Internal Retribution Service</ENAMEX>, why they put <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24-hour</TIMEX> surveillance, how they forged diplomatic cables to frame
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Kennedy</ENAMEX> in a political assassination. "Just keep it as small a little
cloud as you can," <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief of Staff</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">H.R. Haldeman</ENAMEX> advised his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fellows</ENAMEX> early
on--which meant payoffs, from money raised off-the-books, to the hirelings
directly responsible for these enormities. They were pressured into leaving the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, testifying that they had done nothing, swearing they had never before
heard of anyone named "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Nixon</ENAMEX>." The bigger the sums, though, the more
intricate the cover-up.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>'s presidency limped to its denouement by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> of a grim paradox: His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lieutenants</ENAMEX> were soon suspected of conducting
illicit operations of such high stakes and complexity that only a senior
official would have supervised them. But the more senior the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> who was
suborned into taking responsibility, the farther he stood to fall; and the
better he knew the error of trusting this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> to protect him. It was only
a matter of time before someone who had seen how things worked inside of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oval Office</ENAMEX> would, when called before the prosecution, choose self-preservation
over loyalty.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Dean</ENAMEX>
was the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> to break. For months <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dean</ENAMEX>'s claims that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> was (like
himself) guilty of obstruction of justice simply pitted his own word against
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>'s. Then in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid-1974</TIMEX> a mid-level <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX> casually mentioned to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Judiciary Committee</ENAMEX>--assuming the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> already knew--that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> recorded
his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oval Office</ENAMEX> conversations. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Sixty</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> worth of reels, subpoenaed by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> and carried to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courtroom</ENAMEX> in a single lockbox, yielded a
"smoking gun": In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 1972</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> had ordered the (loyal) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> to warn the (
not so loyal) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> off its <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX> investigation. Not even offering up his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief aides</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Haldeman</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Ehrlichman</ENAMEX>, could protect <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Nixon</ENAMEX> from the
incriminating testimony of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Nixon</ENAMEX>. With the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> shading toward a
unanimous impeachment, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 1974</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> resigned.

            The story of the tapes, meanwhile, was only beginning.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> whisked them immediately to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Archives</ENAMEX> for safekeeping. But
as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-decadelong campaign for rehabilitation gathered steam,
protecting the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4,000 hours</TIMEX> of unsubpoenaed tapes became his new obsession, even
at an estimated cost of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5 million</NUMEX> in legal fees. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Only last April</TIMEX> did Stanley
Kutler, author of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Wars</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX> , and the advocacy group <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public</ENAMEX>
Citizen reach the settlement that now gives us access to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">200 hours</TIMEX> of
conversations classified by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Archives</ENAMEX> as touching "abuse of power."
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Only last November</TIMEX> did Kutler get access to the actual recordings from which he
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">edited Abuse of Power</ENAMEX> .

            Which brings us to the book.
It's been a flush <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">autumn</TIMEX> for political voyeurs, what with the publication of
tape transcripts from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JFK</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Cuban Missile Crisis</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LBJ</ENAMEX>'s momentous <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> year
as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kutler</ENAMEX>'s book, alas, is the most sloppily edited of the bunch.
When the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cast</ENAMEX> of The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Kennedy Tapes</ENAMEX> speculates whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Khrushchev</ENAMEX> is
pulling a "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Suez</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hungary</ENAMEX>," a quick glance at its introduction quickly reminds us
of that dimly remembered corner of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX>. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX>, in Taking
Charge, cusses a damning <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> editorial (a favorite pastime), a
footnote tracks down the article and quotes from the offending passages. To
read these books is to plant oneself firmly in their worlds.

            To read
this book, on the other hand, is to hold on for dear life while a tornado of
invisible winks, quadruple <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">entendres</ENAMEX>, and mystifying personages blows you
by--unless you happen to know, for example, that the "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes</ENAMEX>" on Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">124</NUMEX> is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">billionaire Howard Hughes</ENAMEX>, with whom <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don Nixon</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sr.</ENAMEX>, that is, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>--not to be confused with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don Nixon Jr.</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nephew</ENAMEX>) was
entwined financially in a way embarrassing to all concerned.

            
If the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Free Press</ENAMEX> hadn't been so eager to join
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> rush, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kutler</ENAMEX> might have realized he had even more scoops on his
hands than he thought. Consider <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ehrlichman</ENAMEX>'s reference to a certain "left-wing
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX>, [<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> name unknown] <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pomerantz</ENAMEX>, or whatever his name is,"
whose generosity towards the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George McGovern</ENAMEX> campaign raises <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>'s
suspicions. It would have required a minimum of effort, and would been useful
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>, for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kutler</ENAMEX> to have pointed out that "[<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> name unknown]
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pomerantz</ENAMEX>" was probably <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Peretz</ENAMEX>, now <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> in chief of the New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> --and at the time a left-wing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> and generous
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">McGovern donor</ENAMEX>.

            To pick
these nits is not to deny <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kutler</ENAMEX>'s heroic efforts to bring this <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">material</ENAMEX> to the
public. Already, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> have been filled with careful
parsings of the evidence presented here to reevaluate, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> more time, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nixon</ENAMEX>
legacy. (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Conventional</ENAMEX> wisdom watch: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Nixon</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">funeral</ENAMEX> wouldn't have
amounted to a polypresidential love-in had these tapes come out in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early '94</TIMEX>.)
This is vital work.

            But it is not the most vital work. The statute of
limitations has run out on these crimes. It may be that the best way to read
this text in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> ahead will not be with a magnifying glass, but through
the looking glass--as a prism to discern what the political culture that
produced <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> shares with our own. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, after all, elected <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>--and not
despite the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">paranoia</ENAMEX> and dread that runs through this book but, in some
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ways</ENAMEX>, because of it. What was his appeal to the "silent majority" but a
subtle invitation to think like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>: to believe that our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> might be
our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX>, and that our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX> might engulf us?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX>, who presided over
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Committee</ENAMEX> while it stood by its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> until the last,
said it best at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>'s funeral: "The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">second half of the 20</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">century</ENAMEX> will be known as the age of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>." May <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next half-century</TIMEX> speak
better of us.

         
      
   
