
   
   
      
         
            Light and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Dark</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Luther King</ENAMEX> was
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">beatified</ENAMEX> because he died dramatically with his sins unknown and the civil
rights movement still seen as an epic gathering of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroes</ENAMEX>. Hero worship
dominated the story from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Montgomery</ENAMEX> bus boycott in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1950s</TIMEX> through the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reaganaut</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">'80s</ENAMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> finally began to acknowledge that the civil rights
establishment had just as many fakers as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">saints</ENAMEX>. The inner workings of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">King</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organization</ENAMEX> have yet to be fully revealed. But enough has been said to show
which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King's lieutenants</ENAMEX> covered up his sexual peccadilloes and vied obscenely
for his attention and the chance to succeed him in the public eye.

            The tale
of the selfless prophets is giving way to a more realistic but no less amazing
story of how egoists, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hustlers</ENAMEX>, and sensualists rose above their failings to
remake the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. In his memoir, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Walking With the Wind</ENAMEX> , Rep.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Lewis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">D-Ga.</ENAMEX>, pushes this new openness a good deal further. He speaks
bluntly about the movement's faults--and his own--during his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> of the
competitor and the principal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operator</ENAMEX> in the dangerous voting rights campaigns
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mississippi</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alabama</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> respected his civil rights <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forefathers</ENAMEX> but
did not worship them. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A decade</TIMEX> younger than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> and substantially more
aggressive, he regularly dismissed the advice of bigwigs like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thurgood Marshall</ENAMEX>, pursuing a course far more radical than theirs in the deep
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South</ENAMEX>. But what is freshest about <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Walking With the Wind</ENAMEX> is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> is
equally candid about the class conflicts that afflicted the modern civil rights
movements from the very beginning. Tensions between the uneducated rural poor
and the urban <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX> were glaringly obvious to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-Americans</ENAMEX>, but
largely invisible to the white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historians</ENAMEX> who succeeded them.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thirty years</TIMEX> is less than the blink of an eye in human
history. Yet it was that recently that black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alabama</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mississippi</ENAMEX>
were arrested, beaten, fired from their jobs, and even lynched for trying to
vote. The campaign that overturned <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> apartheid was a potent form of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">theater</ENAMEX>, in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">demonstrators</ENAMEX> embraced the opportunity to be shot, gassed,
and thrashed in order to generate outrage against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern</ENAMEX> racism. The most
harrowing parts of this book tell of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> and the integrated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freedom</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Riders</ENAMEX> who rode on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">buses</ENAMEX> through the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX> to test federal laws that forbade
segregation in interstate transport. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bus</ENAMEX> was firebombed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Anniston</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ala.</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bus</ENAMEX> was surrounded by a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mob</ENAMEX> that had lynching on its mind until an
undercover <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policeman</ENAMEX> got off the bus brandishing his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pistol</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freedom Riders</ENAMEX>
bus carrying <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> had the unfortunate experience of arriving in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Montgomery</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ala.</ENAMEX> The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mob</ENAMEX> that came to savage them bore a striking resemblance to the
flesh-eating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">zombies</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cult</ENAMEX> movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Night of the Living Dead :</ENAMEX>

            And
then, out of nowhere, from every direction, came <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. White <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Men</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Dozens</NUMEX> of them. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Hundreds</NUMEX> of them. Out of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">alleys</ENAMEX>, out of
side <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX>, around the corners of office <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>. ... They carried every
makeshift weapon imaginable. Baseball bats, wooden <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX>, bricks, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chains</ENAMEX>, tire
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">irons</ENAMEX>, pipes, even garden tools--hoes and rakes. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">front</ENAMEX>, their faces twisted in anger, screaming, "Git them niggers, GIT them
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">niggers</ENAMEX>. " ... And now they turned to us, this sea of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, more than
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three hundred</NUMEX> of them, shouting and screaming, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> swinging fists and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> swinging heavy purses, little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> clawing with their fingernails at
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faces</ENAMEX> of anyone they could reach. ... I could see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Zwerg</ENAMEX> now, being
horribly beaten. Someone picked up his suitcase, which he had dropped, and
swung it full force against his head. Another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> lifted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> and held it
... while others, including <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, scratched at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jim</ENAMEX>'s face. His
eyes were shut. He was unconscious. ... At that instant I felt a thud against
my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>. I could feel my knees collapse and then nothing.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SNCC</ENAMEX> pioneered the strategy of trading
fractured skulls for press attention and moral outrage. This seems
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">coldblooded</ENAMEX>--until the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> considers that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> thrust himself into the most
dangerous confrontations. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">admirers</ENAMEX> called it bravery. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> called it
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">redemptive</ENAMEX> suffering," a concept he picked up from studying <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gandhi</ENAMEX>, among
others. But what it amounted to was putting yourself forward to be beaten,
possibly to death, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX> after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week after week</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">month</TIMEX> after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">month</TIMEX>. What
would drive someone to do this is still an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enigma</ENAMEX> to me.

            The
method succeeded to perfection when <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alabama</ENAMEX> state troopers bludgeoned and
tear-gassed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Selma</ENAMEX> march led by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1965</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX> had skipped the march,
fearful of the violence. But "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bloody Sunday</ENAMEX>" at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Selma</ENAMEX> outraged the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> and
gave <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lyndon Johnson</ENAMEX> cover to press for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Voting Rights Act</ENAMEX>. Wildly
successful, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Selma</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">campaign</ENAMEX> nonetheless marked <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the beginning of the end</TIMEX> for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">movement</ENAMEX>. The civil rights <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">coalition</ENAMEX> was tearing itself apart in disputes
over tactics, money, and who would get the most exposure in the press.

            Egos were clearly at issue. But so were the antagonisms
that had long separated middle- and upper-class <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> from their sharecropper
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cousins</ENAMEX>. A blatant elitism infested the movement for racial uplift from the
outset. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> civil rights <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> were from the mulatto elite, which
historically discriminated against darker-skinned <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> and held many of the
same ideas about them that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX> did. These antipathies mellowed into
condescension in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">W.E.B. Du Bois</ENAMEX>, a scion of the fair-skinned elite, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-founder</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAACP</ENAMEX>, and the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> to earn a Ph.D. from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Du Bois</ENAMEX>' racial philosophy emerged in his essay on "the talented <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">tenth</NUMEX>,"
assigned the task of lifting up the rest. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Du Bois</ENAMEX> wrote, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Progress</ENAMEX> in human
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">affairs</ENAMEX> is more often a pull than a push, a surging forward of the exceptional
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, and the lifting of his duller <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">brethren</ENAMEX> slowly and painfully to his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vantage</ENAMEX>-ground."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> had
lots of experience with snobbery from high-toned <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Negroes</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAACP</ENAMEX> in
particular was chock full of fair-skinned <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the black middle class.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX>, by contrast, was darker-skinned and had been raised in poor, rural
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alabama</ENAMEX>. His accent and modest, even diffident, manner led the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Negro</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> to
view him as much less than he was. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> describes the civil rights <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elite</ENAMEX> as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bourgeois</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> who enjoyed fund-raisers but had never known the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">billy club</ENAMEX> and
"tended to look down through a telescope at the little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>." Meeting with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilkins</ENAMEX> to plan the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">March on Washington</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1963</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> found himself being
treated like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hick</ENAMEX>.

            
The most complex tensions were between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lewis</ENAMEX>
and his close <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleague</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julian Bond</ENAMEX>, whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> was a pillar of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Negro</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elite</ENAMEX> and a close <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Du Bois'</ENAMEX>. Bond must have found it satisfying
to be accepted by a black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who had been raised hard--and who was not from
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">affluent</ENAMEX> set. The official line is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bond</ENAMEX> were fast friends
when they were in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SNCC</ENAMEX> together but fell out in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX>, when they both ran for
the same congressional seat. Walking With the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wind</ENAMEX> tells a different
story. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> hints at secret annoyance with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bond</ENAMEX> from the first mention, in
which he writes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julian</ENAMEX> was "like most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>, more upper
crust than those of us from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nashville</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> portrays <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SNCC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">branch</ENAMEX> as
being made up of well-off <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Negroes</ENAMEX> who carped all the time.

            The split seemed to come in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1969</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julian Bond</ENAMEX> was elected to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgia</ENAMEX> state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legislature</ENAMEX> and became
the darling of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> left's radical chic <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">set</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> advised <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bond</ENAMEX> to stay
at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX>, build a political machine, and run for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>. Bond
rejected this advice. But <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a quarter of a century later</TIMEX>, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> faced off in a
bitter campaign for the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th</ENAMEX> congressional district seat. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew</ENAMEX>
Young, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maynard Jackson</ENAMEX>, and the mulatto <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elite</ENAMEX> dismissed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> and lined up
behind <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bond</ENAMEX>. Late in the book, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> remarks bitterly on press coverage that
referred to Bond as "light-skinned, dashing, erudite, articulate" and to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lewis</ENAMEX>
as "short, squat, thick-necked, balding, dark, scowling, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sharecropper</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>."
Influential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> from around the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> advised him to quit the race and
leave the seat to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> many of them viewed as its rightful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heir</ENAMEX>. Still
angry, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> writes, "Throughout <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">my years</TIMEX> in the movement ... <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> had always
underestimated me ... often in the end to their dismay."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> brought to the
campaign the same intensity he had trained upon redneck troopers and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sheriffs</ENAMEX>.
When he defeated <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bond</ENAMEX>, it was more than just a victory for himself. It was a
victory for the dark-skinned, dirt poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masses</ENAMEX> against the hincty <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Negroes</ENAMEX> who
had historically looked down on them.

         
      
   
