
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White Heat</ENAMEX>

            Should we be sad that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">James</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cagney</ENAMEX> is slipping from memory, or was it inevitable that his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> would fade?
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">These days</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cagney</ENAMEX>'s image tends to flicker: He's that tough <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who talks so
fast you can hardly hear the words, and who, at the end of his films, gets
killed. Few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cagney</ENAMEX>'s performances as intimately as they know the
high points of the performances of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Humphrey Bogart</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy Stewart</ENAMEX> or Cary
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grant</ENAMEX>. Or compare <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cagney</ENAMEX> with fellow macho icon <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Wayne</ENAMEX>: The punk <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gangster</ENAMEX>'s
stock has fallen, while the silent cowboy's keeps on rising. What <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> do
recall about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cagney</ENAMEX> they're likely to have picked up from imitators (including,
of all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sammy Davis Jr.</ENAMEX>), who loved to mimic his nasal, rapid-fire
delivery, and to re-enact that moment at the end of his films when he gets
plugged with what seems like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">300</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bullets</ENAMEX> and reels theatrically for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">12 minutes</TIMEX>
before dropping dead.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cagney</ENAMEX>'s
slow fade is especially surprising when you consider how much the genre he
helped to invent, the gangster film, thrives. As described by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCabe</ENAMEX> in
his old-fashioned and sometimes overly affectionate new biography, the street
milieu that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cagney</ENAMEX> brought to the screen seems contemporary, too. He was born
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1899</TIMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower East Side</ENAMEX>, into an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> facing problems
you can still see <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every week</TIMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYPD Blue</ENAMEX> . His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> was a tragic
combination of saloonkeeper and drunk who died relatively young during the
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Spanish flu</ENAMEX> epidemic of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1918</TIMEX>. His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">martyr</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> red hair--the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">stuff Oedipus</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complexes</ENAMEX> are made of. He grew up all the way east on
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">76 th Street</ENAMEX>, in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yorkville</ENAMEX>, and although he seems to have been a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mama</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">loner</ENAMEX> who liked to read, tough <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> in the neighborhood gave him
nicknames like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Red, Runt</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Short Shit</ENAMEX>, and forced him to learn how to fight.
(A few of them also taught him <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Yiddish</ENAMEX>, a language he adored and drew on
throughout his life for insults. He called his main career <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nemesis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studio</ENAMEX> head
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Warner</ENAMEX>, "the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schvontz</ENAMEX> ," one of <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Yiddish</ENAMEX>'s many creative terms for
"prick.") <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cagney</ENAMEX>'s first showbiz gig was unplanned and inauspicious: a musical
revue about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sailors</ENAMEX> in drag. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCabe</ENAMEX>, the need to support his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fatherless</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, not vain hopes of becoming a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX>, is what drove him.

            He worked his way up in vaudeville, perfecting a
distinctive style of dance in which he stiffened his legs and stuck out his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">butt</ENAMEX>, and he was playing a sniveling bootlegger on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner</ENAMEX>
recruited him to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1930</TIMEX>. While other movie <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> of the early
'30s filmed literary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adaptations</ENAMEX> or drawing-room comedies or musicals, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bros.</ENAMEX>, which specialized in no-frills realism, set Cagney to work in a cycle of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">social</ENAMEX>-problem flicks--movies drawn from headlines about striking milk truck
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX>, warring <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">taxi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX> and, of course, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gangsters</ENAMEX>. These films claimed to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">warn America</ENAMEX> about its urban ills, but what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cagney</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> breakout hit, The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public Enemy</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1931</TIMEX>), conveyed was the charisma of the amoral hood. He
played <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Powers</ENAMEX>, a street punk who gets rich running <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">booze</ENAMEX> during
Prohibition, grows too big for his britches, and winds up being shot. Other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> had played scum, but only <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cagney</ENAMEX> played scum with an awesome dignity,
like a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">predator</ENAMEX> in a nature documentary. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Years later</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Tynan</ENAMEX> said this
was the role that let <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audiences</ENAMEX> admit they'd take a stinking lowlife over a
fussbudget <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">any day</TIMEX>.

             

            The career
that followed is a good example of how shrewd the old <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">studio system</ENAMEX> was at
figuring out exactly what a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> is supposed to do, and an even better example
of how the system locked <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> into an increasingly stultifying caricature of
their greatest roles. Cagney riffed on this hard-boiled persona for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about a</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decade</TIMEX>, most harrowingly in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Angels With Dirty Faces</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1938</TIMEX>), playing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rocky Sullivan</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">killer</ENAMEX> who freaks out just as he's about to go to the
electric chair. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> is left to guess if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rocky</ENAMEX> is spineless or if he's
just trying to convince all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> who worship him that crime doesn't pay.)
To keep his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> from getting bored, he improvised what he called "goodies,"
little touches like kicking a chair out from under his co-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX>. Shortly before
he died, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cagney</ENAMEX> described to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McCabe</ENAMEX> his method of acting. Basically, he
listened. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Watch Cagney</ENAMEX> while someone else is speaking and you'll see a darting
eye, a quivering eyebrow, a split<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">-second</TIMEX> grin. He hardly moves, but he makes
everyone on-screen seem important, and he creates a rare kind of in-the-scene
suspense.

            
Nonetheless, he kept getting stuck with hack
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX> and predictable scripts. Relief came when he got to play the great
Irish song and dance <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George M. Cohan</ENAMEX> in the musical <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yankee</ENAMEX> Doodle
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dandy</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1942</TIMEX>). At last, a showcase for his stiff-legged routine and a chance
to be recognized as a wholesome <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patriot</ENAMEX>, instead of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX>. He thought he'd
broken out of his niche, but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner</ENAMEX> still wanted to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> him around. So, in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1942</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cagney</ENAMEX> became one of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> to start his own production <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>.
Unfortunately, in his rush to change his image he picked a string of sappy,
pseudo-profound roles. He was a gentle <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> newspaperman ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Johnny Come</ENAMEX>
Lately , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1943</TIMEX>), or a lovable alcoholic who sits in a bar <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all day</TIMEX> musing over
the destinies of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Time of Your Life</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1948</TIMEX>). A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> of
times during this period, he'd test-screen a film, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> would object to
the new passive <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cagney</ENAMEX>, and he'd have to shoot a new ending in which he went
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">crazy</ENAMEX> and punched someone out.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McCabe</ENAMEX>
leaves the impression that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cagney</ENAMEX> never got over this rejection of his
sentimental side. When he started out in show business, he was something of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">lefty</ENAMEX>, living briefly on a quasisocialist commune in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX>, sending money
to striking <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">lettuce</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pickers</ENAMEX>, and naming <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stalin</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gandhi</ENAMEX> as his
favorite human beings in a survey in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1933</TIMEX>. But he was less an ideologue than an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">idealist</ENAMEX>, and as he got older his views shifted to the right. In fact, beneath
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cagney</ENAMEX>'s amoral public image there seems to have been a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman Rockwell</ENAMEX>
struggling to get out. In his spare time he wrote naive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mystical</ENAMEX> verse about
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">God</ENAMEX>'s presence in nature: "All space is filled with wondrous things/ Unseen by
human eye./ Before us hover <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">kings</ENAMEX> and queens,/ With realms that float and fly."
Perhaps the most shocking fact revealed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cagney</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX>'s
lifelong secret desire to leave <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> and go into agriculture. He bought a
number of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farms</ENAMEX> and apparently loved to sit in the pasture and meditate on his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cows</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cagney</ENAMEX>'s corniness never really worked on-screen--the
"goodies" were drowned out by windy speeches--but when he turned it upside down
in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX> 
               Heat , his great <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1949</TIMEX> comeback to the gangster genre, he
was unmatched as a ruthless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pervert</ENAMEX>. He played <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cody Jarrett</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of a
bank-robbing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gang</ENAMEX> who was trained in criminality by his mother, and who, though
well into middle age, still dotes on her with an infant's fierce love. White
Heat features <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cagney</ENAMEX>'s greatest primal tantrums: in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX>, when he
finds out that his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> is dead and moans like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">maniac</ENAMEX>; and at a chemical
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">refinery</ENAMEX>, where he screams, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Top of the world</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Ma</ENAMEX>!" and then gets shot by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> and consumed by fire.

            To play
someone this unpredictable <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, we might turn to an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicolas Cage</ENAMEX>.
But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cage</ENAMEX>'s eruptions look narcissistic next to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cagney's</ENAMEX>: When he snaps, he's
not responding to other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in a scene, he's hearing voices in his head. The
other obvious comparisons to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cagney</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert De Niro</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Pacino</ENAMEX>, but
they're prestige <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX>--cerebral, introverted, and usually not as funny. I
tried to think of a modern <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> who is as natural as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cagney</ENAMEX>, and to my
surprise the name that made the most sense was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Travolta</ENAMEX>. Like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cagney</ENAMEX>, he
has a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dancer</ENAMEX>'s grace. In <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Saturday Night Fever</ENAMEX> his charisma elevated junk
to greatness, and in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pulp</ENAMEX> 
               Fiction he played a dirt-bag with just
the right winking theatricality. Also, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years ago</TIMEX>, when left to choose his
own material, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Travolta</ENAMEX> made the hideous Phenomenon , thereby
demonstrating a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cagneyesque</ENAMEX> taste for treacly fables.

            
The search for a modern <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cagney</ENAMEX> is a vain
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>--nobody could compare to him. So why do we remember <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wayne</ENAMEX> so much better?
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> reason is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cagney</ENAMEX> didn't make enough really great films. But there's a
larger explanation. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wayne</ENAMEX> had the good luck to rule over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Westerns</ENAMEX>, a genre that
was set on wide-open land and commemorated the past and dealt in stark moral
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">truths</ENAMEX>--a genre doomed to grow obsolete, leaving <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wayne</ENAMEX> to dominate the
landscape, a proud and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lonely warrior</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cagney</ENAMEX>'s charisma launched what looks,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades later</TIMEX>, like the most enduring film style of all. He's been sucked into
the cultural ether. His skepticism and short fuse, which once seemed so
radical, are taught at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Actors Studio</ENAMEX>. His name may be vanishing, but more
than ever, he's everywhere.

         
      
   
