



<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Groups</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Locale To Serve</ENAMEX> the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 3, 2002</TIMEX>
Vulnerable
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Salt Lake City</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tribune</ENAMEX>

BY <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EDWARD MCDONOUGH</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Five</NUMEX> independent <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Salt Lake</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> that provide legal
services to the poor, ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minorities</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">seniors</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with
disabilities have joined together to acquire a west-side downtown
building where they will have their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX>. The new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community</ENAMEX>
Legal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Center</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">205</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N. 400 West</ENAMEX> is a project of "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">And Justice for</ENAMEX>
All," which, until this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">venture</ENAMEX>, has been a joint fund-raising
campaign by an alliance of the non-profit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX> of free legal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">services</ENAMEX>. "And <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Justice for All</ENAMEX>," which solicits donations primarily
from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundations</ENAMEX>, was the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> joint fund-raising
campaign of legal services <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community Legal Center</ENAMEX> is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> joint <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> project of public
service law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid Society</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Salt Lake</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disability Law Center</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Multi-Cultural Legal Center</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senior Lawyer Volunteer</ENAMEX>
Project and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Utah Legal Services</ENAMEX> will share the new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX>, and
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Wednesday</TIMEX> their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> were given a tour of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community Legal Center</ENAMEX> hosted by staff <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>. All of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> can share the same reception area and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX> waiting <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> is close in, across the street
from <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">West High</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> blocks from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gateway</ENAMEX>. It has its own
parking, something that's hard to find downtown and which has been
a problem for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> as well as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>. Owning and sharing the
building and not paying rent times <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> will save the non-profit
agencies <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $375,000</NUMEX> each year. My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assistant</ENAMEX>, Charity
Christenson, pointed out that the shared <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> will also be
efficient for those needing legal services. No longer will a woman
desperate for a protective order, for example, have to run all over
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">town</ENAMEX> trying to find the right <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>.
After the tour, we found <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jaye Olafson</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cookies</ENAMEX> and
brownies reception on the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> floor. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jaye</ENAMEX> and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erik</ENAMEX>,
own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tomax Technologies</ENAMEX> and were the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sellers</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>. Jaye
explained how much of the renovation had been merely uncovering
what was already there. The hardwood floors, wooden ceilings and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">brick</ENAMEX> and stone interior walls were all hidden behind coverings and
old paint. She loves the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>, and they only moved out because
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> had outgrown the space. So they renovated the old
Sweet <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Candy Company building for Tomax</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Olafsons</ENAMEX> are delighted
with the new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> had been like <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>, she
explained, and so it was important who would be living there. I
noted on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donor</ENAMEX> list that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX>, through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Olafson Group</ENAMEX>, had
become one of the major <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> of the project.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stewart Ralphs</ENAMEX>, the executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid Society</ENAMEX>,
explained that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community Legal Center</ENAMEX> Campaign still has a long
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ways</ENAMEX> to go, with a bit more than half of the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4 million</NUMEX> projected
cost received so far. There still needed to be furnishings and
office equipment and such. He promised that they would be getting
in touch with us later on the subject.




