



A helping hand for helping hands
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INLAND VALLEY</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 9, 2002</TIMEX>

<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mancy Mintie</ENAMEX>'s Uncommon Good <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> pays the school
debts of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> and health-care <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> dedicated to serving
those less fortunate.
By <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joanna Corman</ENAMEX> / <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">joanna</ENAMEX>.corman@latimes.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Samels Ceballos</ENAMEX> entered <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Loyola Law School</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
knowing she wanted to represent the poor. She graduated in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>
owing <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$58,000</NUMEX> in loans.
She was about to run out of means to pay back those loans when
she took a job at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inner City Law Center</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>, a firm
that fights slum <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">landlords</ENAMEX>. It was there that she met <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mintie</ENAMEX>.
Mintie, a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Claremont</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">resident</ENAMEX>, made it possible for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ceballos</ENAMEX> to
represent poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> against wealthy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">landlords</ENAMEX>, a calling about
as low-paying as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> jobs get, and pay off her loans at the same
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>. "It kind of stepped in at the right time," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ceballos</ENAMEX>, who
has loan payments averaging <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$800</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX> and whose starting salary
was <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$30,000</NUMEX>. "Because of the program, I've been able to stay here.
... There was no way I could make that payment. I barely make it
now with my regular bills."
Mintie, who turns <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">48 this month</TIMEX>, started <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Uncommon Good</ENAMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 1999</TIMEX>. The nonprofit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX> pays the debts of attorneys
and health care <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> who work with the poor. It grew out
of her work at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inner City Law Center</ENAMEX>, which she founded in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX>, and often depended on the skills of young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> with a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">social</ENAMEX> conscience. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>, she stepped down from her role as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>. Over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next year</TIMEX> she realized she needed incentives to
keep <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> around after they got <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years</TIMEX> of experience. Not
only were there fewer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> entering the field of poverty law,
some were being driven out of the profession.
The reason: With <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one year</TIMEX> out of graduate school
facing an average debt of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">just less than $90,000</NUMEX> and starting
salaries at legal aid <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> averaging <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$31,000</NUMEX>, they
couldn't afford the job.
"It really had become an economic impossibility to take these
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">jobs</ENAMEX> and survive on them," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mintie</ENAMEX> said. "That finding became the
wake-up call for me and hopefully it will be the wake-up call for
others in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> that cares about access to justice for the
poor."
Her career started <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than 20 years ago</TIMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">garage</ENAMEX> behind a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catholic Worker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">soup</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen</ENAMEX> on skid row in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>. She lived
on a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3-</NUMEX><TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a-week</TIMEX> stipend that she spent on pantyhose and bus
fare.
Her law practice grew to an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> that brought in
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">dollars</NUMEX> of damages through its cases against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">L.A.</ENAMEX>
slumlords, allowing poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> to set up college funds and buy
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">homes</ENAMEX>. In all those <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, she never lost a case.
When she stepped down, she had time to notice what was happening
to the field of poverty law.
"I realized with a shock that the work had really disintegrated
and we had lost a whole generation of public-interest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>," she
said. "It had gone from being an economic sacrifice as it was in my
day to an economic impossibility. ... The whole system has
essentially collapsed."
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mintie</ENAMEX> also started to ask questions about the medical field.
Almost every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who walks into a free medical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clinic</ENAMEX>, she said,
faces some legal problem such as an eviction or the loss of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Security</ENAMEX> benefits. And many of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> had medical problems
from living in slum housing such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cockroaches</ENAMEX> lodged in ear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">canals</ENAMEX> and rat bite fever, a nonfatal malady that particularly
affects <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mintie</ENAMEX> noticed that health-care <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX>
were graduating with staggering debts and also couldn't afford to
work with the poor.
Her work was noticed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oprah Winfrey</ENAMEX>, who invited her on the TV
show <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 26, 2001</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mintie</ENAMEX> received a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100,000</NUMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Use Your Life</ENAMEX>
Award" from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oprah</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angel Network</ENAMEX>, a nonprofit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> that
awards money to those who help others. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mintie</ENAMEX> said that all of the
money has gone to her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> -- none was spent on overhead. She
will be out of funds by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">spring</TIMEX>.
She is trying to get religious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> to sponsor
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX>. It is a secular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>, but one that grew out of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mintie</ENAMEX>'s religious convictions.
"I was raised <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX>. I think the tradition for compassion for
the poor encouraged that gift in me," she said. "My faith said,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">'Yes</ENAMEX>, this is right.' "
She said she hopes that religious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> see the link
between their beliefs and her work.
"For so long there has been such misunderstanding between the
religious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> and the work <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> do for the poor. The work
that we do is the purest form of expression of the core values of
all of the major faith traditions."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Uncommon Good</ENAMEX> has a few religious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sponsors</ENAMEX>, including her
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">church</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Our Lady of the Assumption in Claremont</ENAMEX>, where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mintie</ENAMEX> plays
piano <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> at the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6:30 a.m.</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mass.</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Fourteen</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> now receive money from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Uncommon Good</ENAMEX>. Debt
payments can be <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">as low as $300</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">as high as $2,000</NUMEX>. Some
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> grew up poor and want to give back, while others feel
the need despite having a middle-class upbringing. But a
commonality among some of them was a decision all faced -- should
they leave their jobs for higher-paying ones? Their low salaries
and high debt payments were making it impossible to live.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Recipients</ENAMEX> include <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lisa Levsen</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">33</TIMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> who graduated from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USC Medical School</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$144,000</NUMEX> in debt and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">monthly</TIMEX> loan payments
of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,200</NUMEX>. She works as the head <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physician</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mission</ENAMEX>, a free <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clinic</ENAMEX> on skid row.
And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Martinez</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">28</TIMEX>, who cut his medical school studies
short because he couldn't afford the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$39,000</NUMEX> in loans after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> of graduate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX> of college. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX> works
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> jobs as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physician</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assistant</ENAMEX> and supports his elderly
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Uncommon Good</ENAMEX> has a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22</NUMEX>-member <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> and is recruiting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mentors</ENAMEX>. One
goal is to get the state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legislature</ENAMEX> to pass a law to provide loan
forgiveness to medical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> who work with the
poor. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mintie</ENAMEX> said she hopes her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> can be a national
model for other professions.
She is trying to bring legal aid services to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inland Valley</ENAMEX>
-- the closest legal aid <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> is in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El Monte</ENAMEX> and represents
700,000 poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Fernando</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Gabriel</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inland</ENAMEX> valleys.
"Unless the legal aid is in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX>, you can't say you are
serving the poor," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mintie</ENAMEX> said.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neal Dudovitz</ENAMEX> is the executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Neighborhood Legal</ENAMEX>
Services of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles County</ENAMEX>, the legal aid <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El Monte</ENAMEX>.
He sees attorneys new to poverty law leave all the time because
they can't afford the salary with their law school debt.
"She's really opened a lot of eyes in terms of having people
understand how the educational debt is limiting and reducing the
services that are available to low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX>," Dudovitz
said. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy</ENAMEX> is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">light years</TIMEX> ahead of the curve on this stuff. Very
little is being done practically to solve it."
Mintie, her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> say, could have made a lot of money in
private practice.
"She's very kind and pleasant," said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Julius Thompson</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">45</TIMEX>, an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inner City Law Center</ENAMEX> and an <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Uncommon Good recipient</ENAMEX>.
"But she's also a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> on a mission. When she sets her sights on
something, she's a formidable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX>."



