



Abuse penalties questioned
Fines the same for beating a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> in county

By <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria Herne</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 17, 2002</TIMEX>
If you beat a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Schuylkill County</ENAMEX>, you'll probably get a
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100</NUMEX> fine.
If you repeatedly beat a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>, you'll probably get the same
fine.
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">county</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> heard <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">98</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Protection</ENAMEX> From Abuse cases,
finding the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defendant</ENAMEX> guilty in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">48 percent</NUMEX> of those cases, either
after a hearing or through a technical violation or plea.
Of those found guilty, the majority were ordered to pay court
costs, plus a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100</NUMEX> fine. No <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defendants</ENAMEX> were ordered to pay more
than a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$250</NUMEX> fine for violating the court order. In <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">27 percent</NUMEX> of
the cases, the charges were dismissed or the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defendant</ENAMEX> was found
not guilty. In the rest of the cases, charges were withdrawn or the
matter is not yet resolved. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarah T. Casey</ENAMEX>, executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of
Schuylkill Women in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crisis</ENAMEX>, finds it disturbing that in most cases,
the fine for violating a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PFA</ENAMEX> is little more than the fine someone
would get for cruelty and abuse toward an <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animal</ENAMEX>.
"In most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">counties</ENAMEX> surrounding <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Schuylkill County</ENAMEX>, the
penalties given for indirect criminal contempt are much stiffer
than those in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Schuylkill County</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Casey</ENAMEX> said. "What kind of message
are we sending those who repeatedly violate Protection <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">From Abuse</ENAMEX>
orders? That it's OK to abuse <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Schuylkill County</ENAMEX>, because
you'll only get a slap on the wrist?"
Under state law, the minimum fine for contempt of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PFA</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100</NUMEX>;
the maximum fine is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">up to six months</TIMEX> in jail.
Like others who are familiar with how the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">county</ENAMEX>'s legal system
does and doesn't work for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> of domestic violence, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Casey</ENAMEX>
believes some changes are in order.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Valerie West</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mid-Penn Legal Services</ENAMEX>,
with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pottsville</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Reading</ENAMEX>, regularly handles domestic
violence cases.
She finds fault with the local requirement that a custody order
must be established within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30 days</TIMEX> after a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PFA</ENAMEX> is filed.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">West</ENAMEX> said she feels a custody order should be allowed to stand
for the full term of the PFA - <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">up to 18 months</TIMEX> - as it does in many
other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">counties</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>.
"It places an undue burden on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">plaintiff</ENAMEX>, in terms of cost,
finding legal representation and facing their abuser - not to
mention a further burden on the system to provide those services,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">West</ENAMEX> said. "It may be difficult for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> to reach an
agreement so soon after violence has occurred. It's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">counter-productive</ENAMEX>."
The lack of supervised custody visitation in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">county</ENAMEX> - a
neutral, safe, supervised place where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> can be exchanged
from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> to another for the purposes of visitation
- is also a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX>.
"Right now we don't have any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> in the county willing to
handle supervised custody visits," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">West</ENAMEX> said. "Obviously, in
domestic violence cases this is a major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> to us. There's a
potential for further incidents of abuse to occur during these
meetings without some sort of outside supervision."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marsha Chwastiak</ENAMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pottsville</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mid-Penn Legal Services</ENAMEX>, said she would like to see more funds made
available to provide social services for troubled families
grappling with domestic violence issues.
"If I had one wish for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX>, it would be to have more
resources available to help these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> so they can try and sort
out their problems," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chwastiak</ENAMEX> said. "In the majority of domestic
violence cases I see, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> and mental health problems are
at the heart of the problem. I feel these are more social problems
than legal cases," she said.
Other problems targeted by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SWIC</ENAMEX> include a need for more
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">expedient</ENAMEX> service of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PFAs</ENAMEX>; the need for free or affordable legal
representation and assistance with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PFA</ENAMEX> and contempt hearings and
other civil matters related to abuse, including custody and
support; and the lack of proper training by law enforcement
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> in handling domestic violence cases, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Casey</ENAMEX> said.
A recent <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$202,297</NUMEX> federal grant from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Department of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Violence Against Women</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office</ENAMEX> may be the answer to some of
these problems.
Through the collaborative efforts of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Schuylkill Women In Crisis</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schuylkill County Sheriff's Department</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">county</ENAMEX> grant writer
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lorraine A. Bennick</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pathways</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Safety</ENAMEX> program was
initiated.
The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two-year</TIMEX> program is fully funded under the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Department</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Grants to Encourage Arrest Policies and Enforcement</ENAMEX>
of Protection Orders" initiative. Some of the ways the funds will
be spent include:
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$90,000</NUMEX> to hire a civil <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice attorney</ENAMEX>, at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$45,000</NUMEX> a year for
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX>, to ensure that all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> of domestic violence are
represented at <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> hearings in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PFAs</ENAMEX> and assisted with other
civil matters.
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20,171</NUMEX> to support overtime costs of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> additional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> to
serve <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PFAs</ENAMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nonscheduled work hours</TIMEX>, ensuring more expedient
and immediate delivery and service of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PFA</ENAMEX> orders.
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3,645</NUMEX> to develop a domestic violence training program for local
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">police departments</ENAMEX>, led by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX>'s advocacy <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trainer</ENAMEX>; the goal of
these <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mini-workshops</ENAMEX> will be to ensure that local police
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">departments</ENAMEX> consistently adhere to proper PFA protocol.
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$15,000</NUMEX> to hire a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultant</ENAMEX> to provide a complete, detailed
study of establishing the most cost effective link between county
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">facilities</ENAMEX> and municipal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">police departments</ENAMEX> and to establish <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JNET</ENAMEX>,
an information management system funded by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PA</ENAMEX> and
operated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Network</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JNET</ENAMEX> was launched in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ridge</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schweiker</ENAMEX> administration
to help local and state police, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prisons</ENAMEX> and probation and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parole officers</ENAMEX> exchange instantly updated information on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> moving through the criminal justice system - making it
possible to better track potentially dangerous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>.
By helping justice <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> share criminal files more easily,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JNET</ENAMEX> improves efficiency and reduces potential errors that could
occur from each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> maintaining disparate data files.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JNET</ENAMEX> is also used to prevent the detention of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>
wrongly identified as criminal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suspects</ENAMEX>.
"The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pathways</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Safety</ENAMEX> program will compliment existing SWIC
programs and address problems experienced by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> of domestic
violence," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Casey</ENAMEX> said. "We believe that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> of domestic
violence deserve immediate, consistent, respectful treatment and
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offenders</ENAMEX> receive swift, efficient, just punishment."




