



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Daily News</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 7, 2002</TIMEX>

Advocate for Poor Has Own Obstacles
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg Wilson</ENAMEX>
Former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Mazzariello</ENAMEX> was finally doing the kind
of legal work he'd always dreamed of, but after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">less than a year</TIMEX> of
helping <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East New York</ENAMEX>'s poor, he's getting booted from the bodega
he turned into an office.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nearly a year ago</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mazzariello</ENAMEX>, a former assistant district
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> who grew up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East New York</ENAMEX>, started a nonprofit practice
helping the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">working poor</ENAMEX> navigate the legal system. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Immigration,</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">landlord-tenant</ENAMEX> disputes and even criminal cases are the specialty
of his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">East New York Legal Services Corp.</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">New Lots Ave.</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>, in a former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodega</ENAMEX>, was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mazzariello</ENAMEX>'s idea, and he
got some help from high places early on.
"I picked up the phone and called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudy Giuliani</ENAMEX> on his radio
program," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mazzariello</ENAMEX> said. "I said, 'Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX>, we're interested
in renting <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">space</ENAMEX> in a building the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> owns.
"I swear, within <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an hour</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> was ours. We filled out
all the paperwork. We got the nonprofit status from the feds. We
were rolling."
Refusing to charge <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mazzariello</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">42</TIMEX>, said he used his
family's savings to sustain the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first year</TIMEX>.
Already recognized as a federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">nonprofit</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> is awaiting
state status that would allow it to survive on charitable
donations.
"This is what I want to do - to give back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX>,"
said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mazzariello</ENAMEX>, who worked under <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brooklyn</ENAMEX> District Attorney
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Hynes</ENAMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990 to 1993</TIMEX>, followed by a stint as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Education</ENAMEX>'s chief <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX>.
Under the city <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Housing Preservation and Development Department</ENAMEX>'s
tenant ownership program, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mazzariello</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Guzzo</ENAMEX> learned
they could rent to own. They invested <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$8,500</NUMEX> in a new facade, rest
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room makeover</ENAMEX> and other modest improvements.

Another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bidder</ENAMEX>
Then, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mazzariello</ENAMEX> got bad news from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>. A
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tenant</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> had put in an application to buy it first.
Program guidelines give <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tenants</ENAMEX> priority over commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">users</ENAMEX>.
Department <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokeswoman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carol Abrams</ENAMEX> said homeownership comes
first, even over community-minded <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mazzariello's</ENAMEX>.
"We give priority to the residential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tenants</ENAMEX> because we're a
residential housing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abrams</ENAMEX> said.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julio Montalvo</ENAMEX>, whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> live in one of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> residential
units above the storefront legal practice, plans to buy the
property. He did not say how much he was paying, but he said the
units are rent-controlled. That makes getting fair market value for
the commercial space a must. That could amount to several times as
much as the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$250</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mazzariello</ENAMEX> currently pays the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Housing</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Preservation and Development Department</ENAMEX>.
"I embrace the kind of business he is running," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Montalvo</ENAMEX> said.
"But we didn't go into this in bad faith. Everything being done
here is being done properly. If he has a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beef</ENAMEX>, he should take it
to" the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>.





