



Legal services <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> expands

By <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Myerhoff</ENAMEX>
Published: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, July 19, 2002</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">PASADENA</ENAMEX> -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Neighborhood Legal Services</ENAMEX>, which provides free
legal services to the poor, has expanded into the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">San Gabriel</ENAMEX> and
Pomona valleys, areas with large <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX>, many of whom
speak limited or no <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>.
Language is their biggest obstacle, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">communities</ENAMEX>'
cultural isolation and service <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX>' lack of cultural
expertise also play a part, said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NLS</ENAMEX> executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dubovitz</ENAMEX>.
And with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">13 percent to 15 percent</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> living below the poverty line, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NLS</ENAMEX> services are badly needed,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dubovitz</ENAMEX> said.
"Although it is a significant part of the poverty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asians</ENAMEX> historically have not been able to participate in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">services</ENAMEX> and programs available to the poor," he said.
From simple telephone advice to complete legal representation in
court, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> provides free <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumer</ENAMEX>, health, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">immigration</ENAMEX>, housing, public benefits and labor legal services to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who earn <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">under $1,380</NUMEX> per month.
Legal service <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX> have long served large Latino
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">populations</ENAMEX>, who have cultural diversity but share a common
language.
"I remember <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the days</TIMEX> when there were only a handful of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in
the legal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> who spoke <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Spanish</TIMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dudovitz</ENAMEX> said. "Now <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> are interchangeable. Our goal is to have that for the
major <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> languages as well."
Before the expansion, only a few <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NLS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> spoke <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">languages</ENAMEX>, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rebecca Yee</ENAMEX>, who was hired by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NLS</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX> to design and head the project.
"Now we have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> speaking <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Cantonese</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mandarin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Thai</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khmer</ENAMEX>
(from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambodia</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Korean</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Vietnamese</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Tagalog</ENAMEX>," Yee
said.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> hired to work with the program is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Irene</ENAMEX>
Mak, a family law <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> who speaks <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cantonese, Mandarin</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thai</ENAMEX>.
Mak was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> at a private law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> before she went to work
for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NLS</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years ago</TIMEX>, earning <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">up to $20,000 less</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> working on
domestic violence cases.
"The job is more satisfying than the money," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mak</ENAMEX>, who grew
up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Thailand</ENAMEX> before coming to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. "I
could use my language skills and wanted to give back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">community</ENAMEX>."
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NLS</ENAMEX> expanded when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services Corp.</ENAMEX>, the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> that
funds <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX> of free legal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX> nationwide, reduced the
number of grantees in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> area from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five to three</NUMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dudovitz</ENAMEX> said.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NLS</ENAMEX> won the competitive grant over the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services Program</ENAMEX>
for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pasadena</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">San Gabriel-Pomona</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">valleys</ENAMEX>. That boosted its client
base from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16,000</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">around 25,000</NUMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NLS</ENAMEX> opened an office in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monte</ENAMEX>.




