



Give <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">So All May Have Justice</ENAMEX>
Editorial
In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawmakers</ENAMEX> do not feel the need to appropriate money so
that the poor and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elderly</ENAMEX> can afford quality legal care. Perhaps
this is because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX>, spurred on by campaigns such as the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> one called, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">And Justice for All</ENAMEX>," have been unusually
generous in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX>, donating money for this purpose. But the
need keeps growing larger, and that means <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX>, and all others
with the means, have a greater obligation to help.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX>, the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">And Justice for All</ENAMEX>" campaign is suffering from
some of the same problems facing other charitable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>
after the terrorist attacks of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 11</TIMEX>. Individual and corporate
donations remain strong, but so far no large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> has
stepped forward with a big challenge grant, as has happened in each
of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past three years</TIMEX>.
That means the responsibility for giving is greater now than
ever.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX>'s poor and disadvantaged need all types of legal help, from
dealing with domestic abuse to protecting limited assets in old
age. This campaign provides financial assistance to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> that
regularly deal with these problems and know how best to direct the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resources</ENAMEX>.
Hard as it is to believe, the campaign is only in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">its fourth</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Three years ago</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> went without
competent legal representation because the resources simply weren't
available. Back then, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disability Law Center</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid Society</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Utah Legal Services</ENAMEX> combined received <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">less than $75,000</NUMEX> in
donations from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> and other legal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX>. Since then,
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">And Justice for All</ENAMEX>" has raised <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.3 million</NUMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">More than one-third</NUMEX>
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah Bar</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,221</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX>, have contributed. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Organizers</ENAMEX> say
this is one of the highest rates anywhere in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>. The giving
hasn't been limited to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Philanthropists</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> and
other private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> have donated <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $368,000</NUMEX>.
None of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contributors</ENAMEX> can afford to let up now, especially
with the economy suffering both locally and nationally. And the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two-thirds</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah Bar</ENAMEX> that does not donate needs to step up.
Unemployment rates are up. Bankruptcy rates are higher than ever.
The need never has been greater.



