



<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Annual</TIMEX> Fee to Rise <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$49</NUMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid Gets Boost</ENAMEX>

<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Flynn Rooney</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 4, 2002</TIMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Illinois Supreme Court</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> hiked <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> registration
fees by <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$49</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> to boost both legal aid services and support for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> and alcohol problems. Under the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">high court</ENAMEX>'s
order, the base <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> fee for active <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> rises to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$229</NUMEX> as of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 1</TIMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">high court</ENAMEX> raised that fee to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$180</NUMEX> from
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$140</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lawyers</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">their first three years</TIMEX> of practice or who are
inactive but wish to remain on the roll of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> pay <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$90</NUMEX>.
Most of the latest increase -- <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$42</NUMEX> -- will go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lawyers</ENAMEX>
Trust Fund of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX>, which disburses monies to legal aid
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organizations</ENAMEX> that assist low- income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> in civil matters.
The other <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$7</NUMEX> will go the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lawyers' Assistance Program Inc.</ENAMEX>, which
helps <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> overcome <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol addiction</ENAMEX> and mental
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">illness</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lawyers Trust Fund</ENAMEX> and LAP aim, respectively, to improve
legal services to the poor to provide equal justice under the law,
and to increase public confidence in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> of justice,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Ann G. McMorrow</ENAMEX> said.
"These <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> separate increases in the fees <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> pay is a step
closer to achieving those <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> goals," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McMorrow</ENAMEX> said in written
statement. "In times of a downturn in the economy, they demonstrate
a commitment by the full <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>, and by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX>, to
assume responsibility for those unable to afford legal services and
for those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> who need compassion and help."
There are now <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 57,000</NUMEX> active <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX>.
The fee increase is expected to generate <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2.4 million</NUMEX> for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lawyers Trust Fund</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $400,000</NUMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAP</ENAMEX>, to provide
additional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> and resources.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lawyers Trust Fund</ENAMEX> administers the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">high court</ENAMEX>'s Interest on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lawyer Trust</ENAMEX> Accounts, or IOLTA, a program that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pools clients</ENAMEX>'
money, escrow funds, for instance, and that in turn generates
income for the trust fund.
But low interest rates and a sagging economy have plagued the
program. The deposits earned <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2.5 percent</NUMEX> in interest <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year ago</TIMEX> and
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> average <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.65 percent</NUMEX>, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruth Ann Schmitt</ENAMEX>, executive
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lawyers Trust Fund</ENAMEX>.
As a result, funding available for the legal aid <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> has
plummeted by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">more than 50 percent</NUMEX>, from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3.7 million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year ago</TIMEX> to
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.5 million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schmitt</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>'s
action raising the fee "is lifesaving for our grantees," Schmitt
said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lawyers Trust Fund</ENAMEX> helps underwrite operations at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">34</NUMEX> legal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, including the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Assistance</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foundation of Metropolitan Chicago</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Land of Lincoln Legal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Assistance Foundation Inc.</ENAMEX>, based in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Springfield</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prairie State</ENAMEX>
Legal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Services</ENAMEX>, based in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rockford</ENAMEX>.
"This is a big step the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> has taken in demonstrating
for all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> in the state how important it is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> be
made aware of their responsibilities to try to ensure legal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">services</ENAMEX> for all," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leonard F. Amari</ENAMEX>, a past <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Bar Association</ENAMEX> and chair of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lawyers Trust Fund</ENAMEX>,
said in a press release.
The fee increase is "an important step that will give lawyers
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> an opportunity to fully recover from substance abuse and
mental <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">illness</ENAMEX> so that they can perform their jobs to the best of
their ability, thereby assisting the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sheila</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">M. Murphy</ENAMEX>, a former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cook County Circuit Court</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> who is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAP</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, said in the release. More than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years ago</TIMEX>, the high
court established a special <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> assistance
programs, chaired by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Timothy L. Bertschy</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Peoria</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> and
former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ISBA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> urged the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justices</ENAMEX> to provide
additional resources for such programs in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX> through
increased registration fees.
"There are going to be some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> I suspect who are going to
object to the increase, but the recommendation made to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme</ENAMEX>
Court regarding the fee increase had broad support from bar
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associations</ENAMEX> across the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bertschy</ENAMEX> said in the release.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAP</ENAMEX> has helped <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> facing personal crises for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 20</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. The additional revenue generated by the fee hike will allow
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAP</ENAMEX> to establish <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> in central and southern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX> and
expand its outreach in law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murphy</ENAMEX>. She added
that the additional funding also will allow <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAP</ENAMEX> to help more with
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">relapse</ENAMEX> treatment and following up with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> who have completed
the program.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAP</ENAMEX>'s current funding primarily comes from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s two
largest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar associations</ENAMEX> and private donations.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">high court</ENAMEX>'s order <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> amends <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court Rules 751</ENAMEX> and
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">756</NUMEX>, authorizing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Attorney Registration and Disciplinary</ENAMEX>
Commission to collect and automatically pass along fees to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lawyers Trust Fund</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lawyers' Assistance Program Fund</ENAMEX>. The latter
is a special state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">treasury</ENAMEX> account created at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">high court</ENAMEX>'s
request and allowed for under legislation enacted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>.




