



The Courier-Journal
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, January 23, 2002</TIMEX>


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anthem Payout Poses Problem</ENAMEX> for Some
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Poorest Policyholders</ENAMEX> could lose <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX>, other Benefits
It might have seemed like manna from heaven - <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">up to thousands</NUMEX> of
dollars dropping, often unexpectedly, into the hands of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">half-million Kentucky</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this month</TIMEX>.
But for some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX>, there is a downside to the checks from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anthem Inc.</ENAMEX>, issued to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policyholders</ENAMEX> as part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">insurer</ENAMEX>'s
conversion to a publicly traded <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>.
The poorest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> could actually suffer from the windfall
by losing their benefits under <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX>, food-stamp and other
programs. That's because they suddenly have more money than the
eligibility threshold for aid.
TO avoid losing valuable benefits such as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid-paid</ENAMEX> spot
in a nursing home, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> may need to spend their money fast -
as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early as the end of this month</TIMEX> - but make sure they do it in a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> that meets program guidelines.
"You would think money out of the blue would be a good thing,"
said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jaime Odle Harmon</ENAMEX>, executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lexington</ENAMEX>-based
Access to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Foundation</ENAMEX>. "We're just trying to make sure that
it is, and doesn't have a negative impact on low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> and
their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>."
Legal aid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kentucky</ENAMEX> have put together an action team
and held frequent statewide conference calls in response to
concerns from aid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anthem</ENAMEX> payouts
could cost <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> their benefits, at least temporarily.
"We're getting deluged" with calls on the issue, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hamon</ENAMEX>,
whose <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> supports the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s legal-services programs and
operates a legal hotline for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elderly</ENAMEX>.
The basic advice is this: if you received a check or stock from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anthem</ENAMEX> and you haven't disposed of it yet, pick up the phone and
call a legal-aid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>, benefits <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counselor</ENAMEX> or someone else who
understands eligibility guidelines. And do it right away.
"There are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> out there who are available to help anyone who
has a problem. It's legal service and it's free," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amy Turner</ENAMEX>,
a staff <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisville</ENAMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid Society</ENAMEX>, which
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">covers Jefferson</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX> surrounding <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">counties</ENAMEX>.
The sudden concern over losing benefits was triggered by the
recent mailing by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anthem</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX>-based <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">insurer</ENAMEX>, of about
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2 billion</NUMEX> in checks, plus shares of stock worth a bit more than
that, to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1 million</NUMEX> eligible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policyholders</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>. About
half of those were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kentucky</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>.
The distribution was a result of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anthem</ENAMEX>'s conversion <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>
from a mutual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, owned by its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policyholders</ENAMEX>, to a publicly
traded <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> owned by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shareholders</ENAMEX>.
Despite earlier mailings from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anthem</ENAMEX>, the checks caught many
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> by surprise. And while it was generally a nice surprise, it
worried many aid-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> who fear losing benefits - especially
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elderly residents</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX> nursing-home beds.
To qualify for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX> and some other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>-administered aid
programs in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kentucky</ENAMEX>, you can't have <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $2000</NUMEX> in liquid
assets on hand. That includes cash and stock. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX> threshold is even lower, $<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1500</TIMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anthem</ENAMEX> payouts were large enough to put many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">seniors</ENAMEX> over
those limits. The average payout was <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4,400</NUMEX>, and the largest -
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $22,000</NUMEX> went to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who had been with Anthem the longest,
presumably <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">seniors</ENAMEX>.
When the checks started showing up in mailboxes sometime after
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX>, many aid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> were confused about why they got the
windfall - and what to do with it.
They were justifiably concerned, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> say.
"I think there's a real danger that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> will lose benefits
because they won't understand how to handle this (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">money</NUMEX>)," said
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glenda Harrison</ENAMEX>, staff <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northern Kentucky Legal</ENAMEX>
Aid <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Society</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Covington</ENAMEX>.
"In particular, the elderly (could) be hurt by this," she said.
"We are concerned that they won't know, one, what this is going to
mean, and then, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>, even if they know what it means, won't know
who to contact to help them through this."
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anthem</ENAMEX> considered the potential effect of its payouts on
public-aid benefits before making its distribution, said
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">spokeswoman Lauren Green-Caldwell</ENAMEX>. But after talking to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> involved, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> concluded "that
we are not in a position to provide advice to these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>," she
said.
She said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> believes the distribution has "been a
really good thing" and was handled fairly.
While <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> wondering how to handle their payout should consult
an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> abou their particular situation, there are some general
guidelines.
"You can't give it away, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jess Williams</ENAMEX>, branch <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> for
eligibility policy for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kentucky Department</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid Services</ENAMEX>.
He said many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are asking if they can give it to their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> to put it in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">trust</ENAMEX> for them. The answer is no.
In general, you must receive fair-market value for whatever you
spend it on. That means for example, "You can't pay your son
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10,000</NUMEX> for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> that is worth <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2000</NUMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee Richardson</ENAMEX>, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisville</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> specializing in elder law.
The good news, for those who must spend <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">up to $22,000</NUMEX> in a few
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX>, is that there is a fairly broad latitude in what you can
spend the money on. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kentucky</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX> officials
suggest such alternatives as buying a prepaid burial, paying
premiums in advance on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> supplement health-insurance policy
or paying outstanding medical bills. Other allowable expenditures
could include buying a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> for medical transportation needs, making
home repairs or paying property taxes.
The main requirement is, you must get value for your money.
Otherwise, when you report spending to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX> - as is required -
official could treat the money as unspent, which could affect your
benefits.
In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>, similarly, "there isn't really any particular
restriction on what you can buy with your money . . .as long as you
spend the money," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Holly</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">paralegal</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indian</ENAMEX>
Legal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Services</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bloomington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>.



