



The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Associated Press</ENAMEX>

Law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> debts forcing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recruits</ENAMEX> to private sector
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 18, 2002</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">WASHINGTON</ENAMEX> (AP) - Most new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> won't consider working for
government or public advocacy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> because their need for money
to pay off massive student loans leads them to the more lucrative
private sector, a study being released <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> found.
Legal education debt, which tops <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$84,000</NUMEX> for the average new
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>, prevents <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">66 percent</NUMEX> of law <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> from taking public
interest jobs, according to the joint study by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Equal Justice Works</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Association for Law Placement</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Partnership</ENAMEX> for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public Service</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washingtonbased</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> promote public interest
work.
"The bottom line is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s law school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduates</ENAMEX> are drowning
in debt and shut out of public service at a time when the federal
government is facing losses of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over half</NUMEX> its work force due to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">retirements</ENAMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Max Stier</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief executive</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Partnership for Public Service</ENAMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">More than 94 percent</NUMEX> of law <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> reported borrowing money to
attend law school, where median tuition is nearly <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$23,000</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>,
but law <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> are not alone in having to contend with spiraling
education costs.
The need to pay off student loans discourages <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> from going
to rural <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> or inner-city <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX>. A chronic teacher
shortage has led some <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> to consider ways to help
teaching-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">educa</NUMEX>-tion <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> pay off college debts.
The student loan <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nellie Mae</ENAMEX> says the average college
graduate's student-loan debt has reached <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">at least $19,400</NUMEX>. In
addition, figures for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> showed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduates</ENAMEX> had average credit
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">card</ENAMEX> debt of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">around $2,750</NUMEX>.
In the law study, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 68 percent</NUMEX> of public interest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX>
surveyed - government <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX>, legal aid <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>, public
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defenders</ENAMEX> and other nonprofit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> - reported recruiting
difficulties. Most blamed the combination of low starting salaries
and high law school loans for discouraging law <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> from public
service jobs.
The report encourages law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> to create
programs to help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> who choose public service pay back loans
in their lower-paying jobs. A few <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>, including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgetown</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX>, already have them.
The median starting salary <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> at private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">law firms</ENAMEX>, was
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$90,000</NUMEX>. By contrast, public interest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> pay new graduates
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $35,000</NUMEX>, while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> pays <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$40,000 to $45,000</NUMEX>.




