



<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Assuring Underprivileged</ENAMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Voice</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Jurist Credits Parents for Strong Sense</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social</ENAMEX>
Responsibility
By <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina Spee</ENAMEX>

<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday, October 2, 2002</TIMEX>
Profile:


<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laurie D. Zelon</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Superior Court</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> Career highlights: Appointed by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gray Davis</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Superior Court</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 2000</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morrison & Foerster</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991-2000</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hufstedler, Kaus</ENAMEX> &
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ettinger</ENAMEX> (and predecessor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX>), <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1983-91</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">associate</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beardsley</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hufstedler & Kemble</ENAMEX> (and related <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX>), <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1977-82</TIMEX> Law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard Law School Age</ENAMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">49</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">LOS ANGELES</ENAMEX> - As an undergraduate at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cornell University</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laurie</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D. Zelon</ENAMEX> monitored campus demonstrations. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the only
student-run chapter of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Civil Liberties Union</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zelon</ENAMEX> worked to resolve disputes between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police officers</ENAMEX> to help protect the public's right to peaceful
protest.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thirty years later</TIMEX>, as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Superior Court</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>, Zelon
has added the public's right to a fair trial to the list of
constitutional rights she works to preserve.
A former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles County Bar Association</ENAMEX>,
Zelon, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">49</TIMEX>, says her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30 years</TIMEX> of public-interest work have allowed
her to understand the legal needs of the underprivileged.
She emphasized "how important it is for them to feel that
they're being listened to, that they have an opportunity to say
what they need to say - for them not only to get a fair trial but
to believe that the system is being fair to them."
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> who appear before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zelon</ENAMEX> attest to the fact that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> in her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courtroom</ENAMEX> have faith in her
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">objectiveness</ENAMEX>.
"I can't think of a single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX> that hasn't had a fair hearing
in front of her," <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Deputy Public Defender</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Noel Leon</ENAMEX> said. "She's
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fair</ENAMEX> to both sides. It sounds crazy, but that's not always how it
is."
Described by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> who appear before her as a consummate
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">professional, Zelon</ENAMEX> projects quiet determination, intense
intellectual curiosity, confidence and thoughtfulness, on and off
the bench.
"Her judicial temperament is excellent. She never gets ruffled,"
Deputy <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">City</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Wong</ENAMEX> said. "I think she is a brilliant
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">jurist</ENAMEX>."
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zelon</ENAMEX> has been a longtime <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocate</ENAMEX> of equal access to justice
for all and an outspoken <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">proponent</ENAMEX> of increased, and more
stabilized, funding for legal-services programs.
But as a newly assigned <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Clara</ENAMEX> Shortridge Foltz
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Criminal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Center</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zelon</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day-to-day</TIMEX> work no longer affects
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> on such a broad scale.
She is an active <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court-Community Outreach</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Bar Association</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ethics 2000 Commission</ENAMEX>
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Bar of California</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Statewide Bench</ENAMEX>-Bar
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coalition</ENAMEX>.
But her work on the bench affects the lives of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">underprivileged</ENAMEX>, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zelon</ENAMEX> puts it, "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>."
"I can't be an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocate</ENAMEX> anymore in the way that I was, but there
are lots of opportunities that I have found within the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> that
are appropriate to the ethical limits that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> have," Zelon
said.
"I affect <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s lives <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> at a time in this job, but
sometimes, the effect can be pretty profound, and sometimes, it's
not what you hoped it to be," she said.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zelon</ENAMEX> works to ensure that her misdemeanor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> is a relatively
welcoming place for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defendants</ENAMEX> she comes face to face with on a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> basis.
"I've talked to so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX>, either directly
or through the reports from their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX>, about how alien a
place the justice system can be, how unapproachable it can seem to
them," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zelon</ENAMEX> said.
According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> who appear before her, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zelon</ENAMEX> succeeds
in making everyone in her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courtroom</ENAMEX> at ease.
"She treats everyone, from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defendants</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX>,
with the highest respect," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wong</ENAMEX> said.
"A lot of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> really feel that they're not afraid to come
to court because they know she'll listen to them, and they like her
positive reinforcement," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leon</ENAMEX> said. "She becomes familiar with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who have been in court over and over. She actually
cares."
According to Deputy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public Defender Debbie Canada</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jurors</ENAMEX> also
are impressed with the respect Zelon pays them and the gratefulness
with which she thanks them for their time.
"She's very good with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">juries</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX> said. "She's very polite,
and she makes them feel like their contribution to the system is
important."
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zelon</ENAMEX> acknowledges that she makes an effort to ensure that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jurors</ENAMEX> leave her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courtroom</ENAMEX> with a sense of confidence in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organization</ENAMEX> of courtroom proceedings and the effectiveness of the
trial-by-jury system.
"What I try to do, so I can get enough trial time and so that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jurors</ENAMEX> are used in a way that makes sense to them, is start
trial by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10:30 in the morning</TIMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zelon</ENAMEX> said. "When <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are late,
it makes it hard to keep things working in a rational fashion."
While unprepared <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> annoy her, several things about the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> who appear before her impress <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Zelon</ENAMEX>.
"One of them is the ability to humanize the case, to take it out
of this range of procedures and rules," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zelon</ENAMEX> said. "The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>
thing is getting in there, digging so hard so that they understand
completely and exactly what the facts are. ... Those are the ones
who really shine."
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zelon</ENAMEX> said her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">accountant</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">housewife</ENAMEX>, gave her
a strong sense of social responsibility.
"No matter what I ended up doing, I think I would have found
some way within that profession to do public work, because that's
what I was taught," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zelon</ENAMEX> said. "It was always a part of me."
She was born in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX> and went to high school in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Westbury</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.Y.</ENAMEX> She received her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bachelor</ENAMEX>'s degree from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cornell</ENAMEX>
University in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1974</TIMEX> and then attended <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard Law School</ENAMEX>.
At <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zelon</ENAMEX> made history when her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> won the Williston
Competition, a contract-negotiating contest open to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">first-year</TIMEX> law
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>. It was the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time a team with a female
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> had won the competition.
In a class made up of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20 percent</NUMEX> women, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zelon</ENAMEX> held the position
Review. She also was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX> Voluntary
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Defenders</ENAMEX>.
"It was an interesting time, and there were an awful lot of
changes going on," she said. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> were always aware of the issue
[of gender], but I was never denied an opportunity."
As a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Civil Liberties Union</ENAMEX>, she sat on
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX> and discussed issues before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX>, such
as the proposed <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> march in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Skokie</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ill.</ENAMEX>, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 1970s</TIMEX>.
Shortly after earning her law degree, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zelon</ENAMEX> joined the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
Bar <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association</ENAMEX>'s young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> division, where she served on and
chaired several pro bono and public-service <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committees</ENAMEX>.
"I worked on ... helping to develop standards for pro bono
programs, encouraging recruitment, getting law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> to talk more
about pro bono, [and] getting law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> more involved in a [formal]
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX>," she said.
She spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 years</TIMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">litigator</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hufstedler</ENAMEX>, Kaus
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">& Ettinger</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>, where she combined her love of
science with her passion for litigation as an environmental law
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">specialist</ENAMEX>, and then at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morrison & Foerster</ENAMEX>, where the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>'s
large environmental <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> and other science-based <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">divisions</ENAMEX> gave
her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> to expand her practice area.
Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> allowed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zelon</ENAMEX> to focus on her private practice and do
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">community</ENAMEX> service. During her career, she accomplished several
things to improve legal funding for the poor, locally and
nationwide.


•
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 1980s</TIMEX>, she became chair of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Bar</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standing Committee on Lawyers' Public Service</ENAMEX>
Responsibility, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> responsible for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">association</ENAMEX>'s
position on legal services for the poor.


•
During her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995-96</TIMEX> term as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">County Bar Association</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zelon</ENAMEX> appeared before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> and
successfully argued against its proposed elimination of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Service Corp.</ENAMEX>, which grants funds to independent local programs
that provide civil legal assistance to the poor.


•
After being named chair of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Bar's Commission on</ENAMEX>
Access to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zelon</ENAMEX> worked with the state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Judicial</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legislature</ENAMEX> to
establish a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10-million</NUMEX>-a-year legal-access fund for programs that
deliver free legal services.


"The impact of her interest and work on the provision of legal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">services</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> is immeasurable," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patricia</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phillips</ENAMEX>, senior of-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morrison</ENAMEX> &
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foerster</ENAMEX>. "Its value is felt <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> by someone who would
otherwise be floundering around in the legal system yet dealing
with very serious problems."
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zelon</ENAMEX>'s public-interest work has not gone unnoticed. Several
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organizations</ENAMEX> that share her commitment to public service -
including the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Legal Aid & Defender Association</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Bar of California</ENAMEX> - have honored her.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Two years ago</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zelon</ENAMEX> received the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laurie D. Zelon Pro Bono</ENAMEX>
Award, which had been named for her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one year earlier</TIMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Law</ENAMEX>
Firm <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Pro Bono</ENAMEX> Project, which she'd helped found.
"I didn't find out until I was standing in the great <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hall</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>, surrounded by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">300</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who were there, that the
award had been named for me and was thereafter going to be given in
my name. It's very hard to believe, for anyone who knows me well,
but I was actually speechless for a period," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zelon</ENAMEX> said.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zelon</ENAMEX> faced one of the greatest challenges of her legal career,
she said, when her appointment to the bench forced her to switch
gears from civil litigation to criminal law.
"It was a steep learning curve for me," she said. "It's a whole
different set of processes. The rules are different. The case law
is a whole <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> unto itself."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorneys</ENAMEX> praise <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zelon</ENAMEX> for her thorough understanding of the
law.
"She's extremely well-versed in the law," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leon</ENAMEX> said.
"She's very thorough in her research," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wong</ENAMEX> said.
Of course, not all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> concur with every decision Zelon
makes in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>. Some city <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> disagree with her
interpretation of evidentiary statutes when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zelon</ENAMEX> puts limits on
their use of hearsay testimony.
But <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> who have appeared before her say that they
appreciate her intelligent interpretation of the law.
"Her rulings always have a firm foundation behind them no matter
which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> is adversely affected," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wong</ENAMEX> said.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zelon</ENAMEX> and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>, certified public <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">accountant</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David George</ENAMEX>,
have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeremy</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel</ENAMEX>, who are college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>.
Her outside interests include skiing, reading and music.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zelon</ENAMEX> considers herself lucky because she loves her position as
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>.
"Sometimes, when you want something a lot, there's this fear in
the back of your head that, if you get it, you're going to be
disappointed," she said. "I wanted this a lot, and I haven't been
disappointed for a minute."
But something tells those who know her that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zelon</ENAMEX> won't stay put
for long before she tackles a greater challenge, and the call that
has driven her constantly to give back to the community moves her
forward.
"I have a feeling that she's not going to be a misdemeanor trial
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> for that much longer," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wong</ENAMEX> said. "She's slated for higher
things."




