



<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tallahassee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX>

<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney</ENAMEX> gives of his time generously
For the public good

By <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James L. Rosica</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 12, 2002</TIMEX>
For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past 20 years</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard M. Smith</ENAMEX> has helped
senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> with their legal needs, free of charge.
But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX>, like many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteers</ENAMEX>, doesn't want any accolades.
"I'm no saint," the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">80-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tallahasseean</ENAMEX> said. "I'm just a
country <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>."
His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assistant</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Twyla Sketchley</ENAMEX>, sat behind his shoulder
and silently mouthed, "He is a saint."
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Every month</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX> visits the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Smith Williams Center</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bond</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">community</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wakulla County Senior Citizens Council</ENAMEX> building
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Crawfordville</ENAMEX> to advise <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">seniors</ENAMEX> on wills, power of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> and
other legal matters.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX> practiced law for a living until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1982</TIMEX>. Since then, he's
been semi-retired, devoting himself to helping fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">seniors</ENAMEX> who
are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">needy</ENAMEX>.
"I'm getting unable to do much physically, but my brain hasn't
quit," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX>, who walks with a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cane</ENAMEX>. "And I'd rather people
ask a foolish question now than have them make a dumb mistake
later."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sketchley</ENAMEX> helped <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beatrice Jackson</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Williams Center</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX>, who said she was "over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">60</TIMEX>,"
needed help with estate planning.
"He's not through with me yet ... but he's done a real good
job," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX>, a retired state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX>.
Over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX> said, he's helped <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> with not only
wills but also adoptions, divorces and even animal control cases.
"Someone's <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> was bit by a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX>, as I recall," he said.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX> coordinates his volunteer lawyering through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Florida</ENAMEX>, a nonprofit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> serving low-income
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>.
"He's such a fine, fine <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>," said executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kris</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Knab</ENAMEX>. Without him, "there would be a huge (number) of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who
would go without assistance. ... We're so impressed with his
dedication and commitment."
Also impressed is his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chesterfield Smith</ENAMEX>, former
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Bar Association</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> emeritus of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holland & Knight</ENAMEX> law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>.
"I'm real proud of him," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">85</TIMEX>, who went to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Florida</ENAMEX>'s law school at the same time as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard</ENAMEX>.
"Even then, he would worry about pro bono work and has done it most
of his life."





