



Legal <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Services Avoids Budget Cut</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$19 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congressional</ENAMEX> appropriation is good news for the
national <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">nonprofit</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tuscaloosa</ENAMEX> office

By <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephanie Hoops</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 26, 2003</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> stepped in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> to pass a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$19 million</NUMEX> appropriation
for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services Corp.</ENAMEX>, which serves the legal needs of the poor
through state programs nationwide.
The appropriation was good news for the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>, one
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">paralegal</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretaries</ENAMEX> who work at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tuscaloosa</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal</ENAMEX>
Services <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> and receive salaries much less than those of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> at private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">law firms</ENAMEX>.

From left, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Frances</ENAMEX> and Artis
"I'm ecstatic," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willie Mays Jones</ENAMEX>, managing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> of the
McKinney talk to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willie Mays Jones</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tuscaloosa</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>. "We didn't
know what was going to happen." managing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Services</ENAMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tuscaloosa</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>. The infusion of funds effectively saved
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alabama</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services</ENAMEX> programs, which have been scrambling to
find funding amid layoffs and benefit cuts.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>' appropriation for LSC takes it from a budget of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$329.3</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$348.4 million</NUMEX>, which will be divvied up nationwide. And
it means <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alabama</ENAMEX> won't have a half-million dollars cut from its
budget as had been expected. Instead, it will receive <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6.4 million</NUMEX>
for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year 2003</TIMEX>, the same as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>, said national LSC
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">spokesman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric Kleiman</ENAMEX>.
"It was like pennies from heaven," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kleiman</ENAMEX> said.
But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alabama</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">programs</ENAMEX> still lack funds, said
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tracy Daniel</ENAMEX>, executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of the/sAlabama Law
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foundation</ENAMEX>.
"We're just treading <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel</ENAMEX>, whose organization
gives money to LSC programs in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alabama</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel</ENAMEX> said funding must be doubled in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next five years</TIMEX> if
Legal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Services</ENAMEX> is to continue to meet the needs of the poor.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alabama</ENAMEX> spends <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">less than $11</NUMEX> per eligible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services</ENAMEX>,
and the national average is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> is at the bottom of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nation</ENAMEX> in funding the services.
"We are dead last," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melinda Waters</ENAMEX>, executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of
Legal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Services Corp.</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alabama</ENAMEX>, the largest of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s three
LSC programs.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alabama</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services</ENAMEX> programs have been working with a
statewide <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">task force</ENAMEX> to find a way to improve its system. They've
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">presented LSC</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>, with a proposal to centralize
the services into one program, which the national <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> is
expected to accept or reject <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX>.
Consolidation would be a big change because the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> has been
operating for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> programs, which together serve the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">state</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">67</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">counties</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Waters</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">program</ENAMEX> serves <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">counties</ENAMEX>, including
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tuscaloosa</ENAMEX>. The other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metro Birmingham</ENAMEX>,
which serves <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jefferson</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Shelby</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">counties</ENAMEX>; and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">North Central Alabama</ENAMEX>, which serves <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madison</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morgan</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Limestone</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cullman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">counties</ENAMEX>.
"The main problem we're facing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> is the fact that there are
[<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">698,079</NUMEX>] <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> living at or below the federal poverty guidelines
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alabama</ENAMEX> and we have, in our <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">counties</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">45</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> to serve <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">76</NUMEX>
percent of that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Waters</ENAMEX> said.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alabama State Bar Volunteer Lawyers Program</ENAMEX> helps the state
to some extent. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Lund</ENAMEX>, program <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>, said <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">25 percent</NUMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> with an active license volunteer. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX> have
programs as well, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lund</ENAMEX> said she has no data on them.
"I can't tell you how important I think a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services</ENAMEX> program
is, not only for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alabama</ENAMEX> but for our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and system of
government," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lund</ENAMEX> said.
"If a large portion of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> has no access to the third
tier of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, they're basically ostracized."
Even with the volunteer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>, however, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 10 percent</NUMEX> of the
need is being met, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel</ENAMEX> said.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>-based <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services Corporation</ENAMEX>, a private,
non-profit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> established by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1974</TIMEX>, provides
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">85 percent</NUMEX> of the funding for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services</ENAMEX> programs
nationwide.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alabama</ENAMEX>'s funding comes primarily from the national <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>, with
other funds coming from federal and private grants, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alabama</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Bar Interest</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lawyers Trust</ENAMEX> Accounts program and private
donations.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who use <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services</ENAMEX> include <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veterans</ENAMEX>, family
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with disabilities. Legal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Services</ENAMEX> provides
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> to help them only with civil legalities, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumer</ENAMEX>,
family, housing and employment law matters. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX> are free.
Only those whose incomes do not exceed <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">125 percent</NUMEX> of the federal
poverty level qualify for the services.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Frances McKinney</ENAMEX> saw her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tuscaloosa</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal</ENAMEX>
Services <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McKinney</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> was sold in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX> on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tuscaloosa County</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Courthouse</ENAMEX> steps after she and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> were
sued by a local business. Legal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Services</ENAMEX> is trying to get it back
for the elderly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McKinney</ENAMEX> said she wouldn't know what to do if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services</ENAMEX>
weren't around.
"We'd probably lose everything we had if we didn't have this
place," she said.
In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Alabama</ENAMEX>, abused <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> make regular use of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services</ENAMEX>
as well.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tuscaloosa</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Turning Point Domestic Violence Sexual</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Assault Services</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">160</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who sought shelter used
Legal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Services</ENAMEX>, said executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathy Benitez</ENAMEX>.
"I had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX> come in off the street <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> and she said,
`I'm really afraid he's going to kill me this time, I need a
protection from abuse order.'" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Benitez</ENAMEX> said. "So I immediately
called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services</ENAMEX> and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> made an appointment with
her, worked her in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">that afternoon</TIMEX>. That's just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> recent
example."
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> who work for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alabama</ENAMEX>'s programs are not highly paid.
Starting pay is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">only $31,196</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Waters</ENAMEX> said. Tax records show Waters
earned <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">around $65,000</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>. By comparison, tax records show the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of the program at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Atlanta Legal Aid Society</ENAMEX> earned
upwards of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$80,000</NUMEX> during that time.
But those who work for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alabama</ENAMEX> say the money
is not why they entered the field.
"Having grown up poor myself, I know that a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are
taken advantage of and need someone to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocate</ENAMEX> for them," said
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> has been with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alabama</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tuscaloosa</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> since
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX>. Raised in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">housing projects</ENAMEX>, she took the job after graduating
from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Alabama School of Law</ENAMEX> because she wanted to
give back to her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX>.
"I could have gone to a law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> and I would have made more
money - a lot more money," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> said. "I know that I'm not getting
paid as much as I could in the private sector, but I'm doing a lot
of good work for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who really need it."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Waters</ENAMEX> said she'd like to get an appropriation from the state
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">legislature</ENAMEX> to help <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alabama</ENAMEX>, but she realizes
that is unlikely, given the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of the economy. A better option
might be to tack a filing fee onto new cases filed in state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX>,
with the money going to help fund <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services</ENAMEX>, she said. That is
how indigent criminal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defenders</ENAMEX> get paid.
"We can't lobby," she said. "We do not have paid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyists</ENAMEX> and
we are, in fact, a non-profit public interest law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> and that
kind of approach to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">legislature</ENAMEX> would require a lot of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">education</ENAMEX>."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Waters</ENAMEX> said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> is already making difficult
decisions about who to turn away.
"Unfortunately our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>, being poor, have nowhere else to
turn for legal representation," she said. "So unlike <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are
fortunate enough to be able to afford <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> and can go to
another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>, our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> are simply lost in the legal system if
they cannot get access to it from us."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reach Stephanie Hoops at stephanie</ENAMEX>.hoops@tuscaloosanews.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> or
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">722-0204</ENAMEX>.




