



Legal Aid seeks to balance scales of justice
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 3, 2002</TIMEX>

<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Tilghman</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Five</NUMEX> times more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">needy people</ENAMEX> ask for help than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> can
assist
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Albany</ENAMEX> In <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX>, the phones ring relentlessly at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Albany</ENAMEX>'s
Legal Aid <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>, each call bringing another story of low-income
troubles, legal crisis or bureaucratic confusion.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> usually is so overwhelmed, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> who work there
say, that they have to stop taking calls and evaluating new cases
for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 a.m.</TIMEX>
The calls come from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina Lavery</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scotia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> of a
self-employed auto <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mechanic</ENAMEX>. She called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid</ENAMEX> after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> of
wrangling with federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bureaucrats</ENAMEX> who denied her request for
financial help -- <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $6,000</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> -- to provide speech therapy
for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">her 2-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>, who was born with autism.
"They almost always deny you at <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lavery</ENAMEX> said. "You have
to have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> to show them you mean business."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lavery</ENAMEX> considers herself among the fortunate few whose cases are
accepted by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid</ENAMEX>, one of the only places in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capital Region</ENAMEX>
that provides free legal services for civil matters such as custody
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">battles</ENAMEX>, landlord-tenant disputes or public assistance appeals.
Legal Aid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> say their <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney staff</ENAMEX> can provide full
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">services</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only about one</NUMEX> in every <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who ask for them,
leaving many to fend for themselves.
Unlike criminal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>, where those accused have a constitutional
right to a taxpayerfunded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> facing civil matters
either have to hire their own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> -- often at rates of more than
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$200</NUMEX> an hour -- or go it alone.
"There is a whole class of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who don't get in," said
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lillian Moy</ENAMEX>, executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid Society of</ENAMEX>
Northeastern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>. "And for them, the price for losing your
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">house</ENAMEX> or losing your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> or not getting the income the household
needs is incredibly significant."
In many cases, poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have to face off alone against
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adversaries</ENAMEX> who have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX>. In landlord-tenant cases, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">landlords</ENAMEX>
are almost always represented, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tenants</ENAMEX> almost never.
In the family <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX>, single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> who can't afford attorneys
sometimes have to go up against former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouses</ENAMEX> who can afford legal
representation.
Although the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> often try to find court-appointed attorneys
to represent those who don't have them, there is no guarantee.
"Clearly, it's not fair. There is a disparity: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> of
economic means will generally do better in the judicial system than
those without economic means," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Levin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York State Bar Association</ENAMEX>'s Access to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Committee</ENAMEX>.
And the ripple effects can be felt throughout the court system,
as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> have to stop and explain basic rules that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> would already understand.
"It usually takes longer because you have to sort of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurse</ENAMEX> the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> through the process," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dennis Duggan</ENAMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Albany County</ENAMEX>
Family Court <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> who said he often sees <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> handling their own
cases.
Legal Aid spends <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $2 million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> culled from a variety
of state and federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>.
A large portion comes from the interest generated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s
escrow accounts that is set aside by law for low-income legal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">services</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> serves <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 4,500</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">About 81</NUMEX>
percent receive only limited <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX>, such as a single
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">consultation</ENAMEX>, rather than full-time representation.
No-cost legal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX> also are offered to a more limited degree
from places such as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Women's Bar Association of the Capital</ENAMEX>
District or student <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clinics</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Albany Law School</ENAMEX>.
But for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> who spend most of their time practicing other
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">areas</ENAMEX> of the law, pro bono cases concerning aspects of family law
or public assistance can be difficult, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Levin</ENAMEX> said.
The vast majority of cases never involve a trial and can be
taken care of administratively.
"It's such a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bureaucracy</ENAMEX> that poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> deal with that a lot
of it is just straightening things out," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anne Erickson</ENAMEX>,
executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Greater Upstate Law Project</ENAMEX>, which
provides support services and updated legal information for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX>
like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lavery</ENAMEX> said the help she got from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Security</ENAMEX> benefits it helped her secure, have been invaluable.
"I honestly believe if it wasn't for them, I never would have
gotten it. I'd probably still be fighting," she said.




