



<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barnes</ENAMEX> to work pro bono pro

<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Duane D. Stanford</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 18, 2002</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Gottlieb</ENAMEX> thought it was a joke when he checked his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">voicemail</ENAMEX> and heard <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roy Barnes</ENAMEX> saying he wanted to come to
work for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Atlanta Legal Aid Society</ENAMEX>.
"How would you like to have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six months</TIMEX>?" <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Barnes</ENAMEX>
asked the executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>. At least, it sounded like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barnes</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gottlieb</ENAMEX>, who was vacationing in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Zealand</ENAMEX>, asked his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> to check it out. She confirmed the unbelievable --- it
was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barnes</ENAMEX>, and the offer was legit.
"I've never heard of a former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> going to work for a legal
aid program," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gottlieb</ENAMEX>. "I take that as an incredible
compliment."
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Two days</TIMEX> after the news leaked out, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barnes</ENAMEX> confirmed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> he
will go to work for the nonprofit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six months</TIMEX>, donating
his time to handle cases on behalf of lowincome <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Georgians</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barnes</ENAMEX>,
speaking at a press conference attended by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gottlieb</ENAMEX>, said his first
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">priority</ENAMEX> has always been to look out for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Georgians</ENAMEX>' interests.
"Holding elective <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> is not the only way to help others,"
said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barnes</ENAMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> who helped found a high-profile law firm
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Marietta</ENAMEX> before winning the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX>'s race in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>.
The move could also help <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barnes</ENAMEX> clean up the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King Roy</ENAMEX>" image
that dogged him during his re-election campaign and contributed to
his surprise loss to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sonny Perdue</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 5</TIMEX>. Asked about his legacy
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barnes</ENAMEX> was cautious: "I'm not a big one on legacy; that's
up to others to determine."
Political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultant</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick Dent</ENAMEX> said it is unlikely that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barnes</ENAMEX>
is attempting to remake his image, especially since it could be
construed as a negative by those who believe <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barnes</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberal</ENAMEX>.
"I think it's refreshing to see someone leave public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> and
not cash in, and do something he really does care about," said
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dent</ENAMEX>, who served as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zell Miller</ENAMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1990s</TIMEX>.
Legal aid's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteer lawyers</ENAMEX> work on behalf of low-income
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> who often don't have access to the legal system. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> handle only civil cases.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barnes</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> got to know the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> while working to
protect <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">borrowers</ENAMEX> from socalled "predatory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lenders</ENAMEX>." Legal aid
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> helped <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barnes</ENAMEX> write and pass legislation this year
regulating certain high-cost loans.




