



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Atlanta Journal-Constitution</ENAMEX>

<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barnes</ENAMEX>' new job will improve justice for poor
BY <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MAURICIO VIVERO</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 10, 2003</TIMEX>
On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, departing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roy Barnes</ENAMEX> will spend <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">his first day</TIMEX> as
a private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen</ENAMEX> by starting his new job as a full-time, pro-bono
(unpaid) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Atlanta Legal Aid Society</ENAMEX>.
The decision by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barnes</ENAMEX>, the most improbable casualty of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Election</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Day 2002</TIMEX>, to go to work for legal aid was almost as unexpected as
his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX> defeat. As a legal services <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barnes</ENAMEX> will help
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> escape domestic violence, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mauricio Vivero</ENAMEX>

is vice president
seniors fight predatory lending scams and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> obtain child
support for their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>. of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal</ENAMEX>
In doing so, he will take his place on the front line of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> legal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Services Corporation</ENAMEX>, the
uphill and underpublicized struggle to achieve equal access to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> too poor to afford
legal representation. based nonprofit
corporation
chartered by
The inaccessibility of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> civil justice system is hardly a
new development, but it <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">took Barnes</ENAMEX>' decision to put the national media spotlight on our
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s ongoing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1974</TIMEX> to promote equal access to
access-to-justice crisis. civil justice.
The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> census reports that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 43 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>
qualify for free federally funded legal assistance, yet fewer than
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20 percent</NUMEX> of eligible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> income: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$11,075</NUMEX> or less) are
able to obtain legal help when they need it, according to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Bar Association</ENAMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgia</ENAMEX>, there is just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> legal aid
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> for every <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10,500</NUMEX> eligible poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barnes</ENAMEX> understood this problem long before he became <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX>.
While in private practice, he handled many pro-bono cases and was a
frequent volunteer in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Cobb County</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> of the federally
funded <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Atlanta Legal Aid Society</ENAMEX>. Most memorably, he secured a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$115</NUMEX>
million judgment in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX> against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fleet Finance</ENAMEX> for victimizing
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homeowners</ENAMEX> -- many of them senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> -- with its
widespread predatory lending mortgage practices.
His long-standing commitment to the underserved is certainly
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">admirable</ENAMEX>, but it should not be viewed as a rare and laudable act
of civic virtue. To be admitted to practice law, every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX>
must take a professional oath to promote <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice</ENAMEX> -- and every
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">state</ENAMEX>'s ethical rules include language indicating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>'
responsibility to be guardians of fair play for those living in
poverty.
In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgia</ENAMEX>, many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">law firms</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> and private attorneys
are working pro bono to serve the neediest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>. Yet <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 23</NUMEX>
percent of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">23,598</NUMEX> active <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> reported meeting the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Georgia State Bar</ENAMEX>'s goal of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">50 hours</TIMEX> of pro-bono <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>.
The need for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteers</ENAMEX> is most severe outside the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>-county
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX> metropolitan area, where <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">70 percent</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s poor
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are served by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 24 percent</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>.
National pro-bono participation is even worse. <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Only 23 percent</NUMEX>
of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">roughly 1 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> volunteer even one
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hour</TIMEX> of pro-bono <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annually</TIMEX>, according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABA</ENAMEX>.
Shamefully, over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last decade</TIMEX>, the average revenue of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s most successful <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">law firms</ENAMEX> has increased by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 50</NUMEX>
percent while pro- bono <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> have dropped by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one-third</NUMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barnes</ENAMEX> knows these statistics help explain the unflattering
public image of the legal profession. Speaking to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Georgia School of Law</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduates</ENAMEX> at their <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> commencement, he
said, "The cold, hard reality is that far too many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> face the
possibility of an unjust outcome because they must navigate an
often complicated legal system without the benefit of competent
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX>. Why? Because competent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> in the corporate practice
don't want to get involved. They don't have the time. They have too
many <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> to bill."
Sometimes, it seems, we forget that "justice for all" is part of
our national creed. I, for one, will not forget <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s
poignant reminder in the aftermath of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 11</TIMEX>: "We're in a fight
for our principles," he told us, "and our first responsibility is
to live by them."
Our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">democracy</ENAMEX> will suffer greatly if so many of our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s
poor continue to be priced out of the justice system. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lawyers</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Georgia</ENAMEX> and across the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> must follow <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barnes</ENAMEX>' lead -- or
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> will continue to arrive at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courthouse</ENAMEX> door
to find they cannot afford the price of admission.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mauricio Vivero</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services Corporation</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>-based <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">nonprofit corporation</ENAMEX> chartered by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1974</TIMEX> to promote equal access to civil <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice</ENAMEX>.




