



The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bergen County Record</ENAMEX>

Legal aid <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> fights for survival
Merger expected to replace criticized office
Douglass Crouse

<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, November 8, 2002</TIMEX>
For <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than half</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a century</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Passaic County</ENAMEX> Legal Aid
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Society</ENAMEX> has fought on behalf of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">county</ENAMEX>'s poor, in disputes
ranging from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">housing</ENAMEX> to child custody to public assistance.
But for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last several years</TIMEX> it has often done that job
poorly, according to state and federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>. And barring a
long-shot legal victory, as of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 1</TIMEX> the autonomous <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">county</ENAMEX> office
will be replaced by a new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">administrators</ENAMEX> will report
to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> based in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jersey City</ENAMEX>.
Federal legal aid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> drew up the new service area uniting
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bergen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hudson</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Passaic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">counties</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>, insisting the change
will trim administrative costs without compromising services.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Passaic County</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> and its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> see it differently.
They say top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">decision-makers</ENAMEX> will be too far from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>
and non-profit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> that rely on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> for help. And in a
federal lawsuit, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> argues that a merger would
jeopardize its educational programs and minority hiring efforts,
and that its imposition amounts to bureaucratic bullying by state
and federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>.
Those same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> have repeatedly accused the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Passaic County</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> of mismanagement.
Reviews since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> have found evidence of shoddy accounting,
poor morale, excessive staff turnover, and double counting of cases
- and alleged that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> made limited efforts to rectify the
problems. At times in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> has received its
state and federal funding on a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">month-to-month</TIMEX> basis, which one
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">federal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> called "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> step short of defunding."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Leaders</ENAMEX> of the county <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>, which employs <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>
paralegals, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> support <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paterson</ENAMEX> and
Wanaque, say <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> have "greatly exaggerated" the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>'s
problems, which they call mostly bureaucratic.
"Just let them argue that their [merger] plan makes sense,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maxim Thorne</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>'s deputy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>, said of the
higher-level legal aid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>. "They could never replicate our
services or equal the accumulated value of this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>."
Over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> reapplied for a federal grant to
serve <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Passaic County</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the coming year</TIMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services Corp.</ENAMEX>
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> rejected the application, saying it failed to address
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> needs of the entire tri<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">-county area</ENAMEX> - a requirement
under the new rules.
By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid-December</TIMEX>, the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> is expected to award <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Passaic</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">County</ENAMEX>'s federal funding - <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $385,000</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> - to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northeast</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Jersey Legal Services</ENAMEX>, the tri-county <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>. State <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">funds</ENAMEX> of
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $1.6 million</NUMEX> could follow, although <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thorne</ENAMEX> noted the state
appropriated <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$927,000</NUMEX> of that amount through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 2003</TIMEX>.
The state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury Department</ENAMEX>'s legal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX> representative
did not return repeated calls for comment.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">District Court</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> refused to order an
extension of the existing office's federal funding as it fights the
merger plan. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thorne</ENAMEX> said he may appeal.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Timothy K. Madden</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hudson County Legal Services</ENAMEX> and
soon-to-be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of the tri-county <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>, said he will open a
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paterson</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 1</TIMEX>, giving priority in hiring to staff laid
off from the current <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>.
"I'm confident that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Passaic County</ENAMEX>'s low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> will
be served better than what they get now," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madden</ENAMEX> said, adding he
had not yet settled on a location.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anna Navatta</ENAMEX>, who controls a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.4 million</NUMEX> budget as head of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bergen County Legal Services</ENAMEX>, will become <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">deputy director</ENAMEX> of the
tri- county <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>. She said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bergen</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> will otherwise
remain intact.
"We actually hope to expand our services as a result of the
merger," she said.
By contrast, under the consolidation Executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Atlas</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thorne</ENAMEX> will likely lose their jobs, which last year
brought them <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$131,319 and $114,031</NUMEX>, respectively.
"This is not about job security for me and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maxim</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Atlas</ENAMEX> said.
"Our sole motivation is to save what I think is an essential
service and innovative program."
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Passaic County Legal Aid</ENAMEX> works on behalf of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 4,000</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> each year, and provides lowfee legal help for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 20</NUMEX>
non-profit and faith-based <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>. Its many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> argue that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>'s expansion of community development work - including
helping non-profits incorporate or defend themselves in lawsuits -
sets it apart from other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Pascrell Jr.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paterson</ENAMEX>, who has sought to mediate
the dispute, wrote of his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX>, "We are not aware of any
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stakeholder</ENAMEX> who was consulted on this sudden proposal, no less any
that support it."
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> also has a lauded history of activism. In response to
its lawsuit in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>, a judge ordered the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paterson Housing Authority</ENAMEX>
to correct a defective relocation plan for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbus Housing Development</ENAMEX> and remove all squatters
and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealers</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thorne</ENAMEX> also argued successfully before the state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>
that Head Start and similar preschool programs should receive full
state funding. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> continues to represent Head Start in
low-income districts.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Community leaders</ENAMEX> say they worry that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">center</ENAMEX>'s specialized
programs could be lost under a merger and that a new location will
create confusion for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madden</ENAMEX> said his focus will be
individual cases, and that "any resources we can spare to do
community economic development, we will."
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> created the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services Corporation</ENAMEX> (LSC) in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1974</TIMEX> to
improve low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX>' access to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX>. In
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> cut legal-aid funding by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a third</NUMEX>
or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$122 million</NUMEX> - state programs started facing more rigorous
requirements for grant renewals, including achieving "optimal
configuration of service areas."
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Earlier this year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services of New Jersey</ENAMEX> proposed halving
the number of its state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> areas to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX>, with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Passaic</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">County</ENAMEX>'s program left intact. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services Corp.</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> overruled that part of the plan.
In submitting the state plan, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melville D. Miller Jr.</ENAMEX>, president
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX>, argued that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Passaic County</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>'s alleged problems made it an undesirable merger
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX>.
In a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX> letter to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Atlas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John N. Erlenborn</ENAMEX> wrote
that his decision was based in part on "continuing problems" at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Passaic County</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>.
A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services Corp.</ENAMEX> audit in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> found <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">45</NUMEX> duplicate case
files in a random sample of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">400</NUMEX> cases. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thorne</ENAMEX> acknowledged that his
staff's lack of familiarity with a new computer system led to
"some" duplicate files, but said database training and increased
oversight by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supervisors</ENAMEX> addressed the problem.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Atlas</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX> also overstated staff turnover, arguing
that many of the cited <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> were short-term <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>. Others
left, for instance, to join private practice or after failing to
pass the state bar, he said.
"We'll be the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> to admit we make mistakes, but most of those
are bureaucratic. They don't involve delivery of services," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Atlas</ENAMEX>
said. He said state and federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> have failed to afford the
agency a proper hearing.
Legal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Services Corp.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric Kleiman</ENAMEX> contended that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Atlas</ENAMEX>
and his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> "have had ample opportunity to make their case to
us."
In its suit, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Passaic County</ENAMEX> office asserts that the federal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agency</ENAMEX>'s executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randi Youells</ENAMEX>, sought the merger
in large part because of her personal history with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>,
which refused to hire her as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultant</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kleiman</ENAMEX> called
that charge "completely spurious."





