



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>

Study <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Finds Bias on the Job Is Still Common</ENAMEX>

By <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REED ABELSON</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 24, 2002</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Women</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minorities</ENAMEX> appear to be benefiting from greater
employment opportunities in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, but discrimination
remains a significant problem, according to a study to be released
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professors</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rutgers School of Law</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Newark</ENAMEX>. The
study, which extrapolated from federal data on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 200,000</NUMEX> large
and midsize <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX>, concludes that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about two million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>
were affected by intentional discrimination in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Roughly</NUMEX> a
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> studied appeared to have discriminated
against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minorities</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> job category, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> said
The study was based on information collected from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> by
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Equal Employment Opportunity Commission</ENAMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990 through 1999</TIMEX>
on so-called EEO-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> forms. The husband-and-wife <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alfred W.</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruth G. Blumrosen</ENAMEX> then looked at how many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> or minority
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> employed in different job categories compared
with how many were employed at other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> in the same industry
in the same geographic area.
They described a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> as an intentional discriminator if its
employment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minorities</ENAMEX> was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least two</NUMEX> standard
deviations from the average. Legally, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> are presumed to
discriminate if their employment numbers are far below the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">norm</ENAMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">About 22,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> were identified as "hard core"
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">discriminators</ENAMEX>. These <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> employed below-average numbers of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minorities</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 years</TIMEX> and their hiring of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> or
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minorities</ENAMEX> was so far below the averages that there was only one
chance in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a hundred</TIMEX> that the discrimination occurred randomly.
The study also found rising employment for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minorities</ENAMEX>,
suggesting significant progress in the workplace.
The names of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> are confidential and were not known
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professors</ENAMEX> expect to make their study
available through a Web site, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">www.</ENAMEX>eeo1.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blumrosens</ENAMEX>, who
were instrumental in setting up the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">E.E.O.C. in 1965</ENAMEX>, also say the
government should make more active use of their data.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">commission</ENAMEX> said it did not comment on draft reports.





