



<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boone</ENAMEX> legal service for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">needy</ENAMEX> may end

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kix Paul</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 23, 2002</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boone</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ia</ENAMEX>. -Poor and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elderly people</ENAMEX> may soon go without legal
representation in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boone County</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boone County Legal Aid</ENAMEX>, which for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">31 years</TIMEX> has provided legal
services to those who couldn't afford them, will close in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX>
if a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10,000</NUMEX> grant from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prairie Meadows Racetrack</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Casino</ENAMEX> is not
awarded.
The legal service is one of the few programs in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> that offers
legal representation to those who qualify without turning to the
state for its services.
"It is a very sad situation, but that's the fact," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schroeder</ENAMEX>, city <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supervisor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boone County</ENAMEX> Legal Aid.
For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past two years</TIMEX> using money mostly from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">county</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schroeder</ENAMEX> has upheld the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outfit</ENAMEX> alone, taking on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 60</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>, and settling cases that range from domestic abuse to
bankruptcy. He also has a private practice.
If the legal service closes, he's unsure where his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> will
go.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boone</ENAMEX> gave <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schroeder</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6,300</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX> to resolve
pending cases, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathy Berg</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boone</ENAMEX>'s finance <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX>. Without
that, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">program</ENAMEX> might already be closed.
"All <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> are having problems with finances," <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boone</ENAMEX> Mayor
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Maybee</ENAMEX> said. "No one else stepped in. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">county</ENAMEX> didn't. The
state didn't."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donovan Olson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of the county <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board of Supervisors</ENAMEX>, said
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> quit funding the legal service in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX> because it felt
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">county</ENAMEX> didn't need it. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drake University</ENAMEX> ended its funding after
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000 spring semester</TIMEX> "for a variety of reasons," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Suzanne</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Levitt</ENAMEX>, the law <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> who oversaw the program, said via
e-mail.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Olson</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schroeder</ENAMEX> must prove <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prairie Meadows</ENAMEX> is the primary
money <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> to grant the program any more money.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schroeder</ENAMEX> ran the program without the help of law <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> or
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Drake</ENAMEX>, which had provided <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">as much as two-thirds</NUMEX> of the money in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">some years</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Olson</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> did not want to be the main money
source. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schroeder</ENAMEX> told them he would apply for grants, but he
received none.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schroeder</ENAMEX> may not hear from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prairie Meadows</ENAMEX> until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>, but he
believes he can last until then.




