



The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">San Diego Union-Tribune</ENAMEX>

Bridging the legal aid access gap

<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karen A. Lash</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Earl Johnson Jr.</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 10, 2002</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lash</ENAMEX> is associate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dean</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Southern California</ENAMEX>
Law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">School</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Second District</ENAMEX>
Court of Appeal. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lash</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> are co-chairs of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>
Commission on Access to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX>. The full report can be viewed at
(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">calbar</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">org</ENAMEX>).
In her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year-long</TIMEX> odyssey through the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice</ENAMEX> system,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katherine</ENAMEX>, a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">35-year-old</TIMEX> single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>,
experienced failure at every turn.
Leaving her abusive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>, she moved into the only apartment
she could afford, and soon discovered a broken toilet and non-
working <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">oven</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX> and roaches, and a fourthfloor <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">landing</ENAMEX> with no
railing. She began withholding rent pending repairs her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">landlord</ENAMEX>
refused to make, but then her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medi-Cal</ENAMEX> benefits were cut off when
she could not provide rent receipts. She lost health care for her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and herself, although she is a borderline diabetic in need
of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medication</ENAMEX> and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> were suffering from <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX> bites.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katherine</ENAMEX> tried to seek help through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX>. Representing
herself at an administrative hearing, she lost her appeal to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">restore Medi-Cal</ENAMEX> benefits because she did not have proper
documentation of the rent account. When she went to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courthouse</ENAMEX> to
file a complaint against her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">landlord</ENAMEX>, she found the process so
confusing that she gave up and went home.
According to "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Path to Justice: A Five-Year Status Report</ENAMEX> on
Access to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>," prepared by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>
Commission on Access to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katherine</ENAMEX> is just one of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4.6</NUMEX>
million poor <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Californians</ENAMEX> whose basic civil legal needs -- often
involving such critical needs as housing, health care, education,
employment, safety and transportation -- are not being
addressed.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> has a critical dearth of legal services for the poor,
and, as this report makes clear, it is imperative that the state
join with the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and private funders to increase
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resources</ENAMEX> so that all <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Californians</ENAMEX>, regardless of income, have
equal access to our justice system.
Our justice system is predicated on the assumption that both
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> will be represented by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> who act as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gatekeepers</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">guides</ENAMEX> through a complex legal system that would otherwise be
inaccessible to many of us. Unfortunately, the most vulnerable
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of our society are the least able to afford legal services.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> does have a strong network of legal aid <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>
that try to help meet the needs of the poor, but there's just one
legal aid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> available per <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poor people</ENAMEX>. We may promise
"justice for all," but for those who can't afford a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>, that
promise is often a lie.
In its new report, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission on Access</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX> notes
some significant steps toward providing equal access to justice for
all <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Californians</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>, thanks to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gray Davis</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legislature</ENAMEX>, the state committed <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10 million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> to legal
aid for the poor. In addition, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">California Supreme Court</ENAMEX> Chief
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald George</ENAMEX> made "access to justice" issues a top
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">priority</ENAMEX>, and a growing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> of judicial, legal and civic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> committed to expanding legal aid is working to ensure that
what little funding is available is used in the most efficient way
possible.
But resources are extremely limited. The combined federal and
state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> support in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> is at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$84.5 million</NUMEX> on legal
aid for the poor -- <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">just $13.20</NUMEX> per poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission on</ENAMEX>
Access to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX> says that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> investment would have to
triple to match the investment made by comparable <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> and the
combined public/private investment must reach <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$533 million</NUMEX> to
adequately meet the legal needs of the poor. That may sound beyond
financial reach, but it is actually <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 2 percent</NUMEX> of the amount
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Californians</ENAMEX> spend on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> each year -- and that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2 percent</NUMEX> would
be providing legal assistance to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">nearly 20 percent</NUMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>.
This isn't a controversial issue. Close to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Americans</ENAMEX>
(<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">89 percent</NUMEX>) agree that legal help for civil matters should be
provided for low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">commission</ENAMEX>'s
report. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Eight</NUMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> even support the idea when it is
described as a government-funded program. Indeed, in many states
throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, government funding for lega l aid doubles
or triples that of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>. And democratic governments
throughout the world have recognized that government funding for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> is as critical to a fair legal system as are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX>, courts
and laws. For a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> whose economy is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">sixth</NUMEX> largest in the
world, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> should certainly be able to adequately fund free
civil legal aid.
More funding and more resources for legal services for the poor
must be a statewide priority. Recent achievements -- new government
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">funding</ENAMEX>, a growing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> of legal aid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> -- demonstrate
that the goal of equal access to justice for all <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Californians</ENAMEX> is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">achievable</ENAMEX> and that the public as well as key <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> throughout
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> will support the effort.
The statistics might seem cold, but it's impossib <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">le</ENAMEX> to remain
complacent after meeting someone like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katherine</ENAMEX> -- or a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> who
has been left homeless by an illegal eviction, a senior who lost
his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> to foreclosure from a crooked loan transaction, or a
domestic violence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> unable to navigate the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> to get a
restraining order. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> can -and must -- do better.





