



Business Wire
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State's Poor</ENAMEX> to Lose <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2 Million</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday, November 13, 2002</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">DETROIT</ENAMEX>-(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BUSINESS WIRE</ENAMEX>)-<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 13, 2002</TIMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michigan</ENAMEX> will lose <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX> in federal funding and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$600,000</NUMEX> in state funding to provide
legal aid to the poor in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX>, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deierdre L. Weir</ENAMEX>,
executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid and Defender Association, Inc.</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s largest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">provider</ENAMEX> of legal services to the poor.
Current federal funds of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">nearly $10.7 million</NUMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Services Corporation</ENAMEX> (LSC) will drop to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$8.7 million</NUMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>,
according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weir</ENAMEX>. She said that the reductions reflect a decline
in the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> who are living in poverty,
according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Census Bureau</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> census.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> uses census data to determine funding across the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>, and
according to the census, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s poverty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> fell from
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">an estimated 1.2 million</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">an estimated 968,000</NUMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s legal aid <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> are also bracing for yet another
cut in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">some $600,000</NUMEX> of state funding. A portion of filing
fees paid by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">litigants</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">circuit courts</ENAMEX>, and a portion
of interest on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> trust accounts (IOLTA) are earmarked for
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michigan</ENAMEX> legal aid programs. These funds are expected to drop from
currently <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$7.5 million</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6.9 million</NUMEX> when the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michigan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Bar Foundation</ENAMEX> makes distributions <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>. Most of the
decrease is attributed to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past year</TIMEX>'s low interest rates.
"The irony of these funding cuts is that while there may be
fewer poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michigan</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, the demand for service will
not change because the poverty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> remains so large and the
legal aid funding so little that local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX> will never able to
serve all who need our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weir</ENAMEX>. "It's as if the poor
will be victimized <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">twice</NUMEX>-once for being poor and again as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>
of these funding cuts."
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Census Bureau</ENAMEX>, in spite of its best efforts, cannot
locate every poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> living in a census tract, therefore the
poor are also undercounted, added <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weir</ENAMEX>.
The brunt of these cuts will be felt most in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wayne County</ENAMEX> where
according to the census <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">some 333,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poor people</ENAMEX> live, the largest
concentration of poverty in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAD</ENAMEX> will lose more than
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$870,000</NUMEX> for legal aid in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wayne County</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly half</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s
total loss, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weir</ENAMEX>.
While difficult to measure, the loss of funds will mean that
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">several thousand</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michigan</ENAMEX>'s poor in need of legal service will
not receive it, or they will receive significantly limited <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX>.
Cutbacks will include service in such civil legal matters as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">landlord-tenant</ENAMEX>, bankruptcy, consumer, child custody, predatory
lending, mortgage foreclosure, utility shutoffs, social security,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">wills</ENAMEX>, and probate.
"Local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX> will have to work harder and smarter and use
more technology instead of staff to provide as much service as we
can with fewer dollars," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weir</ENAMEX>. "We will be providing more
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">selfhelp</ENAMEX> training to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> enabling them to navigate the legal
system on their own in routine matters, more assistance on the
telephone, and less direct representation by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> in specific,
high impact matters.
Currently, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michigan</ENAMEX> has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX> legal aid <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> covering the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">state</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">83</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">counties</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Eight</NUMEX> receive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> funding in addition to
receiving charitable gifts and grants from various local
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX>. Most of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX> rely on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> funding for at
least <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">40 percent</NUMEX> of their <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> operating budgets. Some of these
providers have already laid off <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> and support <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> in
anticipation of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>'s reduced funding, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weir</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weir</ENAMEX> added that the legal aid <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> will also recruit more
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> from private practice to handle legal aid cases for free,
and accelerate efforts to find alternative funding.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> is a private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">nonprofit organization</ENAMEX> established by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1974</TIMEX> to provide legal services to the poor. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>
appropriated <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$329 million</NUMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> to distribute to local programs
across the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> has requested the same amount for
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>'s funding request from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> is essentially unchanged,
says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weir</ENAMEX>, because the poverty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> has decreased in some
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michigan</ENAMEX>, but has risen in others, and the number of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> living in poverty has changed little over the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past decade</TIMEX>.
According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S Census Bureau</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">33.6 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> were living below poverty level in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>, compared to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">31.6</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>.
However, the census <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bureau</ENAMEX>'s adjusted estimates for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX> show an
increase in poverty nationally. "The poverty rate and the number of
poor both rose in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>, to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">11.7 percent</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">32.9 million</NUMEX>, up
from

<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">11.3 percent</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">31.6 million</NUMEX>," states <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Poverty</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>, a recent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bureau</ENAMEX> report.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weir</ENAMEX> says that traditionally <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> sticks to the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10-year</TIMEX> census
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX>, and will not change its funding based on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2001</ENAMEX> data,
however it is possible that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> will make an adjustment in the
future.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAD</ENAMEX> was established in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1909</TIMEX> as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid Society of Detroit</ENAMEX>
and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> is the largest legal aid <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">provider</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michigan</ENAMEX> and one of
the largest of its kind in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> With a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">80</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX>
and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">90</NUMEX> support <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> provides civil legal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">services</ENAMEX> and criminal representation of indigent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defendants</ENAMEX> in both
state and federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAD</ENAMEX> services <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 15,000</NUMEX> citizens
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annually</TIMEX>.
In addition to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAD</ENAMEX> is funded by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Way</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southeastern</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michigan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michigan State Bar Foundation</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Detroit Area Agency</ENAMEX> on
Aging, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Senior Alliance</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">City of Detroit</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wayne County</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Housing and Urban Development</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Administrative Office</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Courts</ENAMEX>, and private donations.




