



Business Wire

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Equal Access</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Foundation Allocates $8 Million</ENAMEX>
to Low-Income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Residents</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday, November 13, 2002</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">AUSTIN</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>-(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BUSINESS WIRE</ENAMEX>)-<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 13, 2002</TIMEX>-The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Equal</ENAMEX>
Access to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Foundation</ENAMEX> (TEAJF) has announced its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX> grant
plan for the designation of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$8 million</NUMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX> of civil
legal services to the poor, otherwise known as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid</ENAMEX>.
The funds will assist nonprofit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> in providing legal
assistance, such as advice or representation, to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> who
cannot afford <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court of Texas</ENAMEX> created the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foundation</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">txiolta</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">org</ENAMEX>) in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1984</TIMEX> to administer funds earmarked for the
provision of civil <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid</ENAMEX> to low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Texans</ENAMEX>. Currently, TEAJF
manages funds from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Interest</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lawyers' Trust</ENAMEX> Accounts (IOLTA)
Program; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Basic Civil Legal Services</ENAMEX> (BCLS), a court filing fee
add-on; and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crime Victims Civil Legal Services</ENAMEX> (CVCLS)
Program.
The grant awards in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort Worth</ENAMEX> are as follows:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">----------------------------------- City Organization</ENAMEX> IOLTA BCLS
Total ----------------------------------- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dallas Catholic</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Charities</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> 36,000 38,000 74,000
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">----------------------------------- Dallas Dallas Bar</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community Service Fund</ENAMEX> 35,000 21,000 56,000
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">----------------------------------- Dallas Dallas Legal</ENAMEX> Hospice
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">55,000 55,000</NUMEX> ----------------------------------- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dallas Housing</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crisis Center</ENAMEX> 29,000 21,000 50,000
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">----------------------------------- Dallas Legal Services</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">North</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>(a) <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">321,000 196,000 517,000</NUMEX>
----------------------------------- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> Total <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">476,000 276,000</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">276,000</NUMEX> -----------------------------------
According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Census Bureau</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">approximately 293,000</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas County</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX>, or <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">13 percent</NUMEX> of the county <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>,
live below poverty level. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Eleven</NUMEX> percent of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tarrant County</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">population</ENAMEX>, or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">150,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX>, live below poverty level. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TEAJF</ENAMEX> grants will allow <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">39</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> of which are
located in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas County</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of which are located in Tarrant
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">County</ENAMEX>, to continue or increase their services to ensure that all
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Texans</ENAMEX> are afforded access to justice.
In addition to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> located in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort</ENAMEX>
Worth, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Equal Access</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Foundation</ENAMEX> has allocated
funds to the following <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> that serves the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northwest Texas</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Service Area</ENAMEX>, including <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tarrant</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">counties</ENAMEX>, but whose main
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> is located in another city




