



<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Daily</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American News</ENAMEX>

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Butler Co.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> give time to provide equality in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">justice</ENAMEX>
By <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackie Harder ~</ENAMEX> Staff <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Writer</ENAMEX>

<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 11, 2002</TIMEX>
There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 30</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Butler County</ENAMEX> that volunteer
for an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> offering free legal services for low income or
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elderly households</ENAMEX>. Legal Services of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Southern Missouri</ENAMEX> (LSSM)
serves <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">43</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">counties</ENAMEX> in this area and is dedicated to ensuring all
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, regardless of their income, equal access to legal advice
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX>. Out of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">43</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">counties</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSSM</ENAMEX> service region,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Butler County</ENAMEX> has the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX> highest number of cases served in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>
and the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> largest number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney panel members</ENAMEX>.
"The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Butler County</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> have really stepped up to the plate
to help us represent the poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">county</ENAMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSSM</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Development</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sharon Alexander</ENAMEX>. "We had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">approximately 400</NUMEX>
cases in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Butler County</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>."
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSSM</ENAMEX> is funded by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services Corporation</ENAMEX> (LSC)- a
private, not-for-profit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>. Created by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, LSSM
also receives funding from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Missouri Lawyer Trust</ENAMEX> Account
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foundation</ENAMEX> and local area <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> on aging. But LSSM credits the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> that volunteer their time and skills to representing the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">underprivileged</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elderly</ENAMEX> for the success of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>.
Currently, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSSM</ENAMEX> utilizes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">243</NUMEX> private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> who
provide a minimum of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">20 hours</TIMEX> of pro bono or two pro bono cases per
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>.
"Fundamentally, what we're trying to do is provide equal access
to justice, for all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> - regardless of their economic
standing," said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSSM Board</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX> and volunteer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hall</ENAMEX>. "If a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> knocks his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> down, breaks her jaw or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX> -
abuses her terribly - he will be picked up and put in jail. But
he's entitled to have a public <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defender</ENAMEX> ... Don't you think she's
entitled to have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> to get a temporary restraining order from
this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>?"
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSSM</ENAMEX> operates like a law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>, but does not charge fees to their
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>. Due to federal guidelines, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSSM</ENAMEX> does not accept cases
concerning criminal, post-criminal, or municipal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> matters.
Rather, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> provide pro bono <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> in matters such as
protecting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouse</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> abuse, protecting individuals
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> from loss of housing through illegal eviction or
assisting the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elderly</ENAMEX> in disputing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX> claim denials.
"<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> example of a case we recently handled was over in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Springfield</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander</ENAMEX> said. "There was an elderly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who had
some plumbing work done to her home and the work was not up to
standards and the cost was above what it should have been ... we
were able to help her through our pro bono program. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> local
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Springfield</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> volunteered to handle the case."
According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSSM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> won the case and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> did not have to pay for the shoddy plumbing, nor did she have
to pay any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> fees. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">About two weeks later</TIMEX>, the local
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">newspaper</ENAMEX> reported that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sheriff</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> was investigating
the plumbing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> for defrauding the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elderly</ENAMEX>.
To qualify for legal assistance, one's income must be at or
below <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">125 percent</NUMEX> of the poverty level, as determined by the
federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. According to statistics provided by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSSM</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15.8</NUMEX>
percent of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSSM</ENAMEX>'s service area are classified as
poor and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20 percent</NUMEX> are classified as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elderly</ENAMEX>. Due to their limited
staff and budget, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSSM</ENAMEX> can only serve a fraction of those who need
legal representation. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">almost half</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSSM</ENAMEX> case
applications were denied.





