



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Associated</ENAMEX> Press

Campaign Pays for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Victims</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Representation</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, October 15, 2002</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BOISE</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Idaho</ENAMEX> (AP) - <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Victims</ENAMEX> of domestic violence will have
access to quality legal representation through a campaign
undertaken by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Idaho</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Copple Trout</ENAMEX>
and corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>.
"<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Thousands</NUMEX> of times <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Idahoans</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> of domestic
violence. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> are often <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and they
frequently have few resources with which to pursue their legal
rights," <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trout</ENAMEX> said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>.
"This <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">campaign</ENAMEX> helps fill that gap in legal services for women
who need the help at a time when they are in crisis."
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Idaho Partners</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Project</ENAMEX> has already secured
pledges of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $35,000</NUMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">law firms</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>. The goal is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100,000</NUMEX>. The drive to
pay for free legal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX> will continue for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the next two</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX>.
The money goes to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Idaho</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid Services</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Idaho</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Volunteer Lawyers Program</ENAMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 5,000</NUMEX> petitions were filed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Idaho</ENAMEX> for
protection orders in domestic violence cases. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">More than 12,000</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> contacted <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shelters</ENAMEX> or crisis hotlines.
Joining <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trout</ENAMEX> in the announcement was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Idaho Bar Association</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred Hoopes</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Idaho Falls</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ida</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">West Energy Co.</ENAMEX> Chief
Executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Officer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy Hill</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the project's executive
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">committee</ENAMEX>. Also on hand were some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> of such
violence, but benefited from free legal services.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX>'s campaign generated enough money and resources to
help <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 450</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>. The help ranged from representation in
protection order hearings to legal assistance in divorce,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">visitation</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> support cases. The donations are tax
deductible.




