



Legal Aid in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Civil Matters</ENAMEX> is Important
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawmakers</ENAMEX> are quickly moving through legislation to
provide legal aid for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">needy families</ENAMEX> dealing with civil
litigation.
When <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">indigent citizens</ENAMEX> get in criminal trouble, public <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defenders</ENAMEX>
are made available by law. But civil issues involving family law,
domestic violence, immigration, financial or housing problems can
undermine a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s employment and destabilize a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> in short
order.
So it is not just compassionate to ensure that legal services of
this type are available; it is also in the broader interest of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> and society. And an exemption --- that the money
wouldn't be used to fight <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DUI</ENAMEX> charges --- is completely
appropriate.
Though some <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10 million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> would probably fill the bill for
civil legal aid in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>, just <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$500,000</NUMEX> is in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s
strained budget at this time.
Prior to the welfare reform legislation, some federal resources
were available for civil legal aid --- that and the vast amount of
pro bono work by private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX>. That's <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $170 million</NUMEX> a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> alone.
It had been hoped to use surplus federal funds earmarked for
transitional welfare programs as part of the welfare reform
movement, said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Florida Bar</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Terry Russell</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lauderdale</ENAMEX>. But those funds wound up set aside for other uses at
the same time as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> faces a budget crisis.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> is one of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">just 11</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> that provide no such funding
whatever, so it's to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawmakers</ENAMEX>' credit that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HB</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">491/SB 512</ENAMEX> have
unanimously passed out of every <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> to
date.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Naples</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dudley Goodlette</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burt</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saunders</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>, both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX>, are being supported by our
area <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Reps.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bev Kilmer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Curtis Richardson</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Will Kendrick</ENAMEX> and by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sens.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Lawson</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Mitchell</ENAMEX>.
The legislation is restricted at this point to, most likely,
pilot programs with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Community Affairs</ENAMEX> contracting
with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> such as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Florida Bar Foundation</ENAMEX> to distribute the
money most effectively.
And much depends upon the availability of funds at the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 8</TIMEX>
revenue estimating conference, which will give <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawmakers</ENAMEX> the latest
figures on how much they can spend in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002-03</TIMEX> budget.
Where there is a will, there is a way, however, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawmakers</ENAMEX>
have made the vital <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> step of declaring their determination to
extend to the indigent the availability of legal representation in
civil matters.



