



<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> Is Not An Empty Word

Legal <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Services Reaches Through Barrier of Poverty</ENAMEX> to Aid
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Clients</ENAMEX>



<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shirley Downing</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, November 9, 2002</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thelma James</ENAMEX> was a prime <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> for a real estate ripoff: She
is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">68</NUMEX>, has precious little money and can't read or write.
"I won't lie to you. I was so-o-o excited," the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">widow</ENAMEX> and former
duplex dweller said of the purchase of her <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> home, a sagging
frame <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Snowden</ENAMEX>. "I was glad to get me a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>."
When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James</ENAMEX> realized she had been swindled she turned to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Memphis</ENAMEX>
Area <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services</ENAMEX>, which represented her in a lawsuit. Now,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">monthly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> notes have dropped from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$796 -</NUMEX> more than
twice her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">monthly</TIMEX> income - to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">an affordable $247</NUMEX>. Some of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who took advantage of her through a questionable loan
program were sent to jail.
"I don't know what I would have done without <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services</ENAMEX>,"
said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James</ENAMEX>. "They solved a lot of my problems."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James</ENAMEX> is one of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 3,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> served <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MALS</ENAMEX>, which provides assistance for civil matters, such as domestic
abuse and family-related problems, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> and Supplemental
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Security Income</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veterans</ENAMEX>, housing and consumer fraud cases.
Like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James</ENAMEX>, most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> are elderly or female. Some are
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">handicapped</ENAMEX>. Some need medical care or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veteran</ENAMEX>'s benefits. Some are
trying to escape eviction or an abusive marriage. And <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">87 percent</NUMEX>
live at or below poverty level.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Shelby County</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> A C <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wharton</ENAMEX> recently said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services</ENAMEX> is
important for those who, because of poverty or other struggles in
life, think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice</ENAMEX> is an empty word. "They must be given reason to
believe that the law is for them too," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wharton</ENAMEX>, a former
executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MALS</ENAMEX>.
But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MALS</ENAMEX> faces a funding crunch <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>, brought on by a
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$200,000</NUMEX> shortfall from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> revenue <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>. Even though more
than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">150,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Shelby</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fayette, Tipton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lauderdale</ENAMEX>
counties qualify for public legal aid, the latest census shows a
loss of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10,166</NUMEX> poverty-level <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> in the area. The population
shift translates into a loss of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$163,000</NUMEX> by the parent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Services Corp.</ENAMEX>, combined with the loss of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$35,000</NUMEX> in
court-generated fees from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> other programs.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lawyers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> are trying to raise money for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> that
many say has worked magic with little more than gumption,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">hardscrabble</ENAMEX> dollars and a rambling, <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>-floor warren of rooms
across the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Hall</ENAMEX>.
Several <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">law firms</ENAMEX> have donated <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $25,000</NUMEX> and the Community
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foundation</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greater Memphis</ENAMEX> recently pledged <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$75,000</NUMEX> over three
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MALS</ENAMEX> was formed here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than 30 years ago</TIMEX>. Today, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX> staff
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">26</TIMEX> office workers and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Memphis</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>-
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> law <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> work out of rented <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> in the old <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Claridge</ENAMEX>
Hotel <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">109</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N. Main</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Offices</ENAMEX> are spartan. There are no lush rugs or stylish
furniture. The large table in the conference <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> is simple
varnished <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wood</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Offices</ENAMEX> are small and mostly plain, except for the
eclectic mix of pop art, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">statuary</ENAMEX> and neon that adorns
litigation <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Webb Brewer</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">space</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brewer</ENAMEX>, who has been at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 years</TIMEX>, said there is a
need for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> of all stripes to help with the problems of the
poor.
"The private bar could meet more of the need through pro bono
work, but there are still cases that involve the systemic problems
for low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that we would need to do," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brewer</ENAMEX>.
"The legal system marketplace just doesn't serve low-income
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> too well, except in fee-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">generat</NUMEX>-ing type cases," <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Brewer</ENAMEX>
said. "If a poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> gets run over by a bus, an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> might
take that case because they might be able to recover part of the
damage award as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> fees. But so many of the cases we handle
have to do with basic rights and a decent life. There is just no
profit motive."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Pivnick</ENAMEX>, law <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Memphis Law</ENAMEX>
School and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of political programs at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MALS</ENAMEX>, said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Services</ENAMEX> is a great learning laboratory for law <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>.
"There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who have problems
that never get an opportunity to appear in court," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pivnick</ENAMEX> said.
"Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> may not be particularly articulate. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Courts</ENAMEX> have rules
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> don't always understand."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brewer</ENAMEX> said a major focus of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>'s work involves
housing.
"Although a lot of our work is grant-driven, we find that the
lack of safe and decent affordable housing and the prevalence of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">predatory</ENAMEX> lending are the biggest problems in our client
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">population</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brewer</ENAMEX> said, referring to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James</ENAMEX> spoke with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> during a recent visit at MALS
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX>. Other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> there <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that day</TIMEX> included a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">42-year-old</TIMEX> woman
who needed help getting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> support payments from her former
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">lover</ENAMEX>, a married <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">preacher</ENAMEX> who had fathered a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> with her during
a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six-year</TIMEX> affair.
Down the hall was longtime <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community activist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Georgia King</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">62</TIMEX>,
talking to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> about her pending eviction from a high-rise
efficiency <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX> said she is accused of having too much
clutter.
"I was homeless when I went there, and everything I got,
somebody had give to me," she said, noting she is trying to sift
through things. "If they had give me a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-bedroom I would have
room for everything. "
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX> has high praise for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services</ENAMEX>. "They help you in a lot
of different areas," she said.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dana Brandon</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">43</TIMEX>, turned to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MALS</ENAMEX> for help finding a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and
treatment program for her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> after it became clear the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> would not fit into any of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> school system's special
education programs.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brandon</ENAMEX> could not hire a private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> because she has to
stay home to tend her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>, who is often violent and who requires
constant supervision. "I think they have been very helpful," she
said.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andre Turner</ENAMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ex-Marine</ENAMEX>, turned to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services</ENAMEX> when he was
fired from his job for missing too much work. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Turner</ENAMEX>'s 12-year-old
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> needs a kidney transplant and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Turner</ENAMEX> said he had to miss work
to take him to numerous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> and dialysis visits.
When he was fired, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Turner</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> lost his insurance and his place
in line for the transplant.
"I felt like my rights were violated," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Turner</ENAMEX> said, noting that
though the case is still pending, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services</ENAMEX> was able to get
the insurance reinstated. The transplant is now closer to
reality.
The hardest part of losing his job, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Turner</ENAMEX> said, was answering
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>. "He still asks me if he is going to die, and if I'm still
going to give him my kidney."



