



The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commercial Appeal Memphis</ENAMEX>

Grants Help <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Optimize Nonprofits</ENAMEX>' Ability to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aid Community</ENAMEX>
Programs
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deborah M Clubb</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, October 26, 2002</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Memphis Area Legal Services</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> other nonprofit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> will
share <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $124,000</NUMEX> to help them operate, analyze and plan for
growth and survival, thanks to a new focus by the Community
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foundation</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greater Memphis</ENAMEX>.
The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> grants flow from a new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nonprofit Capacity Building</ENAMEX>
program at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundation</ENAMEX>, part of a trend among <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">philanthropists</ENAMEX> to
give money to help <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> grow stronger, rather than to the
program services they provide.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community Foundation</ENAMEX> program is primarily for well-
established nonprofits that may need assistance to take the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organization</ENAMEX> to another level of performance, said foundation
executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gid Smith</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MALS</ENAMEX> grant of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25,000</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annually</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX> is called a
"bridge" grant to help the nonprofit law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> survive a short-term
challenge. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MALS</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this month</TIMEX> announced it expects to lose
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$200,000</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX> and beyond, largely due to a drop in the number of
poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> it serves in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">counties</ENAMEX>, according to the latest
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Census</ENAMEX>.
The nonprofit law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 40</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> and an annual
budget of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3 million</NUMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX> it received <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 6,000</NUMEX>
applications for help and was able to serve <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3,421</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MALS</ENAMEX> has
appealed to the legal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> for funds and greater commitment to
pro bono services - donating their expertise to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">needy</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community Foundation</ENAMEX> is awarding <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25,000</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> but
requiring <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MALS</ENAMEX> to submit a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three-year</TIMEX> fund-raising plan. In the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">third year</TIMEX> of the grant, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CFGM</ENAMEX> funds will be awarded as a
match, with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MALS</ENAMEX> raising <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">at least $3</NUMEX> for every <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1</NUMEX> the foundation
provides.
In effect, the grant challenges <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MALS</ENAMEX> to raise <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">at least $100,000</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003 and 2004</TIMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX>, that campaign - primarily among
private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> - drew <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">less than $40,000</NUMEX> while the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nashville</ENAMEX>
legal aid fund-raising garnered <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $500,000</NUMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harrison D. McIver III</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MALS</ENAMEX> executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>, said the agency
was "very gratified" by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community Foundation</ENAMEX>'s grant. "We have
been working very hard to call the legal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX>'s and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">public</ENAMEX>'s attention to our funding crisis and its impact on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MALS</ENAMEX>'s
efforts to secure equal access to justice for our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX>'s poor
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elderly residents</ENAMEX>."




