



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coup Reshapes Legal Aid Programs</ENAMEX>:
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Directors</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Path is Smooth While Another's is Rough</ENAMEX>
By <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gina Keating Daily Journal Staff Writer</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">LOS ANGELES</ENAMEX> - A government-sponsored coup <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> made <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bruce</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iwasaki</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neal Dudovitz</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">kings</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles County</ENAMEX>'s
federally funded legal aid <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX>.
The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> emerged atop a changed landscape that resulted from
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a decade</TIMEX> of begging for a share of shrinking public dollars doled
out by an unsympathetic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>-controlled <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>. That era was
capped in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>, when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services Corp.</ENAMEX> forced <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">275</NUMEX> legal aid
providers nationwide to combine into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">179</NUMEX>.
To comply with the orders from their main funding source, a new
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX> of poverty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> emerged - a tech-savvy and button-down
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">breed</ENAMEX> who swapped neighborhood <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">walkin offices</ENAMEX> for toll-free phone
lines, self-help <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kiosks</ENAMEX> and Internet access to legal advice.
While some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> made the dramatic change look
effortless, for others, it did not come easy. And few programs
provide more dramatic illustrations of the promise and pitfalls of
government-funded legal services than <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles County</ENAMEX>'s two
largest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX> of federally funded services - <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foundation</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pacoima</ENAMEX>-based <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Neighborhood Legal</ENAMEX>
Services of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles County</ENAMEX>.
From his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Koreatown</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iwasaki</ENAMEX>, a soft-spoken former
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O'Melveny & Myers</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX>, quietly engineered a merger between
a much smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid Society</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Long Beach</ENAMEX> and his program, the
Legal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aid Foundation</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>. The merger was completed
peacefully within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> of the federal order.
Today, the programs operate seamlessly, offering new innovations
- including toll-free multilingual phone <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisers</ENAMEX>, expanded hours
for domestic-violence <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clinics</ENAMEX>, and renewed immigration and consumer
aid - built on the foundations of the old program. The organization
is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>' largest government-funded <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>, with a budget of
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$11 million</NUMEX> leveraged into <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$40 million</NUMEX> in legal services to the
poor.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iwasaki</ENAMEX>'s careful respect for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Long Beach</ENAMEX> program and its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> earned him the political capital he needed to complete his
takeover in a matter of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX>.
"The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Long Beach</ENAMEX> program had strong support in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> so
in a situation like that, one has to recognize that it's not like a
takeover where I have all the answers and I know best," Iwasaki
said. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> who are working there have the
contacts and the knowledge that will allow service to
continue."
Things have gone less smoothly across <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>. There, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dudovitz</ENAMEX>, a
longtime poverty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> and executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Fernando</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Valley</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">36-year-old</TIMEX> legal aid program, continues to struggle with
his hostile takeover of the neighboring <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Gabriel</ENAMEX>-Pomona Valleys
service area <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one year</TIMEX> after it was accomplished.
On the bright side, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dudovitz</ENAMEX> has extended his respected program
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">San Gabriel-Pomona Valley</ENAMEX>, and he now operates on
a much larger budget, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6.5 million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>. However, his clash
with the old <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">San Gabriel</ENAMEX> program resulted in litigation, bitter
feelings and a mission that some say is not clearly focused on
serving poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.
"It was a difficult situation that was probably mishandled by
everyone," a longtime <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">observer</ENAMEX> of the public interest community
said of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">San Fernando Valley-San Gabriel-Pomona Valley</ENAMEX> merger.
"There are very few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who come out as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroes</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Personalities</ENAMEX> got involved when they shouldn't have. Things were
said that caused bad feelings and couldn't be unsaid."
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iwasaki</ENAMEX>'s merger with the smaller, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">48-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Long Beach</ENAMEX>
program was friendly and fast, and no one - not even <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Long Beach</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> - lost a job.
When it was over, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iwasaki</ENAMEX> had <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 million</NUMEX> more in federal dollars
and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX>. Long <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beach</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> regained services they had
lost <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> when federal budget cuts and dwindling grants
reduced the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> and cut immigration and
consumer law programs.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iwasaki</ENAMEX> said, "[I judged the transition] better than I could
have hoped for."
Former <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Long Beach</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Executive Director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Toby Rothschild</ENAMEX>, now a
policy wonk in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iwasaki</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outfit</ENAMEX>, agreed.
"To some extent, I did look at it and say, 'We are the littlest
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">kid</ENAMEX> on the block, and we don't want to get beat up so we need a
bigger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protector</ENAMEX>,'" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rothschild</ENAMEX> said. "Once we got past that, it
became a real positive for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Long Beach</ENAMEX> program and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Long Beach</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>."
But to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">San Gabriel-Pomona Valley</ENAMEX> legal aid program, the
positives of merging with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dudovitz</ENAMEX>'s program, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Fernando Valley</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Neighborhood Legal Services</ENAMEX>, were never obvious.
A meeting in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late 1999</TIMEX> between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dudovitz</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">San</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gabriel</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pomona Valley</ENAMEX> program's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> showed how little the two
programs had in common and how difficult bridging the gap between
their ideologies would be, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dudovitz</ENAMEX> recalled.
Although no merger plans were discussed, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> at the
smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">program</ENAMEX> knew of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dudovitz</ENAMEX>'s preference for impact litigation
over direct services.
"We had a discussion about what our separate views were,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dudovitz</ENAMEX> said. "The message we got was that they wanted their
program to stay as it was."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lauralea Saddick</ENAMEX>, former executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">San</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gabriel</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pomona Valley</ENAMEX> program, said her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> simply did not share
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dudovitz</ENAMEX>'s desire to spend money influencing social policy and
participating in high-profile litigation over poverty-related
issues.
"Our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX>'s philosophy was that the money given by the federal
government was to help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with basic everyday needs," Saddick
said. "It might take a little bit of humility to take those kinds
of cases. Impact work is very important ... but what was the good
of getting the law changed if no one is there to help the
individual?"
Before the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Gabriel</ENAMEX> program was subsumed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dudovitz's</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>,
it offered to merge with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid Society of Orange County</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX> of both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> eschewed impact litigation in
favor of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">1960s</NUMEX> model of providing direct client services.
Supported by resolutions from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pasadena</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Gabriel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastern</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foothill</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar associations</ENAMEX>, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> programs drew up plans to
merge and submitted them to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services Corp.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dudovitz</ENAMEX> won <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iwasaki</ENAMEX>'s backing to oppose the deal, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Services Corp.</ENAMEX>, the national funding source, overruled the proposed
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">San Gabriel-Pomona Valley</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Orange County</ENAMEX> merger. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 27, 2001</TIMEX>,
the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> awarded the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">San Gabriel-Pomona Valley</ENAMEX> service
area to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dudovitz</ENAMEX> under the umbrella of an expanded <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Fernando</ENAMEX>
program, citing the location of both programs in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>, which
would allow "better coordinated and more effective advocacy on
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">county</ENAMEX> government policies."
The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">San Gabriel-Pomona Valley</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">program</ENAMEX> sued <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services Corp.</ENAMEX>
to stop the takeover, claiming the federal program based the
decision on favoritism for the politically active <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dudovitz</ENAMEX> and the
politically powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iwasaki</ENAMEX>.
Though the federal suit accomplished little, it effectively
suspended <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the old</TIMEX> program and the start of the new one
for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nearly a year</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Hundreds</NUMEX> of case files, as well as <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX>
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pasadena</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pomona</ENAMEX>, remained under the old program's control
until the litigation ended in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 2001</TIMEX>.
"We weren't being uncooperative in the matter, they were not
reasoning [the transition] out like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>," former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">San</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gabriel</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pomona Valley</ENAMEX> board <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerome Applebaum</ENAMEX> said.
During <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this period</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dudovitz</ENAMEX> did what he could to claim his new
territory - a huge area bounded by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ventura</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kern</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bernardino and Riverside</ENAMEX> county lines and state <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Route 60</ENAMEX>. He
renamed his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">program Neighborhood Legal Services</ENAMEX> of Los Angeles
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">County</ENAMEX>.
He set up a temporary office in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El Monte</ENAMEX>, advertised his
toll-free phone line through the radio, local elected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX>. He sent paralegals and staff <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> to conduct
several daylong educational <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clinics</ENAMEX> at local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and
communitybased <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>. And he accepted city <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>'
invitations to analyze and comment on a low-income housing
ordinance in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pasadena</ENAMEX> along with other housing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Neighborhood Legal Services</ENAMEX> participated in several cooperative
efforts with homeless advocacy and health care <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> in his new
territory.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dudovitz</ENAMEX> said that he is halfway to his goal of reorganizing his
new territory.
Still untaken are several steps that required goodwill from
local bar <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX> and others who had opposed the
combination.
"[I am] not a fan of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neal</ENAMEX>'s," admitted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Peck</ENAMEX>, a former board
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">San Gabriel-Pomona Valley</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">program</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pasadena Bar</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peck</ENAMEX> says bad feelings still linger among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">allies</ENAMEX> of the old
program who feel left out.
"They really screwed us. We had a good program," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peck</ENAMEX> said.
An <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">observer</ENAMEX> familiar with the reconfiguration debate who
requested anonymity wondered why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dudovitz</ENAMEX> had not spent more time
mending fences.
"He ought to be bending over backwards for reconciliation, but
if you want to do impact work and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">San Gabriel Valley</ENAMEX>
want direct services, you have to accommodate that or change your
approach," the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">observer</ENAMEX> said. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neal</ENAMEX> would never consider doing
that."
More than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> after he officially incorporated the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">San</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gabriel</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pomona Valley</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dudovitz</ENAMEX> had not placed a local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">resident</ENAMEX> on
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Neighborhood Legal Services</ENAMEX> or made the rounds of the
private legal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> to recruit the volunteer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>.
"Our emphasis has been on having our potential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> know
about us and deliver services to them," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dudovitz</ENAMEX> said. "We have
done that spectacularly."
He did not hire any of the old program's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> and has
yet to permanently place any of his <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX> new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hires</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">San</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gabriel</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pomona Valley</ENAMEX>. The lack of a legal aid presence in Pomona
prompted the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar association</ENAMEX> and court <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> to start their own
once-<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">monthly</TIMEX> family law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clinic</ENAMEX>.
After learning of the effort, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dudovitz</ENAMEX> sent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX> to staff
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clinic</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three hours</TIMEX> per <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX> and is helping to write a grant
application to fund a self-help kiosk for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pomona</ENAMEX> patterned on the
center he pioneered in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Van Nuys</ENAMEX>.
The help, although late, has earned Dudovitz some
appreciation.
"There has been a transition and [the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clinic</ENAMEX>] has helped to fill
some void," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deni Butler</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">administrator</ENAMEX> for the Eastern
District <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Superior Court</ENAMEX>. "But we are working together quite nicely
contrary to what the other side issue is."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott Wheeler</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastern Bar Association of Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Angeles</ENAMEX> and an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ally</ENAMEX> of the old program, said he mobilized his <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> to staff the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clinic</ENAMEX> after watching the ranks of unserved
poor grow over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past year</TIMEX>.
"We felt we needed to take care of something that had
disappeared. We established the program because we were concerned
about the changeover," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wheeler</ENAMEX> said.
While acknowledging that building the new program from the
ground up has been slow going, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dudovitz</ENAMEX> expects to serve <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">up to 30</NUMEX>
percent more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">San Gabriel-Pomona Valley</ENAMEX> than his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">predecessors</ENAMEX>.
Of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">700,000 to 1 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are eligible for legal
aid services in his combined area, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dudovitz</ENAMEX> estimated that he will
serve <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 30,000</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annually</TIMEX>. During <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">his first year</TIMEX> in the new
territory, he served <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25,000</NUMEX> in the program - a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20 percent</NUMEX> increase
over his caseload for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Fernando</ENAMEX> alone, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dudovitz</ENAMEX> said.
"The reality is we have to make the transition step by step,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dudovitz</ENAMEX> said. "We need to establish some infrastructure before we
go out. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the worse things that you can do is promise services
that we can't deliver."
During his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">29-year</TIMEX> tenure as a public interest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>, Dudovitz
has proved that he can deliver on some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corp.</ENAMEX>'s key objectives.
By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>, he had diversified funding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> for his then-<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5.2</NUMEX>
million budget so that just <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">32 percent</NUMEX> came from federal programs.
He got the rest from private funds and state and local government
contracts and grants.
He hoped to do the same thing for the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">San Gabriel-Pomona Valley</ENAMEX>
program, whose <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.8 million</NUMEX> budget was derived almost entirely of
Legal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Services Corp.</ENAMEX> grants.
He had learned the importance of reputation to private sector
his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">program</ENAMEX> before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> for excellence in cases stemming from
the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">1994 Northridge earthquake</ENAMEX>.
"After that, we were able to raise funds," he said. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">People</ENAMEX>
generally want to give to programs that do quality work because
they get results. We are creative and effective <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX>."
Competitive bidding also became easier with a reputation to back
up his grant proposals, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dudovitz</ENAMEX> soon was raising enough to
develop slick promotional materials and to share funds with other
public interest programs to cement collaborative efforts on health
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">care</ENAMEX>, policy advocacy, homelessness, domestic-violence assistance,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">self-help</ENAMEX> and technology development.
He developed a reputation as an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">innovator</ENAMEX> with a
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">multimillion-dollar</NUMEX> grant from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">California Endowment</ENAMEX> to fund a
countywide health advocacy program called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health Consumer Center of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>.
The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3-year-old</TIMEX> program connected <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poor people</ENAMEX> with health
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">care</ENAMEX> and earned <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Dudovitz entr√</NUMEX>©e to legislative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committees</ENAMEX> and
elected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> grappling with how to provide medical services
for the poor.
Long before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services Corp.</ENAMEX> advised legal aid programs to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">recruit</ENAMEX> more privatesector <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dudovitz</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> established
domestic-violence <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clinics</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Fernando Valley</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courthouses</ENAMEX>
in a partnership with the local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar association</ENAMEX>.
He tapped that relationship again in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> to create two
self-help legal access <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> -<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Van Nuys</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courthouse</ENAMEX> and
the other at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">James Monroe High School</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Hills</ENAMEX> - where legal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">magnet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> assist pro per <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defendants</ENAMEX>.
"One of the things that is clear is that we could throw <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50 or 60</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> out there, and we could never approach the need in regards
to providing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one-on-one</NUMEX> service," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dudovitz</ENAMEX> said. "But we can be
effective if [we are] thoughtful about how we employ <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> and the
balance of the service we provide."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dudovitz</ENAMEX> acknowledged that the acrimonious transition may not
have been ideal for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> but said the range of services now
available to them will more than compensate for any lapse of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">services</ENAMEX>.
Although he lauds his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counterpart</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iwasaki</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Long Beach</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">community</ENAMEX> for their ideal marriage, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dudovitz</ENAMEX> had no regrets about
his own stormy rise to power.
"They were one of probably a handful of places in the country
where that happened," he said. "We have an opportunity to grow a
program based on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30 years</TIMEX> of experience - we aren't stuck with the
old way. That's an opportunity that very few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have had."



