



Court <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Keeps Judge From Distributing Funds To Legal Aid Groups</ENAMEX>;
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon Is Challenging His Authority To Spend Up To $750,000</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Virginia Young Post-Dispatch Jefferson City Bureau</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Missouri Court of Appeals</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Louis</ENAMEX> has blocked a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>'s
proposal to give <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">as much as $750,000</NUMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> that provide
legal services for the poor.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney General</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jay Nixon</ENAMEX> sought the order, which was granted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> on an emergency basis. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> wanted to prevent <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cole</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">County Circuit</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Brown III</ENAMEX> from distributing the funds
as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early as today</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> is challenging <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX>'s authority to spend the
money. An <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Osage County</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> who heard the dispute sided with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brown</ENAMEX>
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> is appealing that decision. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s
action bars <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX> from transferring the money until the appeals
court rules.
The funds are part of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $2.75 million</NUMEX> in interest that
accrued in several <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> cases brought on behalf of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney general</ENAMEX> contends that the money belongs in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s
unclaimed property <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">fund</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brown</ENAMEX> decided <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> to designate some of the money for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">four</TIMEX>
legal aid <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>, including the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Louis</ENAMEX>-based <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal</ENAMEX>
Services of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Eastern Missouri</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokeswoman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Still</ENAMEX>, said the emergency order "was
needed to keep the money in safekeeping, so it could be distributed
to its rightful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX>." While legal aid is a worthy cause, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>
"doesn't believe the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> has legal authority to give the money to
that cause," she said.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dale Doerhoff</ENAMEX>, said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s action was
unnecessary because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX> never intended to distribute the money
until all legal questions about his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authority</ENAMEX> were resolved.
The money is left over from cases involving utility bill
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">overpayments</ENAMEX> and an insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> insolvency. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cole</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">County Circuit</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Byron Kinder</ENAMEX> used some of the money to remodel
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Cole County</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Courthouse</ENAMEX> and to pay additional salaries to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">courthouse secretaries</ENAMEX>.



