



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crain</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Business</ENAMEX>

Legal Aid carrying on without the mod cons: Still displaced,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> make do with boxes, leaky storage <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 9, 2002</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Gandel</ENAMEX>
In her storage <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>-turned-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer Baum</ENAMEX> works under an
expanding leak that is causing the ceiling to turn brown and
crumble. Mold grows in the buckets positioned to catch the
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>.
She shrugs it off. Outside her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">office</ENAMEX> she has taped up a clear
plastic suit, and a sign that reads, "All <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> must don
protective gear before coming in."
Such is life in limbo. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nearly a year</TIMEX> after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 11</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal</ENAMEX>
Aid Society-the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>'s poor and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homeless-remains</ENAMEX>,
well, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homeless</ENAMEX>.

Contaminated space
The nonprofit has been barred from returning to its <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">90</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX>, across from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Trade Center</ENAMEX> site, because
of environmental concerns.
Legal Aid has uncomfortable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">More than 11,500</NUMEX> New
Yorkers continue to work out of temporary <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">space</ENAMEX>, according to
analysis by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX>-based real estate brokerage <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TenantWise</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inc.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crain</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Business</ENAMEX>. That's <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">8%</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">137,000</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> who lost their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> or access to them when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Twin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Towers</ENAMEX> collapsed.
Legal Aid's 450 displaced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffers</ENAMEX> have spent the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past 12 months</TIMEX> spread among previously unused spaces-some unused
for good reason-in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">nonprofit</ENAMEX>'s other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX>. It could be
another year and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a half</TIMEX> before they return to their old desks.
They have contended with difficult working conditions as demand
for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid</ENAMEX>'s services is on the rise because of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 11</TIMEX> and the
deteriorating economy. The civil <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">division</ENAMEX> is spread among a few
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">boroughs</ENAMEX>. Their papers and documents, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">some 20,000</NUMEX> boxes worth, are
stuck in a storage <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Linden</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.J.</ENAMEX>
"I am counting <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the days</TIMEX> till we can have all the parts back in
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> place," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Banks</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid</ENAMEX>'s associate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX>.
In the memories of the exiled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>, the old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> has
achieved mythical proportions. They say the wood paneling and rugs
had the ability to cool emotions and lift spirits.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Montague Street</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brooklyn Heights</ENAMEX>,
where <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">65</NUMEX> displaced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> have cobbled together space amid the
faded and scratched walls, looks more like a bargain <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">basement</ENAMEX>.
Jammed into small <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> is still trying to piece
together a sense of place.
Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Baum</ENAMEX> replaced the wind-up chattering teeth she lost, and she
has established a new emergency drawer of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Motrin</ENAMEX>, pantyhose and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tampons</ENAMEX>. But it took <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> to collect all of the squishy, bendable
toys she used to relieve stress.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elisabeth Benjamin</ENAMEX> was able to salvage some things from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">90</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church St. But</ENAMEX> fears of what wafted into her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> are causing her
to throw out almost all of them. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rolodex</ENAMEX> she crossed barricades
to retrieve in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the days</TIMEX> after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 11</TIMEX> is headed for the trash.
"I keep saying, 'That's from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">90</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church</ENAMEX>-wash your hands,' " says
Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin</ENAMEX>, the supervising <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> of the health law
practice.


The wanderer
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Davol</ENAMEX> is a nomad. When he moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Montague Street</ENAMEX>, the
staff <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> shared an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleague</ENAMEX>. But confidential
client meetings or phone calls continually forced one of them to
leave the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> up, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davol</ENAMEX> agreed to wander, inhabiting the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> of vacationing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffers</ENAMEX>.
He and his <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> boxes have moved in and out of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past month</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a half</TIMEX> alone. Part <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">caretaker</ENAMEX>, part squatter, Mr.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Davol</ENAMEX> has developed a green thumb with office <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> and has become
accustomed to working in front of pictures of other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s loved
ones. He has also become a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">connoisseur</ENAMEX> of grade-school art.
"Some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> have lots of finger paintings," says Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davol</ENAMEX>,
studying a work of diagonal and vertical red smears on brown
construction <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>. "I've seen better."





