



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center</ENAMEX> could help you defend yourself in court
By <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russell Lissau Daily Herald</ENAMEX> Staff <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Writer</ENAMEX> Posted on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 27</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>
Representing yourself in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> can be a tricky endeavor. There
are confusing legal terms to learn, strict procedures to follow and
volumes of case law that often need to be understood to prepare a
case.
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Lake County</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> and a private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> that assists indigent
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">litigants</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX> want to make the practice easier by creating
a self-help <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who choose to represent themselves in
legal matters.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX>, which will be housed in the law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> at the main
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courthouse</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Waukegan</ENAMEX>, could open <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later this summer</TIMEX>.
"I think it's going to be extremely helpful," <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Court</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Administrator Bob Zastany</ENAMEX> said. "There is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> out there
that will take advantage of this resource."
The self-help <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> will be the only one of its kind in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">county</ENAMEX>. Only a few operate nationwide, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> said.
The project is the work of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lake County</ENAMEX> circuit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> officials
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prairie State Legal Services</ENAMEX>, a statewide <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> with an office
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Waukegan</ENAMEX> that provides information and legal assistance to poor
and elderly <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> has received a
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25,000</NUMEX> grant from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Illinois Equal Justice Foundation</ENAMEX>, a
nonprofit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> that funds programs designed to increase access to
legal information and assistance, to help pay for the effort.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prairie State</ENAMEX> will share the money with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">county</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">county</ENAMEX>'s law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> is on the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> floor of the
governmental <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N. County St.</ENAMEX> The new self-help center
will be designed to help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">litigants</ENAMEX> find the information they need
to properly represent themselves in court, an undertaking that can
be complicated and confusing.
"Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> can do OK on their own, and some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> can do OK
with some help," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Rothnagel</ENAMEX>, the managing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prairie State Legal Services</ENAMEX>. "But other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> can't do it. It's
not always easy."
Self-representation is a right affirmed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Supreme</ENAMEX>
Court. The practice is far more common in civil matters than in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminal</ENAMEX> cases. In fact, self-represented <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">litigants</ENAMEX> - formally
called "pro se" in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Latin</ENAMEX>, or "for oneself" - in criminal defenses
are so rare that statistics about the practice generally are not
kept, legal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> say.
Among the civil cases most likely to feature pro se litigants
are divorce, personal injury and eviction disputes.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> represent themselves in court for a variety of reasons,
with one of the biggest being financial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX>. According to a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX> survey by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Bar Association</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who make less
than <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50,000</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> are more likely to represent themselves than
wealthier <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">litigants</ENAMEX>. However, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 20 percent</NUMEX> of self-represented
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">litigants</ENAMEX> say they can afford an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> but do not want <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, the
survey said.
Many how-to books are available on the subject of
self-representation, and the Internet is loaded with resources
about pro-se litigation.
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Lake County</ENAMEX>'s self-help <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> will help pro se <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">litigants</ENAMEX> locate
those resources and apply them to their cases, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">proponents</ENAMEX> said.
The space, which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zastany</ENAMEX> hopes to open by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 1</TIMEX>, will feature
computers that will give <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patrons</ENAMEX> access to case histories, legal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">glossaries</ENAMEX> and other information through the Internet and CD-ROMs.
It also will have paper documents that often are used in court
proceedings, as well as a special telephone line that will help
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who speak languages other than <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> get the information
they need.
A <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">county</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX> will be on hand to assist <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">litigants</ENAMEX> with their
research as well.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zastany</ENAMEX> said the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> will demystify the judicial process for
many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.
"We're bringing these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX> directly to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who need
it," he said



