



Disaster <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">center</ENAMEX> to open <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>

By <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerard MacCrossan</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kerrville Daily Times</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Emergency Management Agency</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> will be in
Kerrville <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> to open a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Disaster Relief Center</ENAMEX> to help local
residents and business <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> impacted by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s floods.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FEMA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">information officer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Lindsay</ENAMEX> announced <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> that
the relief <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">center</ENAMEX> will be open <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">from 9 a.m. to 6 p.m.</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven days</TIMEX> a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>, until further notice at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trinity Baptist Church</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FEMA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX> will be on hand to meet with flood <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> to
answer questions and provide recovery information and written
materials about various assistance programs. Among the disaster
programs available are temporary housing assistance, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> and
family grants, low interest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Small Business Administration</ENAMEX> loans,
disaster un-employment assistance and crisis counseling.
"This is a great opportunity for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kerrville</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kerr</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">County</ENAMEX> to sit down with the different <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> and get their
recovery questions answered," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mindy Wendele</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX> of Kerrville
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokeswoman</ENAMEX>. "Although the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Disaster Recovery Center</ENAMEX> will open
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, it is extremely important for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> to
call the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FEMA</ENAMEX> disaster number to begin the application
process."


The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FEMA</ENAMEX> disaster number is (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">800</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">621-3362</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FEMA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspectors</ENAMEX> were in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kerrville</ENAMEX> again <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, inspecting
some damaged <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX>. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lindsay</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FEMA</ENAMEX> has already received
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">44,000</NUMEX> inspection requests in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>.
The number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> seeking relief from the floods across
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Texas</ENAMEX> increased by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 1,000</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, bringing the
total to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5,855</NUMEX>, he said. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FEMA</ENAMEX> has already distributed <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.8 million</NUMEX>
in relief in the form of emergency <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">housing</ENAMEX>.
"The registration process is going rapidly," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lindsay</ENAMEX> said,
adding that most registrations took <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">between 5 and 7 minutes</TIMEX>.
Aid also is available from the local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapter</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Red Cross</ENAMEX>,
but flooding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> must interview with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Red Cross</ENAMEX> separately
to receive aid from them, too.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daletta Andreas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill Country</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapter</ENAMEX> executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>, said
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapter</ENAMEX> has received calls from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who thought registering
with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FEMA</ENAMEX> or for cleanup services from local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> automatically
registered them for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Red Cross</ENAMEX> services. That's incorrect, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andreas</ENAMEX>
said.
"They need to come in and go through our interview process," she
said.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Red Cross</ENAMEX> service center, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">333</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Earl Garrett St.</ENAMEX>, is open from
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 a.m. to 6 p.m.</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX>, and will be open <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this weekend</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andreas</ENAMEX>
said.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> seeking assistance must provide identification proving
they reside in the area.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Bar of Texas</ENAMEX> are offering free legal advice
for flood <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Victims</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">counties</ENAMEX> declared a federal
disaster can call (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">800</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">504-7030</ENAMEX> for assistance with basic legal
questions.
The free legal assistance hotline, operated in coordination with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Rural Legal Aid</ENAMEX> and volunteer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> from across the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>,
will be available <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">from 8 a.m. to 8 p.m.</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>,
and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 a.m. to 6 p.m.</TIMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>.
"Once flood <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>' immediate needs are met, they may encounter
legal questions regarding lost documents, landlord-tenant disputes,
or probate matters," said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Bar</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guy Harrison</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Longview</ENAMEX>. "We want to do whatever we can to help <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Texans</ENAMEX> through
this trying time."
Volunteer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> will offer basic advice, answer legal
questions and provide appropriate referral information in both
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Spanish</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Callers</ENAMEX> requiring more detailed advice or
continuing legal representation may be referred to legal aid
programs, pro bono <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> or private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX>.




