



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 8, 2002</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX>'s Domestic <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Violence Ruling</ENAMEX> Creates an Outcry in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kentucky</ENAMEX>

By <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">FRANCIS X. CLINES</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EXINGTON</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ky.</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 4</TIMEX> - The violent arena of domestic abuse
litigation has grown a bit more volatile here, now that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> has
decided to hold <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in contempt of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> for returning to men
who had been ordered to stay away from them. "You can't have it
both ways," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Megan Lake Thornton</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fayette County</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">District Court</ENAMEX> in recently fining <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> women <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100 and $200</NUMEX>
respectively for obtaining protective orders forbidding their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partners</ENAMEX> from contacting them, then relenting and contacting the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>.
Ruling that the order was mutually binding, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thornton</ENAMEX> also
cited the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> for contempt.
"It drives me nuts when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> just decide to do whatever they
want," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thornton</ENAMEX>, who is experienced in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s thick
domestic abuse docket, which produces <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">close to 30,000</NUMEX> emergency
protective orders <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kentucky</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> say there is a virtual
epidemic of abusive relationships in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thornton</ENAMEX>'s ruling has alarmed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> for battered
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, who plan to appeal it. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> say the finding goes
beyond existing law and is unrealistic because some renewed
contacts often prove unavoidable in domestic abuse cases, which
involve economic and family dependency and other complications of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> living.
The state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> on domestic violence has pointedly agreed,
warning that the ruling could cause abused <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> to hesitate in
bringing their plight before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> for fear of being chastised
for their trouble.
"The reality is it's easy to say they should never have
contact," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sherry Currens</ENAMEX>, executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kentucky</ENAMEX>
Domestic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Violence Association</ENAMEX>, an advocacy and legal protection
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX>. "But we're talking about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in long-term relationships.
They may have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in common. It's pretty hard to say, `<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Never</ENAMEX>
speak again.' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> have financial difficulties. They may love the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX>. It's not an easy thing."
But <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thornton</ENAMEX> declared in court, "When these orders are
entered, you don't just do whatever you damn well please and ignore
them."
The ruling stunned <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cindra Walker</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> for the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>,
who is with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central Kentucky Legal Services</ENAMEX>, which represents many
of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of indigent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> caught in abusive
relationships.
"For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">over five years</TIMEX>, I've been in court practically every day
on these abuse cases," Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walker</ENAMEX> said, "and I've never before had
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> threatened with contempt."
"The domestic violence law is a tool for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> to use to be
safe," not a device to punish them, she said.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in the ruling said she eventually moved back
with her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> while the other had occasional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contacts</ENAMEX>, Ms.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walker</ENAMEX> said.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thornton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> said judicial rules barred her from
commenting on the cases. But her <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> rulings made clear that she
expected the original orders against all contact to apply equally
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> suspected of abuse and the abused.
"They are orders of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>," the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> declared, according to
court transcripts obtained by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Lexington Herald</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Leader</ENAMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">People</ENAMEX>
are ordered to follow them, and I don't care which side you're
on."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carol Jordan</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Governor</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Child</ENAMEX>
Abuse and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Domestic Violence</ENAMEX>, said she disagreed with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thornton</ENAMEX>'s ruling even as she sympathized with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX>
who must try to oversee violent domestic situations.
"These are tough cases for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX>," Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX> said. "They are
dealing with complex human emotions. They are dealing with
danger."
But if the ruling stands, Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX> warned, some abused women
will conclude that they will not be treated fairly if they seek
refuge in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX>. This sort of ruling "absolutely increases
abused <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s level of risk" by seemingly encouraging their
abusers, Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX> said.
In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kentucky</ENAMEX>, as in much of the rest of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>, abuse victims
have increasingly turned to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> as protective orders have
become more accepted, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Billie Lee Dunford- Jackson</ENAMEX>, assistant
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of family violence law and policy for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Council</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Juvenile</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Family Court</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judges</ENAMEX>. Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> "have been making
clear to the batterers that the issue is between the state courts
and them," Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dunford- Jackson</ENAMEX> said, rather than a domestic issue
between <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>.
A "sizable minority" of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> may still regard the conflicting
parties equally in their rulings, she said, but newer state laws
have increasingly put the focus on violent abuse as the main
problem requiring state intervention.
Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walker</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Harrison</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin Hull</ENAMEX>,
declined to be interviewed. Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walker</ENAMEX>, one of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> legal service
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> handling <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of abuse cases in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">counties</ENAMEX>, said, "Our
big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> now is the chilling effect this will have."
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Two years ago</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kentucky Legislature</ENAMEX> considered a proposal to
apply the protective orders equally to the accused and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX>,
Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX> said, but the notion of mutual protection, equating the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>, is not part of state law.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thornton</ENAMEX>'s ruling, she contended, will "establish a
barrier that stops abused <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> from seeking protection of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX>."




