



The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clarion Ledger</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 18, 2002</TIMEX>

Domestic violence aid offered
Program pays for needed legal help in abusive situations

By <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sherri Williams</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clarion-Ledger Staff Writer</ENAMEX>
Domestic violence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> needing legal help can get it through
a program launched by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central Southwest Mississippi Legal Services</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corp.</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Domestic Violence Legal Assistance Program</ENAMEX> fills the gap of
legal resources for domestic violence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">survivors</ENAMEX> who can't afford an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX>.
Domestic violence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">survivors</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jackson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vicksburg, Hattiesburg</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oxford</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pascagoula</ENAMEX> can all get help. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julia Crockett</ENAMEX>, deputy
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central Southwest Mississippi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services Corp.</ENAMEX>,
said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">program</ENAMEX> expects to help <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly 1,000</NUMEX> domestic violence
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crockett</ENAMEX> said legal help gives domestic abuse <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">survivors</ENAMEX> a way to
rebuild their lives.
"They have been made to feel by the abuser that no one is going
to help them do anything, so when they come to us they are
desperate," she said. "Those who need legal help and don't get it
feel totally lost. Because then they feel like they are forced to
stay in that situation."
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crockett</ENAMEX> said the program, funded by a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$300,000</NUMEX> grant from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX>, has no economic restrictions on who can
get help. Legal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX> typically helps the poor.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gladys Bunzy</ENAMEX>, who said she was in an abusive relationship with a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boyfriend</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight years</TIMEX>, said such a program is long overdue and
could be a lifeline for those escaping violent relationships.
"When I finally made up my mind to leave, I had a restraining
order put against him and that was <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50</NUMEX> but that was <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50 well</NUMEX> spent
to me," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bunzy</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">40</TIMEX>. "For <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who can't afford it, this will
be a godsend ... If a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> knows she is going to get some help
that will be a burden off her mind, if the law will help her keep
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> away from her."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gwen Bouie-Haynes</ENAMEX>, project <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Domestic Violence</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Services Center for Catholic Charities Inc.</ENAMEX>, said often domestic
violence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">survivors</ENAMEX> do not have the money to seek legal
representation.
"Legal assistance is a major issue for women fleeing a domestic
violence situation," she said. "Often times <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> are in need of
immediate legal assistance services for the protection of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>. To get a protective order you need to be
represented by an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX>."
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crockett</ENAMEX> said the pilot program was launched in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Haven House Family Shelter Inc.</ENAMEX>, a domestic violence shelter for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vicksburg</ENAMEX>. The program has helped <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> in
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">90</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> cases, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">150</NUMEX> legal counseling sessions have been held
there.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lark Johnson</ENAMEX>, executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> at the shelter, said some of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> would never have received legal help had it not been for
the program.
"In the past, they would have had to report their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouse</ENAMEX>'s
income and that would be included in determining whether they were
eligible to get legal help, whether they had access to that money
or not," she said. "They can get help now with no barriers for
custody cases, protective orders and other things."
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson</ENAMEX> said through the program her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shelter</ENAMEX>, which served <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">187</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>, has been able to form better
relationships with those who work with domestic violence
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>.
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judges</ENAMEX> and law enforcement <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> are trained to help them
understand what their options are to stabilize a violent home,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson</ENAMEX> said. "They are also trained to detect evidence of domestic
violence in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>. So they won't have to solely rely on the
testimony of the victim."
Educating <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> and law enforcement <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> is a program
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">priority</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crockett</ENAMEX> said, because in that emotional and painful
situation "sensitivity and education is absent" among some who deal
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>.
For details about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Domestic Violence Legal Assistance</ENAMEX>
Program, call <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">601-948-6752</ENAMEX>.





