



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Daily</ENAMEX> Law Bulletin

<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald Hilliker</ENAMEX> Steps to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Fore</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Organization</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julia Brunts</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 5, 2002</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald B. Hilliker</ENAMEX> has his work cut out for him -- <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">as much as $1</NUMEX>
million worth. Hilliker, a long-time <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> for the
Legal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Assistance Foundation of Metropolitan Chicago</ENAMEX>, has taken over
as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hilliker</ENAMEX>'s term is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one year</TIMEX>, and
it happens to be <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> in which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundation</ENAMEX> anticipates large
reductions in funding from several of its money <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sheldon Roodman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAF</ENAMEX> executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1976</TIMEX>, said the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">foundation</ENAMEX> has an <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> budget of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $12 million</NUMEX>. Of that,
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $6.4 million</NUMEX> has in the past come from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corp.</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entity</ENAMEX> that disburses federal money for legal aid.
In the wake of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> census, which showed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35,000</NUMEX> fewer poor
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, as well as a change in the distribution
formula, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAF</ENAMEX> expects to get <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$350,000</NUMEX> less from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> starting next
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roodman</ENAMEX> said.
In addition, he said several <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundations</ENAMEX> that give money to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAF</ENAMEX> have seen their endowments shrink with the declining stock
market, and the money available from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Interest</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lawyers Trust</ENAMEX>
Accounts program also has dwindled as interest rates have
approached <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX>.
At the same time, requests for services from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundation</ENAMEX>,
which has the mission of providing free legal aid to poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in
order to make "equal access to justice" a reality, have increased
as the economy has softened.
"We're caught in a vise here with more demand and less
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resources</ENAMEX>," he said. "There is a real challenge for our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX> to help us raise additional funds to help offset these
losses and to help prevent reductions in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> and services to our
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>." He said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hilliker</ENAMEX> will be a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> to lead the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organization</ENAMEX> through such an effort. An <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAF</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> since the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid-'80s</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hilliker</ENAMEX> has been involved with legal aid in some way for
his entire career. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hilliker</ENAMEX> earned his law degree from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northwestern</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University School of Law</ENAMEX> and was admitted to practice in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1969</TIMEX>. His
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> job was in legal services as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reginald Heber Smith</ENAMEX>
fellow.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hilliker</ENAMEX> is now a complex litigation <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDermott, Will</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">& Emery</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pro Bono Committee</ENAMEX>. He said
he's never lost interest in having <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> do what they can to help
those in need.
"The central issue is that we are a society of laws, and for
that to truly work, there must be equal access to the justice
system for everyone, whether they have the ability to pay or not,"
he said.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roodman</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hilliker</ENAMEX> is in an excellent position to help the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">foundation</ENAMEX> attract more private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recruit lawyers</ENAMEX> in
private practice to volunteer their services. "I think Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hilliker</ENAMEX>
brings extraordinary leadership to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>," he said.
"Because of his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many years</TIMEX> of service on our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX>, he knows its
strengths and the importance of its work. He will be good at
getting the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> to take a more active role in
fund-raising."




