



Area <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid Entities Merge</ENAMEX>

By Analisa Nazareno
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 6, 2002</TIMEX>
The letterhead on correspondence still bears the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bexar County</ENAMEX>
Legal Aid name, even though the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> is no longer.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Rural Legal Aid</ENAMEX> - known for its fearless and sometimes
controversial advocacy of the poorest of the poor - <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> took
over <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> serving the legal needs of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">indigent</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Southwest Texas</ENAMEX>, including the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bexar County</ENAMEX>.
The new <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">68</NUMEX>-county legal aid <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> has yet to be named and
stretches from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El Paso</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corpus Christi, Harlingen</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> for the super-sized law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> has big plans.
"I'm more interested in looking at what we as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> can do
to address the serious problems of poverty than the number of cases
we close," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Hall</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TRLA</ENAMEX> executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>.
In the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rio Grande Valley</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hall</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> set up separate
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> to assist small-business <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> with
low-interest loans and legal representation. They also operate a
legal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX> that assists migrant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kentucky</ENAMEX>.
Now, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hall</ENAMEX> said, he wants to make services to the poor more
efficient by working with law <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> who will handle less
complicated legal matters, allowing licensed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> to take more
"high impact" cases to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>.
"What we need to do is handle cases as efficiently as we can,
leveraging the amount of time of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> that goes in there and
maximizing the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that they can help at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hall</ENAMEX> said.
His plan is to place the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">110</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> working
on specialized legal issues.
He wants to expand the law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clinic</ENAMEX> it already has with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Mary</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University Law School</ENAMEX> to involve <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Law School</ENAMEX>.
The law <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Mary's</ENAMEX> interview potential <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>,
assist them with filling out legal documents and answer the
telephones for the legal hotline, freeing up <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TRLA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> to handle
the complicated cases, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hall</ENAMEX> said.
By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of September</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hall</ENAMEX> said all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> working
with the poor in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">68county</NUMEX> area will be placed on the same
computer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> so they can pass cases to the best available
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> on the former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid of Central</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bexar County</ENAMEX> Legal Aid resisted the merger, saying that
the mergers were done illegally and without the input of board
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>. They also argued that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hall</ENAMEX>'s litigious style hampered
their ability to garner funds from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TRLA</ENAMEX> generated controversy in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, when its attorneys
challenged the rights of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">800</NUMEX> military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX> to vote in Val
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Verde County</ENAMEX> elections by absentee ballot after a former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ku Klux</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Klan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> won a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">county</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commissioner</ENAMEX> post.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brendan Gill</ENAMEX>, the former executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bexar County</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX>, said he has since come to see the merger as a positive move
for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South Texas</ENAMEX>.
"I always knew there were good points to merging, just as I knew
that there were bad points," <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gill</ENAMEX> said. "Now I'm hoping to
accentuate the good points and hope that will minimize the bad
points."
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gill</ENAMEX> now heads the newly merged <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>'s elder law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX>.
Some changes, including eliminating pay differences between
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> as well as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> support <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> across the state and
technology training, could be <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> in the making, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hall</ENAMEX> said.
Another issue is whether to change the name of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Rural Legal</ENAMEX>
Aid so that it reflects the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">territory</ENAMEX>'s diverse landscape.
"Overall, I think the change will be good," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Loza</ENAMEX>, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Antonio</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> and the local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coordinator</ENAMEX> for the bargaining
unit of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Organization of Legal Services Workers</ENAMEX>. "I
think that the poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> in the true rural areas will benefit
from more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> with a wide range of expertise. Someone in
Natalia that may not otherwise have access to an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> or advice will be able to have that."
Since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hall</ENAMEX> has been meeting with nonprofit leaders
and others who expressed concern that a merger would mean less
representation for the poor in their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX>.
"I know change can be difficult, but I think we need to give it
a chance," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joyce Coleman</ENAMEX>, who as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Family Violence</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prevention Services</ENAMEX> worked with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bexar County Legal Aid</ENAMEX> to provide
legal assistance to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Battered Women's Shelter</ENAMEX>.
"I think it may actually be a good thing for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coleman</ENAMEX>
said.
"Larger is not always better, but sometimes it can be."




