



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eviction</ENAMEX> law is fine with local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tenant</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 20, 2002</TIMEX>

By <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Roelofs</ENAMEX>
As a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tenant</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grand Rapids</ENAMEX> public housing
complex, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aubrey Robertson</ENAMEX> puts security at the top of his home
priority list.
Because of that, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robertson</ENAMEX> is all for a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX>-tolerance drug law
in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Creston Plaza</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartments</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grand Rapids</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northeast</ENAMEX>
Side.
That includes cases in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> may be evicted for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> use of a single family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX>, even off the premises.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robertson</ENAMEX> sees it as a tool to keep his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> as clean and safe
as possible.
"If there's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> (using <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>), that is a start," said
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robertson</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">52</TIMEX>, a native of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jamaica</ENAMEX>.
He has lived <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past four years</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Creston Plaza</ENAMEX> with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>,
Tammy, and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Precious</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent months</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robertson</ENAMEX>
was pleased to see casual <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> use at the complex diminish with the
installation of security cameras.
"If there is a start, then there will be some other problem. I
totally agree (if there is a drug link), get them out."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> say the law -- argued <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Supreme</ENAMEX>
Court -- tramples on individual rights and harms the very people
public housing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> are supposed to help.
"It's basically one strike and you're out, and I think they went
beyond what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> intended," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Chielens</ENAMEX>, executive
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Western Michigan Legal Services</ENAMEX>.
"Someone who had no knowledge or involvement in a criminal act
is being punished. That's kind of a basic due process notion that
we have had in our legal tradition for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time</TIMEX>."
The case was brought by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oakland</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX>, senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>,
including <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">63-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">great-grandmother</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pearlie Rucker</ENAMEX>. They
received eviction notices because of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> use of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">caregivers</ENAMEX>.
Rucker was ordered out because her mentally <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">disabled daughter</ENAMEX>
was caught with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> blocks from the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> she shared
with her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> and other family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>, court records show.
An appeals court blocked enforcement of the law.
At issue is whether housing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX> are being more aggressive
than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> intended. The law was passed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX> and endorsed by
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> and by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> administration
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>.
The law was written at a time when public housing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complexes</ENAMEX> were
under assault by drug-dealing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gangs</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> were pressured
to take action.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Families</ENAMEX> can be removed for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> use by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX>, whether the
drug activity is in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> or somewhere else.
enforcement program, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tenants</ENAMEX> may not avoid eviction simply by
claiming ignorance of the crime or an inability to stop it.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carlos Sanchez</ENAMEX>, executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grand Rapids</ENAMEX> Housing
Commission, believes the law can be effective if it's applied with
discretion.
The commission administers <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 3,500</NUMEX> public housing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grand Rapids</ENAMEX> area, including <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Creston Plaza</ENAMEX>.
"I think if it's done with caution, it's a tool that we
desperately needed in our developments," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sanchez</ENAMEX> said.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sanchez</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grand Rapids</ENAMEX> doesn't have the large-scale drug
problems larger <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> do -- and he wants to keep it that way.
"We've done the best we can to keep it from being so
drug-infested it becomes a war zone. Once the development is taken
over, it's very difficult to take them back."
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sanchez</ENAMEX> said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">commission</ENAMEX> relies on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> reports in deciding
evictions, which he estimated at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one or two a year</TIMEX>.
Among those cases, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leslie Curry</ENAMEX>, litigation
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Western Michigan Legal Services</ENAMEX>, was that of a mother
evicted from public housing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a year ago</TIMEX> with several young
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>.
She was removed because her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> was arrested selling
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> outside the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Curry</ENAMEX> said. That left her with the
hardship of seeking a place she could afford for herself and her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, without the certainty she afford the rent.
"She didn't know about it," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Curry</ENAMEX> said of the drug deal.
"In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grand Rapids</ENAMEX>, subsidized housing is critical to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s
ability to maintain basic security in their lives."




