



<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Twenty-five</NUMEX> low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> saved from homelessness
Legal services attorneys negotiate agreement with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City of East</ENAMEX>
Wenatchee
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">EAST WENATCHEE</ENAMEX> - After <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than a year</TIMEX> of effort, attorneys
with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northwest Justice Project</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this week</TIMEX> told <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>
in a mobile home <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> here that they can keep their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> and no
longer need to fear eviction.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">East Wenatchee City Council</ENAMEX> has entered into an Interlocal
Agreement with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wenatchee Housing Authority</ENAMEX> authorizing the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Authority</ENAMEX> to purchase and maintain the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Mobile Park Plaza</ENAMEX> mobile
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home park</ENAMEX>. Located <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">just</NUMEX> north of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Wenatchee Valley Mall</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">park</ENAMEX> had been threatened with closure for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than a year</TIMEX>.
"We cannot say enough about how relieved we are that this is
over," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Manuel Luna</ENAMEX>, one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Mobile Park Plaza</ENAMEX>.
"We were afraid that no solution would be found, and that our
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> would have no place to go. We are very grateful for the
help of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX>. Without them, we would not have saved our
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">homes</ENAMEX>. We are also thankful for the help of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Housing Authority</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Lacy</ENAMEX>."
Formerly owned by local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">businessman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Jennings</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mobile Park</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Plaza</ENAMEX> had been home to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">45</NUMEX> low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>, many of them Latino
farm <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 2000</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennings</ENAMEX> gave the park residents
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">notice</ENAMEX> of his intent to close the park effective <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 30, 2001</TIMEX>.
While some park <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> decided to move, others, including <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>, organized an informal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">association</ENAMEX> to relocate or save
their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX>. Unable to afford private legal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>
asked for help from legal services <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northwest</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Project</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia Legal Services</ENAMEX>.
In the succeeding <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX>, these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> worked with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Greater Wenatchee Housing Authority</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">state Office of Community Development</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chelan County</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">City</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Wenatchee</ENAMEX>, state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">legislators</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennings</ENAMEX> and others to secure
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">funding</ENAMEX> and find a solution.
"There seemed to be a never-ending set of obstacles," said
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patrick Pleas</ENAMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northwest Justice Project</ENAMEX>. "Mr.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennings</ENAMEX> had financial considerations, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX> had growth and
economic development considerations, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State and Housing</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Authority</ENAMEX> had their own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thankfully</ENAMEX>, hard work and good
will from all parties allowed us to find a solution that works for
everyone."
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northwest Justice Project</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia Legal Services</ENAMEX> are
non-profit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> that provide civil legal assistance to
low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> throughout <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s Access to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Network</ENAMEX>, these
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organizations</ENAMEX> work with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteer attorneys</ENAMEX> to ensure
that justice is available to those who face critical legal problems
and can't afford private legal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX>.
Services such as those provided to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mobile Park</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Plaza</ENAMEX> now hang in the balance, in light of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Governor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Locke</ENAMEX>'s
recent cutting of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2.4 million</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> state funding for civil
legal services - <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly half</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yearly</TIMEX> contribution to
legal services <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">programs</ENAMEX> statewide.



