



Federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> asserts claim to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday, September 22, 2002</TIMEX>
By <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herb Frazier</ENAMEX>
A congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> that funds legal services for low-income
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> is battling <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charleston</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> over control of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>
that once housed legal assistance programs in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charleston</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgetown</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Conway</ENAMEX>.
At stake is prime real estate in the coastal <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>, including a
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charleston</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> in the heart of upscale commercial development
on upper <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">King Street</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>-based <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services Corp.</ENAMEX> wants the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>
transferred to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">S.C.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Centers for Equal Justice</ENAMEX>, said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">spokesman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric Kleiman</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> was once the funding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Neighborhood Legal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Assistance Program Corp.</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charleston</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> funding
went to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greenville</ENAMEX>-based equal justice <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX>.
In an <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 21</TIMEX> letter to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NLAP</ENAMEX> board <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerald A. Kaynard</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John N. Erlenborn</ENAMEX> said: "If <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NLAP</ENAMEX> fails to effectuate
these transfers by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 31</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> will take all necessary steps to
protect its interest in these properties."
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kaynard</ENAMEX> did not return repeated phone calls from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Post</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Courier</ENAMEX>.
As part of its funding agreement, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">LSC</ENAMEX> requires property
purchased with government funds be returned to the nonprofit
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">corporation</ENAMEX> if a local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> loses its grant, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kleiman</ENAMEX> said. In
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">4th Circuit Court of Appeals</ENAMEX> upheld that requirement in
a lawsuit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> filed in a property dispute with a legal services
program in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Stone Gap</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Va.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kleiman</ENAMEX> said, "We will continue to work with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NLAP</ENAMEX> to work out an
orderly transfer of the property. We hope this can be resolved
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">amicably</ENAMEX>." <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NLAP</ENAMEX> lost its federal grant with a nationwide
consolidation of legal aid programs. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX>, the federal agency
awarded a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4.4 million</NUMEX> grant to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Centers for Equal Justice</ENAMEX>,
which has a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charleston</ENAMEX> area <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> and sites in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Carolina</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>.
With a budget of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$329 million</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> provides civil legal
assistance to low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in every <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">county</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, Kleiman
said. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NLAP</ENAMEX> was created in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1968</TIMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A decade later</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> used a
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50,000</NUMEX> LSC grant to buy a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">438 King St.</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charleston</ENAMEX>
and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$33,000</NUMEX> to buy a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">201 King St.</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgetown</ENAMEX>,
according to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Erlenborn</ENAMEX>'s letter to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kaynard</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NLAP</ENAMEX> used
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$63,000</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> funds to buy property at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">607</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Main St.</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Conway</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">letter</ENAMEX> said.
On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 14, 2001</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NLAP</ENAMEX> transferred title of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">King Street</ENAMEX>
building in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charleston</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Charleston County Bar Association</ENAMEX>,
according to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">county</ENAMEX> property records.
The local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX> paid <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5</NUMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>, which sits between a
redeveloped office <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> and an antique <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX>. The local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX> said
it would maintain the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> for "legal services to indigent
residents of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charleston County</ENAMEX> and coastal <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Carolina</ENAMEX>," the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">records</ENAMEX> said. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">King Street</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> appears to be vacant.
Notices at the entrance direct <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> to the equal justice center
on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">West Montague Avenue</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Charleston</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">E. Douglas Pratt-Thomas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX>, was not
available for comment.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charleston County</ENAMEX> has not appraised the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">King Street</ENAMEX> property
because it is tax-exempt. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randall Goldman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managing partner</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patrick Properties</ENAMEX>, which owns <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">440 to 456</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">King St.</ENAMEX>,
said he estimates <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">438</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King St.</ENAMEX> would sell for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">between $700,000</NUMEX> and
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$900,000</NUMEX>. "That <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>, which was purchased solely with federal
legal aid dollars, should be used to provide legal services for
poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Carolina</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kleiman</ENAMEX> said.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> wants the title to go to the equal justice <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charleston</ENAMEX> or "we want <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">100 percent</NUMEX> of the proceeds from the sale of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> to stay in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charleston</ENAMEX>. We are not contemplating taking
that money out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Carolina</ENAMEX>," he said. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kleiman</ENAMEX> said if the
neighborhood legal program in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charleston</ENAMEX> "had honored their
obligation, this would not be an issue."



