



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">California Bar Journal</ENAMEX>

Few who need legal help get it

<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December, 2002</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> lags far behind comparable <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> in funding legal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">services</ENAMEX> for the poor, a situation so dire that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 28 percent</NUMEX> of
the civil legal needs of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s poor and lowerincome <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX>
are being addressed.
That figures translates into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> without the
ability to access the justice system, according to a new study by
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">California Commission on Access</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX>, which also found
that despite increased spending, the gap between need and services
remains substantial.
"As a practical matter, in most cases there can be no access to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice</ENAMEX> without access to legal assistance," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Londen</ENAMEX>, past
commission chair and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morrison & Foerster</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francisco</ENAMEX>.
"Whether we like it or not, sometimes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">landlords</ENAMEX> illegally evict
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tenants</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> with disabilities are denied proper care,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veterans</ENAMEX> don't get services guaranteed to them, and elderly people
need legal assistance to escape the abuse of a caregiver."
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> has the highest number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in poverty in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nation</ENAMEX> - <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6.4 million</NUMEX>, including <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly one</NUMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. Half
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s increase in poverty in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1990s</TIMEX>, when the number of
poor jumped <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">30 percent</NUMEX>, occurred in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly 25</NUMEX>
percent of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s poverty increase occurred in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">County</ENAMEX> alone.
Even those with jobs are suffering: <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">26 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> earn poverty level wages. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">commission</ENAMEX>'s report, "The
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Path to Equal Justice: A Five-Year Status Report on Access to</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>," examined how the legal needs of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s
poor have changed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last five years</TIMEX> as well as both the
shortcomings of the justice system and the improvements during that
period.
Despite increases in state funding to meet the legal needs of
the poor, low interest rates (which have reduced the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IOLTA</ENAMEX> fund),
high unemployment and the present economic downturn have threatened
any gains.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX> spend <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times more than
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> to meet the poor's legal needs, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Connecticut</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX> spend more than twice as much, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> like
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">England</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scotland</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Zealand</ENAMEX> spend anywhere
from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two to 14</NUMEX> times more proportionately than <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, despite
the fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> has the world's <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">sixth</NUMEX> largest economy.
The report says the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> would need to triple its combined
public and private investment in legal services to adequately meet
the legal needs of low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Californians</ENAMEX>.
The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> welfare reform legisla tion, in particular, brought
dramatic changes to the lives of those living in poverty, for while
fewer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> now receive welfare benefits, those who left welfare
to work are still poor. And the legal issues they face "have become
more numerous and complex," the report said.
"Parents who found only low-paying jobs without health benefits
did not improve the well-being of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Women</ENAMEX> who entered
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workforce</ENAMEX> in low-skilled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">positions</ENAMEX> with no opportunity to
acquire marketable skills lack realistic long-term options.
Obstacles to employment such as lack of child care and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">transportation</ENAMEX>, domestic violence and job discrimination raise a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX> of new legal issues."
Those issues revolve around an extensive universe of problems,
including housing, education, domestic violence, immigration,
employment, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">grandparent guardianships</ENAMEX>, bankruptcy and consumer
debt, veterans' issues, elder abuse and home equity fraud, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">report</ENAMEX> said.
To meet all those needs, there is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> legal aid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> for
every <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10,000</NUMEX> poor <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Californians</ENAMEX>. Despite this bleak picture, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">state</ENAMEX>'s civil <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice community</ENAMEX> has taken significant steps to
close the gap between need and services in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past five years</TIMEX>:
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">legislature</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> established the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Equal Access</ENAMEX>
Fund, which has provided <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10 million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annually</TIMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> for more
than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> local legal services programs.
Access to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> has been enhanced through a variety of
self-help options, including online assistance in every <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">county</ENAMEX>, a
system of family law facilitators, increased funding for
alternative dispute resolution and simplified forms and
procedures.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Judicial Council</ENAMEX> is addressing language barriers by
increasing the availability of qualified <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">interpreters</ENAMEX> and
translating forms and instructions into <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Spanish</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>-ese,
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Korean</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX>.
Legal services programs have been strengthened by offering a
wide range of services, including self-help <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clinics</ENAMEX> and hotlines
and working relationships with social services <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> to meet all
of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">client</ENAMEX>'s needs.
Still, when <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">more than 70 percent</NUMEX> of the poor's legal needs are
not being met, much remains to be done, the report points out. It
recommends adding to the access fund, increasing both the number of
pro bono <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> and financial contributions from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX>, improved
assistance for unrepresented <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">litigants</ENAMEX> and access to an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX>
for those who require <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, and development of a statewide plan to
distribute legal services more evenly throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> to
insure that the rural <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> also is served.
"I know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fe llow judges</ENAMEX> want to do justice and not inflict
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">injustice</ENAMEX>," observed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Earl Johnson</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">California Court</ENAMEX>
of Appeal, who chaired the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> that researched and wrote the
report.
"More than anyone, they know it can be nearly impossible to do
the former and avoid the latter in a one-sided contest where only
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> litigant has a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>."
"Our whole <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">society</ENAMEX> is harmed when access and fairness are
denied," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Londen</ENAMEX>. "Clearly, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> can - and must - do
better."





