



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jackson Sun</ENAMEX> (TN)
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grant</ENAMEX> to help fight domestic abuse
By <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rachel Myer</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 10, 2002</TIMEX>
A <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Tennessee</ENAMEX> nonprofit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> will use a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$300,000</NUMEX>
federal grant to hire an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish-speaking</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">paralegal</ENAMEX>
to help provide legal assistance to domestic violence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Department of Justice</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two-year</TIMEX> grant will begin <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 1</TIMEX>,
which is the start of domestic violence awareness month.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Tanner</ENAMEX> announced <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> that the grant was
awarded to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Tennessee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jackson</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organization</ENAMEX> provides legal assistance and advocacy in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">counties</ENAMEX>.
"This award will offer assistance as we look for whatever ways
possible to stop domestic violence and help the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> who are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> of abuse," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tanner</ENAMEX> said in a news
statement.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> doesn't have a staff <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> who speaks <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX>
and the need is increasing with growing <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX>, said
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>'s executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Xanthopoulos</ENAMEX>.
He estimated the money will help handle <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at least another 180</TIMEX>
cases <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> closes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 2,500</NUMEX> cases a year.
The money was timed well because the legal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> had recently
lost <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $120,000</NUMEX> in grant money due to a decrease in the poverty
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Tennessee</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Census</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Xanthopoulos</ENAMEX> said.
"The drop in poverty is a good thing, but there is still a great
need out there," he said. "So this was a very good thing."
Having legal representation at divorce and child custody
hearings is important in helping <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> leave abusive and
sometimes dangerous situations, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret Cole</ENAMEX>, executive
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wo/Men's Resource and Rape Assistance Program</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX>. Her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northwest Safeline</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partners</ENAMEX> in
the grant. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northwest Safeline</ENAMEX>, based in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dyersburg</ENAMEX>, is a family
violence intervention project that serves <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dyer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Obion</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lake</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Crockett</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">counties</ENAMEX>.
The grant also will help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> go through court proceedings
after losing a job or being evicted because of an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">abuser</ENAMEX>'s actions,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Xanthopoulos</ENAMEX> said.
"It's going to help the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>, but it's also going to help
their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>," he said.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">More than 270</NUMEX> domestic violence assaults in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Madison County</ENAMEX> were
reported <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tennessee Bureau of Investigation</ENAMEX>
statistics. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jackson</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 730</NUMEX> domestic violence assaults
were reported <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>, according to records.
"Domestic violence is certainly on the increase and we need to
do something to curve that. I see this as helping that," Madison
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">County Sheriff David Woolfork</ENAMEX> said of the grant.
Domestic violence accounted for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> murders in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> have said. And the increase in calls prompted
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jackson Police</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick Staples</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> to form a focus <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> to
determine if police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> need to make changes in their response
to domestic calls.



