



<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kalamazoo Gazette</ENAMEX>

<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Alamo Fire Victims Sue Landlord</ENAMEX>
By <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Craig McCool</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 8, 2002</TIMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Nine</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> displaced by a fire at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Alamo Hills Apartments</ENAMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> filed lawsuits <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> against the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment complex</ENAMEX>.
They allege that the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> could have done more to protect
belongings they were forced to abandon in the aftermath of the
blaze.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bernard Dempsey Jr.</ENAMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Western Michigan Legal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Services</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> that represents the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tenants</ENAMEX>, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alamo Hills</ENAMEX>
gave the displaced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> very limited opportunity to remove
belongings.
"They were given <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three days</TIMEX> to get their stuff out, and if they
couldn't get moved out in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three days</TIMEX>, their stuff was discarded,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dempsey</ENAMEX> said. "<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Alamo Hills</ENAMEX> just threw it out."
Others, he said, lost possessions to looters after the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 23</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">blaze</ENAMEX>, which left <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">78</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> temporarily homeless.
According to the lawsuit, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tenants</ENAMEX> were prohibited from
entering their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartments</ENAMEX> to retrieve possessions and were promised
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> would provide security.
A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesperson</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PM One</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that manages <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Alamo Hills</ENAMEX>,
could not be reached for comment.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Nine</NUMEX> separate suits were filed in 8th <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">District Court</ENAMEX>, which
handles civil claims of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">less than $25,000</NUMEX>.
"We're asking for the reimbursement of the value of their
property and a small amount for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stress</ENAMEX> -- <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3,000</NUMEX> on top of their
out-of-pocket expenses for their lost stuff," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dempsey</ENAMEX> said.
"They're not looking to get rich off this. A lot of this is
simply because they were treated so badly."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dempsey</ENAMEX> said most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tenants</ENAMEX> who filed suits still live at
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment complex</ENAMEX>, although many are trying to find homes
elsewhere.
"The new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartments</ENAMEX> (they were provided) were not in very good
shape. That's actually one of the claims," he said.




