



<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tulsa</ENAMEX> World
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday, April 28, 2002</TIMEX>

<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">'Law Firm to the Poor' Needs Help; Pursuing</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julie Delcour</ENAMEX>
With an onionskin-thin budget <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several years back</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Eastern Oklahoma</ENAMEX>, the area's largest "law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> to the poor,"
nearly became <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lip Service of Eastern Oklahoma</ENAMEX>.
Funding cuts closed some satellite <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> and reduced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>.
Remaining <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> could serve only a small percentage of the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">303,000</NUMEX> potential <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSEO</ENAMEX> persevered.
The budget still isn't big enough. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> aid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> is available
per <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11,000</NUMEX> eligible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> compared to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> per <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">375</NUMEX> people
in the general <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Services</ENAMEX> are expanding, however, thanks to a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 million</NUMEX> public
fund drive, that is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$59,400</NUMEX> short of its goal. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tulsa</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX>
Riggs, who heads the drive, is pushing for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX>,
especially local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>, to put it over the top.
"We're so close. We really want to reach that <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 million mark</NUMEX>,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Riggs</ENAMEX> said.
Not many causes are as worthwhile. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Riggs</ENAMEX> says legal-aid <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>
help stabilize society; they're a safety net for those in need.
"They help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> cope, help them seek redress for a grievance,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Riggs</ENAMEX> said.
"For our legal system to work <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> need representation. A
family's problems can be mitigated with some legal advice before
they spill over into <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> delinquency, housing problems,
unemployment, marital problems and deeper poverty."
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fund-raiser</ENAMEX> lost some steam following <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/11</TIMEX>, and with staff
distraction over the merger of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSEO</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid Services</ENAMEX> of
Western <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX>, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> became <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Services of Oklahoma Inc.</ENAMEX>
The fund drive started with an appeal to local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>, who
provided <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about a third</NUMEX> of the donations. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Businesses</ENAMEX> and
foundations
also have helped. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tulsa Foundation</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">businessman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kaiser</ENAMEX> are major contributors. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sarkeys Foundation</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman</ENAMEX>
provided a gift of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$161,000</NUMEX> to update computers.
Historically, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSEO</ENAMEX> letter-writing campaigns generated from
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$11,000 to $25,000</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annually</TIMEX>, recalls <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dallas Ferguson</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tulsa</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> and board <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LASO</ENAMEX>. That amount hardly
offset enormous cuts, beginning in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Services Corp.</ENAMEX>, the chief funding source for state legal-aid
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>.
Threatened with extinction, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSEO</ENAMEX> clawed its way back with the
help of state funding, grant money and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tulsa Area United Way</ENAMEX>.
Meanwhile, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> keep coming. At least <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three-quarters</NUMEX> are
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> living in poverty. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> helps more than
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">A third</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSEO</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> are the working
poor who receive no government benefits. Many are senior
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>.
Riggs regrets that retired <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tulsa</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Athens</ENAMEX>, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">champion</ENAMEX> of legal aid, did not live to see how much the money has
meant. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Athens</ENAMEX> died <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>. In his honor, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Oxley Foundation</ENAMEX>
donated <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$200,000</NUMEX> to expand a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX> hot line. That service, which
will be expanded statewide, enables <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">needy people</ENAMEX> to consult an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> about civil legal problems, including rent and contract
disputes, domestic abuse, consumer issues and custody matters.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorneys</ENAMEX> handle no criminal cases.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">R.H. Harbaugh</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundation trustee</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleague</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Athens</ENAMEX> at
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conner & Winters</ENAMEX> law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>, said his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mentor</ENAMEX> had "a special
interest in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who could not afford legal services. He was
aware of the hot line and supported its expansion."
Said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Riggs</ENAMEX>:
"We use lofty phrases such as 'with justice for all,' when we
talk about our legal system. That phrase is etched on our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>. Those are just empty words if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't
have access to that system."




