



The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fort Worth Star-Telegram</ENAMEX>

<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grant</ENAMEX> to beef up legal aid reserves
By <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Max B. Baker</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 18, 2002</TIMEX>
A state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundation</ENAMEX> is giving West Texas <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort Worth</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapter</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAACP</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $1 million</NUMEX> to help
provide civil legal services to the poor.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Equal Access</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Foundation</ENAMEX> announced that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort Worth-based</ENAMEX> nonprofit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> will receive grants from funds it
controls, including the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Interest</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lawyers' Trust</ENAMEX> Accounts, or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IOLTA</ENAMEX>, program.
West Texas <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services</ENAMEX>, which works with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">106</NUMEX>
counties including <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tarrant</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lubbock</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Midland</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Potter</ENAMEX>, will get
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $1.03 million</NUMEX>. The legal aid <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> cleared <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 8,300</NUMEX> cases
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>.
"It is going to help us out tremendously with our program," said
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathy Duncan</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">West Texas Legal Services</ENAMEX>. "If it wasn't for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">grant</ENAMEX>, we couldn't continue to do the work we are doing."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">West Texas</ENAMEX> handles such cases as divorces, protective orders in
domestic violence cases and land-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lord-tenant</ENAMEX> disputes. It has a
staff of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 100</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>, including <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> and support
staff, in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> branch <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAACP</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fort Worth Justice Project</ENAMEX> will get <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$49,000</NUMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Officials</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>'s legal assistance program were not
available to comment.
Created by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Supreme Court</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Equal Access</ENAMEX> foundation
has distributed <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $8 million</NUMEX> statewide. Besides the IOLTA
program, the money comes from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> filing fees and a state
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminal victims</ENAMEX> assistance program.
In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4.2 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> qualify for legal assistance
guideline. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tarrant County</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">204,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are eligible for legal
aid.
The grants come at a time when funding for programs providing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> for the poor are in jeopardy from declining interest
rates, cutbacks in federal funding and legal challenges.
"It needs to be a whole lot more," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betty Torres</ENAMEX>, executive
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX>-based <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundation</ENAMEX>. "Although the poverty
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> has increased, statewide and federal funding
for this vital work is in decline."
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">About $4.9 million</NUMEX> being distributed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> comes from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IOLTA</ENAMEX> fund, which is interest earned on money paid to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">retainers</ENAMEX> or to cover <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> costs. The funds are held in trust
accounts.
Because of lower interest rates, foundation <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> anticipate
having only <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3.3 million</NUMEX> in that fund <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>. To make the money
go further, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> persuaded <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> to waive service fees of
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $555,000</NUMEX>.
As part of a national overhaul of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services Corp.</ENAMEX>, the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> legal aid <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> are being folded into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>,
creating huge <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> handling cases in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">counties</ENAMEX>.
On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 31</TIMEX>, West Texas <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services</ENAMEX> will merge with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Services of North Texas</ENAMEX>, which is in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> and covers <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">counties</ENAMEX>. Renamed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northwest Texas Legal Aid</ENAMEX>, its <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX> will
be in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arlington</ENAMEX>.
Created by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1974</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services Corp.</ENAMEX> is frequently
a budgetary target. It has been requiring <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> to consolidate
legal aid <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> in an attempt to conserve money and improve
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">services</ENAMEX>.
The future of the IOLTA program is also in doubt.
On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 9</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Supreme Court</ENAMEX> will hear arguments about the
constitutionality of the IOLTA program in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Opponents</ENAMEX> say the interest earned on the trust funds belongs to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> and cannot be diverted to charitable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> without
compensating their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> or getting their permission.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">9th U.S. Circuit Court of Appeals</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX> ruled
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> fund is constitutional, while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">5th U.S.</ENAMEX>
Circuit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court of Appeals</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Orleans</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> ruled that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>'
fund was an improper taking of assets.




