



<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, June 18, 2002</TIMEX>

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Free Legal Assistance</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Close</ENAMEX> as a Keyboard
State experimenting with video <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kiosks</ENAMEX> to help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">litigants</ENAMEX> file
forms and get basic advice.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monte Morin</ENAMEX>
Times <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Staff Writer</ENAMEX>
When single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thurman Williams</ENAMEX> needed help filling out
papers in a custody suit recently, he didn't look to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> for
help. He walked to a computerized kiosk at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lamoreaux Justice</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Orange</ENAMEX> and started tapping the keys.
As part of a legal experiment, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">litigants</ENAMEX> without <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> across
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> are using computerized video <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kiosks</ENAMEX> to prepare common
court filings and seek basic legal advice.
The kiosk used by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Williams</ENAMEX> is part of a statewide effort to cope
with a flood of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">litigants</ENAMEX> who cannot afford or refuse to hire
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>. Court <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> statewide fear the number of
self-represented <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">litigants</ENAMEX> has reached crisis levels and threatens
to clog <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> calendars.
Like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Williams</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 6,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Orange County</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">litigants</ENAMEX> have
initiated court actions on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">I-</ENAMEX>CAN! <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">kiosks</ENAMEX> or accessed the programs
on the Internet, using home computers. Similar programs are
operating in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sacramento</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ventura</ENAMEX>.
A recent study of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kiosks</ENAMEX>' <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18 months</TIMEX> of operation
concluded it is too soon to tell if the system will relieve
pressure on court calendars. But the report, by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UC Irvine's School</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Ecology</ENAMEX>, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> were overwhelmingly positive about
the free legal assistance.
"It's made life a lot easier for me," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Williams</ENAMEX> said. "It's
helped keep me from going to the poorhouse."
The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">29-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Orange</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">resident</ENAMEX> was directed to a kiosk in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lamoreaux Justice Center</ENAMEX> by court <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>. After putting on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">headphones</ENAMEX> and following the directions of a videotaped <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">instructor</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Williams</ENAMEX> filled out a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">quarter-inch stack</NUMEX> of paternity and custody
documents. The exercise took <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">20 minutes</TIMEX>; it would have cost him
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $800</NUMEX> if he had relied on a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>, he said. "It was a lot
easier than I thought."
Whether they can't afford a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> or just want to save money,
more <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Californians</ENAMEX> are going to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> without a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>.
"I'm just amazed at the numbers," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Commissioner</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salvador</ENAMEX>
Sarmiento, who hears <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">between 40 and 90</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>-support cases a day in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lamoreaux Justice Center</ENAMEX>. "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Eighty</NUMEX> percent of the cases I hear
involve <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> representing themselves. These cases can take <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50%</NUMEX>
longer to process than others."
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sarmiento</ENAMEX> said the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kiosks</ENAMEX> have put many cases on the fast
track.
"Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who appear before me without <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> are real
nervous," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarmiento</ENAMEX> said. "They don't know what to expect and they
want to tell me everything. It's an opportunity for them to vent. A
lot of what they say is irrelevant. When they go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kiosks</ENAMEX>
though, I get the information that I need so I can rule."
Of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4.3 million</NUMEX> state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> who find themselves in court
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each year</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than half</NUMEX> are pro per, or self-represented
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">litigants</ENAMEX>. The phenomenon is particularly evident in family <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX>,
where <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">fewer than 16%</NUMEX> of all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>- support cases involve parents
who are both represented by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>. Also, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">80%</NUMEX> of all
domestic-violence cases are handled without <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Bar of California</ENAMEX> has characterized the trend as "the
pro per crisis in family law" and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Judicial Council</ENAMEX> has
established a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">task force</ENAMEX> on the matter.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legislature</ENAMEX> has attempted to address the problem by
establishing family- law facilitator <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> throughout the state
to help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">litigants</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>-support matters. In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> such as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Orange County's</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> have offered workshops for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">litigants</ENAMEX>.
Classes often have <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two-month</TIMEX> waiting lists.
In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Van Nuys</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> established the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Self-Help Legal</ENAMEX>
Access <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center</ENAMEX>, in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> can seek legal help from computers
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteers</ENAMEX>.
I-CAN! Kiosks are in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> locations, including the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Orange</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">County</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">district attorney's office</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irvine City Hall</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fullerton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Juan Capistrano</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">libraries</ENAMEX>. However, the busiest
location is in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lamoreaux Justice Center</ENAMEX>.
At the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Family Law Information Center</ENAMEX>, where open boxes of
tissues are displayed as prominently as forms for initiating
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">divorce</ENAMEX>, custody and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>- support proceedings, office assistant
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beatrice Contreras</ENAMEX> said there is often a line of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> waiting to
use the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> machines.
Employing interactive video- and touch-screen technology, the
kiosks guide <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bureaucracy</ENAMEX> of obtaining
domestic-violence restraining orders, establishing child custody,
responding to child support and eviction orders, initiating
small-claims suits and requesting waivers for legal filing
fees.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kiosks</ENAMEX> give instructions in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vietnamese</ENAMEX>
and offer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> video tours of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">court complexes</ENAMEX> and primers on what
to expect during court hearings.
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> like it because they say it's fast and easy and
especially because they don't have to pay for an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX>. They
really like that," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Contreras</ENAMEX> said.
There still are some bugs in the system. Among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX>'
complaints: the small, immobile keyboards are sometimes difficult
to use, and the touch screens have to be tapped in just the right
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX>.
"Mostly it's good comments though," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Contreras</ENAMEX> said. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> will
come in here very confused and very sad and not know what to do.
Once they work with the computer and finish, you can tell they're
not as sad. They're glad that they're getting some help."




