



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Daily</ENAMEX> Law Bulletin

<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Coping With Funds Shortage is Topic</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid Meeting</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel C. Vock</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 25, 2002</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">SPRINGFIELD</ENAMEX> -- <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">About 225</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> and paralegals from across
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX> who provide legal services to the poor will gather in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early next week</TIMEX> for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13 years</TIMEX> to swap
ideas and offer each other encouragement.
But they're also in for some bad news.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John N. Erlenborn</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services Corp.</ENAMEX>, the
entity that doles out federal money for legal aid, will announce at
the conference that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX> will suffer "seven-figure funding
cuts" <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX> because of newly released census figures.
Under federal law, money for legal aid is distributed to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> based on the number of indigent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX>.
Erlenborn, a former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. House of Representatives</ENAMEX>
from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> area, did not disclose how big the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s hit
would be but issued a statement <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> pointing out that only
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> would lose more federal money than <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> gave <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Illinois</ENAMEX> nearly <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$12 million</NUMEX> -- or a
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> of the money going to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s legal aid programs -- to
fund the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Assistance Foundation of Metropolitan Chicago</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prairie State Legal Services and Land of Lincoln Legal Assistance</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foundation</ENAMEX>. Legal aid <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> are already scrounging
for funding as interest rates fall through the floor, because one
of their primary sources of support comes from the interest
generated on client assets held in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">trust</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas L. Kilbride</ENAMEX> will deliver
the keynote speech to the legal aid <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> and will
discuss the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">high court</ENAMEX>'s plan to hike <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> registration fees by
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$42</NUMEX> to cover the shortfall in the interest income.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">high court</ENAMEX> floated a plan during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the spring</TIMEX> legislative
session to raise those fees, which would bring in <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">roughly $2.4</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">million</ENAMEX> and raise the base fee for active <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$180</NUMEX> to
$222.
That proposal languished, but many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">observers</ENAMEX> noted that the high
court could raise the fees without legislative approval.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Organizers</ENAMEX> of the conference acknowledged that much of the
discussion at the event will center on how to use resources most
effectively on a shoestring budget.
In fact, all of the hotel <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> and conference <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> were
donated to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> after another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> announced at the
end of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX> that it was calling off its convention, leaving the
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> open, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Zazove</ENAMEX>, deputy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Land of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the conference's planning <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX>.
A core <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of legal aid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> hatched the idea of a
conference after visiting with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> of similar programs
in other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> who regularly hold such meetings, she said.
Originally, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">organizers</ENAMEX> hoped for a fall convention but they
sprang at the opportunity when the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> opened up.
"This is a unique opportunity for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are in the trenches
delivering services to get together, meet each other and share
ideas," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zazove</ENAMEX> said.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX> will attend sessions on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>-related consumer law,
bankruptcy, immigration, welfare, assisting pro se <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>,
recruiting private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> and Internet resources for both
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruth Ann Schmitt</ENAMEX>, executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lawyers Trust Fund</ENAMEX>,
which is covering some of the costs of the gathering, acknowledged
that the legal aid <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> faces many problems but said the
meeting could give <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> a morale boost.
"It's not often that the rank and file get together to talk
about their problems.... It's usually the leadership," she
said.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX>'s gathering is limited to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> and paralegals
working for legal aid <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>. According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lawyers Trust</ENAMEX>
Fund, which distributes the interest income, there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 250</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> working full time in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> programs
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">receiving LTF</ENAMEX> funds. Another <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> work part time for those
programs.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">organizers</ENAMEX> hope to expand the event in the future to include
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> and private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> and cover more topics in an Access to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Conference</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zazove</ENAMEX> said.




