



Funding cuts force <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid</ENAMEX> to reduce services
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 25, 2002</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">CHARLESTON</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">W.Va.</ENAMEX> (AP) - Shrinking revenue is forcing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Virginia</ENAMEX> to close <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> satellite <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> and lay off <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> provides free legal representation in civil cases to
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 24,000</NUMEX> low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annually</TIMEX>. Legal Aid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> help
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> of domestic violence, and they supervise the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ombudsman</ENAMEX>
program that sends <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> into all the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s nursing
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">homes</ENAMEX>.
"We are here for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who have no place to turn," Adrienne
Worthy, executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>, said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>. "Our
phones ring off the hook now. I do not look forward to saying, 'I'm
sorry. We can't help you."'
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> agreed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> to close satellite offices
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fayetteville</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Madison</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pineville</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Welch</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Winfield</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Williamson</ENAMEX>. Satellite <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clay</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hamlin</ENAMEX> and Summersville
and all <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> regional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> will remain open.
Decreases in two funding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> prompted the cuts, Worthy
said.
Legal Aid gets funding from the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services Corp.</ENAMEX>
based on a formula that counts the number of poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in a
service area. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">West Virginia</ENAMEX> lost <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poor people</ENAMEX>, according to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Census</ENAMEX> figures used by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services Corp.</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> drop will reduce <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Virginia</ENAMEX>'s
budget by <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$400,000</NUMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> also receives a percentage of money from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Interest</ENAMEX>
On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lawyers' Trust</ENAMEX> Accounts. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lawyers</ENAMEX> in private practice give a
percentage of the interest on money in trust accounts to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organizations</ENAMEX> in all <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>.
Low interest rates could mean <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$300,000</NUMEX> less from that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Worthy</ENAMEX> said.
Because of the funding cuts, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> will lose their jobs,
including <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>, paralegals, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> and support <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>, she
said.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">West Virginia</ENAMEX> has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> for every <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7,895</NUMEX> poor
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. For <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who can afford <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>, there is
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> to every <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">368</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, she said.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nate Bowles</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX>, said
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> plans to continue taking on "the cases that evidence the
most desperate need."



