



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CQ Weekly</ENAMEX>

<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">FY 04 Budget Outlook</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services Corporation</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, February 8, 2003</TIMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services Corp.</ENAMEX> (LSC), a quasi-governmental <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> that
provides legal aid for the poor, would receive <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$329 million</NUMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal 2004</TIMEX> under <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s proposal - the same amount
requested in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX> and approved for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002 and 2001</TIMEX>.
If approved, the hold-the-line request for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> means its budget
would erode with inflation for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">another year</TIMEX>, but it could be worse
for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>: Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> fought for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> to do
away with the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">LSC</ENAMEX> altogether, saying legal services <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> were
spending too much time fighting for liberal causes or pursuing
politically charged cases against the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> instead of
representing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">needy</ENAMEX>. Opposition to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> has cooled
since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> approved restrictions (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">PL 104-134</ENAMEX>) on the
sorts of cases federally funded legal aid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> can take. (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Almanac, p. 5-36</ENAMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> cut the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>'s budget deeply in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, but
its funding has recovered slowly. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last month</TIMEX>, in the omnibus
spending bill for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal 2003</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> added a onetime increase
of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$19 million</NUMEX>, which, if approved in the final version, would
bring the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> budget to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$348 million</NUMEX>. The money would go to help
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michigan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX>, that lost money when the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organization</ENAMEX> redistributed its funding based on census counts made
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> of poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX>.
If the extra money survives a conference with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> and
makes it to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s desk, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> may try to include
it in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal 2004</TIMEX> funding.
The federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> began funding some programs to provide
legal assistance to the poor in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 1960s</TIMEX>; the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corporation</ENAMEX> was created in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1974</TIMEX> (PL <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">93-355</NUMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> gives nearly all
its money to state and local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>, which provide civil legal
assistance to those whose income is <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">less than 125 percent</NUMEX> of the
federal poverty level - <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$11,075</NUMEX> a year for an individual and
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$22,625</NUMEX> for a family of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>. Funding for legal services goes to
defend needy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> in domestic violence cases, custody cases and
other such matters, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>.
Since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> who receive money from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services</ENAMEX> have
been prohibited from such activities as lobbying <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">legislatures</ENAMEX>,
filing class-action suits, participating in political
demonstrations or strikes, pursuing abortion-related litigation,
representing illegal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX>, or defending public
housing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tenants</ENAMEX> evicted because they were charged with selling
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>




