



<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ginny Kilgore Honored</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public Service Award</ENAMEX>
By <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elaine Pugh</ENAMEX>

<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 6, 2002</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UNIVERSITY</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miss.</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Catherine V. "Ginny</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kilgore</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oxford</ENAMEX>, an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Mississippi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rural Legal Services</ENAMEX>, has been
recognized for her dedication to serving the indigent.
Kilgore - who oversees delivering legal services to the disabled
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elderly</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">39</TIMEX> north <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mississippi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">counties</ENAMEX> - is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipient</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Mississippi School of Law</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public Service</ENAMEX>
Award. The award was announced recently at a dinne r, held in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kilgore</ENAMEX>'s honor and hosted by law school <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dean Samuel M. Davis</ENAMEX>, who
presented her with an engraved plaque.
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ginny Kilgore</ENAMEX> is a public <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">servant</ENAMEX> in the truest sense," said
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Davis</ENAMEX>. "Her selection continues the tradition of this award in
recognizing those who have labored in the trenches, with little or
no compensation but with great professional and personal
satisfaction in helping to bring justice and equality to those who
need it most."
"This award means a great deal to me," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kilgore</ENAMEX> said, pointing to
others so honored. "The work of those who received the award before
me has been so important; I feel very honored."
After earning <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bachelor</ENAMEX>'s and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX>'s degrees in education and a
few years teaching, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kilgore</ENAMEX> enrolled at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">UM</ENAMEX> law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>. Upon
graduation in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1975</TIMEX>, she entered private law practice in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oxford</ENAMEX>,
joining <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NMRLS</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1978</TIMEX>.
Since then, she has earned promotions from managing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX>,
senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX>, then <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council on Aging</ENAMEX> project.
Since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>, she has worked in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Administrative Law Unit</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Resource Development</ENAMEX>, and directed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Elder Law Project</ENAMEX>, serving
the northern <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>.
She also is an adjunct <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">UM</ENAMEX> law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Civil</ENAMEX>
Law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinic</ENAMEX>. She held a similar post <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years ago</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Elder Law Clinic</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kilgore</ENAMEX> says she's found her niche. "I've always thought it was
important to do work to help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. I really enjoy it. The issues
I've dealt with through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> have been on the side of helping
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> maintain the basics of life - home, healt h care, jobs and
family."
She says her desire to serve others was sparked early, growing
up in a single-parent <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>, aware that her widowed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> faced
certain challenges as she supported her <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> through
public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and college. Not the least of those difficulties,
however, occurred outside the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>.
"I was inspired by my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kilgore</ENAMEX> said. "She ran across
some discrimination in the workplace during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">those years</TIMEX>, and I
never forgot that. She challenged us to think and form opinions
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about</NUMEX> events occurring in our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> during those times in the
'60s, as we sat around the table at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the evening meal</TIMEX>."
Among her other awards, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kilgore</ENAMEX> was recognized by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mississippi Bar Association</ENAMEX> with its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services Lawyer of</ENAMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Year Award</ENAMEX>.
Previous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> of the law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public Service Award</ENAMEX> are
other <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">UM</ENAMEX> law <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alumni</ENAMEX>: Forest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Constance Slaughter-Harvey</ENAMEX>;
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luther Ott</ENAMEX>, formerly director of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stewpot Community Services</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX>; and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bobby DeLaughter</ENAMEX>, the former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">district attorney</ENAMEX> who
spearheaded the prosecution of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medgar Evers</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assassin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Byron De La</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beckwith</ENAMEX>.




