



Good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>'s reward

Working-class <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred Rooney</ENAMEX> will get prestigious
award <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX>.
By <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Devlin</ENAMEX>

<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 1, 2002</TIMEX>
One look at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred Rooney</ENAMEX>, and you just know he's the good
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">guy</ENAMEX>.
A trace of childish innocence in his face gives the lanky
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bethlehem</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy Stewart</ENAMEX>-like quality of quiet trust.
In black jeans and button-down <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shirt</ENAMEX>, he's a kind of folk <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX>
in the south <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bethlehem</ENAMEX> melting pot where he's crafted a law
practice catering to working-class <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> - mostly <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Latino -</ENAMEX> in
the shadow of the hulkish remnants of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bethlehem Steel</ENAMEX>.
A <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two-hour</TIMEX> drive away, at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City University of New York Law School</ENAMEX>
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Queens</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rooney</ENAMEX> spends <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several days</TIMEX> a week helping upstart
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> develop storefront practices that, like his, provide legal
representation to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> who can't afford a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$250</NUMEX>-an-hour legal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">counselor</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kristin Booth Glen</ENAMEX>, the law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dean</ENAMEX>, took <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> look at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rooney</ENAMEX> and knew he was the right <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> to head the innovative
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community Legal Resources Network</ENAMEX>.
''Fred's so low-key, he's <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Midwestern</ENAMEX> in effect,'' says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glen</ENAMEX>, a
former <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>. ''He captivates <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, he
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">inspires</ENAMEX> loyalty.''
For bringing legal representation to the poor and a host of
other social causes, including finding medical care for seriously
ill <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Latin America</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moravian College Alumni</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association</ENAMEX> has chosen <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rooney</ENAMEX> for its prestigious <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Haupert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Humanitarian Award</ENAMEX>.
The award, given to only a select few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alumni</ENAMEX>, will be presented
at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7:30 tonight</TIMEX> at a reception on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moravian</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Priscilla Payne Hurd</ENAMEX>
campus.
Moravian, where he was an undergraduate in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 1970s</TIMEX>,
inspired <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rooney</ENAMEX>'s deep sense of social justice.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bethlehem Steel</ENAMEX> executive in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, he came to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bethlehem</ENAMEX> campus from an affluent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">upbringing</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Long Island</ENAMEX>.
The young <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rooney</ENAMEX> might have set his sights on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>,
like his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncle</ENAMEX>, former <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred Rooney</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bethlehem</ENAMEX>.
After all, politics run in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rooney</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>. His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>, state
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">T.J. Rooney</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bethlehem</ENAMEX>, is a power in the state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legislature</ENAMEX>
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic Party</ENAMEX>.
But on a trip to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colombia</ENAMEX> when he was a junior at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moravian</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> of privilege saw human suffering, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">malnutrition</ENAMEX> and poverty
the likes of which he had never imagined.
''I couldn't understand why we live this way and they live that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX>,'' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rooney</ENAMEX> recalled. ''It's been the guiding light of my life
ever since.''
After graduating in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CUNY Law School</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> class in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX>, he
took a job with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lehigh Valley Legal Services</ENAMEX>. He loved the work,
but his income was so low he met federal poverty guidelines that
qualified him for his own low-income legal services.
While <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classmates</ENAMEX> were working for big <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX>, Rooney
was driving a wellworn <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chevy Nova</ENAMEX> that had to be coaxed to start
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">every morning</TIMEX>.
Fluent in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Spanish</ENAMEX>, he set up a practice in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bethlehem</ENAMEX> and
attracted <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latinos</ENAMEX> clustered in the old neighborhoods off the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lehigh</ENAMEX>
University <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campus</ENAMEX>.
''Fred was ahead of his time in addressing the needs of the
Latino <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX>,'' said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">District</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michele Varricchio</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Allentown</ENAMEX>, a former law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partner</ENAMEX>. ''He sees everyone as being
equal.''
Key to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rooney</ENAMEX>'s success, in addition to being bilingual, were
his ''low bono'' rates. He didn't work free, known as pro bono, but
charged <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one-third</NUMEX> the going rate and took a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">client</ENAMEX>'s ability to pay
into account when making up the bill.
''I didn't get the whole fee, but I got something,'' Rooney
says. ''It helped pay the bills, and I was doing the right
thing.''
Though he didn't fully realize it, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rooney</ENAMEX> was pioneering a
prototype community service law practice.
At <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CUNY</ENAMEX>, law school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">administrator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sue Bryant</ENAMEX> was thinking along
the same lines.
She envisioned a network of solo <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">practitioners</ENAMEX>, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rooney</ENAMEX>,
serving ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> across the metropolitan area. By
providing research services, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mentors</ENAMEX> and continuing education - all
the things they'd have if they worked in big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">law firms</ENAMEX> - storefront
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> could make a living charging affordable legal rates, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bryan</ENAMEX>
theorized.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community Legal Resources Network</ENAMEX> ''helps <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> become
economically viable so they can serve the poor and lower middle
class, who often can't afford legal representation,'' said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dorothy</ENAMEX>
Zellner, the law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokeswoman</ENAMEX>. ''It's a perfect fit for the
school's motto: law in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> of human needs.''
Studies suggest <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">80 percent</NUMEX> of the legal needs of low-income
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> go unmet.
Largely because of his experience in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bethlehem</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rooney</ENAMEX> was hired
to run the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community Legal Resources Network</ENAMEX>. Over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX>,
using grants from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Open Society Institute</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foundation</ENAMEX>, the program has grown to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>. The number is
expected to double in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next year</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nat Hentoff</ENAMEX>, civil liberties <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Village Voice</ENAMEX>,
called the network a ''seminal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> for justice, equal and
practical.'' The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Bar Association</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journal</ENAMEX> is planning an
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a half-dozen</NUMEX> other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX> are looking at duplicating
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rooney</ENAMEX>'s program.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roberta Chambers</ENAMEX>, who set up practice in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Queens Village</ENAMEX>, is
typical of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Fifteen</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> she came to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jamaica</ENAMEX>. She didn't
have a green card, but she did have a dream: to become a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>.
She became a registered <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurse</ENAMEX>, but always held on to the idea
that someday she would be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>. She enrolled in CUNY - the most
diverse law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> - and achieved her dream <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX>.
Now, with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX>'s help, she runs a neighborhood law
practice in a converted storefront. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Immigrants</ENAMEX>, social <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> and
bus <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX> come to her for advice on divorce, child custody and
bankruptcy.
''I handle average-type <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> stuff,'' said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chambers</ENAMEX>, sitting
in front of a wall of used law books she picked up at auction.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chambers</ENAMEX> charges <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$150</NUMEX> an hour, compared with the going New York
rate of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$250</NUMEX> for consultation and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$500</NUMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> appearances.
Rarely is she paid the full fee.
''Many times I have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX> who's out of work and we negotiate
a fee or work out a payment plan,'' she says. ''I have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who
swear by me. They always come back and bring others with
them.''
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rooney</ENAMEX> system is working in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Queens</ENAMEX>, as it has in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bethlehem</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rooney</ENAMEX>'s vision and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX> of hard work have paid off for the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">49-year-old</TIMEX>.
He has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partners</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lori Mannicci</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Gardner</ENAMEX>. They
handle the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day-to-day</TIMEX> operations, while <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rooney</ENAMEX> commutes to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
and does pro bono work for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and community <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>.
''My part in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> is not to generate income,'' he said. ''A
very large percentage of what I do is pro bono or low bono.''
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roberta Chambers</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX>, Rooney
predicts, will follow the same path. They, too, will get to the
point where they are no longer dependent solely on low bono
fees.
He's confident that they, like he, will always give generously
of their legal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">talent</ENAMEX>.
''The idea is to never completely get away from the communities
that gave you your start,'' he said. ''When you're blessed with
good fortune, you need to give something back.''





