



Legal Aid forced to raise rates

Hoped-for grants fail to come through for busy firm

Mon, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 10, 2002</TIMEX>
By <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">TIM GURRISTER</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard-Examiner</ENAMEX> staff
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OGDEN</ENAMEX> -- For most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>, full waiting <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> and appointments
booked out to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid-July</TIMEX> would equate to a lucrative law
practice.
But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Smith</ENAMEX> drives a 6-year-old <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">140,000 miles</NUMEX> on
it, and paying his senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">paralegal</ENAMEX> minimum wage <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the last few</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> has put him in the red. Hoped-for federal grants haven"t
come through, so he"s had to raise his rates.
As of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> he charges <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50</NUMEX> an hour minimum instead of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25</NUMEX>
for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX> of his yearling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northern Utah Legal Aid</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foundation</ENAMEX>.
That"s in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>"s market where fees range in the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$150 to $250</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an hour</TIMEX> range in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ogden</ENAMEX> area, and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">up to $400</NUMEX> an hour in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Salt</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Lake</ENAMEX> area.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX>"s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-lawyer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundation</ENAMEX> basically helps the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> who have
too much money to qualify for the federally funded <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Utah Legal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Services</ENAMEX>, but not enough money to afford a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>.


Public interest law
"It"s public interest law," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX> said. "I wouldn"t be doing it
if I didn"t enjoy it. You can take a case just on its merits.
"It"s very personally satisfying to do good legal work without
having to worry about getting paid.
"That"s a luxury <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> don"t usually have."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX> headed the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ogden</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Utah Legal Services</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nine</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, leaving <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a year ago</TIMEX> over a dispute with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Salt Lake</ENAMEX>. The departure left him free to open his own discount law
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">shop</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2485 Grant Ave.</ENAMEX>
His "work in progress," as he calls it, mirrors the no-fee legal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">services</ENAMEX> guidelines. He uses the same federal poverty guidelines to
determine his <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hourly</TIMEX> rate, which tops out at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$87.50</NUMEX>.
A big part of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX>"s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clientele</ENAMEX> comes from referrals from his
old job. His client base is all referrals, since he doesn"t
advertise.
If he did advertise, his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteer</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">45-hours</TIMEX>-<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a-week</TIMEX> office
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jody Smith</ENAMEX>, no relation, says she might kill him.


"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Swimming upstream</ENAMEX>"
"We"re swimming upstream big time here," she said. The office
opens at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 a.m.</TIMEX>, and rarely closes before <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6 p.m.</TIMEX>, with <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7:30 the</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">norm</ENAMEX>, and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 p.m.</TIMEX> not unusual.
"We close when we get to close," she said. "And then he (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank</ENAMEX>)
will come in on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturdays</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sundays</TIMEX> to catch up on paperwork. My
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">husband Bob</ENAMEX> is totally supportive, or I couldn"t do this."


Pro bono help needed
With the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$80,000</NUMEX> in grant funds he was trying for, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX> had
thought of hiring a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>, and paying <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jody</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Smith</ENAMEX> won"t say
it, but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jody</ENAMEX> will mention her disappointment at how few lawyers
volunteer to help the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundation</ENAMEX> by taking some cases pro bono,
without fee.
"We get a lot of that," she said, noting that so far only Lavar
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bud" Stark</ENAMEX> is pitching in.
"I have not asked other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> to handle cases, so I haven"t
been turned down," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Smith</ENAMEX> said. "So I can"t say I"m
disappointed.
Not yet. He"s planning to take a formal proposal to one of the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">monthly</TIMEX> meetings of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weber County Bar Association</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this summer</TIMEX>.
He"ll be asking all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> who refer penniless <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> to him,
to set up a fee schedule like his, so he can refer his overflow to
them.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the most recent local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> to "pledge" as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jody Smith</ENAMEX>
calls it, is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kent Snider</ENAMEX>.
"He"s fabulous," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Snider</ENAMEX> says of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Smith</ENAMEX>. "He"s too modest.
There"s a huge need he"s trying to fill."
It"s endemic to the entire profession, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Snider</ENAMEX> said: "Basically
if you"re rich, you can hire <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>, and if you"re poor, you can
have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> appointed.
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Anything</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between</TIMEX>, you"re screwed. Basically the general
public can"t afford appropriate legal services."


Family law a priority
The biggest part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundation</ENAMEX>"s work is family law:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">divorce</ENAMEX>, custody, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> support, etc.
In the midst of his custody fight, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Barboza</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ogden</ENAMEX>, heard
about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two months ago</TIMEX>.
"If someone trusts their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> with an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX>, I"ve got to
get that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX>," he said.
He"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">d</ENAMEX> used up <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$900</NUMEX> on his prior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX>, a lot of it blown on
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> failed attempts to get his exwife served with adoption <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>.
She died before that could happen while hospitalized with a chronic
ailment.
"I couldn"t get anything done with the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> without more
money.
"It was kind of a little miracle that I got hold of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank</ENAMEX>,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Barboza</ENAMEX> said. "He didn"t sit there rubbing his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> wondering what
to do like these other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>. He just said. 'It looks like a
tough fight. Let"s get it on,' and went right to work."


Praise for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX>
An <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ogden</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, who has been in a custody fight with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ex-wife</ENAMEX>
for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than two years</TIMEX> over visitation of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a 3-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sanpete County</ENAMEX> he hasn"t seen since she was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8 months old</TIMEX>, also had
praise for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>"s experience had left him bitter about the legal system,
since he wasn"t able to retain a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>.
"A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> of any kind would help, otherwise they assume you"re a
deadbeat," the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> said. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX> was able to hook him up with a pro
bono <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sanpete County</ENAMEX>, unable to take the case himself,
since his range of practice is from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Logan</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bountiful</ENAMEX>.
"He"s a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>. He"s trying to help a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, but he"s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">overwhelmed</ENAMEX>," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ogden</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> said. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank</ENAMEX> was referred to me by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who was
referred to me by another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>." "You wonder what you"re going to be
when you grow up," <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX> said. "Hopefully along the way you
find something you enjoy. This type of law suits me.
"I don"t know why. Who knows. I just get personal satisfaction
out of this."





