



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Greensburg Daily News</ENAMEX>

From <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cornfield to Courtroom</ENAMEX>

<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Cummings</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 14, 2002</TIMEX>
Growing up on a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farm</ENAMEX> near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Paul</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">L. Mark Bailey</ENAMEX> didn't dream
of becoming a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>. Even when he graduated from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Decatur High</ENAMEX>
School in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1975</TIMEX>, sitting on the bench someday seemed more like a
leisurely activity than a career.
Somewhere along the line, all of that changed. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bailey</ENAMEX> received
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bachelor</ENAMEX>'s degree from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Indianapolis</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1978</TIMEX>
and a jurisprudence doctorate from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana University</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX>
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1982</TIMEX>. After <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several years</TIMEX> of private practice from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1982-90</TIMEX>, he
became the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Decatur County</ENAMEX> Court for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>
legislature renamed that judgeship and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bailey</ENAMEX> was tabbed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Decatur</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Superior Court</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992-98</TIMEX>, winning reelection twice. From
there, his career continued on the fast track and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bailey</ENAMEX> was
appointed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank O'Bannon</ENAMEX> to sit on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana Court of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Appeals First District</ENAMEX>, where he works <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.
Despite his quick climb up the legal ladder, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bailey</ENAMEX> has always
found time to help out in causes he feels strongly about. It was
for his dedication to the law and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are affected by
it that he was recently recognized.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana Pro Bono Commission</ENAMEX> hosted its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> celebration
event, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randall T. Shepard Dinner</ENAMEX>, at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">French Lick Springs Spa</ENAMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">More than 100</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dignitaries</ENAMEX> were present
for the gathering. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the highlights of the event was the
presentation of the first-ever <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randall T. Shepard</ENAMEX> award for
excellence in pro bono work. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bailey</ENAMEX> received the award for his
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX> of volunteer work at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana Pro Bono Commission</ENAMEX>.
The award was named after the chief <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> to honor his statewide vision on justice. The
qualifications for the award were based upon demonstrated
dedication to the innovative development and delivery of legal
services to the poor in one of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX> pro bono <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">districts</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>.
"This award came as a real surprise to me. It is truly an honor.
Just being the first chair of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">commission</ENAMEX> which began the
implementation of the pro bono process was somewhat humbling. It
took a lot of hard work by all of the committee <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> to make
this a reality," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bailey</ENAMEX> said. "It also takes a commitment by all of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> to make sure that every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> can have
their day in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>. It is on their behalf that I accepted the
award. It is so important that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> remain open to all
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> not just the rich."
Although this award will now be handed out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annually</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bailey</ENAMEX> was
selected for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several years</TIMEX> of his commitment. In being named the
original <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana Pro Bono Commission</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ago</TIMEX>, he led the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX>-member <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> to create a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX> that would
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">embrace Shepard</ENAMEX>'s pro bono ideals from beginning.
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bailey</ENAMEX> was chosen because he should be looked at as the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX> of all future winners. Those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> should
strive to follow his example. He dedicated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX> of his life
to creating the framework of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana Pro Bono Commission</ENAMEX> as it
was set up by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana Code 6.5</ENAMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer Konomos</ENAMEX>, executive
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana Pro Bono Commission</ENAMEX>. "He is a joy to work
with and is very professional. He's dedicated to justice and
ensuring that every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> has the ability to take their legal
issues to court regardless of their social stature."
To date, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IPBC</ENAMEX> has contributed <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $1.3 million</NUMEX> to help
provide civil legal services to the poor.
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bailey</ENAMEX> is very patriotic and proved that by dedicating three
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> of his life to this cause. His mission was to make sure that
no one was left behind in our legal system. Because of him lawyers
are lining up <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> to be part of what he created. This is just
a wonderful <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> to be part of," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Konomos</ENAMEX> said.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IPBC</ENAMEX> has received praise from legal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> nationwide. When
it was created, it was the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of its kind in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>.
Recently, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> has created a similar program after
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX> created in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>.
Perhaps the most glowing comments on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bailey</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">philanthropy</ENAMEX> came
from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> after whom the award was named.
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bailey</ENAMEX> has taken the lead in creating this program that
helps <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who cannot afford a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> for civil litigation.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>, related to the project, are often asked to
speak nationally about our system," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shepard</ENAMEX> said. "That is a great
compliment to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bailey</ENAMEX> and to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>. Many types of civil litigation
involve things that are dear to us. Our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX>, jobs and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>
can be at stake. These are important issues dear to him. He's a
decent self effacing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who works hard at being a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>. We're
all better off because he is in that position."
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bailey</ENAMEX> still seems to have a hard time accepting that the award
was really given to him.
"These are the ideals I used when I was in private practice. As
a trial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> I am always happy to see equity in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX>. It is
when we have competent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> representing both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">litigants</ENAMEX>,
regardless of money, that the system works best. I look at it as a
form of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">homeland</ENAMEX> security which has become so prevalent lately,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bailey</ENAMEX> said. "We need to ensure that the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">branch</ENAMEX> [the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">judiciary</ENAMEX>] of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is working for everyone. I'm so
pleased that I was recognized for my efforts, I just can't take all
of the credit. So many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were involved in this process. I also
think this looks good for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Decatur County</ENAMEX>. I have the highest regard
for their judicial system."





