



<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bryant</ENAMEX> seeks to help rent-to-own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tenants</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lynchburg Virginia</ENAMEX>

By <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael Hewlett</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News & Advance</ENAMEX>
The eviction of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lynchburg</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX>, partly as a result of a "rent-to-own" contract, has drawn
the attention of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Assembly.</ENAMEX>
But a bill drafted by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Del. Preston Bryant</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lynchburg</ENAMEX>, won't be
addressed until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX> after the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Virginia Housing Commission</ENAMEX>,
prompted by a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate Joint Resolution</ENAMEX>, offers its recommendations
based on a statewide study of rent-to-own contracts and other
housing issues.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bryant</ENAMEX> said he read about the issue in a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX> News & <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Advance</ENAMEX>
editorial. The editorial stemmed from a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News & Advance</ENAMEX> article
which highlighted <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> who were being
evicted after their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1328 Bedford Ave.</ENAMEX>, was cited for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dozen</ENAMEX> code violations.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> had been paying <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$425</NUMEX> a month in a rent-to-own
agreement for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX>, or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">roughly $25,500</NUMEX>. They still had
another <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 years</TIMEX> to go to complete the contract.
"I called the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Virginia Legal Aid Society</ENAMEX> and also talked to
(<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">City</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter Erwin</ENAMEX> and (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Housing Authority</ENAMEX> executive
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ed McCann</ENAMEX> about it," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bryant</ENAMEX> said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>. "I asked them to
take a look at this issue as an ad hoc <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX>."
"I was a little concerned about it and wanted to see if there
was any reasonable steps that could be taken to help protect <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX>
that are not overly burdensome."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bryant</ENAMEX>'s bill, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> Bill <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1122</TIMEX>, requires all rent-to-own
contracts to be recorded in the land deeds where the property is
located along with any documents indicating the financial
arrangement. It also requires <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">landlords</ENAMEX> to have their property
inspected prior to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tenants</ENAMEX> signing a rent-to-own contract and to
provide the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tenant</ENAMEX> with the inspection report.
"Many times, those entering into these contracts are your less
sophisticated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bryant</ENAMEX> said. "And while I don't think we as
a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> can protect everybody we can take some steps to help
protect <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lawyers</ENAMEX> say the rent-to-own contracts are legal but the
contracts do tend to take advantage of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with limited
options.
"We always tell people not to sign those," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Renae Patrick</ENAMEX>,
managing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lynchburg</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Virginia Legal Aid Society</ENAMEX>, in a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 27, 2001</TIMEX> article about rent-to-own contracts.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Commissioners</ENAMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lynchburg</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Redevelopment and Housing</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Authority</ENAMEX> approved <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last September</TIMEX> a resolution that would require
inspections every time a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tenant</ENAMEX> moved out.
That proposal also required an inspection before a new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tenant</ENAMEX>
signs a rent-to-own contract. The resolution must come before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX>
Council for final action.
City <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Manager</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kim Payne</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> will look at that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resolution</ENAMEX> as part of the budget process.
"The rental program is under discussion but beyond that there
hasn't been much activity," he said.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> started the rental inspection program in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> in an
attempt to crack down on property <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> who fail to maintain their
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">homes</ENAMEX>, whether split into <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartments</ENAMEX> or rented as a single-family
residence.
The program gets its geographic boundaries from census tracks
and roughly covers much of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">White Rock Hill</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">College Hill</ENAMEX>, Tinbridge
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX> and the lower <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rivermont</ENAMEX> area.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Payne</ENAMEX> said he and other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">administrators</ENAMEX> are looking at how broad
the rental inspection program should be and whether the changes
will mean more staffing and more money.
"I would guess that decision will have to be made as we move
through the budget process," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Payne</ENAMEX> said. City <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">administrators</ENAMEX> will
present their budget proposal to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> in mid-March.
"I applaud <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Del. Bryant</ENAMEX> for introducing the bill," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Payne</ENAMEX> said.
"It's consistent with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">council</ENAMEX>'s concerns and that of the housing
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">authority</ENAMEX>. If it's not a statewide issue, it's an issue in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lynchburg</ENAMEX>."




