



Helping Hands
Funds to help battered <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> with divorce, child custody
cases
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Liz Stevens</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday, October 27, 2002</TIMEX>
Legal assistance for battered <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> is hard to come by. But it
just got a little easier to find in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tarrant County</ENAMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This month</TIMEX>, the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Violence Against Women</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office</ENAMEX> awarded a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two-year</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$350,000</NUMEX> grant to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Women's Haven</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tarrant County</ENAMEX>.
The money will allow the shelter to add a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> full-time <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX>
to its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> and contract with the law school <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clinic</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wesleyan University</ENAMEX> for pro bono and student services.
Most important, the funds will help fill a frustrating gap.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Women's Haven</ENAMEX>, which provides shelter and outreach to
domestic-violence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>, already has a full-time <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX>. But
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> is prohibited (by funding parameters) from representing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in matters of divorce or child custody.
That's not a problem for most of the shelter's indigent
residents, who can access free legal aid locally from West Texas
Legal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Services</ENAMEX>.
But many of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> served by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Women's Haven outreach</ENAMEX>
programs are the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">working poor</ENAMEX>, who don't qualify for free legal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">services</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Divorces</ENAMEX> and custody battles are simply out of their
financial reach.
"They can't begin to save up enough money for a divorce, so
they're stuck," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sonyia Hartwell</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Women's Haven</ENAMEX>'s associate
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>. "They're completely shut out of the civil<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">-</ENAMEX>law
system."
In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>, unlike in some other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who aren't divorced
can't gain full control over their portion of assets. And they
can't obtain <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> support.
The grant will also provide law <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> with valuable
experience working these types of cases. "They can't go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>,
but they can interview <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> and do all the initial intake work
that needs to be done" as well as investigative work, says
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hartwell</ENAMEX>.
And there's no shortage of abuse <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> who need this kind of
help.
"Within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">60 days</TIMEX> of hanging out her or his shingle," says
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hartwell</ENAMEX> of the yet unhired new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX>, "we'll have an active
caseload of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> or more."



