



Helping Out at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tax Times</ENAMEX>
By <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony Perez Cassino</ENAMEX>
For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past few weeks</TIMEX> my usual stack of junk mail has been
supplemented with a steady stream of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX> tax statements and forms,
reminding me that the clock has begun ticking towards <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 15</TIMEX>. I
admit that even though my taxes are relatively simple and I took a
tax course in law school, I still hire an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">accountant</ENAMEX> to complete
the forms. I found law school discussions concerning the concept of
"basis" or "stepped-up basis" to be about as easy to follow as the
rule against perpetuities.
Of course, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> tax concept that we all understand is an
audit. The prospect of being audited may be one of life's most
stressful experiences, so I can only imagine how daunting it would
be if I had to do so without any professional assistance. But that
is the exact situation that many low- and moderate-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX>
face when being audited by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Internal Revenue Service</ENAMEX>. With the
push in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX> to move <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from welfare to work, there are
many new low-wage first-time <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">filers</ENAMEX>, who are often automatically
audited. Still others fail to file, file incorrectly or fail to
take advantage of programs like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Earned Income Tax Credit</ENAMEX>.

Legal Clinics
In an effort to redress this problem, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> has taken the
unusual step of funding legal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clinics</ENAMEX> that assist low-income
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX>. Under the project, which was created as part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX>
Restructuring and <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Reform Act of 1998</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> provides funding to
programs that offer tax education and representation to low-income
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>. This may seem a little bit like supplying a rival army
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ammunition</ENAMEX>, but in fact it is entirely consistent with the
stated mission of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX>. In a press release referring to the
program, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Commissioner</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles O. Rossotti</ENAMEX> stated that the
clinics mesh with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> mission statement of providing "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX> top quality service by helping them understand and meet
their tax responsibilities by applying the tax law with integrity
and fairness to all." He went on to say that "these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clinics</ENAMEX> fill a
critical need. They reach out to help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who frequently have
nowhere else to turn for legal assistance on tax matters." A number
of programs in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> that are funded by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> rely heavily on
volunteer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> to serve <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>, including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Brooklyn</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Low-Income Taxpayer Clinic of South Brooklyn Legal Services</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Low Income Taxpayer Clinic</ENAMEX> operated by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Legal Aid Society</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Volunteer Division</ENAMEX>. These programs address a valid complaint by
corporate tax <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> that there are not enough opportunities for
them to use their unique skills to help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> on a pro bono
basis. However, participation in a taxpayer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clinic</ENAMEX> is not solely
limited to tax <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> since these programs provide extensive
training and mentoring.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the most important services provided to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> of
taxpayer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clinics</ENAMEX> is assistance in seeking a refund under the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Earned</ENAMEX>
Income <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tax Credit</ENAMEX> provisions. While <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> brings a new round
of partisan battles in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> over the tax code, the EITC
program is one proposal that satisfies a broad cross-section of the
political spectrum. It is a vital income supplement and work
incentive program targeted to low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">working families</ENAMEX> with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. It has been called the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s most successful
anti-poverty program, distributing over <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$30 billion</NUMEX> of assistance
to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">almost 19 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Twenty-eight percent</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>
that benefited from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">program</ENAMEX> had incomes below <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10,000</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX>
percent were below <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20,000</NUMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>, it lifted <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 4.8</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> out of poverty.
Despite all of its success, there are still many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> who do
not apply for the credit because of a lack of awareness.
Ironically, for those who do apply, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EITC</ENAMEX> represents the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX>
largest area for audits by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX>. Both of these scenarios point
to the importance of having professional assistance throughout this
process, and to the vital role of the low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayer</ENAMEX> clinics.
Although these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clinics</ENAMEX> are relatively new, they have been
well-received by volunteer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> who have been instrumental in
establishing the programs.
This collaboration is noteworthy for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least two</NUMEX> reasons: it is
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX> for future <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partnerships</ENAMEX> between the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and the
private sector, and it is an example of some of the very diverse
pro bono opportunities for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> that have been created in recent
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. Unfortunately, during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past decade</TIMEX> government funding for
legal services for low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> has declined at almost all
levels. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid-1990</TIMEX>'s there was a concerted attempt in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>
to eliminate funding entirely for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services Corporation</ENAMEX>, a
nationwide <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">program</ENAMEX> dedicated to providing civil legal services to
lowincome <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>. Although the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">program</ENAMEX> continues to survive, its
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">funding</ENAMEX> has been reduced by <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $100 million</NUMEX>. On the state
level, funding from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Interest on Lawyer</ENAMEX> Account fund has
decreased by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1990</TIMEX>'s due to declining interest
rates. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> should be commended for recognizing the importance
and benefits of ensuring equal treatment for all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Just a few years ago</TIMEX>, pro bono work usually meant litigation.
Although litigation continues to be a leading pro bono activity,
new projects have been created that tap into the multitude of
expertise within the profession. There are pro bono programs that
now <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> with volunteer corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> to assist
not-for-profits and micro-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enterprises</ENAMEX> as well as on economic
development projects. The taxpayer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clinic</ENAMEX> is unique because it is
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the few opportunities for tax <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">practitioners</ENAMEX> to assist
individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX> on a pro bono basis.
I cannot say that I am prepared to give up my aversion to the
tax code, but the lowincome taxpayer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clinics</ENAMEX> are an innovative way
for those who are comfortable with its provisions to help others in
need. In the case of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Earned Income Tax Credit</ENAMEX>, it is also a
rare opportunity to significantly enhance the living situation of a
low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> by obtaining funds rightfully due them. If you
would like to get involved, please contact The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brooklyn Low-Income</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taxpayer Clinic of South Brooklyn Legal Services</ENAMEX> at (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">718</ENAMEX>) 2375500
or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Low Income Taxpayer Clinic</ENAMEX> operated by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Legal Aid</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Society's Volunteer Division</ENAMEX> at (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">212</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">426-3094</ENAMEX>.




