



Higher <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> filing fees could help fund <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid</ENAMEX>

By <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deborah Yetter</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday, December 29, 2002</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Backers</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid</ENAMEX> services for the poor are pushing a measure
that would increase court filing fees in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kentucky</ENAMEX> to raise money
for the program, which faces steep funding cuts.
The proposed bill, sponsored by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Geveden</ENAMEX>,
D-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wickliffe</ENAMEX>, would double the portion of the fee that goes to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal</ENAMEX>
Aid -- in district court to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10</NUMEX> from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5</NUMEX> and in circuit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20</NUMEX>
from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10</NUMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kentucky</ENAMEX>'s current fee for filing a case in district <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> is
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50.50</NUMEX>, and in circuit court <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$108</NUMEX>.
The increase still would leave <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kentucky</ENAMEX>'s filing fee costs below
those of surrounding <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> and would raise <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $1.3 million</NUMEX> a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> -- almost enough to replace what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid</ENAMEX> is losing from
federal and other sources, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Hamon</ENAMEX>, executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of
the Access to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Foundation</ENAMEX>, a state poverty law resource
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">center</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lexington</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Geveden</ENAMEX> said his measure appears to be the only potential source
of money for the program, which is being forced to lay off workers
and close <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> around the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Geveden</ENAMEX> said he's concerned because federal funding hasn't
increased in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> with increased poverty are
taking a greater share of the money.
''If you don't come up with the money somewhere, legal services
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in need will diminish or go away,'' he said.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hamon</ENAMEX> said the proposed bill has attracted a number of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">co-sponsors</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">backers</ENAMEX> are hoping to get it passed in
the upcoming legislative session.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hamon</ENAMEX> said she knows fee increases aren't popular with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawmakers</ENAMEX>
but hopes they realize the crisis <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid</ENAMEX> is facing.
''A lot of poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are not going to get served,'' she
said.
The measure has the endorsement of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kentucky Bar Association</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">association</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governors</ENAMEX> voted unanimously <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX>
to back the bill, said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KBA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Catron</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bowling</ENAMEX>
Green <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>.
Legal Aid ''has been a godsend to a great number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in
this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>,'' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Catron</ENAMEX> said. ''We simply must find a way to provide
those services to the public.''
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry York</ENAMEX>, executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Appalachian Regional Defense</ENAMEX>
Fund, which provides <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid</ENAMEX> services in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">37</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastern Kentucky</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">counties</ENAMEX> and is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KBA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX>, said he hopes the measure is
approved.
''It would really offset the current cuts,'' he said.




