



IT'S <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>: DO YOU KNOW YOUR IOLTA INTEREST RATE?
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> has historically provided mandates for the
deposit of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">client</ENAMEX> funds into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">attorney trust</ENAMEX> accounts. Before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX>,
federal <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">law</ENAMEX> prohibited interest to be generated on checking
accounts maintained by federally insured <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX>. Therefore, client
funds were deposited into interest-free <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">attorney trust</ENAMEX> accounts.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> received a windfall: shortterm, interest-free "loans" for
their use.
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX>, banking laws changed. For the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> could
offer interest on checking accounts or NOW accounts. However,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> could rarely take advantage of these interest-bearing
accounts for their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>. The purpose of depositing funds into an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX>'s trust account was either for short-term deposits with
immediate access to the funds, or for small amounts whose interest
would not exceed the costs attendant to separate accounting.
Therefore, individualized interest-bearing trust checking accounts
were unwieldy and impractical. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Clients</ENAMEX> could rarely, if ever, earn
a positive net interest. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX> joined the ranks of
those <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> that adopted the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Interest</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lawyers' Trust</ENAMEX> Accounts
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IOLTA</ENAMEX>) Fund as a method of collecting and using the interest that
would be earned on these deposits. Rule <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1:28A</TIMEX>. All <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> now
have similar IOLTA programs.
Pursuant to our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> rules, participation in the IOLTA program
is mandatory. The type of funds to be deposited is strictly
circumscribed, and the use to which that combined interest can be
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">assigned</ENAMEX>, carefully delineated. As a result, what might have
amounted to a pittance for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX>, in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">conglomerate</ENAMEX> became a
substantial fund.
According to information routinely gathered and analyzed by our
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IOLTA</ENAMEX> fund, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year 2000</TIMEX>, the average balance of all IOLTA
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> trust accounts in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX> alone on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">any given day</TIMEX>, at
any given time was <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.2 billion</NUMEX>. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the third quarter</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 30, 2001</TIMEX> (the last date for which this data is available),
that amount had increased to an average <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> balance of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.5</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">billion</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">roughly 120</NUMEX> participating <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX>. That is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.5</NUMEX>
billion that these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> can use to fund their mortgages, home
equity loans, automobile loans, and other types of loans for which
they receive <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">approximately 7 percent</NUMEX> or more on interest they
charge.
Have you checked the interest rate your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> pays on your IOLTA
account? The rates vary greatly from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.25 percent</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2.75 percent</NUMEX>,
depending on the bank you choose. Although this rate variation may
seem minimal, if all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> paid <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IOLTA</ENAMEX> interest at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 0.25</NUMEX>
percent, the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> earnings on <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.5 billion</NUMEX> would be only
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3,750,000</NUMEX>. If every IOLTA account paid <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2.75 percent</NUMEX> (a rate that
even <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IOLTA</ENAMEX> concedes is wishful thinking), the earnings would be <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX>
times greater, or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$41,250,000</NUMEX>.
While many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> continued to pay the same rates in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX> that
they paid in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>, others reduced the rates they pay. In fact, the
average IOLTA interest rate paid in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> by all of the
participating <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> was <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1.6 percent</NUMEX>. Unfortunately, the average
interest rate paid through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the third quarter of 2001</TIMEX> dropped to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.4</NUMEX>
percent.
A comparison of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of the major participating banks
demonstrates the disparity in their approaches to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IOLTA</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> bank
dropped its interest rate in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 2001</TIMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1 percent</NUMEX>. The other
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> pays the fund interest based upon tiered account levels, more
typical of a large commercial account. As the balance in the
account goes up, the interest rate goes up as well, to a high-
water mark of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1.98 percent</NUMEX> for accounts with balances of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$250,000</NUMEX>
or more. While <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a third</NUMEX> major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> advertised its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX> money
market account rates to be <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">between 1.73 percent</NUMEX> for accounts with
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5,000</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2.47 percent</NUMEX> for accounts with <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50,000</NUMEX> or more, that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> pays IOLTA a flat <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1.1 percent</NUMEX>. Even its advertised passbook
savings <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">accounts</ENAMEX> earned <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1.49 percent</NUMEX>.
Meanwhile, some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> that have reduced interest rates to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IOLTA</ENAMEX> also charge higher activity fees to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IOLTA</ENAMEX>. A few <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> charge
fees <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">as high as 23 percent</NUMEX> of the gross interest earned. On
average, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IOLTA</ENAMEX> fund repays <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5 percent</NUMEX> of all its earnings to
those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> that charge for these accounts. These fees generally
include <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">monthly</TIMEX> account fees and per check and per deposit charges
on each transaction. Yet, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only half</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IOLTA</ENAMEX> participating
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> actually charge the fund these fees. Half of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> charge
no fees whatsoever, simply satisfied to have these accounts as a
significant growing source of inexpensive money to use almost
interest-free.
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IOLTA</ENAMEX> collected <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$16.3 million</NUMEX> to fund its very narrowly
construed mission. As designated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>, the fund
uses the money to provide legal aid to the poor, and education and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">beneficial</ENAMEX> services to the public. Legal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Services of New Jersey</ENAMEX>
receives <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">75 percent</NUMEX> of the funds. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Bar</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foundation</ENAMEX> receives <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">12.5 percent</NUMEX> for educational lay programs
relating to law and justice, and other public service programs such
as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School Mock Trial Competition</ENAMEX> and numerous
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">publications</ENAMEX>. The balance of the funds is granted to small entities
that provide legal services and assistance to the indigent.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">R.</ENAMEX><TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1:28A-4.</TIMEX> For instance, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IOLTA</ENAMEX> grants money to several <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX>
Appointed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Special Advocate Programs</ENAMEX> (CASA) for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Essex</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morris-Sussex</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mercer</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Atlantic-Cape</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX>. The CASA program is a
volunteer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who assist and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocate</ENAMEX> for the
rights of individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in foster care. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IOLTA</ENAMEX> grants go to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Covenant House Youth Advocacy Program</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocate</ENAMEX> of legal
rights of homeless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youths</ENAMEX> who, having reached <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the age of 18</TIMEX>, are no
longer eligible to be in foster care. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2.1 million</NUMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IOLTA</ENAMEX> grants will support these and numerous other crucial programs
that offer priceless services to the poor.
The <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$16.3 million</NUMEX> raised for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IOLTA</ENAMEX> is not enough. Legal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Services</ENAMEX>
which provides civil legal services to the poor, the disabled, and
the most vulnerable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, can only represent, at
best, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">25 percent</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are in need of assistance and
who meet the requirements for representation. In a "legal triage,"
they must select those most in immediate need. The rest of their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">applicants</ENAMEX> must wait, or give up.
Even the amount of the fund is not guaranteed. In the pending
difficult economic times, when the rush to refinance has passed,
will these accounts maintain their <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.5 billion</NUMEX> average daily
balance? If interest rates continue to decline, or the daily
balances decrease, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IOLTA</ENAMEX> fund will be curtailed. With less
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">funding for Legal Services</ENAMEX>, what will happen to those so much in
need? What will happen to the pro bono requirements already imposed
upon <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX>?
What can we, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX> who control these accounts,
do to protect the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IOLTA</ENAMEX> fund? The easy answer is: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ask</ENAMEX>." Ask your
bank what interest rate it pays to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IOLTA</ENAMEX>. Ask your bank what fees
it charges to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IOLTA</ENAMEX>. Comparison <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX>. Understand the spread between
what your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> pays the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IOLTA</ENAMEX> fund and what it charges your
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>. Yet, we only can control our own accounts.
Better yet, we call upon the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Bar Association</ENAMEX>,
and each county <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar association</ENAMEX>, to lend a voice to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IOLTA</ENAMEX>. The bar
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associations</ENAMEX> could consult with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IOLTA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX>, and then
contact <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> to determine which ones are providing the best
returns with the lowest costs to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IOLTA</ENAMEX>. The promise of more
business, or the loss thereof, would have far more impact coming
from an association than any single law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorneys</ENAMEX> hold the purse strings. Why not turn them into reins?
We can, with little effort, steer our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> trust accounts to
those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> that are willing to pay just a little more for the
privilege of receiving our trust deposits.



