



<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Salt Lake City</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tribune</ENAMEX>

<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Seniors Find It Pays to Know Rights</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday, July 24, 2002</TIMEX>

By <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Rolly</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">JoAnn Jacobsen</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wells</ENAMEX>
When <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">74-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Penny Sweat</ENAMEX> was evicted from the HUD-subsidized
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Glendale Senior Housing</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Salt Lake City</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX>, she moved to
a nonsubsidized <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> times her previous rent because
she was unaware of her rights.
It turns out the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> of the seniors complex, its attorneys
and government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">overseers</ENAMEX> were unaware, too.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee Kemp</ENAMEX>, a hearing-impaired <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">disabled vet</ENAMEX>, also was
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">evicted</ENAMEX>, but he contacted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Utah Legal Services</ENAMEX> and was told to stay
put.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marty Blaustein</ENAMEX> then notified <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Utah Nonprofit Housing</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corp.</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX>, that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kemp</ENAMEX>'s eviction was not legal and
that he had a right to a hearing.
That didn't stop <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Utah Nonprofit Housing</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> from then
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sending Kemp</ENAMEX> a summons to show cause why he had not moved out.
Meanwhile, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sweat</ENAMEX>'s granddaughter called <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Salt Lake City</ENAMEX> housing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>, federal housing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>, state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> and several
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Utah Nonprofit Housing</ENAMEX> to find out about her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">grandmother</ENAMEX>'s rights. Nobody knew.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blaustein</ENAMEX> then took <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sweat</ENAMEX>'s case along with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kemp</ENAMEX>'s and demanded
her ousting be rectified.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Utah Nonprofit Housing</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marion Willey</ENAMEX> returned from an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">out-of-town</ENAMEX> trip and learned <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUD</ENAMEX> procedures were not followed.
The eviction was activated because of ongoing personality
conflicts among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">seniors</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX>, he said, and the new
building <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> decided the problems were with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sweat</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kemp</ENAMEX>.
Several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tenants</ENAMEX> blame other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">perpetrators</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rift</ENAMEX>, however.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX> said when his building <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> retained
by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, they erroneously told her she could go ahead and
kick out the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tenants</ENAMEX>. When she called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUD</ENAMEX> to make sure, the inquiry
got bogged down in bureaucracy and nobody called her back.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willey</ENAMEX> says he has offered <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sweat</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kemp</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartments</ENAMEX> in another
complex operated by his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> at their old rates. He also is
retaining new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX>.





