



<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> for all is a never-ending quest
Documentary shows how <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services</ENAMEX> aids <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who have
nowhere else to turn

By <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudy Larini</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 23, 2003</TIMEX>
After becoming disabled in a machete attack on a visit to his
native <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Haiti</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jean-Claude Joseph</ENAMEX> needed help persuading his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">landlord</ENAMEX> to move him from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a fifth</NUMEX>-floor <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> on the
ground floor.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isaac Benjamin</ENAMEX> became ensnared in a bureaucratic snafu that took
away his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> disability payments for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">more than two</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>.
The story of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sierra Leone</ENAMEX>, was more
compelling. Beaten, raped and tortured in her politically
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">repressive</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">homeland</ENAMEX>, she knowingly used someone else's passport to
escape to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, but was caught by immigration <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> upon
her arrival. She desperately sought political asylum.
Not the kind of cases that lead to ground-breaking upheavals in
the law, but the kind of cases that are handled day in and day out
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> for the legally <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">disenfranchised</ENAMEX> who have no where else
to turn.
The work of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services of New Jersey</ENAMEX> will be
highlighted in a onehour documentary, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Quest for Justice</ENAMEX>," to be
aired <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 p.m.</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Jersey Network</ENAMEX>. Produced by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">NYD2</TIMEX>, a
communications <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> based in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Somerset</ENAMEX>, the documentary features
case histories of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> whose needs ranged from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">housing</ENAMEX> to
fighting off deportation.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph</ENAMEX>, a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">54-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">naturalized citizen</ENAMEX>, turned to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal</ENAMEX>
Services when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">landlord</ENAMEX> of his federally subsidized apartment
complex in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth</ENAMEX> turned a deaf ear to his request for a
ground-floor <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX>.
Having lost the use of his left <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX> in warding off the machete
attack during a robbery attempt, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph</ENAMEX> said he found it
increasingly difficult to negotiate the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> flights of stairs
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">lugging groceries</ENAMEX> or laundry on the frequent occasions when the
building's elevator was out of order.
"With this, it became impossible for me to stay upstairs," he
said, pointing to the scars on his forearm. "If I cannot carry my
groceries or my laundry, how can I live?"
"It was a compelling case," said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Hilaire</ENAMEX>. "The key for us -- and we have to make tough decisions
all the time on whether to take a case -- was visualizing what he
had to do to get to the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX> floor, struggling with a bag of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">groceries</ENAMEX>," he said.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">53</TIMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jersey City</ENAMEX> had been collecting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>
disability after undergoing double bypass surgery when the checks
stopped coming. He said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> claimed he had failed to return
a form updating the condition of his health.
"But what got me was they didn't let me know they didn't get it,
they just cut me off," he said, adding he found it impossible to
negotiate the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bureaucracy</ENAMEX> himself.
"When I would call them up or go up there, they would give me
blank stares," he said. "I didn't know what to do."
So he contacted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services</ENAMEX> and his case was assigned to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">paralegal David Morris</ENAMEX>.
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isaac</ENAMEX>'s case was one of government screw-ups," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morris</ENAMEX> said,
recounting how <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> shuffled his file from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore</ENAMEX> and then <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX> before finally tracking it down.
Legal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Services</ENAMEX> eventually got <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin</ENAMEX>'s benefits restored.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha</ENAMEX>, who does not want her last name used, believes she owes
her very life to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laura Adjangba</ENAMEX>, who won
"This is a great thing she has done for me in this world," she
said as tears welled up in her eyes. "God just brought her to take
care of my problem."
In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services</ENAMEX> has represented <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 1.3</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> since the program was conceived during <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lyndon Johnson</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">War</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Poverty</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid1960s</TIMEX>.
In a survey <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services</ENAMEX> determined that more than
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one-third</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX>'s poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> -- <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 400,000</NUMEX> people
-- have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> civil legal problem <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>. There are <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal</ENAMEX>
Services <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> in every <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">county</ENAMEX> except <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Salem</ENAMEX> and they handle
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">roughly 50,000</NUMEX> cases a year.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX> has a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services</ENAMEX> budget of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">almost $38 million</NUMEX> and
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500</NUMEX>, including <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 200</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>, many of whom could be earning considerably more in
the private sector, are uniformly devoted to the principle of
providing legal assistance to those who otherwise might be denied
their day in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>.
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> often say, 'Oh, you work with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services</ENAMEX> because you
couldn't work for a big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">300</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>,'" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grayce</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wiggins</ENAMEX> explains on the documentary. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> that work at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Services</ENAMEX> are committed to the mission of legal services. This is
more than just a job. This is about changing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s lives."
"With this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>, you hear them regularly say to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> they
are honored to practice this kind of law," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael DeFabrizio</ENAMEX>,
an NYD2 <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX> and the executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producer</ENAMEX> of the
documentary.
In the opening segment of the documentary, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicholas deB</ENAMEX>.
Katzenbach, who was <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney general</ENAMEX> under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX>, scoffs at
the notion that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services</ENAMEX> is just another government
handout.
"I think many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> think of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services</ENAMEX> as something
charitable," he said. "The purpose of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services</ENAMEX> is not to give
something to the poor other than the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice</ENAMEX> that every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> is
entitled to."
Does <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeFabrizio</ENAMEX> believe his documentary will help convince
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of the need for the kind of help offered by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Services</ENAMEX>?
"You hope that the public cares," he said. "Civilization really
depends on human beings caring about other human beings."




