



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Associated</ENAMEX> Press

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX> requests filing surcharge to fund legal aid for
poor
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 15, 2003</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OLYMPIA</ENAMEX> (AP) - <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Washington Supreme Court</ENAMEX> is asking the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legislature</ENAMEX> to approve a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$90 surcharge</NUMEX> on a court filing fee to
help provide legal help for the poor in civil cases, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief Justice</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerry Alexander</ENAMEX> said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>.
"Some might say, why should we support this when we face tough
financial times?" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander</ENAMEX> asked in his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State of the Judiciary</ENAMEX>
address to a joint session of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legislature</ENAMEX>. "It seems to me in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, where we rejoice in the fact that we are a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> devoted
to the rule of law, we should not ration access to justice."
The recommendation comes from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Task Force on Civil</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Equal Justice Funding</ENAMEX>, created in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX> to look for ways to cope
with the sparse amount of money available for such cases. As the
task <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> was studying the issue, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$900,000</NUMEX> was cut from state
support for civil equal justice services.
That prompted the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> main legal services <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX> -
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia Legal Services</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northwest Justice Project</ENAMEX> - to cut
their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffs</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander</ENAMEX> said.
The change would increase the cost of filing a lawsuit in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Superior Court</ENAMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$200</NUMEX>. The total fee would be split, with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">54</NUMEX>
percent going to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">counties</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">46 percent</NUMEX> going to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> for a
newly created equal justice account.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander</ENAMEX> also requested money for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> additional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Superior</ENAMEX>
Court judgeships and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> additional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">District Court</ENAMEX> judgeships,
arguing that increased caseloads require more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Superior Court</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">District Court</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> would be in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark County</ENAMEX>, with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Superior Court</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> added in the joint
district that serves <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Franklin counties</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> each in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kittitas</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kitsap</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">counties</ENAMEX>.




