



Kiosks for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> forms work well, study says
System to help the uninitiated fill out minor paperwork could go
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">statewide</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> says.
May <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23, 2002</TIMEX>

By <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">COURTNEY</ENAMEX> PERKES
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Orange County Register</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roberta Adams</ENAMEX> skipped the thick how-to guide on child-custody
forms and sat down at a computer at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lamoreaux Justice Center</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Orange</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Garden Grove</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> answered a series of questions to create
and print a form to file with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>.
"It's easy," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adams</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25</TIMEX>. "I thought I'd have all kinds of
questions and have to take the forms home."
A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of California</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Irvine</ENAMEX>, study released <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>
found an interactive computer system effectively helps <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> fill
out paperwork for restraining orders, eviction defense,
small-claims cases and requests for filing-fee waivers. Not only
does the system make life easier for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who can't afford a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>, but it also might improve efficiency in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> because
the forms, which are printed out when completed, are easy to read
and are being filled out correctly, the study found.
Since the program started in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 6,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have
used the free system, located in public <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> throughout <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Orange</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">County</ENAMEX>.
The system was developed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid Society of Orange</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">County</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $800,000</NUMEX> in grants. The program avoids legal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">jargon</ENAMEX>, offers a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courthouse</ENAMEX> video tour and sticks to a fifth-grade
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vocabulary</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Users</ENAMEX> can choose <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Vietnamese</ENAMEX>.
Kiosks are in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courthouses</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fullerton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Orange</ENAMEX>, the district
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>-support <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid Society</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ana</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irvine City Hall</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Juan Capistrano Library</ENAMEX>. The
program is also available online.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Cohen</ENAMEX>, executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid</ENAMEX>, said the study
should clear the way for expansion throughout <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>. Locally,
a program for divorce petitions will be added <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this summer</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cohen</ENAMEX> said the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">system</ENAMEX> proves the benefit of technology tailored
to those who aren't computer-savvy. He said much of the technology
now available requires Internet skills and access. Low-income
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, however, have less access to computers and less experience
using them.
"Our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> have to catch up, and they have to become a part of
the mainstream," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cohen</ENAMEX> said.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bonnie Hough</ENAMEX>, supervising <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">California Judicial</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX>, said the system in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Orange County</ENAMEX> is one
of the best in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> because it is comprehensive and easy to
follow.
"The way the program works is it asks you questions rather than
giving you a form," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hough</ENAMEX> said. "A lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are just
intimidated by forms, whether they're easy or not. Think of all the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">H&R Block</ENAMEX> for a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1040</TIMEX> EZ."
Family support <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Commissioner</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salvador Sarmiento</ENAMEX> said he's noticed
the quality of documents filed with help from the computer
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">kiosks</ENAMEX>.
"A large percentage of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that come before me do not
have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarmiento</ENAMEX> said. "Anything that can assist them in
preparation for their hearing is much appreciated."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wendy Maloney</ENAMEX> spent <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nearly an hour</TIMEX> filling out a request for a
restraining order on the computer in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Orange</ENAMEX>. She wore headphones to
listen to instructions and also read them on the screen.
"You're going through domestic violence and you're going to be
nervous with that kind of paperwork, and you want to do it right,"
she said.




