



Law-school grads balking at low-pay jobs
Enormous college loans behind legal-aid snub

<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom McGhee</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 8, 2003</TIMEX>
Law school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduates</ENAMEX> paying back <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$80,000</NUMEX> and more in college
loans are reluctant to seek low-paying jobs representing the poor,
legal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> say.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Students</ENAMEX> leaving law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> earn <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> salaries as low as
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25,000</NUMEX> working for government public-service <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>, while
those who land jobs with top-ranked law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> make <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$80,000</NUMEX> a year
or more.
Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduates</ENAMEX> who take jobs with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Colorado Legal Services</ENAMEX>, which
handles housing and other civil disputes for the poor, pay up to
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$800</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX> on student loans, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Asher</ENAMEX>, executive
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> pays newly graduated lawyers <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$31,736</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Denver</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$24,911</NUMEX> elsewhere in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>.
Top <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Denver</ENAMEX> and elsewhere pay <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">first-year</TIMEX> associates
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$80,000 to $125,000</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>.
Galloping tuition payments have reduced the pool of applicants
for legal aid and other public service jobs, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Asher</ENAMEX> said.
Nationally, law school tuition doubled <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 1991 and 2001</TIMEX>,
according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Association for Law Placement</ENAMEX>, based in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>
'A significant number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have said that for them the
pressure of student loans eliminates their options and choices,'
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Asher</ENAMEX> said.
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Sixty-six percent</NUMEX> of law <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> surveyed nationally in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>
said that debt kept them from considering a job with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> like
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Colorado Legal Services</ENAMEX>, said a study by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Association</ENAMEX>
for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Law Placement</ENAMEX>. And <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">68 percent</NUMEX> of public-interest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX>
reported difficulty in recruiting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX>.
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>, median private law school tuition was <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $23,000</NUMEX> a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>, according to the study.
The average law school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduate</ENAMEX> carries debt of more than
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$84,000</NUMEX>. That doesn't include debt racked up on undergraduate
work.
It is a source of frustration, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Libby DeBlasio</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Denver</ENAMEX> law <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX>. 'It's kind of a joke among a lot of us who
want to do public interest law. We say, 'Yeah, this is what I want
to do, but I may have to work in a private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> and be a drone for
a while."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer Knight</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Colorado Legal Services</ENAMEX> who
handles housing and other civil cases for the poor, is paying off
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">roughly $80,000</NUMEX> in loans. And she received a scholarship that paid
half her tuition at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northeastern University</ENAMEX>'s law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Knight</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">31</TIMEX>, is a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> who grew up in a low-income
housing development. When she was still in high school, she decided
she wanted to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> and work with the poor.
Many of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Knight</ENAMEX>'s fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minority</ENAMEX> law <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> also were
interested in public service, she said. But most went into private
practice.
'A lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> I went to law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> with were fired up about
public practice, but they had more debt than I did,' she said.
At the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s largest law school, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Denver</ENAMEX>,
tuition climbed from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $15,000 to $23,994</NUMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past 10</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>.
By comparison, tuition at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Colorado Law School</ENAMEX>
at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boulder</ENAMEX> is much lower for state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> - <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6,754</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>. Out-
of-state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> pay <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$21,252</NUMEX>.
So far, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Asher</ENAMEX> said, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Colorado Legal Services</ENAMEX> has been able to
attract the talent it needs.
The state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public Defender</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> - where new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> make
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$43,536</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> - also continues to attract good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>, said
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frances Smylie Brown</ENAMEX>, chief <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">deputy</ENAMEX>.
But in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last several years</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> widened its search for
potential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hires</ENAMEX>, reaching outside the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time in
its history.
'We don't have a large enough pool of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">applicants</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Denver</ENAMEX>
openings we have <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each year</TIMEX>,' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smylie Brown</ENAMEX> said. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DU</ENAMEX> has a law-
student <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 1,000</NUMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CU</ENAMEX>'s population is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about half</NUMEX>
that.
Population growth and a corresponding increase in crime are
primarily responsible for the dwindling number of local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>,
but interest is also waning, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smylie Brown</ENAMEX> said.




