



<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huss Grad</ENAMEX> Earns <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Law Award</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">College</ENAMEX>

By <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erin Elizabeth Walker</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gazette Correspondent</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PRINCETON</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">W.Va.</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cathy Wallace</ENAMEX> did not always know what she
wanted to be when she grew up.
She wanted to help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, but did not know exactly how. A
suggestion from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> sparked her interest.
"When I was in college, I thought I wanted to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX>," she
said. "I found I didn't want to do that and realized an interest in
psychology. I didn't know what I wanted to do, but all my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>
thought I should go into law because I was always on a soapbox. I
decided to try it."
Recently, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wallace</ENAMEX> received the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Outstanding Woman Lawyer</ENAMEX> in
Public Interest <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Law Award</ENAMEX>. The award was voted on and presented by
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s caucus of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Virginia</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University College of Law</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wallace</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">38</TIMEX>, called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Gastonia</ENAMEX> home from the age of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> until she
graduated from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hunter Huss High School</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1983</TIMEX>. Her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carter</ENAMEX>
Bond, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">66</TIMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carol Bond</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">59</TIMEX>, are still <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gastonia</ENAMEX>.
From <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hunter Huss</ENAMEX>, she moved on to pursue a degree at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pfeiffer</ENAMEX>
University in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Misenheimer</ENAMEX>.
After graduation from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pfeiffer</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX> with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bachelor</ENAMEX>'s degree
in both biology and psychology, she worked as legal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louis A. Bledsoe Jr.</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year and a half</TIMEX>.
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Working</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louis Bledsoe</ENAMEX> was a pivotal moment," she said.
"That was when I decided to go into the practice of law."
She received her law degree at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Arkansas</ENAMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> and began her legal career in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public Defender Corp.</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Princeton</ENAMEX>. She also taught criminal justice <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classes</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bluefield</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">College</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Virginia</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wallace</ENAMEX> lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Athens</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">W. Va.</ENAMEX>, with her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rob</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37</TIMEX>, and
her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rachel</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Claire</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>.
Working in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Princeton</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Virginia</ENAMEX>, she is also
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Junior Girl Scout leader</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Athens</ENAMEX>, on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Advisors</ENAMEX> for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Children</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Home Society</ENAMEX> and on several <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committees</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Concord</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Methodist Church</ENAMEX>.
Legal Aid of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Virginia</ENAMEX> provides civil legal services and
advocacy to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Virginia</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> is the
result of a merger between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Appalachian Legal Services</ENAMEX> and the West
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Virginia Legal Services Plan</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wallace</ENAMEX> worked with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joyce McConnell</ENAMEX>, associate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dean</ENAMEX> for academic
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">affairs</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Virginia</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University College of Law</ENAMEX>, to set up a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kellogg Grant</ENAMEX> internship for law <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WVU</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>.
"The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> can go down into the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">counties</ENAMEX> and help domestic
violence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wallace</ENAMEX> said. They hold workshops for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SAFE</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stop Abusive Family Environment</ENAMEX>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wallace</ENAMEX> helped to implement and supervise. McConnell spearheaded
writing the grant. They came up with the interns themselves and set
up guidelines for the internship.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adrian Worthy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Virginia</ENAMEX>, has known
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wallace</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>.
"She is very committed to her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> who are both low income
and have troubling domestic problems," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Worthy</ENAMEX> said. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cathy</ENAMEX> is very
passionate about their concerns. She's good at looking at the big
picture. She's responsible for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> and she looks at how to
deliver as many services to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">as many</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> as possible."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wallace</ENAMEX>'s commitment has been acknowledged. She was promoted in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX> to regional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX>. She manages legal services for
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">approximately</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">counties</ENAMEX> south of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charleston</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">W. Va.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wallace</ENAMEX> has enjoyed all of her work experience.
"This job gives me the opportunity to help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>," she said. "I
go home feeling satisfied with my job."
Her mother sees <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wallace</ENAMEX>'s job as simply a manifestation of who
she has always been.
"She's not just good at what she does, but she's also helping
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carol Bond</ENAMEX> said. "She's always been concerned with helping
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. That's just her nature."




