



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>

Law <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Schools Urge Graduates to Start Small and Think Local</ENAMEX>
By <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg Winter</ENAMEX>

<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 16, 2002</TIMEX>
Life for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partners</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cates</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katalinic & Lund</ENAMEX> holds
little of the glamour one might expect from a career in law.
Instead of lunches at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lutèce</ENAMEX>, they caucus at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Palace Diner</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Queens</ENAMEX>. Wooing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> means passing out <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fliers</ENAMEX> on street <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">corners</ENAMEX>,
not securing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">box seats</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Madison Square Garden</ENAMEX>. To make ends meet,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> stacks pipe and cleans the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">yard</ENAMEX> at a plumbing
warehouse. Another handles urine samples in a hospital <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lab</ENAMEX>. A sign
of failure, of a feeble economy, perhaps? Hardly. They are heeding
the call of a growing pool of law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>, which are for the first
time pointing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduates</ENAMEX> in a new direction and teaching them how to
get there. Forget the lure of large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX>, the security of a
government post. Here is how to grapple "in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">justice</ENAMEX>," as many of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> put it, instead.
Convinced that corporate largess and government programs barely
dent the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s legal needs, the law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> are urging graduates
to buck tradition, pass up big salaries and ignore mushrooming
student debt to join tiny neighborhood practices or simply start
their own, all with an eye toward charging no more than their
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> can afford.
This is not pro bono legal work; it is "low bono," a term the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> coined to define the atypical kind of law career they are
training <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> for. While its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">practitioners</ENAMEX> do charge for their
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">services</ENAMEX>, they are also dead set on turning no one away - or at
least as few as possible.
"When you go into this kind of social justice law, it's really
brutal and you're almost guaranteed to struggle for a couple of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> before there's a light at the end of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tunnel</ENAMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred</ENAMEX>
Rooney, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community Legal Resource Network</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of New York School of Law</ENAMEX>, from which the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> of the
newly formed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cates</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katalinic & Lund</ENAMEX> graduated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last May</TIMEX>. "But
if our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduates</ENAMEX> don't do it, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who cannot
access <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice</ENAMEX> in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> will continue to soar."
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">movement</ENAMEX>, primly called the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">consortium</ENAMEX>, started <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ago</TIMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CUNY</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northeastern University</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Maryland</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Mary's Law School</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Mary's</ENAMEX> later dropped out.)
Since then, it has drawn <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> additional law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> to its ranks:
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Michigan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rutgers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Syracuse Law Schools</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Law School</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of New Mexico School of Law</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas M.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cooley Law School and Touro Law School</ENAMEX>. It has elicited at least
initial interest from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19</NUMEX> more. Mixing foundation money with their
own to go beyond the standard curriculum, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> are teaching
the nuts and bolts of running a business, setting up client
referral <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX> for fledgling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">practitioners</ENAMEX> and holding seminars
to tackle the mundane cha llenges of going it alone that are often
considered superfluous to the study of law.
As further encouragement for the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200 or so</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">followers</ENAMEX> they have
picked up already, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">consortium schools</ENAMEX> have given their
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">graduates Palm</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">organizers</ENAMEX>, paid for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> to help with their
billing, and offered free legal research and even yoga and
meditation classes, almost anything to help make life a little
easier for those trying to hang out their shingles.
"We're talking about training real community <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stua</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rt L. Deutsch</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dean</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rutgers School of Law</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Newark</ENAMEX>. "The
perception is that the solo <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">practitioners</ENAMEX> are the ones who got C's,
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> string who didn't excel enough to get to the big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX>.
We're trying to say that solo practice can be among the highest
forms of public service, and is the only channel possible to
serving low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>."
True or not, there is little debate that most low-income
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>, and many in the middle class, find <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> well outside
their financial reach. Even at the smallest of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX>, the median
hourly rate starts at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">roughly $130</NUMEX> an hour and passes <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$180</NUMEX>,
according to a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX> survey by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Altman Weil</ENAMEX>, a legal consulting
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>. For <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 150</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> in tow, the range is
from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$200</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $320</NUMEX> an hour, the survey found, not counting
the dinners, taxi rides and other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">extras</ENAMEX> that are often tacked onto
the bill.
At those rates, perhaps it should come as no surprise that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">71</NUMEX>
percent of low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">61 percent</NUMEX> of moderate-income
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with civil troub les end up without representation,
according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Bar Association</ENAMEX>. For the truly poor,
meaning they earn <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">no more than $11,075</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>, there are
government-financed legal aid <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> to turn to, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">172</NUMEX> in all, but
these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> are so overwhelmed that only one in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who
qualify for help actually gets any.
By contrast, big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">law firms</ENAMEX> are slowly stepping up their
commitment to free services, after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 years</TIMEX> of pulling back. Yet
their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> still spend <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">less than 42 hours</TIMEX> a year doing pro bono
work, far short of the profession's guidelines to perform at least
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">50 volunteer hours</TIMEX> each year. Even during more charitable times,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar association</ENAMEX> says, most of the free or less costly work is
handled by small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> and solo <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">practitioners</ENAMEX>, making the m a
natural target for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">consortium</ENAMEX>'s sights.
"A lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> still go to law school because of their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ideals</ENAMEX>, and they're willing to bite the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bullet</ENAMEX>, drive old <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>, not
buy a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> and keep living a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX>'s life for a few more years
until they get settled," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lovely Dhillon</ENAMEX>, the former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">San</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francisco</ENAMEX> assistant district <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> who heads the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">consortium</ENAMEX>.
"It's incumbent on us to help them."
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">consortium</ENAMEX> certainly has a lot to overcome, most notably the
pull of big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">law firms</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Twenty years ago</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times as many law
school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduates</ENAMEX> went into solo or tiny practices as went to firms
with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 100</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>, according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Association</ENAMEX>
for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Law Placement</ENAMEX>. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>, the two poles had flip-flopped,
with the biggest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> attracting <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">30 percent</NUMEX> more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduates</ENAMEX> than
the smallest, and given the difference in pay it is not hard to see
why.
Joining a firm with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fewer than 10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> means starting at
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$43,000</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">association</ENAMEX> says. The bigger a practice gets,
though, the higher its starting salaries climb, topping out around
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$125,000</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> at the largest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX>. Considering that law school
tuitions have roughly doubled in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last decade</TIMEX>, pushing the
median student debt past <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$84,000</NUMEX>, it is understandable why some
question how far the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">consortium</ENAMEX> can spread.
"It's a great idea, but the pressure of academic debt really
leads <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> in big <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Theresa J. Bryant</ENAMEX>,
executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of the career development <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale Law</ENAMEX>
School, which is not part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">consortium</ENAMEX>. "When you're standing
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$90,000</NUMEX> in debt, going small may present a bit of a challenge."
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fair</ENAMEX> enough, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">consortium</ENAMEX> says. Not all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduates</ENAMEX> will be able
to scrounge for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> it may take to build a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clientele</ENAMEX>, nor
should they. But since <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">as many as 30 percent to 40 percent</NUMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduates</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CUNY</ENAMEX> go into small or solo practices
within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years</TIMEX> of graduating, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">deans</ENAMEX> argue, it seems folly
not to teach them how to stay afloat financially and take on
low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> at the same time.
How do you advertise? How do you bill <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> and, perhaps even
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">trickier</ENAMEX>, get them to pay? How can you remain affordable and still
pay your rent? What kind of office software will you need? How
about malpractice insurance? Such are the sobering questions,
rarely highbrow enough to find their way into legal pedagogy, that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">consortium</ENAMEX> seeks to help their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduates tackle</ENAMEX>.
"Important as they are, these issues are low on the academic
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pecking</ENAMEX> order, and not what get most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faculty</ENAMEX> recognized," said
Law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Schools</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> of law at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stanford University</ENAMEX>, also
outside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">consortium</ENAMEX>. "The truth is, legal education is partially
responsible for the disconnect between what ordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> need
and what educated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> can supply."
Even for the most intrepid and socially conscious of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduates</ENAMEX>,
starting a practice requires a giant leap of faith, and more than a
little guesswork. Charging sliding-scale fees means coming up with
a new wage for almost every case one takes, and seldom can
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">practitioners</ENAMEX> rely on anything more solid than their own
judgment.
"How much will we charge?" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tristan Da Cunha</ENAMEX>, one of the new
graduates starting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cates</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katalinic & Lund</ENAMEX> asked with a shrug,
furrowing his brow as if the question had never come up. "I think
it's fair to say we'll be heavily discounted.





