



Legal Aid looks to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">legislators</ENAMEX> for help

By <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robyn L. Minor</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday, January 26, 2003</TIMEX>
Still stinging from federal grant cuts, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kentucky Legal Aid</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> is hoping the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Assembly</ENAMEX> will help heal the
wounds.
"We found a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sponsor</ENAMEX> for legislation," <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott Crocker</ENAMEX>
said. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Geveden</ENAMEX> has introduced legislation that will
increase the Access to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX> supplement on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> filing
fees."
The legislation would increase that supplement on filing civil
cases from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5 to $10</NUMEX> in district <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> and from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10 to $20</NUMEX> in
circuit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX>. Basic filing fees would then be <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$55.50</NUMEX> in district
court and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$118</NUMEX> in circuit.
The Access to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX> fees are sent to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundation</ENAMEX> that
provides money to legal aid <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bowling Green</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kentucky Legal Aid</ENAMEX>. That <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> provides legal aid in non-criminal
cases to low-income, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elderly</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">disabled residents</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">35</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">counties</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kentucky Bar Association</ENAMEX> is supporting the legislation.
"They felt the additional filing fee would not prevent people
from being able to file lawsuits," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crocker</ENAMEX> said.
In fact, the additional fees will ensure wider access to the
judicial system for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kentucky</ENAMEX>'s poor, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Geveden</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wickliffe</ENAMEX>.
"I was pleased to (sponsor the legislation) because it will
provide access to legal services to the poor and underprivileged in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kentucky</ENAMEX> that otherwise would have been denied them because of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">federal</ENAMEX> budget cuts and because of some reduction in funds because
of state budget," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Geveden</ENAMEX> said.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Statewide</ENAMEX>, legal aid budgets were cut <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.58 million</NUMEX>. The
proposed legislation is expected to generate <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $1.5</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">million</ENAMEX>.
Because of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $300,000</NUMEX> in cuts, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kentucky Legal Aid</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bowling</ENAMEX>
Green is in the process of closing its <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hopkinsville</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> and
already has closed and consolidated others.
A total of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> full-time positions and one part-time position,
including <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> and secretarial or clerical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">positions</ENAMEX>, were
eliminated.
If legislation passes and more funding comes in, cuts in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">services</ENAMEX> would be re-evaluated.
The Access to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX> money is distributed to legal aid <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>
based on a poverty population formula. <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">About 21 percent</NUMEX> of the fees
would come to this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kentucky Legal Aid</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crocker</ENAMEX> said.
"We have bipartisan support on this issue and it isn't a tax
increase," he said. "... There is no one actively lobbying against
it, so we hope it would pass."
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Geveden</ENAMEX> agrees that the bill's chances for passage "are pretty
reasonable."
And while he is pleased to have the endorsement of the bar
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">association</ENAMEX> and others, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Geveden</ENAMEX> said, "The best endorsements come
from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> at home.
"And I think ... they are doing a good job having people
contacting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">legislators</ENAMEX> to encourage their support."
To track the proposed legislation - <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HB</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">163</NUMEX> - visit the Web site
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">lrc</ENAMEX>.state.ky.us. To leave a message for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">legislator</ENAMEX> in support
of the proposal, call (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">800</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">372-7181</ENAMEX>.




