



Newsmaker: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal</ENAMEX>-aid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX> loves challenges
BY <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">JULIE ANDERSON</ENAMEX>
WORLD-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HERALD STAFF WRITER</ENAMEX>
Taking charge of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nebraska</ENAMEX>'s statewide legal-aid law firm fit
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doug German</ENAMEX>'s beliefs in treating everyone fairly and holding those
in power accountable.

It also fit with his
history of taking on new challenges.
Over his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nearly 60 years</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eustis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Neb.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> has served
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace Corps</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colombia</ENAMEX> and worked as an advance <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> during
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert F. Kennedy</ENAMEX>'s run for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> bought into a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farm</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Costa Rica</ENAMEX> and later adopted
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> from that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. And during a short career as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cornhusker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX>, he shooed a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Osborne</ENAMEX> off a
practice <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">field</ENAMEX>.
But after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a quarter century</TIMEX> in private practice, he
resigned in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 2000</TIMEX> and became executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nebraska</ENAMEX>
Legal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Services</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> had just been created through the merger of three
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">groups</ENAMEX>: the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid Society</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Omaha</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services of Southeast</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nebraska</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Western Legal Services</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Grand Island</ENAMEX>.
Since then, he's logged <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">60,000 miles</NUMEX> between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eustis</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>'s
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> across the state and thrown himself into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>'s
effort to see that as many low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nebraskans</ENAMEX> as possible get
legal help.
Right now, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nebraska Legal Services</ENAMEX>, which handles <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 95</NUMEX>
percent of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s legal-aid cases, figures it reaches <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 15</NUMEX>
percent of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">211,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nebraskans</ENAMEX> eligible by income for its
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">services</ENAMEX>. That's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 8,500</NUMEX> cases a year.
Most of the cases involve family law - from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> abuse and
neglect matters to landlord-tenant disputes. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> does not
handle criminal cases.
Based on an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Bar Association</ENAMEX> formula, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> estimates
that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nebraska</ENAMEX>'s low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> will be involved in about
65,000 significant legal matters <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>.
Those who can't afford access to the criminal justice system may
lose hope or take matters into their own hands, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> said.
"I have a fear that we have a generation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are
coming up not believing in the system," <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> said. "That's going
to spell problems."
Originally, most legal-aid work was funded by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> through
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services Corp.</ENAMEX> With cuts in federal funding, local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX>
have been pressed to raise more money.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX> funding will make up <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.53 million</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nebraska</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3.9 million</NUMEX> budget <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>. The rest will come from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nebraska Commission on Public Advocacy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nebraska</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>' trust
accounts, individual donations, grants and contracts.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric Kleiman</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services Corp.</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>, said <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> has been out front nationally in
raising funds and in using new technology, including a statewide
Web site.
"The best program <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> are the ones that are
able to adjust to the reality of the time," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kleiman</ENAMEX> said.
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> came to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nebraska Legal Services</ENAMEX> with a goal of doubling
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>'s capacity to serve. That means raising <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">an additional $2.5</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> step toward that goal was a recent pledge by some of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">state</ENAMEX>'s leading <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> to raise <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">up to $1 million</NUMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> over
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next three years</TIMEX>. Other campaigns are under way.
In addition, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nebraska Legal Services</ENAMEX> is involved in a committee
developing a statewide plan for expanding legal services for
low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX>.
The legal profession, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> said, has an obligation to provide
access to the justice system because it has taken on the role of
gateway to that system.
In a sense, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">German</ENAMEX>'s new job isn't far from where he started
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades ago</TIMEX>.
After finishing high school in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cozad</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Neb.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> went off to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Nebraska-Lincoln</ENAMEX>. As a sophomore, the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">6-foot-1</NUMEX>,
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">160-pound</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">quarterback</ENAMEX> joined the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">freshman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX>. It was
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1961</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Devaney</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">One day</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> was out throwing passes at an early practice.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> often dropped by asking to run a few plays. One was a skinny
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">redhead</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> agreed but told the redhead he'd better get out of there
when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">linemen</ENAMEX> came out. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Two weeks later</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Osborne</ENAMEX>, then a
graduate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assistant</ENAMEX>, was one of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coaches</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German's</ENAMEX> football
career was short - he admits he was outclassed - but he still has a
copy of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Devaney</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> playbook.
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> graduated with a mechanical engineering degree in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1965</TIMEX>,
then joined the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace Corps</ENAMEX>, spending <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colombia</ENAMEX>.
Back in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nebraska</ENAMEX>, he helped organize part of a whistlestop tour
from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cheyenne</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wyo.</ENAMEX>, across <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nebraska</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Kennedy</ENAMEX>
campaign. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A few weeks later</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> was assassinated in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> moved on to simultaneously earn a law degree from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UNL</ENAMEX> and
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX>'s degree in regional planning from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX>. He worked for a legal-aid <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> and briefly
ran a legal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clinic</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>. Then he went into private
practice in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cozad</ENAMEX>.
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1979</TIMEX>, he stopped at a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lexington</ENAMEX> clothing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> to buy cowboy
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">boots</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> persuaded him to see a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farm</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Costa Rica</ENAMEX>,
mostly as a fun trip.
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partners</ENAMEX> still own the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">60-acre</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farm</ENAMEX>. He and his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Connie Koch</ENAMEX>, own the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jose Bravo Coffee Co.</ENAMEX>, which buys and
markets part of the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">40,000 pounds</NUMEX> of environmentally friendly
coffee the farm produces <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each year</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Koch</ENAMEX> owns the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Eustis Pool Hall</ENAMEX>, a local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">landmark</ENAMEX> and restaurant,
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hotel Eustis</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Koch</ENAMEX> adopted <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Costa Rica</ENAMEX> not long
after their marriage in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985</TIMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Years before</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colombia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> had
looked into the eyes of poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and told himself he'd help if
he was ever in a position to do so.
The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> oldest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> are married and have their own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>.
The youngest attends classes and is a standout point <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guard</ENAMEX> at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eustis-Farnam High School</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> knows, because he goes to her
games.
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX>, who also plays <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX>, wants to make sure his new
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> have an opportunity for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> time while doing
good work.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> is driven by reasons other than money, he said, and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> employs some of the area's best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> in their
fields.
"We will be known, if we're not already, as an outstanding law
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>."



