



The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star-Ledger Newark</ENAMEX>

Survey: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal</ENAMEX> system fails poor - Most don't know how to find a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>, or think they can't afford one
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kate Coscarelli</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday, October 27, 2002</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Each year</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than one-third</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX>'s poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> -
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 400,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> - have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> civil legal problem
such as a dispute with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">landlord</ENAMEX>, a divorce or bankruptcy. But
fewer than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> get help from a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>, according to a
survey.
Many of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't seek a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>'s help because they
think they cannot afford it, think the problem is not important
enough or think nothing can be done about the problem.
Complicating the situation is that many of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't
know where to find a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>.
These findings are part of a survey, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of its kind in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">almost 20 years</TIMEX> to examine the experiences of the poor in the legal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">system</ENAMEX>, released <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> by the nonprofit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services of New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jersey</ENAMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Edison</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporation</ENAMEX> that coordinates the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s system
of legal aid <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> has a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$38.5 million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> budget that comes mainly
from state appropriations and the interest from the trust accounts
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> maintain for their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>' funds.
The findings should put the legal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> on notice that more
needs to be done because the problem is only going to get worse,
said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melville Miller</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services</ENAMEX>.
"The enormous legal assistance gap cannot be tolerated by a just
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">society</ENAMEX>, by a society that asks <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to be governed by the rule
of law," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miller</ENAMEX>. "A key part of that is the notion of equal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice</ENAMEX> and equal access to the court system. If, in fact, you
don't have equal access then we don't have equal justice."
Among the other survey findings:
ugh few of those surveyed were able to get legal help, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 71</NUMEX>
percent believe the court system is a fair place to resolve
disputes, and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">roughly 61 percent</NUMEX> believe the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> and legal
system help make society safe.
The most common type of legal problem had to do with housing.
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">About 20 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> had problems such as poorly maintained
rental property or disputes with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">landlord</ENAMEX> or utility <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">About 18 percent</NUMEX> had consumer-related issues. Among the claims
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> cited included being denied credit and problems
regarding taxes or bankruptcy.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> who are younger, employed, responsible for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> or
living in rental housing are more likely to experience at least one
problem <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each year</TIMEX>.
The survey relied on telephone interviews with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,013</NUMEX> randomly
selected <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX>- and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX>- speaking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> in all <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">counties</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between July</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>. Each of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">participants</ENAMEX>
lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at least one year</TIMEX> and earned an annual
of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>, the limit for legal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX> would be <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$36,200</NUMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> of limited financial means can find themselves in an
unstable situation when faced with legal problems, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jon Dubin</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of clinical programs at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rutgers University Law School</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Newark</ENAMEX>.
"It is a very precarious existence if you are living on a low
income and you barely have enough for anything else except for food
or clothing, and then all of a sudden there is an additional demand
on you based on some legal matter - that throws everything off. Now
you are facing the prospects of homelessness, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">malnutrition</ENAMEX> and
worse," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dubin</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Caroline Grant</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">74</TIMEX>, wanted to get a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> to fight the traffic
ticket she was given for running a stop sign after getting into an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">accident</ENAMEX> recently. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ocean County</ENAMEX> resident
- who has a bad heart and supports her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> on a
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$404</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">monthly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> check - couldn't afford <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>.
"They wanted a lot of money that I just didn't have. So, I went
to court by myself and told them the truth, but it didn't do me any
good. I still had to pay the ticket . . . I just figure if you are
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rich</ENAMEX> you can afford a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>, if you are poor you take what you
get," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grant</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">resident</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mayetta</ENAMEX> section of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Stafford</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Township</ENAMEX>.
Based on the current resources, the gap is unlikely to be closed
anytime soon, the study found.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorneys</ENAMEX> working for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services</ENAMEX> help <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 50,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>. And <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clinics</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and other
nonprofit legal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> help <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10,000</NUMEX> more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>. There
are no reliable numbers to determine how many cases are handled by
private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> for free, but those contributions are minor.
Around the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, the picture is similarly bleak, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William</ENAMEX>
Hornsby, staff <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Bar Association</ENAMEX>'s division
for legal services. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABA</ENAMEX> has conducted similar studies that
support the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX> findings. The most recent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABA</ENAMEX> survey was
released in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> which found <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 20 percent</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s poor
who need a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>'s help can find one.
"The challenge is for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> with their own case to find
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> who is most appropriate," he said. "The challenge for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> to have outreach in ways that are
effective and reach those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>."
Elsewhere, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> have come up with innovative ways
to reach <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in need of legal help. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Monica</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX>,
local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> opened a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Grind</ENAMEX>, where for
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $20</NUMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> can get a cup of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX> and a consultation with
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore</ENAMEX> area, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Maryland</ENAMEX> created
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Civil Justice Network</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">consortium</ENAMEX> of solo and small law firm
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> who want to do public interest work. And in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX>, one <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beckman & Hirsch</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Burlington</ENAMEX>, offers an online program that
leads <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> through a series of questions to create a will.
In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX>, outreach efforts are limited.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Somerset County</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapter</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Civil Liberties</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union</ENAMEX> holds a free legal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clinic</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the second Thursday</TIMEX> of every
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">month</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">About 10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> attend the meetings in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">atrium</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">county</ENAMEX>'s administration <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>. Each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> talks over their
problem with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alisa Mariani</ENAMEX>, vice chair of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">chapter</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Organizers</ENAMEX> try to get the word out as best as they can but they
realize the program doesn't fill the void, she said.
"We make it clear that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> cannot take a case, they are
just there to give them some initial direction about whether they
have a good case," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mariani</ENAMEX>.
Court <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> include the phone numbers of the local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal</ENAMEX>
Services <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">county</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> referral system on every summons.
They also created a packet of information available for free to
help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> navigate the court system without a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>. While court
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> are concerned about the findings, their assistance can
only go so far, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Winnie Comfort</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokeswoman</ENAMEX> for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Administrative Office</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Courts</ENAMEX>.
"The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> does what it can and it is important that the court
remain a fair and neutral ground," she said.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Leaders</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Bar Association</ENAMEX> called the gap
revealed by the survey "overwhelming" and said it provides hard
facts the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX> can examine to find more ways to help low-income
residents get <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX>.
"Clearly, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't know how to reach <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>. Such services
should be better publicized, they should be better promoted," said
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harold Rubenstein</ENAMEX>, executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar association</ENAMEX>. "It's
the beginning of looking to see how you meet those needs."




