



Legal hotline for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">seniors</ENAMEX> loses grant, won't expand

By <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy Weaver Teichert</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, January 25, 2003</TIMEX>
The loss of a federal grant has stymied plans for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senior</ENAMEX>
Legal Hotline to expand its free legal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX> statewide.
The hotline lost out on a grant from the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Administration</ENAMEX>
on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aging</ENAMEX>, which would have provided <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$175,000</NUMEX> a year for the next
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Mandel</ENAMEX>, supervising <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX>, protested to federal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> about the way the hotline's grant application had been
evaluated. He said a package of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> letters of support failed to
reach some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX>.
The hotline, which is part of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services of Northern</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, was the only <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">California</ENAMEX> application from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX> submitted
nationwide for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.5 million</NUMEX> in grants. "It was because of a
screw-up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> is losing having a program
like this," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mandel</ENAMEX>. "Other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> got it instead."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kay Loughrey</ENAMEX>, a program information <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">specialist</ENAMEX> with the aging
administration, said grant applications were ranked a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> time
after the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> got a chance to review the letters. "They went
above and beyond what would be customarily done," she said. "They
still did not rank high enough to be selected."
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mandel</ENAMEX> said the loss means the hotline won't continue with plans
to expand statewide and won't be able to serve as many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern California</ENAMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">About two</NUMEX> full-time staff positions will be lost along with
other cuts in staff <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 7,200</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were given
quick legal advice over the telephone and by email, but that number
may drop by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,000 to 2,000</NUMEX> with the staff cuts <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>, Mandel
said.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chisorom Okwuosa</ENAMEX>, legal services <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">developer</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Department</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aging</ENAMEX>, said state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> supported the hotline's
grant application. The service is needed but the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s budget
crisis means it is not in a position to step in and help. "There is
a need to expand legal services as a whole," she said.
The hotline will emphasize help to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sacramento County</ENAMEX> seniors
with funds provided by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Area 4 Agency</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Aging</ENAMEX>. It offers legal
advice on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">landlord</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tenant</ENAMEX> disputes, foreclosures, consumer
disputes and planning for long-term care, including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>
issues.
The hotline also has special funds to help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX> who are
caring for their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandchildren</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sacramento</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Placer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yuba</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sutter</ENAMEX>,
Yolo, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nevada</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sierra</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">counties</ENAMEX>. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX> need help on
custody issues.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Earlier this year</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senior Legal Services Task Force</ENAMEX>
submitted a report to the state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legislature</ENAMEX> that supported a
statewide senior legal hotline.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mandel</ENAMEX> said the hotline is searching for private foundation
funds to finance its expansion and may increase its efficiency with
a new telephone system.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senior Legal Hotline</ENAMEX> can be reached at (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">916</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">551-2140</ENAMEX> or
(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">800</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">222-1753</ENAMEX>




