



Legal Aid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> heeds call to serve

<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 30, 2002</TIMEX>

Depictions of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> pop culture are
notoriously unkind.
Whether castigating them on the silver screen, between the lines
of pulpy, true-crime narratives, or in the jokes told around the
proverbial water cooler, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> have been on the receiving end
of many a hackneyed punch line.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roseburg</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> is doing her best to refute the cultural
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">stereotype</ENAMEX>, however. Legal Aid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sharon Lee Schwartz</ENAMEX> knew
when she entered law school at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Georgetown University</ENAMEX> that she
wanted to use her training to help others.
"A reason I went to law school was to do social <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice</ENAMEX> work,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schwartz</ENAMEX> said recently. "I get paid to make the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> a better
place for vulnerable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> -- and I like that." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schwartz</ENAMEX> grew up
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.C.</ENAMEX> She earned a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bachelor</ENAMEX>'s degree in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>
literature from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Davidson College</ENAMEX> before heading to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgetown</ENAMEX> for
her law degree, where she finished in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>.
"When I was in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> I really liked <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Virginia Woolf</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schwartz</ENAMEX>
said of her nascent literary tastes. "Right now what I read is
nonfiction.
"I've been reading a lot about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buddhism</ENAMEX>," she added. "I just
sort of call it my peace studies program -- any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> that I think
has ideas (as to) how <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> can live together without killing each
other, that's what I like to read."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schwartz</ENAMEX> replaced former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lori Rubenstein</ENAMEX> at
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Roseburg</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, although she initially interviewed for
the position in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>. During that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two-year</TIMEX> interim, she worked for
Legal Aid on a reservation in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Dakota</ENAMEX> practicing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tribal</ENAMEX> and housing law. Legal Aid is a nonprofit national
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organization</ENAMEX> aimed at providing low-cost or free legal aid to those
who need it.
A <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Dakota</ENAMEX> blizzard <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six years ago</TIMEX> prompted her to call the
Roseburg <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>, which, coincidentally, was in the process of
trying to find her to fill the vacancy left by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rubenstein</ENAMEX>'s
departure.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schwartz</ENAMEX> said her job keeps her involved in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> -- and
allows her to sleep with a sound conscience.
"Just because there's so much more demand for our services than
we can actually meet, once we actually take a case we always feel
like we're on the right side," she said. For the time being,
however, both her sleep and her job may have to suffer some
periodic disturbance. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schwartz</ENAMEX> and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott Cohan</ENAMEX>,
welcomed their <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> into their lives <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sophia Clare</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cohan</ENAMEX>.
"It's wonderful," said the new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>. "I mean, it's really,
really fun."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schwartz</ENAMEX> plans to take maternity leave until <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the end of</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX>.
Rounding out the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX>'s other full-time roles as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> to
her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> and legal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ally</ENAMEX> to the poor is that of amateur <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>.
"I guess I've sold a few things," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schwartz</ENAMEX> said, but "mostly I
just make things for myself. "I just finished a stained glass
window that I've been working on for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX> ... I paint the
walls of my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all</TIMEX> different colors and patterns and things like
that."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schwartz</ENAMEX> has also tried her hand at sculpting <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">clay</ENAMEX> -- and her
welding torch at sculpting <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">steel</ENAMEX>.
"I just want to make things that are interesting to look at,"
she said. "I can't say that my art's intended to give any
particular message."
Asked how she and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> manage to juggle so many competing
demands upon their time, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schwartz</ENAMEX> replied, "we don't watch TV."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schwartz</ENAMEX> tries to limit herself to a normal <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">eight-hour</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">work day</TIMEX>,
she said, in spite of a heavy demand for indigent legal services in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX>. "I figured out early on that I could work around the
clock and still meet only a fraction of the need," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schwartz</ENAMEX>
said.




