



<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charleston Gazette</ENAMEX>

Legal Aid campaign <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> of the way to fund-raising goal

<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul J. Nyden</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 12, 2002</TIMEX>
Legal Aid of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Virginia</ENAMEX> announced <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> that it has
already raised <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$300,000</NUMEX> toward a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three-year</TIMEX> goal of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.2 million</NUMEX> to
help its work defending the rights of poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adrienne Worthy</ENAMEX>, executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid</ENAMEX>, said her
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agency</ENAMEX> will receive <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$400,000</NUMEX> less in federal funds in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX>, because
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Census</ENAMEX> found <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30,000</NUMEX> fewer poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>.
"We cannot meet our needs with previous federal funding levels,
especially since the economy has worsened since the census was
completed," she said.
Today, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Virginia</ENAMEX> has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 315,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poor people</ENAMEX>, or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX>
percent of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s entire <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Nearly one</NUMEX> of every <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> lives in a household whose
income falls below federal poverty levels. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">More than 31,000</NUMEX> elderly
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">West Virginians</ENAMEX> also live in poverty.
A pamphlet being distributed by the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Campaign</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid</ENAMEX>
points out, "There is only one Le gal Aid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> for every <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7,900</NUMEX>
poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Virginia</ENAMEX>. This compares to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX>
for every <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">368</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> in the general <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>."
The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-chairmen</ENAMEX> of the campaign are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Emch</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson Kelly</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott Segal</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Segal Law Firm</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Emch</ENAMEX> said on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, "I have a lot of confidence in lawyers
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Virginia</ENAMEX>, who are professionally responsible and understand
the importance of this project. Everyone has a stake in making our
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">justice</ENAMEX> system accessible and fair."
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Segal</ENAMEX> said raising money to help <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid</ENAMEX> is critical "to help
battered <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> transferring from welfare to jobs in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">economy</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elderly</ENAMEX>. It is important to guarantee everyone
access to justice in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>."
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid</ENAMEX> helped <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 9,500</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poor people</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Individuals</ENAMEX> helped by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid</ENAMEX> include: a young mother
and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> being abused by a violent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouse</ENAMEX>, a severely
disabled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> in need of medical care, a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who needed
more time in vocational training to escape welfare, and a woman
suffering from <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">dementia</ENAMEX> in a nursing home whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> was trying
to strip her of her financial assets.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid</ENAMEX> spent <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$387</NUMEX> for work on its average case.
The cost to provide <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">each hour</TIMEX> of legal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX> was <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$23</NUMEX>.
Legal Aid also works closely with local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">community organizations</ENAMEX>,
state and local Bar <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX>, social <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> and local
government <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Major contributors</ENAMEX> include: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson Kelly</ENAMEX>; the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Segal Law Firm</ENAMEX>;
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bowles</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rice</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">McDavid, Graff & Love; Spilman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas &</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Battle; Bordas & Bordas; DiTrapano, Barrett & DiPiero</ENAMEX>; the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">West Virginia State Bar; and Hill</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peterson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Carper</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bee</ENAMEX> &
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Deitzler</ENAMEX>.
Anyone interested in contributing to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid's</ENAMEX> fund-raising
drive may contact them at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">922 Quarrier St.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charleston</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WV</ENAMEX> 25301.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> may also call <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">343-3013</ENAMEX> or (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">800</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">642-8279</ENAMEX>.





