



Legal services for poor facing statewide cuts
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, October 5, 2002</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">LOUISVILLE</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ky.</ENAMEX> (AP) - The loss of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.36 million</NUMEX> could mean the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">state</ENAMEX>'s legal services for the poor will lose <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> of their <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX>
regional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of a poverty-law resource center
said.
It could also mean the loss of some of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">72</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kentucky</ENAMEX> for the program commonly called "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid</ENAMEX>," as well as
legal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assistants</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>.
"This is a major funding crisis for legal aid throughout the
state," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Hamon</ENAMEX>, executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of the Access to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Foundation</ENAMEX>, a statewide poverty-law resource <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">center</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lexington</ENAMEX>.
Legal Aid provides noncriminal legal assistance to the poor in
areas such as family law, consumer fraud, housing evictions and
foreclosures.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Statewide</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid</ENAMEX> will lose <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $800,000</NUMEX> in federal funds -
a cut of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 13 percent</NUMEX> from the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6 million</NUMEX> it got <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> from
the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services Corp.</ENAMEX>, which provides most of the money
for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> also is facing the loss of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $460,000</NUMEX> - nearly all
the grant money it gets through the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Violence Against Women</ENAMEX>
Act - for legal services for poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who suffer domestic
violence. In addition, because of lower interest rates, it is
facing a decline of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $100,000</NUMEX> in funds from interest collected
on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">trust</ENAMEX> accounts.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hamon</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kentucky</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">programs</ENAMEX> still
are reviewing the cuts.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott Crocker</ENAMEX>, executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kentucky Legal Aid</ENAMEX>, which
serves western and southern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kentucky</ENAMEX>, said his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> will lose
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $260,000</NUMEX> out of a budget of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $2.2 million</NUMEX>. All of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agency</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> are poor, and many are elderly or disabled, he
said.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisville</ENAMEX> region is facing the potential loss of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> or
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> staff <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> because of the cuts, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dennis Bricking</ENAMEX>,
executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisville</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid Society</ENAMEX>, which
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">serves Jefferson</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX> surrounding <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">counties</ENAMEX>. The cuts will come at
a time when the demand for services is increasing.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bricking</ENAMEX> said he expects to lose <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $170,000</NUMEX> out of an annual
budget of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $3 million</NUMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hamon</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> are forced to prioritize cases. For
example, they are more likely to take on eviction cases or
domestic-violence cases if there are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> involved and
foreclosure cases when an elderly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> has been the victim of
fraud and risks losing a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>.
Unless <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> increases funding, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kentucky</ENAMEX> will lose about
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$800,000</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX> from the federal program that supports <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid</ENAMEX>
because funds are tied to each <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s poverty rate. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kentucky</ENAMEX>'s
poverty rate declined <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 3 percent</NUMEX> under the latest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Census</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kentucky</ENAMEX> where poverty declined slightly suffered
cuts because other large <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> had significant increases in
poverty and will drain additional federal money from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal</ENAMEX>
Services <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">fund</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hamon</ENAMEX> said.
An amendment to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> appropriations bill offered by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harkin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX>, that would increase federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid</ENAMEX> funding is
pending, but its passage is uncertain, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bricking</ENAMEX> said.
Legal Aid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> are particularly worried about impoverished
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">areas</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, such as eastern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kentucky</ENAMEX>, served by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Appalachian Research and Defense Fund</ENAMEX>, or APPALRED.
"What you've got is poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with acute legal needs not being
able to have those needs met," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ernie Lewis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of the state
public-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">defender system</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APPALRED</ENAMEX>. "I think
each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> and each executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> are going to have to reduce
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">services</ENAMEX> for poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>."
He said he expects <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APPALRED</ENAMEX> to see a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$600,000</NUMEX> cut in its <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4</NUMEX>
million budget. Legal Aid of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bluegrass</ENAMEX>, which serves the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lexington</ENAMEX> area and northern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kentucky</ENAMEX>, could not be reached for an
estimate on its cuts.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Next year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kentucky</ENAMEX> will lose <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">almost $500,000</NUMEX> in grants through
the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Violence Against Women Act</ENAMEX> used to provide legal
assistance to poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> of domestic violence. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX> declined to renew those grants under new
policies that direct the money to start-up programs instead of
funding existing programs, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hamon</ENAMEX> said.



