



The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Florida Times-Union</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, May 25, 2002</TIMEX>

Legal Aid in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Clay County</ENAMEX> Could Get a Boost
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">R. Michael Anderson</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> who are most in need of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>'s help in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Clay County</ENAMEX>
often are the ones who can least afford it. That's when
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jacksonville Area Legal Aid Inc.</ENAMEX> steps in to fill the gap.
But even though <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> provide legal services to
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of indigent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Northeast</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>, including
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> a year in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Clay County</ENAMEX>, the needs of many others go unmet
due to budgetary constraints and staffing limitations.
With <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">paralegal</ENAMEX> in its <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Clay County</ENAMEX> branch
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Green Cove Springs</ENAMEX>, the non-profit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> handled more
than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">300</NUMEX> cases <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Figgins</ENAMEX>, executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>.
But for every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX> who received help fighting negligent
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">landlords</ENAMEX>, abusive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husbands</ENAMEX> or federal benefit program
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">administrators</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> others did not.
"Study after study shows unmet needs to be <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 80 percent</NUMEX>," he
said.
The ability to handle more cases is about to take a big jump,
however, as a result of an increase in revenue from fees charged
for every civil action filed in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Clay County</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">County</ENAMEX>
Commission has endorsed a request to boost the filing fee from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10</NUMEX>
to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25</NUMEX> and could approve an ordinance <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">as early as Tuesday</TIMEX> to
implement the fee hike.
"Currently, we spend <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $250,000</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Clay County</ENAMEX>, which
is <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 8 percent</NUMEX> of our budget," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Figgins</ENAMEX>, adding that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clay</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">County</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> also represent <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 8 percent</NUMEX> of the total "poverty
population" served by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Duval</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Baker</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Nassau</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Clay</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">counties</ENAMEX>.
The additional revenue from higher court-filing fees will total
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $60,000</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>, of which <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">approximately $40,000</NUMEX> will be spent
on salary for an additional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> to assist <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gloria Einstein</ENAMEX>, who
has been the only <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Clay County</ENAMEX> for many
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>.
The only way to get a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> so cheaply will be to find one with
limited experience, or perhaps one fresh out of law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> with a
strong desire to "provide <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice</ENAMEX> to low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>," Figgins
said.
Legal Aid handles only civil cases. Child custody and domestic
violence cases, housing discrimination, divorce, consumer fraud and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> entitlements make up the majority of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>'s case load.
The last time court filing fees were increased in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Clay County</ENAMEX> to
help fund the program was in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commissioners</ENAMEX> approved an
increase from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5 to $10</NUMEX>.
Of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 300</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid</ENAMEX> cases in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clay</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>, roughly
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">40 percent</NUMEX> involved <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who had been abused by violent husbands
and were seeking divorces, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Figgins</ENAMEX> said. Most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> were
referred to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quigley House</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Clay County</ENAMEX>'s sexual
assault and domestic violence <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX>.
In domestic violence situations involving married <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> need to legally sever their marital relationship with their
abusive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouses</ENAMEX> in order to move on with their lives, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Figgins</ENAMEX> said,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jacksonville Area Legal Aid</ENAMEX> provides the expertise to
accomplish that.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sharon Youngerman</ENAMEX>, executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quigley House</ENAMEX>, said
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 75 percent</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who come to her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> in search of
help have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. But most have no financial resources, which is
why so many remain in abusive situations for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>.
"Everyone asks why does she stay in the abusive situation,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Youngerman</ENAMEX> said. "Well, if she can't get a divorce she doesn't have
any kind of legal paperwork that would require him to support her
[and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>]."
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">services Legal Aid</ENAMEX> provides, she said, are critical to
helping indigent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> of domestic violence achieve the freedom
they need to start their lives over and begin to recover from years
of physical and psychological trauma.
"Very few of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> have the financial resources to do this
on their own," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Youngerman</ENAMEX> said. "Generally, if they had the
resources they don't need shelter and they can afford private
counseling."




