



Times <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Albany, NY</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 14, 2002</TIMEX>

Legal Aid Society ensures justice for needy
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arthur J. Siegel</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times Union</ENAMEX> coverage of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Law Day</ENAMEX> quoted Chief <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judith S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kaye</ENAMEX> as saying, "The promise of freedom and equal justice is an
empty one if our justice system is not accessible." Unfortunately,
there was no mention of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capital Region</ENAMEX>'s own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid Society</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northeastern New York</ENAMEX>, the nonprofit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> that works to
ensure that justice is available to the poor, the disabled and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">endangered</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LASNNY</ENAMEX> is one of the oldest and most cost-effective legal
services <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. Originally
incorporated in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1923</TIMEX> as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid Society of Albany</ENAMEX>, it now
serves income- eligible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">counties</ENAMEX> throughout the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capital Region</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LASNNY</ENAMEX> provides only needed civil legal aid --
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">urgent</ENAMEX>, noncriminal assistance to low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LASNNY</ENAMEX> helped <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 14,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.
Funding for legal aid preserves community resources and saves
tax dollars. For example, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>, LASNNY:
Opened <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">585</NUMEX> cases for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> of domestic violence, helping
to break the cycle of violence that causes so much lasting harm to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>.
Prevented or forestalled <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">112</NUMEX> evictions, saving shelter costs of
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$151,619</NUMEX> and the disruption that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> suffer when they are
displaced.
Won <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">87</NUMEX> SSI/SSD cases enabling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> to receive <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$850,016</NUMEX> in
retroactive benefits, saving state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$441,786</NUMEX> and enabling
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with disabilities to live with dignity.
Because we lack sufficient public and private support, the
dedicated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LASNNY</ENAMEX> are limited in their
ability to serve all those in need. As a result, an estimated <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">four</NUMEX>
out of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> requiring legal help in our community
do not receive it.
Our elected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>, and all who are concerned about providing
equal access to justice for all, must step forward and support
Legal Aid services. If not, many of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> will continue to
be denied the protection of the laws and freedoms we cherish and
promote throughout the world.




