



Cuts in federal, private funds mean less legal aid
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 28, 2002</TIMEX>
By <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Skiles Luke</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poor</ENAMEX> will have less access to free <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> thanks to a
recent one-two punch: a cut in federal funding for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s
biggest free law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clinics</ENAMEX> and a drop in a statewide fund that pays
for legal aid.
The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> that deliver most of the legal aid to the poor
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX> will lose <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $920,000</NUMEX> in congressional funding
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">annually</ENAMEX>, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric Kleiman</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services Corp.</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>-based <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> that distributes federal money for
legal aid.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> allocates money to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> based on the number of poor
counted in the last census. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> census showed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX> with
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 35,000</NUMEX> fewer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are eligible for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> services because
of low income, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $22,000</NUMEX> a year for a family of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>, Kleiman
said.
The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> are the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Assistance Foundation</ENAMEX> of
Metropolitan <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rockford</ENAMEX>-based <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prairie State Legal Services</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alton</ENAMEX>-based <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Land of Lincoln Legal Services</ENAMEX>.
The cuts will take the biggest bite out of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Land of Lincoln</ENAMEX>, a
network of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> who help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">southern Illinois</ENAMEX> with problems like eviction, access to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Security</ENAMEX> and obtaining orders of protection from abusive
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouses</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>, which gets <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than half</NUMEX> of its <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5 million</NUMEX> budget
from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>, will lose <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$525,000</NUMEX>, said executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bartylak</ENAMEX>. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> will likely be laid off, and agency
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> will meet <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> to discuss whether to cut services,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bartylak</ENAMEX> said.
Land of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> helped <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tasha Johnson</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marion</ENAMEX> get <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Security</ENAMEX> benefits to support her <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> after the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">29-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> was diagnosed with non-<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Hodgkin's lymphoma</ENAMEX>, a type
of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>, she said. Her application had been rejected <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three</TIMEX>
times.
"They're known for helping <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>," she said.
Although the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> groups deliver most legal aid in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX>,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of other programs offer similar services and all will feel
the pain when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lawyers Trust Fund of Illinois</ENAMEX> doles out grants
for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX>.
The fund, created by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Illinois Supreme Court</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1983</TIMEX>, gets
interest from escrow accounts and other money <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> often keep
for their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> and spends it on legal aid.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX>, the fund will likely award <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">just half</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3.5</NUMEX>
million it usually gives <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">some 34</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> statewide, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruth Ann</ENAMEX>
Schmitt, the trust fund's executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Illinois General Assembly</ENAMEX> has appropriated <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $500,000</NUMEX>
annually for legal aid in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX>, an amount <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bartylak</ENAMEX> said has
not been much reduced.
Still, of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populace</ENAMEX> states, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX> ranks
last in the amount of money <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">legislators</ENAMEX> appropriate for legal aid,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Erlenborn</ENAMEX> said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this year</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sheldon Roodman</ENAMEX>, executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Assistance</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foundation of Metropolitan Chicago</ENAMEX>, said the work these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> do
is critical.
"(They take) cases like preserving an elderly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s home
being foreclosed because of a predatory loan," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roodman</ENAMEX> said, "or an
illegal eviction of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who will become homeless. If people
don't have access to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX>, somebody who has the upper hand
takes advantage."



