



<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vacaville Reporter</ENAMEX>

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Library Lawyers</ENAMEX>
Program provides many with legal advice
By <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Darryl Richardson</ENAMEX>

<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 16, 2002</TIMEX>
When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shane Massello</ENAMEX> realized his former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">landlord</ENAMEX> was not going
to return a security deposit he believed he was entitled to, his
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> thought was to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> for the money. The amount
involved, however, was not enough to justify bringing in a lawyer
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Massello</ENAMEX> didn't know how to begin a case in small claims court.
Program Information
Interested in free legal advice through the program? Arrive at
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vacaville</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1020</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Ulatis Drive</ENAMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4 p.m.</TIMEX> on the
following dates: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 23, May 7, May 21, June 4</TIMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18</TIMEX>. Appointments will be taken at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4:05 p.m.</TIMEX> The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> visits
will begin at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6 p.m and last until 8 p.m.</TIMEX>
Fortunately for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Massello</ENAMEX> and other local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with similar
problems, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vacaville Public Library</ENAMEX> has a new program designed
to assist <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with legal questions. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lawyer</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Library</ENAMEX>
program is an offshoot of a long-standing program at the Vallejo
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">library</ENAMEX>, which has proven to be very effective in providing people
with free, unbiased advice. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vacaville</ENAMEX> program kicked off in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> and has proven to be so popular during its <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> sessions
that it has already expanded from one meeting per month to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>.
"I knew about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vallejo</ENAMEX> program and wanted to see if it would
work here," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Brownell</ENAMEX>, who is coordinating the program for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX>. "I knew there would be some demand for this, but I was
really pleased with the turnout for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> sessions."
Because the program is just starting in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vacaville</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only two</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> are available during <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the two-hour</TIMEX> sessions. Those wishing
to speak to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> are allowed up to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">20 minutes</TIMEX> to discuss
their cases and receive advice on how to proceed.
"Basically I just shoot them in the right direction," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gene</ENAMEX>
Windham, a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vacaville</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> specializing in probate and tax law
who helped out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this week</TIMEX>. "Sometimes the case is outside
our areas, but we can at least give them some clues on if they have
a case and how to go from here."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brownell</ENAMEX> said the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> programs have featured questions on
almost every type of legal problem imaginable.
"We have seen conflicts with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX>, family law issues,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">immigration</ENAMEX> and financial problems," he said. "All kinds of things
you don't need to go to court to resolve."
Most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> attending the most recent session said they
were simply looking for advice on whether they have a legal case
and how to proceed from here.
"I'm here to get advice because I don't know what to do next,"
said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlene Jerrell</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Suisun</ENAMEX>, who was seeking help with a
financial issue. "I like the fact that I can find out what is and
isn't available for me. The fact that an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> will talk to me
and I can ask them questions is great."
Part of the agreement the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> must sign before meeting
with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> is not able to serve as the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> during any action in the matter. This fact is very
important to many of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">includ ing Massello</ENAMEX>.
"It's a tremendous help," he said. "They are simply answering
questions without thinking of how they can make money. It's nice to
not have to worry about seeing a biased <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX>."
After a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10-minute</TIMEX> meeting with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Windham, Massello</ENAMEX> said the
discussion was everything he hoped for.
"It was excellent," he said. "I wanted to get some information
on how to continue and I got more than I was expecting. It sounds
like we will be able to get everything we want and then some and if
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> is in a good mood, we might get even more!" Because the
Vacaville program is just starting up, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brownell</ENAMEX> said the number of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who can be seen <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">each night</TIMEX> is small, but plans are already
in place to increase the totals. "Because we only have two
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> per <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> right now, we can only see <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 15</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> each
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>," he said. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vallejo</ENAMEX> program has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> each
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, so they can see more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. It's too early to tell, but I
think we will likely have another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> here soon."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brownell</ENAMEX> also said a partnership with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Solano County Bar</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association</ENAMEX> should help get the word out to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> who might
want to donate their time.
"This is a pure pro-bono project," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brownell</ENAMEX> said. "We really
commend them for coming in during <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the evening</TIMEX> and helping out."
The initial demand for legal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX> was what prompted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brownell</ENAMEX>
to add a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> session <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each month</TIMEX>. He said the plan is to hold the
event on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first and third Tuesdays of each month</TIMEX>, but the
schedule is somewhat different for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next several months</TIMEX>. The
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next sessions</TIMEX> will be held on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 23, May 7 and 21 and June 4</TIMEX> and
18.





