



<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lindsay</ENAMEX>'s legacy

Nonprofits honor the retired <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> and volunteer for his
dedication to social justice.

By <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Carr Mayle</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SAFE Shelter</ENAMEX> executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gail Reese-Wheeler</ENAMEX> vividly
recalls her first encounter with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Lindsay</ENAMEX>'s indomitable
spirit.
It was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nine years ago</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reese-Wheeler</ENAMEX> was barely into her
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX> with the shelter when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lindsay</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SAFE Shelter</ENAMEX> board
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX>, invited her to lunch to talk about "some ideas he had for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shelter</ENAMEX>."
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim</ENAMEX> had so much vision and enthusiasm," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reese-Wheeler</ENAMEX> says. "By
the end of that <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one-hour</TIMEX> lunch, he had listed off <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least 20</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">projects</ENAMEX> - not the least of which was a new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shelter</ENAMEX> -- and was
sitting there waiting for me to respond.
"He scared me to death, until I began to realize that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jim</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lindsay</ENAMEX> was the kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who would roll up his shirtsleeves and
work right beside you."
On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lindsay</ENAMEX> got his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> look at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of his most
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fervent</ENAMEX> hopes come true -- a new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SAFE Shelter</ENAMEX>. As his son,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken</ENAMEX>, wheels him up the concrete ramp and through the doors,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lindsey</ENAMEX>'s grin says it all.
"I'm amazed. I had hoped this would happen, but I never dreamed
it would be so soon or so grand," he says with difficulty, picking
his words carefully.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lindsay</ENAMEX>, who has suffered several strokes and moved with his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shirley</ENAMEX>, to an assisted-care <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jacksonville</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fla.</ENAMEX>
was back in town for "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Lindsay Day</ENAMEX>," which included a tour of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shelter</ENAMEX> and a reception attended by many of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> whose
lives he touched as a volunteer with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Savannah</ENAMEX> nonprofits.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lou Barnes</ENAMEX> first met <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lindsay</ENAMEX> when he served on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> of
Parent and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Child Development Services</ENAMEX>, where she was the human
resources <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manager</ENAMEX>. Later, they both served on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SAFE Shelter</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX>.
"I wouldn't have missed this day for anything," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barnes</ENAMEX> says.
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim</ENAMEX> is such a giving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>, so committed to helping those less
fortunate. I've seen very few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> as dedicated to community
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">volunteerism</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim</ENAMEX>. Yes, he was retired and had the time, but he
could have just as easily spent that time on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">golf course</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jim</ENAMEX>
is one who has always given as generously of his time as he did his
money."
A retired corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lindsay</ENAMEX> entered <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oberlin College</ENAMEX> at
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14</TIMEX>, then went on to law school at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Michigan</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daughter Pippi Ellison</ENAMEX>, who flew down from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> for the
celebration, says her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s passion for social <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice</ENAMEX> "has
always been there."
"From very early on, I learned that there were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in
circumstances very different from ours and that ignoring those
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> was not an option," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellison</ENAMEX> says. "My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> was always
working for fair- and low-income housing.
When the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellison</ENAMEX> says, her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> got
the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> involved in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York City Mission Society</ENAMEX>,
passing on the exclusive <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> camps to send his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">society</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> for inner-city <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>.
"I was a camper and my older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counselors</ENAMEX>.
It was education through immersion," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellison</ENAMEX>, who works as a
clinical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychologist</ENAMEX> near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>.
Meeting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Lindsay</ENAMEX> was an education of a different sort for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Broker</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Georgia Legal Services</ENAMEX>.
"This was back when we were on the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> floor of the Urban
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health Center</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">York Street</ENAMEX> and I had been managing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> for
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only a year or two</TIMEX>," Broker recalls. "In strolls <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Lindsay</ENAMEX>,
saying he's a retired <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> now living in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Savannah</ENAMEX> and he was
interested in doing free legal work for poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.
"He really shook up my whole mindset," Broker says. "I was so
focused on bringing in new young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> right out of school
because that was what we could afford. It never occurred to me that
there might be older, experienced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> out there willing to
help."
It was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lindsay</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Broker</ENAMEX> says, who first broached the idea of
having a senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteer attorney</ENAMEX> program, which is flourishing
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lindsay</ENAMEX> helped out at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Georgia Legal Services</ENAMEX> by working on
benefits cases, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX> claims. He and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Broker</ENAMEX> later began the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Mediation Center</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Savannah</ENAMEX>, with both
serving on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">nonprofit</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX>.
But, perhaps <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lindsay</ENAMEX>'s biggest contribution to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Georgia Legal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Services</ENAMEX> was the inspiration he provided its young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>.
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim</ENAMEX> sat in on our <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> meetings, listening to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> talk
about their cases," Broker says. "He had such a depth of
understanding, a maturity of judgment and an uncanny ability to
hone in on the real issues.
"Just to hear him say, 'I believe in what you're doing,' raised
our game and made us want to work harder.
"I think that's the kind of effect <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Lindsay</ENAMEX> has on everyone
he touches."





