



Local <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Attorneys Lend a Free Hand</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane D Albritton</ENAMEX>
Upon admission to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX>, every <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> must recite the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lawyer</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oath</ENAMEX>, which states in part: "I will never reject, from any
consideration personal to myself, the cause of the defenseless or
the oppressed." To that end, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> are expected, although not
required, to contribute <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">25 hours</TIMEX> a year pro bono - free - for the
common good.
However, the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> Report of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services/Pre Bono</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee</ENAMEX>, of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Judicial Advisory Council</ENAMEX> found that the ability
of low- and middle-income <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coloradans</ENAMEX> to obtain equal access to the
legal system has been limited by the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> available
and willing to serve them and by the growing complexity of the
law.
The law in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern Colorado</ENAMEX> remains as <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> as it is
anywhere else, but the willingness of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> to take on pro bono
work in defense of the "defenseless or oppressed" appears to be
exemplary.
Generally speaking, there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> routes to equal access for
those who cannot afford legal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX>: the public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">defender</ENAMEX>'s office
(for criminal- cases); legal services (federally funded); and the
local bar <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX> that coordinate pro bono work. Both legal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">services</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar associations</ENAMEX> complement each other in ways
that provide a fairly broad net of support. Despite the population
growth in the area and the uneasiness in the economy, the
resilience of this net has proven remarkably strong.
"The advantage of our program is its predictability," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosenberg</ENAMEX>, chair of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Pro Bono</ENAMEX> Project for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Larimer County</ENAMEX>. "Every
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, we have review and intake in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort Collins</ENAMEX>; every
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, we have review and intake in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Loveland</ENAMEX>. It is always at
the same time and in the same place."

Long history in Larimer
The work by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Larimer County Bar Association</ENAMEX> has been going on
for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18 years</TIMEX>, and in that time <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">several thousand</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> have been
served. During <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 51-week</TIMEX> period <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between June 2000 and May 2001</TIMEX>,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">250</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> came through intake in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort Collins</ENAMEX>. Of those, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">150</NUMEX>
got the advice they needed and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">33</NUMEX> received <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> referrals. In
Loveland, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">23</NUMEX> were assigned <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosenberg</ENAMEX> explained that the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Pro Bono</ENAMEX> Project does not take on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminal</ENAMEX> cases, bankruptcies, dependent or neglected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, or
fee generating cases such as personal injury.
"In personal-injury cases, an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> can work for a
contingency fee," she said. "Most of our cases involve domestic
law. This is an area where we have seen an increase in a need for
help."
In addition to the referrals made through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar association</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Larimer County</ENAMEX> conducts bar <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clinics</ENAMEX> and classes.
"Once <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX> I instruct a divorce class, and every other month
I teach a class in parental responsibility (custody) or the single
parent," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kris Merkel</ENAMEX>, pro bono and legal-aid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coordinator</ENAMEX> for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Larimer County Bar Association</ENAMEX>. "We provide all the forms and
teach <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who come how to handle the process pro se, on their
own."
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Merkel</ENAMEX> has noticed that there has been an increase over the past
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> in domestic cases. She attributes part of this increase to the
fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have been moving to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> in hopes of finding
the promised land, as outlined in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Money Magazine</ENAMEX>. What they have
found instead is a minimum-wage job market and out-of-sight real
estate prices. To make matters worse, the economy has
flattened.
"When the economy goes bad, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> that are already struggling
tend to fall apart," she observed.
Federally funded legal services, in both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Larimer</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weld</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">counties</ENAMEX>, have also felt the pressure of increased domestic
dissolution.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mario Rivera</ENAMEX>, managing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greeley</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>, noted
that his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> has handled <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> more cases in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX> than in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>.
"The highest number of cases for us are domestic," he said.
"Given our resources, we can only handle the most pressing cases
such as restraining orders. We are also being inundated by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bankruptcies</ENAMEX>, but in those cases we can only take on cases of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> whose wages are being garnished and who can't take care of
their basic needs with what they have left."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rivera</ENAMEX> pointed out that helping <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>, many of whom are not
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">native English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speakers</ENAMEX>, becomes problematic as demands increase
and funding to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services Corp.</ENAMEX> remains stagnant.
"The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> cut back funding by a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1982</TIMEX>,
and then the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Contract</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> cut funds again," he said. "So
we continue to work with a budget that is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two-thirds</NUMEX> of what it
was."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Bye</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rivera</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counterpart</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Larimer County</ENAMEX>, works with a
staff of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX>. He faces the ongoing quandary of seeing a need for
more outreach in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> but lacking the resources to
implement it.
"If it had not been for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren Rudman</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Hampshire</ENAMEX>), the
Legal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Services Corp.</ENAMEX> might have disappeared altogether," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bye</ENAMEX> said.
"As it is, we are restricted in how we can proceed. We cannot bring
class-action suits, and we cannot ask for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX>'s fees when we
win a case. Those restrictions take a big bite out of our
power."


Work often challenging
Both <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rivera</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bye</ENAMEX> added that despite the pinch in federal
support, the generosity of their local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar associations</ENAMEX> and the
Legal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aid Foundation</ENAMEX> keep the neediest in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern Colorado</ENAMEX>
well-represented. But representing this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> that often
lacks education and legal sophistication, can challenge even the
most-dedicated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX>. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> have no phone and no other
address but the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> at the shelter.
"Many of those who come to us do not understand the implications
of communications from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosenberg</ENAMEX>. "So by the time
we get the case, it is a crisis. Sometimes it is difficult to talk
to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">client</ENAMEX> directly. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> who take on these cases often
do so on extremely short notice."
She also noted that while an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> might be taking on a case
pro bono, the implications of handling the case poorly remain
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">constant</ENAMEX>.
"If you handle the case wrong, you are exposed for damages," she
said. "And once you're on a case, you stay on unless you can get
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>'s permission to withdraw. Very few realize what a service
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys volunteer</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX>."
In part, grants from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Colorado Lawyers Trust</ENAMEX> Account
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foundation</ENAMEX> defray some of the costs associated with maintaining a
strong pro bono, program. These funds cover the salary of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">paralegal coordinator</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kris Markel</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Larimer County</ENAMEX>), telephones,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> supplies and malpractice insurance.
"The work that our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> do is remarkable," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosenberg</ENAMEX>.
"Some-times our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> are not the most agreeable in the world,
but <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> when I put out forms asking for pro bono work, they
started coming back by fax almost immediately."
While the will to assist the low income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> has not
abated in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern Colorado</ENAMEX>, those involved with federally funded
legal services must wait to see who <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> appoints to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services Corp.</ENAMEX> And they hope the spirit of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren Rudman</ENAMEX> will prevail.




