



The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX>

<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lockyer Warns of Firms Posing</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid Services</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jocelyn Y. Stewart</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday July 5, 2002</TIMEX>
State <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Atty</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Lockyer</ENAMEX> is warning <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Californians</ENAMEX> to beware
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> that advertise "legal aid" or "legal services," only
to provide costly and shoddy services that may hurt <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> in
court.
The warning, in a recently released consumer alert, is a
reaction to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> that prey on the public's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">trust</ENAMEX> in
legitimate legal aid <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>.
"The true nonprofit legal services <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>
provide indispensable free legal assistance to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> who can't
afford to hire an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> but need help while facing dangerous
domestic violence situations, evictions from their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> and other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">emergencies</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lockyer</ENAMEX> said in the alert.
Legal aid services are nonprofit, publicly funded <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>
that provide services to low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> at no charge or for a
minimal fee. Certain court forms refer the poor to legal aid.
But some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX>, staffed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are not <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX>,
have adopted "legal aid" or similar names, leading some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to
believe that they are nonprofits.
In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>, many of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> ended up at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid Foundation</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>, a legitimate nonprofit
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organization</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elena Popp</ENAMEX>, executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundation</ENAMEX>, welcomed the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney general</ENAMEX>'s alert.
"It is actually very painful for us to see <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> come into this
office having paid <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$400</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$500</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$600</NUMEX> to someone to prepare paperwork
that is badly done," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Popp</ENAMEX>. "So they've been ripped off once by
having to pay this fee and then in court by losing their case."
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">attorney general's office</ENAMEX> filed a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of the
court brief in support of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Shasta County</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> who won a
case against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Modesto</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">resident</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter Moore</ENAMEX>, who also used the name
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff Simmons</ENAMEX>.
The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">plaintiffs</ENAMEX>, all of whom were facing eviction, said they
were deceived into calling <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moore</ENAMEX> by his use of the term "legal aid"
in advertising.
"Here we have a profit-seeking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">businessman</ENAMEX> who's not a lawyer
calling himself <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">'Legal Aid' in the Yellow Pages</ENAMEX> and on the
Internet," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Rhoades</ENAMEX>, litigation <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Housing</ENAMEX>
Rights <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center</ENAMEX>, and lead <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> on the case.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moore</ENAMEX> operated a business offering several types of legal
services through advertisements that appeared in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> throughout
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>.
During the trial, former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moore</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> said they had been
trained to tell <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">callers</ENAMEX> they were the same "legal aid" mentioned in
court forms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moore</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> charged <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$85 to $400</NUMEX> to type simple
forms, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rhoades</ENAMEX> said.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> found <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moore</ENAMEX> guilty of violating the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Unlawful Detainer</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Assistance Act</ENAMEX> and of practicing law without a license and acting
with fraud, malice, or oppression.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> determined that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moore</ENAMEX> had violated <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>'s Unfair
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Business Practices and False Advertising Laws</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 2001</TIMEX>,
the judge ordered <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moore</ENAMEX> to pay restitution and issued a statewide
injunction prohibiting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moore</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">associates</ENAMEX> from using the term
"legal aid" and similar names. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> ordered <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moore</ENAMEX> to advertise
the verdict in newspapers in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>.
The case is on appeal.
To verify that a legal aid <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> is federally funded or
to find a local nonprofit legal aid <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> may refer to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services Corp.</ENAMEX>'s Web site, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">lsc</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">gov/fundprog.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">htm.</ENAMEX>
Those who have been victimized by document <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">preparers</ENAMEX> who are not
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> should call their local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">district attorney</ENAMEX> or the Attorney
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public Inquiry Unit</ENAMEX> at (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">800</ENAMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">952-5225</TIMEX>. Complaints may be
filed online at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">http://www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ag</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">ca.gov/</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX>.
Those in need of assistance may call the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid Foundation</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> at (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">800</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">399-4529</ENAMEX>




