



<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Foster</ENAMEX>'s Online

<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 19, 2002</TIMEX>



Study: Low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> lack <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> in court
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">PORTLAND</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maine</ENAMEX> (AP) - Low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maine</ENAMEX> involved in
divorce or parental rights cases are often denied the benefits of
court <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> because their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> cannot afford to pay the
fees, according to a new report.
The report by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Muskie School of Public Service</ENAMEX> at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Southern Maine</ENAMEX> completes a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three-year</TIMEX> evaluation of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX> ad Litem - or GALs - in divorce and parental rights and
responsibilities cases in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GALs</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> or licensed mental health <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counselors</ENAMEX> appointed
by a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> to represent a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>'s best interests in family
proceedings. Their fees, which can range <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">between $75 and $150</NUMEX> per
hour under a private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">system</ENAMEX>, are paid for by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, said
Muskie Fellowship recipient <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alison Beyea</ENAMEX>.
"Overall, we found that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GALs</ENAMEX> are very beneficial," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beyea</ENAMEX>,
who co-wrote the report with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank D'Alessandro</ENAMEX>. "However, we also
discovered that in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds of</NUMEX> cases <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each year</TIMEX>, the court
recommends that a GAL be appointed but cannot do so because the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> can't afford the fee."
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beyea</ENAMEX> said the study was conducted because of growing concern
that low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> were subject to intense, emotional
arguments that more affluent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> would be sheltered from.
"The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are living in fairly intolerable situations while
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> are battling it out," she said. "There may not be
anyone else involved to insulate them."
Often, GALs end up doing more social work than legal counseling,
such as improving communication between family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beyea</ENAMEX> said.
"Collaboration with mental health <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> is critical," she
said.
Beyea, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pine Tree Legal Services</ENAMEX>, conducted the study
and said she surveyed district court <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX>, case management
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX>, family law <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> registered to be <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GALs</ENAMEX>.
There were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">170</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GALs</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maine</ENAMEX> at the time of her study, she
said.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beyea</ENAMEX> said the report's findings are timely, given that Chief
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leigh Saufley</ENAMEX> has said that one of her priorities is to
provide <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GALs</ENAMEX> to all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, regardless of economic
background.
Unlike <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> protective cases, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in divorce proceedings
are not guaranteed the right to a court-appointed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">guardian</ENAMEX> by the
state. Low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> who have been <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> of abuse or
neglect are not charged for guardians; rather, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">state</ENAMEX> pays the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAL</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50</NUMEX> per hour under the state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> budget.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beyea</ENAMEX> said she would like to see the state implement a similar
program that offers resources to lower-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> involved in
divorce and parental rights and responsibilities cases. "We do
think, given the report, that there might be some legislative
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">appropriation</ENAMEX>," she said.



