



Major Changes Hit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Legal Services</ENAMEX>
Restructuring <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Plan Prompts Lawsuit</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bronx</ENAMEX>
By <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Wise</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> legal services program is undergoing a radical
restructuring at the prompting of the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corporation</ENAMEX>.
The transformation will leave the program, which was formed in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1967</TIMEX> along the model of decentralized <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school boards</ENAMEX> under local
community control, with a far more centralized structure.
For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last 35 years</TIMEX>, the program has had a two-tiered
structure, in which a citywide <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>, now called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services</ENAMEX>
for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> (LSNY), has received federal funds that in turn
have been distributed to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> different local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX>, which
provided the bulk of services in civil legal matters to indigent
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">New Yorkers</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSNY</ENAMEX>'s role has been generally limited to certain
administrative functions, though over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> it has come to run
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> programs of its own.
Under the revised structure, which is expected to be put in
place in the early part of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSNY</ENAMEX> will have a controlling
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">voice</ENAMEX> in the selection of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX> for the local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX>. In
addition, the local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> are being asked to adopt new
certificates of incorporation and bylaws, which some of the groups
contend vastly expand <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSNY</ENAMEX>'s powers. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> program, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bronx</ENAMEX> Legal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Services</ENAMEX>, was so distressed by the changes that it filed a lawsuit
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Southern District of New York</ENAMEX>, seeking to block its
restructuring. <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Approximately</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">140</TIMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">160</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> working in the
program are employed by the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX>. The remaining
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> work either in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">LSNY</ENAMEX> central <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> or in the two
programs it directly runs: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> for the elderly and the other for
the poor in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Williamsburg</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brighton Beach</ENAMEX> sections of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brooklyn</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSNY</ENAMEX> disperses <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">approximately $33 million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>, of which <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$12</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">million</ENAMEX> comes from the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services Corporation</ENAMEX>. Of the
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$12 million</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">22 percent</NUMEX> is earmarked for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSNY</ENAMEX> budget and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">78</NUMEX>
percent is allocated among the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX>, according
to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSNY</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokeswoman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edwina Martin</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services Corporation</ENAMEX> insisted upon the changes,
according to its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric Kleiman</ENAMEX> because the New York
program's structure is "completely anomalous" in that there are
"<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">two degrees</NUMEX> of separation" between the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporation</ENAMEX> and the
programs actually delivering civil legal services.
The change is necessary, he added, to assure "a true oversight
mechanism" for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> program. As the funding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSNY</ENAMEX> subcontracted with the local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX> to provide legal services,
and was left with only the "drastic remedy" of defunding a local
program if problems in management or delivery of services were
uncovered, he said. Defunding was not a viable remedy, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kleiman</ENAMEX>
added, because "the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> hurt are those who benefit from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">services</ENAMEX>."
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Law Journal</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NY</ENAMEX>) - <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 15, 2002</TIMEX>

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bronx Program</ENAMEX>'s Lawsuit
However, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walker Thompson</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bronx</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services</ENAMEX>,
which filed a lawsuit on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 5</TIMEX> seeking to block the changes, said
the restructuring "threatens our ability to be a good legal
services program."
The change in corporate structure, he explained, "eviscerates
local control by placing power in a distant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entity</ENAMEX> - LSNY - with
little need to be accountable to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bronx</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX>."
Also, he charged that bylaw changes, which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSNY</ENAMEX> is forcing
through its exercise of its power over his program's purse,
"expands enormously <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSNY</ENAMEX>'s legislative power to tell local programs
what they can and cannot do." The changes, he added, further
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">empower LSNY</ENAMEX> to get involved in the minutiae of running local
programs by, for instance, requiring <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSNY</ENAMEX> to approve the
expenditure of very small sums of money.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael W. Martin</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fordham University School of Law</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX>
who sits on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSNY</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX>, however, countered that the changes
were narrowly tailored to ensure effective monitoring by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSNY</ENAMEX>,
while still preserving the power of local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX> to run their
programs. He explained, for instance, that provisions were being
written into the new bylaws that would prohibit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSNY</ENAMEX> from forcing
any bylaw changes for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX>. These provisions, he said, would
preserve forever the rights of local programs to "disassociate"
with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSNY</ENAMEX>.
The core change in corporate structure under the reorganization
recasts all <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> of the local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> as membership
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organizations</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSNY</ENAMEX> as the sole <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX>. Under <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>'s
not-for-profit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporation</ENAMEX> law, a non-profit can be structured
along the lines of a business <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporation</ENAMEX> by creating a class of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>, analogous to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shareholders</ENAMEX>, who run the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">corporation</ENAMEX> through their power to select the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporation</ENAMEX>'s board
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX>, explained <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sean Delaney</ENAMEX>, one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> who worked
on the restructuring for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSNY</ENAMEX>.
Businesses use the device to create a wholly owned <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">subsidiary</ENAMEX>,
said Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Delaney</ENAMEX>, executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lawyers' Alliance of New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York</ENAMEX>. Similarly, he said, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSNY</ENAMEX> will exercise control over the local
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> by being designated as the sole <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> in each
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">corporation</ENAMEX>, empowered to choose or discharge <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin</ENAMEX> asserted that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSNY</ENAMEX> "has no plans" under
consideration to exercise its powers as the sole corporate member
to force any changes on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX> of the local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX>. He
also pointed out that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSNY</ENAMEX> has agreed to bylaw changes that
circumscribe its otherwise unlimited powers over the selection and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">replacement</ENAMEX> of local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>. For instance, he said, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSNY</ENAMEX> had
agreed to select new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> from a slate put together by a local
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">corporation</ENAMEX>.
But <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bronx</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services</ENAMEX>' Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thompson</ENAMEX> took little comfort from
those concessions.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Law Journal</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NY</ENAMEX>) - <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 15, 2002</TIMEX>
Even without the corporate changes, he noted, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSNY</ENAMEX> has asserted
the right to withhold from the local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> money that it
gets on their behalf from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services Corporation</ENAMEX> and any
other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX>. For his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>, that would mean <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSNY</ENAMEX> can withhold more
than <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">80 percent</NUMEX> of its <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4.5 million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> budget if its lawsuit
fails. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bronx Legal Services</ENAMEX> raises <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $450,000</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> through
its own fund-raising initiatives, he explained.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Needleman</ENAMEX>, the executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brooklyn Legal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Services Corp.</ENAMEX> A, said there is wide backing from the other
programs for the lawsuit, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bronx</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services</ENAMEX>
for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">02-6199</TIMEX>. But he added that many other groups
"had gone along [with the reorganization] reluctantly" when faced
with the possible loss of most of their budgets.
The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> local programs in addition to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bronx</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brooklyn Legal Services Corp.</ENAMEX> A are <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bedford</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stuyvesant Legal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Services</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harlem Legal Services</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South Brooklyn Legal Services</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corp. B</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MFY Legal Services and Queens Legal Services</ENAMEX>.




