



Making a case -- your own -- in court
By <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jared Cook</ENAMEX>
07/14/2002
Yes, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> are expensive.
But help is now here for those few brave <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">souls</ENAMEX> determined to go
to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> alone.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Flagstaff</ENAMEX> community <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> received valuable tips and
general advice from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> legal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX> at
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">People's Legal Services</ENAMEX>' <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">monthly</TIMEX> seminar on how to represent
yourself in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>.
The seminar is held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the second Thursday</TIMEX> each month from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6 to 8</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">p.m.</TIMEX>, usually in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">County Board of Supervisors</ENAMEX> meeting <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> at
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">219</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cherry St. The</ENAMEX> meetings feature a panel consisting of a
professional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Attendee Robert Gooch</ENAMEX> was there for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> time, working to
prepare for his upcoming court date regarding <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> damages.
"It's really a great service," he said. "I think the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Constitution</ENAMEX> was written up so you could represent yourself."
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable Charles Adams</ENAMEX> of the Coconino
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">County Superior Court</ENAMEX>, agreed, but highly discouraged
self-representation. He spent <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the first 15 minutes</TIMEX> of the seminar
making certain that all present understood how hard it was to do
well.
"It is extremely difficult to represent yourself," he said. "If
you do, you have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fool</ENAMEX> for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX>."
But with that said, he and fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">panelist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elaine</ENAMEX>
Fridlund-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Horne</ENAMEX>, a family law <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> in solo practice in
Flagstaff, began to tell <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attendees</ENAMEX> how to do it, focusing first on
careful planning.
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Prior Planning Prevents Poor Performance</ENAMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adams</ENAMEX>, citing
what he called the "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Five P</ENAMEX>'s."
And poor performance isn't afforded much leniency. According to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adams</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX> law says that those representing themselves are held
to the same standards as an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> with respect to knowledge of
both the law and legal procedures.
Fridlund-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Horne</ENAMEX> suggested starting by researching the specific
legal issue at stake at a law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">People's Legal Services</ENAMEX>
makes one available to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> at its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">222</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">E. Birch</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Avenue</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">librarians</ENAMEX> there can offer limited assistance in
finding the needed information.
Once a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> has a general idea what area of the law is at
issue, he or she should consult with an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX>, taking advantage
of the free consultations that many offer. Fridlund-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Horne</ENAMEX> suggested
starting with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yellow Pages</ENAMEX> to find the right <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX>.
But, like a mechanic, she said, "the best way to find an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> would be by word of mouth."
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> can give basic advice about what will need to be
done to file a lawsuit, or to defend against one. But after that,
you're on your own.
Library research and consultation, however, are only part of
your preparation. An understanding of courtroom procedure is vital
before you try to represent yourself.
Fridlund-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Horne</ENAMEX> recommended that a layperson attend several
trials, especially in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courtroom</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> who will hear
their case, to gain familiarity with the courtroom atmosphere and
procedure. The court system is open to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">observers</ENAMEX>, with very few
exceptions, and such an opportunity ought not be missed.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adams</ENAMEX> warned against taking courtroom television as an accurate
depiction of a real courtroom.
"Do not use <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judy</ENAMEX> as a role model -- except for how not to
do it," he said.
In a real <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courtroom</ENAMEX>, he and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fridlund-Horne</ENAMEX> agreed, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s
entire demeanor is a part of the evidence that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> sees. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> a witness presents himself affects the credibility of his
testimony.
"Your credibility begins when you open your mouth," she said.
"You should be very respectful."
That respect, she said, need not be for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> personally.
But his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> deserves and demands it.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adams</ENAMEX> suggested a simple rule for behavior while representing
yourself: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mean</ENAMEX> what you say, say what you mean, and don't do it in
a mean way," he said. And, of course, he said, demonstrate the
facts with cold, hard evidence.
"What the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> really wants are the facts -- he wants to make a
good decision," he said.
Proper <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> and presentation of those facts, then, is
essential to representing yourself successfully. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adams</ENAMEX> recommended
focusing on the basics: who, what, where, when and how. These
should be the core of someone's opening and closing statements.
For the actual presentation of the facts, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adams</ENAMEX> suggested simple
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">storytelling</ENAMEX>, his method of choice as an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> communicating the
facts of a case to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>.
"You're trying to create a painting, using words," he said.
"That is the art of advocacy."
The story, however, must be backed with evidence. Bearing in
mind, then, that the stories told in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> will almost certainly
diverge from one another, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX> emphasized that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> should
do whatever possible to obtain objective evidence to confirm his or
her story. That evidence can include corroborative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> -- and
even a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">layperson</ENAMEX> representing himself has the power of subpoena to
require testimony.
Fridlund-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Horne</ENAMEX> cautioned particularly against trying too hard to
disprove the opposition, instead of presenting positive evidence to
prove one's own case.
"Focus on proving your side," she said.
But above all, she said, show respect to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>, to the
opposition and to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX>, in dress, in speech and in general
bearing.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judges</ENAMEX> certainly appreciate it. And often, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adams</ENAMEX>,
they will return the favor.
"I admire you for trying to do this on your own," he said. "You
have the right -- and I think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> respect that."
For smaller cases, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> suggested trying alternative
dispute resolution, a service offered by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Coconino County</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Superior Court</ENAMEX> and most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX>. It may consist of working with a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mediator</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>-conducted settlement conferences, arbitration,
private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mediators</ENAMEX> or other methods.
It's a service to help you stay out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courtroom</ENAMEX>, he said.
You can request it after filing your complaint, but, as with
anything filed with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>, nothing can be done about your request
until the other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> responds.



