



Unlikely <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX> puts <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> on national team
By Maribel Villalva
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday, Feb. 9, 2003</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Florentino</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lico</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Subia</ENAMEX>'s entire life history is inside his
Chihuahuita <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South El Paso</ENAMEX>.
He sits in his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen</ENAMEX> and points to the adjacent <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> where he
was born. He goes to another <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> and pulls out a handful of
legal-size envelopes with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of black-and-white photographs
that document <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">his days</TIMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boxer</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Korean War</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veteran</ENAMEX>, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">motorcyclist</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>.
But the envelope that continues to grow <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each year</TIMEX> is the one
with pictures of him with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">first lady</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laura Bush</ENAMEX>,
along with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> cards he's received from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> over the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. It's a friendship that began spontaneously <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about five years</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ago</TIMEX> and changed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Subia</ENAMEX>'s life.
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> look at me and wonder why I'm <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> with him," Subia
said. "But he took a liking to me."
Subia was nominated by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> of directors
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services Corp.</ENAMEX> -- a nonprofit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> dedicated
to providing legal services to low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last weekend</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Subia</ENAMEX> traveled to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>, along with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominees</ENAMEX>,
to meet with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> of directors.
His name has been submitted to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> for confirmation, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organization</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> expect <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Subia</ENAMEX> to be approved in the next few
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mauricio Vivero</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Subia</ENAMEX>
made a great impression on everyone at the meetings.
"He provided some valuable insight to us because he comes here
as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are eligible for our
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">services</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vivero</ENAMEX> said. "If approved, he's going to be a fresh
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">voice</ENAMEX> and a great contributor to this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX>."
Subia, who quit high school at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 14</TIMEX> to help his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and who
has never earned <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than</NUMEX> minimum wage in his life, never imagined
he could <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> serve on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> at the request of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. And while he's nervous about his new duties, it's the
words then-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> told him that give him the confidence he
needs.
"He told me, 'You just keep on being <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lico</ENAMEX>. You've got common
sense, and those are the kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> I like,' " <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Subia</ENAMEX> said.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Subia</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">28 years</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mickie Subia</ENAMEX>, traveled to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX> While <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Subia</ENAMEX>'s trip was paid for by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organization, Mickie's</ENAMEX> was not. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Friends</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> pulled enough
money together to send <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mickie</ENAMEX> on the trip. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Subia</ENAMEX> said he wanted to
share the experience with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mickie</ENAMEX> was more than happy
to go.
"It felt really nice that everybody got together to do something
for us," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mickie</ENAMEX> said.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cesar Viramontes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">International Garment Processors</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El Paso</ENAMEX>, was one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> who pitched in for the trip.
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lico</ENAMEX> likes to be recognized as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biker</ENAMEX>, but I'm sure he's very
happy and proud to be assigned to anything by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Viramontes</ENAMEX> said. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lico</ENAMEX> can offer a lot of input from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">perspective</ENAMEX> of a barrio <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>, and he's also someone who is always
helping other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>."
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Subia</ENAMEX> never hides his identity. He bought a suit for the first
meeting with the other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX>, but by the second
meeting, he wore the clothes all <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El Pasoans</ENAMEX> recognize him in: his
jeans, leather jacket and bandanna.
"They got to see who I really am," he said.

A strange twist of fate
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Subia</ENAMEX>'s friendship with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bushes</ENAMEX> began through a tragic event
in his life -- the death of his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Florentino</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nunie</ENAMEX>"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Subia Jr.</ENAMEX>
It was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Father</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Day, 1980</TIMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Subia</ENAMEX> got the call all parents
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dread</ENAMEX>. Nunie was killed instantly in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">motorcycle-car</ENAMEX> accident in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX>.
"That was the hardest day of my life. I think I got all my gray
hair in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the two weeks</TIMEX> after that," he said.
To memorialize his son, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Subia</ENAMEX> asked his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist friend</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Felipe</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Adame</ENAMEX> to paint a mural at his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>. The mural depicts two
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">motorcycles</ENAMEX> in the back of a pickup, which is headed toward the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">beach</ENAMEX>.
At about the same time, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El Paso</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">gallery</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adair Margo</ENAMEX> was
involved in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Junior</ENAMEX> League of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El Paso</ENAMEX> project that was documenting
murals in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, which is how she came across <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lico Subia</ENAMEX>'s home.
Then, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margo</ENAMEX> was giving a tour of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s murals to
then-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">first lady</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laura Bush</ENAMEX>, they stopped at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">met Subia</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mickie</ENAMEX>. She returned to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a later</TIMEX> visit
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">first lady</ENAMEX> even tried on his leather jacket and posed for a
picture on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Subia</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">motorcycle</ENAMEX>.
When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Subia</ENAMEX> finally met the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few days later</TIMEX> at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chamizal National Memorial, Subia</ENAMEX> needed no introduction.
"He told me, 'You don't have to tell me who you are. My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>
told me all about you,' " he said.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margo</ENAMEX> said both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lico</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mickie</ENAMEX> have an unforgettable quality
about them, which is why the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">Bushes</ENAMEX> have always wanted to see them
on their trips to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El Paso</ENAMEX>.
"They are just who they are," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margo</ENAMEX> said. "That's why I love
when things (like the nomination) happen to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are not
clamoring for it. Lico was never seeking this, but the president
recognized a quality in him."
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Subia</ENAMEX> acknowledges that none of this would have happened if it
weren't for the mural outside his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>. He said his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> is looking
out for him from beyond the grave.
"I would prefer to have my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> alive and to be with him, but he
did help open a lot of doors for me."
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Subia</ENAMEX>'s new role in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services Corp.</ENAMEX> will require him to
work on behalf of poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> who are requesting legal
assistance. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Subia</ENAMEX> is no stranger to helping <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.
Even though he and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> are low-income, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Subia</ENAMEX> has never
shied away from raising money for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> less fortunate than
himself.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Subia</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">motorcycle</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX>, the Iron <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Horses</ENAMEX>, which
raises money <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year-round</TIMEX> for a variety of causes, but mostly to help
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>.
"The way I see it, I got it made in the shade," he said. "There
are some really needy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> out there."




