



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maryland</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid Bureau</ENAMEX>: A national <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, January 4, 2003</TIMEX>
When it comes to nationally ranked <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX>,
several come to mind: the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Terps</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johns Hopkins University</ENAMEX> and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baltimore Symphony</ENAMEX>, just to name a few.
Here's another <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to add to the list <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Co</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid Bureau</ENAMEX>,
founded in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1911 and today</TIMEX> recognized nationally for its leadership
in providing civil legal services to the poor.
"In terms of delivery of service, innovation, and diversity in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid Bureau</ENAMEX> is in the forefront of programs
around the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> that promote access to justice," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha</ENAMEX>
Bergmark, senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX> for projects at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Legal</ENAMEX>
Aid and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defender Association</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>
"<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> has a lot to trumpet," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bergmark</ENAMEX> added. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bureau</ENAMEX> has become a lead <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice community</ENAMEX> by
building <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partnerships</ENAMEX> with other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> and the
mediaCoall critical components to make justice available to all in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maryland</ENAMEX>."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John A. Tull</ENAMEX>, a private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultant</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> who has worked
with legal services <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than 30 years</TIMEX> and is a
former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX> of the national <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services Corp.</ENAMEX>, said
Legal Aid "really stands out for its remarkable sense of commitment
to make a difference in the lives of its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>."
That's particularly noteworthy because of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tenor</ENAMEX> of the times
for legal services, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tull</ENAMEX> added, noting that funding concerns and
Congressional restrictions could dampen zealous and creative
advocacy.
For academic recognition, you don't have to go far.
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid</ENAMEX> now offers some of the most creative services for
legal aid found across the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael A. Millemann</ENAMEX>, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Multnomah County</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ore.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid Service</ENAMEX>. "It has
state-of-the-art intake and has recruited some excellent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> to
its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>."
A private, nonprofit law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> around <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid Bureau</ENAMEX> boasts a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$15 million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> budget, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly 300</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 140</NUMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>) and handles <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 50,000</NUMEX>
cases <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bureau</ENAMEX>, headquartered in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore</ENAMEX>, is the
cornerstone of civil legal services in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> responsible for propelling the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bureau</ENAMEX> into the front
rank of legal service <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX> nationally was executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles H. Dorsey Jr.</ENAMEX>, who led the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1974</TIMEX> until his
death in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>.
Under <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dorsey Co</ENAMEX> who grew up in segregated <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore</ENAMEX>, was the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduate</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Loyola College</ENAMEX> and the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX>
to serve on the state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board of Law Examiners Co</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bureau</ENAMEX> expanded
into a statewide law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> that reached out to the rural as well as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">urban</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poor</ENAMEX>.
Dorsey was also a driving force behind <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid</ENAMEX>'s downtown
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX>, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> specifically designed
and built to house a legal services <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX>. Building on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">foundation</ENAMEX> established by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dorsey</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilhelm H. Joseph Jr.</ENAMEX>, who
became executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>.
Millemann, who worked at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX> beginning in
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late 1960s</TIMEX>, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph "</ENAMEX>has exceeded my expectations of what's
possible by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">500 percent</NUMEX>. He's attracted good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, generated
enthusiasm, and gained the respect of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX> and the law
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>."
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> indication of that success is funding. To raise money from
the private bar, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph</ENAMEX> created the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Equal Justice Council</ENAMEX>,
spearheaded <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> by retired <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Piper Rudnick</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managing partner</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Decatur</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">H. Miller</ENAMEX>.
The result? Since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid</ENAMEX> has increased its annual
revenue by <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6 million</NUMEX>, renovated all of its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> and increased
staff salaries <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Co</ENAMEX> which helps explain why <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX> out of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX> (or
managing) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> around the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> are former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid</ENAMEX> lawyers
who returned after stints in private or government <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">practice</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">beneficiaries</ENAMEX> of the improvements are <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>,
who include <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> of subsidized and public housing, the
elderly, migrant farm <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>, and neglected and abused <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>.
Examples of this bread-and-butter work include highly contentious
custody disputes, cases involving sub-standard housing and loss of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">shelter</ENAMEX>, and the loss of disability and other health benefits, to
name a few.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bureau</ENAMEX>'s major objectives are to increase economic stability
of its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>, preserve affordable housing, and stabilize families
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX>. Yet the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bureau</ENAMEX>'s efforts go beyond helping
individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>. Those objectives include making changes in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">systems</ENAMEX> that affect the poor.
For example, one ongoing project (funded by the Abell
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foundation</ENAMEX>) works to decrease employment barriers to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">45,000</NUMEX>
non-custodial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fathers</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore</ENAMEX> whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>-support obligations
(especially money owed to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>) exceed their ability to
pay.
"Current <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> support policies are driving many of them out of
the above-ground economy," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hannah E. M. Lieberman</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bureau</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of advocacy. "Without change, we're consigning
another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> to entrenched poverty."
Another example: housing preservation. Under a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three-year</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Department of Housing and Urban Development</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid</ENAMEX> is
helping <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Marylanders</ENAMEX> living in properties
where federal subsidies are about to run out.
In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Annapolis</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bureau</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20-year</TIMEX> representation of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bloomsbury</ENAMEX> public housing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">project</ENAMEX> resulted in a victory that will
result in the relocation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> Co many of them elderly and
disabled <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Co</ENAMEX> to new waterfront <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">housing</ENAMEX> that will keep the last black
neighborhood in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> intact.
"Instead of moving to a remote area far from jobs, shopping,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and public transportation, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> will move a block
to new housing that will conform to historic-area building
standards on a former parking lot on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">College Creek</ENAMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LaBella</ENAMEX>, chief <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bureau</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anne Arundel County</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>.
While <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid</ENAMEX>'s efforts historically have been aimed at
helping the poorest of the poor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Co</ENAMEX> because of funding limitations,
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only about 20 percent</NUMEX> of eligible potential <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> are served Co
some recent technological innovations will also help meet the civil
legal needs of both low- and moderate-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX>.
In partnership with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maryland Legal Assistance Network</ENAMEX>, a
project of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maryland Legal Services Corp.</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bureau</ENAMEX> is
developing a centralized intake and referral system for all legal
service <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX> around the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">state Co</ENAMEX> in other words, a legal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hotline</ENAMEX> with onestop shopping.
The effort, now in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the final months</TIMEX> of a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 million</NUMEX> grant
received by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MLSC</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years ago</TIMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Soros</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Open Society</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institute</ENAMEX> to create a national demonstration project, is the
largest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundation</ENAMEX> grant ever to a state legal services
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organization</ENAMEX>.
Other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MLAN</ENAMEX> projects include a Web site for the general public
called the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peoples Law Library</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">peoples</ENAMEX>-law.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">org</ENAMEX>) that increases
public access to legal information and legal pro se assistance for
a variety of common legal problems. Another Web site,
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MDJustice</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">org</ENAMEX>, assists legal services and private pro bono
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> to better serve low- and moderate-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>.
The bottom line? It's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid</ENAMEX>'s commitment to justice.
"We at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bureau</ENAMEX> have the most exciting and satisfying jobs in
the world," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bureau</ENAMEX>'s executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>. "In a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">society</ENAMEX> that stresses individual achievement <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Co</ENAMEX> where you pull
yourself up by your bootstraps <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Co</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid Bureau</ENAMEX> helps those
without boots.
"By providing access to justice to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">tens of thousands</NUMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marylanders</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> and support <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> bring
equity and stability to society."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert J. Rhudy</ENAMEX> is executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maryland Legal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Services Corp.</ENAMEX> He can be reached at rhudy@mlsc.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">org</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Surkiewicz</ENAMEX>
is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of communications at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid Bureau</ENAMEX>. His
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">email</ENAMEX> is jsurkiewicz@mdlab.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">org</ENAMEX>.



