



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Daily</ENAMEX> Law Bulletin

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Online Resources Available</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid Attorneys</ENAMEX>

<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam W. Lasker</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 1, 2002</TIMEX>
A local technology <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">center</ENAMEX> has opened the doors to a statewide
Internet community for legal aid <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX> and pro bono
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Illinois Technology Center for Law</ENAMEX> & the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public Interest</ENAMEX>
launched <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> new Web sites <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> that will allow the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s
legal services <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> to swap training information, to maintain
individual listings of services and volunteer opportunities and to
schedule events on an electronic calendar.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ITC</ENAMEX>, housed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>-Kent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">College of Law</ENAMEX> and funded in
large part by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Bar Foundation</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lawyers Trust Fund of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services Corp.</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>, developed
the online <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> in what is promised to be a userfriendly
environment.
"We are replacing the older test <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">site</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">two</NUMEX> dynamic
database-driven Web sites ... with content-management system
software," said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ITC</ENAMEX> Executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lisa A. Colpoys</ENAMEX>. "It sounds
complex," she added, "but it really allows nontechnical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like
me and other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> to add content directly to the Web sites so
they become a legal aid community online."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Contributors</ENAMEX> need only be able to use Internet browsers and
basic word processing and email programs, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Colpoys</ENAMEX> said.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">illinoislegalaid</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">org</ENAMEX> and www.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">illinoisprobono</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">org,</ENAMEX>
include a list of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 90</NUMEX> state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>, most of which
provide direct legal services to indigent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>. Staff <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> at
those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> can update the online information about the services
they provide and they can add to an electronic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> of legal
information in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> different practice areas -- without leaving their
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX>.
"We're really relying on our legal aid <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">partners</ENAMEX> across the state
to build this legal-services <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Colpoys</ENAMEX> said. "Each practice
area contains information for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> to learn about that area of
law so they can get training or support ... without having to go to
the [actual] <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX>."
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ITC</ENAMEX> has enlisted legal services <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> from across the
state to manage each of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> categories, and those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteers</ENAMEX>
will organize contributions and add them to a searchable
database.
Private practice <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> looking for pro bono work can visit
the illinoisprobono.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">org</ENAMEX> Web site, which has a list of volunteer
opportunities from each of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> can search
through that listbased on criteria including the location where the
work needs to be done and the field of law in which it
concentrates.
"It's providing an avenue for increasing communication through
legal interest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> really have an
opportunity to reach out to the general legal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> by posting
volunteer opportunities," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Colpoys</ENAMEX> said.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anne Stalder Nelson</ENAMEX>, executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabrini Green</ENAMEX>
Legal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aid Clinic</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>, said the Web sites will serve as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resource</ENAMEX> that previously would have come at significant cost.
"As the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of a small legal aid <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clinic</ENAMEX>, this is huge for
us -- it's giving us access to resources we wouldn't otherwise be
able to afford," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nelson</ENAMEX> said. "It's coordinating legal services in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX> in a way that hasn't ever been done before."
She expects the Web sites will help promote smaller legal aid
providers among the general legal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX>, which will help
attract more volunteer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nelson</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ITC Board</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Directors</ENAMEX>, also said the available training materials, the
online calendar and the message <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX> will save a lot of time in
getting new interns and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteers</ENAMEX> up to speed.
"To the small legal aid <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX>, it helps us do our jobs much
better so we can spend more of our time doing what's important,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nelson</ENAMEX> said.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ITC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert A. Glaves</ENAMEX> is the executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Bar Foundation</ENAMEX>, which provides funding to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 40</NUMEX>
local legal aid <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>, and he said the Web sites will help those
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> run more efficiently.
"It's going to reduce the duplication of efforts and it's going
to increase efficiency by increasing the communication among people
doing similar work," he said. "The collective knowledge comes
together and saves them time that they can spend on their
cases."





