



New funding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> sought for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foundation</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> asks
businesses to donate
By <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Fimea</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arizona Business Gazette</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 31, 2002</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Rubin</ENAMEX> thinks the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arizona Bar Foundation</ENAMEX> should look beyond
the law office
for financial support.
"We hear from a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who don't believe the government
should provide legal services," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rubin</ENAMEX>, who began his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one-year</TIMEX>
term as foundation <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX>. "I want to challenge them
to see what they can provide. The business community could deliver
funds and help with real needs. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who use legal services
are good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are just down on their luck."
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bar Foundation</ENAMEX> funds legal aid for the poor and educational
programs at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>. Its budget comes from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> contributions,
grants and interest from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">trust</ENAMEX> accounts, For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">foundation</ENAMEX> awarded <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">nearly $950,000</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> (see sidebar).
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rubin</ENAMEX>, a sole practitioner in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tucson</ENAMEX>, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundation</ENAMEX> has
"quietly done a fabulous job" at legal services and civics
instruction. Where it's fallen short is in getting its message
across.
"We haven't been as good at communicating our story," he
said.
"We provide services to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> all over the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX>
has sent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">delegations</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX> to learn how our justice system
works. You can't have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">democracy</ENAMEX> without also having a place to
resolve disputes."
As he begins his term, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rubin</ENAMEX> faces an altered funding landscape
for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> primary legal-aid <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community Legal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Services</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Phoenix</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern Arizona Legal Aid</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tucson</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">People's Legal Services</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Flagstaff</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arizona Equal Justice</ENAMEX>
Campaign has secured a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three-year</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.4 million</NUMEX> commitment through
a campaign that asks <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arizona Bar</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> to contribute the
equivalent of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">billable hours</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annually</TIMEX>.
"We're friendly <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX>. I've made my <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two-hour</TIMEX> pledge,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rubin</ENAMEX> said. The difference is that besides the "big <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>," the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">foundation</ENAMEX> also gives money to smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catholic</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Services and the Southern Arizona People's Law Center</ENAMEX>. "We
also fund a program at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">ASU</ENAMEX> law school where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> help the
homeless get reacquainted with the legal aspects of society," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rubin</ENAMEX>
said. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> show them how to get a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX>'s license or deal
with income taxes, things that we take for granted." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rubin</ENAMEX> has held
nearly every position within the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundation</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">treasurer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">president-elect</ENAMEX> - since joining its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>. He
has watched as the trust
account fund has swelled and contracted, depending on the
pricing whims of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX>.
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>, for example, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundation</ENAMEX> awarded <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$788,000</NUMEX> in grants
- a drop of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">nearly $200,000</NUMEX> - because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> reduced the interest
rates paid on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">trust</ENAMEX> accounts. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Funding</ENAMEX> has returned to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">pre-2000</ENAMEX> level, for which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rubin</ENAMEX> credits former foundation <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Gaona</ENAMEX>.
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX> did a tremendous job," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rubin</ENAMEX> said. "He'd meet with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> and after his meetings, the rates would go up."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rubin</ENAMEX> doesn't expect interest rates on the trust accounts to
suddenly increase - "the highest rates <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> are less than they
were <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 years ago</TIMEX>; that's the economy" - but he said the foundation
must continue to advocate its cause.
"The funds we get from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> reflect a decision to part with
money that they could use for other purposes," he said. "We have to
make the case that our mission is important to them."
Besides his legal career, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rubin</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founder</ENAMEX> of an online
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bookstore</ENAMEX> (lawyerbriefs.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>) that reviews <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">law-based</NUMEX> novels. The
site lists about 600 titles from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past 20 years</TIMEX>, with reviews of
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about one-third</NUMEX> of the books.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Lescroart</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Lashner</ENAMEX> are among <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rubin</ENAMEX>'s favorite
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>; he is less enamored of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Grisham</ENAMEX>.
"My purpose is to see if these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> stay reasonably true to
the law and don't get too fanciful," he said. "It's a hobby that
doesn't get too much time <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX>."
When he looks back a year from now, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rubin</ENAMEX> said he hopes the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">foundation</ENAMEX> has new programs, a higher profile and a rejuvenated
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX>.
"I want to leave knowing I started us on the road to bigger and
better things," he said.





