



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Jersey Law Journal</ENAMEX>

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N.J. Legal Services Consolidated Plan Panned</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Passaic</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary P. Gallagher</ENAMEX>,

<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday, October 14, 2002</TIMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Passaic County</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid Society</ENAMEX> is suing to block a
proposal to reduce <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX> legal-services areas to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>,
claiming the consolidation is a concerted effort to defund the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Passaic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">branch</ENAMEX>.
The federal court suit, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Passaic County</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid Society</ENAMEX> v.
Legal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Services Corp.</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">02</NUMEX>-CV-<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3866</TIMEX>, names as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defendants</ENAMEX> the national
Legal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Services Corp.</ENAMEX>, which distributes federal grants to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">providers</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX>, which distributes
state money.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Passaic Legal Aid</ENAMEX> argues that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> has effectively debarred it
from receiving future grants without providing the notice and
hearing required by law.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Passaic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> is refusing to join in that reconfiguration,
which goes into effect <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 1</TIMEX>. Deputy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maxim Thorne</ENAMEX> says
the plan would threaten innovative programs that have expanded the
range of services offered, and won awards and broad community
support.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSNJ</ENAMEX>, on the other hand, say <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Passaic Legal Aid</ENAMEX>
voluntarily sacrificed its chance for federal funding. They say the
local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> seeks special treatment by being exempted from
requirements that apply to all LSC grantees in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>.
"It was <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Passaic</ENAMEX>'s choice not to be part of the consolidation,"
says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSNJ</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melville D. Miller, Jr.</ENAMEX> None of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s
other legal services <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">programs</ENAMEX> opposes the reconfiguration, adds
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miller</ENAMEX>, who is a named <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defendant</ENAMEX> in the suit.
Under the reconfiguration plan, only <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Essex-Newark Legal Services</ENAMEX>
would continue to serve a single <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">county</ENAMEX>. The rest of the state
would be divided into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> regions of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">counties</ENAMEX> each.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Passaic County</ENAMEX> has been rolled into a <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Northeast</ENAMEX> service area that
also includes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bergen</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hudson</ENAMEX>. At present, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX> serve a
single <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">county</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> serve <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">counties</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> serves <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>.
The reconfiguration is part of a nationwide effort by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> to
boost cost-effectiveness by reducing the number of providers
through a competitive bidding process imposed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> under a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> law. As a result of the process, many <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>, including <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maine</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Connecticut</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> now have only a single LSC
grantee, while <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> have a mere <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bergen</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hudson</ENAMEX> have submitted a joint bid to serve the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bergen-Hudson</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Passaic</ENAMEX> area. Though <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Passaic</ENAMEX> submitted its own bid,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> deemed it nonconforming because it disregarded the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reconfiguration</ENAMEX> and sought to continue serving only <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Passaic</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">County</ENAMEX>.
Because it is now too late to submit a proper bid, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Passaic</ENAMEX> will
not receive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> funding in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX>. That will leave almost a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$400,000</NUMEX>
hole in its budget of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">over $2 million</NUMEX>, estimates <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Passaic Executive</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Atlas</ENAMEX>.
That is bad but not fatal news. "If all we lost was the federal
money, we could easily accommodate that," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Atlas</ENAMEX>.
He and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thorne</ENAMEX>, however, say the loss of federal funds is the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> step in a process that will also cost them <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $1.5 million</NUMEX>
in state funding, which makes up the bulk of their budget. Most of
the state funding is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IOLTA</ENAMEX> money and state appropriations funneled
through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSNJ</ENAMEX>.
And, says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Atlas</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSNJ</ENAMEX> seems to be in lockstep with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>."
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miller</ENAMEX> would not say whether <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Passaic</ENAMEX>'s loss of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> grant
would be followed by a cutoff of state funding, but comments, "we
have only, historically, had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">provider</ENAMEX> in any geographical
service area." The consolidation has not cost any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> jobs but
will reduce the number of executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX>, he adds.


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'Hostility</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Antagonism</ENAMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSNJ</ENAMEX> originally proposed a state plan that would leave the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Passaic</ENAMEX> area separate because of its size and problems that made it
an undesirable merger <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partner</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX> for programs, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randi Youells</ENAMEX> rejected that
suggestion and adopted the plan merging <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Passaic</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bergen</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hudson</ENAMEX>. In a letter <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last March 28</TIMEX>, she said her decision was based
on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> of unresolved problems with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Passaic</ENAMEX>, combined with its
"hostility and antagonism."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Youells</ENAMEX> wrote, "It is highly unlikely that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCLAS</ENAMEX> will ever be in
a position to give <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> in this service area the level of
service and benefits commensurate with the amount of resources
available to them."
A <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 2000</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Site Visit Report on Passaic Legal Aid by LSC</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSNJ</ENAMEX> and the state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Legal Services</ENAMEX> supports that view. It
found strengths like a high-caliber, diverse <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> and an active
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">community</ENAMEX> education program that includes a cable television show.
But these were offset by a poor intake system, uneven supervision,
a failure to undertake "aggressive legal work" and "a disturbing
intransigence" by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> to address longstanding morale and
turnover problems.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Four</NUMEX> former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Passaic Legal Aid</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>, who requested anonymity,
confirm that those problems drove them and others to leave the
program.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Passaic Legal Aid</ENAMEX> argues that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> used the consolidation process
to deny funding based on performance without a required hearing.
Though <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Passaic Legal Aid</ENAMEX> did meet with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Erlenborn</ENAMEX>
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thorne</ENAMEX> says the meeting was too limited in scope to
satisfy due process.
Though <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSNJ</ENAMEX> recommended keeping the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Passaic</ENAMEX> service area
separate, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Passaic</ENAMEX> Legal contends that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSNJ</ENAMEX> is acting as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>'s agent
in defunding the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Passaic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX>. Further, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Passaic</ENAMEX> charges that LSNJ
is breaching a fiduciary duty owed to local programs by competing
with them for money to fund its own programs.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Passaic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> also accuses <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Youells</ENAMEX> of retaliating against it
for refusing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miller</ENAMEX>'s suggestion to hire her as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultant</ENAMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>, an argument <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miller</ENAMEX> dismisses as "preposterous."
On the policy side, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Atlas</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Thorne</ENAMEX> contend that the combined
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hudson-Bergen</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entity</ENAMEX> would not be able to take over the community
and economic development-type services <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Passaic Legal Aid</ENAMEX> has been
providing along with the core litigation <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX> traditionally
offered by legal aid <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX>.
They boast of national recognition for their work in this area,
Award in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Passaic Legal</ENAMEX> has been marshalling political and community
opposition to the merger. For example, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Pascrell Jr.</ENAMEX>,
D-NJ, wrote to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>; the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Passaic County</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board of Chosen freeholders</ENAMEX>
passed a resolution against it; and local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayors</ENAMEX>, the state and
local bar <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX> and various community <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups clients</ENAMEX> have
written letters on behalf of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Passaic</ENAMEX> Legal Aid.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Passaic Legal Aid</ENAMEX> also met with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Assignment</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Passero</ENAMEX>
to warn that it might soon be forced to pull out of many of its
cases.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Passero</ENAMEX> says he is pleased with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Passaic Legal Aid</ENAMEX>'s work in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> and is concerned because of the differing demographics of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">counties</ENAMEX>. Compared with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bergen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Passaic</ENAMEX> has many more people
who are poor and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spanish-speaking</ENAMEX> and receive housing aid and they
should not have to travel elsewhere for legal aid, he says.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miller</ENAMEX> says they will not have to, as no <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">county</ENAMEX> will lose an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> on account of the merger.
Nor will community development help be sacrificed. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hudson</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">County</ENAMEX> was one of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> to do that kind of work, though not to
the extent that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Passaic</ENAMEX> does," says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hudson Legal Aid</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madden</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madden</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bergen County</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anna Navatta</ENAMEX> and others met with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Passaic Legal Aid</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX> and discussed the
possibility of directing some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> money to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Passaic</ENAMEX> as a
subgrantee for its community development work. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bergen</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hudson</ENAMEX>
nixed the plan <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX>.
"We were willing to explore possibilities and maybe even lend
assistance," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madden</ENAMEX>. But "the new entity does not want to have
any responsibility for administering a grant."
What the case comes down to is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>'s discretion to reconfigure
the service areas in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Kraus</ENAMEX>, who represents LSC
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Youells</ENAMEX>. A similar legal challenge in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> failed, says
Kraus, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Newark</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Latham & Watkins</ENAMEX>,
citing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O'Donnell</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eidleman</ENAMEX>, No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">00</NUMEX>-<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1901</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4th Cir.2001</NUMEX>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Harvey</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Newark</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenberg</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dauber</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Epstein</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">& Tucker</ENAMEX>, who represents <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSNJ</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miller</ENAMEX>, calls <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Passaic Legal</ENAMEX>
Aid "a renegade…that is asking the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> to buck the national trend
and the wishes of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Magnanini</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Latham & Watkins</ENAMEX>, worries that
a grant of injunctive relief could hold up <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> funding for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bergen</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hudson</ENAMEX>.
But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miller</ENAMEX> says, "I would be stunned if there was an injunction.
Legally, I don't think there's any ground. No federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> will
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">block</ENAMEX> funding for legal assistance."
Unless <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">District</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Walls</ENAMEX>, who is assigned to the
case, calls a halt to the process, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> expects to make final grant
awards by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early December</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSNJ</ENAMEX> have both moved to dismiss the case. Those motions,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Passaic Legal Aid</ENAMEX>'s request for relief are scheduled to be
heard on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 29</TIMEX>.





