



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oregon Poor Vitally Need Legal Boost</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Landauer</ENAMEX>

<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, October 22, 2002</TIMEX>
If you can't get a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>, you can't afford to be poor.
Consider this memo on a case handled through <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El Programa</ENAMEX> Hispano
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Henry Catholic Community Hispanic Center</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gresham</ENAMEX>:
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eva Cortes-Espino</ENAMEX> went to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Affordable Automobile Wholesale Inc.</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AAW</ENAMEX>) in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Southeast</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Portland</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 7</TIMEX> searching for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>. . . .
She asked to see the title, wondering about previous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> and the
possibility of past accidents. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AAW</ENAMEX> assured her that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> had
never been in an accident and had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> previous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX>. Eva was
put under . . . pressure to purchase the car immediately. Eva can't
read <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">translator</ENAMEX> was not involved. . . . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eva</ENAMEX> signed a
contract putting down <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,300</NUMEX> and financing the balance of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4,500</NUMEX> at
a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">39.6 percent</NUMEX> interest rate.
"Eva immediately had problems with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>. She tried to return
(it), but to no avail. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eva</ENAMEX>'s mechanic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> inspected the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and
found several large sticks lodged underneath the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> to prevent it
from rattling. The mechanic determined that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> had been
totaled, citing a cracked engine <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">block</ENAMEX>."
No liability was conceded, but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cortes-Espino</ENAMEX> got full
restitution. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealer</ENAMEX> took the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> back. The deposit was
returned. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">buyer</ENAMEX> was taken off the finance-contract hook. All of
this required muscle. It was applied pro bono by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert</ENAMEX>
Hamrick at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schwabe Williamson & Wyatt</ENAMEX> law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">East</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">County Legal Clinic</ENAMEX>.
Reflect also on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seth Jackson</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mack</ENAMEX>'s chances to live
an ordinary life. This recent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Head Start graduate</ENAMEX> has had a seizure
disorder since he was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 months old</TIMEX>. Rules prevented Head Start
from administering <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oxygen</ENAMEX>, so <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sonja</ENAMEX> had to be at the school
or nearby with an <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oxygen</ENAMEX> pack.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> application for <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Supplemental Security Income</ENAMEX>
to help with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seth</ENAMEX>'s care was denied. So was its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX> request. Then
Legal Aid in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Multnomah County</ENAMEX> helped with an appeal.
SSI applications require detailed information from treatment and
service <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX> to succeed. Few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> get easy, inexpensive
access to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX>' records or, in this case, to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX>'
evaluations of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seth</ENAMEX>'s speech difficulties.
Legal Aid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leslie Kay</ENAMEX> provided record-gathering and
legal expertise and prepared a case for hearing. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 26</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seth</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> learned that he is eligible for benefits. In his
kindergarten class, he can be given <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oxygen</ENAMEX> when he needs it, speech
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tutoring</ENAMEX> and other help. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mother Sonja</ENAMEX> will be able to get qualified
care for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seth</ENAMEX> and take up schooling or part-time work.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lawyers</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Todd Trierweiler</ENAMEX> & <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Associates</ENAMEX> attempt rescue
missions in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">monthly</TIMEX> bankruptcy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clinics</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>'s support staff
helps volunteer non-bankruptcy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> to enter data for those
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>' bankruptcy forms.
Volunteer pro bono and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid</ENAMEX> services such as these are
vitally needed as poor and moderate-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Oregonians</ENAMEX> try to stay
healthy in a sick economy. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Two years ago</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 18 percent</NUMEX> of low-
income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> could get legal help for their problems, a study
sponsored by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oregon State Bar</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> found. The average
statewide jobless rate back then was <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4.9 percent</NUMEX>, lowest in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nation</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Almost two</NUMEX> percentage points higher now, it's one of the
highest. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Two years ago</TIMEX> fewer than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were unemployed in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Portland</ENAMEX>. It's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">75,000</NUMEX> now.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Almost 486,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Oregonians</ENAMEX> are eligible for free civil legal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">services</ENAMEX>. But only <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">111</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oregon</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> work for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal</ENAMEX>
Aid. Low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> desperately need more private-sector
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> to volunteer services (and money) to help full-time <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal</ENAMEX>
Aid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> lift the load.
More <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>-law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX> are essential, especially in child
custody and domestic violence cases, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX> study reports.
Advocacy help is needed to increase the quantity and quality of
housing for low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, reduce unlawful discrimination and
enforce the residential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">landlord tenant</ENAMEX> act in the face of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">evictions</ENAMEX>. Cases involving collection of wages, wrongful discharge,
discrimination and unsafe working conditions have become
conspicuous as <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Oregonians</ENAMEX> struggle against a vicious economic
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">undertow</ENAMEX>.
The urgent thrust of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lawyers' Campaign</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Equal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX>, now at full flood, is to have more private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> throw
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">lifelines</ENAMEX> to the poor, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elderly</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">disabled</ENAMEX>, unemployed and
disadvantaged drowning in the legal surf.




