



<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Paralegal Honored for Aiding Homeless</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pa. Agency</ENAMEX> Lauds
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conestoga Woman</ENAMEX>
P. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">J. Reilly</ENAMEX>
If <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Valerie G. Case</ENAMEX> could achieve <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> more goal before she
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">retires,</ENAMEX>
she said she would like to see "homelessness as we know it"
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">eradicated</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lancaster County</ENAMEX>.
"The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lancaster Interagency Council for the Homeless</ENAMEX> is in the
early stages of its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10-year</TIMEX> plan to end homelessness," Case said.
"I'd really like to see that plan fully implemented before I
retire."
Working toward such a lofty goal as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">paralegal</ENAMEX> with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lancaster</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MidPenn Legal Services</ENAMEX> is what earned Case, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">52</TIMEX>, of
Conestoga, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pennsylvania Legal Services Center</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Striving</ENAMEX>
for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Excellence Award</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>.
The award is given <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each year</TIMEX> to an outstanding and dedicated
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">employee</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s legal services field.
Serving much of central and south central <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX>,
MidPenn
Legal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Services</ENAMEX> provides legal assistance with civil cases to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">people</ENAMEX>
with low incomes.
Case has worked in the field since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1969</TIMEX>, when a legal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">services</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agency</ENAMEX> was first opened to serve <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lancaster</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">York</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Reading</ENAMEX>.
Various
small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> merged over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> to form the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>,
which
serves <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">counties</ENAMEX>.
As a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">paralegal</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Case</ENAMEX> spends much of her time helping people
who
can't afford legal services obtain medical, housing, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social</ENAMEX>
Security
and other benefits from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>.
"There must be something in all of us that needs to be
needed,"
Case said. "Giving back <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> their dignity, letting them have
peace
in their lives, is a definite reward for me."
Case said the passion to help others was instilled in her in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1973</TIMEX>
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vicki Powell</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">paralegal</ENAMEX> who trained Case to work with
low-
income and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">disabled clients</ENAMEX>.
"Back then, there was no formal training in something like
this," she said. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vicki</ENAMEX> taught us how to talk to these people
without talking down to them. She taught us how to treat them with
dignity."
Case's dedication to helping others doesn't end at her office
door.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">From 1983 to 1985</TIMEX>, she was a civil <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee board</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Legal Aid and Defender Association</ENAMEX>. She was public sector
chair of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Federation of Paralegal Associations</ENAMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1984</TIMEX> to
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>.
And she was a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nationwide Employee Benefits</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Organization</ENAMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1984 to 1988</TIMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">From 1990 to 1995</TIMEX>, Case managed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lancaster Legal Services Office</ENAMEX>
and has served intermittently as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>.
Since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Case</ENAMEX> has been involved with the formation and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">development of Lancaster Interagency Council</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Homeless</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">council</ENAMEX> is comprised of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 30</NUMEX> local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>
that meet on a volunteer basis to learn about new programs and
discuss the unmet needs of the homeless and how to address
them.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">council</ENAMEX> helps homeless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> get food and clothing, enter
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> and alcohol treatment and employment programs and find
housing.
"One of the most inspiring aspects of my work is the people
around me," Case said. "When you work with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are as
dedicated as my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX>, it's contagious."



