



Business Wire

<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Philly Lawyers Lead in Pro Bono But Need to Do More</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, June 28, 2002</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">PHILADELPHIA</ENAMEX>--(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BUSINESS WIRE</ENAMEX>)--<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 29, 2002</TIMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> have reason to be proud of their collective "commitment to
make legal services available to the poor and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">needy</ENAMEX>" in the region
but the "justice system still remains closed to many" and much more
needs to be done.
That's one of the key conclusions of a sweeping <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">78</NUMEX>-page report
released <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> by the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13,000</NUMEX>-member <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Philadelphia Bar Association</ENAMEX>
and hailed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chancellor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allan H. Gordon</ENAMEX> as a "a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">comprehensive</ENAMEX> inventory of what we've done and a blueprint for the
future of our efforts to deliver legal services to those in
need."
"This report," the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chancellor</ENAMEX> added "contains recommendations
which will help ensure that our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association</ENAMEX> will continue to be a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> in the delivery of legal services provided pro bono publico
(for the good of the public)."
Such services are usually provided by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> through various
public interest programs at no fee or a reduced fee as part their
ethical commitment under the Rules of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Professional Conduct</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Pro Bono</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Task Force Report</ENAMEX>, produced by a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX>-member
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee</ENAMEX> appointed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chancellor</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX> offers <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX> detailed
recommendations to improve the pro bono efforts in the region.
These include:
-- Making pro bono a part of the culture and fabric of the legal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">community</ENAMEX> to dramatically increase participation in the direct
representation of the poor and disadvantaged.
-- Asking the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pennsylvania Supreme Court</ENAMEX> to adopt a measurable
standard of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">50 hours</TIMEX> of pro bono participation per <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>, per year
as an aspirational goal under the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Model Rules of Professional</ENAMEX>
Conduct.
-- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Honoring the Association</ENAMEX>'s historic financial commitment to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Philadelphia Volunteers for the Indigent Program</ENAMEX> (VIP) and
raising more money to increase financial support for pro bono
through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Philadelphia Bar Foundation</ENAMEX>.
-- Awarding continuing legal education credits for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> who
accept pro bono cases in a new area of practice with a one-time
award of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> additional credits suggested.
-- Requiring all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board of Governors</ENAMEX>
to take <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> pro bono case during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each year</TIMEX> of their
service to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association</ENAMEX>.
-- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reporting</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> of their pro bono <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annually</TIMEX> to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pennsylvania Supreme Court</ENAMEX> which would maintain the confidentiality
of such reports and use the information to assess the need for
increased services.
-- Encouraging large and mid-size <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">law firms</ENAMEX> to support pro bono
through sound, written pro bono policies and an <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">quantifiable</ENAMEX> means of reporting each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>'s pro bono
commitment.
--Expanding pro bono opportunities for paralegals. --Recognizing
outstanding pro-bono <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> by law <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>. --Maximizing
technology to enhance the delivery of pro bono
legal services. --Investigating the feasibility of a central
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> for all area <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> which provide legal services to the
poor.
-- Considering some type of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">billable hours</TIMEX> credit extended by
large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> to their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partners</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">associates</ENAMEX> for pro bono work and
viewing pro bono as a positive factor in employee evaluations.
-- Developing pro bono mentoring programs.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Task Force Report</ENAMEX> has been accepted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board of Governors</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chancellor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gordon</ENAMEX> has appointed a special
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">committee</ENAMEX> to be chaired by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chancellor</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">-Elect Audrey C. Talley</ENAMEX> to
consider the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Report</ENAMEX>'s observations and recommendations and suggest
possible action to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gordon</ENAMEX> thanked <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Task Force Co</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chairs Aretha Delight Davis</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seymour Kurland</ENAMEX> and all of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Task Force</ENAMEX> "for their
hard work and extraordinary service to the profession."
"I know that this report is the result of many <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">long hours</TIMEX> of
hard work, research, sound study and innovative thought," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gordon</ENAMEX>
said "It is an impressive document that is worthy of the most
serious and sustained consideration. The path which is charted in
this report is a marathon, not a sprint. Consequently, I'm sure we
will be turning to it again and again as we seek to carry out our
commitment to those who need but cannot afford legal services. That
is a commitment that we are duty-bound to honor and it is a
commitment that we can and will uphold. The journey along this path
begins <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> " he concluded.




