



A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Politician Practices What He Professes</ENAMEX>

<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gene R. Nichol</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday, December 29, 2002</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Chapel Hill</ENAMEX> -- There must be something different about former
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Georgia</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governors</ENAMEX>. I was never crazy about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy Carter</ENAMEX> while he
was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. But since he left <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>, he has led like none
other. Whether by swinging his solo hammer or by standing for peace
against the epithets of the world, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carter</ENAMEX> has become the first
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>. Some shine best as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>.
Soon, the world will be treated to a brand new ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgia</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roy Barnes</ENAMEX> was upset in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sonny</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Perdue</ENAMEX>. I had the misfortune of watching one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barnes</ENAMEX>-Perdue
debates on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">C-SPAN</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sonny</ENAMEX> didn't know much. But he knew <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barnes</ENAMEX> had
tried to do something about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Confederate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">symbol</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Georgia</ENAMEX>
flag. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Lott</ENAMEX> must have been moved.
So now <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barnes</ENAMEX>, too, will "retire" into <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizenship</ENAMEX>. The
patterns, of course, are well established. Former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governors</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX>, majority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> and the like can expect a cascade of
lucrative offers. Law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> fight for their names and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contacts</ENAMEX>.
Lobbying outfits roll out a carpet of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX>.
And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roy Barnes</ENAMEX> has an added benefit. He is apparently a skilled
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> -- having built a hugely successful trial practice in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marietta</ENAMEX> before running for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Georgia</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> have
speculated that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barnes</ENAMEX> could go to work for any number of
silk-stocking <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> for a seven-figure salary.
So it is perhaps understandable that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Gottlieb</ENAMEX>, executive
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Atlanta Legal Aid Society</ENAMEX>, initially thought it was
a joke when he received a phone message from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Governor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barnes</ENAMEX> saying
he'd like to go to work as a legal services <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>. "I've never
heard of a former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> going to work for a legal aid program,"
said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gottlieb</ENAMEX>.
But it was no joke. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barnes</ENAMEX> has confirmed that he'll join the
non-profit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six months</TIMEX>, donating his time and considerable
skills to handling the legal cases of lowincome <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Georgians</ENAMEX>. "Holding
elective <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>," he explained, "is not the only way to help
others."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barnes</ENAMEX> won't lack for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Atlanta Legal Aid</ENAMEX>
handled <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over 20,000</NUMEX> cases -- representing <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>, domestic
violence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>, desperate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> seeking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> support, elderly
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homeowners</ENAMEX> fleeced by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lenders</ENAMEX> and the like. But due to the federal
budget cuts of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past 25 years</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> was forced to turn
away <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">many thousands</NUMEX> more.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Georgia</ENAMEX> is a lot like the rest of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. Huge percentages
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> are priced out of the legal system.
So <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barnes</ENAMEX>' remarkable decision swims against the tide on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
fronts. First, as one astonished <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultant</ENAMEX> put it, "it's
refreshing to see someone leave political <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> and not cash in."
And, <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>, as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> of the legal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barnes</ENAMEX> seems to
have decided that an unfulfilled rhetorical pledge to legal
equality isn't enough.
For <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generations</ENAMEX>, we have we have declared, as a cornerstone of
constitutional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, that "there can be no equal justice
where the kind of trial a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> gets depends on the amount of
money he has." But study after study shows that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 80 percent</NUMEX> of
the legal needs of the poor in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> are unmet. The
figure is almost as bleak for middle -income <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>.
Yet, unlike many industrial <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX>, we've recognized no general
right to representation in civil cases. Less than <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1 percent</NUMEX> of our
total expenditure for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> goes to service for the poor. Most
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> do no pro bono work at all. Recent affluence has eroded
rather than expanded support for such programs. Over the past
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decade</TIMEX>, the average revenue of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s most successful firms
increased by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">over 50 percent</NUMEX>, and their pro bono work dropped by a
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>. We carve "equal justice under law" on our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courthouse</ENAMEX> walls.
But that's about as far as the sentiment goes.
It is true, I'll concede, that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roy Barnes</ENAMEX> has only committed
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgia</ENAMEX> legal services <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">program</ENAMEX>, not the rest of
his life. And he is already a wealthy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, so it's not exactly the
same thing as a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> going to work for exceedingly modest
wages.
But <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the perplexing rituals of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> politics is
listening to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> explain that he runs for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> because he is driven to "represent the interests of ordinary
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>." We accept these claims even though we know the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> has never spent a moment representing the powerless
before the campaign began, and that it would never even occur to
him to be bothered with such matters once the election is over.
Besides, even if it's just for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six months</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barnes</ENAMEX> has made it
clear he'll roll up his sleeves and be a real <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>.
He'll be trying cases, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX> after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX>. No <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>. No prepared papers.
No scripted presentations. No <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assistants</ENAMEX> toting his bags. Just a
daunting caseload and beleaguered, frightened <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>. Standing
shoulder to shoulder with those who have no one else to speak for
them. Carrying out the highest aspirations of both the legal
profession and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> democracy.
I love <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy Carter</ENAMEX>. I'm starting to feel the same way about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barnes</ENAMEX>.
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gene R. Nichol</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dean</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burton Craige</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> of law at
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UNC School of Law</ENAMEX>.)




