



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Greensboro News & Record</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 1, 2002</TIMEX>

<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lawyer</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Poor Lacking Legal Aid; The New Head of the American</ENAMEX>
Bar <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Association Calls the Dearth of Help for Low-Income Americans a</ENAMEX>
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Travesty</ENAMEX>."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Fuchs</ENAMEX> Staff <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Writer</ENAMEX>
Poor <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> are not getting the legal help they need, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president-elect</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Bar Association</ENAMEX> told lawyers
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greensboro</ENAMEX>.
"In a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two-year</TIMEX> period, the average <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> needs
legal
services once or twice," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alfred P. Carlton Jr.</ENAMEX>, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Greensboro</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">native</ENAMEX> who will take office in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX>. "Half of them go
unrepresented, which is a travesty."
The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Raleigh</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> delivered his remarks during the
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Greensboro</ENAMEX>
Bar <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association</ENAMEX>'s annual luncheon.
In his <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">20-minute</TIMEX> remarks, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carlton</ENAMEX> described providing legal
services to low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> as one of the biggest
challenges
facing the legal profession.
But it's not that there's a shortfall of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carlton</ENAMEX>
pointed
out there are twice as many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> on a per capita basis than
when
he started practicing law <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25 years ago</TIMEX>.
"The conundrum is the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> is being
underrepresented,"
he said.
Part of the solution, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carlton</ENAMEX>, is maintaining funding
for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services Corp.</ENAMEX>, a private, nonprofit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>
established in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1974</TIMEX> that provides legal aid to low-income people
in
civil matters.
For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the second consecutive year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX>
supported <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services</ENAMEX>' funding request by asking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> to
give
the group <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$329.3 million</NUMEX> under his budget proposal for next
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>.
That request matches <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services</ENAMEX>' current <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> spending
plan.
Legal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Services</ENAMEX> provides grants to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">179</NUMEX> local programs serving
every <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">county</ENAMEX> and congressional district in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>.
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services</ENAMEX>-funded <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> handled <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 1</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX> civil cases. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">More than two-thirds</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>'s clients
are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, most of them <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s conference at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marriott</ENAMEX> in downtown <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greensboro</ENAMEX> was
attended by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 100</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, including former state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme</ENAMEX>
Court <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Frye</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">District Court</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judges</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">A. Robinson</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hassell</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph E. Turner</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">District Attorney</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stuart Albright</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> from area high <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX>.




