



Poverty <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lawyers Poorer Than Ever</ENAMEX>?

Disparity in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Salaries Far Greater Now</ENAMEX>
By <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Adcock</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Law Journal</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 8, 2002</TIMEX>
It was hardly the most enlightened of times, not with the
"conflict in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indochina</ENAMEX>" rapidly becoming <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s costliest and
most divisive war.
Yet simultaneously, there was the social activism of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Warren</ENAMEX>
Court, and a national <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> moved to declare a more worthy
campaign in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1964</TIMEX>: the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">War</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Poverty</ENAMEX>.
It was a time when progressive young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> began a long
struggle - not yet won - for the right of all poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to free
and effective legal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX>. They are <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s "grayheads" of the
poverty law bench, as the new generation of public service lawyers
affectionately call them - a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> whose idealism comes at a
far steeper price, at least on the surface.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel L. Greenberg</ENAMEX> remembers a negligible difference in the
average <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> starting pay for poverty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> and their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counterparts</ENAMEX> at big <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6,500 and $7,500</NUMEX>,
respectively. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">The year</TIMEX> was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1969</TIMEX>, said Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenberg</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney in chief</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid Society of New York</ENAMEX>.
"That year, one <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> doubled the starting salary, and then the
others quickly followed suit," said Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenberg</ENAMEX>. "In part, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> were saying that they were losing the best and the brightest,
to use the phrase of the time, to the emerging new legal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">services</ENAMEX>."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nowadays</ENAMEX>, a poverty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> working for one of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>'s many
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> representing the indigent - including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brooklyn Legal Services</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lawyers Alliance</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>,
InMotion, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lawyers Committee for Human Rights, Volunteers of</ENAMEX>
Legal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Service</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bronx Defenders</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Lawyers for the</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public Interest</ENAMEX> - might begin his or her career at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$32,000</NUMEX> per
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">annum</ENAMEX>, compared with the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$125,000</NUMEX> average <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">first-year</TIMEX> associate
salary at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s larger <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX>.
Which is not to say that youthful idealism collapsed with the
incredible inflation of private law firm salaries.
"There are reasons why <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> do this work, it's about larger
things you believe in," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lynn Vogelstein</ENAMEX>, a documentary
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">filmmaker</ENAMEX> who is now a staff <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> practicing family law at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South Brooklyn Legal Services</ENAMEX>. As a filmmaker, she said, "I was
somewhat frustrated because the social impact is very indirect.
"My cases present me with incredibly interesting legal and
intellectual issues about the role of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s lives,
the responsibility the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> has in our lives - the intrusion of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> into <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s lives.
"I'm confronted by such issues <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX>," said Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vogelstein</ENAMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">36</TIMEX>, a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduate</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York University School of Law</ENAMEX>.
"Sometimes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> think you're a do-gooder and making this big
sacrifice, but the thing is - I get to practice at so many
different levels, which is something a lot of young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> in
private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">practice</ENAMEX> don't realize."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katherine R. Locker</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">29</TIMEX>, knew her calling from childhood,
growing up with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> who suffered developmental disabilities.
Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Locker</ENAMEX> became a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX>, then later went to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard Law School</ENAMEX>.
Today, she runs her own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilot</ENAMEX> project within the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Juvenile Rights</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Division of Legal Aid</ENAMEX>.
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Families</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX> need <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>, even if they don't have the
means," said Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Locker</ENAMEX>, supervising <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathryn A.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald Education Advocacy Project</ENAMEX>, named for the late
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">administrator</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York City Family Courts</ENAMEX>. With the help of
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">paralegal</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> staff <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX>, her project has a broader
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vision</ENAMEX> of legal advocacy.
"We spend a lot of time going to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and negotiating, with
the hope of resolving problems before litigation. With the
appropriate services, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> can surpass what's expected of
them."
At <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 48</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sean Delany</ENAMEX>, executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lawyers Alliance</ENAMEX>
for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, which provides business services to non-profit
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organizations</ENAMEX>, holds a perspective midway between the grayheads and
the new breed of poverty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>.
When he was at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Virginia School of Law</ENAMEX> in the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late 1970s</TIMEX>, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Delany</ENAMEX> said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tuition</ENAMEX> was modest, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,500</NUMEX> per
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">semester</ENAMEX>. Today, not only do law school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduates</ENAMEX> forego the
opportunities of a large salary, but they have these enormous
tuition debt burdens."
A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduate</ENAMEX> of a top-tier law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> may carry a debt burden of
as <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">much as $100,000</NUMEX>. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>, certainly not all, credit a
portion of tuition debt in return for public law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX>. And last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Bar Association</ENAMEX> created a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission on Loan</ENAMEX>
Repayment and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forgiveness</ENAMEX> to formulate ways to expand such credits
beyond the relative handful of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> offering such help - usually
the more well-endowed campuses such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYU Law</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard Law</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia Law School</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale Law School</ENAMEX>.
But no national standard of debt forgiveness is even near at
hand, and the help that now exists does not mean that young poverty
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> do not worry about what they owe.
"I'm in a huge, overwhelming sea of debt," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer Arons</ENAMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">28</TIMEX>, a criminal defense <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff attorney</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Manhattan Legal Aid</ENAMEX>. "So
the money thing's tough."
She chose <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYU Law</ENAMEX> over <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia</ENAMEX> specifically because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYU</ENAMEX> would
cover more of her tuition. And she chose public interest law
because otherwise, "I would have been ostracized. My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> were
Marxists, and so were my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX>."
Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arons</ENAMEX> and her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mate</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephanie Schwartz</ENAMEX> - make
something of a political odd <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid</ENAMEX>. While Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arons</ENAMEX>
was a so-called red diaper <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX>, Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schwartz</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carol</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schwartz</ENAMEX>, a law-and-order <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council of the District</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia</ENAMEX>.
"They try to see her as less of a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>," said Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schwartz</ENAMEX>
of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>. "My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> was a corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>, and he hated it.
They're both proud of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">underdog</ENAMEX> work.
"Our [criminal justice] system is scary. Most who have to go
through it are poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of color. I worked in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX>'s
office <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one summer</TIMEX>. I decided I could never be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX>."
Like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ms. Locker</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael A. Rothenberg</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Lawyers for</ENAMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public Interest</ENAMEX> became "hooked on trying to make a difference,"
as he put it, while growing up with a learning disabled
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sibling</ENAMEX>.
"I watched my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> struggle to get my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> the services he
needed," said Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rothenberg</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37</TIMEX>, who is now executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Lawyers</ENAMEX>. "Even with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> being a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>, it was
tough."
Early in his public law career, as a staff <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brooklyn Legal Services</ENAMEX>, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rothenberg</ENAMEX> worked as co-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> with
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanley Rothenberg</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moses & Singer</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LLP</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Father</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> made a successful appeal before a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social</ENAMEX>
Security administrative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> on behalf a learning disabled
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX>.
"My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> was able to help me with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>," said Mr.
Rothenberg, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduate</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYU Law</ENAMEX>. "So unlike the truly new
generation, I wasn't faced with the debt burden.
"But public service wasn't something I thought about," he said.
"I knew what I wanted to do, and money wasn't the issue."

Issue of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Money</ENAMEX>
For better or for worse, money can be an issue for young public
interest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> - whether or not they have debts. "Can you really
live on <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$32,500</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>?" Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rothenberg</ENAMEX> asked. "It's
do-able, but it's hard and there are sacrifices. I'm looking at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ways</ENAMEX> to raise salaries."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John "Chip" Gray Jr.</ENAMEX>, the project <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Brooklyn</ENAMEX>
Legal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Services</ENAMEX>, and at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">59</NUMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veteran</ENAMEX> of poverty law, said he likes
to find <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> in private practice willing to scale back.
"To cut your income by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two-thirds</NUMEX> or more, now that takes
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>," said Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gray</ENAMEX>. "We get them that way sometimes.
"I wasn't much interested in being a corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>. My mother
was a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> when I was growing up in the
'50s," said Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gray</ENAMEX>. "Your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s a big influence on you.
"So it was an easy decision for me. But there are a lot of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who have to fight their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> to do something like this,
condemning themselves to limited income.
"It takes real commitment to the importance of the work," said
Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gray</ENAMEX>. "Which I find fascinating on a substantive legal
basis."
All public law services depend on pro bono work by the private
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX>, and nearly every <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> contributes, especially in
the wake of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 11</TIMEX>.
"We try to involve our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> in pro bono right from the start
of their careers," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher K. Tahbaz</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37</TIMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Debevoise & Plimpton</ENAMEX>. "It's an important part of what a lawyer
in private practice should be doing."
Lately, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gray</ENAMEX> and his fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grayheads</ENAMEX> have been discussing
the question: With the increasing disparity in salaries between
public and private law, is it more difficult to recruit and hire
the kind of idealistic young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> who seemed to be everywhere in
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">'60s</NUMEX>?
For his part, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gray</ENAMEX> answered, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">No</ENAMEX>, I haven't noticed
that."





