



<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Antonio</ENAMEX> Express-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News</ENAMEX>

Pro-bono road show; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community Court</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carver Academy</ENAMEX> is for
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bexar Residents Who Can't Pay</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Manny Gonzales</ENAMEX>

<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, October 11, 2002</TIMEX>
For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12 years</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Idolina Pecina</ENAMEX> has wanted a divorce but could
never afford it.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This week</TIMEX>, she stood before a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>, raised her right hand and
took an oath. For better or for worse, she said, she's going to
"finally get my divorce and get on with my life."
Pecina, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">38</TIMEX>, a machine <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operator</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Levi Strauss & Co.</ENAMEX>, has
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and can't afford the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2,500</NUMEX> needed to pay for a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> costs.
Now, thanks to a new community <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courthouse</ENAMEX> that opened <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>
at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carver Academy</ENAMEX>, she'll get her divorce with the help of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bexar County District Court</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$300</NUMEX>-an-hour-plus lawyers
who are volunteering their services to bring free legal aid to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">poverty-stricken Bexar</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> are offering their expertise as part of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community Justice Program</ENAMEX>, a new facet of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Antonio Bar</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association</ENAMEX>'s pro-bono work to bring free legal services to
residents outside of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courthouse</ENAMEX>'s confines.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">community courthouse</ENAMEX> will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every second Tuesday</TIMEX> of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the month</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carver</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">217</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paso Hondo</ENAMEX>.
"The help is here," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pecina</ENAMEX> said, adding that she got help at
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carver</ENAMEX> from a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> who, if he had charged her, would have cost
her <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$800</NUMEX>. "I couldn't afford it, but now I finally get what I've
wanted all these <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>."
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Earlier this year</TIMEX>, the state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> called on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> to bring more legal services to the poor.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">community courthouse</ENAMEX>, in response, will bring to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who
meet federal poverty standards free legal counseling and court case
filing. It also will involve <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> hearing civil <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> cases
ranging from divorces to name changes.
The program is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of its kind in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> that includes
state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> presiding over hearings, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Hall</ENAMEX>, executive
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Rural Legal Aid Inc.</ENAMEX>, a nonprofit that matches
poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> across <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South Texas</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> who will work for
free.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> deals with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 10,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poor clients</ENAMEX> a year who
need legal help, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hall</ENAMEX> estimates <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 260,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in Bexar
meet poverty limits and are eligible for the community courthouse
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">services</ENAMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Twenty</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">applicants</ENAMEX> sought help from the program on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">its first day</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carver</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Eleven</NUMEX> of them filed divorce petitions -the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> step to getting divorced.
Already there's a short waiting list, but to apply call (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">210</ENAMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">227-0111</ENAMEX>. To qualify, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> must make <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">less than $11,075</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>,
or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">less than $22,625</NUMEX> for a family of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>.
"I spoke to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> before coming here, but he wasn't very much
help," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gloria Aguirre</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">26</TIMEX>, crying as she sought divorce help
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>. "In fact, when he realized I couldn't pay him, he didn't
want to talk about the case anymore.
"I've been needing a divorce for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>," she added.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karen H. Pozza</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">District Court</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phyllis Speedlin</ENAMEX>
started the community <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courthouse</ENAMEX>, recruiting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> from across
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">county</ENAMEX> to give away their time.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Antonio</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bar Foundation</ENAMEX> and the local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX> donated more
than <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5,000</NUMEX> to the program, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">organizers</ENAMEX> are looking for more
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ways</ENAMEX> to fund it, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pozza</ENAMEX> said.
They plan to open another community <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courthouse</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Mary</ENAMEX>'s
School of Law in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the spring</TIMEX> and are searching for future <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> on
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South Side</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North Side</ENAMEX>.
Already, several of the most prestigious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">law firms</ENAMEX> in the city
have sponsored a day, lending their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> to the program, Pozza
said.
"We've had no trouble at all finding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> who are willing
to help," she said.
Most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> who volunteered <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> were corporate
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX>, many of them inexperienced with family law. However,
those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> underwent training sessions, a refresher course, on
family law, which they studied in law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lawyer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamont Jefferson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Supreme Court Justice</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wallace B. Jefferson</ENAMEX>, is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pecina</ENAMEX>'s new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX>.
"It's refreshing that all these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> are just happy to have
you as their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>," he said.





