



<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorneys</ENAMEX> step up pro bono efforts
As the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s need for services grows, area's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> urge
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partners</ENAMEX> to volunteer their time.

By <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russ Rizzo</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 5, 2002</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">INDIANAPOLIS</ENAMEX>- <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Four years ago</TIMEX>, the state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> asked law
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> to address a growing problem: Not enough <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> were
donating time for pro bono work, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were left
with no legal help in civil cases.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s legal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">giants</ENAMEX> responded.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barnes</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thornburg</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s largest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>, asked all of its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> to volunteer at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">least 25 hours</TIMEX> a year helping low-income
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on the clock.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">335</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> now can bill <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">up to 50 hours</TIMEX> of pro bono
work, which is free legal service for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who cannot afford
it.
"We're saying that instead of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that week</TIMEX>-and-a-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of work for a
paying <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX>, we want you to do this good, important pro bono
work, and you're not going to get punished," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Maley</ENAMEX>, who
helped create the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>'s policy. "In fact, you're going to be
rewarded."
For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ice Miller</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>-largest
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>, have earned bigger bonuses by clocking pro bono <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ice Miller</ENAMEX> organized with the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Heartland Pro Bono</ENAMEX>
Council to provide more free help. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> receives
requests and puts a qualified <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> on the job.
"We are sending a message to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> that pro bono work is
part of their jobs as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ice Miller</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managing partner</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Art</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kalleres</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Indianapolis Star</ENAMEX> for a story published
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> have set an important precedent for others to follow,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marion County Superior Court</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David J. Dreyer</ENAMEX> said.
"When they say that everybody should do this, that makes it a
status-quo obligation for every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dreyer</ENAMEX>, whom the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> appointed to boost pro bono efforts in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX>.
"If they do it, that's what all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> should be doing."
For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than a decade</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> such as Cinergy
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eli Lilly and Co.</ENAMEX> have offered free help to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid</ENAMEX>, which
handles <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8,000</NUMEX> cases <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> full-time and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> parttime
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>.
But large law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> just now are getting organized to do similar
work, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Floreancig</ENAMEX>, general <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Society</ENAMEX>, one of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> pro bono <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX>.
Smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> also stepped up their efforts. All <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> at
Bamberger, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Foreman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oswald & Hahn</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Evansville</ENAMEX> agreed to take
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> pro bono case <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cathy Nestrick</ENAMEX>
said.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Landlord</ENAMEX> disputes and divorces are among the most common types
of pro bono cases. But the definition of pro bono work differs
among <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barnes & Thornburg</ENAMEX> used to include time working for legal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organizations</ENAMEX>, like the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar association</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maley</ENAMEX> said. The new
policy narrows the definition to providing legal advice or
representation to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who cannot afford it.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Baker & Daniels</ENAMEX> considers time spent helping neighborhood
organizations pro bono work.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> will not set a companywide goal for all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> to meet
because free time varies for each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burke</ENAMEX> said. Paying
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> for pro bono work is out of the question.
"I think pro bono ought to be that. It is what you devote to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">community</ENAMEX> and to those in need," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burke</ENAMEX> said. "That there is some
sort of financial compensation there, to me, means it isn't pro
bono."
No matter what path <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> take to offer more help, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX>
still has a long way to go to meet the need, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Floreancig</ENAMEX> said.
"We could throw as many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> as we can get at the poor and
still need more," he said.




