



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Daily</ENAMEX> Law Bulletin
May <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21, 2002</TIMEX>

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marketing Group</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Offer 'Pro Bono' Services</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kate Schott</ENAMEX>
Law Bulletin <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Staff Writer</ENAMEX>
A legal marketing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> is asking its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> to do
what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> have been doing for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapter</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Marketing Association</ENAMEX> will
offer pro bono services to legal-aid <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LMA</ENAMEX> will help the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> develop long-term business
plans and marketing strategies.
While gaining access to justice is their <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> priority, most
legal-aid <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> put marketing and development on the back
burner.
They often survive on a bare-bones budget, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteers</ENAMEX>
and generous donations
- all for the sake of helping disadvantaged and low-income
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> obtain legal services. Many legal-aid <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> have a
strong mission but lack a long-term plan, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Stankard</ENAMEX>, client
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">services</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gardner</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carton & Douglas</ENAMEX> and former
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">treasurer</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LMA</ENAMEX>.
"These are issues that we wrestle with in practice <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> of law
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX>," she said. "What is your plan? If [the legal-aid
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organizations</ENAMEX>] have a direction and a plan and goals, you have
something you can work towards."
But most legal-aid <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> can't afford and don't have the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resources</ENAMEX> to develop marketing.
"[The project] represents an opportunity for marketing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> within the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">law firms</ENAMEX> to do some of the same [pro bono
work] we ask our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> to do," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael R. Ralston</ENAMEX>, president
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LMA</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of marketing for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vedder</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Price</ENAMEX>. "It was
that recognition that led us to ... undertake this."
Although it's common for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> to offer pro bono services to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> in need, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stankard</ENAMEX> said, legal marketing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX>
historically haven't done so.
"We thought it was a great opportunity for legal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">marketers</ENAMEX> to
give something back to the legal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX>," she said.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stankard</ENAMEX> said the marketing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> will offer advice such
as developing marketing brochures, volunteer recognition and
increased advertising.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Bar Foundation</ENAMEX>, which supports <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 40</NUMEX> legal-aid
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organizations</ENAMEX>, will hold a seminar/reception with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LMA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> to
discuss the project at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 p.m.</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> at the law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sidley</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown & Wood</ENAMEX>.
To start, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foundation</ENAMEX> hopes to match <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LMA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> with at
least <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> of its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>.
Legal aid <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> are in great need of increased
awareness, says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leslie A. Corbett</ENAMEX>, executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of
Coordinated Advice and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Referral Program</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services</ENAMEX>. She
said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> provide little information to the general public
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">legislature</ENAMEX>, which need the education the most.
"[The public and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">legislature</ENAMEX>] don't see legal services as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">social</ENAMEX> service," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Corbett</ENAMEX> said. "They see it as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>'s job."
But the legal-aid <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> don't know how to spread the word about
the positive benefits of their work.
"Bottom line -- we just don't know how to do that," Corbett
said. "I think legal-aid <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> and small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nonprofits</ENAMEX> don't
even think about [public relations] and marketing because all of
their resources go into the services they provide."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julia C. Langfelder</ENAMEX> began her job as the development <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coordinator</ENAMEX>
for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center for Conflict Resolution</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a year ago</TIMEX>. Her
position is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CCR</ENAMEX>'s history and was developed to expand
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>'s reach through special events, marketing and public
relations.
"It's very new to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> and it's interesting coming
in from a [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX>] marketing background," she said. "I think in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nonprofits</ENAMEX> in general there's a lack of [marketing]."
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> reason, she said, is a due to a limited budget.
"It's very difficult but you get very creative," she said. "You
start looking into new ways of [planning events]."
In her experience, legal aid <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> are in need of
long-term plans, guidance and structure, she said.
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Marketing</ENAMEX> is a process and lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't realize that,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Langfelder</ENAMEX> said. "A lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have a misconception that this
can happen <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">overnight</TIMEX>.
"[The pro bono project] is a great asset for all of us," she
said. "This is really going to push us forward."




