



Program <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lodges Spirit</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 20, 2002</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Snow</ENAMEX> has been falling regularly for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several weeks</TIMEX>, heartening
those wishing for a traditional white <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX>. Carols are playing
just about everywhere as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shoppers</ENAMEX> hit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> for their annual
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">holiday</ENAMEX> gift-buying.
Tradition and feelings of good will are big <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this time</TIMEX> of the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>.
And a group of local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> has been doing its best <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>
to add to a goodwill tradition of its own: providing free legal
service to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> facing eviction just before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the holidays</TIMEX>.
Billed as "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Home for the Holidays</ENAMEX>," the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four-day</TIMEX> project marked
its <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> year in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Syracuse City Court</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>.
"There have been a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central New York</ENAMEX> Executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dennis Kaufman</ENAMEX> said. One woman
he represented was facing eviction with her <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, and a
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a fifth</NUMEX> on the way.
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tenants</ENAMEX> not represented by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> normally get evicted. When
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tenants</ENAMEX> have vigorous representation, the outcome is much
different," <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis Liebler</ENAMEX> said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> as
he joined <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about six</NUMEX> other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> doing pro bono work.
Across <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four days</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank H.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hiscock Legal Aid Society</ENAMEX>, along with a number of private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> -
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> of them from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mackenzie</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> - working
through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Onondaga County Bar Association</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Volunteer Lawyer</ENAMEX>
Project, offered assistance to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who went before <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">City Judge</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeffrey Merrill</ENAMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">About three dozen</NUMEX> cases, involving <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">123</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> facing eviction,
were handled, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Volunteer Lawyer Project Director</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara Romeo</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Romeo</ENAMEX> said the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> prevented <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">13 evictions</NUMEX>, had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> others
dismissed and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> other put off until after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the holidays</TIMEX> for a
trial.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Seventeen</NUMEX> evictions were delayed, giving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> additional
time to find new housing, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Romeo</ENAMEX> said. And in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> other cases, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> were not able to get extensions but were able to avert
judgments against the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tenants</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heather Stimpson</ENAMEX> and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>, were facing an eviction
proceeding <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> when she was introduced to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liebler</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">landlord</ENAMEX> was claiming <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stimpson</ENAMEX> owed <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2,750</NUMEX> in back rent, but
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stimpson</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Liebler</ENAMEX> she was planning to move out anyway because
of the poor condition of her West <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Belden Avenue</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">residence</ENAMEX>.
With <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liebler</ENAMEX>'s help, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stimpson</ENAMEX> was given until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 29</TIMEX> to move.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">landlord</ENAMEX> was not awarded any money.
"I think it's great," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stimpson</ENAMEX> said of the free legal service
when she returned to court <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> who was facing
eviction from another of the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">landlord</ENAMEX>'s properties.
"It's a lot better than having to get myself out before
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX>," she said.
Liebler on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> also helped <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Bell</ENAMEX> keep his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Columbus</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Avenue</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">residence</ENAMEX> through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the holidays</TIMEX> and into <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the new year</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell</ENAMEX>
had recently been approved to have the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> subsidize
part of his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">monthly</TIMEX> rent, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s portion of the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX> rent was going to be delayed until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX>, and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">landlord</ENAMEX> was reluctant to wait.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Liebler</ENAMEX> explained the situation in court and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">landlord</ENAMEX>, who
had already received <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell</ENAMEX>'s portion of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX> rent, agreed to
wait for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s portion. "I get to keep my place," <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell</ENAMEX>
said, adding that without <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX>, he wouldn't have known what to
say in court and would have lost the case.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">About half</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>'s eviction calendar failed
to show up, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kaufman</ENAMEX> said, noting those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> unfortunately miss
out on the free legal help being offered.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> offering her help <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> was
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edwina Schleider</ENAMEX>, whose regular law practice involves representing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">landlords</ENAMEX> in similar matters.
"This makes me feel very good coming here and doing this," she
said, noting she regularly volunteers her services to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tenants</ENAMEX> at
eviction <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> once a month.



