



Providing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid To The Poor</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Terry Russell</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Florida Bar</ENAMEX>, has spent months
pushing legislation that would provide state funding for legal
assistance for the poor. He makes a compelling case.
Legal assistance means providing advice and other help in civil
matters to low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Floridians</ENAMEX> with generally uncomplicated legal
problems. For many, it is the key to stabilizing their lives.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bar</ENAMEX> says <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">roughly 30 percent</NUMEX> of indigent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> have some
legal needs in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a given year</TIMEX>, yet <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> makes no annual
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">legislative</ENAMEX> appropriation to serve these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX>. Instead, the
state depends on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">41</NUMEX> local not-for-profit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>, funded at
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$54 million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>, and the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$172 million</NUMEX> in time donated by members
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Bar</ENAMEX> to serve these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">needy families</ENAMEX>.
These legal aid <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> providing pro bono
services do a commendable job, but they cannot meet the demand. As
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russell</ENAMEX> points out, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">some 400,000</NUMEX> legal aid cases go unassisted each
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>. He hopes a streamlined and more efficient <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> can be put
in place to ensure that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Floridians</ENAMEX> who need help have access to
it.
That <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> is provided for in The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Florida Access</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Civil</ENAMEX>
Legal <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Assistance Act</ENAMEX>, which has passed out of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committees</ENAMEX> in both
the state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> and is headed to appropriations
review.
The act proposes to create an administrative framework under the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Department</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community Affairs</ENAMEX> to contract with a statewide
not-for- profit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> to allocate funds to nonprofit legal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organizations</ENAMEX>. The cost is estimated at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10 million</NUMEX> to be obtained
from unused federal welfare funds from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Temporary Assistance</ENAMEX> for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Needy Families</ENAMEX> program.
But the funding is uncertain, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> failed to reauthorize
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$65 million</NUMEX> in supplemental <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TANF</ENAMEX> moneys. Nevertheless, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russell</ENAMEX> is
determined.
Significantly, the bill places limits on how funds can be used.
Funds may not be used to lobby for passage or defeat of
legislation, nor to provide legal advice in criminal or post
conviction proceedings. They cannot be used to sue the state or any
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> or subdivisions of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, nor any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX> or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX>. Nor can the moneys be spent to initiate or
participate in a class-action lawsuit.
Some question the constitutionality of the act in light of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> decision <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> that struck down on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First</ENAMEX>
Amendment grounds a law that limited what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> could argue when
representing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> in welfare cases. This bill, however, is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">distinguishable</ENAMEX> because it limits specific representation and does
not restrict <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> in the manner of that representation.
For every poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> that receives legal assistance, Russell
says, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> will go without any aid. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legislature</ENAMEX> should
help fund <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> that offer such assistance to those in
need.



