



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rental</ENAMEX> rules scarce in rural <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX>
By <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JASON CLAYWORTHRegister Staff Writer</ENAMEX>
05/14/2002
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iowans</ENAMEX> who live in mobile <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> face increasingly
unsafe conditions because no laws exist to govern how landlords
care for property outside city limits, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> say.
None of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">99</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">counties</ENAMEX> regulates upkeep on rental property
in unincorporated areas, according to county <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">auditors</ENAMEX>. That leaves
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rural</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">renters</ENAMEX> in mobile home <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartments</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> with few
places to turn when they encounter problems, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Simmons</ENAMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iowa Coalition for Housing</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Homeless</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simmons</ENAMEX> said he fears a disaster because of bad wiring or other
problems.
"If it's not installed properly and if it's not maintained, it
could be life-threatening," he said.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simmons</ENAMEX> works most directly with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> of the approximately
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">55,700</NUMEX> mobile <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX>. Most either rent the mobile <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> or
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lots</ENAMEX> where the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> are parked. "There's nobody telling that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">landlord</ENAMEX> to fix the property," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simmons</ENAMEX> said. "More and more we are
seeing this as a problem."
State law mandates that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 15,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX>
regulate rental <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX>. But zoning ordinances have pushed many
mobile <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home parks</ENAMEX> out of city limits, where regulations are
lacking.
"It's pretty amazing how many elected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> aren't even
aware of this issue," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Terry Nelson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Manufactured Home Owners Association of America</ENAMEX>. "A lot of people
rely on their local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> for protection."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karen Fraise</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tenant association</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Westside</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Trailer Park</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mobile Homes</ENAMEX> near <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Fort Madison</ENAMEX>, said the lack of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">oversight</ENAMEX> has caused problems for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 80</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> there.
"Just because we live in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trailer</ENAMEX> doesn't mean we're trailer
trash," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fraise</ENAMEX> said. "We're human beings."
Residents complain that the smell of a nearby septic lagoon
makes them sick. Deep holes in the road and balky water pressure
have gone unresolved for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several years</TIMEX>, she said. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Anderson</ENAMEX>, an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX>, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fraise</ENAMEX> exaggerates the problems, some of
which, he added, have not been brought to his attention. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lee County</ENAMEX>
has sewage disposal health rules, which he has not violated, he
said.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anderson</ENAMEX> said he complains that some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tenants</ENAMEX> don't take care of
the property even after repairs are made.
"When you have rental <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">properties</ENAMEX>, how the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tenants</ENAMEX> take care of
the place is what it looks like," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anderson</ENAMEX> said.
Some <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">counties</ENAMEX> rely on their health <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">departments</ENAMEX> to solve rural
renter complaints about sewage, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX>, and vacant, vermin-infested
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">homes</ENAMEX>, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Peterson</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iowa Association of Counties</ENAMEX>.
Many types of problems - such as broken doors or weak water
pressure - aren't considered health issues, he said.
"I don't know what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> do if they feel they are being
unfairly treated," he said. "I don't know where they would go to
file a complaint."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Bohlen</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">resident</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oakwood Heights Mobile</ENAMEX> Home
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community</ENAMEX> near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ankeny</ENAMEX>, said not having somewhere to turn when there
are problems leaves many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mobile-home dwellers</ENAMEX> feeling helpless. For
example, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oakwood Heights</ENAMEX> does not have a storm shelter, he said.
"The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tenants</ENAMEX> feel very frustrated," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bohlen</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">40</TIMEX>, who owns his
mobile <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> and pays <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$280</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX> to rent the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lot</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judy Johnson</ENAMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oakwood Heights</ENAMEX>, said the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">well-run</ENAMEX>. If <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> are unhappy, they can "put wheels on their
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">homes</ENAMEX> and go someplace else," she said. "There's no shelter, and
we're not going to build a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shelter</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> said. "We don't have
to. We're not breaking any rules."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Tenants</ENAMEX> of mobile home <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX> often feel forced to move when
conditions become intolerable. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> has landlord-tenant laws, but
no state or county governing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> regulates them, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robb</ENAMEX>
Goedicke, an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid Society of Polk County</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Tenants</ENAMEX> often must take their problems to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> before landlords
are forced to make changes, he said.
"The problem is the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">county</ENAMEX> doesn't have any enforcement <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goedicke</ENAMEX> said. "Who does the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tenant</ENAMEX> turn to<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>"



