



Mobile <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> sue <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> for loss, moving costs
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 29, 2002</TIMEX>
By <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jan Ackerman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post-Gazette Staff Writer</ENAMEX>
Residents and former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> Place mobile home
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">park</ENAMEX> that is being demolished to make way for a city-owned
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">community</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">center</ENAMEX> are demanding that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> compensate them
for lost <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trailers</ENAMEX> and relocation costs.
On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, a group of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> filed a lawsuit against
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX>, seeking damages for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> who were displaced and
sometimes forced to abandon their mobile <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> because they
couldn't afford to move them.
The lawsuit, filed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Neighborhood Legal Services</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association and Community Justice Project</ENAMEX>, asked the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Allegheny</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">County</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> to appoint a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> under the state Eminent
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Domain Code</ENAMEX> to determine "just compensation and relocation
expenses" for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> who still live there and for several
who already were evicted.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> has offered <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$700,000</NUMEX> for the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">7.2-acre</NUMEX> site, which
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward J. Raimondi Jr.</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Munhall</ENAMEX> bought for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$500,000</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 2000</TIMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> plans to build a community <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">center</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> Place and a
future fire <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX> on the site.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Raimondi</ENAMEX> has been evicting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> and demolishing trailers
that are left behind in order to meet a city requirement that he
present a clean piece of land with no environmental concerns.
In the suit, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NLS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eileen D. Yacknin</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evalynn B.</ENAMEX>
Welling, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community Justice Project</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX>, contend that the city
is trying to avoid its responsibilities to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tenants</ENAMEX> under state
eminent domain code and the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Housing and Community</ENAMEX>
Development Act by having <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Raimondi</ENAMEX> carry out the evictions.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> contended that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> has an obligation to pay
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tenants</ENAMEX> for damages they have sustained by being evicted for
property that will be used for a public purpose.
"Many of them were compelled to abandon the mobile <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> they
had owned for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, because they lacked the financial resources --
typically <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2,500 to $3,000</NUMEX> -- which would have been required to
move their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> from the property," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yacknin</ENAMEX> wrote.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yesterday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Deputy Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sal Sirabella</ENAMEX> said he had not seen the
lawsuit. He said the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> still maintains that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> of the
mobile <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home park</ENAMEX> must seek any compensation from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Raimondi</ENAMEX>, not from
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>.
"Our agreement of sale is with Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Raimondi</ENAMEX>, and the issues
between him and the former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tenants</ENAMEX> are his to resolve," said
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sirabella</ENAMEX>.
"I believe we have a sales agreement that has been signed,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sirabella</ENAMEX> said, adding that no closing date has been set.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">plaintiffs</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joan Tate</ENAMEX>, who is disabled, was forced to
move into a federally subsidized rental housing in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX> because of
"increasingly uninhabitable conditions in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX>," the suit
said.
Tate, who receives <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">less than $600</NUMEX> a month from <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Supplemental</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>, could not afford to pay <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">several thousand dollars</NUMEX>
to relocate her <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mobile home</ENAMEX>, which was appraised at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2,500</NUMEX>. As soon
as she moved out, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mobile home</ENAMEX> was demolished, the suit
said.



