



Retirement Has Its Appeal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lawyers</ENAMEX> Form <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Group</ENAMEX> to Offer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indigent Clients</ENAMEX>

<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christine McConville</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday, January 26, 2003</TIMEX>
It started out as one of those talks <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the end of a</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer day</TIMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Two years ago</TIMEX>, former <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Middlesex County</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward Ginsburg</ENAMEX> and
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX> were sitting by the edge of a pond in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Hampshire</ENAMEX>,
discussing his approaching <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">70th birthday</TIMEX>.
"I don't believe in retirement. I don't like that term," said
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ginsburg</ENAMEX>, recalling <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that day</TIMEX>'s conversation. Having reached the
court system's mandatory retirement age, the lifelong <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Newton</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">resident</ENAMEX> left the courtroom. But he has taken on another full-time
venture - turning into reality a vision he and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX> had on
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that summer day</TIMEX>.
Senior Partners for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX> is less than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four months old</TIMEX>, but
already <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ginsburg</ENAMEX> has some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> working for
some of the region's poorest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> provide expert
legal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> for indigent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who need help with divorces,
custody battles, and other family law matters. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> case has already
been settled; <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX> others are in the works.
The initiative is his response to a pattern he noticed during
his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25 years</TIMEX> as a family court <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>.
"There's a disconnect between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who need
their services. <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Sixtyfive percent</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in probate court
appear without <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> because they can't afford them.
"I have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> who says that going into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> without a lawyer
is like going to a foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> without a guide. Sometimes the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who represent themselves don't even know the significant
facts of their case.
"This is an effort to do something about that, while giving
older, retired <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> a chance to stay active," he said. "It helps
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> by giving them <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> to argue the cases, too."
So far, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ginsburg</ENAMEX>, who works out of an office on Longfellow Place
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>, has recruited <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>, including a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">91-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>
from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cape Cod</ENAMEX>, a retired <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>, and an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> on dividing pensions
after a divorce.
Former <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Newton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas B. Concannon</ENAMEX> has signed on, along
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lowell</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andover</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Weston</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wayland</ENAMEX>.
Retired <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herbert Hershfang</ENAMEX> just settled the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>'s first
case, a divorce.
"It wasn't complicated," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hershfang</ENAMEX> said of the case. But he
supports the cause, partly because as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Municipal</ENAMEX>
Court and other <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courtrooms</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hershfang</ENAMEX> witnessed firsthand how many
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> can't afford <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>.
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ginsburg</ENAMEX> is to be commended for filling a really
important need in our court system," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hershfang</ENAMEX> said. "He had done a
wonderful job as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>, and then as soon as he leaves, he fills
this need."
To <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ginsburg</ENAMEX>, it's just the right idea, at the right time.
"I think it's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Voltaire</ENAMEX> who said, 'There's nothing more powerful
than an idea that has come of age.'
"Everything just fell into place, and I thought, 'I've got to
seize the opportunity and run with it,' " said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ginsburg</ENAMEX>, who names
former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy Carter</ENAMEX> as a role model.
"Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidents</ENAMEX> retired, and what happened to them? They fade
away, but I think [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carter</ENAMEX>] had more influence after his
presidency."
The participating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> say <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ginsburg</ENAMEX>, a diehard <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Red Sox</ENAMEX> fan
known for his trademark bow ties, is tough to turn down.
Concannon, who at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">63</NUMEX> is still practicing full time, said he
couldn't say no to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ginsburg</ENAMEX>, a longtime <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>.
"He fished me in," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Concannon</ENAMEX> said, adding, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> need <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>,
and there's a growing amount of poor that need pro bono
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">services</ENAMEX>."
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Volunteer Lawyers Project of the Boston Bar Association</ENAMEX>
supplies the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>. That <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>'s executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>, Meg
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Connolly</ENAMEX>, said all the cases are screened <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>, to make sure they
have legal merit and that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">client</ENAMEX> meets federal poverty
guidelines. That means that an individual can't earn more than
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$11,075</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>, and that a family of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> may not earn more than
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$33,938</NUMEX>, she said.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Connolly</ENAMEX> said her program has been working to provide free legal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">services</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25 years</TIMEX>, and the demand isn't abating.
Having someone like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ginsburg</ENAMEX> working on the same problem helps
out.
"He has the cachet of being a long-standing family court <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>,
and lots of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like him," she said.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ginsburg</ENAMEX> has a lifetime of connections to tap, "and he's an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert tapper</ENAMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Reilly</ENAMEX>, executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Continuing Legal Education Inc.</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> hosts training seminars <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first Wednesday</TIMEX> of each
month to keep the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> up to date on marital law and
family <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> issues.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reilly</ENAMEX> said he has been stunned at the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who have
been showing up.
"For a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the legal services, the initial reaction
[to the program] was: 'Been there, done that; doesn't work.'
"But based on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> of [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ginsburg</ENAMEX>'s] <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personality</ENAMEX>, and that
he's at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX>, he's gotten some very senior people
on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reilly</ENAMEX> said. "You don't realize you want to do this
until he talks to you."
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> who are participating, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reilly</ENAMEX> said, "still want to
have an intellectual experience, and they want to be part of the
legal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX>.
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">And</ENAMEX>," he said, "I'm sure their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouses</ENAMEX> are delighted to push
them out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first Wednesday</TIMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every month</TIMEX>."
For more information, call <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senior Partners</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> at
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">617-523-5600</ENAMEX> or e-mail <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senior Lawyers</ENAMEX> @aol.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.




