



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roanoke Times & World News</ENAMEX>

Legal <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Aid Group Celebrates 30 Years of Service</ENAMEX>

<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Dellinger</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, November 14, 2002</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southwest Virginia Legal Aid</ENAMEX> serves <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">counties</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX> lawyers
and a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">32</NUMEX>-member <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Tate</ENAMEX> remembers it didn't start that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX>.
"The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">first day</TIMEX> I showed up at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid</ENAMEX>, I interviewed myself,"
he said. He was its only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>.
Tate, now in private practice in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marion</ENAMEX>, was hired as the
program's first <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1972</TIMEX> after a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marion</ENAMEX>-based community
action program secured grant money to establish the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Smyth-Bland</ENAMEX>
Legal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aid Society</ENAMEX>.
That was the start of legal aid in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southwest Virginia</ENAMEX>, and Tate
was among those who gathered here over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX> to celebrate its
30 years of service. It now covers localities from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lee County</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christiansburg</ENAMEX>.
"The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Smyth County</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX> was rather small, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bland County</ENAMEX> bar
was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Hardy</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tate</ENAMEX> said, referring to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who, for many
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, was the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bland County</ENAMEX>. So the effort to bring
legal services to those who could not otherwise afford them began
in a small way.
Many viewed the early legal aid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> as "wild-eyed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">radicals</ENAMEX>,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tate</ENAMEX> said. "We started with a budget that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> wouldn't pay the
salary of one staff <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>."
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> handled <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX> cases in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">its first year</TIMEX>. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1973</TIMEX>, it had
opened an office in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Abingdon</ENAMEX> and, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1976</TIMEX>, in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wytheville</ENAMEX>. Most of
its early cases involved divorce and family law. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1978</TIMEX>, it
changed its name to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southwest Virginia Legal Aid Society</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eilene McIlvane</ENAMEX>, who was not a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>, became its executive
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1981</TIMEX>. By then, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">program</ENAMEX> had added <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carroll</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grayson counties</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Galax</ENAMEX> and had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Harley</ENAMEX>, who became its executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX> and still
holds that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>, joined it in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1975</TIMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">paralegal</ENAMEX> and came back
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1979</TIMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>.
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1960s</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harley</ENAMEX> said, legal aid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> were banned from
practicing in some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX>, so the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southwest Virginia</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> became
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partners</ENAMEX> with the private bar to avoid that.
During <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 1980s</TIMEX>, federal funding for legal aid was
reduced and, by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1984</TIMEX>, only the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marion</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> was still in business.
By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 1980s</TIMEX>, state funding increased. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>, the program's
work mainly involved helping <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with food stamps, housing,
health care and other basic needs. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>, it employed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>.
"We caught our stride in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '80s and '90s</TIMEX>. We still have a long
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> to go," <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harley</ENAMEX> said. "I like to think we will never feel that
we have arrived."
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services Corp.</ENAMEX>, which is now the program's major
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">funding</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">source</ENAMEX>, began pushing in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> for smaller programs to
merge. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Between 2000 and 2001</TIMEX>, those west of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roanoke</ENAMEX> did. The board
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">New River Valley</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid Society</ENAMEX> voted to join the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southwest Virginia</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Client Centered Legal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Services</ENAMEX> in the westernmost part of the state opposed the merger,
but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southwest Virginia</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> eventually hired <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> former
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> of that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> and opened a new office in the coalfields.
Its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> are now in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Castlewood</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marion</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christiansburg</ENAMEX>.
Asked later about the program's future, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harley</ENAMEX> said it is only
now settling in to its expanded service area and seeking continuing
partnerships with the private bar and various <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>.
"We're entering a time of reduced funding for much of our work,
but we just got an increase in our domestic violence funding, and
we are working closely with the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> domestic-violence programs
within <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">our</TIMEX> service area," he said. The new funding comes through
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Department of Justice</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cynthia Kinser</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Virginia Supreme Court</ENAMEX>, keynote
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX> for the celebration, said the concept of legal aid can be
traced back to wording in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Magna Carta</ENAMEX>, but the first
version in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> was an <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1876</TIMEX> program in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> to help
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX>. That <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> changed its name to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Society</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1890</TIMEX>.
It was the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Economic Opportunity</ENAMEX> Act of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1964</TIMEX> that began providing
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">federal</ENAMEX> funding for programs to bring legal services to the poor,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kinser</ENAMEX> said. "Legal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Services</ENAMEX> has fundamentally changed how
government <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> relate to the poor," she said.





