



Rumble in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bronx</ENAMEX> over <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services</ENAMEX>
Under orders from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services of New York</ENAMEX> is
moving to take more control of its neighborhood law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX>, but
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX>, in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bronx</ENAMEX>, refuses to play along and is
taking its main funder to court to stop it.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jill Grossman</ENAMEX>
In the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bronx</ENAMEX>, where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> have the least access to legal
representation of any <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">borough</ENAMEX>, one of the few <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">law firms</ENAMEX> that
provides free legal services there is putting its funding on the
line.
For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bronx</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services</ENAMEX> has been warned that it
would have to consolidate with the rest of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal</ENAMEX>
Services system. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last Monday</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bronx</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> filed a
lawsuit against its funders, claiming these demands violate both
their contract and federal antitrust laws.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bronx Legal Services</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walker Thompson</ENAMEX> said the increased
central oversight dictated by its funders compromises his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>'s
independence. But others think the lawsuit is a mistake. "The
position that consolidation means the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> will suffer is
exactly wrong," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ghita Schwarz</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services</ENAMEX>
Staff <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX> for legal service <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bronx Legal Services</ENAMEX> is one of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">seven</NUMEX> nonprofit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> that contract with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> (LSNY) to
provide legal services to the poor. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSNY</ENAMEX>, in turn, reports to its
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">national</ENAMEX> parent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporation</ENAMEX> and primary funder, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corporation</ENAMEX> (LSC), established by federal legislation in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1974</TIMEX>. All
are chronically under funded: According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 20 percent</NUMEX>
of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">43 million</NUMEX> potential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> eligible for federally-funded
legal assistance actually get the help.
And changes made by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> didn't help matters: The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">legislature</ENAMEX> cut LSC funds by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">31 percent</NUMEX>, to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $280 million</NUMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">That same year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> also told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> to start using
competitive bidding for its contracts. Struggling to continue its
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mission</ENAMEX> of serving the poor, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> ordered each of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX> state legal
service <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> it finances to find new funding resources and to
coordinate services better.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, like many <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>, did not embrace the idea at <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>.
But recognizing that its own funding could be jeopardized if it did
not follow <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>'s orders, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSNY</ENAMEX> released a plan in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 2000</TIMEX> that
consolidates services and centralizes decision-making. While
preserving the neighborhood <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>' own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX>, the
proposed plan makes them accountable to one central <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSNY</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> for
decisions like staffing and budgets.
To date, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> have given the plan a
preliminary thumbs-up. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bronx</ENAMEX> alone refused, saying that
Legal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Services</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> might be forced to answer to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSNY</ENAMEX>'s funders
rather than focus exclusively on their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>' interests. The
plan, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thompson</ENAMEX> explained, "enhances the likelihood of the lawyer
having to look over his shoulder."
Legal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Services of New York</ENAMEX> calls that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX>--and the lawsuit
itself--unfounded. "The new system does raise the accountability
level," said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSNY</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael W. Martin</ENAMEX>. But he added that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSNY</ENAMEX> is "committed to the need of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> and to local
input"--which is why <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSNY</ENAMEX> is maintaining the local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Limits</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NY</ENAMEX>) - <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 12, 2002</TIMEX>
More importantly, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSNY</ENAMEX> has to hold onto its federal funding.
Because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> will only fund <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> that cover the entire
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSNY</ENAMEX> has to cover the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bronx</ENAMEX>. If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thompson</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> won't
cooperate, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSNY</ENAMEX> will have to break ties with it and
find another local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thompson</ENAMEX> seems willing to take the risk. In studying his <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4.6</NUMEX>
million budget, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 40 percent</NUMEX> of which comes directly from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSNY</ENAMEX>,
he determined that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bronx</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services</ENAMEX> could run on its own in two
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>--if he starts fundraising now



