



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Service Agency Tries</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simplify Legal Problems</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maine</ENAMEX>'s
Needy
By <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betty Adams</ENAMEX>

<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 17, 2002</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">AUGUSTA</ENAMEX> - <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Ninety percent</NUMEX> of the cases handled by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX>
Comart are settled before they turn into lawsuits.
That's best for his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>, he says, because most are people
with low incomes and a history of legal problems that could prove
detrimental if aired in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Comart</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pine Tree Legal Assistance Inc.</ENAMEX>, a
statewide <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> that provides free legal aid to those who
qualify.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">35 years old</TIMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">administrators</ENAMEX> estimate it has
helped <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 250,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">those years</TIMEX> with urgent legal
problems.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX> alone, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> aided <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 14,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>,
according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nan Heald</ENAMEX>, who has been with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pine Tree Legal</ENAMEX> since
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985</TIMEX> and directed it since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>.
Comart, who lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Readfield</ENAMEX>, is based in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Augusta</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>, a short walk from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Augusta</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">District Court</ENAMEX> and Kennebec
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">County Superior Court</ENAMEX>. But most of his work is done outside the
courtroom and over the telephone with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">administrators</ENAMEX> of state
programs, including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX>, and with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">landlords</ENAMEX>.
Another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> handles domestic violence cases,
and still another is on-site at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lewiston District Court</ENAMEX> every
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> to assist an average of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> facing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">eviction</ENAMEX> who
want to speak to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>.
"We deal with a lot of emergencies," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Comart</ENAMEX> said. "It's still
amazing how many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> call us up <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day before</TIMEX> or after their
hearing. They either didn't go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> or they lost at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>."
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pine Tree</ENAMEX> is dealing with fewer evictions pending in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Augusta</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">District Court</ENAMEX>. "In this area, I haven't seen too many bad
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">landlords</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Comart</ENAMEX> said.
Part of the problem, he said, is that rents are rising but wages
and public benefits are not.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> takes credit for "abolition of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">debtors</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX>, the
right to due process and a fair hearing, the first successful
employment-discrimination lawsuits, improved housing codes and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Comart</ENAMEX> said legal aid works well in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maine</ENAMEX>. He contrasted it to
his experience in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1970s</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early 1980s</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kentucky</ENAMEX>.
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX> were viewed as complete <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">outsiders</ENAMEX>," he
said. "The judicial system and the private bar had no use for us
and no support. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maine</ENAMEX> is much different. I'm sort of amazed at the
level of support by the private bar."
Through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Volunteer Lawyers Project</ENAMEX>, private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> donate
their services to do some cases for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pine Tree</ENAMEX>, including debt
collection and contract disputes.
Over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past two decades</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Comart</ENAMEX> has seen the role of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pine Tree</ENAMEX>
change in response to federal funding cuts and stricter
regulations.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heald</ENAMEX> said, "We used to have almost all of our funding from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>, general unrestricted funds. Now that is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about half</NUMEX>. The
rest are specific <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> grants that require us to do particular
kinds of work."
Some of that work includes access to health care benefits and
aiding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> that may have a housing problem but also have other
issues, such as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">disabled child</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heald</ENAMEX> said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> can try to
find mental health services, school <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX> and others. "We're
looking at the big picture," she said.
"We specialize in public benefits, housing evictions and
domestic violence," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Comart</ENAMEX> said, but added that because of such a
high volume of need and staffing reductions, "most cases are advice
and brief services as opposed to extended representation."
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> has shrunk over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past few years</TIMEX> because it's been
barred since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> from bringing class-action lawsuits and welfare
reform challenges and banned from collecting attorneys fees from
lawsuits and from doing any legislative lobbying.
Former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff attorneys</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Henderson</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Hastedt</ENAMEX>
subsequently began the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maine Equal Justice Project</ENAMEX>, which
concentrates on lobbying and class actions.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Interest on Lawyer Trust</ENAMEX> Accounts, administered by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maine</ENAMEX>
Bar <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foundation</ENAMEX>, helps to fund <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pine Tree Legal, Maine Equal Justice</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cumberland Legal Aid</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Elderly</ENAMEX>. In
addition, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> have assessed a fee on civil filings, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">funding</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">source</ENAMEX> that supports the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maine Civil Legal Services Fund</ENAMEX>.
And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coffin Fellowship Program</ENAMEX> provides money for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> who
do domestic relations work.
While <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pine Tree</ENAMEX> has income guidelines for its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> in housing
and public benefits cases, there are no income limits for those
receiving services to prevent domestic violence.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Comart</ENAMEX> said a new video-conferencing feature allows those at
domestic violence shelters to get legal help without going to
court.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> offers forms for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">renters</ENAMEX> to try to get their security
deposit returned, and forms for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who want to get divorced or
modify their divorce decree. Some of those are available on the Web
at
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ptla</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">org</ENAMEX> and can be printed out and taken to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>.
Other information is provided also, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pine Tree</ENAMEX>
does client education exclusively.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pine Tree</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> are located in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Augusta</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bangor, Lewiston</ENAMEX>,
Machias, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Portland</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Presque Isle</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockland</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">53</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>, including <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">27</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX>, some
of whom function as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">administrators</ENAMEX> and others who are part-time.




