



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Deseret News</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, April 12, 2002</TIMEX>

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kudos for Supporting Legal Center</ENAMEX>
By <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John A. Adams</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Utah State Legislature</ENAMEX> in the just-completed session has
stepped forward in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> of very difficult financial challenges
and, in honor of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleague</ENAMEX> the late <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pete Suazo</ENAMEX>,
appropriated <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100,000</NUMEX> toward the purchase of a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> to create
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s first <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community Legal Center</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Suazo</ENAMEX>, who represented <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Salt Lake</ENAMEX>'s urban and diverse
District <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2</TIMEX>, was admired by his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> for his tireless
efforts for equal access to justice for all of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community Legal Center</ENAMEX> will be located in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Suazo</ENAMEX>'s district and
is a project of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s leading <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX> of free civil legal
services to lower-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> -- the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disability</ENAMEX>
Law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Center</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid Society</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Salt Lake</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Utah Legal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Services</ENAMEX>. Their efforts, like those of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Suazo</ENAMEX>, promote economic
and family stability, fight injustice and help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> help
themselves.
These <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>, which have a total of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">84</NUMEX>
staff <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> provided legal advice or represented
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> in disputes in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over 21,000</NUMEX> legal matters. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>
resolve serious legal problems for those with no place else to turn
-- the poor, ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minorities</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">seniors</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with
disabilities. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> will also house <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> smaller
volunteer-based programs, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Multi-Cultural Law Center</ENAMEX> and the
Senior <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lawyer Volunteer Project</ENAMEX>.
Each of these not-for-profit legal service <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX> has a
specific mission or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX> base: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Utah Legal Services</ENAMEX> focuses legal
assistance to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid Society</ENAMEX>
assists <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> with domestic relations and domestic violence
issues in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Salt Lake County</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disability Law Center</ENAMEX> focuses on
assistance to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with physical and mental disabilities; the
Senior <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lawyer Volunteer Project</ENAMEX> assists elderly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> with
estate planning and end-of-life issues; and the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Multi-Cultural</ENAMEX> Law
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center</ENAMEX> provides a variety of legal aid to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX>'s growing ethnic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX>.
To their credit, these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> have been a model of cooperation
and innovation to improve efficiencies in the delivery of legal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">services</ENAMEX> in our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Several years ago</TIMEX> they formed the "and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> for All" campaign, which raises money from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">private Utah State Bar</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">law firms</ENAMEX> are among the
most generous in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>; <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $1.5 million</NUMEX> has been raised
since the campaign began.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Co</ENAMEX>-location helps the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> meet <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> important goals.
First, "one-stop shopping" will make access to legal aid and our
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nation</ENAMEX>'s system of justice easier for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Utahns</ENAMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, it will allow the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> to share some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> and
services to achieve efficiencies of operation.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last</TIMEX>, it will provide greater opportunity for volunteer service
by private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> and law <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>. It should be noted that two
of these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> also have <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ogden</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Provo</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cedar City</ENAMEX>
so that legal needs elsewhere in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> may be served.
The former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morrison</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Merrill Building</ENAMEX> located at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">205 N. 400</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West</ENAMEX> is the site of the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community Legal Center</ENAMEX>. The
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">30,000-square-foot</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> was recently refurbished by its prior
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Olafson Group</ENAMEX>, which generously donated <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$400,000</NUMEX> toward
the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4 million</NUMEX> project.
The appropriation of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100,000</NUMEX> sends a clear message that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">legislators</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Leavitt</ENAMEX> are willing to lead out and not
just give lip service to helping <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Utahns</ENAMEX> obtain access to our legal
system. It is hoped that the example of our political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>,
coupled with the generous contributions already made by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organizations</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>, including the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George S.</ENAMEX> and Dolores
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dore Eccles Foundation</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Utah Bar Foundation</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herbert I.</ENAMEX> and
Else <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B. Michael Foundation</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Salt Lake</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX>, and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">trustees</ENAMEX>, will prompt other
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">foundations</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> and private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> to contribute the
remaining funds necessary to pay for the purchase of the
building.
Apart from the capital campaign that is now under way, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> are making a major difference in helping increase access to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than a third</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Bar</ENAMEX> contributed to the "and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Justice for All</ENAMEX>" campaign, and
more than <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$440,000</NUMEX> was raised to help these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> operate and
perform their vital mission.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> pulling together for a common worthwhile cause makes all
the difference, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> starts at the top. Thanks to our
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legislature</ENAMEX> for leading out in difficult financial times.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John A. Adams</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president-elect</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Utah State Bar</ENAMEX>.




