



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Law Journal</ENAMEX>

Survey: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Most Law Students Can't Afford</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public Service</ENAMEX>

<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Adcock</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12-09-2002</TIMEX>
For those worried about the indebtedness of young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> --
and how this affects the future of government and public interest
law -- fresh anxiety arrived <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX> with a national survey
showing that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two-thirds</NUMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s law school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduates</ENAMEX> cannot
afford to think about taking low-paying jobs.
Mortgage-sized tuition debts, warned the report, have dire
consequences for the future of poverty law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> and legal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">departments</ENAMEX> in state and federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">47</NUMEX>-page report,
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">From Paper Chase to Money Chase</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Law School Debt Diverts Road</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public Service</ENAMEX>," was sponsored by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Partnership for Public</ENAMEX>
Service, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Equal Justice Works and the National Association for Law</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Placement</ENAMEX>.
At the heart of the report was a survey of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,622</NUMEX> third-year law
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">117</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campuses</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">District of Columbia</ENAMEX>.
Among the findings:


•
Nearly all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> surveyed -- <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">94 percent</NUMEX> -- borrow
money for tuition.


•
While <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">39 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduate respondents</ENAMEX> showed
significant interest in working for the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, fewer
than <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3 percent</NUMEX> accepted federal job offers.


•
Most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> -- <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">68 percent</NUMEX> -- reported
difficulty in recruiting young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX>.


•
Nationally, the average <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">monthly</TIMEX> payment to retire law
school debt on a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10-year</TIMEX> plan is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$950</NUMEX>.


•
For <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">83 percent</NUMEX> of student <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">respondents</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6,000</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> in
loan repayment assistance could mean the difference between taking
a high-paying job in corporate law versus the modest salaries
offered by federal government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">positions</ENAMEX>.


In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, salaries at public interest law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> can be as
low <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">as $32,000</NUMEX> to start, but with many entry-level jobs beginning
at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $40,000</NUMEX>. Staff <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> positions at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> and federal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> begin at slightly higher salaries.
"These [debt] problems blunt the desire to serve that is
prevalent among law school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduates</ENAMEX>, and have negative
consequences for society as a whole," the report declared.
"Low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> must negotiate legal issues to satisfy their
basic needs for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>, housing, health care, personal safety and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">education</ENAMEX>. These needs go unfilled due to the limited availability
of public interest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>.
"At the same time, the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s role in representing
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> in its regulation, policy development and oversight
responsibilities demands the most skilled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>," the report
added. "In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next five years</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">more than 50 percent</NUMEX> of the federal
[<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX>] <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workforce</ENAMEX> may be eligible to retire."
For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past decade</TIMEX>, bar <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> and across the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> have been well aware of increases in the cost of attending
law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>, increases that have briskly outpaced inflation in any
other realm. Yet <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only a half-dozen</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> currently offer loan
forgiveness programs to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduates</ENAMEX> who agree to work for government
or non-profit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>. The state programs are economically modest,
as is the only loan forgiveness initiative on the near horizon for
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, the "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Student Loan Assistance for the Public Interest</ENAMEX>," a
program adopted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last summer</TIMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York State Bar Association</ENAMEX> when
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House of Delegates</ENAMEX> met in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cooperstown</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry M. Greenberg</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Albany</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.Y.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Couch</ENAMEX>
White who previously served <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14 years</TIMEX> in state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, was made
chair of a standing state bar <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> assigned to work with the
Bar <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foundation</ENAMEX> to put the plan into operation.
"Hopefully, we'll be up and running in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenberg</ENAMEX> told the
Law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX>. "Necessarily, it will be modest at <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>. You have to
crawl before you walk.
"In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first year</TIMEX>, I would imagine we would have approximately
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25,000</NUMEX> to dispense in grants in the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2,000 to $4,000</NUMEX> range," he
said. "In relative terms, and given the programs that exist in a
few other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>, this would put us in a comparable position."
But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenberg</ENAMEX> could not identify the source of the initial
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25,000</NUMEX>.
"We're looking for it, but we don't have it in hand," he said.
"This program is going to have to go out and raise money and have
an endowment. Every segment of the profession has an interest in
trying to ameliorate this [student debt] problem.
"This new and relatively artificial wall to public law service
participation needs to be addressed. The problem is only getting
worse."
With reference to increasing law school tuition and the boomer
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> of public service <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> nearing retirement age,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenberg</ENAMEX> added, "We're dealing with doubledigit inflation as far
as the eye can see, and that's pushing so many young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> to
private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">practice</ENAMEX> -- a certain type of large-firm practice with
salaries of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$120,000 to $160,000</NUMEX>. And who's going to replace these
[public service <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>]? You can lose institutional memory and
expertise."


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CITY BAR REPORT</ENAMEX>
A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association of the Bar</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">City of New York</ENAMEX>,
meanwhile, has been discussing student debt for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six months</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lawrence Grosberg</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> Law School <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> and chair of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">city Bar</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Education</ENAMEX> and Admission to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bar Committee</ENAMEX>, said
he expects to issue a draft report on loan forgiveness within <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX>.
"We're preparing a report to describe the depth of the problem,"
said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grosberg</ENAMEX>. Though he would not disclose specific ideas on
implementing debt relief in order to make public law a viable
option for young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX>, he added, "It's an enormous
problem."
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Bar Association</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission on Loan Repayment</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forgiveness</ENAMEX> is "alive and well," according to its co-chair, Frank
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">M. Coffin</ENAMEX>, senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Court of Appeals for the First</ENAMEX>
Circuit in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Portland</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Me</ENAMEX>. He said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">commission</ENAMEX> was to meet in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Phoenix</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 7</TIMEX> to finalize its report for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABA</ENAMEX>'s general
meeting <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next spring</TIMEX>.
In a telephone interview, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coffin</ENAMEX> provided no details of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">commission</ENAMEX>'s thinking, but said it would make recommendations
in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> broad <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">areas</ENAMEX>: federal, state and campus.
"We're trying to liberalize the [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">federal</ENAMEX>] <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Stafford</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Perkins</ENAMEX>
loan programs," he said. "We're preparing a state tool-kit of
various options available, based on the experience of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> that
already have [loan forgiveness] plans. And we're trying to
inculcate a wider acceptance of plans at law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coffin</ENAMEX> has personal reasons for agreeing with the alarm
sounded by the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Paper Chase to Money Chase</ENAMEX>" report. "When I have a
law <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clerk</ENAMEX> leave me to go into a big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>, that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clerk</ENAMEX> starts off
earning more money than I do," he said. "I don't think crisis would
be overstating the case."
In view of public-spirited young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> forced to take
high-paying jobs at private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX>, would an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABA</ENAMEX> program ask those
same <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> to help fund loan forgiveness in the interest of
government or poverty law career options?
"This is within our vision, but I doubt if we could do it this
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coffin</ENAMEX>. "We recognize that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> are being called
upon to do not just this [loan forgiveness] but many other
charitable things."
Law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school deans</ENAMEX>, to be sure, will soon be confronted with all
these recommendations from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar groups</ENAMEX>. Meanwhile, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least two</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">campus</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> have been outspoken on the subject of student debt
and the zooming rise in tuition costs.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kristin Booth Glen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dean</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City University of New York</ENAMEX>
School of Law, likened competition for top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> to the
seductive practices of credit card <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>.
"There's a sort of bidding war going on, with law schools
offering ever-increasing financial packages -- most of it loans,"
said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dean Glen</ENAMEX>. "Law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> have a real obligation to be extremely
specific about what kinds of debt burdens <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> are going to
have, and to discourage borrowing whenever possible."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph D. Harbaugh</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dean</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Shepard Broad Law Center</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nova</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southeastern University</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort Lauderdale</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fla.</ENAMEX>, is likewise
concerned about his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduates</ENAMEX>' debt burdens. He tells <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>: "If
you live like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> while you're a law <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX>, you're
definitely going to live like a student when you're a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dean</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harbaugh</ENAMEX> expressed skepticism about the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">cent</NUMEX> ral thesis of "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paper</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chase</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Money Chase</ENAMEX>," that debt-strapped young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> cannot
afford public law careers.
"My sense is that there are a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">applicants</ENAMEX> for [public
service] jobs," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dean Harbaugh</ENAMEX>.
Indeed, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen M. Aronson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> recruitment <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coordinator</ENAMEX> at
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York City Human Resources Administration</ENAMEX>, said he has no
problem finding available young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>. His problem, he said, is
the current hiring freeze imposed on all city <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>.
"We don't have any jobs right now, but I interview <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. When
this freeze lifts, I want to stay in touch," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aronson</ENAMEX>. "I just
got back from a job fair in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> where I identified about two
dozen very qualified young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX>."
There remains the question of exactly why law school tuitions
have boomed during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past 10 year</TIMEX>, a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">76 percent</NUMEX> increase among
private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>, according to the report, and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">140 percent</NUMEX> for
in-state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> of public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>.
"Law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>," said the executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of a major <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
public law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> who asked to remain anonymous, "are profit
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">centers</ENAMEX>."





