



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Targeting Domestic Violence Center</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">To Help Victims</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Laidler</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe Correspondent</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">SALEM</ENAMEX> - It's a traumatic prospect for any domestic violence
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX>: having to do battle with her batterer in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>. But the
ordeal is even more difficult for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> who can't afford a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>.
Soon a new resource will be available in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Essex County</ENAMEX> to expand
legal help to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> who find themselves in that predicament.
Set to open <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 22</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Essex County</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Family Legal Aid Center</ENAMEX>
will provide free legal assistance to low-income domestic violence
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> in civil <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> will be close to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Essex</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Probate</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Family Court</ENAMEX>, where many matters involving domestic
violence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>, from restraining order applications to child
custody disputes, are heard.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Advocates</ENAMEX> for domestic violence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> say the new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX>,
funded with a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$303,000</NUMEX> federal grant, will be an important step
toward getting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> the legal help they need.
"We're thrilled," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ross Dolloff</ENAMEX>, executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Neighborhood Legal Services</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lynn</ENAMEX>-based <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> that will run the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> in collaboration with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lowell</ENAMEX>-based <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Merrimack Valley Legal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Services</ENAMEX>.
The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> provide free legal representation to low-income
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, including domestic violence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>, in civil matters. But
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dolloff</ENAMEX> said there is a "huge need" for the services, and the new
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">center</ENAMEX> will "get us much further along in terms of our ability to
serve that need."
The grant will pay the salaries of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> and an intake
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">specialist</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18 months</TIMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX>, which will operate out of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">rented</ENAMEX> space in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Salem</ENAMEX>'s old <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Masonic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">70</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington St.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Center organizers</ENAMEX> hope to obtain more funds to extend the
program.
In addition to expanding the amount of legal help available, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">center</ENAMEX>, because of its location near the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Probate Court</ENAMEX>, will allow
for that help to be more readily accessible. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Merrimack Valley Legal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Services</ENAMEX>, which has an office in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lawrence</ENAMEX>, is convenient for people
with cases in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Essex County Probate Court</ENAMEX> division in that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>.
And both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Merrimack</ENAMEX> and Neighborhood are near district <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX>. But
neither has an office in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Salem</ENAMEX>.
"<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Salem</ENAMEX> . . . is really developing into the chief probate court
for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">county</ENAMEX>, so it's very, very critical that we have a presence
there," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth MacIver</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Merrimack Valley Legal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Services</ENAMEX>. "It's just going to serve our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> a whole lot
better."
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dolloff</ENAMEX> said that because the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> will be just up the street
from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>, it will be easy for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Probate Court</ENAMEX> staff to refer
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to it.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> is also designed to improve coordination among the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> legal service <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> in the region that provide
counseling and other non-legal services to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> of domestic
violence.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Six</NUMEX> of those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> teamed up with the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> legal service
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> to apply for the grant: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Help for Abused Women</ENAMEX> and their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Children</ENAMEX>, based in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Salem</ENAMEX>; the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Women's Resource Center</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lawrence</ENAMEX>;
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newburyport Crisis Center; Action Inc.</ENAMEX>, in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gloucester</ENAMEX>;
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alternative House</ENAMEX>, based in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lowell</ENAMEX>; and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">North Shore Community</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Action Program</ENAMEX>, based in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peabody</ENAMEX>. The money was awarded through the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US Justice Department</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Violence Against Women</ENAMEX> office.
"It really brings together for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who
do work for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> of domestic violence in a single project. So
it's quite exciting," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">MacIver</ENAMEX> said.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dolloff</ENAMEX> said the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> staffing the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patricia A.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Levesh</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vita Palazzolo</ENAMEX>, will work closely with the domestic
violence service <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>. He said that would allow for easier
referral from those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> needing legal help, but
also referral by the center of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> who need counseling and
other support services.
"It's going to be hugely beneficial for our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>," said
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Candace Waldron</ENAMEX>, executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Help for Abused Women</ENAMEX> and
their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Children</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Waldron</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HAWC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> help domestic violence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> file
restraining orders in district <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>. But she said any complicated
issues relating to divorce, child custody, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> support are
typically heard in probate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>, and for those matters, "we really
need legal representation for our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>. That's what this center
is going to provide."
Having a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> can often be the difference between a woman
staying in a violent relationship and being able to break out of
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Waldron</ENAMEX> said.
"Batterers use the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> as a way to maintain control," she
said. "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the ways is they make threats like, 'Don't divorce
me. I can get everything, including the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>.' That's one of the
main reasons <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> don't want to leave. Without a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> facing the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">batterer</ENAMEX> in the context of the courtroom . . . it can be
intimidating. A lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> don't even want to start the process
because they feel already defeated."
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Levesh</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Palazzolo</ENAMEX> both bring experience in representing
domestic violence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>. Each lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gloucester</ENAMEX>.
A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduate</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New England School of Law</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Levesh</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">47</TIMEX>, has been a
staff <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> for legal service <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16 years</TIMEX>. For
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past five years</TIMEX> she has worked for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Greater Boston Legal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Services</ENAMEX>, based in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>. Before that, she worked for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambridge</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Somerville Legal Services</ENAMEX>, based in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambridge</ENAMEX>, and for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southeastern Massachusetts Legal Servces</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Bedford</ENAMEX>.
Palazzolo, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">29</TIMEX>, is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduate</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston College Law School</ENAMEX>. She
has worked as an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Merrimack Valley Legal Services</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past two years</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Levesh</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Palazzolo</ENAMEX>, who serve on a statewide family law task
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">force</ENAMEX>, both say they look forward to working at the new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX>.
"It's an opportunity to do the kind of work I'm doing now -
which is advocating for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> of domestic violence - in my own
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">backyard</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Levesh</ENAMEX>, who served for a time on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HAWC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX>, said.
"It's really exciting to me to be able to work with these people
who are so committed to this work."
Said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Palazzolo</ENAMEX>, "One of the things that excites me about it is
starting up a new office and making our legal services more
accessible to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North Shore area</ENAMEX>. . . . Being in
Salemwill be a big plus for a lot of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>."



