



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Terrorist Attack Upstages Legal Services Initiative</ENAMEX>, But
Provides <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Greater Urgency For It</ENAMEX>
By <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Adcock</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">One morning</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Bookstaver</ENAMEX> arrived at work in lower
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX> and literally pulled the plug on the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> official news
of what is surely the most substantial initiative for pro bono
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">publico</ENAMEX> in the history of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York State Unified Court</ENAMEX>
System
- establishment of the "Access to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Center</ENAMEX>," the first
court-sponsored <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entity</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> to address the shortfall of
civil legal services to the poor.
As communications <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX>, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bookstaver</ENAMEX>
ordinarily has the duty of spreading such news across the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>.
But on <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX> in question, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bookstaver</ENAMEX>, a former
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX>, knew there was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> story to be told: the big one
still making headlines, known as simply "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9/11</NUMEX>."
Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bookstaver</ENAMEX> was himself caught up in the middle of that big
story, walking along <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">West Street</ENAMEX> on the way to his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>. At <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9:03</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a.m.</TIMEX>, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> terrorist- piloted <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> screamed
overhead, then slammed into the south <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tower</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Trade</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center</ENAMEX>.
With building debris and an ocean of smoke and dust pouring down
from the sky, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bookstaver</ENAMEX> ran for his life - <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> blocks
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">southeasterly</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Court Administration</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beaver</ENAMEX>
Street. He would later tell a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Law Journal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> of the
"deafening, thunderous, whistling noise that was like a missile - a
sound I never hope to hear again."
Finally, he was safe inside <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OCA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX>, part of a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX>-story
complex. But even there, he recollected, the walls shook and a
telephone slid off his desk as the twin <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">towers</ENAMEX> of the former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trade Center</ENAMEX> imploded and collapsed. He spotted his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assistant</ENAMEX>, Mai
Yee, at the fax machine. She had just sent the official news to the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contact</ENAMEX> on her list: the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Law Journal</ENAMEX>.
"I took the cord out of the wall from the fax machine," Mr.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bookstaver</ENAMEX> said in a recent interview. "I said, 'Look, I'm not
going to send out something that's terribly important that could be
construed as trivial.' "
Meanwhile in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Albany</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jurists</ENAMEX> were set to back up the
news release with a press conference - Chief <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judith S. Kaye</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief Administrative Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Lippman</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juanita Bing</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newton</ENAMEX>, deputy chief administrative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> for justice initiatives.
But never mind, news of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Center</ENAMEX> - all the more important
in the wake of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 11</TIMEX>, an event that left <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands more</NUMEX> New
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yorkers</ENAMEX> impoverished - would have to wait. Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bookstaver</ENAMEX>'s
reasoning for the delay went deeper than journalistic instinct,
back to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">his years</TIMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press officer</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Emergency Services Unit</ENAMEX>
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Fire Department</ENAMEX>. With reference to the devastation
he witnessed, he said, "Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would think that with all those
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">firefighters</ENAMEX> that it was OK, that things were under control. But I
know too much. I knew that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> of mine were dying in those
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>."
Thus, the consensus-building for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Center</ENAMEX>'s main order
of business - the creation of a working <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX> for the orderly
donation of legal services by the private bar - did not commence
until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last June</TIMEX>, with the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> pro bono convocations held
at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campus</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fordham University School of Law</ENAMEX>.
Two more convocations are scheduled for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX>: at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of New York</ENAMEX> campus in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Buffalo</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 15</TIMEX>; and at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Albany</ENAMEX>
Law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">School</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 25</TIMEX>. The final convocation is set for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 8</TIMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Geneva</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ramada Inn</ENAMEX>. Notes on the wide-ranging discussions at
each convocation will be compiled by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> and
submitted to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court of Appeals</ENAMEX> for further consideration.

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public Service Bar Exam</ENAMEX>
At the same time, though in a far less formal way, consensus
building also began in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX> for yet another far-reaching proposal
for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX>' consideration, one with a distinctive pro bono
element - the so-called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public Service Alternative Bar Examination</ENAMEX>.
Within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next several weeks</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association of the Bar</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">City</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York State Bar Association</ENAMEX> will issue
a joint report, based largely on the findings of a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three-year</TIMEX> study
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kristin Booth Glen</ENAMEX>, a former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Supreme Court</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dean</ENAMEX>
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City University of New York School of Law</ENAMEX>.
The report will recommend a pilot <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">project</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">up to two years</TIMEX>'
duration to assess the effects of substituting public service for
the multi-state law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">segment</ENAMEX> of the current bar exam. At personal
option, law school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduates</ENAMEX> could perform supervised work in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> instead of demonstrating their ability to memorize tracts of
black letter law. In an essay scheduled for publication <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next month</TIMEX>
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia Law Review</ENAMEX> - titled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Thinking Out of the Bar Exam</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Box</ENAMEX>: a <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Challenge</ENAMEX> and Proposal for Change" - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dean Glen</ENAMEX> contends that
public service, scored by specially trained <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">evaluators</ENAMEX>, would be a
more useful test of future <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>' potential than rote memory, and
would simultaneously strike down what she sees as unfair barriers
for poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minorities</ENAMEX> seeking entry to the legal
profession.
In a copy of her essay for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia Law Review</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dean Glen</ENAMEX>
suggests that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> opting for public service could help fill
what Chief <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kaye</ENAMEX> and others have championed in the wake of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 11</TIMEX>: the need to maintain the historic outpouring of volunteer
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">lawyering</ENAMEX>, and increase the spirit of volunteerism.
"The [alternative exam] would require <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">applicants</ENAMEX>... to work as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> in the court system for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 to 12 weeks</TIMEX>, performing a
variety of tasks," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dean Glen</ENAMEX> writes in her essay. "[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX>]he court
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">system</ENAMEX> has an enormous need for additional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> assistance....
[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX>]he chief <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> has created numerous worthy justice initiatives
[but because] there is little or no additional funding... the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> must rely on pro bono legal services if those initiatives
are to be successful.
"Placing [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX>] <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">applicants</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three months</TIMEX> contributes to, but
does not solve the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX>' needs," the essay continued. "This is
why those who elected the [alternative exam] would have an
additional obligation-150 pro bono <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> owed to the court system
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the three years</TIMEX> following admission.
"For every <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> successful [alternative exam] <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">takers</ENAMEX>, the courts
would have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30,000</NUMEX> pro bono <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> of service, to be utilized as the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> found most compelling. As an additional advantage, all of
that pro bono service would be done by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> already familiar
with and trained in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> they would serve."
As an example of urgent pro bono need, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dean Glen</ENAMEX> cited the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Civil</ENAMEX>
Court of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s busiest. In landlord-tenant
disputes, small claims and housing matters, high numbers of poor
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">litigants</ENAMEX> must argue pro se. Only some of them receive help from
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Civil Court</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Self-Representation Office</ENAMEX>, which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dean Glen</ENAMEX>
termed a "valiant attempt" at fair resolution. In the press release
delayed by Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bookstaver</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last September</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lippman</ENAMEX> was more
forceful in assessing the need for pro bono.
"The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of civil legal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX> has reached a turning point
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lippman</ENAMEX> said in the release. "<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Ninety percent</NUMEX> of
all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tenants</ENAMEX> appearing in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Housing Court</ENAMEX> - many facing eviction from
their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> - do not have an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX>. And while the demand is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">great</ENAMEX>, the supply is shrinking.
"[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX>]he <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York State Access</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Center</ENAMEX>... will galvanize
our efforts to find permanent civil legal service funding streams,
and I am confident that it will make significant headway in this
important area of public interest."
Among the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">approximately 150</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fordham</ENAMEX> convocation
was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin J. Curnin</ENAMEX>, a senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">associate</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stroock</ENAMEX> & Stroock
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">& Lavan LLP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney director</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public Service</ENAMEX>
Project.
"We heard a lot of good ideas from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who've been
contributing for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many years</TIMEX> to pro bono <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX>," said Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Curnin</ENAMEX>.
"We have to sift through all the ideas and decide what's best for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, and how to accommodate our differences. We do things
differently in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>, for instance, than upstate." He
added, "We've made a good start."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frederick P. Rooney</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community Legal Resource</ENAMEX>
Network at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CUNY Law</ENAMEX>, identified a major task ahead in meeting Chief
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kaye</ENAMEX>'s hopes for keeping the pro bono ball rolling:
legislation.
"We've got to reduce the liability of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> willing to engage
in pro bono, in much the same way the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Good Samaritan Law</ENAMEX> protects
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> who stumble onto accidents and provide care," said Mr.
Rooney, who is also a general practice <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rooney</ENAMEX>, Mannicci
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">& Gardner LLC</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bethlehem</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pa.</ENAMEX>
On the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public Service Alternative Bar Examination</ENAMEX>, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Curnin</ENAMEX>
was reserved. "It will be a lightning rod for controversy," he
predicted. "But a new idea like that, as bold as it is - that's
what you'd expect."
Taking note of the generally conservative impulse of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>'s
legal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX>, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Curnin</ENAMEX> suggested that the multiple pro bono
aspect of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dean Glen</ENAMEX>'s sweeping proposal could be lost on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> who
might dismiss the matter in terms of a bar exam procedural issue
with a "social good" patina.
"A lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are going to look at it and say, 'Well, I took
the exam the way it is and that's what I had to do it,"' said Mr.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Curnin</ENAMEX>. "What I'd love to see is this [alternative bar exam] in
conjunction with an increase in legal work for the poor at law
school <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clinics</ENAMEX>." Perhaps if the economic doldrums continue, and the
poor get poorer, the pro bono increase that Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Curnin</ENAMEX> and others
want will indeed occur. There does seem to be a relationship
between the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of the economy and the amount of free legal
service that big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX>, at least, are willing or able to
perform.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Two years ago</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Lawyer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> (a sister <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Law Journal</ENAMEX>) found that during the fat <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year of 1999</TIMEX>, the
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">approximately</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> highest-grossing
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> spent an average of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">eight minutes a day</TIMEX> on pro bono cases, or
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about 36 hours</TIMEX> per year, which is down significantly from an
average <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">56 annual</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the recession year of 1992</TIMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Bar Association</ENAMEX> recommends that private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> attorneys
contribute <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">50 hours</TIMEX> per year to pro bono work. By contrast, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York's Volunteers of Legal Service</ENAMEX> recommends <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 hours</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Esther F. Lardent</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pro Bono Institute</ENAMEX> at
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late '90s</TIMEX> saw <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> at large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> suddenly responsible for
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">as many as 2,300</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">billable hours</TIMEX> per year, compared with the less
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>- consuming and more typical <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1,700 hours</TIMEX>.
Poverty law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>, too, have recently registered fewer hours
of service to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> who most needed legal help. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>-controlled <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> prohibited <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> receiving federal
funding - the mainstay of nearly all poverty law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> - from
engaging in class-action lawsuits and matters involving abortion,
illegal immigration or challenges to reduced welfare benefits
inaugurated by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and some other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>. But even
in good times - for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>, at least - there remain <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> seemingly
immovable stumbling blocks for private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> willing to go to
bat for poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> caught up in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Civil Court</ENAMEX> matters:
Corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> whose transactional work seldom takes them
inside a live <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courtroom</ENAMEX> full of emotional, frightened <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">testy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> may feel like <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> out of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> in the great sea of
pro bono work: divorce and child custody issues, landlord-tenant
suits, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>' compensation and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> claims.
In a recent interview, Chief <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kaye</ENAMEX> noted efforts by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Bar</ENAMEX> and by emergency <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">consortia</ENAMEX> of large <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> to
address this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX>.
"We saw a whole new model develop - a holistic approach to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">lawyering</ENAMEX>, one-stop shopping," she said. "Corporate lawyers
received brush-up training from the [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Bar</ENAMEX>], and a given firm
without certain expertise felt free to call on another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> that
had it." The result for pro bono <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> traumatized by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 11</TIMEX>,
said Chief <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kaye</ENAMEX>, was more efficient delivery of needed
service: emotional, frightened <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> had only one contact to
make, no matter how many problems they had; the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> would sort
out the mess. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the principal functions of the Access to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Center</ENAMEX>, she said, would be to foster such a holistic
approach.


The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Slowly Grinding Wheels</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX>
On the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> point, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newton</ENAMEX> said in a recent interview,
"I've heard this complaint <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred</NUMEX> times. An <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> arrives [in
Civil <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Court</ENAMEX>] at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9:30 in the morning</TIMEX>, hoping the matter can be taken
care of in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an hour</TIMEX>. But then for a whole range of reasons, the case
might not be heard until <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">late in the afternoon</TIMEX> - if at all that
day."
In meetings around the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newton</ENAMEX> has invited court
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">administrators</ENAMEX> to suggest solutions to such complaints. A solution
that makes most sense, she said, would be to change calendar
procedures in order to expedite hearings where pro bono <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> are
scheduled to appear.
"We can solve this if we keep working together," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newton</ENAMEX>. With reference to the dramatic increase in pro bono after
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 11</TIMEX>, she added, "The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> thing I learned is that there is a
great passion among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> to focus on access to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">justice</ENAMEX>, no matter what problems we have to solve.
"The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> thing I learned is the importance of collaboration
among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX>, bar <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX>, private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> and civil legal
service <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX>. If we get everybody to the table, we'll
crystallize these problems and turn our focus onto solutions that
will work."
Meanwhile, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rooney</ENAMEX> suggested that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> might individually
elect to do more reduced fee or "low-bono" work - in the manner of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marcos & Negron LLP</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABA</ENAMEX>
presented the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> with its <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pro Bono Publico Award</ENAMEX>, despite the
fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marcos & Negron</ENAMEX> does not work for free.
"But they do outstanding work at reduced fees, and it was good
to see that encouraged by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABA</ENAMEX>," said Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rooney</ENAMEX>. His own firm
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bethlehem</ENAMEX>, he said, operates under the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marcos & Negron</ENAMEX>
philosophy.
"We make a decent living. Sure, it would be great to make a lot
more. But when you represent a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX> in desperate need of service
who may not have the required retainer - guess what?
"That <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> will come back to you when they have a personal
injury case, or some other case that has the chance of substantial
economic gain," he said. "Kindness can pay off."




