



Business Wire

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Supreme Court</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deborah Hankinson Lauded For</ENAMEX>
Contributions to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services</ENAMEX> to the Poor
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, October 11, 2002</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">AUSTIN</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>--<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 11, 2002</TIMEX>--The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Equal Access</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foundation</ENAMEX>, the largest <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>-based funding source for legal aid
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organizations</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, has awarded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deborah Hankinson</ENAMEX>
the prestigious <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harold F. Kleinman</ENAMEX> award for outstanding
contributions to the delivery of civil legal services to the
poor.
Hankinson, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court of Texas</ENAMEX> liaison to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foundation</ENAMEX>,
has worked tirelessly to ensure that poor and low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Texans</ENAMEX> are
afforded access to justice. She led the charge in the creation of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Access</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Commission</ENAMEX>, an umbrella organization
designed to enhance the quality of legal services to the poor. She
was a strong supporter of the recent change to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Bar of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> dues statement that requires <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> to "opt-out" of making
a contribution to legal services. Through the opt-out approach,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> contributed <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>, doubling <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>
contributions. Additionally, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hankinson</ENAMEX> was instrumental in securing
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5 million</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crime Victim Compensation</ENAMEX> funds, dedicated to the
provision of civil legal services for low- income crime
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>.
"In this time in which access to justice for underprivileged
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Texans</ENAMEX> has suffered from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congressional</ENAMEX> retreat, litigation assault
and a decline in statewide funds, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hankinson</ENAMEX> has been a
source of innovative ideas and inspirational <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX>," TEAJF
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Board</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Tate</ENAMEX> said. "Her dedicated efforts have improved
the lives of countless poor <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Texans</ENAMEX> by opening for them the doors of
our justice system. She is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harold Kleinman Award</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">personified</ENAMEX>."
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kleinman Award</ENAMEX> is named after former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Equal Access</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Foundation</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harold F. Kleinman</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foundation</ENAMEX>,
wishing to recognize <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kleinman</ENAMEX>'s outstanding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>, commitment
and public service to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>, created the award to
confer prestige and honor upon <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> in the field of access to
civil justice.
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deborah Hankinson</ENAMEX> has brought to the issue of civil legal
services to the poor the same passion she brings to her role as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Supreme Court</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas R. Phillips</ENAMEX> said.
"She works from a formidable personal and intellectual commitment
that we can and should do better to make the justice system
accessible to all."
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Equal Access</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Foundation</ENAMEX> presented the
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Kleinman Award to Hankinson</ENAMEX> at its annual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court Luncheon</ENAMEX>. Upon
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">acceptance</ENAMEX> of the award, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hankinson</ENAMEX> said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This</ENAMEX> award means so much
to me. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harold Kleinman</ENAMEX> was the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managing partner</ENAMEX> at (the law firm
of) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thompson & Knight</ENAMEX> when I began working there. All the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">associates</ENAMEX> admired him tremendously. He was the example of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">professionalism</ENAMEX>, community service and compassion."
Hankinson, a native of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>, graduated cum laude with her
doctorate in jurisprudence from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern Methodist University</ENAMEX>
School of Law. She was appointed to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court of Texas</ENAMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>, and was elected to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>. She will step down from
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 2002</TIMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Equal Access</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Foundation</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">txiolta</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">org</ENAMEX>)
administers funds to create community capacity to provide civil
legal services for low- income <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Texans</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> is
committed to the vision that all <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Texans</ENAMEX> will have equal access to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">justice</ENAMEX>, regardless of their income. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foundation</ENAMEX> administers the
Interest on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lawyers' Trust</ENAMEX> Accounts (IOLTA) fund, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Basic Civil</ENAMEX>
Legal Services (BCLS) fund and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crime Victims Civil Legal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Services</ENAMEX> (CVCLS) fund. The funds from each of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> are
earmarked to assist nonprofit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> in providing free civil
legal services to low-income




