



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Lawyer</ENAMEX>

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GRANT PROVIDES FUNDING TO CONNECT LEGAL AID CALL CENTERS</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Alice Robbins</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 9, 2002</TIMEX>
A <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100,000</NUMEX> technology grant awarded to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Rural Legal Aid</ENAMEX>
will fund an <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX> call <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> and connect it with <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Antonio</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corpus Christi</ENAMEX> to assist the poor with legal problems
in a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">68</NUMEX>-county area of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Southwest Texas</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>-based
Legal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Services Corp.</ENAMEX>, which oversees federally funded legal aid,
awarded the grant to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TRLA</ENAMEX>, which serves an area extending from
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX> south to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rio Grande Valley</ENAMEX> and west to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El Paso</ENAMEX>. The
award was announced at a news conference on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 30</TIMEX> at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Texas School of Law</ENAMEX>, which is participating in the
project.
According to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 20 percent</NUMEX> of the low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Texans</ENAMEX> who
have a civil legal problem are able to obtain <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> to
represent them.
"It's a serious problem when <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> out of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> low-income people
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> arrive at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courthouse</ENAMEX> door and essentially discover
they cannot afford the price of admission," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mauricio Vivero</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX>. "While this grant cannot ensure justice for all
in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Southwest Texas</ENAMEX>, this new legal advice line will mean <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX>
more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> can access critical legal advice when they need it
the most."
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TRLA</ENAMEX> executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Hall</ENAMEX> says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">call-in service</ENAMEX> is
more than a hotline for legal advice. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">UT</ENAMEX> law <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> will staff
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> and conduct the initial interviews with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> to find
out what their legal problems are and how they can be helped.
"It provides the front end for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> in dealing with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hall</ENAMEX> says. The idea, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hall</ENAMEX> says, is to keep <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> off
the phones so that they can spend their time handling cases. Hall
says that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> will do eligibility screening to determine
whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">callers</ENAMEX> qualify for legal assistance from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TRLA</ENAMEX>. If a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">caller</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">meets TRLA</ENAMEX>'s eligibility requirements, a comprehensive case work-up
will be done by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX>, who may have to call a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courthouse</ENAMEX> to get
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">records</ENAMEX> on the case, he says.
"What you normally think of a hotline doing is spending <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 15</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX> on the phone with somebody, giving them some quick legal
advice, hanging up the phone and going to the next light blinking
on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hall</ENAMEX> says. "The way we try to approach it is to
identify every legal problem that a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">client</ENAMEX> has."
All the information and records that a student <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">obtains</ENAMEX> are filed
in a computer system accessible by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TRLA</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> throughout its
service area, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hall</ENAMEX> says.
This won't be the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TRLA</ENAMEX> has used law <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> to
take calls from indigents. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">center</ENAMEX> will expand services
provided by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telephone Access</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> call <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Antonio</ENAMEX>, where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Mary's University School of Law</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> man the
phones.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hall</ENAMEX> says the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Antonio</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> -- opened as an experiment
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about five years ago</TIMEX> -- has made "a tremendous difference in our
ability to reach out" to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>, whether they are in rural or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">urban</ENAMEX> areas. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TRLA</ENAMEX> also operates a small <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">call-in center</ENAMEX> in Corpus
Christi, where paralegals take the calls, he says. With funding
from the grant, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> will be tied together in an
integrated phone system, he adds.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Christine Reed</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">TAJ</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">San</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Antonio Center</ENAMEX> opened <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 5,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX> files stemming from calls
received in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>. The goal of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">center</ENAMEX>, which is expected
to open by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 2003</TIMEX>, is to double the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> served,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hall</ENAMEX> says.
Law <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> who work at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Antonio</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">center</ENAMEX> are given an
opportunity to use their legal skills. Depending on the amount of
training they have, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> can dispense preliminary legal advice
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> but must document what advice they gave, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reed</ENAMEX> says. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reed</ENAMEX>
says <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> also are called to assist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> in rural areas with
pro se divorces for cases that she determines can be handled in
that manner. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> talk to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> on the phone to get
the information on divorce cases and prepare the pleadings, which
are reviewed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> before being given to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> to take to
court, she says.
"We follow that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX> through to filing it, to getting the
final hearing, to preparing the final decree, to making sure she
gets divorced," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reed</ENAMEX> says.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reed</ENAMEX> says privilege attaches when the law <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> take
calls.
"They're working basically as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">paralegal</ENAMEX> or legal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assistant</ENAMEX>,"
she says. "It's the same as calling and speaking to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>."
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reed</ENAMEX> says the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Antonio</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">center</ENAMEX> fields calls on a number of
legal problems. <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">About 20 percent</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">callers</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> of
domestic violence who are given information about <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shelters</ENAMEX> where
they can find help, she says.
Calls also come from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who have been denied food stamps or
have problems with their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">landlords</ENAMEX>, she says.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hall</ENAMEX> says that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UT</ENAMEX> law <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> will be needed to answer
calls at the new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX>.
The indigents served by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">center</ENAMEX> won't be the only ones to
benefit. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Powers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UT</ENAMEX> law school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dean</ENAMEX>, says the project will
benefit the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> who participate, teaching them early in their
careers about the need for pro bono <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX>.
Says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Powers</ENAMEX>, "This grant will help provide our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> with
valuable professional
experience that will help them in whatever areas they go into,
but will also help them understand and have the ideals of providing
legal services to every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>."




