



The Columbian
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, June 11, 2002</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington State Legal Aid Program Challenge</ENAMEX>

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reaches U.S. High Court</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">PAUL QUEARY</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Associated Press</ENAMEX> writer
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OLYMPIA</ENAMEX> -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Supreme Court</ENAMEX> agreed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> to hear a
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> case challenging the widespread practice of pooling
client money held by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> and using the interest to pay for
legal services for the poor.
A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Supreme Court</ENAMEX> rule issued in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1984</TIMEX> requires lawyers
to put <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>' money in a pooled account if the amount is too
small or will be held for too short a time to earn interest for the
individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX>.
The rule was later expanded to include real estate closing
offers.
The interest from the pooled money adds up to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $6 million</NUMEX>
per year statewide. It goes to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Foundation</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>,
which doles it out to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">34</NUMEX> legal aid <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> around the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Legal Foundation</ENAMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>, organization
that defends private property rights sued in federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>
to overturn the practice. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundation</ENAMEX> argues the practice
essentially steals the interest from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>, an illegal taking
of personal property under the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Fifth Amendment</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Constitution</ENAMEX>.
"No one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> suffers an awful lot," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Samp</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">foundation</ENAMEX>'s chief <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX>. "But it's a small amount of money
that's stolen from a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>."
Similar programs called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IOLTA</ENAMEX>, or Interest on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lawyers' Trust</ENAMEX>
Accounts exist in all <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> so the case could have broad
impact.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Advocates</ENAMEX> argue that the program is an important source of legal
help for poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> forced to deal with civil legal matters
including domestic violence protection orders, child custody fights
and eviction disputes.
"We only can help <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">right now</TIMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about one</NUMEX> out of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who ask
for help," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara Clark</ENAMEX>, executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foundation</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>. "The potential loss of this funding is
very devastating."
IOLTA contributes <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">38 percent</NUMEX> of the money available for low-
income civil legal assistance in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX> said.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Advocates</ENAMEX> also argue that interest is essentially created by the
program because taxes and accounting costs would eat away the money
if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> tried to set up a similar program to benefit the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>.
But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Samp</ENAMEX> argues that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IOLTA</ENAMEX> programs essentially discourage
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> from setting up such pooled accounts that might benefit
their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>.
A <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">District Court</ENAMEX> initially dismissed the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> case,
overturned the ruling. Then the full <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">9th Circuit</ENAMEX> overruled its own
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justices</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s favor, agreeing with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s contention
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> weren't harmed because the interest wouldn't be
earned otherwise.




