



The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Pro Bono 2001</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Amon</ENAMEX>
Staff Reporter
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SEPT. 11 CAST</ENAMEX> a pall over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>, but it led to a high point in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>' efforts to give back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">More than 2,500</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">areas</ENAMEX> have helped affected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> and small-business <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX>
through local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar groups</ENAMEX>. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association of Trial Lawyers of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> has moved to assist <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> free of charge when they go
file for federal aid.
The pages that follow describe the work of those and other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The National Law Journal</ENAMEX>'s pro bono awards for
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>.
But what about the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 11</TIMEX>? From all the
indicators available, the record is mixed at best.
At the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">106</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> that reported their pro bono <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> to the NLJ
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past two years</TIMEX>, the number dropped from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3.28% to 3.06%</NUMEX> of
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">billable hours</TIMEX>. That number is high--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Bar Association</ENAMEX>
suggests <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3%</NUMEX> as a goal--but the drop appears significant and it's
arguable that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> reporting seem likely to be the ones
donating the most. Though it is a small percentage, the difference
represents <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX>. At a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">300</NUMEX>-lawyer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>, it would
translate into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 1,300</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> a year, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than half</NUMEX> a
hard-working <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>'s billable time.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Esther Lardent</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pro Bono Institute</ENAMEX>, administers
its <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Pro Bono Challenge</ENAMEX>, which confidentially tracks big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">law firms</ENAMEX>'
pro bono work. The data for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX> aren't tallied, but she says the
numbers appear flat. "We have some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> that are strong and some
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> that have struggled," she says.
The key to a commitment to pro bono, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lardent</ENAMEX> says, is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>'s
stance on whether pro bono work counts internally as billable
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Firms</ENAMEX> that are giving <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">billable-hour</TIMEX> parity for pro bono
work and showing that they mean it are the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> that are strong,"
she says. There's no count of pro bono contributions of solo
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">practitioners</ENAMEX> or midsize and small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX>. But by one measure, it
seems to have been static.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services Corp.</ENAMEX> (LSC), which works with attorneys
representing poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, hasn't tallied <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s numbers, says
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mauricio Vivero</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX> of public affairs, but he expects
them to be flat. That would follow a sharp decline <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year earlier</TIMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">From 1999 to 2000</TIMEX> the number of pro bono cases handled by
LSC-affiliated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> dropped by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20,000</NUMEX>, led by a drop in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7,200</NUMEX>.
Still, solo <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">practitioners</ENAMEX>, like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tallahassee</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fla.</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karen</ENAMEX>
Gievers, continue to distinguish themselves. <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Award</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX> Gievers
has worked <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">more than 1,000 hours</TIMEX> on behalf of foster <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lawyers</ENAMEX> in death penalty work say they've seen a drop in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">volunteerism</ENAMEX>. Capital cases are expensive and demanding, and those
involved in placing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> on them say large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> in particular
have shied away from them.
"It's a real crisis," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin Maher</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
Bar <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association</ENAMEX> pro bono death penalty representation project. "In
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alabama</ENAMEX> alone, there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on death row who don't have
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>."
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> who has fought a capital conviction for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> is
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">award</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">JoNell Thomas</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX> solo practitioner. She's
worked <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">more than 2,500 hours</TIMEX> and counting on behalf of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Mazzan</ENAMEX>,
who was on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nevada</ENAMEX>'s death row for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 years</TIMEX> before his release.
Also noteworthy is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lindquist & Vennum</ENAMEX>, whose
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles J. Lloyd</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven M. Pincus</ENAMEX> represented <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albert Ronnie</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burrell</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wrongfully</ENAMEX> convicted of the murder of an elderly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burrell</ENAMEX> spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13 years</TIMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisiana</ENAMEX>'s death row before being
released <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James H. Schropp</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York's Fried,</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Frank, Harris, Shriver & Jacobson</ENAMEX>, represented <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Max Soffar</ENAMEX>, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inmate</ENAMEX> whose capital murder conviction was reversed after <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>.
And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edwin S. Matthews Jr.</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coudert Brothers</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">represented Don Paradis</ENAMEX>, who was released from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> after <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> on death row in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Idaho</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paradis</ENAMEX> won't be retried.

<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Unpopular Clients</ENAMEX>
Taking unpopular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> and controversial cases is another
measure of commitment. <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Award</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathleen T. Zellner</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Naperville</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ill.</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zellner & Associates</ENAMEX> secured the release of
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> sentenced to life for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX> rape of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> medical
student. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>, she spent <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">800 hours</TIMEX> of pro bono time and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50,000</NUMEX>
of her own money on an appeal based on DNA evidence.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Lubitz</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Swidler Berlin Shereff Friedman</ENAMEX>,
challenged an <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Annapolis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Md.</ENAMEX>, ordinance allowing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> to
eject <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from designated "drug loitering-free zones." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lubitz</ENAMEX>'
demonstrated that the law targeted predominantly minority
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> found it unconstitutional.
In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pepper Hamilton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Richman</ENAMEX> spent 18 years
in litigation with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> over its <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prisons</ENAMEX>. In a class action
that concluded in a settlement at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of 2000</TIMEX>, he succeeded in
changing the oppressive conditions of confinement in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">prisons</ENAMEX>.
Among the nominations for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NLJ</ENAMEX>'s award were a number of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> who performed significant pro bono work that helped
nonprofit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> provide legal services to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">needy</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Sullivan</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Salt Lake City</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Phoenix</ENAMEX>'s Snell
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">& Wilmer</ENAMEX> has spent countless pro bono <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> helping
to increase the proportion of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> who donate to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> public
interest law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5% to 36%</NUMEX>.
An important figure in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Terry Walsh</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alston</ENAMEX> &
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bird</ENAMEX>, who has championed the welfare of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgia</ENAMEX>. Not
only has he helped set up <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> to provide services for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Truancy Intervention Project</ENAMEX>, but he resigned
his equity <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partnership</ENAMEX> to be able to do so.
Some cases are challenging because they are so unusual. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lawyers</ENAMEX>
at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Perkins Coie</ENAMEX> represented <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War-era</ENAMEX> defectors
who claim the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> didn't keep promises of financial support. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hale</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betsy Alaniz</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> overcame a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> claim of immunity
from judicial scrutiny, and the case is in discovery.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reed Smith</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> spent <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6,352 hours</TIMEX> to recover the archive of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">photographer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Teenie Harris</ENAMEX>, who was swindled out of his
negatives.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cindy Kernick</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donna Doblick</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Colleen Lynch</ENAMEX> won a jury
verdict that awarded <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harris</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $4.2 million</NUMEX> in damages,
enough to permit the estate to get a judgment and execute on the
negatives.
An area in which pro bono work has surged is among another
traditionally unpopular and vastly under-represented <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX>.
"There's a greater level of interest in immigration, asylum and
international human rights work," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lardent</ENAMEX> says.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Latham & Watkins</ENAMEX> was an award <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX> chiefly because of its
remarkable involvement in immigration cases on behalf of
unaccompanied <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minors</ENAMEX>.
Among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">runners-up</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> solo <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor Newhoff</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy Kelly</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Greater Boston Legal Services</ENAMEX> estimates that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newhoff</ENAMEX> spent between
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">500 and 750 hours</TIMEX> on pro bono in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX> on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX> cases she took through
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kelly</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>. And she did other pro bono work as well.


Problems for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 11</TIMEX> may reflect a failing of the legal profession during a
crisis for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Middle Eastern</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sohail Mohammed</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clifton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.J.</ENAMEX>, solo practitioner, has been
scrambling to get information on the number of them locked up in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX> after the attacks. He estimates it may be upward of <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">600,</ENAMEX>
mostly without <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>.
helping to find <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> to take cases but says he's frustrated that
other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>, including the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Immigration Lawyers</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association</ENAMEX> (AILA) haven't acted faster to organize pro bono
representation.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeanne A. Butterfield</ENAMEX>, executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AILA</ENAMEX>, says it
hasn't tried to organize pro bono <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> for those detained

because of the charges they face.
"The most pressing need for pro bono are for asylum <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">applicants</ENAMEX>,"
she says. "A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> visa overstayer is not going to be a high
priority for pro bono assistance."
While <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AILA</ENAMEX> has joined the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACLU</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> in a
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Freedom of Information Act</ENAMEX> request to find out who is being
detained where and why, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mohammed</ENAMEX> notes that the reasons for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX>' detention were not immediately clear and sometimes had
dire consequences.
"For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first three or four weeks</TIMEX> when we were at the height of
these disturbing trends, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were picked up and missing from
their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> died in detention," he says. "I would
expect the legal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> to be in the forefront of trying to
bring this issue to light."




