



The Bend Bulletin

High Court <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Visits Bend</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Promote Better Legal Aid</ENAMEX>

<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew Taran</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, October 24, 2002</TIMEX>
When an <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oregon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> arrived at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central Oregon</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Office</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid Services</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening about 30 minutes</TIMEX>
late and with wind-blown hair, nobody thought much of it.
Then again nobody attending an open house to discuss legal aid
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">funding</ENAMEX> and service issues in the state knew exactly what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas A.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Balmer</ENAMEX> went through to give a speech on the subject.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Halfway to Bend</ENAMEX> on his drive form <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Salem</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Balmer</ENAMEX>'s old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Volvo</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">wagon</ENAMEX> started smoking and died. Only as far as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Santiam Pass</ENAMEX>,
there was no time to spare.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Balmer</ENAMEX> grabbed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> that he had jotted notes for his speech
on and abandoned his neck tie and formerly reliable <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicle</ENAMEX>. It had
been a long time since he flagged a ride with his thumb, but he was
desperate. Luckily a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mustang</ENAMEX> convertible headed for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bend</ENAMEX> offered a
lift.
A little car trouble wasn't about to keep him from delivering
his message.
"Through support for legal aid we can make sure we are not
closing courthouse doors on anybody," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Balmer</ENAMEX> told <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">judicial</ENAMEX> and legislative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> during the open house.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oregon</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> strive to provide civil legal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">services</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s lowincome <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">About 20 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oregon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> qualify for the legal aid
but <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only about 111</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">less than 1 percent</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX>) compose
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s legal aid services <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX>.
Legal Aid <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> reject <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> out of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that qualify
for help and have a legitimate grievance because they don't have
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resources</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> said.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oregon</ENAMEX> is meeting <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">18 percent</NUMEX> of the need for civil legal
services to low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oregonians</ENAMEX>, according to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Need</ENAMEX>
Study.
"The biggest crisis is federal funding," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Turner</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Central Oregon</ENAMEX> regional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bend</ENAMEX>. "Federal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">funding</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of what it was in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX>." In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> legal aid services
were nearly eliminated by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>. Instead, they cut
funding by <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$122 million</NUMEX>, causing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">300</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> closures and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">900</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> layoffs nationwide.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX> funding accounts for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about one third</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oregon</ENAMEX>'s
estimated <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$11.5</NUMEX> legal aid budget. The remainder comes from filing
fees, interest on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lawyer</ENAMEX>'s Trust Accounts, contributions from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundation</ENAMEX> grants and corporate support.
With that money legal aid provides the poor, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elderly</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">disabled</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">unemployed</ENAMEX> and disadvantaged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> with civil legal services.
They help those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with housing, domestic violence, divorce,
child custody and employment cases.
A big part of legal aid's success depends on pro bono, or free,
work by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>.
"Legal aid is so important for our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> because
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> need to have access to the court system," former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">state</ENAMEX> Sen.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neil Bryant</ENAMEX> said.
For that reason it's too important for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> not to
participate pro bono, he said.
Retired <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Thalhofer</ENAMEX> agreed.
At <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s open house the local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> honored him with an
award for his dedication to providing pro bono legal assistance for
low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">seniors</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central Oregon</ENAMEX>.
"It's kind of fun doing this pro bono work," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thalhofer</ENAMEX> said.





