



Legal <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Services Too Crucial to Take Cut</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerry L. Alexander</ENAMEX>, Chief justice
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerry L. Alexander</ENAMEX> is chief <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington State</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>.
On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 14</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Locke</ENAMEX> issued an order cutting <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly half</NUMEX>
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> state funding for civil legal services - <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2.4 million</NUMEX>
-from the state budget. Already strained to the breaking point,
this cut will devastate the civil equal justice delivery system in
our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>.
For the poor and vulnerable, the justice system represents the
place of last resort - the place where essential rights are
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">enforced</ENAMEX> and defended. For <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> upon <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> who need
protection from domestic abuse, wrongful eviction or the improper
denial or termination of essential governmental assistance, our
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">state</ENAMEX>'s civil legal services programs (pro bono legal aid) hold the
key.
If this budget cut is left unmitigated, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX>'s action
threatens irreparable harm to truly effective and important legal
services programs. It is critical that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legislature</ENAMEX> correct this
situation by replacing all or most of the amount cut.
I was a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Superior Court</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thurston County</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX>. Before
me was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> with a toothless smile. As I remember it, the state
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Department</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social and Health Services</ENAMEX> had agreed to pay to pull
his teeth out but, due to a budget crisis, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> decided
that it would not pay for the dentures that he needed. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> had
no money and could not afford to hire a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>. However, a legal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">services</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spokane</ENAMEX> filed a lawsuit challenging the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>'s refusal to pay for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s dentures. I decided that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> had acted illegally. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> got his teeth. And in
my view, justice was served.
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX>, there were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> primary legal services programs in our
state. Together they had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">130</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> and the
responsibility to serve the civil legal needs of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 550,000</NUMEX> poor
and vulnerable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. There were legal
services <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX> locations from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Walla Walla</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Port Angeles</ENAMEX>,
from <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Clarkston and Colville to Chehalis and Longview</ENAMEX>, from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX>
to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spokane</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">those days</TIMEX>, the poor had a place to go, and they
knew it.
The picture is much different <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. The legal services programs
that existed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX> are gone, gutted by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two decades</TIMEX> of budget
cuts, stagnant funding and increasing costs. In their place we have
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> statewide <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX> of direct legal assistance to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poor</ENAMEX> and
vulnerable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. They operate with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a third</NUMEX> fewer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> and
must try to meet the needs of a poverty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> that has doubled
to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly 1.2 million</NUMEX>. While these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> are joined by
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteer attorneys</ENAMEX> who <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> contributed more
than <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">27,000 hours</TIMEX> of free legal assistance, civil <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice</ENAMEX> is still
unavailable for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> who need it. The <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2.4 million</NUMEX> cut will
cause irreversible damage.
Most of us have no idea how many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> are
barely surviving. They are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> of domestic violence, single
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">moms</ENAMEX> trying to navigate the regulatory maze that strangles their
efforts to move from dependency to self-sufficiency, foster
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> who are maltreated, migrant and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seasonal</TIMEX> farm <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> who
are not paid or are forced to work in unsafe and unsanitary
conditions. There are so many needing help, each with a compelling
and sometimes life-and-death story. Until now, the legal services
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">system</ENAMEX> has been able to support <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only an estimated 20 percent</NUMEX> of
those who need our help. It is unfathomable to think about the
impact of further cuts.
It is obvious that every social and human service budget will
suffer from very painful cuts as a result of the current budget
crisis. But legal services are not just social programs, they are
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">justice</ENAMEX> programs.
Legal service programs are the only solution for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">disenfranchised Washingtonians</ENAMEX> who need to assert and enforce their
rights on matters of sheer survival. And, given the weak economy
and the forthcoming budget cuts, these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> need more help right
now, not less.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Every day</TIMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> recite the Pledge
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Allegiance</ENAMEX>. The pledge ends with an affirmation of the essential
promise of our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">democracy</ENAMEX> - "with liberty and justice for all."
The
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> is carved with the words "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Equal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> Under <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Law</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> in every corner of the world fight and
die for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> ideal of equal justice.
But does equal justice exist only for those with means to
petition the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX>? Can equal justice exist where the laws cannot
be enforced because the poor cannot secure <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX>? Each time a
poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> is denied access to the justice system - to assert or
defend important legal rights - a small piece of our democracy
dies.
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 2001</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington State Supreme Court</ENAMEX> created the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Task Force on Civil Equal Justice Funding</ENAMEX>, with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX>
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Judiciary</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legislature</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>. This
task <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> is committed to solving the problem of adequately
funding access to civil <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice</ENAMEX> in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. Formed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three months</TIMEX>
before anyone knew the depth of the state budget cuts, we
admittedly are alarmed. How can we resuscitate an already sick
system while enduring even deeper cuts?
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legislature</ENAMEX> needs to do the right thing for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of
this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. It must act to replace all or most of the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2.4 million</NUMEX>
cut from legal services. It is our duty as a democratic society -
and as compassionate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> - to make
sure that we really do ensure justice for all.



