



The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Record</ENAMEX>

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Towson Attorney Designs Project</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Benefit Legal Aid</ENAMEX>

<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Earl Kelly</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 6, 2002</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lawyer Eliot M. Wagonheim</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Towson</ENAMEX> has designed a project that
will benefit <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore County</ENAMEX> law-related <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> and
establish a fund for helping area <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">firefighters</ENAMEX> who become
disabled.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wagonheim</ENAMEX> said the program not only will benefit the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">needy</ENAMEX>, but
also will help improve the public image of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>.
"It not only raises money for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">charity</ENAMEX>," he said, "but gives
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> something else to think about the next time they hear a
lawyer joke."
Called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Take 2</ENAMEX>, the endeavor will be funded by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> who
donate either <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2 percent</NUMEX> of their earnings or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2</NUMEX> for each billable
hour charged on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Thursdays</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 2003</TIMEX>. As for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> who
handle contingency cases or who are salaried, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wagonheim</ENAMEX> said they
could participate by donating some amount that approximated such a
donation.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Donors</ENAMEX> may earmark contributions to go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid Bureau</ENAMEX>
for use in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore County</ENAMEX>, to charitable programs run by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baltimore County Bar Foundation</ENAMEX>, or to benefit <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">firefighters</ENAMEX> and rescue <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> who are killed or injured.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wagonheim</ENAMEX> said he initially hoped to recruit <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 300</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contributors</ENAMEX> for Take <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2's first year</TIMEX>, and projected donations of
upwards of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$15,000</NUMEX>.
After contacting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> about Take <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wagonheim</ENAMEX> is beginning
to revise his projections.
"The response has led me to believe its going to be much higher
than that," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wagonheim</ENAMEX> said. "I can't tell you how excited I am by
it."


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Focal Point</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wagonheim</ENAMEX> has experience in creating charitable endeavors. He
was one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">organizers</ENAMEX> of the now-famous <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Chesapeake Blues</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Festival</ENAMEX>, an event held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each Year</TIMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sandy Point State</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Park</ENAMEX> outside <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Annapolis</ENAMEX> for the benefit of several <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">charities</ENAMEX>.
But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wagonheim</ENAMEX> eschewed the publicity.
"I really hope the focus won't be on me doing charity work but
will be on Take <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2</ENAMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wagonheim</ENAMEX>, who added that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore County</ENAMEX>
Bar <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen J. Nolan</ENAMEX> was instrumental in
launching the new program.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nolan</ENAMEX> said of Take <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2</ENAMEX>, "Lawyers individually are doing a lot for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX>, and this is one way we can channel our efforts."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilhelm H. Joseph Jr.</ENAMEX>, executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bureau</ENAMEX>, which helps fund legal services for the poor in civil
matters, said that <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Take 2</ENAMEX> "is not charity. It's about the
professional responsibility of each individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> and the Bar
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association</ENAMEX>."
The Take <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> initiative will reach well beyond the legal
profession and serve <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the broader <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore County</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">firefighters</ENAMEX> do not have a formal program to
provide a financial boost to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">firefighters</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">paramedics</ENAMEX> who are
injured and unable to work.
This shortcoming became evident following terrorist attacks on
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Trade Center</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>, where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">firefighters</ENAMEX> have
such a fund that helps <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> in times of need.
"Let's say a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore County</ENAMEX> firefighter is from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North County</ENAMEX>
and they are injured and are in the shock trauma <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore</ENAMEX>
but a family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> can't commute from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX> line,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wagonheim</ENAMEX> said. "Right now, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">firefighters</ENAMEX> will pass the hat and
help raise money to put the family up, but there is no fund."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Firefighter Michael R. Rehfeld</ENAMEX>, a ladder <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX> and
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17-year</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veteran</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX>, was working to create such a fund,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wagonheim</ENAMEX> heard of his efforts.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rehfeld</ENAMEX>, reached <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> between emergency runs caused by the
heavy <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">snowfall</ENAMEX>, said critically injured <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">firefighters</ENAMEX> and rescue
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> often must hire others, such as plumbers and yard <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>,
to help maintain their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> during periods of convalescence.
"We saw what happened up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> and how much critical need
there was to establish this," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rehfeld</ENAMEX> said. "Take <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2</ENAMEX> is the starting
point, and we hope to establish an endowment."
Wagonheim, who teaches the professionalism course for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maryland State Bar Association</ENAMEX>, said he is working with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MSBA</ENAMEX> to
create a statewide Take <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>-type program.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorneys</ENAMEX> who want to participate in Take 2 may call the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baltimore County Bar Association</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">410-337-9103</ENAMEX> or contact the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">association</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bcba</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">org</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wagonheim</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">wtlawfirm</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.





