



Understanding Where They're Coming From

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hotline</ENAMEX> offers aid and advice to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> who find
themselves in desperate situations and don't know where to
turn.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erin Chan</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday, July 14, 2002</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kim Luu</ENAMEX> and her <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-workers</ENAMEX> never see the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">callers</ENAMEX>' faces.
They will never meet <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">42-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tranh Tran</ENAMEX> and her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cash-strapped Westminster</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, never hug the terrified
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">70-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who has just been evicted and never personally
comfort the battered <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> seeking divorces but petrified of losing
their immigration status.
But they've talked. And that's enough to touch the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">callers</ENAMEX>'
lives.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Luu</ENAMEX> and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> work at a toll-free hotline, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Language Legal Intake Project</ENAMEX>. They use their language skills and
experiences--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luu</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> fled <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Vietnam</ENAMEX> when she was an
infant--to add resonance to their advice.
With their fluent <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Vietnamese</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mandarin</ENAMEX>, they help Tran
understand her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>'s eligibility for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medi-Cal</ENAMEX> and food stamps,
assist the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">70-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> in finding a place to live and advise
abused <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> how they can stay in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> while staying away
from their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husbands</ENAMEX>.
Through the free hotline, which officially made its debut last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Luu</ENAMEX> and other project <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> calm anxious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">callers</ENAMEX> and even
elicit laughs from those who don't know where else to turn.
"These <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are desperate for information," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juliet Stone</ENAMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">29</TIMEX>, the project's supervising <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX>. "This is so needed in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">community</ENAMEX>."
The project links <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> legal service <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Angeles</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Orange</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">counties</ENAMEX>--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asian Pacific American Legal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid Foundation</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Neighborhood Legal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Services</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid Society of Orange County</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Callers</ENAMEX> dial (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">800</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">267-7395</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Vietnamese</ENAMEX>-language assistance,
or (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">800</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">520- 2356</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mandarin</ENAMEX>. An <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX> records personal
information and determines, on the basis of income and place of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">residence</ENAMEX>, if a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">caller</ENAMEX> is eligible for assistance. After a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two-month</TIMEX> pilot program, the hotline is now in full operation.
Plans are to expand the effort to include <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Korean</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khmer</ENAMEX>, the
main <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cambodian</ENAMEX> language, by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>.
A confused <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tran</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Luu</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few weeks ago</TIMEX> seeking advice on
Medi-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cal</ENAMEX>, a term she had heard since arriving <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two months ago</TIMEX> from
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ho Chi Minh</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, the former <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saigon</ENAMEX>.
"A lot of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> come from an inherently repressive
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">regime</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luu</ENAMEX> said. "They don't think of going to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> for
assistance and public benefits."
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Luu</ENAMEX> recorded <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tran</ENAMEX>'s basic information and described <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Medi-Cal</ENAMEX>'s
medical assistance programs, advising <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tran</ENAMEX> of her rights and
finding a location close to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tran</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Westminster</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> where she could
apply.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hotline staff</ENAMEX> can elicit information that would be
difficult, if not impossible, in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Luu</ENAMEX> recently spent an
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hour</TIMEX> on the phone with a distraught <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>.
"She just kept crying," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luu</ENAMEX> said. "We have to be extremely
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> with them."
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> had called <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> before she was to be evicted from
her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX>. After coaxing information from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luu</ENAMEX> called
the elder-abuse hotline. Although the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> was evicted, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Luu</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resourcefulness</ENAMEX> and a social <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX>'s efforts found her a place at
a senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> facility.
"We're looking for a new way of serving the underserved
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">community</ENAMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Cohen</ENAMEX>, executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Society of Orange County</ENAMEX>. "Anything we can do to get out in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">community</ENAMEX>, to make <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> aware of how easy it is to get service,
that they won't be ripped off, is important.... "
According to census data, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Vietnamese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Orange</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">County</ENAMEX> jumped by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">nearly 89%</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 1990 and 2000</TIMEX>, while the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> increased by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">44%</NUMEX>.
In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles County</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Vietnamese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> rose <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">nearly 25%</NUMEX>
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the decade</TIMEX>, while the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> leaped by more than
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">34%</NUMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">More than 1.5 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asians</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Pacific Islanders</ENAMEX> now live in
the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">counties</ENAMEX>. Many have little or no <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> skills.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stewart Kwoh</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asian Pacific American Legal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center</ENAMEX>, said the idea of a hotline had been tossed around for
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. But the latest census figures and an influx of grant money
convinced center staff <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> that the time had come to begin the
program.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kwoh</ENAMEX>'s efforts have raised <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $300,000</NUMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Open</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Society Institute</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community Technology Foundation</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> to anchor the hotline.
Staff <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> have appeared on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Vietnamese</ENAMEX> radio and Mandarin
television to publicize the program.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tran</ENAMEX> called the hotline after her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> heard <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Luu</ENAMEX> on Bolsa
Radio, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">106.3</NUMEX> FM. The broadcasts have made <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Luu</ENAMEX> a celebrity of sorts.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Callers</ENAMEX> regularly greet her with: "Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kim</ENAMEX>, I have this problem and
I need your help."
In part, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hotline workers</ENAMEX> gain <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX>' faith because they
understand where their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">callers</ENAMEX> are coming from--literally.
When she glances down at the tattoo on her right forearm, staff
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anita Le</ENAMEX>'s forehead furrows in pain at the bold black
letters that spell out "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Le Quang Thai Ha</ENAMEX>." That's the name of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> who never made it out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>--who at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 15</TIMEX>, drowned
when bullets tore through the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> in which she was trying to
escape.
"We never forget where we came from," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Le</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">29</TIMEX>, who arrived
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six years</TIMEX> after her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>'s death. "We're in
a vacuum without helping others."
Stories stream from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Luu</ENAMEX>, too, of how she and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> fled
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Vietnam</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1979</TIMEX>. She described how her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> sat waist-deep
in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks</TIMEX> on a leaky fishing boat to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>, how
her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> gave up his own ration of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rice</ENAMEX> to feed his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, how
they settled in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisville</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ky.</ENAMEX>, with <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100</NUMEX> and a gold wedding ring
among them.
"Right now, I'm giving back to the community I grew up in," said
Luu, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX>, who lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alhambra</ENAMEX>. "The fact that I speak <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vietnamese</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> reconfirms that I'm still very <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Vietnamese</ENAMEX>.
"Even though I'm <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX>, I can relate to them. I understand
the depths of their pain."




