



Unusual <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Woodburn</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> helps indigenous <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexicans</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday, October 28, 2002</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alex Davis</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WOODBURN</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ore.</ENAMEX> (AP) - The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> refuses to pay me. My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are sick and don't speak <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>. We don't understand the law
about <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pesticides</ENAMEX> in the fields.
For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oregon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmworkers</ENAMEX> have raised these issues in
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Spanish</ENAMEX>. But what if the questions come in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mixteco</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Triqui</ENAMEX> or
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zapotec</ENAMEX>?
A small legal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> in downtown <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Woodburn</ENAMEX> is offering an answer.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Indigenous</ENAMEX> Project, a new program run by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oregon Law Center</ENAMEX>,
is one of only a handful of places in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> where
indigenous farmworkers from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central America</ENAMEX> can find
free and confidential legal aid.
The project aims to reach the growing number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are
following the agricultural migrant stream to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oregon</ENAMEX> but don't share
the language and culture of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spanish-speaking</ENAMEX> farmworker
majority.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julie Samples</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> with the program, estimates the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> indigenous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> at around <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, a dramatic
increase compared to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a decade ago</TIMEX>. Most are from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oaxaca</ENAMEX>, a state of
rugged mountains and extreme poverty in southern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>.
Samples, a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduate</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lewis & Clark Law School</ENAMEX>, spent
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> traveling to dozens of labor <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camps</ENAMEX> throughout the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willamette Valley</ENAMEX> to talk with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> about their legal rights.
She says indigenous farmworkers, driven north by economic hardship,
are more likely than <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speakers</ENAMEX> to be denied wages or forced
into substandard housing.
Most are <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mixtecs</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> familiar with injustice toward
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indians</ENAMEX> in their native <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. The bias continues in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>, sometimes from the larger <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> mainstream.
"Most of them have never had a fair shake from the outside
world," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Wilk</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oregon Law Center</ENAMEX>'s
Woodburn <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>. "They're not familiar with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
legal system."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilk</ENAMEX> says the indigenous program is at the same point where
legal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX> were <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two decades ago</TIMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">native Spanish</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speakers</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>, in a heavily <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic</ENAMEX> area of downtown
Woodburn, is a testament to the difficulty of reaching the
indigenous community.
A sign on the front door indicates the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> is "abierto," or
open in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Spanish</ENAMEX>. A coffee table inside is stacked with copies of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">El</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Noticiero Legal</ENAMEX>, or The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal News</ENAMEX>. But few materials are available
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mixteco</ENAMEX> or other indigenous tongues, in part because they barely
exist in written form.
Instead, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Samples</ENAMEX> is creating audio cassettes of legal
information. She works with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Valentin Sanchez</ENAMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oaxaca</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">native</ENAMEX> who
speaks <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mixteco</ENAMEX>. They spend most of their time
traveling to housing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camps</ENAMEX> - few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> own <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> - and setting up
presentations in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and community <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">centers</ENAMEX>.
The project was modeled after a similar effort created in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>
by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">California Rural Legal Assistance</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Irma Luna</ENAMEX>, a community worker
with that program, said it's not uncommon for indigenous laborers
to perform piecework for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 hours a day</TIMEX> and be paid <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$30</NUMEX> or
less.
Studies in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> show that most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mixtecs</ENAMEX> follow the tomato,
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">lettuce</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chile harvests</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central Valley</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fruit</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">berry</ENAMEX> harvests of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oregon</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>. Most are highly mobile,
young and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">male</ENAMEX>. Language is often a major stumbling block for
recent arrivals.
There have been a handful of high-profile cases in which
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">indigenous workers</ENAMEX> were charged with crimes in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oregon</ENAMEX> and detained
for lengthy periods due to communication barriers.
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 1990s</TIMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mixtec</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Santiago</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ventura</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morales</ENAMEX> spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX> in an <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oregon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> before his murder
conviction was overturned.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Several years later</TIMEX>, a migrant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adolfo Ruiz-Alvarez</ENAMEX>
was released from a state mental <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> of
psychiatric evaluations and drug treatments. He had been charged
with trespassing and public indecency near <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Mount Angel</ENAMEX>, but didn't
understand the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">interpreters</ENAMEX> who interviewed him in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Spanish</ENAMEX>. A
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">native</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oaxaca</ENAMEX>, he only spoke <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">an Indian dialect</TIMEX> called Triqu
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">i.</ENAMEX>
The majority of the cases in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Woodburn</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> are far simpler.
Common issues range from wage claims to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poor</ENAMEX> working conditions to
sexual harassment. Most are settled with a phone call or a letter
threatening litigation.
Sanchez, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indigenous Project</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tri-lingual employee</ENAMEX>, said the
number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mixtecs</ENAMEX> has grown considerably since he arrived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oregon</ENAMEX>
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 1990s</TIMEX>. He sees Mixtecs playing <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX>, shopping in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Woodburn</ENAMEX> grocery <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> and speaking his language on public
telephones.
A downtown <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX> called "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El Oaxaqueo</ENAMEX>" offers a place where
Mixteco <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speakers</ENAMEX> can find <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Oaxacan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> and beaded jewelry
made by indigenous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. From behind the counter, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lopez</ENAMEX>, who is <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mixtec</ENAMEX>, can call out prices to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mixteco</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish or English</ENAMEX>.
"I'm working on my <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> language now," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lopez</ENAMEX>, referring
to his <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classes</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Woodburn High School</ENAMEX>.
Some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mixtec</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> also have formed native <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>, or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hometown associations</ENAMEX>, that send money home for projects such as
telephone lines or <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> paving. The informal associations select
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> at random to return home for periods of service - working
as a volunteer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX>, for example, or town <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clerk</ENAMEX>.
Not all Oaxacans classify themselves as <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX>. Some trace their
ancestry to the influence of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oaxaca</ENAMEX> is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> most common source of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>
for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oregon</ENAMEX> public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>, which suggests a growing trend of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">indigenous people</ENAMEX> moving here.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oregon Law Center</ENAMEX> is one of a few legal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> that cater to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">farmworkers</ENAMEX>. The project is funded by a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two-year</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$80,000</NUMEX>
fellowship from the nonprofit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Academy</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Educational Development</ENAMEX>,
along with grants of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$37,500</NUMEX> each from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Spirit Mountain</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community Fund</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Campaign</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Equal Justice</ENAMEX>, and a grant of
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$12,500</NUMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PacifiCorp Foundation for Learning</ENAMEX>.
The money goes toward language resources, transportation and
legal research. It also provides a salary for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Samples</ENAMEX>, who speaks
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sanchez</ENAMEX>, who also speaks <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mixteco</ENAMEX>.
Legal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aid Services of Oregon</ENAMEX> runs a similar <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> in Woodburn
next door to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Indigenous</ENAMEX> Project, but is restricted in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> it serves - usually <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> with legal documents only -
because it receives federal funding.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nargess Shadbeh</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oregon Law Center</ENAMEX>'s farmworker
program, said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indigenous Project</ENAMEX> will continue into the future
if more funding can be raised. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">center</ENAMEX> has applied for several
grants since the first fellowship was awarded to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Samples</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>.



