



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Valley Needing Legal Services</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McALLEN</ENAMEX> (AP) - The consolidation of legal services <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poor</ENAMEX> may improve efficiency, but won't increase the number of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> served, a rural legal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">specialist</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South Texas</ENAMEX> says.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Hall</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Rural Legal Aid</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Weslaco</ENAMEX>, said
legal services for the poor in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rio Grande Valley</ENAMEX> are inadequate
and need a dramatic increase in funding.
"We've got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> for every <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poor people</ENAMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Valley</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hall</ENAMEX> said in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>'s editions of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Monitor</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">McAllen</ENAMEX>).
As part of a nationwide overhaul of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services Corp.</ENAMEX> to get
more poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> legal help, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> legal aid <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> are
being folded into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>, creating mega-programs involving <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">counties</ENAMEX> across <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">thousands of miles</NUMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McKay</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>, said the refocused
and larger programs can raise more money, find more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> and
increase the number of poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who get help through the civil
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts system</ENAMEX>.
The programs, supplemented by funding from state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX>,
bar <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundations</ENAMEX>, provide free legal help to the
poor but not in criminal cases.
But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hall</ENAMEX> said what's needed is more money. He said his group
takes on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 10,000</NUMEX> cases per year with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight or nine</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX>.
Of the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$329 million</NUMEX> appropriated by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corp.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Valley</ENAMEX> receives <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $15 million to $20</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">million</ENAMEX> and employs <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 37</NUMEX> staff <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Organizations</ENAMEX> that
provide free or "pro bono" services are able to maintain a better
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>-to-client ratio because they often specialize in particular
kinds of cases, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hall</ENAMEX> said. Even accounting for pro bono work, as
much <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">as 90 percent</NUMEX> of the legal needs of the poor go unmet,
according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Underwood</ENAMEX>, a law <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baylor</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX>.
"If every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> was doing pro bono work,
then that still wouldn't be enough," he said.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Underwood</ENAMEX> said <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> working full-time for a legal services
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX> can accomplish <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">as much as 20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> doing part-time pro bono
work on a similar case.
"The problem is, there's never been adequate public funding," he
said.
But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Boehm</ENAMEX>, a former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> said a lack of
funding for the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">LSC</ENAMEX> program is not the problem, it needs
reform



