



Alpaugh <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> fees may triple

It's either a big increase or a loss of service for the Tulare
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">County town</ENAMEX>.
By <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joan Obra</ENAMEX>
Alpaugh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> may see their water fees triple to avoid
losing service at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the month</TIMEX>.
The debate will unfold <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX> at a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tulare County Water Works</ENAMEX>
District <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1</TIMEX> meeting. The district, which provides water service to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">homes</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alpaugh</ENAMEX>, faces an unpalatable choice: raise its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">monthly</TIMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20</NUMEX> household fee or go without the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">arsenic</ENAMEX>-tainted and undrinkable
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tulare County Water Works</ENAMEX>' contract with its only <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">supplier</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alpaugh Irrigation District</ENAMEX>, which supplies <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX> in the
area, ends <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 1</TIMEX>. And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alpaugh Irrigation</ENAMEX>, which provides <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">recordkeeping</ENAMEX> and maintenance services to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tulare County Water</ENAMEX>
Works, is scaling back its role. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">district</ENAMEX> will sell only water
as of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 1</TIMEX>, at a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">monthly</TIMEX> price of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$43.50</NUMEX> for a household.
"We can no longer do it for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20</NUMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alpaugh Irrigation</ENAMEX> board
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Martin</ENAMEX>. The district, which didn't increase prices
fast enough to meet the rising cost of delivering <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>, amassed an
estimated <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$330,000</NUMEX> power bill during the state energy crisis. Last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">month</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Alpaugh Irrigation</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> approved a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">monthly</TIMEX> fee increase
from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20 to $68</NUMEX>.
If <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tulare County Water Works</ENAMEX> wants to keep its <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">170</NUMEX> hookups
flowing, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin</ENAMEX> said, it must also raise rates.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tulare County Water Works</ENAMEX> can't raise prices until a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 17</TIMEX>
election. The propertyrelated fee increase requires <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voter</ENAMEX> approval
under <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Proposition 218</ENAMEX>, a process <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tulare County Water Works</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> started after they learned the outcome of Alpaugh
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Irrigation</ENAMEX>'s vote.
At <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tulare County Water Works</ENAMEX>' informational meeting,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> will explain the rules. To block the possible fee increase,
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">51%</NUMEX> of property <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">district</ENAMEX> must submit protest votes in
writing. No protest vote means approval of the price jump.
But misinformation already is rampant. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sandra Meraz</ENAMEX>, Tulare
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">County Water Works</ENAMEX> board <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, interrupted an interview
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> when a screaming and crying farmworker arrived.
The farmworker thought the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> was getting turned off <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meraz</ENAMEX> explained later.
Part of the confusion stems from <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Prop. 218</ENAMEX>. A section of it
calls eligible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> of record." Another calls them
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tenants</ENAMEX> ... directly liable to pay the assessment, fee, or charge
in question."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alpaugh Irrigation</ENAMEX>'s board limited the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voter</ENAMEX> pool to property
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX>, sending each <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX>-only notices.
There weren't enough <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish-speaking</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> to warrant
bilingual notices, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin</ENAMEX> explained in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX>.
But that move left <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speakers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">renters</ENAMEX> angry. As a
result, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Schneider</ENAMEX>, executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central California</ENAMEX>
Legal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Services</ENAMEX>, is building a lawsuit against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alpaugh</ENAMEX>
Irrigation.
The district "should have sent notices to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">renters</ENAMEX> in addition to
property <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX>," he said.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tulare County Water Works</ENAMEX> may also come under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schneider</ENAMEX>'s
fire.
The district sent notices only to property <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> because "it's
a property-related fee," <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patrick Enright</ENAMEX> said. He's not
yet sure whether <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tulare County Water Works</ENAMEX> will accept <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">renters</ENAMEX>'
protest votes at the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 17</TIMEX> meeting




