



The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baltimore Sun</ENAMEX>

Weak economy, court challenge threaten legal services'
funding
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Advocates</ENAMEX> turning to state for financial assistance

<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrea F. Siegel</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, January 11, 2003</TIMEX>
The main funding source for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX>'s legal services to the
poor has fallen on hard times, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> are preparing to seek
unprecedented state financial help - even as they keep an eye on a
legal challenge that threatens to cut off a main source of funding
for such <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX> nationwide.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maryland Legal Services Corp.</ENAMEX> - which supports <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">28</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> providing legal help to those with cases involving
domestic abuse, landlord-tenant disputes and other issues - faces a
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 million</NUMEX> budget shortfall because of slack interest on the
accounts that help fund it.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s chief <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> is seeking a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.2 million</NUMEX> subsidy to
close the gap in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$7 million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> budget, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> are planning a strong push in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Assembly.</ENAMEX>
"You can bet we will be doing every kind of lobbying we can do
for our funding," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilhelm H. Joseph Jr.</ENAMEX>, executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maryland Legal Aid Bureau</ENAMEX>, the largest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">provider</ENAMEX> of legal help
to the poor. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bureau</ENAMEX> receives <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3.4 million</NUMEX> of its <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$15 million</NUMEX>
budget from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maryland Legal Services Corp.</ENAMEX>, which was
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert M. Bell</ENAMEX> said his budget request is intended
"to maintain the same level of services that we have had in the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last several years</TIMEX> in terms of access to justice" for the
needy.
The timing is awful, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> concede, as the state legislature
weighs what to do about an expected <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.2 billion</NUMEX> state budget
shortfall.
Complicating the picture is a case pending before the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> that challenges the mechanism
every <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> uses as a mainstay of legalservices funding.
At issue is an arrangement that skims interest from short-term
trust accounts that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> hold on behalf of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> and
funnels it to legal-services <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>.
By law, the interest must be too small to be worthwhile for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> to process for individual account <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">holders</ENAMEX>.


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IOLTA</ENAMEX> challenged
Until interest rates plummeted, this mechanism (known as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IOLTA</ENAMEX>,
or Interest On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lawyer Trust Accounts</ENAMEX>) pumped <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">up to $4 million</NUMEX> a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> legal services and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $160 million</NUMEX> into such
services nationwide.
But <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX>, the high court heard a constitutional challenge
claiming that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> takes the interest without just
compensation to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>. A ruling is expected by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>.
Even if the funding mechanism is upheld, legal-services groups
will be hard-pressed to meet their needs because of low interest
rates, according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Bar Association</ENAMEX>.
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the fiscal year that ended in June</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IOLTA</ENAMEX> revenue in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX>
was <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3.8 million</NUMEX> - down from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4.2 million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years ago</TIMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5.2</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX> in the heyday of high interest rates. That led to cuts this
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">up to 20 percent</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX> legal-services <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>, despite
emergency infusions of cash.
"Under the best-case scenario - if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IOLTA</ENAMEX> is upheld - we are
projecting a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.2 million</NUMEX> shortfall," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert J. Rhudy</ENAMEX>,
executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MLSC</ENAMEX>. "The critical need for legal aid
has gone up because of the recession."
He said that without more state help, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MLSC</ENAMEX> will cut grants
by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">up to 25 percent</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>. That would force <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> to drop some
advocacy work and thus serve fewer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.
As it is, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> say the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">110,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Marylanders</ENAMEX> they reach
probably are <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">no more than 20 percent</NUMEX> of those in need.
The <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$65,000</NUMEX> going to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Women's Law Center</ENAMEX>, for example, funds
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two days a week</TIMEX> of a statewide hot line, counseling <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,600</NUMEX> needy
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> -so many that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">callers</ENAMEX> say it can be hard to get
through.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Callers</ENAMEX> include those who have been abandoned without access to
family money, those not receiving court-ordered <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> support and
those who want to leave their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husbands</ENAMEX> but are unsure about their
legal rights.
In the event of a funding cut, "there is no way we would be able
to pick it up," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">L. Tracy Brown</ENAMEX>, executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">center</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J. Peter Sabonis Jr.</ENAMEX>, executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Homeless Persons</ENAMEX>
Representation Project in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore</ENAMEX>, which took a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX> cut
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>, will reduce outreach if more funds disappear.
"That means, for us, we won't have a presence out in front of a
welfare <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>, we won't be out there on the day <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">laborers</ENAMEX>' line at
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4:30 in the morning</TIMEX>, we won't have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> at a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">soup</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen</ENAMEX>,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sabonis</ENAMEX> said.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shelly Norman</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30</TIMEX>, got her legal aid from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sabonis</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>.
After a drug conviction kept her out of subsidized housing, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX> intervened and got her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">housing</ENAMEX> - along with a court hearing
that changed her conviction to a misdemeanor with probation before
judgment. She is about to return to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> for a hearing to clear
her record.
Meantime, she has graduated from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Coppin State College</ENAMEX>, works as
a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> and alcohol <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counselor</ENAMEX>, left subsidized housing and plans to
start work on a master's degree <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>.
"They've helped me so much, my life has truly turned around,"
she said.
Other programs focus on battered <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, the
disabled, day <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">laborers</ENAMEX>, community improvement <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> and crime
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>.


Lobbying campaign
To help ensure that such services continue, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX>
Bar <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> are lobbying <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">legislators</ENAMEX> to
explain how legal services help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">constituents</ENAMEX> in every district. For
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time, and at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">judiciary</ENAMEX>'s request, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rhudy</ENAMEX> has sent
every new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">legislator</ENAMEX> an orientation package about legal help for
the poor.
Though optimistic, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> know that getting <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.2 million</NUMEX> from
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> is an uphill fight.
"Everyone else ... is looking for more funding in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> when
there is a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 billion</NUMEX> shortfall," said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Speaker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael E.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Busch</ENAMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anne</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arundel County</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX>.
"Everybody has taken a big hit," said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas V.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Miller</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Prince George's County</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX>. "I do believe the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">legislators</ENAMEX> will look askance at new issues."
A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.-</ENAMEX>elect <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert L. Ehrlich Jr.</ENAMEX> said the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">incoming</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> could make no funding promises.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Advocates</ENAMEX> are looking at other ways to generate money.
A letter-writing campaign asks every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> to
donate "at least the dollar value of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">billable hour</TIMEX>" - typically
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">hundred dollars</NUMEX> - to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid Bureau</ENAMEX>.
Check, in lieu of work
Starting <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next month</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> must report to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> how much
free or low-fee legal work they do for the poor and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">charities</ENAMEX>, with
a goal of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">50 hours</TIMEX> a year.
Though many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> provide such services, they are also being
urged to write a check to a legal-services <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> in lieu of
the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Advocates</ENAMEX> also might borrow ideas from other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tennessee</ENAMEX>
has a surcharge on speeding tickets, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX> assesses an annual lawyer
registration fee, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas</ENAMEX> uses dollars from its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crime Victims</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Compensation Fund</ENAMEX> for such programs.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maryland</ENAMEX> has a surcharge on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> filing fees that goes to legal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">services</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">needy</ENAMEX>.





