



<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wilmington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> honored for pro bono work
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sean O'Sullivan</ENAMEX>

<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 28, 2002</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wilmington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dana Harrington Conner</ENAMEX> has won a national
award for her work with an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> that offers legal
assistance to low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>.
The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sandra Day O'Connor Award</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Professional Service</ENAMEX> was
presented to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conner</ENAMEX> in a ceremony at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Supreme Court</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 19</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conner</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37</TIMEX>, is the managing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Delaware Volunteer Legal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Services</ENAMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteer attorneys</ENAMEX> offering help to
low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX>. She also is an adjunct <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Widener University School of Law</ENAMEX>. The award was given to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conner</ENAMEX>
"for her outstanding work in public service, pro bono and community
service on behalf of indigent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX>," according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inns of Court</ENAMEX>, which presents the award.
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Delaware Volunteer Legal Services</ENAMEX> helped more than
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,000</NUMEX> low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defendants</ENAMEX>.
"The entire law school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> is proud to be associated with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dana Harrington Conner</ENAMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Widener Dean Douglas E. Ray</ENAMEX>. "Her
award is a tribute to her public service."
The national award was created to recognize an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> in
practice for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">less than 10 years</TIMEX> for excellence in public interest
or pro bono activities. The award is named for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O'Connor</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conner</ENAMEX> said she was honored to receive the recognition.
"The award says a lot about the legal profession, that it places
such a high honor on pro bono <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX>," she said, adding that it
also says a lot about the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Delaware Bar</ENAMEX>, which nominated her.
"I get to receive this award, but there are a lot of people
behind it," she said. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">More than 600</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Delaware</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> have
participated in providing the free legal service, she said.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conner</ENAMEX> said she hopes news of the award will inspire others to
do volunteer work.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Inns of Court</ENAMEX> is a national legal association
composed of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 24,000</NUMEX> federal, state and local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>, law <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professors</ENAMEX> and law <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Delaware Supreme Court</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy J. Holland</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>'s
national <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>.




