



Proposal floated to study <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wingate</ENAMEX>'s winds
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday June 7, 2002</TIMEX>

BY <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BRAD BENNETT</ENAMEX>
bbennett@herald.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>
An environmental <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> may study the winds that flowed from the
old Wingate landfill <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">incinerator</ENAMEX>'s smokestacks, and identify wide
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">areas</ENAMEX> where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> may have been exposed to toxic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemicals</ENAMEX>.
That was among the latest ideas suggested in a proposed study
that would search for a link between the landfill's contaminants
and high rates of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">illness</ENAMEX> around it.
Black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community leaders</ENAMEX> supported the study at a meeting on
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, despite skepticism from government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> that the
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$120,000</NUMEX> earmarked for it may not be enough.
''Not only is the money short, but time is even shorter,'' said
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Wilson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ombudsman</ENAMEX> for the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agency for Toxic Substances</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disease Registry</ENAMEX>, which will make the money available only if
the health-study proposal from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid Service</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Broward County</ENAMEX>
is strong enough.
Friction between competing community <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> nearly jeopardized
the health study, which must reach community consensus and be
funded by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 30, 2003</TIMEX>.
The proposal -- complete with a line-item budget and commitments
from participating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> -- is expected to reach the state
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Department</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health</ENAMEX> by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 8</TIMEX>.
If the study bears out enough facts to merit more research, the
state could apply for another <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$120,000</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the second year</TIMEX>.
But the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> grant is by no means guaranteed, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilson</ENAMEX> said,
adding that his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>'s budget has already been cut by <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">million</ENAMEX>.
''The problem here is money,'' said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Estok</ENAMEX>, an
environmental <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineer</ENAMEX> and health <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">specialist</ENAMEX> who works with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal</ENAMEX>
Aid. ``We're trying to get what we can for our dollar.''
The study proposal goes beyond looking at a link between the
landfill and high rates of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> near it, and also seeks to study
non-fatal diseases such as skin <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">rashes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">thyroid disorders</ENAMEX> and
abnormal liver function, among other illnesses.
Although a previous version of the study sought to exhume the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">infants</ENAMEX> and to autopsy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX> whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> live in the
area around the capped landfill, the new version suggests that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">autopsy</ENAMEX> might have to be funded another way.
The landfill, at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1300 NW 31st Ave.</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort Lauderdale</ENAMEX>, operated
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">from 1954 to 1978</TIMEX>. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> believe its contaminants made
them sick, but no study has ever proven a link.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> has capped the landfill and wants to create a golf
course on the site. Some black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community leaders</ENAMEX> support those
plans. Others are focused on forcing the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> to relocate residents
and clean up toxic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemicals</ENAMEX> now buried under the plastic cap.




