



<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Workers</ENAMEX>' aid <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">center</ENAMEX> open today
By <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holly Edwards Staff Writer</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 13, 2002</TIMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Thousands</NUMEX> of low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Fernando</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Valley</ENAMEX> face exploitation in the workplace -- <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">overtime</TIMEX> without pay,
long <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> without breaks, earnings below the minimum wage.
Now, those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> may be able to recover what they are owed
through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Workers</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Rights Self-Help Center</ENAMEX>, which opens at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 a.m.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mission College</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sylmar</ENAMEX>.
Housed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campus center</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>' rights
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">center</ENAMEX> will be staffed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteers</ENAMEX> -- college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Neighborhood Legal Services</ENAMEX>, a nonprofit
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organization</ENAMEX> that provides legal help to the poor. It will be open
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>.
Those involved with the effort say the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> will help workers
to learn how to stand up for their rights and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> to learn
skills they can use in the workplace.
"A lot of times education is done in a vacuum, but this will
help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> learn to deal with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are upset, spot legal
issues and learn to be empathetic and still do their job," said
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Jordan</ENAMEX>, a law <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mission College</ENAMEX>.
"For the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>, the goal is self-empowerment through
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">education</ENAMEX>, and they might also decide to sign up for a night course
while they're here."
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>' rights <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">center</ENAMEX> is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> created by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Neighborhood</ENAMEX>
Legal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Services</ENAMEX>. The other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">center</ENAMEX> has operated at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monroe High School</ENAMEX>
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Hills</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> and serves <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 100</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> each
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">month</TIMEX>, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy Cervantes</ENAMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Neighborhood Legal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Services</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> is funded by a grant from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Bar of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>. It will provide brochures, form letters seeking back
pay and other benefits, and help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> understand the law, but it
will not provide legal representation, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cervantes</ENAMEX> said.
It will also help all low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>, regardless of their
residency status.
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Immigration</ENAMEX> status is irrelevant," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cervantes</ENAMEX> said. "This a
place where anyone can get legal information. It's open to all
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> who have employment problems."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cervantes</ENAMEX> said workplace abuses are widespread and occur
primarily in the garment, construction, restaurant and domestic
services <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX>.
In <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> case she is now reviewing, she said <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> who were
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cousins</ENAMEX> worked for the same construction <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> and put in
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> of unpaid labor. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> is owed <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$70,000</NUMEX>, while
the other is owed <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20,000</NUMEX>, she said.
"The most important thing is to keep track of all the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> you
work, especially if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employer</ENAMEX> doesn't provide that information,"
she said. "You don't have to have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>, but you have to know
your rights."
Many of those exploited in the workplace are undocumented
residents who believe they have no rights, while others are
threatened with termination if they complain, she said.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cervantes</ENAMEX> added that undocumented <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">laborers</ENAMEX> have the same rights
as anyone else in the workplace, except they can't file for
unemployment benefits if fired.
"If undocumented <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> didn't have rights, it would amount to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">slavery</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cervantes</ENAMEX> said. "Most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> don't exploit their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>, but there are some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> who really do take advantage
of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> are more vulnerable to this
abuse."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edgar Villatoro</ENAMEX>, a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Van Nuys</ENAMEX>, said
he worked <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">100-hour</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX> for a party supply business but was paid
for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">only 40 hours</TIMEX>. With <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cervantes</ENAMEX>' help, he said he wrote his
employer a letter demanding the money, provided an account of the
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> he worked, and just received <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> checks totaling <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">more than</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3,000</NUMEX>.
"A lot of times I worked <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Villatoro</ENAMEX> said. "But
when I asked my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> about the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">overtime</TIMEX>, he told me I could walk
out the door anytime."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cervantes</ENAMEX> said this is exactly the type of exploitation that can
be prevented through education.
"We're helping them to help themselves by knowing their rights,"
she said.



