



Working <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">for Free Pays Off for Caring Lawyer</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Zucker</ENAMEX> chooses to provide pro bono legal aid to poor
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tenants</ENAMEX> over more prestigious work, and it has become his life's
passion.

<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karima A. Haynes</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday, January 5, 2003</TIMEX>
Nothing in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Zucker</ENAMEX>'s upbringing seems to have prepared him
for his life's work defending the poor.
A tall, athletic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who favors pleated khakis and starched
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">button-down</ENAMEX> shirts, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Zucker</ENAMEX> grew up in an upper-middle-class enclave
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">west San Fernando Valley</ENAMEX>, far from the poverty he now sees
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX>.
At <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taft High School</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UCLA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zucker</ENAMEX> said, the closest brush
with poverty was reading newspaper articles about unscrupulous
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bosses</ENAMEX> withholding wages from garment district <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>.
Before graduating from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Loyola Law School</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>, Zucker
interviewed with a prestigious <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Monica</ENAMEX> law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> and deftly
matched wits with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partners</ENAMEX> over lunch at an upscale <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX>.
Yet as he chatted amiably with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partners</ENAMEX>, something wasn't quite
right.
"I just didn't get the impression that they were really happy,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zucker</ENAMEX> said. "They seemed to be more passionate about their weekend
plans than the work they were doing."
After the meeting, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zucker</ENAMEX> realized he had to ask himself some
fundamental questions. What was his life's passion? What work would
be so satisfying that he'd do it for free?
He found the answer as he recalled his schooling. Zucker
remembered the elation he felt in law school, when he helped
resolve a landlord-tenant dispute while volunteering at a legal aid
program.
"There was no big, dramatic event in my childhood that made me
want to help poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zucker</ENAMEX> said. "But it doesn't take a
bleeding heart <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberal</ENAMEX> to rally behind a cause and do the right
thing."
Today, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zucker</ENAMEX> has dedicated his career to helping poor people
gain access to quality legal representation. He is a full-time
business law <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cal State</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Northridge</ENAMEX>, where in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> he
founded the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Center</ENAMEX>, a hands-on program where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> earn
course credit by helping low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with landlord-tenant
disputes. Through the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 30</NUMEX> indigent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> a year
receive free legal help, ranging from filling out documents to
receiving representation in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>.
The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">35-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northridge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">resident</ENAMEX> also serves as supervising
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Van Nuys Self-Help Legal Access Center</ENAMEX>, a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-room
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> in a prefabricated <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> in the shadow of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Van Nuys</ENAMEX>
Courthouse where the impoverished go to resolve all manner of legal
problems.
On <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a recent morning</TIMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> dispensed advice in
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> about divorce proceedings to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a dozen</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> seated around a
conference table. A law <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX> huddled over a stack
of papers. And <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteers</ENAMEX> tended to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> at a counter
while other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> sat at computers downloading forms from the
Internet.
Zucker, who <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteers</ENAMEX> at the center <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several days a week</TIMEX>, was
recently honored for volunteering more than <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">150 hours</TIMEX> in free legal
services to the poor -- <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than three</NUMEX> times the time donated by
most practicing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX>, he said.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Bar of California</ENAMEX> presented <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zucker</ENAMEX> with its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pro Bono Service Award</ENAMEX> for his volunteer work with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tenants</ENAMEX>' rights issues. The award was established in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1983</TIMEX> to give
statewide recognition to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> for providing pro bono legal
services to the poor.
Zucker was nominated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Van Nuys</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ventura</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">County Superior Court</ENAMEX>, where he has served as a temporary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> in
Small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Claims Court</ENAMEX> and has volunteered with a court-sponsored
program for at-risk high school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>.
Being acknowledged by his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peers</ENAMEX> was a thrill, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zucker</ENAMEX> said, but
his greatest honor comes from earning praise from his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>.
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zucker</ENAMEX> is a huge <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocate</ENAMEX> for the little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>," said
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicole Blackman</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21</TIMEX>, a senior business major at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cal State</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northridge</ENAMEX>. "He is one of those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who wants to see good things
happen to good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>."
The toughest challenge in defending the poor is focusing on a
case's merits and not on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">client</ENAMEX>'s circumstances, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zucker</ENAMEX> said.
"I am a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>, and my job is to protect the interests of my
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX>, but some cases don't have merit and I have to let them go,"
he said. "I don't take every case, but I take the clients
seriously."
On <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a recent morning</TIMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Access Center</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Zucker</ENAMEX> sat at a
small table with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacqueline Green</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">41</TIMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Hollywood</ENAMEX>. The
single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> was trying to avoid being evicted.
"He is treating me like <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Green</ENAMEX> said. "He is a kind,
nice-hearted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>. He doesn't care if you are on public assistance:
He's willing to help."
Although he is doing what he loves most, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zucker</ENAMEX> said, at times,
he gets worn down by his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>' overwhelming poverty. To relieve
the burden, he frequently goes for long drives or talks <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX> with
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kiren Dosanjh</ENAMEX>, also an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cal State</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Northridge</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX>.
Looking back, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zucker</ENAMEX> said he doesn't regret his decision to
dedicate his career to defending the poor.
"Someone once said, 'Get a job you love, and you'll never work a
day in your life,' " <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zucker</ENAMEX> said. "I believe it's more important to
get a job you are happy with and let things flow from there."




