
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		what do you think
 	
 	
 		well i think <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> research should be funded more than it's currently being funded i think that
 		uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> including i mean mostly the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> but also you know a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> i think that it's a disease of of a certain population i meaning <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">um homosexuals</ENAMEX> and and uh intravenous drug users
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		in fact it is very much a a normal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s uh <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX> as well i think that we should fund much more
 	
 	
 		sure
 		right i think i i agree with that to a certain degree
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> certainly on an absolute scale it should be i i think it should be funded more
 		on a relative scale um looking at it in comparison with other
 		problems and no it's not a big environment
 		i'm not so sure about that however
 		um yeah you're right definitely there's there's a definite um stigma out there that yeah it's it's it's limited exclusive to intravenous <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homosexuals</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">um blacks</ENAMEX> or whatever
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and that's not that's not the case anymore it may have started out that way even though there's there's still no proof of that
 		actually the most recent
 		um the that i've gotten is they're starting to look at um
 		well it started over in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX> they're starting to look at
 		i believe
 		but believe it of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">monkey</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah  the  <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">monkey</ENAMEX> i think
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah there was some kind of research going on
 		and i can't remember what the exact uh gist of it was but something they hadn't considered before and it's like they now they're trying to go way back to the original
 		<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> outbreaks of it to see if they can uh nail down what  exactly it was
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		but uh
 	
 	
 		well you know you have you have a point about you know where there's other issues that that need a lot of funding too  sure that is true
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh there's a lot of things that are funded and a lot of waste that can be redirected too  i think that that again that uh
 	
 	
 		oh sure
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> is is something that has to be dealt with by every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> um and and not just in
 		understanding that it's you know can affect uh everyone
 		but in acting um in a uh you know sensible way to avoid uh the spread of this disease
 	
 	
 		yeah um-hum well i i agree with that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um the point i i wanted to make was just strictly the environment like right now they say we've lost forty percent of the ozone layer just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		in in selected in selected spots and that's really becoming a really big problem but that's not to down play the importance of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> research you know
 	
 	
 		sure
 		right right
 	
 	
 		um when you think about that importance you also have to consider that uh
 		not only is <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> good in and of it's own but it also uh has a lot to deal with
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">um cancer</ENAMEX> and with mononucleosis and all the all the various diseases that affect the T cell from a and the and the when the white <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> of the immune system because all fairly interrelated
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 		right
 	
 	
 		so i think research on <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> would benefit all that stuff
 	
 	
 		yeah good point um i i think more often should go into you know <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> uh education
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		you know commercials you know public service commercials um schools
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		things like that
 	
 	
 		but it seems a lot like they're almost covering it up at this point
 	
 	
 		yeah which is ridiculous
 	
 	
 		you you you really don't see a lot out there
 	
 	
 		it's like coming up with  plague you know no it's not happening
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh disregard the you know  one out of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> dropping dead next to you you know
 	
 	
 		right you know that's that's for sure i i like i said i go to school at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UCF</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>
 		and actually that kind of hits home because that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kimberly Begajah</ENAMEX> that had <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AIDS</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and died from it she went to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dentist</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stewart Florida</ENAMEX> that's where she got it
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 	
 	
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stewart</ENAMEX>'s like <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three hours</TIMEX> away from where i go to school
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i hear a lot more in local news about it
 	
 	
 		uh more than that i had a couple of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> who went to that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dentist</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		interesting
 	
 	
 		yeah and they were definitely sweating bullets there for a while um and found out that they they were negative you know they didn't have any problems but um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know boy talk about making you think twice before you go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dentist</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		or any health care practitioner at this point
 	
 	
 		yeah i guess so
 	
 	
 		yeah because they really the last article i read on that they still hadn't figured out how she could've gotten it from him
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because he he as far as they could tell he sterilized the equipment he used gloves he did all the the proper precautions
 		um asides from telling his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> that he had <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AIDS</ENAMEX>
 		um but still that didn't make any difference they still got it so they they're not real sure how that how that worked
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		but uh
 		yeah i'm i'm a lot more cautious of that but
 		
 		
 	