
 
     		
 	
 		okay uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well we just got our income tax return and i'm perfectly happy what about you
 	
 	
 		well let's see um i haven't gotten <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX> yet because my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> are getting all that stuff at um at home in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bay area</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so i'm not sure how much i'm getting back but i'm pretty sure should get back a little bit since i'm still a student so not too much
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		not too bad though
 	
 	
 		but as far as writing checks out and paying taxes i think it's pretty high but i i'm uh you know i i guess that's where we have to be where it we have to keep raising them for to keep some of the things that that we have and
 	
 	
 		yeah it it's one of  those necessities of life that we all have to you know pay taxes but uh although it is kind of a pain sometimes though
 	
 	
 		it's just scary though about you know how high are the taxes gonna be when my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are my age
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know that that's that's scary too because it's not anything like the way it was when i was young and small and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know that that's a scary part too that you have to think about
 	
 	
 		yeah and and like as as time goes on you know things get more expensive and because we're  we're increasingly complex society <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that day</TIMEX> by day things get more um things get more expensive as well as more complex
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and you know taxes are one of the ways that help pay for a lot of the things that are needed in this society
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i mean everything from you know from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> to um to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> to um to feeding the homeless to um to you know feeding the homeless to uh maintaining <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prisons</ENAMEX> to maintaining polices or fire <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">departments</ENAMEX> and things like that
 		and it's now there's more and more things that need attending to and that sort of thing and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know it's it's becoming a a large responsibility but someone someone has to pay for it and that's us
 	
 	
 		yeah and then you find out about all these things about are your taxes you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX> are your money is your money going to where you want it to go and there's gonna be a special <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> i i can't i can't remember if it's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Twenty Twenty</NUMEX> or one of those things where um
 		i think it's one of the local news i think they're having an a documentary something about that about they're trying to catch some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> about
 		not spending your tax pay monies right and fraud and that kind of thing you know and that's kind of scary too
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh so that would be interesting to see i wanted to see that program
 	
 	
 		yeah and and even even <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> it's like you know there's still a considerable amount of taxes that you know we're paying for but you'd think that we're still in this this this uh deficit state that we're still not able to pay off things just because
 	
 	
 		i know
 	
 	
 		the budget's not big enough as it is
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and makes you wonder when there's  you know uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> out there that have you know tax rates also like close to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">fifty percent</NUMEX> or higher
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know it's like fifty percent of everything you make is already gone before you can get it and that that's kind of a scary thought and i hope it doesn't come down to that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but on the other hand they also while while those <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> that have high taxes also have things like um like socialized <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX> and things like that too which are nice fringe benefits of it
 		so everyone has everyone has the access to medical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> as well as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> that sort of thing and it's good but it's it's the price they pay
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i mean it it can be argued one way or another whether the economically it's actually good for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> or good for any given <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> to have that because those those <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> tend to be um as far as cash flow a a lot
 		um have a be tend to have a much slower cash flow and don't try and generate a larger um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		a large amount of revenue because there's so little um currency flow through out the economic system
 	
 	
 		hm
 		well
 		you sure do know a lot know a lot
 	
 	
 		uh just keeping up with the times that's all
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		as it as it turns out you know it's one of those <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of those interests that you know i kind of like to keep up on because well it's nice to know that when i'm actually you know i do start working that
 		i'll like to know like where my tax dollars are going too  i work hard to to get you know i like to know where it's going to
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		that's true
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		what do you think about these items that are gonna be um taxed even more like <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">um tobacco</ENAMEX> and that kind of thing
 	
 	
 		i think in a in a way it's good in a way it's not um but i think in general it's probably good i mean a lot of things like <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco</ENAMEX> and alcohol and things like that have been have been in the past
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um have been not taxed because there's been such a large lobby against them against the taxes for them you know sponsored by <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> and tobacco <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it's things like <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco</ENAMEX> are um they're they're a proven health hazard to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">smokers</ENAMEX> as well as nonsmokers
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right
 	
 	
 		and it's as far as a safety thing in like in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Luis Obispo</ENAMEX> for example there's an ordinance which states that um there's no smoking in any public areas
 		and so if you walk into any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> or any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX> there's no smoking allowed anywhere
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	