
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay i'm here how do you feel about the public schools
 	
 	
 		well
 		our public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> are are really poor i feel um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i'm not sure where <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgia</ENAMEX> ranks in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> but uh we're toward the bottom
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh there's a lot of things that i see
 		that are so obviously wrong
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that you would think it'd be easy to correct but the system doesn't allow for the corrections
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah how about you
 	
 	
 		well that's interesting i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> who used to live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kennesaw Georgia</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yes
 	
 	
 		and uh she has a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> actually has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> now but only had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> when she was there
 		and she complained quite a bit about this school system there
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		and
 	
 	
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Cobb County</ENAMEX> is better than the county i'm in she was in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Cobb County</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 		right i'm i can't really say much about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> up here i really don't come from here
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i'm only up here temporarily on an internship but um i live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Orlando Florida</ENAMEX> usually
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> down there from what i know are not bad they're pretty good
 	
 	
 		well that's great
 	
 	
 		but i know that in some i know in a lot of rural areas they're not that good
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		for example i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX> and he says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> there are are incredibly bad um just terrible
 	
 	
 		well i feel that we're way behind uh i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> that is in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> grade and uh they have just now taken up division
 	
 	
 		hm
 		wow
 	
 	
 		uh yeah and and you know i  my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and i go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> and we buy these math books and and fractions and multiplication division things and
 	
 	
 		that is slow
 	
 	
 		i feel like uh
 		there are several areas that we're just really really slow in and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i don't blame the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> as much as i blame the system it is
 	
 	
 		what do you think's wrong to cause that
 	
 	
 		well well for one thing there's not enough money in the school system and the money they do have they're not they do not use it wisely uh she my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">twenty seven</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and that's certainly is a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> for one person
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		to deal with on an <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> basis
 	
 	
 		perhaps
 	
 	
 		uh
 		but more than that i don't think that they have the authority to command the attention of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and when you have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> in that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> that constantly keep the ca class in an uproar and you're not at liberty
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		to do something about it other than give them on campus isolation or send them to the principal<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">'s office</ENAMEX> and it
 	
 	
 		yeah that's that's one thing i worry about
 	
 	
 		it you know it can you it can really be bad uh also i think
 		we have a lot of uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Hispanics</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		there you go uh-huh
 	
 	
 		and we have a lot of uh uh the county i am i'm in uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minorities</ENAMEX> are mostly <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah probably quite a few black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> up there and and
 	
 	
 		no  we're from a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">county</ENAMEX> and uh we're from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">county</ENAMEX> they marched in we're in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Forsyth</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">county</ENAMEX> yes and we and there's very very few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> uh so uh so that's um
 	
 	
 		no
 		oh is that right
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		i i hate to say  it's not a problem uh because i hate to feel like they are a problem although they are
 	
 	
 		yeah but you know it it it's you don't want to seem racist or prejudice or whatever but then again yeah there is no denying that it that
 	
 	
 		but it is a problem
 		uh especially in the inner <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> inner city
 	
 	
 		sure you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> you have to admit that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> have to slow things down for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who don't understand especially if there's not a very well developed special education program at the school
 	
 	
 		well and  you can't put all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in special education uh and if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> do not care enough to take an interest in whether the homework is done
 	
 	
 		that's right you can't do that
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know
 	
 	
 		see i grew up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nebraska</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> that i went to there was fantastic it i i really consider myself very very lucky
 		um we had a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> that had classes probably about the same size you're talking <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty seven thirty</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> to class to a class
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		but your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> had control
 	
 	
 		but
 		yeah we zipped right along you know i i was i was doing mathematics fractions and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">division</ENAMEX> and multiplication by the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> grade easily um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah i i believe i was too
 	
 	
 		um-hum but you're right you know with all this  don't hurt the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and don't abuse their rights you've also taken something away from the discipline i think
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		um well it it really is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> of mine because if we could afford it my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> would be in private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> we just cannot afford it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right i was gonna ask you if there that was an option
 	
 	
 		um if
 		
 		
 	