
 
     		
 	
 		the biggest social change that i've seen in the last <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		is that i you know i'm <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">only twenty four twenty five</TIMEX> right just turned <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty five</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years ago</TIMEX> i can remember when it was not common to see <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> or household working
 		and getting behind and uh running into economic problems the way things are <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> um
 		you know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> just to get by in many cases you have to have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> working in the middle income <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> just to stay with where they were in the seventies
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		um-hum um-hum i agree with that
 	
 	
 		and and it's it's really rough that's probably the biggest thing i've noticed
 	
 	
 		well i'd have to take a slightly different thing uh viewpoint uh i'm uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty five</TIMEX> uh and um
 		uh to me it's something a little more subtle it it's just a prevalence of computer technology and uh everyday life i mean
 		i can remember when everything was still done by by hand by paper by hand  as opposed to computer generated paper now
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 	
 	
 		um you know uh before uh you know when uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clerks</ENAMEX> in grocery <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> uh actually had to be able to add things up and in their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> and check it
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		which is  plusses and minuses there i guess
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i remember when we were going to the grocery <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> when i was younger those big monstrosity cash register
 	
 	
 		oh yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">greens</ENAMEX> buttons the rows and rows
 	
 	
 		yeah um-hum
 		and it was actually quite and art form to see some of the you know older or or more experienced cashiers go you know fly through that is like those <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hippies</ENAMEX> see what the abacus is still
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh so uh maybe that's just a different viewpoint uh but uh i just
 		remember everything well just writing a letter for for work you know i mean in word processor you know we can
 		to me i can't even image now how they even produced books or letters before word processors you know then we'd have to through fifty iterations at least the way i write letters and things
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 		yeah i i found all through school you know you write your hand to death you go through pens and uh i'm actually because i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> computers here
 		i'm actually loosing the ability to write by hand and feel comfortable doing it
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		it's too slow i think the speed of the computer i think much faster because i can type much faster than i can actually write now
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and i what happens is words will drop out of writing and i'll go back because i'm thinking so i'm thinking at the speed that i type on the computer
 	
 	
 		right right
 	
 	
 		and you know we didn't have that problem <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years ago</TIMEX> and then we didn't have fax machines and we didn't have to you know press <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> if you want to be directed to the service <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> press two
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah i you know i i i don't even write any more mainly because uh well i can type faster like you can and also my handwriting is  legible i can't i can't blame it on that printer most of the time so
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 		
 
 		it's it's incredible you know i remember i started on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commodore</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixty four</TIMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ninety eighty six</NUMEX> that was my first computer
 		and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> i'm on a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three eight six thirty three</TIMEX> and it's too slow you know i can't wait
 	
 	
 		yeah hey same here same here yeah we
 	
 	
 		
 
 		it's got to go faster you know
 	
 	
 		well we're getting greedy i guess but uh well with regarding to your comment i i have to agree with that too there's a prevalence of uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		of uh two income households that uh you never really saw before although i probably on the exception of that my both my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> did work but most of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends parents</ENAMEX> when i was growing up
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> did not and uh it's simply not the case and uh
 		to to keep the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> that owns your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> happy the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> that owns both your <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> happy and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> that owns your credit card happy  you do have to
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i think my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> in fact uh started to work part-time now because we'd started out we got married she had not uh uh wanted to work uh after we had our <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> and i said fine but now
 		paying for these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>  she's she's had to back to work part-time
 	
 	
 		oh yeah up here
 		up here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rochester</ENAMEX> almost everybody works for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kodak</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Xerox</ENAMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten ten years ago</TIMEX> you were always assured of having a job
 	
 	
 		um yeah i remember that
 	
 	
 		and now you you know i my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX> worked for his entire life for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kodak</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> the same thing but now everyone's worried and
 		and uh you can't rely on that kind of thing anymore everything sped up so fast and there's no more old-fashioned reliability in things anymore the way pace the pace has changed
 	
 	
 		i remember when i got out of college which was seventy <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> if you get a job with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Motors</ENAMEX> or AT&T or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX>
 		you're set for life
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		not after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AT&T</ENAMEX>'s going to let go fifty <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousand</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i i'm uh constantly putting stuff up in  telecom
 		from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CWA</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX> there and they're letting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> go like crazy it's just it they're replacing them with computers
 	
 	
 		well you plus you know you know after the uh divestiture or well break up
 		
 		
 	