
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		so interesting political trends or events huh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well i guess the uh most interesting one that's uh going on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">right now</TIMEX> from my perspective is this uh phenomena of um  uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ross</ENAMEX> Perot
 		uh caught his interview last night with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Frost</ENAMEX> and it was the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first time</TIMEX> i had you know heard um you know his views expressed by himself i had heard other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> talk about what they thought he believed in
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but the whole phenomena of him coming out of uh literally no where no party um at least no apparent party support on either side
 		is pretty interesting
 	
 	
 		huh
 		yeah i have not even heard believe it or not of that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> i'm  not kidding when you when you said it it was kind of like a surprise
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		like out of nowhere yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah i think mainly because i haven't been watching what's politically going on um in that at you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		in that aspect uh as far as like now the new health bill that went through <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota</ENAMEX> uh being that it is their neighboring <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> and that i lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota</ENAMEX> and more familiar with the politics that involved with that and that being passed
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but um as far as politics in the grander uh
 		part of it as if you want to look at uh election type things i'm not quite sure even if i'm going to vote uh
 	
 	
 		um-hum yeah
 	
 	
 		it it gets harder and harder each time an election comes up like that to make the decision on who would be the best to run um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well it seems that the decisions so far has been filtered by uh you know party politics so much that when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> finally get <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> approval party support and therefore get presented to the public
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		sure
 		exactly
 	
 	
 		the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> are already beyond what uh most public uh feels is acceptable behavior
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know the one of the common criticisms of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is uh gee he'll say or do anything in order to get to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> and and up unto the point of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh Perot</ENAMEX> being a serious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> it seems like that
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		that was a requirement of being a a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contender</ENAMEX> within the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> is is to have done all those things
 	
 	
 		um-hum sure
 	
 	
 		i mean here's a here's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years</TIMEX> has been working toward you know getting the party nomination and and preparing himself for the presidency
 		and now it seems like both he and the incumbent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> are you know pretty seriously threatened by somebody who comes out of
 		<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a whole</TIMEX> nonpolitical arena
 	
 	
 		he might be a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a one</NUMEX> of those sure uh it it's kind of when you think back of the old politics where a dirt farmer
 		uh when you think of some of the best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidents</ENAMEX> we've had in the past have been <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that have struggled to get to the top i mean they were not rich in in any means
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it has been kind of in the past uh i don't know maybe <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fifty years</TIMEX> that in order for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> to get involved involved with politics they've had to have money
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and you had to have the views of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that were going to be paying your way um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so it makes the common <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> uh not to say that a common <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> couldn't run for government and do a a fabulous job because he's got <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are quite intelligent and
 		i don't know if we'll ever see that you know where a common <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> could ever get in there that has good moral standings and uh has
 		um you know you think of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abraham</ENAMEX> linking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> and you know just the the background of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abraham Lincoln</ENAMEX> you know teaching himself to read he didn't go to college he didn't
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know do all the other things that um you know you would think that was real popular to do and to get politically politically involved and and have money he didn't come from money um
 	
 	
 		um-hum yeah
 		and and yet even he was a a consummate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX> in the sense that uh not only did he fail uh fail in business twice with bankruptcy and and failure but he lost some eighteen elections before he finally won one
 	
 	
 		and now it it
 		um-hum sure
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> election <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> and only election he won was um the presidency
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		he he had lost every other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> that he had you know he was appointed a couple of times to like uh  uh state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">legislator</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so you really know a lot of his background
 	
 	
 		yeah then when then when he finally did when an election uh it was the presidency yeah
 	
 	
 		it was the big one it's the one that everybody wants yeah whether or not uh you know you look at all these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> that want to become <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> i really have to ask them why you know um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		but
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it's the toughest job in the world to do and not only that you don't have that much freedom to make choices i mean you have to go through so many different you got to go through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> and all of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a</NUMEX> other things to get a bill passed
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and sure you can veto veto it at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the last minute</TIMEX> but then it's not like you have all that power and i think along time ago <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Presidents</ENAMEX> did have a lot of power and i think we're
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	