
 
     		
 	
 		uh i don't know do you want to start
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well i haven't uh i haven't thought a lot about government <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> universal health care i've uh uh
 		worked for a you know private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that that provides uh health insurance although i you know they're they're
 		like many are are increasingly working on uh cost cutting things such that at this point i'm not very satisfied with the kind of things that they're doing they  gone to
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		network <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> which doesn't include our uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> and uh only certain <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> well
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		network <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> where they will
 		uh  same deal as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> that they will pay a higher percentage and pay more of the costs with if you use their particular ones that they've negotiated with but uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh i don't like the uh seems to me that we're getting that that's kind of going towards the the
 		socialized <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX> in terms of of
 		not having a choice in where where or when you want to have have your
 		health care uh without the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> being involved it's just a private form of it but the same kinds of of drawbacks i think uh uh what about you what what's your situation as far as
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		well um i'm a graduate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> and so i get health care through the school um so i'm for health care purposes i'm a a state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX> so we have the state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> union
 	
 	
 		okay
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> and we have our choice of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">like twenty</NUMEX> different plans with you know twenty different <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> that operate in the state um and you know i'm on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blue Cross Blue Shield</ENAMEX> uh i guess it's uh comprehensive
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> and you know i end up i'm paying  like <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five dollars</NUMEX> a month for health care coverage you know um and then i pay <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">another five dollars</NUMEX> for dental um
 	
 	
 		hm um-hum
 	
 	
 		so you know for someone who's in a huge <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX> like uh the you know all state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> it it you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it's kind of the issue is kind of moot but i look at my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s um self employed he's an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> um and right now i mean it's just him and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretaries</ENAMEX> and he pays out uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		what is it <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">forty eight hundred dollars</NUMEX> a month for health care for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and and the two uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretaries</ENAMEX> you know which is yeah it's just  it's extraordinary you know um
 	
 	
 		amazing
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and so you know i look at my end of it and things aren't too bad but you know i look at at my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s side of things and they're horrible you know and i hear a lot of horror stories from other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> too
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um you know that they have to deal with horrible um you know PPOs or HMOs or something like that you know where you can't choose your own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> and and you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		um-hum  and and uh you know it it uh uh
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> i work for is big big enough that they can that they've got clout but i you know feel guilty and resent a little bit the fact that that
 		for instance you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> that just leaves them worse off cause the the health care providers end up making up what what uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employer</ENAMEX> doesn't pay them uh by charging more for uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you know so that that that doesn't seem to me to be a fair thing either and uh from
 	
 	
 		exactly yeah
 		no
 	
 	
 		from what i hear <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX> has a has a really a a pretty good system in terms of of universal government health
 		uh insurance depending on who you listen to why there may or may not be longer waits than here for some elective <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">surgeries</ENAMEX> but but uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		in terms of the per <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> health care that they spend it's it's on the order of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> as much uh
 		as the as the per capita average in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> i think and and very nearly comparable service and i you know  i'm i'm willing to accept some  some limits in terms of
 		i think it's <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oregon</ENAMEX> that just gone through a uh passed a state uh health insurance scheme where they had a commission draw up a very uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know very detailed and stringent priority list of what uh of of the uh different procedures and the and their costs
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and prioritized in terms of the of the cost effectiveness and then just went down the list and said okay here's the cutoff point if it you're below this point then it then the the odds of it doing you
 		any good versus the costs are just not enough to be um effective and we'll uh we won't pay for those things and uh you know i'm i'm not
 	
 	
 		hm interesting
 		
 		
 	