
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		experience with um
 		uh dealings in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> are that i'm one of these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three million</NUMEX> dish <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> in this country
 		and we've been fighting since <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about nineteen eighty six</NUMEX> to try and get some legislation enacted against some of these cable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> and how they've been stumping on their competition and what little there is
 		and it's a very pro consumer type of legislation but we're constantly running into trouble trying to get it passed because we're up against huge pack money donations from the cable TV industry
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and i've come to learn that a lot of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> unless you can mobilize enough consumers
 		or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> to make a stink about an issue if there's a big pack check involved they'll take the check every single time
 	
 	
 		uh i guess it's not totally
 		not understandable  you know i'm i'm sure that if you're looking at whether or not you're going to get elected and have enough money to run that they've got to uh got to take that into consideration
 	
 	
 		oh sure but i think it goes i you know a little of it obviously is they're getting themselves prepared for when they're out of office when they become <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultants</ENAMEX> or high-powered <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyists</ENAMEX> themselves
 		and uh i i think that although some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that we have in elected <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> are upstanding honest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i think that as they're in the system from longer and longer
 		they get corrupted by it basically by losing touch with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that they're supposed to be serving and i think they forget who it is they're supposed to be representing
 	
 	
 		it's uh well it it's it's such a complicated thing let me just relate to you uh
 		an experience that i had with politics at a lower level uh and i think what it boils down to is that if you can't find compromise you're not going to be successful
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um  in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty six</NUMEX> i was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of of an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">association</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DPMA Data Processing Management Association</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh which was actually at the time we were the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> largest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapter</ENAMEX> in the world we had <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five hundred</NUMEX> plus members
 		and it was just i mean an absolute uh unforseen unforseen unforeseen thing that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> should become <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> in this good ole boy city okay
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		don't misunderstand me now but it it all came down to the fact that you had to be able to deal i mean we had uh our board our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> and our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board board</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about twenty</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> now this is a good size group of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to manage
 		and to come to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> voice on on certain things you understand
 		and in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">my year</TIMEX> we did perfectly fine and the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gentlemen</ENAMEX> that came behind me was a uh wonderful intelligent smooth really good looking successful young black man
 		but he had his own agenda and wouldn't compromise with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> he thought that because he was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> he could drive through whatever he chose
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it was a terrible a terrible situation
 		i mean the whole thing almost fell apart
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and i think what you have to do i mean you i think it's important to have an agenda but you also have to be able to to compromise on it because if the majority are against you
 		and you lose more than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two or three</NUMEX> times you know you lose it it been a terrible situation for you and your reputation
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		and i think what happens is in order to get anything passed in the big political system in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> you have to you know compromise with other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and vote for something you don't really believe in
 		but so that they will vote for something that you're asking for
 	
 	
 		yeah that's that kind of um you know i in a in it's gotten very pervasive
 		when it comes to expectations on the part of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of each of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> that you try not to cross party lines on certain votes especially these days
 		and the problem comes about when you have somebody who wants to vote for something the other party <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> strongly and
 	
 	
 		and they really want to vote for it
 	
 	
 		yeah well in some cases they do they vote their conscience and then of course you know they may be punished for not doing the appropriate thing that that came down with the cable issue
 	
 	
 		yeah uh-huh
 	
 	
 		because we had a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh John Danforth</ENAMEX> who is strongly in support of it but then you had the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> strongly against it because it would reregulate to an extent
 	
 	
 		yes it would
 	
 	
 		and they just wouldn't hear of it at all so we had trouble but he stood his ground
 		and carried with him a lot of influence you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> underneath him who are <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> but at the same point it causes a lot of strife and then <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> dig their heels in and
 	
 	
 		and you know there's probably <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about ten</NUMEX> percent or maybe less than that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">five percent</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who can vote their own conscience and still be successful but all the rest fall by the wayside
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah you have to be a real old timer and powerful to be able to do that especially when it's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> assignment handout time and
 	
 	
 		right right i am
 	
 	
 		things like that
 		
 		
 	