
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well what's your opinion on capital punishment
 	
 	
 		well uh
 		i uh i agree with it as long as uh
 		as long as there's no
 		no shadow of a doubt of guilt
 	
 	
 		right i agree with that too i uh this this is probably going to be not a big debate or anything  uh
 	
 	
 		uh
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i am for capital cu punishment only for murder i mean you know i think they asked in the recording uh what in in what crimes but only
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		if someone has murdered someone you know that's about the only thing but uh how is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgia</ENAMEX> for uh capital punishment are they executing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> or
 	
 	
 		uh yeah yeah um
 		not very often but they they do send some
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every now</TIMEX> and then you know as
 	
 	
 		what
 		well needless to say <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> is uh probably the leader
 		uh i we may have started you know capital punishment back up again and uh i think we've probably executed more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> than any other state
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh
 		a case out in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> what was it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week or so ago</TIMEX> was rather interesting in how that uh they prolonged the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> that was supposed to be executed
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and i just i can't see any real value in just letting these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> live out their sentences
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah it seems a little bit ridiculous because of
 		just the tax dollar it takes to
 		maintain somebody that's hopelessly
 		you know just uh violent
 	
 	
 		um-hum and
 	
 	
 		and uh it's doesn't make much sense
 	
 	
 		how do you feel about <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">insanity</ENAMEX> pleas
 	
 	
 		i uh
 		i i don't think it's much of a
 		a
 		reason for
 		um
 		i i don't think it's much of a
 		reason to get somebody off a off the hook i mean
 		like uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeffrey Dahlmer</ENAMEX> i i don't know i haven't
 		followed that since you know it was on the news but
 		uh you know i've i've heard that there might be some <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">insanity</ENAMEX> there i don't you know i'm i'm not
 		at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all up to date</TIMEX> on that but you know if uh something like that if it if you can
 		get off on <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">sanity insanity</ENAMEX> on something like that which i i believe you know there's a certain degree of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">insanity</ENAMEX> there but that's certainly not
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i don't i don't believe it's uh
 		an excuse by any means you know
 	
 	
 		well i had heard of a case out in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> of someone who had murdered his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> or some sort of thing and they put him away uh
 		in an insane asylum you know because he pleaded <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">insanity</ENAMEX> and after he was in maybe twelve <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> or so they let him out he went out and he killed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> more people
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah i just don't
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		i don't think that's uh
 		an excuse at all
 	
 	
 		well i guess it's sounds rather heartless but i guess if they're that bad if they're that badly off mentally then perhaps it's just as well to to end their life
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		aren't we cruel people
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh i don't i don't think so i mean i just you know
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		if i i think in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> you know when crime gets bad they you know they take a few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> out in the public <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">square</ENAMEX> and they execute them and crime goes down  you you you know
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh so there's i think it i think it works since most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't believe in being forced you know
 	
 	
 		well i say they may say it's not a deterrent and perhaps it isn't but i guess
 		i just feel if nothing else it's justice i know that if someone murdered a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> i'd want justice done and i'd want to see them punished for their crime
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah yeah i i agree
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		i agree
 	
 	
 		uh perhaps the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> have kind of a good idea you know if you steal something they cut off your hand and and the punishment fits the crime
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah i think that's uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		not a bad idea of course there there'd be a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>  that couldn't uh couldn't function for awhile you know until they got it through their heads that you know that was going to be enforced
 	
 	
 		well this is very true
 	
 	
 		
 
 		you'd have to phase that one in slowly or i think or you would have
 	
 	
 		
 
 		use someone as an example and see how it worked
 	
 	
 		a bunch of
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		but then you got to pick who it's going to be
 	
 	
 		well i i was a little concerned i was going to get someone on the phone that was totally against capital punishment and
 		in any conversation that i've had through this <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> thing you know i've never met anybody that i got into a screaming argument with or even really disagreed with heavily but i thought this could be one you know it could be a very
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		
 		
 	