
 
     		
 	
 		um basically what do you do to get your news
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well
 		most of my reading tends to be professional reading so  uh scanning headlines in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> or reading over my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s shoulder tends to be about the only newspaper stuff i do
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> is pretty much for local news anyway uh when it comes to national or statewide things uh i keep uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Public Radio</ENAMEX> station uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's available here uh on all day
 		and uh that's pretty much where i get my uh both uh statewide and and national news coverage together with uh a little bit of TV news in the uh in the evenings
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but primarily from from radio uh which is you know that's a dosage of about uh
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about two</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two and a half hours</TIMEX> of news a day
 	
 	
 		depending on how long it takes you to get to work
 	
 	
 		well well i it's on in my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> and i can i can hear it as i'm working when i'm here  my commute is is <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about fifteen minutes</TIMEX> uh so uh uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh okay
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know that's not an issue but that's primarily you know where i end up getting it from
 		and and that for for me is as much a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a</NUMEX> a choice because i find it to be a good way to do it as it is a response to limited time for doing reading and stuff
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's probably more because i just enjoy the coverage than it is because i don't have time to read the paper you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well do you find that they uh tend to after a certain period of time broadcast the same thing over and over
 	
 	
 		well they do to some extent i i hear some some repeats between uh uh <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Morning Edition and the All Things Considered</ENAMEX> in the afternoon uh
 		i we do also have a repeated an intentionally repeated coverage they start at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five thirty in the morning</TIMEX> and uh uh
 		they play the first you know hour again over at the tail end of the broadcast so that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who weren't up that early still get to hear it so some of it is intentionally repeated and and so once in a while i'll hear the same story twice
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		or in the afternoon i'll hear the same report from the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondent</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX> uh that they played in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX> so there is to some extent some repetition uh like that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh but uh for me it's better than trying to read uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> or or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US News</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each week</TIMEX> i tried that once and
 		uh when if i have something to read i feel obligated to read it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh then i felt guilty because i never had time to read everything that was in them
 	
 	
 		and so you threw the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> away and wasted your money and
 	
 	
 		yeah that was that was about it you know uh so now i'm saving <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> and and uh by by not publishing subscribing to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> anymore but uh uh
 	
 	
 		
  
 		
 
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well how do you do it
 	
 	
 		well basically i get i listen to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX> uh <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">on the the Good Morning America</ENAMEX> and while i'm getting ready for work and other than that occasionally um i'll catch some news when i come home
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s a big news <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> and he'll always have the news on but sometimes i'll get involved doing some other things and um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> maybe on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX> but during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX> i just really don't have the time in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX> to get it uh and i'll listen to  news on the radio but just in the car radio going to and from work in between music
 	
 	
 		uh see  here we're in in mountain standard time and uh well the few times when i've run into shows like <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Good Morning America</ENAMEX> uh
 		they've really been at the wrong time for me they seem to start very late for us and i got to be at work you know i'm leaving the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">like seven</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fifteen</ENAMEX> and so uh uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the some of them  seem to be you know like they don't come on until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven</TIMEX> or something and and so there's not enough time and uh to to watch it but they have so many other things that are thrown in
 		that you know i really don't care about you know how to make baked <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">potatoes</ENAMEX> or or whatever uh or or or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">weather men</ENAMEX> with funny hats uh wigs you know
 	
 	
 		
 
 		that's another channel
 	
 	
 		you well yeah but they they all the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> ones have a tendency to do a little bit of that
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well this is true they wanna put a little humor in there
 	
 	
 		and
 		uh you know it's mostly just the timing they seem to be on so <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">late in the morning</TIMEX> that i i started wondering to myself you know so who is it that watches these things but i think it's because of our particular time zone
 		uh it we don't go on daylight savings time and so everything gets shifted by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an hour</TIMEX> that may have been when i you know i looked in on it uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time  it's just
 		uh you know for me a lot of what i look for in news is as much analysis kinds of things or uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		sometimes human interest kinds of things that are a reflection of the news rather than just here's the events that happened uh i'm a real history nut and so
 		
 		
 	