
 
     		
 	
 		have you any thoughts
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well you called here so
 	
 	
 		okay well um
 		i'll tell you i am uh uh impressed with the uh uh amount of spending that's occurred so far as as far as <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> research and i think that uh proportionately
 		maybe uh so far it's been enough it seems like it seems like uh
 		but there's not  uh been any money taken away from uh other necessary medical research uh
 		uh subjects uh
 		you know and and allocated towards the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> research i think that <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> research has been a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a</NUMEX> a lot of the funding has not been done by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> a lot of it has been done by private endowment
 		uh but i think the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is doing a good job so far
 		of keeping the uh their portion of the funding up
 	
 	
 		well i um i agree to an extent um i think the problem is is that
 		we're spending money and one of the things that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> likes to do when they're under public pressure is to throw money at the problem
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		in an attempt to try and solve it as quickly as possible and they did that with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> in the eighties  and when you have a lot of money in your budget and you don't wanna have it cut back you spend it even if it means throwing it away
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		and i think that while we need to spend more effort and money on things like education and maybe even alternative treatments and alternative experiments things to keep those afflicted alive at this point
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i think that any money that is given must be given carefully just to something that is a proven point not just thrown at it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um i i don't see that the money is being removed from any other causes um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> has been a problem though especially in the eighties
 		when there wasn't a lot of private dollars around because of the stigma of the disease
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> really didn't <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> didn't wanna be associated with it because it was a morals issue
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		i think we're finally getting over that i thought that was ridiculous reading and hearing about that kind of moral dilemma stuff but
 		i think that it we need to spend a lot more on education and try and get over this thing that we have about
 		not confronting this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> on with some factual advertising for items of condoms and things like that that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		will help prevent the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">uh disease</ENAMEX> as well as instilling the notion that the best way not to get it is not to involve yourselves in unsafe practices in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place
 	
 	
 		exactly um it although i was uh i i was shocked at the public um uh outrage uh that occurred after after i uh think it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Quayle</ENAMEX> who said um
 		you know who suggested that maybe maybe we  you know maybe that is a a possible and and uh
 		uh likely most effective solution is you know abstinence and and yet the a large portion of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> said well that's stupid you know that just shows that you have no interest in in in spending any money on the on the problem and i thought
 		that that that that that's not that's not the point at all
 	
 	
 		well the the problem is that with this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> at least when they say abstinence
 		they often couch that in other things that turn into one of these morals issues
 		which uh makes it turn into a political issue now you see the problem is you have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Institutes of Health</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX> and the like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Centers for Disease Control</ENAMEX> which
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fundamentalists</ENAMEX> in charge of the thing who won't even let you say condom in a meeting
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and these things have been spread around and immediately immediately <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> think well abstinence okay here we have these religious zealots telling us
 		where they're trying to ignore the problem blah blah blah and of course they overreact when you say that the fact that it's just good medical safe practice you know don't expose yourself in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but the it's because the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the the</TIMEX> you know this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> was around when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> when the disease <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> was discovered here and all the social you know implications of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> ignoring it when it first became an issue and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		see that's all carrying over now
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and that's why you're seeing that
 	
 	
 		okay that that makes a little bit of sense uh i i hadn't i was not aware that that was uh such a a within the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NIH</ENAMEX> that uh that was that much uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah there is because what happened is a lot of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and staff <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> are political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">appointees</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		from the south especially who come along with a variety of different religious beliefs
 		some of which held very fervent beliefs
 		and will take their beliefs into the workplace in and in this case a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> consider that to be standing in the way of science and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX> to try and solve this thing
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i i don't like throwing money at the problem uh because
 		
 		
 	