
 
     		
 	
 		okay um  let me see unfortunately we are not much recycling  we don't we don't do enough i know we don't so
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh although uh lately i've been uh a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of mine that i spend a lot of time with
 		does recycle quite a bit and it's it it's uh interesting to watch some of the things that she does and then she's almost had an impact on me um
 		where  she doesn't say anything to me when she comes to my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> but i i can kind of tell it bothers her so uh just unconsciously i've i've stopped buying a lot of um
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		um paper plates and paper cups and i don't do that anymore i don't know why i just don't i just from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">just</NUMEX> from socializing with her so
 	
 	
 		how do you uh how uh is recycling done in your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> is
 	
 	
 		it really it there's not a whole lot there really isn't uh i know in my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s neighborhood in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Antonio</ENAMEX> each
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		each <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> has they're they're given <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> baskets and they put them out on a certain day of the week
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		and each uh home does participate but we really don't have anything uh close in this area that that do anything and and some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> that do
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> are having to pay to participate in it which really doesn't make sense
 	
 	
 		oh
 		right over here they um have several private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> that you can take uh recycled materials to
 		but um if you want to take them all to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> place they have uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first Saturday</TIMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every month</TIMEX> they have certain <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">places</ENAMEX> that you can drop them off that's what i do um
 		and i i recycle aluminum glass
 		um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">newspapers</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah that's good
 	
 	
 		so it's nice to have you know one place that you can take them all to instead of driving the glass to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> place and
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah that's another thing you have to go to different places to do that
 	
 	
 		right
 		right so it's so that's nice it would be it would be really nice if they uh came to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> to pick it up and they just were talking about a bill in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tucson</ENAMEX> about that but uh
 		uh it didn't go through
 	
 	
 		uh-huh but i heard that most <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> that do participate in that are having to pay a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">monthly</TIMEX> fee to do that which uh i don't know it just doesn't make sense to me
 	
 	
 		so
 		right i guess what they what they were talking about here was um
 		was reducing the garbage collection in order to make that up or something you know um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so i guess that's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> option
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		that's good that's good
 	
 	
 		i guess one thing they're working on now is recycling <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">plastics</ENAMEX> too like um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		have you noticed that on the bottom of plastic goods they have this little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">number</ENAMEX> now that tells what kind of plastic it is
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		no
 	
 	
 		yeah i guess the problem with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">plastic</ENAMEX> is there's so many different kinds that you can't recycle you can't just throw all plastic into one recycler
 	
 	
 		oh i didn't know that
 	
 	
 		yeah so now they're like marking um they're i don't know there's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six seven eight</NUMEX> different kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">plastics</ENAMEX> and they they mark on the bottom what kind it is
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so i guess that makes it easy to recycle and then they're
 		they're um trying to make <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">plastic goods</ENAMEX> that don't have a bunch of different <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">plastics</ENAMEX> in them you know that are that are only made out of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> kind of plastic so that that makes it easier i guess
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well that's good i i you know unfortunately <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garland</ENAMEX> doesn't have doesn't they don't i don't know they don't do anything like that or i i you know i read those little slips that come in with your utility bills
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		or your uh garbage collection and they haven't you know talked about doing something like that
 	
 	
 		where does your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> go to recycle
 	
 	
 		she lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Garland</ENAMEX> and i'm not sure where what she does but she's uh oh she's very very heavy in that and she takes her own bags to the grocery store
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um she has no i really i really don't think she has any paper products in her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and just a lot of things i've learned off of her that to start doing and she does make a lot of sense just her whole <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> is like wow
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i guess that's how it gets passed on you know when <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> you hear it from another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> and then uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and then you and then you pass it on so it seems to be catching on uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		slowly but surely i guess
 	
 	
 		yeah and uh my little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> has watches a program that was really neat i sat and watched him you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Barney</ENAMEX>
 		you know the little um i don't know if you know the little character <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Barney</ENAMEX> they had one uh on that kind of type of thing and how <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> can
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		can do that and how to save water brush you know when you brush your teeth turn the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> off and it's really caught on and he's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only four</NUMEX> and he's really caught on
 	
 	
 		wow that's neat that's neat yeah when you
 	
 	
 		and keep the refrigerator door closed and that kind of thing he has really caught on so that's really neat
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well when you start early i guess
 		
 		
 	