
 
     		
 	
 		i guess i guess by what you said you're you you don't feel you're uh privacy has been invaded invaded anytime recently
 	
 	
 		
 
 		no not really um
 		uh the um
 		the the only thing that annoys me is when uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> call and they uh you have solicitation calls
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		probably thing that bothers me that's not really invading my privacy um
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		do you feel that yours is invaded
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> nah i wouldn't call it invading my privacy by any means uh you know i would there there's a lot of times though uh you get those calls and you know
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		when you're sitting at home wanting to relax or or whatnot and you know next thing you know
 		uh someone calls and wants to sell you this or that and it's real hard to you to tell them you know that you're not interested or you do tell them you're not interested and they still keep asking you you know and and
 		keep badgering you about it and that aggravates me but i don't know that you could call that invading of my invading my privacy because
 		you know if we don't want that to happen all we have to do is just call the phone <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> and say look you know i want my name unlisted or i want my you know
 	
 	
 		but but that doesn't work
 	
 	
 		it doesn't
 	
 	
 		uh no because they a lot of times they dial sequentially they get your name from uh if you enter any type of contest or anything
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um you know you enter a sweepstake in the local department store for a shopping spree or something you put your phone number on there they pass your phone number on to another company
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		um or you um
 		or or like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> they just dial randomly or select and stuff they even call the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> here even call <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who already subscribe
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and uh while i was subscribing to the paper i got so upset at them that they you call me <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> more time i'm going to stop subscribing
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and the local the local local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> will nice just you ask them to remove your uh number from their list and um
 		yeah you call up their regular during during <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">regular hours</TIMEX> their um they have a special <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> they'll take your numbers out of their list
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh but the uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Orlando</ENAMEX> paper um yeah they they they refused to take you off of the list and they call <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every month</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		and when you have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than one</NUMEX> phone number you get a call on each number you have
 	
 	
 		good grief
 		well let me ask you about this here's something that uh has been kind of concerning me lately my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fiance</ENAMEX> received a bill from a a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lord</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Taylor</ENAMEX> company uh you you know they're a they're a department store
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		she received a bill from them uh that she had visited some some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> and and i think it was there in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> maybe it was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miami</ENAMEX>
 		uh that she had visited a store there and uh they had this bill uh that she had bought such and such amount of merchandise uh over <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">two hundred dollars</NUMEX> worth of merchandise
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and the date that that she supposedly made this purchase she was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Denver</ENAMEX> with me for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thanksgiving</TIMEX> um and apparently what had happened is someone used her social security number um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and and i've i've heard recently that uh
 		uh that this is a common occurrence where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are using someone's you know they they use <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Blow</ENAMEX>'s social uh social security number uh and can uh potentially ruin someone's credit
 	
 	
 		uh-huh if you know a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s social security <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">number</ENAMEX> and their mailing address in and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s maiden name  uh you can basically become that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> uh person
 	
 	
 		
 
 		huh
 	
 	
 		um if the purchase was made made mail order they should have a record of where it was shipped to and since it wasn't shipped to her address she could prove you know that it wasn't her um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		if it was some you know coming into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> and stuff then she would of had whoever made the purchase would have had sign some kind of um you know document and uh who
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		the signature um they should be able to provide you a copy with that signature and if they can't provide a signature uh you know they'll they have to eat the charge
 	
 	
 		yeah well you
 	
 	
 		but if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> has had their social security her social security number i'd be real concerned that they uh
 		that she's not uh blacklist on uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Telecredit</ENAMEX> what is it it's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telecreder</ENAMEX> something um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		because she won't be able to cash checks because most places verify through there she probably won't be able able to open a checking account or anything without a lot of hassle
 	
 	
 		yeah well we got it cleared up eventually what happened uh
 		
 		
 	