
 
     		
 	
 		you wanna go first
 	
 	
 		
 
 		no you can start
 	
 	
 		okay um one of the things they talked about was uh
 		did we did what do what do we think about a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> making the decision and i really don't agree with that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i think that the trial by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> is better
 		uh you know than even having a unanimous decision rather than to have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> be responsible
 		i don't think that they could be objective in every case every time
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		you you know what i mean
 	
 	
 		right there's there this this this topic is kind of moot um there there's no way we we couldn't survive in a system in a in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">juror</ENAMEX> system in a trial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">system</ENAMEX> without a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> can never be one man <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> can never be objectionable in every case
 	
 	
 		that's it
 	
 	
 		um every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> has their opinions and that's why <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> selection is often very difficult
 		um
 	
 	
 		well i i feel the other thing too uh they were saying uh you know what new ways could you could it you you know change the system
 		i i really think that um we spend a lot of time uh going through appeal after appeal after appeal after appeal i mean if if you go to a trial by jury
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and especially if a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> has confessed if they have been caught you know point blank in the crime there's uh no question it's beyond a reasonable doubt
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		you all these things i mean you know we've gone through this uh over and over again
 	
 	
 		right they shouldn't allow an appeal
 	
 	
 		and it can go on for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten twenty years</TIMEX> i i think this is a little ridiculous
 	
 	
 		yep
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i think the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who benefit from that are the lawyers
 	
 	
 		no that's right i work for a law firm i ought i
 	
 	
 		i i'm serious and i think that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> have caused a lot of the problems that happen that exist in the in the criminal system <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> with plea bargaining
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know if someone is
 	
 	
 		well plea bargaining plea bargaining is a different story
 	
 	
 		well
 	
 	
 		plea bargaining is something completely different that that actually prevents trials or or at least speeds them up
 	
 	
 		well i know that's that's what i'm saying but i think a lot of all of the whole criminal system is messed up
 		in in that regard i mean you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who commit uh crimes that they i don't know how it works exactly but you know they get lesser sentences and i understand that the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">jails</ENAMEX> are full of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you know uh
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 	
 	
 		and that they have to do something but i think that the reason they are full is because they know that they can get away with it
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		you you know what i'm saying that we we don't have um well a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> don't have capital punishment
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and um
 	
 	
 		we do
 	
 	
 		i i think they should i and i think if a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> is guilty of taking someone's life and like you say it's it's there's no doubt whatsoever like drunk <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX> that kill <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and um
 		you know all they they're caught dead to rights i i just think that that's they've they've taken a life and if they should pay for it with their life
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 		when you're saying as as far as the appeal um procedure is concerned we just have the case i'm i'm sure you've probably heard of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marion Berry</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um his final his last appeal was was denied <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two days</TIMEX> before his sentence was up
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		so i mean his appeal was denied and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two days later</TIMEX> he got out of jail
 	
 	
 		it uh
 	
 	
 		for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX> possession but um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		that was absurd  there was no there was no reason the appeal process should have dragged on that long for a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six month</TIMEX> sentence
 	
 	
 		i know that the
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		and i don't know uh what what would you do to change it to make it better
 	
 	
 		well
 		uh
 		the the only thing i can i was you know the the appeal procedure is the only thing i can possibly think of um i like i said as far as removing of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> and having the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> sentence that's absurd there's no way that could work
 	
 	
 		oh yeah i i i don't agree with that at all
 	
 	
 		um
 		but
 	
 	
 		imagine the guilt that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> would have i mean it burned out is there's no possible way that you could um you know feel good about yourself if you had to do something like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that day</TIMEX> after day
 	
 	
 		oh exactly exactly
 		right
 		no one would want the job
 	
 	
 		no really not really
 	
 	
 		um
 		
 
 		and
 		you know like i said the you know everyone has their opinions about every case
 	
 	
 		well would do you think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> should have a trial if they're caught dead to rights like
 	
 	
 		oh yeah i i feel that everyone is everyone is um entitled to a trial by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> that that that right should
 	
 	
 		i mean supposing i come up to you and i just point blank kill you
 	
 	
 		well i mean were there witnesses
 	
 	
 		in other words you're saying that we you have to find out whether it's premeditated or what the circumstances were
 	
 	
 		right
 		right that you can't you can't remove the jury regardless of the case i mean you could have fifty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> watching  a murder take place and you you'd still there's still mitigating circumstances
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		well it's i i feel
 		
 		
 	