
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		um well i'm just really excited about it because i'm graduating from college <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next month</TIMEX> and i hope to be buying a car sometime  in the future
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so so hopefully uh maybe do you have any good advice do you have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> or
 	
 	
 		
 
 		uh yeah i do have a car
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh right now i have sort of a sporty <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> it's a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Subaru</ENAMEX> that is it's called an XT6 i don't think they make them anymore i think i have the last year
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it's one of these <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> that run without needing many repairs um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		my advice about <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> is uh get a good engine get something that goes not because i'm a speed freak uh something because if you want to get on a highway you don't want to step on the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas</ENAMEX> and and say come on come on
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		that's true that's true
 	
 	
 		i do you know  they make jokes about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> picking out the color but i really do like to have a decent sized engine in my car
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and i have a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> cylinder and it does go when i tell it to and and i just like the looks of a kind of sporty <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh i think my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> needs are going to change i had very small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and i was saddled with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">station wagon</ENAMEX> that i never wanted
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		um i was told that you know it'll hold <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">groceries</ENAMEX> and all this stuff well the grocery bags fell over in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">station wagon</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's true they do my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> has one
 	
 	
 		you know and and you know and i wasn't that thrilled to put a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bike</ENAMEX> in it or a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> in it and i didn't so when i got a new car i got a sporty little car and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> were still small enough but they weren't in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> seats anymore and they sat in the back
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and now my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fourteen and a half</NUMEX> and he's taller than i am and every time i go over a bump he crashes his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> because
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh no
 	
 	
 		you know these <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> have they're backseats but they're kind of toy backseats
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		so i think should i get another car uh much to my chagrin it'll have to be something more boxy
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and you know practical again so this i guess i guess this is my reprieve and i guess my suggestion to you is to get something you really enjoy because at some later date you'll have to get something more practical
 	
 	
 		
 
 		that's great advice i'm so glad i got to talk to you that's good that's what i needed to hear  yeah i guess
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i'm looking for uh something kind of small because it's only me and i'm a small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> i'm <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only about five one</NUMEX>  so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> and i'd like to get something made in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> so i would look for that first but
 		if it turns out that a better price is from say <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Subarus</ENAMEX> then i i would go for that because the most important thing is price i mean because
 	
 	
 		well you know the more i think of it  you know with what's going on in the world nowadays i think the next <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> i would try to buy an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> one
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		would you really
 	
 	
 		yeah i think so it's you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Toyotas</ENAMEX> and all those they're they're nice <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> but you know surely there's an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> car i i'd love to check out the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Saturn</ENAMEX> which is supposed to be a new newly made <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> car
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		you would think so
 		um-hum actually i heard really good things about them and uh it's funny because i just spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last weekend</TIMEX> i was down in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX> visiting my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> and they are everywhere down there it's amazing because you hardly see any of them on the road here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX> but i saw <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about ten</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one</TIMEX> weekend
 		and uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> had gone to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dealership</ENAMEX> and she was really impressed she uh the one thing that really impressed her which sounds kind of weird but they actually have women <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">salesmen</ENAMEX>
 		it's weird because i mean have you ever seen a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> car <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">salesman</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah i have
 	
 	
 		really because i was surprised but and she said they were really nice and
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> good thing about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> is it's really hard to dent you know when you're driving a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and you you go in a parking yeah you know most <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> in a parking lot like a cart shopping cart hits it or a car door hits it and you have like these dents well the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> took a hammer to this <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and it didn't dent
 	
 	
 		is it really
 		huh
 	
 	
 		she was like smashing it and it didn't  it's it's made of something i don't what it is but
 	
 	
 		really how was the pricing
 	
 	
 		it's actually supposed to be really good the smaller ones i think around are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight thousand</NUMEX> and then it gets up to maybe twelve thousand
 	
 	
 		oh that's that's not horrible at all that's quite good nowadays
 	
 	
 		so they they look really nice
 		yeah yeah so i don't know maybe that's something to think about because they're supposed to be completely made in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> not one of these deals where
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it says it's made in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> but the engine is really made in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> and all the parts are made in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> right
 	
 	
 		parts are made in different places right i wonder who makes the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">the Geos</ENAMEX> because
 	
 	
 		i think that's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chevrolet</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		is it because they're so cute The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Geo Storm</ENAMEX> is adorable
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		that is really nice that's true i don't know anything about them at all do you know anyone who has one
 	
 	
 		no no i don't in fact i i sat in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one a long time ago</TIMEX> and slammed the car door and it felt a little tinny you know it was it's a smaller lighter car
 	
 	
 		i know
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but you know that was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> that was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about four years ago</TIMEX> when i bought <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX> so it may have changed i know on looks i think the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Storm</ENAMEX> is just adorable little <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> for a single person
 	
 	
 		hm
 		yeah that is really cute that's true
 	
 	
 		hm are are you working yet
 	
 	
 		so
 		um well i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ROTC</ENAMEX> so i'll be in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> so on active duty so yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah because i was wondering if you're are you going to finance it
 	
 	
 		probably yeah is that a good way to go i guess i don't know which one
 	
 	
 		right
 		uh well i have been fortunate enough to be able to just pay for it and i i like to do that but there are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who can pay for it who prefer to finance it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		really
 	
 	
 		yeah it it seems to me as you're paying interest you're bound to be end up paying more i guess now you have to think about uh if the money in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> will get more interest
 	
 	
 		right right
 	
 	
 		uh then then you'll want to finance it but if now the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> are giving so little interest i imagine you might as well just pay for it if you could
 	
 	
 		oh i see
 		
 		
 	