
 
     		
 	
 		what do you think about capital punishment
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well i'm kind of in favor of it for certain crimes
 	
 	
 		yeah which crimes do you feel that
 	
 	
 		well
 		i think first degree murder um
 		probably warrants it
 	
 	
 		yeah because most so many times that's so brutal and just recurrent
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		felons i think should also
 	
 	
 		exactly recurrent crimes like serial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rapists</ENAMEX> or serial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">murderers</ENAMEX> or whatever
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i come from a state that has well i originally come from a state that has uh
 		the death penalty i come from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> and uh they're pretty liberal on it they tend to like fry <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> left and right which go ahead
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah that's a
 		go ahead <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> is too Texas i saw on TV <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the other night</TIMEX> is the has had <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">forty six</NUMEX> in like the past several years
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so they're pretty
 		hip on it too i guess they do it by lethal injection at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Huntsville</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah okay i think <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> still uses electric chair
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um i don't i don't know in some ways i don't like it because it's like you're playing God
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and that's not you know i don't think that's right but on the other hand there's a lot of advantages to it i think crime rates deterred a little bit by using it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and of course you have some savings in terms of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayer</ENAMEX> money keeping <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in jail or not
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> that's a big problem because there's so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">jail</ENAMEX> that they have to let them out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> they
 	
 	
 		yeah that's what's happening here there is like um that's in fact a big gubernatorial issue is the the turn over rates of
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um repeat uh repeat <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offenders</ENAMEX> being let out and doing it again
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">sure</ENAMEX> and it's like you know that's a big problem but there's not a whole lot you can do about it because there's only so many <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">jails</ENAMEX> you can build
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it's really you know it's it gets to be a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a really</TIMEX> a big problem
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um go ahead
 	
 	
 		i wish if they if they were gonna do it they would be a little more consistent in dealing with who gets lethal injection and who doesn't be a little more you know not being able to put it off for fifteen years
 	
 	
 		right
 		um-hum yeah because a lot of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> you know they get in and they they get off for good behavior
 		and i don't know i mean up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota</ENAMEX> where i am now they don't have the death penalty and you can almost sense that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are just laughing at the system
 		you know because they figure well you know sure i i get <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">forty</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> for maybe rape or something um
 		but then for if i if i elicit good behavior i'm out in maybe <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five or ten</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		oh sure you know i mean just because like we said before they don't have enough <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">jails</ENAMEX> um you know there's a lot of incentive for them to be let out early
 	
 	
 		goodness
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but if you've got the death penalty hanging over your head um
 		i don't know i think that may solve a lot of that maybe not solve it but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i don't know maybe even help a little bit
 	
 	
 		i yeah i tend to think the repeal system for the death penalty is a little little too lenient um kind of takes away
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		from the significance of the death penalty
 	
 	
 		um-hum what do you do Georgeanne
 	
 	
 		i'm a graduate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Texas</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh okay great what program you in
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um Audiology</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay fantastic uh i'm a doctoral <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Central Florida</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah what do you do
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		yeah i'm doing an internship up at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Honeywell</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh really neat
 	
 	
 		uh yeah
 		but um
 		i don't know it's it's an interesting issue there's like you say in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> there's been quite a few and and in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last few years</TIMEX>
 		i think there's been a lot i can't i  i mean i can't give you figures but um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i just and this was in conjunction with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> that was put in the gas chamber
 		in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> so i i think it the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">forty sixth</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last twenty five years</TIMEX> i think it's what they gave a run down that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh is that right
 		okay
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> tends to be a little more robust and disciplined area then
 	
 	
 		yeah i i kind of yeah i've heard things about that i've heard that they don't mess around very much yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah um they they don't get repealed as easily as they do
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		like in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> got third you know twice before he went to the gas <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">chamber</ENAMEX> and then they said okay no you don't have to go and then they took him back i mean it just seems
 	
 	
 		jeez that's a lot of repeals
 	
 	
 		yeah it just seemed a little inconsistent and then you had like who you have
 		these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are serial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">killers</ENAMEX> that didn't even get the death sentence back whenever you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah i don't know i i'm trying to think about other crimes that would warrant it uh i guess what is it what's the policy now with treason do they uh do they axe you for treason or is it a life sentence i
 	
 	
 		no i don't i don't think um the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX> doesn't execute anymore so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		or death before the firing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">squad</ENAMEX> or whatever
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so i think about the only one is um
 		rape
 		
 		
 	