
 
     		
 	
 		okay uh okay so our subject is nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> um do you have any experience or any uh opinions on what to do i do
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i do have actually as a matter of fact uh and i'm i'm not sure how it would relate to the big <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> but there are certainly ways and humane and and nice ways of handling care for our elderly
 		i come from a very small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> in northern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX> have banded together and built and staffed a retirement home
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		that's wonderful
 	
 	
 		and the care of course is is wonderful because these are all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who care
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every week</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX> a different uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX> volunteer and come in and maybe have bingo day or special celebration day or help someone with their birthday or whatever
 		and it makes the care very personalized of course but since it is a small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> everybody knows everybody and so there there would be no absolutely <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX> chance of any abuse
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		that's great because uh
 		you know i think that is probably a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> greatest fear and i'm not faced with this yet but my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> is seventy <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> she's in good health and living by herself but um
 		i'll probably be faced with this you know sometime in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next few years</TIMEX> as to what to do when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> gets to the point that she can't take care of herself
 		um
 		unfortunately having her come live with us you know if she needs constant care is not going to be an option and what do you do you know
 	
 	
 		yeah it's it's a real problem um it is a real problem and i know that everybody hates the idea of going to one of these but i also think that
 		it is a choice that we have all made in our lives as we have drawn back and internalized ourselves as opposed to being a part of the community
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh it used to be that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> looked out for you the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX> looked out for you but many of us don't belong to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX> any more
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so therefore we don't have this broadened <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> of caring people
 	
 	
 		and we don't have the nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> that we used to have many <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many years ago</TIMEX> either
 	
 	
 		no
 		no absolutely not you know i presume when when the time comes for something to happen to me that i will probably go back to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> to be in that community
 		but uh
 	
 	
 		well it's good that you know that you have that option available um that because i don't think that too many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> have something like that set up
 	
 	
 		but it's the type of thing where i think we should look at some things that are working and try to use them in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> also
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i mean is there some reason why some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX> here could not band together and do a similar situation
 	
 	
 		probably not
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> and it might even be easier here in that there are so many more <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX> available more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to draw from
 	
 	
 		yes
 		and actually a great deal more money
 	
 	
 		well yes that's for certain my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> lives in a small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> also and i know you know the funds just aren't available uh to do something in a small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> that you have that you can do in a larger town
 		but um uh you know other than care conditions you know i don't know really what else a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> looks for uh convenience for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> would be a a wonderful thing
 		uh but that's
 		that's you know that's not always an option either
 	
 	
 		right but you know if my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> if all of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> still live here and i go back to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> course there is no convenience so probably it would behoove me  to try to start something of this sort here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh
 		that's a big job you know uh
 		so many needs are crying the homeless the abused <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> the the beaten <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wives</ENAMEX> you know there's so many things going on that that how do we all of this
 		and maybe that's a part of it maybe maybe what we can do is uh
 		of course this is kind of a far flung situation but uh you know they're talking about work fare now in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wisconsin</ENAMEX> i believe it is
 		but is there some reason i wonder why we couldn't have some of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> involved in nursing homes
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		is that
 	
 	
 		so that they didn't have to be so expensive you know if you if you've got somebody who is drawing welfare then perhaps that can be quote part of their their payment for their welfare payments
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well and i think that would be a good idea too i don't know if these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> need it for self-esteem it would seem to me that they would but if nothing else yes let them earn some of their money
 	
 	
 		yeah because part of the problem now is that  it costs so much money to get into a convalescent home
 		or or an aged home
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know it's almost prohibited for many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> and uh you know so what do you do does someone go on welfare in order to get in one of those homes
 		or does somebody in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> quit their job so that they can be at home and and but of course that's not always wonderful either because somebody with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alzheimers</ENAMEX> needs <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty four hour</TIMEX> watching and nobody can do that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		that's right that's right i well i guess that's probably as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> get older for
 	
 	
 		nobody can do that
 		
 		
 	