
 
     		
 	
 		i think that the middle east is of all the uh regions of the world the most volatile that we seem to be getting ourselves involved in
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		i'm not sure we're doing so with
 		sufficient knowledge about the history of the area and um with what uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> there expect i think we're just getting ourselves into a barrel of trouble
 	
 	
 		yeah well i think we may have the knowledge knowledge of the history but certainly not any understanding of the history
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		we seem to be you know doing the same we've done in many other cases which is sticking our noses in where it doesn't belong
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and i think it's you know motivated
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		you know clearly by the fact of the resources that are controlled by the region which is
 	
 	
 		oh clearly yes and um
 	
 	
 		of the you know used up in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next twenty to fifty years</TIMEX> there won't any oil any <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX> left i'm sure
 	
 	
 		hum
 		
 
 		well i feel that as far as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> policy's been concerned while i understand um a position in allied um friendship with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Israel</ENAMEX>
 		i think that we've applied a lot of double standards in the legion uh in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past</TIMEX> as far as dealing with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arabs</ENAMEX> versus dealing with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israelis</ENAMEX> and the expectations that we put on the
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		uh <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> uh while basically succumbing to a very powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lobby</ENAMEX> in this country
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and i i think that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> question is a key to a lot of problems in the region
 		and i don't think that this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s handled that well at all
 	
 	
 		yeah well  probably from there is that the
 		same problem as anywhere else anytime you take something away from somebody and give it to somebody else
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that you  didn't own in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place there's you know going to be problems i mean that's basically what's happened i mean
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		basically a handful of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> took away from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX> what was their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">homeland</ENAMEX> and gave it to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israelis</ENAMEX> you know to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israelis</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and you know it's not the way to go about any kind of uh
 		solution that's ever going to be workable you know i mean you neither <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> was consulted up front
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 		yeah i kind of anticipate that because you know we set the stage and how we've dealt with that issue in such a poor manner by basically you know
 		paying lip service to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX> in the past
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		uh i think that's up the stage for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX> effect to for this uh uh revolution of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> fundamentalism what seems to be sweeping
 		definitely through <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North Africa</ENAMEX> and uh within parts of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> as well something which terrifies the moderate <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		well it's pretty scary anybody if you think about i mean any any time you get <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fundamentalists</ENAMEX> you know whatever nature
 	
 	
 		yep
 	
 	
 		and in power anywhere i mean they're they're pure <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fanatics</ENAMEX> and there's that you know fundamentally no way to deal with a fanatic
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and you can't argue with them on any sort of logical or emotional basis
 		a fanatic will believe in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">X Y Z</ENAMEX> and you're never going to change that
 	
 	
 		yeah i i suspect
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know so you might as well not even try
 	
 	
 		i suspect that we'll probably in uh with the demise of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> formation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russia</ENAMEX> whatever ends up coming out of that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that probably the biggest problems we're going to have in foreign policy are going to have <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> in the future
 		i think that we're going to continue to see a lot more fundamentalist influence in the area it's been spawning for a long time
 		the more moderate states uh even including <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi Arabia</ENAMEX> which is a very religious country <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> wise it's not allowed the fundamentalist to gain control
 		but uh i you know <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tunisia</ENAMEX> and uh now we have problems with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sudan</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh these places i think that you know we're just in the beginning here of uh what will probably sweep through i mean <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX>'s suffering the same kinds of problems with fundamentalism right now
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		the more <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> that join with this kind of uh thinking in government the more stronger uh difficulty we're going to have
 		as a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> in dealing with the region because of our past experiences with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah i think a lot of it is is just rejection of the current
 		you know power structure and that power structure happens to be religiously aligned and aligned with uh you know a religious based monarchy in a lot of those countries
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and that they're basically rejecting that power structure in favor of another which is you know return to a fundamentalist thing i mean it's not to unlike what happened in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last ten years</TIMEX> i mean basically <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> rejected you know there's  fundamentalist you know movement
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		wasn't quite as severe or as you know fanatically radical i mean because the
 		uh
 		the class structure is is you know less
 		prolific here or less you know regionally defined here and uh
 		the uh the differences aren't so so strong as in say talking about like <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Saudi</ENAMEX> we're you've got you know uh basically a ruling
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	