
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		we're supposed to talk about if we agree on if we're paying too many taxes or if we're getting our monies worth out of the taxes we pay
 	
 	
 		right i think it's kind of a loaded question i don't think anybody would say we should pay more i think i think most of us feel that we do pay enough
 	
 	
 		no
 		yeah i think here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> they're even running an ah a series right now on the news one of the news <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> about they were like secretly um supervising <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that were supposed to be working for a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">county</ENAMEX> here
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they were hired by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state state</ENAMEX> so they were being paid with our tax money
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and they weren't even doing the job they were out working on other sites not doing a thing on what they were supposed to do
 	
 	
 		well i i think what's happened is a lot of these <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> and city jobs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> feel that once they get them they're entitled to them for life and they can kind of take it easy because they're protected by their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX> etcetera
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh during my college years my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> worked for the state and she got me a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> job and when i came in i'm i was just a little eager beaver and i went through whatever work they gave me
 		and i found <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> sitting around me polishing their nails and
 		they were downright disgusted with me because i was going to come and go but they were going to live there and they didn't like me you know showing them up and finishing stuff so what they did was give me worse and worse and ugly and uglier things to do
 		so i would just back off but and you know that's what it seemed like from the inside um it's not that no one works i think what happens is it's a personality thing and those who just like to do a job well done get to do the work for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three or four</NUMEX> freeloaders
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		who don't do it i think i i you know i think it's a cross section of humanity it's not so much all state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> i mean it's hard to generalize like that
 	
 	
 		yeah i think that we pay enough taxes and i think that if if everybody would be honest with how they dealt with the tax money if we could somehow get the same um ability to
 		get work done and and be honest about it with our tax dollars i don't think they need to raise it and i think they'd be able to
 		handle with what we've got i feel like here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> we pretty much get our monies back out of what we pay i feel very pleased with what they do they've put in
 		you know as far as the state taxes go i don't know about our federal money i think that's all pretty
 		i hope that they're doing better with not spending so much more than what they've got but you know you just never you can't control that but in the state here
 		they've put in bike trails they've got really nice <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX> here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> they keep their their their lots that they own that are green and stuff they keep them really nice
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um their schools</ENAMEX> here are really good and updated they've got computers in the schools
 		i'm very pleased at least with the area that we're in with how they spend their money their their they don't tax us outrageously and they seem to really give us a lot for our tax dollars
 		they offer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> classes for our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> to go to that are just very minimal minimal costs you know just cover the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">instructor</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and um there lots of opportunities that you can take advantage of there are community <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX> here you can take for just practically nothing um they just offer so much for i feel like what we pay in our taxes that i don't mind paying them at all
 	
 	
 		apparently there's been a uh movement where i am i'm on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Long Island</ENAMEX> which is a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">suburb</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New New York City</ENAMEX>
 		and um there's been a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">movement</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> to try get their their home taxes reduced they feel their too high and there's all kind of review <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX> that if you feel strongly about it you can challenge your tax
 		uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> now running an article on state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX> which you know everyone kind of assume at least i did assume that you can get a good education and pay so much less than a private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it seems to be more of an expose than anything i mean you hearing ghastly stories about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> who are taking <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four and five</NUMEX> like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduate</ENAMEX> because when they try to sign up for a class they're so over crowded they can't get in the class
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so in order to finish all the uh requisites they have to just stay longer until they can finally get a hold of the class
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		that this this i thought was totally outrageous that they have teaching assistants well that's that's an old thing you know having graduate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> teach undergrads
 		but some of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are you know from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX> and they don't speak <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> well enough for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> to understand now how could they possibly have someone teaching a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> who is not fluent
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and and i heard that that's true i mean that's i find that incredible that's a
 	
 	
 		so you're not as pleased with your tax dollars and what they're doing in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh yeah well i guess i have a a private um
 		argument argument with them i'm a substitute <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> who you know have have has raised a family my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are older <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> and i'd like to work full-time and they're firing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> left and right and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classes</ENAMEX> are getting bigger <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">our school</TIMEX> budgets are really down
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		maybe it's not handled real efficiently you know that's that's very likely
 	
 	
 		that could be i don't know um
 	
 	
 		my you know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s in the computer business and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> just you know they're updating computers are the hot new thing and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> was
 		
 		
 	