
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		are they doing a lot of recycling out in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgia</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well um at my uh workplace they are we have uh places for aluminum cans and we have uh everybody's been issued a separate trash can for uh
 		recyclable recyclable paper let's let's see them get that word straight uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		as far as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> goes uh it's pretty much voluntary nothing's been done um i don't where i live i live in an unincorporated area
 		and we don't have any uh we have just private uh garbage services and uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> as far as i'm concerned i i guess i should do it but being lazy i don't if if somebody made it easy for me to separate my trash and pick it up i would more than gladly participate  uh
 	
 	
 		yeah i it it is it is to some degree inconvenient i'd have to say that
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		uh around here they've given us mine already got run over um it it  looks sort of like a milk crate a little blue <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk milk crate</ENAMEX> and i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 		and it's not big enough it's it's kind of it's kind of silly and what you do is you put out paper like paper bags and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> and cardboard
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and that you put separately and you also put out in this little ridiculous container any cans or bottles you have you know like your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Campbell</ENAMEX> soup cans and your milk <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cartons</ENAMEX> and that kind of stuff
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		and then the rest you can just you throw out and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> picks it up
 		i've heard of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> where you have to separate your garbage and then put what's left in a clear plastic ga bag so they can kind of look and see if you're throwing out what you shouldn't i thought that was pretty amusing
 	
 	
 		have the garbage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> looking after you i guess
 	
 	
 		i imagine i don't know
 	
 	
 		uh well i used to live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> and um just before i left they were um some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> were making that uh mandatory and uh um
 		fortunately i was in a i was in an apartment <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> and for some reason we just threw everything in the dumpster that was all right
 	
 	
 		well you know it's funny we just got back from a trip to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> visiting some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> uh near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Jose</ENAMEX> and we'd see these signs on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> that said garbage pickup <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> exits down or something
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> for the apartment <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dwellers</ENAMEX> they didn't make it easy to recycle at all what they did was um you would bring it to this garbage place that they designated
 		and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lions Club</ENAMEX> or you know some community <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> would do you the favor of picking it up from there you really had to go out of your way to recycle
 	
 	
 		yeah you know and most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> probably don't wanna carry a couple of bags worth of garbage in their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a few miles</NUMEX> uh i mean it's all it's a good idea we should all do it uh but
 		um if it were from a practical viewpoint from a selfish viewpoint if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> made it easy and convenient for you to do it they would have a lot more participation in my opinion
 	
 	
 		well around here i it's not too bad because on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesdays</TIMEX> you put out your paper and your cans and and plastic things and they go away so that i mean that's not too tough to put that at the end of your driveway
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> have this special garbage fill where they collect all their <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">soda</ENAMEX> cans and they kind of leave it near the dumpster knowing that the neighborhood <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> will grab them because they can sell them or something for recycling
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh
 		gee you haven't
 	
 	
 		so they just leave it out for the vultures to take
 	
 	
 		gee <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> around here i don't think would pay well wouldn't pay any attention to it they'd the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> would get to it before they would i would imagine
 	
 	
 		oh well the soda cans where i live are good for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a nickel</NUMEX> a piece
 	
 	
 		wow
 	
 	
 		so if you bring them to the local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">supermarket</ENAMEX> they have these can crushers and you know you throw all the cans in one at a time it takes time a lot of time and uh you push a button and you get <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a nickel</NUMEX> for every can because someone you had to pay a deposit on it when you bought it
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and you find these old old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and these bag <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> collecting all these things and hauling them in in big garbage bags and they just like take up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of these machines to to get you know couple of money uh bucks for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX> or something
 	
 	
 		is that a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> or state law that uh requires it to be recycled or
 	
 	
 		yeah it's a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> well <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> does it and i know <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vermont</ENAMEX> a lot of the eastern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> do it
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		so you get a lot of old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> one old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fellow</ENAMEX> had crates of beer he made <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> with a bartender a bartender at some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX> and he gets all the beer bottles because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> can't be bothered with it
 		and he said he bought himself i said that's pretty heavy for you isn't it and he says well i just bought myself an old <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">station wagon</ENAMEX> to cart you know this is a real business for him he's making big bucks
 	
 	
 		gee well i i guess if you can buy in bulk it  so to speak
 	
 	
 		well i guess at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a nickel</NUMEX> a shot if these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are retired and they've got nothing better to do i mean they can come away with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten fifteen</NUMEX> dollars at a haul i guess
 	
 	
 		well i bet that's resulted in uh it it would seem to me that's resulted in some cleaner <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">highways</ENAMEX> i would imagine
 	
 	
 		well you you do find <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> picking through the garbage pails at the beach you know my own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> have been guilty of that till they found that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bees</ENAMEX> were attracted to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coke</ENAMEX> cans and that was the end of that
 	
 	
 		surprise surprise
 	
 	
 		i think it's a fair you know for an <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight year old</TIMEX> to get <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> dollars it's like wow
 	
 	
 		gee well that's uh well that you know a state law like that would probably encourage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> down here uh to do it uh i mean i i don't know
 		
 		
 	