
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		um
 		in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> they do have the um capital punishment and um
 		i i just i i'm probably one that has to agree with it too um
 		there're
 		are some things that go on that i just feel that
 		i i just feel that that that that is a need i don't i don't know a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't feel that way either but i just feel that that
 	
 	
 		well i don't know how much publicity it's gotten outside of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> but <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> we just put somebody to death
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um for i think it was a double murder uh to be honest i didn't pay that much attention uh to the details of it um
 		
 
 		but it had a lot of controversy out here uh basically because in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like to protest about everything um
 		but i agree i believe that that there are a number of crimes that capital punishment is the best way to go um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the big disagreement i have is that
 		in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> the appeals process uh is so extensive and takes so long
 		that you end up spending a huge amount of money in like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> to fifteen <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> before you can actually you know put somebody to death for for a crime
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah that is a consequence yeah
 	
 	
 		and i mean that's that's ridiculous i mean if you can you know you you the trial is supposed to prove you know within a reasonable doubt that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> is guilty
 		and then they have appeals well that's fine but it shouldn't take <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than a few years</TIMEX> i mean i should think <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two or three years</TIMEX> maximum you should be able to know and you should be able to either put the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> to death
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		or he's innocent i mean it's if he's guilty for for you know multiple murders or whatever the case may be you know
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well maybe that's something that needs to be worked on but i i just feel that that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		capital punishment needs to stay within the system not all <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> have them but i
 		you know was that was that the i'm not sure if that was in was that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> that that claimed he was abused or
 	
 	
 		yeah he was like um the the the defense the defense they're were giving given was that uh like his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> had had been an alcoholic when when she was pregnant with him and so he he wasn't you know mentally competent or anything else
 	
 	
 		and that he had some he
 		oh yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		which is ridiculous and and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> found him competent um and he knew what he was doing and everything else i mean you know it was it was the best defense they could come up with
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		and how long had he been appealing appealing how long was that
 	
 	
 		i forget i think it was something like twelve <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> or something
 	
 	
 		gosh boy
 	
 	
 		it was it was something really outrageous
 	
 	
 		yeah boy
 		well i mean and it seems like it it rarely does happen you know it's not it's not used that often you know at least here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> but i think it's something that needs to stay i really do
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i think in general uh
 		punishment in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> is a lot weaker than it should be i mean it needs to be you know it's kind of like
 		the the the justice system in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> is kind of like the dog <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">poops</ENAMEX> on the carpet and you wait <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three months</TIMEX> and then you put his nose in it and spank him for it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know i mean there's there's no connection between the two
 	
 	
 		right right
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i mean you take these you know most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are committing violent crimes most of them not all by any means but you know a large percentage are the kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are living very much day to day in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um they don't really see past <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX> much less <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX> and to say you know well if i kill somebody then <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a decade</TIMEX> from now i might face the punishment
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		that's not real it doesn't have any real impact on them
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> and i were wondering about this recently because a an old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of ours in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> this just happened <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a week ago</TIMEX> um her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> just killed her and we're wondering if that has an effect
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		if that if something does capital punishment
 		you know does it happen with that within that uh
 		i don't know
 	
 	
 		um you you mean would he be put to death for that
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		um largely depends on the circumstances and generally
 		you know from what i understand it's it's only the most brutal types of things usually where it's multiple you know
 	
 	
 		i think you're right
 	
 	
 		if if they can say things like you know well he was just you know temporarily insane because of some domestic squabble then
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know they'll they'll give him you know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years</TIMEX> with with parole in in twelve or something like that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah and uh i have an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncle</ENAMEX> that is an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> that defends uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on
 		
 		
 	