
 
     		
 	
 		
   
 	
 	
 		okay well what's happening in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>  <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">well</ENAMEX> that's what we're doing too on our our current events and it's all over the
 	
 	
 		oh what's happening in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> we're all reading about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> i think
 	
 	
 		of course the TV and we're having a little bit of uh uh you know demonstrations here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> but not anything like they're having in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LA</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i should hope not
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		i i i was just reading this morning in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> that it's also spreading to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX> as well
 	
 	
 		oh is that right well it
 	
 	
 		the rioting and all that kind of thing
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> and last night it was going into some of the nicer areas too you know uh rather than just staying in the
 		in the uh in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sections</ENAMEX> that it started in
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		
 
 		but uh i get my current events um <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all three</NUMEX> ways you know talking to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> uh some TV although not much TV and uh reading the paper
 	
 	
 		do you get
 	
 	
 		and
 	
 	
 		uh i'm big on <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX> radio i guess i woken get woken up by the alarm and catch <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>'s news real quickly
 	
 	
 		well that's something i used to do when i had a long drive to work or a or a maybe a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">forty</NUMEX> minute drive to work i would turn the the news on and listen to that all the way
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i don't do that anymore it's just that i guess a habit i've gotten out out of and that's uh that's a real good way to get everything recapped
 	
 	
 		you know i was just doing some thinking recently on we only hear
 		we hear the news in a slanted fashion by how it's reported to us
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i was looking at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX>'s paper and you see uh you know the cover photo is
 		a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> and and in the background everything's in flames
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i think they kind of uh set you up in a way
 	
 	
 		well i know they do
 		i was uh i worked in public relations for um a a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Safeway Stores</ENAMEX> which was a is a big grocery <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX> in used to be in this area it's not here any longer and it used to be in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> i don't know there
 	
 	
 		yeah i've heard of it
 	
 	
 		and uh i was their uh press <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> uh public relations <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about five years</TIMEX> and handled all of the press
 		and i would tell them one thing on the phone very carefully
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and they would report it
 		not so carefully and in different context you had to be so careful uh whenever there was an interview on television uh they would tape a interview ask you lots of questions and then they would just take excerpts out that
 		uh you know  standing alone would didn't mean the same thing
 		and so but we just really you really had a we had a tough time uh
 		relating to what you actually what was actually going on as to what was being reported
 	
 	
 		um i i think uh the news is starting to think of itself as theater
 	
 	
 		well i think you're you may be right there too uh and i can see where
 		did you happen to hear the uh interview of the uh juror
 	
 	
 		no no no
 	
 	
 		uh <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX> on TV
 		she said that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> saw only a small portion of that tape
 		now i you know on this <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodney King</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		now i can't side with her
 		you know
 		because they they you know you can see see what was happening and that's totally wrong
 		but you know we were shown just a portion of something we weren't shown a whole picture
 	
 	
 		well well something i read in the paper was you know if you just hear the headlines you don't know that there were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> that was stopped who got out put their hands up and said okay we give up
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		that's exactly right
 	
 	
 		you know and they don't tell you that that makes you so angry to think that oh they beat on this poor man
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		this one person
 	
 	
 		but he he had a choice to you know this all could have been you know avoided if he had behaved himself i i i believe they overreacted horribly
 	
 	
 		exactly
 		right
 	
 	
 		but you know if you think of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cop</ENAMEX>'s point of view he has a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and he wants to get <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX> and he doesn't know how crazy this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> is
 	
 	
 		exactly and he's resisting
 	
 	
 		so everybody's fighting for their life and you can see how this can get out of hand
 	
 	
 		um-hum exactly
 	
 	
 		but
 	
 	
 		but like you said we were not shown that we were not uh unless we you know read in-depth you you get that you don't get that impression and so that makes everybody up in arms
 	
 	
 		i've been very annoyed lately by the sensationalism that's going on
 		i was uh visiting some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> over the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Easter</ENAMEX> vacation in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX>
 		and the big thing out there was they were finally after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty five years</TIMEX> going to execute someone
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh whereas they've always had a death pentalty penalty they always put it off
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and she had the TV on and they go to say they go on to say well the cyanide came into the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> and after about a minute his head slumped and they went into gross gross detail
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i mean why is this on TV is this news do we want to know it
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		it was disgusting and this whole thing with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willie Kennedy Smith</ENAMEX> you know did he rape this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> did he not why is that headline news
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well it wouldn't be if it was anyone else
 	
 	
 		yeah but i mean i think the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> are irresponsible
 	
 	
 		it wouldn't have been if it
 		
 		
 	