
 
     		
 	
 		see when when when you're with a big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> or a big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> a lot of times uh you know the benefits are good and and you know the pay's regular
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but uh well you know sometimes you don't get tuned in to what's going on and i i i think the biggest benefit or the biggest benefit other than wages that that uh that uh anybody could get in uh in dealing in a with a large company
 		is to be in a situation where you you get to know what's going on and maybe that's that's probably the toughest thing in the whole world to to do
 		what's what's your feeling about benefits what sort of benefits would you like to get from a big company
 	
 	
 		well since i'm kind of on the the older side you know i i i just feel like uh when i start talking about benefits i talk about i'm concerned about medical benefits
 		um
 		my um my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> works for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald Douglas</ENAMEX> and so my his benefits his medical benefits are so excellent you know that's really great
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know i work for um Western a bank <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Western Financial</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh they don't let me know really about anything that's going on
 		even some of the immediate things that i need to know i don't know it until <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the next hour</TIMEX> and then all of a sudden we know we've gotten changes made we're changing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">departments</ENAMEX> we're changing policies we're changing doing other kinds of things which to me is is disturbing
 		i mean i feel like if i i don't necessarily need to uh be involved since i'm pretty much on a low level you are you are right there you know i'm pretty much on a low level as far as uh
 		uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> is concerned but i i do kind of like to know what's going on and what's happening and i think i can be a better and more effective employee if if i had a little bit more information along that line
 	
 	
 		well that i
 		i well i i work for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and uh actually i work for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh my gosh
 	
 	
 		and uh and so well you know we we don't there's lots of things that we don't get told for good reason
 		but uh but basically uh there's lots of things that that we should know about projects i'm an engineer
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know i'm i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">COTR</ENAMEX> and sometimes and i worked in the same <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lab</ENAMEX> with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> and we didn't really know that much about each other's projects for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> and we should've you know we're we're now collaborating
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and it didn't for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> we didn't and which which was uh kind of stupid
 	
 	
 		and it it
 	
 	
 		but uh but uh our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> is doing something else <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> uh we're having a for all unclassified programs we're we're having little tables put out in front of you know <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lab</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hallways</ENAMEX>
 		and everybody all the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> are going to come around and see what sort of things we do
 		which i thought was kind of interesting
 		and but
 	
 	
 		yeah that is interesting
 	
 	
 		but uh but that sort sort of thing but but if but just i think you can tolerate a lot of problems if you understand what's going on
 	
 	
 		exactly
 	
 	
 		and and but of course most time most the time management has a hard time distributing or getting the word out to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who must know
 		and you know if you don't really count if you're not part of the program you might not get told for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> or you might you know if it doesn't impact you directly or if your management doesn't think that
 		but but regard to benefits you know most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> have most big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> have decent you know benefits like retirement and that sort of thing
 		in the private sector i would think that one of the major uh situations especially when you reach you know the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid fifties</TIMEX> was is
 		keeping a job until you retire
 	
 	
 		hm ah right
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineers</ENAMEX> are uh  are baggage to most uh uh as they get older to to most companies
 		and uh it's very much like the military it windows out you know you you think well boy i'm getting more money and i'm getting more responsibility i'm doing this but as you climb up that tree pretty soon you're the the the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">branches</ENAMEX> get smaller on the top of the tree
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and pretty soon somebody falls off i've i've fallen off twice in my private sector
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and uh  and and you know i can get up
 	
 	
 		i know it it seem to be kind of kind of scary you know because you think of um
 		see my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eighteen right now</TIMEX> and he he's uh he wants to go into engineering
 		and the the the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">branches</ENAMEX> of engineering that he wants to go into is now is kind of open and he's interested in basically <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> different <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">areas</ENAMEX> but
 		uh it's difficult for me to  to try to give him any kind of advice or to advise him or anything like that he needs to do his own course investigation and and see what he can do because who knows what's going to happen in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">another thirty years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		um-hum yeah
 	
 	
 		and in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty years</TIMEX> it becomes pretty critical i mean my um brother-in-law is like um i mean he's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixty</TIMEX> he's not ready to retire but his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> is is closing is um is uh closing up
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and because of the defense cutbacks and all that kind of stuff and all the nuclear and stuff which is what he what he was working on he's getting cut back and he's not ready to retire
 	
 	
 		yeah he may be retired
 		
 		
 	