
 
     		
 	
 		well my basic idea on dealing with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US</ENAMEX> budget as unrealistic and  as it may be
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		is to <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of all put an end to these kinds of uh hidden <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user</ENAMEX> fees and uh
 		um other types of uh tricks that have been used
 		to help mask the size of this thing let's get a hold of what the real true sized of it is and then let's deal with it immediately and as quickly as possible even if it means some short term higher taxes
 		to get it down and uh then let's try to make some reforms with the the congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">ha ha</NUMEX>
 		try and make it so that we don't have this problem in the future
 	
 	
 		well i have to i have to say that i would be very in favor
 		of
 		a situation where the revenue generation activities of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> such as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX>
 		are monitored and
 		spending for year
 		X plus <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one</TIMEX>
 		can go no higher than the revenues brought in during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> X
 	
 	
 		you know
 	
 	
 		so that uh forget about this balanced budget this would immediately force them
 		to say well geez um you know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a bad year</TIMEX> and we've only got you know we only took in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two hundred million</NUMEX> dollars uh
 		i realize that i'm off by a factor of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about five</NUMEX> but  we only took in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two hundred million</NUMEX> even though <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> is going better we can still only spend <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two hundred million</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i i just keep seeing unfortunately the problem a lot of the problem why we have this deficits balloon especially during the eighties is just because the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> people
 		bought into this notion that well we can just uh we don't need a higher taxes certainly not they get enough of our money already and
 		the deficit doesn't seem to affect me in my <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> life and routine so so what
 	
 	
 		it's going to affect your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah i know but you notice these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are only now starting to think ahead
 	
 	
 		
  
 		well i i think this has always been the case with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> in that
 		it's made up of a bunch of special interest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> it's only recently that special interest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> have started to exert more power
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh for instance <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">retirees</ENAMEX> they've started to up social security benefits it used to be so social security was just the final safety net
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but it's not that way anymore uh now you've got <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who have
 		uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixty thousand</TIMEX> in tax free income because they invested wisely during their working <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and they're still collecting social security and all of that money is tax free
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i'm sorry i think that um all of the investment income regardless of how you invested should be taxable
 		and the thing is that you should loose social security benefits based on how much income you have
 	
 	
 		yeah the only the only problem comes down as that a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> will scream and yell especially the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AARP</ENAMEX> because they were yelled that well we paid for this all along was this a hidden secret tax the whole time that's our money that they don't want to give back to us now
 	
 	
 		uh yeah i i i i agree i think that social <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">security</ENAMEX> ought to be done away with and put into the uh  tax
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and that's what it is so go ahead and put it in there and uh
 		uh you know i mean they're treating it as a tax they're treating the money as tax revenue it's not something that they're putting aside for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">later</TIMEX> use it goes into the general fund whether or not
 		it wants to to go there that's that's were it goes and it's being used so i mean um
 		uh my personal opinion out here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> we just instituted term limits on the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> for the state legislature
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i don't know whether it's going to have
 		uh the affect that of course all the the career politicos here say oh my God you know you're going to have a bunch of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">amateurs</ENAMEX> running the state legislature
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well well so what  they can't do any worse than the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> that are in there now and
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well yeah we have that out here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> too you know with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mario King Mario</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">legislatures</ENAMEX> are opposing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> are controlled by opposing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> which means basically <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> we have a scream and terrified over the budget
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> which is delayed eternally and then they want to kill each other you know
 	
 	
 		well i think that what we may end up with with the term limits is you get more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> involved in government
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you get more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> seeing how it should work and i think what that will do is that will allow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to say well wait a minute
 		we've got to compromise we've got to work on something we need more of a vision and less of uh God i'll grab my money and do everything i can
 		
 		
 	