
 
     		
 	
 		you wanna start or you want me to start
 	
 	
 		well go ahead if you're
 	
 	
 		okay  personal interests in computers basically nowadays it seems like you can't get by without one everywhere i go it's got some kind of computer interface like pressing on keyboards
 		uh pressing in personal identification numbers all the ATM machines things like that i personally don't own one because i can't afford one
 		uh every time you look in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> and they show you their computers and all the knickknacks they have it seems like they go from their basic computer to all these peripheral devices like uh modems and
 		fancy printers or lazy printers and fax machines and games that they like to play course i i was impressed by some of the games they have like flight simular game <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">simulator</ENAMEX> for the different aircraft
 	
 	
 		yeah well that's uh  actually you might guess you could say even more than just a game it's uh
 		similar to the one they use at uh for training
 	
 	
 		very close to it i understand
 		except for the bouncing around it
 	
 	
 		well i have a i just got a i used to use a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> PC at work now i just got a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">386</NUMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> computer PC
 	
 	
 		you using it mostly for spreadsheets or do you use it for like word processing
 	
 	
 		uh  well i use it uh
 		in my business i have to uh tie into the mainframe and also into a uh minicomputer a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">990</NUMEX>
 		so i use a terminal emulation in uh talking to other computers plus word processing i do quite a bit of that
 		and it's uh that's supposed one of the features of the
 		the new one the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">386</NUMEX> it's got Windows on it and so you can toggle back and forth between uh applications and you know get a
 		get a lot quicker in and out
 		used to be you had to log off  then log back on the other application
 	
 	
 		yeah i use a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Z248 286</ENAMEX> at work but it's basically to tie into the communications network
 		then through our communications network we go to our mainframe on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">base</ENAMEX> there
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and use the Unix operating systems
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		use their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> and we use um read on line news through it
 		and we also have terminal emulations through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty two seventy eight</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and  i don't know i just don't i don't even use the hard disk drive to to copy any floppy disks or anything like that i just basically use it for a
 		a window into there to the Unix world
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah uh
 		we're supposed to be getting a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fifteen hundred</NUMEX> minicomputer pretty soon
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX> or is that an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX> type
 	
 	
 		replace our <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">990</NUMEX> huh
 		uh no it's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> made <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1500</TIMEX> it's a a minicomputer
 		uh it's a newer version of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine ninety</NUMEX> which is one they had
 		it uses uh Unix as one of the operating systems
 		but uh
 	
 	
 		i'm familiar with Unix commands like um copying files and compressing them things like that i just have a fun time using their mainframe at the base but
 	
 	
 		well Unix to me i mean uh that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">System</ENAMEX> Five i mean that's pretty  looks pretty uh user unfriendly
 	
 	
 		it's like a different language all right
 	
 	
 		uh
 		it seems like they sure uh
 		i got a lot of stuff to learn i haven't used it that much so
 	
 	
 		yeah we can use System <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Five</TIMEX> or we can use um C shell
 		you know i like um i favor C shell over the other
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i think i think most of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Bourne</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">shell</ENAMEX> because they were trained in it and they just don't wanna learn something different
 	
 	
 		
 
 		that uh that's a powerful force  once you that's a powerful force once you learn something you you tend to wanna stick with it
 	
 	
 		pardon
 		oh yeah plus everybody in your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> knows it and as the new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> come in they kind of help each other out
 		but you have different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with different backgrounds and they have a hard time sharing information
 	
 	
 		that's like i learned uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DFM</ENAMEX> and PFM you know Professional File <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Manager</ENAMEX> which is can be used as a word processor it doesn't
 		it does everything i need moves splits you know all that but uh
 		doesn't have some of the little fancy stuff like underline caps bold i mean bold and all that so
 		uh that's other than that it's you know perfectly suitable for most things i do
 	
 	
 		yeah the disadvantage disadvantage of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> you can't see all those fancy things  i have another thing called Q-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quadratron</ENAMEX> back in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like to use but it's a very slow system
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i understand it's only on like we use a Gold <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9050</TIMEX>
 		and that's basically their format they use for word processing and they're trying to push <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> into using either WordPerfect
 		
 		
 	