
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> uh now really called the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commonwealth of Independent States</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> is a mess  um uh i think one of the biggest things we have to worry about is the uh control of nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX> especially <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ukraine</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russia</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah i my main <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> right now is <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of all at this point with the current government and situation i don't see them as any threat
 		to us at the moment however with the current state of the central <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> being as um tenuous as it is it wouldn't take much to uh cause a kind of fascist revival
 		within uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> or any of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">republics</ENAMEX> and then we do have a real clear foreign policy and a a problem and a threat
 		because of the number of nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> that are there we seem to have lost the ability to control what's going on in the country
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and any <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> which has as many nuclear weapons as they do is certainly is a threat but perhaps not at this second
 	
 	
 		yeah you know i suppose you you say to yourself what will no rational uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> would would would launch uh nuclear weapons
 		um but i guess that that's wouldn't necessarily hold uh for some radical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> or temporary take over even
 	
 	
 		well i work in international radio um and uh one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> that we're working with has been <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Radio Eurovan</ENAMEX> which is in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Armenia</ENAMEX>
 		and i you know in a sense you'd think being a you know an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> or a westerner it would make sense that we there is no real great threat that these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> aren't nuts
 		but you listen to the what the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Armenians</ENAMEX> have to say about their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Azerbaijanis</ENAMEX> and they launch in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a second</TIMEX> if they had an access to those weapons
 	
 	
 		right
 		
 
 	
 	
 		there is a great deal of religious hatred in that part of the world and this is stuff that goes back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">days of Christ</ENAMEX> i mean
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		this is not a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two hundred year</TIMEX> or or a fifty year uh problem this goes back <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">centuries</TIMEX> and the amount of hatred
 		i mean there's accusations of using chemical <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> now both on both sides and
 	
 	
 		yes yeah
 	
 	
 		it into a republican strife amongst these various um former parts of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX>
 		i think you could have a regional use of nuclear weapons but i don't think that they see us as a threat anymore
 	
 	
 		right i guess i agree with that um
 	
 	
 		
 
 		um the other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> is as time goes on they could become an economic threat um but i think what will happen is they will go through an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		right
 	
 	
 		type of uh introduction into the business world where beginning there'll be cheap labor and uh you you know then we will have an i'd say <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty years</TIMEX> if things stay the way things are now
 		they could become another <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Korea</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malaysia</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Thailand</ENAMEX> type of  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX> for cheap labor where <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> products could be built
 		and uh i think that's where they are headed
 	
 	
 		right well i think that that there's a uh qualitative difference that uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> and and much of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> still has a lot of natural resources that some of these other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> you mentioned just never had
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so that uh  you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">commonwealth states</ENAMEX> could could easily you know leapfrog the uh
 		the you know stepping stone path uh laid out by the by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southeast Asian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well they do have a huge oil reserve the problem is that they don't have the ability to exploit it at this point
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		they could become a major source for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX> for us as well as timber
 		and um other products agriculture could become very important for them using modern farming techniques in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ukraine</ENAMEX>
 		and i suspect they will form some sort of economic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX> when all is said and done  i don't think i don't think
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah yeah we're we're still going through a a uh you know a settling period
 		you know they're not sure who they want their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> to be they're not sure how they want the you know uh relationships between the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> to to shape so i agree with you know they're they need <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">another couple years</TIMEX> to to let them uh settle down
 		and uh start cooperating
 	
 	
 		well i certainly hope that we will i i wish we would incorporate some sort of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">marshall</ENAMEX> plan over there because i think one of the problems that this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> has in dealing with them is we aren't doing enough right now
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and the chances for things getting out of control and another fascist type of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX> rising are quite good
 		um anyone at this point who can give them food security and make them you know feel some pride again could become a major threat especially some of these <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">republics</ENAMEX>
 		which are striving to become independent from central <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX> and that kind of administration
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> and if we don't get our tushes in there and spend more effort and money and funds trying to get things back on the ground there i think we're in
 		
 		
 	