
 
     		
 	
 		so what do you think
 	
 	
 		um well i think uh there's been significant change over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last couple of decades</TIMEX> uh
 		i guess i would say that one of the most um important changes seems to be
 		um
 		that the family the definition of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> is changing a lot
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh yeah no doubt about it the nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and just the whole downsizing approach
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are are are not having kids
 		are not having <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">as early</TIMEX> or as many
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know and that's yeah that goes hand in hand with some of the stuff that i had you know like maybe the whole emphasis on the environment and on social kind of a social awareness approach
 		to where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are starting to think about <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pollution</ENAMEX> and trash a little more and uh and the ozone layer and things like that
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah exactly
 	
 	
 		it's really putting some constraints on your whole uh the whole lifestyle which is
 	
 	
 		it seems to me it seems to me like um like everyone is lamenting you know the loss of the nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and saying that it's going to be the downfall of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> but to me um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i don't know i guess that that's that's probably a pretty liberal view but i mean to me the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the old</TIMEX> um traditional nuclear family um
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		seems to only work seems to work real well uh you know when uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> is in charge of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> when he's working when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX>'s home taking care of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and you know as soon as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> gets equal rights and she can work too
 		then all of the sudden you know there's all these constraints on the family i mean face it it's basically
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		an old um you know religious construction so um it's it's
 	
 	
 		sure
 		yeah
 		see to me it
 	
 	
 		no i i actually i actually think um it's it's better the way it's working out i i think
 	
 	
 		yeah i'm
 	
 	
 		i think that when each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> is is working that uh it makes for more it makes for like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> dependent people
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are sharing their lives rather than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> dependent on another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> seems to me uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		it could be i'm i'm kind of a conservative uh myself although
 		i don't know i've got mixed views i come from a very very conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> where there are you know it's like you mentioned you mentioned it's like you described the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um where the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s in control the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> stays home raises the family things like that however
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i don't think that's a realistic approach anymore especially with the the rising cost of living and things like that there's there's almost no way you can make it with a one income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> anymore
 	
 	
 		yeah it just seems that way
 	
 	
 		um
 		you know regardless of the of the social impact or the the familial impact you got to think about
 		just the pragmatic side of it in terms of how can you afford to raise however many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> one or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		exactly
 	
 	
 		um with one income and it's never going to work i don't think um
 	
 	
 		see i came from um a pretty conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> too
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but the uh thing is that it didn't work out and my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX>'s split up so maybe that's what  yeah maybe that's what um influenced my view
 	
 	
 		oh really
 		yeah my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> yeah my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> fought like <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> um they they did stay together finally and they've been married like forty <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> now but
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 	
 	
 		i know i know what you mean because there's there's a lot of stress in that kind of an environment where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s gone all day
 		and comes home at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> and like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> is like the first thing she hits him with is all these problems
 		you know so both sides are are under a lot of stress that way
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 	
 	
 		i don't know i was
 	
 	
 		of course of course when both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">um parents</ENAMEX> are working the big question is you know who how how do the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> get raised
 	
 	
 		exactly you know that's something my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>'s having to face right now they've both got they've got working <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> both of them and it's like they're always shuffling them off to day care
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and you've got to ask yourself whose morals and whose values are being you know enforced on my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		exactly exactly um-hum
 	
 	
 		you know they come home and start swearing like a blue streak wait a minute i didn't teach them that stuff you know
 	
 	
 		one system that um is interesting that that we we may take in
 		that we might be good might be good for us to take into consideration is um in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> they have this  you heard of that
 	
 	
 		no i haven't
 	
 	
 		where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are
 		it's kind of like of like uh a community <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> i guess where you know all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> um
 		it's kind of like a boarding school i guess and they're but they're raised by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> who sort of act as
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> you know because i guess in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>
 		um you know that happens a lot too that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> are working and or in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> or something like that well um
 	
 	
 		right
 		
 
 	
 	
 		um i don't know it seems
 	
 	
 		that's kind of interesting
 	
 	
 		seems to work really well and they somehow they um do it in such a way you know that they they pass on morals pretty well
 		
 		
 	