
 
     		
 	
 		okay um
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		read any good books lately
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh yes i i've read uh several good books lately uh
 		lot of them uh related to um
 		business and financial matters since that's what i do for a living
 	
 	
 		oh okay um-hum
 	
 	
 		how about yourself
 	
 	
 		uh well i'm in graduate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and so i read a lot of books but i don't know if i consider very many of them good
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		um
 		i haven't read a book for enjoyment since i guess around <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> um  i received received uh
 		uh several books for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> and at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> break i read uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sarum</ENAMEX> by uh uh a fellow named <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rutherford</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		uh it's the history of um well it's sort sort of the historical the historical fiction about uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Salisbury</ENAMEX> area in in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and so uh i i really enjoyed that book a lot uh he's not quite as good as you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michener</ENAMEX> or some of uh some of the other historical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> but he he did his job well so
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		well that sounds good
 	
 	
 		uh
 		do you find it uh do do you find you have much chance to read for for just pleasure or mostly for business
 	
 	
 		no i read for pleasure some also i read a book recently called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Iron John</ENAMEX> have you seen that by Bly
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		i don't think i have seen it
 	
 	
 		okay well it's a book about uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh Greek gods and</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> um mythology
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		as well as uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and interacting with other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and a book about uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and how they mature through life
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and how they deal with life itself
 	
 	
 		oh
 		okay i think i have heard about that
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but it's uh it's all revolved around uh mythology
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> as far as uh traditions from uh other cultures and our culture
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and how we uh interact with one another
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah that sounds great did did it have something to mention about um sort of uh cultural rituals of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">of</ENAMEX> manhood
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		okay yeah i have heard of that i have uh
 		someone suggested that i read it is it <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iron John</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		okay good
 	
 	
 		by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bly B L Y</ENAMEX> i believe it is
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B L Y</ENAMEX> okay
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">great</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh it's a very interesting book
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		uh what are your favorite
 		uh
 		do you have a favorite subject to read whether it be science fiction or or history or
 	
 	
 		well it depends again if we're talking about uh
 		um i read a lot of religious books
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh just because i have an interest in that area
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i read a lot of books in the area of uh um psychology and self help type uh materials
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		okay
 	
 	
 		uh always trying to understand <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> better and understand myself in a relation to other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and try to understand where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are coming from because i'm in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> business
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		okay
 	
 	
 		and uh so that's that's that that's my work is my hobby
 	
 	
 		um-hum that's
 	
 	
 		so i i enjoy it
 	
 	
 		sounds great
 		um uh who is your uh  who is your favorite religious author
 	
 	
 		well i don't know if i have a favorite
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh religious author
 		i would have to say that uh
 		some of the ones that consistently put out good materials
 		uh
 		you know that that's difficult because
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> might write one book real extremely well and some other ones might not write as well
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh i have to stop here and think a second
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the ones that i've read recently that i've read several of his books and i thought that each <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of his books were good
 		he's the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Antonio</ENAMEX>
 		and uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Max Lucado</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Max Lucado</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Max</ENAMEX> consistently consistently writes good books
 	
 	
 		yeah uh he's a great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> i've met him several times uh
 	
 	
 		yes i i know him yeah
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		but uh there's other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> also that have uh
 		uh that write good books from time to time but not consistently put out the materials all the time
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um i'd say another which is a local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> here in Plano
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> is
 		i'm trying to think of his name he's with the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX> church
 		and that is uh
 		i see his name but i can't i mean i see him but i can't see his name
 		
 
 		but he uh he talks about uh he talks about a lot of different topics and dimensions of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	