
 
     		
 	
 		well i haven't had an awful lot of uh incidents in regarding child care when my <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two year old</TIMEX> was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Orleans</ENAMEX> she got bit on the cheek and uh but uh that's about the the uh the extent of it
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but but but the when i really am uh am concerned about is that uh so many of these child care <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">places</ENAMEX> are are coming under uh uh you know investigation for for uh you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> molestation
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i and i and i'm saying to myself well you know you you dump your your your little turnip off to uh you know this child care place and they don't pay very much
 		and why why why would they be interested in your in your little turnip unless you know one of the motivations in the hidden agenda is well that's somebody to molest you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh that's a terrible kind of thing and i i don't think my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> have ever been subject to that but my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> didn't work and so we didn't really didn't have that much exposure to it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well i am a working <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>  i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> since i um since they were very young i've had various various um different alternatives child care arrangements and
 		like most working <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> i i'm really not defensive about it i personally feel um in our particular situation i'm a much better <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> when i work out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> and
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> i think are very very secure well raised <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> my comment on this is that we paid an absolute fortune  over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> for a variety of opportunities
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		so i i i uh you know it is a problem and but as you pointed out i think i think the real problem is the low pay child care <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> and that is sometimes what some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who have to work that is all they can afford
 		when our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> were very young we had a pay a live in paid babysitter that was wonderful and then as they got older they went to uh i preferred to call them <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and they really were <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all day</TIMEX> preschools and they were wonderful
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		and i think they got exposed to a lot of neat things
 	
 	
 		oh well that's interesting
 	
 	
 		but we did we really truly did pay a fortune i mean we were paying
 		at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point
 		well about about close uh close to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about five hundred dollars</NUMEX> a week for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh my God well you must have a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">just one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> ace professional job to support something like that
 	
 	
 		so
 		well i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physician</ENAMEX> i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physician</ENAMEX> uh and as is my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and i and i felt very uh very good about working i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pediatrician</ENAMEX> actually
 	
 	
 		oh well yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so uh but i think there are some wonderful child care opportunities out there for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> but and we all know the kind of things that you're supposed to look for i think
 	
 	
 		well not not all of us you know what the kind of things you're supposed to look for i'm an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineer</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh
 		well i think it's real important that you have a place that <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> have a lot of input into and that they're always welcome and that they have a lot of activities where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> come in during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> and that at any time you can drop in
 		and we had a really wonderful arrangement um i'm with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX> actually and they had a wonderful uh program that started at age three
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it was about a block away from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> where i work and so many times at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">lunchtime</TIMEX> i would go over and visit the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and eat with them and
 		see what they were doing and they had wonderful they had things like gardens and lots of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pets</ENAMEX> and just they had a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> to one uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher student</ENAMEX> ratio so that that sort of and all most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> had degrees um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five hundred</NUMEX> dollars a week for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> that's incredible
 	
 	
 		yeah it was incredible actually  but it was good i mean it was it was at that time there were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and they were in special programs and each one was a little over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two hundred a week</TIMEX> and then in addition i paid a little bit extra
 	
 	
 		oh oh
 	
 	
 		but the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> were i mean they really had some great opportunities but that what you were alluding to earlier is you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who work for minimal wage and
 	
 	
 		well
 		well
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and and really have to feel they have to put their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> sometimes they do put them in uh fairly low paying situations situations
 	
 	
 		you know they could
 		uh somebody will have a job at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three hundred</NUMEX> a week to get off welfare and you know and that's a good starting wage but boy <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">three hundred dollars</NUMEX> a week doesn't go very far on child care
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		no even that
 		that really i think i don't it's been awhile since i've looked at my youngest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> so it's been a little while since i've looked into actually day care <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> but they are you know the good ones do cost maybe <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixty</TIMEX> dollars <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> since and so
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i mean we used to pay pay <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">fifty cents</NUMEX> an hour to babysit but <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine mine</ENAMEX> are <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty two twenty three and twenty seven so</TIMEX> you know that i guess babysitters now are up at what <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five dollars</NUMEX> an hour
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		something like
 	
 	
 		oh my
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well you know but you made the comment <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX> why would someone be interested in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> i mean it has been a real um there there have been some good entrepreneurial type experiences and i think
 		i think they have captured a certain market again but but then there are babysitting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pediatrician</ENAMEX> one of the things we've been real concerned about is the infections as you start putting lots of little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> together the infection rates that go around and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh yeah
 		
 		
 	