
 
     		
 	
 		i guess what
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		this brings to mind is uh um my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX> complaint is then uh
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		the priority that's given to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		that's what comes to mind anyway
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well i don't know i guess uh i think one of the biggest changes that's taken place over the last <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty five years</TIMEX> anyway is um uh
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		uh both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> working and the
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
  
 	
 	
 		the uh mechanisms haven't really been in place to get to give <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> all the attention they need
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so i think that uh and i think we're so reaping the
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		um results of that in uh
 	
 	
 		the consequences
 	
 	
 		a lot of problems yeah i mean i don't blame <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> for um both going to work um both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> going to work
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		it's tough not to for a lot of people
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		but it's been i think that may be the single
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		biggest social change in the middle class anyway that's uh that has uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh</ENAMEX> had a lot more repercussion that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> every thought
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and i have gone through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of decades</TIMEX> together we're both on our early forties
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		um  we've been married uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty two years</TIMEX>
 		so we sort of grew up together and um just had <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> uh so we have a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four year old</TIMEX> and a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two year</TIMEX> old
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first eighteen years</TIMEX> of our marriage um we were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> income <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carriers</ENAMEX> and all that so we had a pretty full lifestyle and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and having the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> we decided to uh to go into one income so i work and she stays home
 	
 	
 		tough isn't it
 	
 	
 		and and it's you know the
 		the ideal value system is is to motivate it there
 	
 	
 		our situation
 	
 	
 		because it it suddenly is something that uh
 		that we thought long and hard about
 	
 	
 		our situation is very much very similar
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX>  we're both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> and  used to working
 		and we decided that when we had <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> that we would uh have somebody home until they were uh well into school
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's difficult especially it's not so much
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		difficult financially i don't think as it is uh culturally
 		in that it's um
 		uh kind of expected i think i think it's difficult on my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> not to be um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
  
 	
 	
 		professionally identified and that sort of thing
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
  
 	
 	
 		but i really feel like it's been worth it for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and when i look around i think uh i'm i'm pretty glad we made the decision we did
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah we've you know experienced a lot the the turmoil of the uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixties</TIMEX> and seventies
 		and uh
 		i think we we were part of that um
 		looking for new value systems and having uh  a vision of the way the world was going to be when we were you know in middle age which i guess we are now
 	
 	
 		and then all of the sudden the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> come along
 	
 	
 		
  
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yeah that too but uh i just think that uh
 		right now we're experiencing a lot of disappointment with uh our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> and and uh
 		the way things haven't really changed and i think that uh you know our personal
 		difficulties are reflected in a lot of the unrest right now we're seeing with respect to politics
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah i i think uh
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		you have to be
 		um i don't want to make it uh more dramatic but you have to be kind of cultural really if you want to put your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> first and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um to sort of uh put a cap on things that you can really have and enjoy and just go ahead and
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		um do what's right by your by your family
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and i don't i i don't see a lot of support out there i see
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> um
 		voting down school taxes and um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh well a degree of the eighties was i think uh maybe the most disappointing social phenomena that i witnessed
 	
 	
 		
  
 		yeah
 		
  
 	
 	
 		because i really did see   you see it in um magnified <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about twenty</NUMEX> times
 	
 	
 		
  
 		
  
 		yeah i mean uh maybe double that again in the east coast
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		uh yeah  and we're we're both from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid</TIMEX> west we're both from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saint Louis</ENAMEX> and uh experienced  but we spent the entire eighties out here and uh
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		we're just <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">thirty miles</NUMEX> outside of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh it's very different than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid</TIMEX> west it's
 	
 	
 		i guess the i guess the  the epicenter of that uh
 	
 	
 		
  
 		yeah yeah i mean it you know the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> around here
 	
 	
 		stuff in the eighties
 	
 	
 		uh you know think they're poor if they can't get a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Polo</ENAMEX> shirt every week
 	
 	
 		um-hum right
 	
 	
 		it it's it's a different perspective and uh you know we got caught up in that we we we had you know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a real decade</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">hay</ENAMEX> day
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		an uh now we're retrenching like a lot of the rest of the country
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh particularly because you know we chose to have a single income and um
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		also working uh in a large corporate setting and that has become unsettled in the last
 		
 		
 	