
 
     		
 	
 		opinion on uh domestic or our policy towards uh <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Latin America</ENAMEX> is that
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		especially during the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> now <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administrations</ENAMEX>
 		we seem to have a double standard in place over um how we treat them <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> down there for example
 		a left <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wing regime</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">communist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX> is God awful and uh basically uh you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Satan</ENAMEX> incarnate
 		while <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> like for a long time uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El Salvador</ENAMEX> and uh uh Guatemala
 		with with right wing regimes we kind of just winked at things like death squads and alike yeah we found <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nicaragua</ENAMEX> to be the most horrible thing in the earth
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and i just felt and it's the same thing with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX> that we we really seem to have this kind of double standard down there
 		whereas if your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX> doesn't want to bother us a reason of threat to us we'll kind of ignore you
 		you can do whatever you want but if you invite the commies in you know look out
 	
 	
 		or if it it doesn't even have to be commies if it's just a little left of uh of uh what the prevailing attitude is in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> it was bad somehow and
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> certainly the right wing death squads were just as uh
 		
 
 		deadly if not more so than anything set up by any of the left <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wing governments</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh and</ENAMEX> and that uh showed in the uh  who allowed to  to come into this country
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 		if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are coming from left wing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> uh it was viewed that they were
 		uh only seeking uh economic uh benefits and not actually escaping uh death threats
 		whereas if uh they were coming from right uh am i saying this correctly or if
 		if if they were coming from um right wing regimes um
 	
 	
 		you wouldn't want them in
 	
 	
 		we wouldn't let them in yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah it's like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guatemala</ENAMEX> how many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Guatemalan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El Salvador</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX> have we seen and heard about in the last <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years</TIMEX>
 		yet <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nicaraguan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX> for the longest time were welcome with open arms as escapees and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and and any communist type of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX> down there i mean the whole the whole farce in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Granada</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh gosh what an embarrassment
 	
 	
 		right was it just
 		i mean it was the most ridiculous thing and this is the kind of policy that we have down there i mean then we have this fake drug war
 	
 	
 		no with uh
 	
 	
 		down there and that seems to be well we'll give you aid but oh no not to feed your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> no we want you to clean up
 		uh our drug problem for us here's some money go shoot <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with it you know
 	
 	
 		right what was the whole thing with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Panama</ENAMEX> i mean here we were paying uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Noriega</ENAMEX> for years
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and and then suddenly
 		we go in and bomb his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Panama</ENAMEX> and and and try and indite him i i don't understand what that was all about
 	
 	
 		well it's the same thing that happened with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and years
 		here we are sending money over here playing these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> off of each other it's was same thing in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> playing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX> off off you know off of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>
 		in this case <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Panama</ENAMEX> off of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nicaragua</ENAMEX> and uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX> and any of the other left wing regimes down there
 		here we are giving them all this money and they're <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crooks</ENAMEX> and then when they don't do something that's suitable to our particular policy we have to go and invade them
 	
 	
 		and uh
 	
 	
 		and for what what does it leave us with absolutely nothing
 		i mean it wouldn't surprise me
 		it wouldn't have surprised me if uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Noriega</ENAMEX> got off on all of the charges that you know instead of being found guilty and then let him go just isn't we're an embarrassment you know
 	
 	
 		truly truly
 	
 	
 		and and i just think you know we have this kind of short term we are not interested in developing the region unless there's big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> involved and wants to get involved down there
 		we we tend to treat them as sort of like a backyard and you know i'm just  just like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right it's sort of it's our our little <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">colony</ENAMEX> is that they do just if they provide the labor and the debiting of uh
 		of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX> or uh uh
 		the
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">united</ENAMEX> fruit then that's fine
 	
 	
 		yep
 	
 	
 		but uh if they're actually trying to educate
 		
 		
 	