
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh with regard to uh to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">jury</ENAMEX> trials i you know i i really feel as though uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> trials are are uh whatever system has been been used historically in particular jurisdiction
 		you know is really the the only kinds of things that you can use because the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">the jurisprudence</ENAMEX> is you know based on on uh you know on accumulated  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> of law
 		and if if you have a situation where you change that body of law then all of sudden they they start they could start going back and digging up all these cases
 		that uh that would be handled differently were they judged by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s standards so i i really don't think it they they can really do much of anything to change it what do you think
 	
 	
 		
 
 		um i i don't think so possibly in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> selection would be the only
 		just for example what we're seeing in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> i guess
 		yeah it makes you wonder um had the jury been a different <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of people
 		what would've happened with that outcome um
 		and  and the problems that that has come
 		that has come from this decision that that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> came to after all of us witnessed what we did with the video tape beating um
 		just makes you wonder i guess whether or not they
 	
 	
 		well won't well maybe they used a little bit too much <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> with stuff like that but then then you know the defense <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> addressed each and every one of those blows apparently
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		that's that
 	
 	
 		and you know the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> sat in the car
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they didn't get beat up
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodney</ENAMEX> got beat up because he he you know he purposes you know he involved himself in some sub self-destructive behavior
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh um
 		just like the burning and looting is self-destruct everybody says well this is the nineties and they're gonna rebuild and it'll be even better
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh yes
 	
 	
 		hey what do you think you know some some black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> with capital is gonna come in and invest in that area
 	
 	
 		uh
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		with everybody with that mindset they they're they're gonna that whole area is gonna be turned into residential ghetto you know and and you might even be able to to use it for for a bombing test site you know
 	
 	
 		they're only gonna suffer
 		yeah they're only gonna suffer they they've defeated themselves with with their looting and violence um
 		i understand why they were upset by the verdict just because even those of us that aren't black or uh don't live there or whatever
 		we all saw the same thing on the on the tape and um
 	
 	
 		well everybody's everybody's saying this is gonna be a new era we're gonna reexamine this thing
 		hey the bunch the average <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> is gonna take a look at that and say suspicions confirmed they're a bunch of animals
 		you know how can you really deal with an environment where you're gonna lose everything
 		<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">forty</NUMEX> deaths i mean there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">forty</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are dead as a result of that
 	
 	
 		i know
 		that's really ridiculous
 	
 	
 		and i'm just trying to determine you know how you address and how you weigh you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodney</ENAMEX> getting getting the the hell beat out of him against you know forty deaths
 	
 	
 		against forty other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> being
 	
 	
 		yeah and there's no other i i'm not sure exactly sure uh what the circumstances surrounding the deaths
 		and i'm very upset that the news media has not identified those deaths and and pursued it you know because i'm interested in the circumstances surrounding this thing
 	
 	
 		those deaths
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		is it a looter that got shot by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">store owner</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		or just a bystander an innocent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bystander</ENAMEX> or somebody got actually beat to death or what um
 	
 	
 		i you know no tears
 		yeah and and so i but i i suspect a number of them you know you you see film of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> being pulled out of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and shot you know in in the street
 	
 	
 		it uh or or beaten
 	
 	
 		and and my reaction is i would've run over fifty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> before rather than stop
 		and uh and there there would've been just uh nothing but carnage after after if i'd been at the wheel no one would've stopped me
 	
 	
 		right
 		that's that's exactly how i feel too i wouldn't have uh they wouldn't have stopped my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> for any anything had i seen them coming but i was just wondering since you were you're in you're back east um
 		and a little closer to the the bigger <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> probably than we are in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Idaho</ENAMEX> here
 	
 	
 		right i'm inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">beltway</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		you know how capital <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">gang</ENAMEX> they always say well inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">beltway</ENAMEX> they think thus and so and i say well wait a minute i'm inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">beltway</ENAMEX> and i don't think like that
 	
 	
 		um-hum oh in what uh section of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> do you work
 	
 	
 		i'm a government employee
 		i'm with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh oh that's interesting
 	
 	
 		yes and and so um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh and</ENAMEX> and the reason i'm doing this whole thing is because you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick</ENAMEX> who is another government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX> wanted a speech segments of my speech that uh were done <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year ago</TIMEX> and he wanted another collection <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> later
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and so this is my <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">seventh</NUMEX> call <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year ago</TIMEX> i did <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> calls
 	
 	
 		oh i see
 	
 	
 		and so that's that's why uh
 		uh that's that's why i'm religiously getting on the phone because i have a unique you know i have a unique situation here in that if i don't participate
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	