
 
     		
 	
 		have you had to return anything  lately
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		uh
 		i had a uh i have a boat i live on the water and i i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> that i like to take out pretty much <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> and
 		i uh took it into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX> to be repaired and i brought it back and it didn't run
 		and i got to i had to i took it back and told them what was wrong and
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh</ENAMEX> took it back out and it still didn't run <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times
 		i had to take it back
 	
 	
 		did you think it was uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mechanic</ENAMEX>'s problem  with the bolt
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh</ENAMEX> was a mechanic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mechanic</ENAMEX>'s problem he didn't really know what was wrong with it and
 		you thought he had fixed it but he he not didn't
 		eventually it got to the point where i said i don't think you know what you're doing i'm going to take it somewhere else and
 		so i did and someone else finally fixed it
 	
 	
 		you mean did you have to pay this fellow
 	
 	
 		uh no i didn't pay him
 	
 	
 		i wouldn't image you'd want to
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i paid him original money to do some other work that he did right but uh the rest of it i didn't
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		didn't pay him
 	
 	
 		no  thinking about products and have they really changed
 	
 	
 		and uh
 	
 	
 		i i think it's hard to say cross the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> that you're not getting what you're getting what you pay for anymore
 		i um just recently had an experience with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sears</ENAMEX> do you have that down in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		well <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sears</ENAMEX> is kind of famous for taking back almost anything they're very good about it
 		i had bought a leather jacket almost about twelve <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> for my ex-husband
 		he is still wearing the darn thing and you know after some time i was fortunate enough to get remarried to a really nice <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fellow</ENAMEX> and i happen to like this leather  jackets and his lasted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a year and a half</TIMEX> and i said there there's no
 		uh this makes no sense the good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> didn't get the good jacket
 		and i called them up and i said i would expect a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX> coat you know we do have in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winters</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> and you i guess you use <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four months</TIMEX> out of the year
 		um this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> didn't get <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight months</TIMEX> out of a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX> coat all the stitches were coming out it's a real mess
 		you know i really expect you to do something about this and i didn't really hang on to receipts or anything and it it took much song and dance
 		uh to get it done but i just picked up a brand new leather jacket today
 	
 	
 		oh good
 	
 	
 		so i'm i'm pretty pleased about that the thing is it only cost <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about a hundred dollars</NUMEX> which for a leather jacket is quite reasonable
 		but the repair i was going to just bring it in and have it repair the repair would've been about seventy
 		and i was going to i was just going to do it i hated to throw it out
 		so i i think if you make enough noise you can get your problems taken care of in most cases
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah so they took and just exchanged
 	
 	
 		uh yeah i i had to bring it in i had to talk to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Roanoke Virginia</ENAMEX> i guess that's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sears</ENAMEX> central
 		but they were really good about it you know they i i wasn't nasty i didn't attack them i said i'm so used to your stuff being wonderful i'm so shocked  and alarmed  this should happen
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and i think it's how you conduct yourself as well if if you're kind of mean and nasty if you you get treated mean and nasty
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but um i was really please and and it is true uh uh generally they back up what they have and
 		it worked out nicely fortunately and it's you know it's like you know when someone else hits your <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> it's not your fault and you don't pay for it but you're majorly inconvenienced
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and i had to carry this jacket around to repair <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> and make <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of phone calls to get it fixed you know it's not like it didn't cost me anything in time and effort
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		what aggravating is uh how much how much time and effort you expect things to be
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		to be right the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time
 	
 	
 		right well you you were talking about <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boats</ENAMEX> it made me think about <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> i had a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">station wagon</ENAMEX> that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> just died
 		and i called up the repair <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX> apparently this some kind of uh box in the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> that just dies and they know it dies
 		and in every <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> you're going to have that's a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> it's going to die and i guess after so many miles
 		and he told me over the phone before he even saw that's probably what it was
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and it is and and they build this little time bombs in so  you know you got to bring it back
 		
 
 	
 	
 		a little black box that
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		tells you when to bring it back in to to for repairs
 	
 	
 		well some kind of part where you can't even an electrical spark off the engine anymore it just the whole thing just dies when you this thing goes
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and you really don't know when it's going to happen you just know that you're going to be stranded if you get a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX>
 		and
 	
 	
 		that's not too
 		not too nice
 	
 	
 		it's kind of upsetting
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		at at the time i knew what it did and what it was called but i don't remember that now
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		have you found that uh clothes and shoes and things you bought  shoddy than they have in the past
 	
 	
 		uh well i haven't bought too much
 		lately uh not for clothing
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		but uh i bought a a lot of stuff i remodeled the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and i bought a lot of a lot of new uh a new new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen</ENAMEX> and new uh fixtures and everything
 		and uh one thing that we i did buy that i had the only problem was a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sears</ENAMEX> stove
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		and uh when i got it it'd a big dent on the top of it
 		so i had to
 		
 		
 	