
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		uh i don't know i can't give uh too good a perspective uh  how things have changed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten twenty or thirty years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well i guess uh
 		i guess the first thing  you know comes to mind would be how they've changed to the worst
 	
 	
 		yeah  how so
 	
 	
 		in a lot of ways
 		yeah well
 		yeah
 		
 
 		i guess break down of the family <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> for one thing
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">astounding drug</ENAMEX> use that's uh going on and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		pretty depressing if you start thinking about it i guess
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah it's uh i don't know it's you know i lived in basically it's a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">suburb</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		um so i you know luckily i'm  in a good area so you know i don't have to really deal with
 		a lot of the problems that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX> has to deal but uh you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are bringing in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> into the grade <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and high <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and stuff
 		you know trying to kill <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">others kids</ENAMEX> and you know it's it's it's outrageous you know
 	
 	
 		unbelievable
 	
 	
 		like like you hit the nail on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> probably that all comes from you know lack of a good family structure
 		for this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you know they just
 	
 	
 		yeah i don't know which came first i don't know i think the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> had a lot to do with it but
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah i don't you know
 	
 	
 		i don't know if that's a cause or an effect
 	
 	
 		yeah that's that's the tricky thing trying to separate
 		figure out which is which um
 		but i don't know you know it i don't think there was much of a problem until crack started hitting the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> really
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah because that's cheap and incredibly addictive and uh
 		you know that seems to be the target choice of the you know poor inter-city people
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX> and marijuana i don't they really were after that i don't think they really touch that that much
 	
 	
 		however on the brighter side <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> seems to be
 		performing a whole lot better
 	
 	
 		well that's true that's true
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh would kill for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dodge viper</ENAMEX> a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the moment</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh a pretty nice car
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		uh the uh
 		why the computers in the engines
 		you know they uh  compensate the whatever problems come along until i just
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		i make <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> and i'm a bitch though
 	
 	
 		yeah it does i mean uh
 		but uh i do have a lot a lot help with those computers you know the curves giving a lot of information diagnostic
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah but doesn't uh help the home mechanic that much unless they've got a uh you know some way to decode all that information
 	
 	
 		sounds like my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s car i just got uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cadillac</ENAMEX> a used <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one eighty six</NUMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		had a few things she had to get fixed on it and we just  so now you just pressed pressed a couple of the buttons up in the
 		uh
 		the air conditioning panel i think and uh and it reads out codes that way
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		hum
 	
 	
 		and then of course have to decipher them
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		with the little book i use
 	
 	
 		hum interesting
 	
 	
 		but uh
 		yeah i don't know uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		street <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gangs</ENAMEX> and all that kind of stuff just
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i think it comes back to the you know that the
 		family isn't
 		fulfilling the role it used to
 	
 	
 		yeah i i think that's probably the key thing you know the key thing so you've got
 		single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> who are trying to raise <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and you know are off working <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all day</TIMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are on their own
 		you know that much guidance they're going to get into trouble and
 		you know now good stable family <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX> uh keep them straight or you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> figure to look up to or anything
 	
 	
 		well
 		
 
 		they get so much information from the
 		TV you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		makes
 		i think part of the
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>
 		you know <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> and so forth and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stands</ENAMEX> in the fact that they were
 		you know able to
 		teach them and tell them about things that and now the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> probably know more than the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> in a lot of cases
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah about somethings but i don't you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		for the more important things about life i think uh a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are missing uh
 	
 	
 		right that's true
 	
 	
 		they're they're out for the the quick buck mentality
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		you know who they gets defined by what kind of tennis shoes they wear
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and uh you know they they don't have
 		really kind of deep personal values anymore you know what
 		
 		
 	