
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and you say you have some strong feelings about uh the issue
 	
 	
 		uh yes i do as far as uh
 		as far as uh
 		as far as immigration as a whole goes
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i think that uh we simply must start
 		accepting everybody in the world
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh i there just is not gonna be room for all of us we don't have jobs now
 		i i think uh i think when we come to a time of recession that it's particularly important that we shut our doors at that time
 		um  hope you're one of the employed right now
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i am one of the unemployed right now
 		i was a systems <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analyst</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">programmer</ENAMEX> for an oil company
 		and uh
 		i applied for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> set of jobs with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> that they had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two hundred</NUMEX> openings but they had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two thousand</NUMEX> applications
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and i know that there are a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foreigners</ENAMEX> uh here you you know doing my line of work
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and of course i'm not perfectly happy about not having a job
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		so how do you feel
 	
 	
 		well i'm a little bit ambivalent the problem with uh
 		and i think one of the problems with immigration policy is like any other political problem is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are not willing to discuss it uh in
 		in terms of what uh really is driving it they're not willing to tell the truth the same way with um uh issues of uh race and things like that
 		i mean right now
 		um i believe there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> policies that uh that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> uses to modulate immigration <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> actually
 		one is at the high end uh they always wanna be able to um do some brain draining
 		they'd always like to be able to attract the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh Einsteins</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chou</ENAMEX> or you know they'd like to be able to get the top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in any field and so they can almost always find room for someone like that
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		at the bottom end
 		they um
 		are always willing to um let in cheap labor  if it lowers the cost of doing business in some particular area and has strong support from the powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in that area
 		those are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>  things that i think are going on although they i i i don't think the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> would tell you that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">okay</ENAMEX> and i think you're right in both cases
 	
 	
 		and then the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> thing  is uh the political aspect of uh uh letting steam come out from under the lid in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		they cannot close off the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> border not because it's physically impossible but because the explosion that would take place in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> would be uh
 		uh would spill over to this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> so they keep allowing um the pressure cooker to um
 		let off steam
 	
 	
 		and i think probably it's pretty important right there how do you feel about <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Haitian</ENAMEX> immigration
 	
 	
 		uh  that's one of the few things i guess i found myself in agreement with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		i think they're very difficult <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> to integrate into uh society they're very difficult um <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> to find jobs and uh and uh places for
 		and so um um i don't deny that we may have been involved in causing the problem that uh in that they're pretty miserable where they are
 		but i'm not to sympathetic about um
 		letting large numbers of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Haitians</ENAMEX> in
 	
 	
 		actually
 		actually i feel  that if we accepted these people
 		that we would eventually have almost the total <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> here
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and it would have nothing to do with political situations it would have to do with poverty
 	
 	
 		right
 		but if you let them yeah if you let them in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a million</NUMEX> at a time it wouldn't make that you know it wouldn't make that big a bulge in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> but politically politically and economically
 	
 	
 		oh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gosh</ENAMEX> have you been to have you been to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Southern Florida</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah well i know about it uh i mean it's it is now with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Haitians</ENAMEX> the way it was with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cubans</ENAMEX> uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years ago</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		well i mean and the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of them together i mean we can it's just as well  you know it's hardly <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> anymore
 	
 	
 		on the other hand you know it the ironic thing about this is that there's
 		nobody more full of the entrepreneurial <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spirit</ENAMEX> than a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> generation immigrant
 		so there's uh uh there's a lot to be said for having a steady stream of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who know how it is someplace else coming in
 	
 	
 		but there's some differences in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX>
 		that that we're getting now well in i particularly have a problem with the illegal immigration
 	
 	
 		right
 		sure
 	
 	
 		i think probably your your a great deal of what you say is true about the legals
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but uh the majority of the illegal immigration we're getting now they do not come here to blend into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>
 		uh they they don't bother to learn our language
 		and uh  <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of all they've they've i'm sorry this i really feel strongly about this we send a lot of money to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	