
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay uh mandatory service yeah i don't think it's a good idea
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> because we'd have to change the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> to  to uh allow uh involuntary servitude uh in service to the government
 		and i'm not sure that we could do that in such a way that we could avoid winding up a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slave</ENAMEX> state
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's i like the idea
 	
 	
 		and in what way are you talking about
 	
 	
 		well  i like the idea of voluntary voluntary support i mean they might be able to ah say that anyone who does that uh gets certain benefits that  would not be available to someone who didn't do it
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but to use force um really sets us a a it it essentially says that your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> there's a title to your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> and that title belongs to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and you are not a free <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right yeah right
 	
 	
 		the idea itself of service is good
 		and when someone is say out of high school and not sure about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> or out of college and not ready to go into a career and they're not committed to huge amounts of debt that's the best time to be able to do work that doesn't pay very well
 	
 	
 		see i i yeah and i also thought that um that would interfere with with college work and
 	
 	
 		yeah unless it were tied directly
 	
 	
 		they didn't
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know if someone were studying something uh let's say take something obscure somebody was studying economics the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Department</ENAMEX> could offer to send them to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> to teach them how to run their country
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true
 	
 	
 		as an extreme example right
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but in reality i think what you would wind up with is a political football where they would see all these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> counts that they can use to for their own will and i just don't think it would work
 	
 	
 		when do they assume this is gonna be proposed or mandatory or when when i what what year are they looking at
 	
 	
 		well they're not it's been suggested and it's sort of a topic of debate every time it comes up it gets voted down the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are pro-military oppose it because they don't want <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to have the right to opt out of the military into something else
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are pro-constitution oppose it on the grounds that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> shouldn't even have the right to enforce you to join the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX> unless the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> is actually under attack
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right
 	
 	
 		so mostly it's just kind of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of those things that goes away  ah they've got a noisy line
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah
 		i thought that was your line
 	
 	
 		yeah well it's somewhere between here and there
 	
 	
 		uh what age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> is are are they looking at
 	
 	
 		uh oh eighteen the draft age yeah  wait a minute yeah  let me see if i can get on a cleaner line if it's my line um
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighteen</NUMEX> yeah that seems normally that would interfere with college i would think
 		i moved maybe that is that's part of it
 	
 	
 		yeah it is my line i was on a radio phone
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		all right that's better yeah no there they they figure that they can draft you at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eighteen age</TIMEX> they usually do draft you at nineteen and that's the age they're looking at
 	
 	
 		oh hm
 	
 	
 		and of course they're this one the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> would be equally grabbed and they're almost on the verge of saying that you if you're gonna draft <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> you're gonna have to draft <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and you're gonna have to put them in front of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> just the same
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		so uh if you're near that age or you know somebody who is uh you know be aware of that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		well that's kind of scary  i'm not near that age  i'm way over it but i do have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> to think about you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh okay
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">yep</ENAMEX> and you don't want them sent off to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> to help defend <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Saddam</ENAMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> gets done arming him
 	
 	
 		that's kind of scary
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know we only find out about that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> after the fact
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so it's another thing when in doubt don't trust the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> at all it's really reached that point
 	
 	
 		oh uh-huh hm
 	
 	
 		hey you're in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Perot</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> i'm really thinking that this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> might be good for us
 	
 	
 		i do too
 	
 	
 		i've been it it seemed dangerous i thought is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> a closet fascist and then i find out that he helped rid the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> of the Gablers
 	
 	
 		he's he's helped out in a lot of ways yeah he's he's from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> or he's in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> area and uh he's very well known around here so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well i'm in the computer biz too so i know he's well known in the industry they uh i i have high hopes for him and i think that you know if he could get <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> interested and encouraged and to believe that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> was actually for us then i'm for him
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah i i
 	
 	
 		i mean in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> primary i'm gonna vote for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX> just because i kind of like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX> and his attitude but when uh when it really comes down in the fall i think i know where it's gonna go
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah i i think he's got a very good chance so there's a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> here pulling for him
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so
 		i don't know  we'll just see how did you uh  you work in the um computer business that what you said
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		you know this
 		yeah i'm an end user i teach <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> how to use <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Macintoshes</ENAMEX> and how to buy equipment and desktop publishing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> production and things related to that
 	
 	
 		oh okay well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> works for um <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Instruments</ENAMEX> and so um that's how we found out about the Switchboard
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh yeah oh that's their project too isn't it i found about it on the network
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	