
 
     		
 	
 		i kind of think the probably the biggest political topic that i can think of at this point
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		is probably the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ross Perot</ENAMEX> uh candidacy uh i think that that has some interesting uh effects to it at this point with the uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		level of um
 		uh outrage outrage that the public seems to have the voting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> seems to have with the existing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> out there and i think that uh
 		that is certainly something that we haven't seen to this level before
 	
 	
 		right well they've been independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> before but uh never
 		as as as popular as he seems to be and i mean it seems to be um doesn't really matter who who it is it's just that fact that he's not in either party
 		that uh seems to be why he's so popular i guess
 	
 	
 		what's your view on
 		big political issues
 	
 	
 		hm
 		um
 		well if we i i i mean sticking with this topic um
 		i would just say that you know it's it's interesting that it doesn't really seem to matter what um what his views are you know i mean he seems to have some views which are pretty conservative and which are pretty liberal
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 		but it it seems like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are more interested in just the fact that he's an alternative you know than to um
 		to what what you know it i i guess he hasn't really outlined a platform yet you know and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> keep asking him you know what what do you feel uh is the best a plan to deal with the budget or blah blah blah
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and um he really doesn't have any answers i guess but that doesn't stop his popularity from swelling you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are just sick and tired of um everyone else i guess
 		it seems to be i don't know it's kind of like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">um people</ENAMEX> always
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> always blame you know they always say how can  uh-oh  <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> outside um
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> always  say how how can these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> be in power and stuff but i guess they forget that they're the ones who put them there in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place you know
 		they're always they're always trying to find <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third third</NUMEX> alternatives like um
 		you know uh limiting limiting number of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> in office for instance
 		but you know all they have to do is vote him out of office you know it's almost like they want to be forced to vote the way that they
 		could in any case you know what i mean
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it seems strange
 	
 	
 		it's it's going to be interesting to see if he uh actually you know we hear the complaints about uh voter apathy and and the whole the whole shebang about throw the bums out
 	
 	
 		
  
 		right
 	
 	
 		it and it it usually you know it's a big deal until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">election day</TIMEX> comes around and then it you know it fizzles out and we end up with the same people
 	
 	
 		exactly
 	
 	
 		and uh you have to wonder whether is this going to be something that uh is really going to result in
 	
 	
 		
  
 		hm
 	
 	
 		um a mass turnout of the current <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that we have in there or whether this is just going to be another of the same old <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">well</ENAMEX> throw the bums out but not my bum you know
 	
 	
 		right right as long as he brings <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pork</ENAMEX> back  my <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> then um what what do you think his
 		chances are what do you think uh how much of the vote do you think he's going to get and do you think he will take it more from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well the media <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> keeps saying that he's supposed to drain it away from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> but i know that there's a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> that don't like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i'm one of them i'm not happy with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> at all uh but
 		i you know i'm concerned more concerned about <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> saying they're unhappy with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> and then they go and vote for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ross Perot</ENAMEX> and then we basically split any protest vote
 		against against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> more or less in half you know i mean you're dividing it too far and then he squeaks by for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four more years</TIMEX> and you know for me that's not a going to be a wonderful uh feeling
 	
 	
 		exactly
 		right
 		exactly
 	
 	
 		but uh
 		i think it'll be interesting to see um whether it turns out he gets more than <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">twenty percent</NUMEX> of the vote if that um i
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		personally i have a i have a problem with
 		with electing someone who's that rich  um i mean they're all that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rich</ENAMEX> anyway but but someone who's advertised as that rich i don't know i it i kind of
 		um have problems seeing what he and i would have in common you know
 	
 	
 		yeah but i you know it'll be interesting i i don't i agree that i don't think that
 		
 		
 	