
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		it looks like um
 		we're going to have um a um
 		sort of a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> movement on our hands in the fall
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		i guess the last time that happen was uh
 		well i guess it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anderson</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seventy two</TIMEX> and then there was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wallace</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixty</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anderson</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty</NUMEX> or whenever it was
 	
 	
 		yeah i remember remember <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anderson</ENAMEX> but also a little a little young for that one
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i guess the
 		what i see behind it this this this uh maybe it's always true of <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> movements but this one seems to be almost entirely negative
 		almost completely a reaction to uh um
 		uh failure of the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> rather than anything positive that's uh represented
 	
 	
 		yeah i  that's a pretty good point i hadn't thought about it like that but yeah it's i guess it's not really um a start up with uh
 		necessarily new ideas and you know this is my positive outlook but rather uh saying well uh i'm just not very happy with uh with the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> seem to be going type of thing
 	
 	
 		yeah i think there's absolutely no political philosophy the only thing that uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Perot um</ENAMEX> seems to has to offer is that uh he's a doer
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 		and since most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> agree on what needs to be done but nobody can figure out how to do it he's just going to say uh
 		i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> i know how to tell people to do things and get them done
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		which is uh pretty attractive and when uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> can't seem to be able to get anything done
 	
 	
 		yeah i guess read a political cartoon uh must be probably <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a week ago</TIMEX> now or maybe you saw it i don't know how widespread this was but it showed uh Perot like revealing his
 		you know what he stood for or whatever it's kind of like he had showed him open up his overcoat and  open he open they drawed him um they drew him  opening up his overcoat and inside was another overcoat
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so it's like you know his he hasn't really he hasn't really said very much of what he stands for or what you know he's kind of pretty much  vowed to saying you know i'll get i'll get this done and get that done you know but what is this and that type of thing
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but
 	
 	
 		well i think um
 		it's it's a reaction to what's what's happened over the last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> or fifteen <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> where um the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> really just seem to be intent on blocking the other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> from getting any further the the uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> want to get the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> want to try to get control of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> but they don't seem to have any really big ideas or sweeping um vision of where things should go
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and now things are are so stalled
 		that uh
 		out of uh pure frustration comes along with uh
 		uh a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who says he can get things done
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so maybe he is part of a um a more general
 		trend in politics over the last <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years</TIMEX>
 		
 
 		the um
 		uh
 		i don't know those of us who weren't too happy with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> saw that as a
 		as just a um  of selfishness and um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		government just got out of the way there wasn't no prevailing philosophy except do what you can to get you something for yourself
 	
 	
 		yeah it it it seems it seems as though that that's definitely definitely a point of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> pretty much trying to block each other and there's been a definite i'd say definite loss in actual
 		you know ideals and there's just there's too much each side you know where there's <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> both of them like trying to
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		you know either play to the hands of like what the dominant philosophy is uh not not not not dominant but like old style philosophy of each each
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		in each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> and not really coming up with a new ideas or the or maybe i mean it it you know it's time for maybe a definite new vision and and what's going on which may be you know a blend of both
 		you know maybe both parties or you know a little bit of this a little bit of that which may not fall into the lines of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">either party</ENAMEX> but you know just doesn't seem as though <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">either party</ENAMEX> wants to do very much that rocks the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> or maybe maybe says oh its time for a little bit of you know
 	
 	
 		um
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		things aren't going very well oh in the big picture maybe right now <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> getting better or it's maybe it's getting worse or who knows but you know it's just like a little ripple in the ocean it's  know some some somebody got to look down the road a ways and say well what's going to go on
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		what
 		yeah what i see is all tactics and no strategy um that and uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it's i mean it's fun to watch on a day by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX> basis but it doesn't get anything done in the long run
 	
 	
 		right right
 	
 	
 		
 
 		if all you're interested in is making the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> look bad and making yourself look good you don't really accomplish anything
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		in the long run the infrastructure deteriorates and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> kind of lose their uh sense of a of purpose
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah i take that definitely
 		
 		
 	