
 
     		
 	
 		uh around here we have a program where uh we we put out the the we separate the bottles and the cans and the plastic stuff
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> and we keep the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> in a in a their collected twice a month
 		and the trash and this this bottled  stuff uh that uh is put in a in a little blue bin that's picked up and sorted out into a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> so they may actually actually have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about three</NUMEX> passes at this collection
 	
 	
 		that sounds
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> for the regular trash one for the uh um you know bottles and cans and one for the newspapers
 	
 	
 		but i gather you do not separate uh the bottles and cans
 	
 	
 		no they they do that on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> they separate them as they as they you know dump them and you know one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> comes around with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> and and dumps it all in there
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh i think they're they're running out of uh you know  the sanitary landfill i think uh is you know running out of course um you being from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Mexico</ENAMEX> you've probably been in to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> especially if your your present location
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		you must have come to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> at least once
 	
 	
 		yes i know not only have i come to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> but um i find it very amusing that uh the
 		thing that was just instituted here is very similar that is we also have blue bins we also separate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> from all of the other stuff which goes into the bin and gets separated in the truck
 		and uh land fill space is indeed the driving factor here and in fact uh despite all of our open space out here land fill space is still um very hard to come by
 	
 	
 		my you've got a lot a lot of nothing out there
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		you know they got i mean there there's got to be a crevice between <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> mountains nobody gives a doggone about that you can you could use for landfill now
 	
 	
 		ah but if somebody can make a regulation about it they will
 	
 	
 		well what other uh well  what uh what unique things you think uh that you can do about it in in what at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Alamos</ENAMEX> uh  other other than nuking it
 	
 	
 		well um
 		yes other than nuking it um in fact <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Alamos</ENAMEX> uh has uh done a fair amount of research uh in recycling things in general
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		um it it involves for instance um creating biological organisms which can remove heavy elements like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Selenium</ENAMEX> and barium and uh other things from
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">waste material</ENAMEX> in general and um and purify the waste of specific uh uh nasty elements
 	
 	
 		well isn't that uh that's uh that's pretty uh upscale uh trash uh uh situation i don't think anybody around here would understand all the all those exotic techniques you know getting rid of the heavy metals
 	
 	
 		
 
 		and the other thing that just was in the local news bulletin was somebody has uh
 		made some special um <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">polymers</ENAMEX> that have the ability to uh make certain <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Actinide</ENAMEX> elements adhere to them um
 		uh they've uh looked at uh <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Plutonium</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">uranium</ENAMEX> and uh some other similar things to try to remove those from radio active waste
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		and again this is driven by all of the documentation and uh E S and H uh uh considerations that uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are uh worrying about i think much more than they should
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		actually i've been involved in recycling for long before it became fashionable back when i was in graduate school i did all of the recycling of the um paper from the computer center
 		and uh in fact i think i was the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> in our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> to have my thesis published on recyclable paper recycled paper
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well that certainly uh you know uh getting into the swim of things
 		i i think it should be it it should go to the to the heart of the matter though and say okay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> you you everybody gets you know <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> pounds of garbage that they can throw away you know uh but more than that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every week</TIMEX> uh you've got to pay by the pound
 	
 	
 		i think that's a wonderful idea
 	
 	
 		i i i i think i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would be would get very very you know they'd be very careful about how they bought stuff
 	
 	
 		the only alternative i would see is uh and this would actually be a little more workable since weighing everybody's garbage would be a real pain
 		uh if you did it by volume rather than by weight it would uh speak more directly to the space need than the land fill
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and it would also cause <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to compact their garbage more uh and uh and limiting the volume is probably a little bit closer to the real problem than limiting the weight
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well of course that uh you know those big <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trucks</ENAMEX> can can probably are far more efficient in packing than any kind of little household compactor
 		
 		
 	