
 
     		
 	
 		why don't you start this time
 	
 	
 		
 
 		okay
 		uh let's see i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Macintosh</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2CI</ENAMEX> and uh i'm a graduate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> in cognitive psychology
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and so i use it basically to run all my statistics and write up my reports and research and all that kind of good stuff
 		and i'd be dead without it
 	
 	
 		yeah i'm in the same position i started on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commodore</ENAMEX> in nineteen <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">um</ENAMEX> and moved up in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty eight</NUMEX> to an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX> system and i'm running on an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX> clone right now
 		under windows which basically is the same thing i think
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and uh i've used it also i do tremendous amounts of word processing i work in radio but i'm required to do a lot of you know journalistic writing and that
 	
 	
 		hm
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh so i do almost everything now in Word or in some other you know word processing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">system</ENAMEX> and uh use it to gather news and information and put it all together for something that's usable
 		so i've had my computer i've i i've found what's happened is that i can't write anymore on paper you know
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		because i type so fast now that any it's distracting to try and write by hand because it takes too long
 	
 	
 		exactly exactly and then i like to like go back and re-edit things as soon as i write it and
 		and you know you can't do that very well with uh a piece of paper and a pencil you know cause it takes so much longer to change things around and and move whole chunks and all this that and the other
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		
 
 		and of course you know i also run a bulletin board from here and i'm involved in FidoNet
 	
 	
 		hm
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		uh i'm the i'm the net <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coordinator</ENAMEX> up here for western and central <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh wow
 	
 	
 		uh part of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Net 260</ENAMEX> here it's got we have eighty nodes in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> alone
 	
 	
 		wow
 	
 	
 		so we try we try and get everybody together and that way it you know you can exchange mail between them and you don't have to call them
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		
 
 		and i just got into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">we FidoNet</ENAMEX>'s now has a thing where we can get in with the internet so i found out
 	
 	
 		uh-huh yeah i've started seeing some uh internet postings from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FidoNet</ENAMEX> and stuff like that
 	
 	
 		yeah i it's where i found out about this through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Comp DCom Telecom</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and i submit some messages on there i it's made things so so much easier it's amazing though that
 		in nineteen <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty six</NUMEX> we were all doing like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three hundred</NUMEX> bawd
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and of course you know now that's like ancient history and you think my God it was only like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five six years ago</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yep yep
 	
 	
 		
 
 		and then here's what we have now i mean what's in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years from now</TIMEX> it's just unimaginable what we're going to be able to do with these things
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah yeah well you know if we ever get any sort of uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ISDN</ENAMEX> running nationally it'll be really incredible
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		if they have the amount of data we can exchange
 	
 	
 		well that's good <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s working on
 	
 	
 		right yeah well that and he's talking about expanding the the internet as it stands now upgrading the backbone stuff like that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh so you know it's going to kind of impact everybody everywhere
 	
 	
 		well i see the phone <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> are working on getting into information services so we're going to have a glut of things everyone i think we're going to see another revolution in
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		computers but i think the reason why it didn't work the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time is that they assumed that everybody would need a computer to do all these things
 		uh when in fact at the time you know back in the early eighties uh and mid eighties you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> didn't the technology wasn't to the point where
 		it was something that could be easily learned for everyone but now we have the things like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mac</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Windows</ENAMEX> and other things where all you got to do is point at something and push a button
 	
 	
 		um-hum oh yeah
 	
 	
 		and i think that the technology's catching up to the point where we're going to be able to do things and make it a lot easier to for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to understand how to do these things
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so i'm hoping that we will see another type of revolution but one that will be a little more friendly to the end user
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah um i think what's going to happen is it's going to sneak into the consumer market uh through the television and through the cable industry and telephone industry
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um i was just reading in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX> they've got an article in the business section uh about how <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AT&T</ENAMEX> has just announced that they plan to offer uh cable TV <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">systems</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five hundred</NUMEX> channels by nineteen <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ninety four</NUMEX>
 		uh  you know
 	
 	
 		well they're working on that i'm a satellite dish <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> and we've been fighting like mad to have these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suckers</ENAMEX> re-regulated you know
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		because of the uh because they've stomped on us
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and so now what's happening is the phone <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> want to get into cable and introduce all these kinds of computer services over <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fiber</ENAMEX> optics
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and the cable industry now wants to get into the telephone industry through these personal communication things
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i think everyone's working now i i mean i'm seeing this we're going to see a lot more in the way of keyboards with electronic program guides and and everything else and ordering systems they have this thing called TV
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	