
 
     		
 	
 		yeah do you have a particular opinion on it
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i'm a little uh i'm a
 		not i i think that
 		that i do i i'm not sure that uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		that i think it should be like a normal practice all the time i think there are certain circumstances where it's important but it it kind of touches on on on privacy
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and so you know i i have kind of a a feeling that that it's a little invasive
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but then again on the other hand you have to stop and realize that um a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are are uh are are trapped in that
 		in that addiction thing you know and it's bad for them but
 		that's not necessarily gonna mean that they're gonna get the help they need and and get cured or anything you know
 		and some jobs uh uh require you to be
 		straight and with it to do a good job and protect yourself and
 		and things like that too you know so how you think how you feel
 	
 	
 		well well i'm kind of ambivalent also you like you say it it does affect your privacy um i guess i
 		how i could cope with it i do think in some cases it does make sense and how i could cope with it was um if when you accepted a job they told you up front this is part of it
 		you know then it's like porn movie you have the choice you know nobody sticks it in your face you've got the choice if you don't wanna deal with it don't take the job
 	
 	
 		right
 		
 
 		there you go that's right
 	
 	
 		um there are certain jobs in which i'd be more likely to feel comfortable about it and and those are the jobs in which a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s performance could affect your life
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		certainly uh someone who carries a gun
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um there's been a lot of publicity um in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Long Island</ENAMEX> where um
 		there's been school <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bus</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX>
 		who have driven erratically and caused accidents and killed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> because they were
 	
 	
 		wow
 	
 	
 		uh on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> and things
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and where your actions could affect somebody's life i'd be much more accepting of drug testing but under no circumstances would i think that you could just go take a job and they could say hey guess what you know we're gonna do this
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		i i think it has to be up front and then you've got the choice of not doing it
 	
 	
 		yeah well well the problem there is that you know a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that have worked for the same <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> for so long um that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> decides well if we're going to hire new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you know
 		well we're going to have to start checking it because we've had a problem in the past
 		well their problem in the past is with past <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> and so the new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are saying well
 		if you know  i i am sure this could happen you know if you're gonna if you're gonna um test us you should be testing the old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> too and so they get into a to a discrimination problem probably or something like that
 	
 	
 		well yeah i imagine it would be just this is new company policy and we're doing it to everybody
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		in which case hey you know you don't like it you can go look for another job but of course that's not so easy you know um
 	
 	
 		see there's one of the big problems <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are are in that situation they need that job
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> and uh
 		then they have the choice of either take the test or don't get the or or don't take the job and if they know they're going to fail the test you know
 		they're kind of in a in a between a rock and a hard place there so it's uh kind of like
 	
 	
 		i took a i'm i'm a licensed art <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> and i substitute which is why i'm home <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> i'm not working i'm not working
 	
 	
 		oh really
 		lucky you
 	
 	
 		well you know i'm home a little too often i think they're they're not calling substitutes that often but at any rate um i had taken a state test to be of all things a court <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> had worked for the state and she thought this was a brilliant idea so i just went along with it i thought it'd be neat you know like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Bond</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> and all this and part of the um you know you take this test i did very well and they called me in for a physical
 		and part of it was a test for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> nobody asked me you know they didn't mention what they were doing but it was perfectly obvious and i you know all government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and all army <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are just tested
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and there was one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fellow</ENAMEX> who just kept horsing around he he seemed almost
 		you know a little crazy
 		but he wouldn't you know give a urine sample and it was pretty obvious why you know he's just like oh i can't do it i can't do it you know  and this went on for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> i was wondering why he didn't just leave you know if you're not going to do it just leave
 	
 	
 		he was gonna fail
 		right because you're not gonna get the job if you don't
 	
 	
 		it was it was almost comical
 		um in my case they didn't follow me in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bathroom</ENAMEX> but apparently they were following you know the more suspicious types into the bathroom
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know because apparently <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i i read somewhere that you can replace your urine with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ginger</ENAMEX> with warm <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sprite</ENAMEX> or something <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mountain Dew</ENAMEX> and it tests you know that it tests like urine and you know it tests okay obviously
 	
 	
 		huh
 		
 
 		i don't know
 		i've heard <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> using somebody elses
 	
 	
 		uh-huh yeah you know i mean i guess if there i guess there is something to be worried about if there's a whole science of knowing how to deal with the test
 	
 	
 		you you know
 		smuggle it in
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		making a whole new element of society out there
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i don't know you know um like i don't uh i don't use <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> you know but  um
 		i know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who do i don't think
 		
 		
 	