
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i don't really know any elderly uh
 		in uh
 	
 	
 		no i hello
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">homes</ENAMEX> or anything
 		
 
 		care of the elderly i guess is
 	
 	
 		yeah i haven't given much thought to it i'm kind of busy raising my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 		the only way i can relate to it is i think of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> taking care of her parents
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and i remember her running over there every <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> to make sure they got
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dressed and and and  fed</ENAMEX> and cleaned
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and uh i remember her saying to me i hope don't ever let me do that to you put me in a home because it's it's hellish on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who has to give the care to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> like that
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		you know these
 	
 	
 		they have uh around here they've got these uh they're like uh condos
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complexes</ENAMEX> and they're uh
 	
 	
 		oh for senior citizens
 	
 	
 		geared to  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elderly</ENAMEX> and senior citizens
 		and they have i think uh like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurse</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> there
 	
 	
 		well i don't think yeah i don't think the problem is i mean those <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">condos</ENAMEX> are like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elderly people</ENAMEX> just living in their own <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartments</ENAMEX> i think the trouble begins when they have more physical problems
 	
 	
 		and they take care of some of that kind of thing
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i mean it's got to be humiliating to have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stranger</ENAMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurse</ENAMEX> or somebody lift you in and out of a bathtub
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know because i mean i'm i'm not aged but i'm i'm forty one now and i still feel twenty something and i realize that my body is kind of traitorous and and and changing on me even though i'm not feeling terribly old
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so i can imagine you  you know being eighty and somebody has to dress you and you're probably sitting there thinking my God this is so degrading but your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> just won't do it
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well i don't know i don't
 		i'm not sure that uh
 		this is necessarily true during even if they're eighty you know because you can
 		a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> uh maintain their
 		their uh fitness and so forth right on
 		up
 	
 	
 		well i i think nowadays <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are making that effort to eat right and to be more fit and i think old age is getting older
 	
 	
 		yeah that's a definitely uh that's statistically true
 	
 	
 		hum are your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> alive
 	
 	
 		and
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty five</NUMEX> i think right now <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty five</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		do  and he fends totally for himself
 	
 	
 		yep
 	
 	
 		that's wonderful
 	
 	
 		he still  yeah he was having a little trouble getting his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX>'s license he lives down in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		where i was raised but uh
 	
 	
 		that's great  that looks good for you too you know  longevity in the family
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right yeah and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> was
 		lived to a pretty ripe old age too
 		of course she was in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> when she lost you know her
 		her mind went
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>'s is
 		still pretty you know pretty well with it
 	
 	
 		well i you know  my thought is if your mind goes at the same rate your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> goes then nobody cares right you know it's like <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> when they're stupid what the hell do they know  i think if one goes before the other is when you run into trouble
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah right i guess
 		yeah well that like that uh
 		what is it uh
 		that disease of the
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alzheimer</ENAMEX>'s
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh that'd be awful
 	
 	
 		well i i think it that kind of thing is probably awful for everybody around you i think these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't rightly know what they're doing
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah really
 		yeah it's hard to say
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true
 	
 	
 		i had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> that got that and he was fairly young i think he was in his
 		like late <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirties</TIMEX> or forties or something like that
 	
 	
 		well is that something that is that something that affects you all the time or do you kind of like wave in and wave out of it
 	
 	
 		uh maybe a little lower
 		i don't know
 		i think it does come and go to some extent but it just keeps continually getting worse
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um that doesn't doesn't sound too pleasant
 	
 	
 		no it isn't
 	
 	
 		well
 		well i you know i
 		talking about  what would you look for if you had to put someone in a home i guess
 		uh
 		i don't know i guess a place that has the most activities you know keeping your mind alive even if you couldn't do very much
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		you'd have to go uh
 		i guess you'd have to go kind try and
 		pay them surprise visits and see if you could tell what the
 		atmosphere was like and so forth
 	
 	
 		yeah that's that's true
 	
 	
 		if they were uh you know seemed to be
 		caring or whether they were just  warehousing them
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		there's a lot of them like that i'm afraid
 	
 	
 		well you know you nobody takes care of your own as well as you would i was brought up in in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> where everybody lived in apartment <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> and there wasn't any room to you know wasn't <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX>  there wasn't a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> to take in the elderly
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so if and when they couldn't take care of themselves they couldn't move in with you because you had a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room apartment</ENAMEX> or something so you know that's why they went somewhere else
 	
 	
 		
 
 		where in the city
 	
 	
 		uh you know
 		my life's changed now i only
 		
 		
 	