
 
     		
 	
 		uh i i hope i don't consider them a uh threat because uh  uh we sure have taken down a lot of security measures that that we once had um i don't know seems um um
 		maybe a little bit young to remember the uh i'm only i'm i'm <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty two</TIMEX> so i don't think i remember the uh
 		uh
 		you know the height of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX> and and whatnot but i
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">huh-uh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i don't know i don't consider the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> a threat in that uh by any means just because of the fact that there's not uh uh anything that they have to threaten us with anymore
 	
 	
 		well there not i mean there really is no <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> now unfortunately they still do have a lot of uh nuclear weapons
 	
 	
 		exactly that's that's true that's
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh the one thing that worries me is is question of stability and control
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh i think it's too early to say you know whether they're going to develop some stable societies there in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> form or another
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		or whether this uh  old uh <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> tendency to
 		turn their fate over to some insane <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ruler</ENAMEX> is going to surface again
 	
 	
 		sure yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		they didn't they didn't have a very good track record even before the revolution
 	
 	
 		no they really didn't uh now you know they never really have had democracy there in any sense so
 	
 	
 		
 
 		no no
 	
 	
 		um
 		it's going to take both democracy and economic progress and uh resolution of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nationalist</ENAMEX> institutes i guess
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		all of that is going to have to happen and if any one of them turn sour they could still be uh dangerous simply because they might not
 		you know they just might sort of lose track of what they're doing
 	
 	
 		right
 		um i i guess
 		i'm not so concerned about an organized danger uh
 		maybe for the maybe for the simple reason that um
 		despite the fact that they do have uh  you know probably a large uh substantial nuclear capability
 		uh i'm not sure that that all of that capability is organized anymore i mean you know just along with it with the dissolution the that the of the uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union</ENAMEX> i think that  a lot happened with the dissolution of their of their military power
 	
 	
 		but that's really part of the danger because they still have uh you know i think there still uh missile uh <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bases</ENAMEX> or silos in uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kazakhstan</ENAMEX> probably in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ukraine</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right right
 	
 	
 		as well as in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> uh those in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> may be some of them in areas that uh may have uh
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		strong local national sentiments because they aren't all <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX> you know they're a lot of enclaves they have other nationalities
 	
 	
 		yeah sure
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and if even one uh
 		missile silo got in the hands of someone who is uh determined to
 		cause trouble for some for some reason they might launch a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missile</ENAMEX> on someone
 	
 	
 		i think i see your point uh you have you have uh where once you had uh one <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> controlling a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a</NUMEX> a large number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX> now you have several
 		smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> uh highly volatile
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> and militaries and it's not always clear which one of them is in charge
 	
 	
 		militaries yeah sure
 	
 	
 		well that's maybe the uh the uh extreme pessimistic view
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um think if uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> has a chance and if they can follow his lead in the other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">republics</ENAMEX> or whatever they want to call themselves now
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um they'll probably come out of it okay
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		uh do you see
 		uh i have not perceived and i wonder if you've perceived any uh uh antiAmericanism uh sentiments uh  on any level like you know that that we receive from the from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> for example
 	
 	
 		what in the former <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um not much i don't think i think that uh
 		probably or uh or uh image there is pretty good most places as i understand it
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		do you worry that we might uh overstep  i guess my question is do you do you think that there are ways that we might overstep overstep our bounds and provoke uh
 		provoke anger in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> and and what would those what would those steps be
 		provoke a threat
 	
 	
 		what might make them angry at us may make the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> angry at us or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> or both or
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		you know both i guess
 	
 	
 		well
 		i think if they uh
 		thought that we were taking advantage of their uh current preoccupations with internal matters or with
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	