
 
     		
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">okay Carol</ENAMEX>
 		so air quality
 	
 	
 		yeah is it i know in here uh downtown <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> it's you i mean you drive by and you can just
 		you can see it  but then again  i was originally was from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> and uh there is a big difference between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		surely
 	
 	
 		and uh they'd have their smog alerts and where you'd have to stay indoors for so many <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> with an air conditioner and of course they don't have that here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 		so there's
 	
 	
 		you mean they don't have the uh the smog alerts
 	
 	
 		no not in not in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> not well not in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> that is
 	
 	
 		right i i yeah i spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a summer</TIMEX> in in in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tyler</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so i know
 		just east of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> there
 	
 	
 		yeah we're going there <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX> uh-huh  we're packing and getting ready to go to
 	
 	
 		oh really
 		yeah
 		actually i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> born person
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i was born in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LA</ENAMEX> so i know what you're talking about in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LA</ENAMEX> it's pretty bad
 	
 	
 		yeah oh okay yeah you do then
 	
 	
 		
 
 		um the worst <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> in the in the world is actually uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico City</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		is it really i would not imagine that
 	
 	
 		yes
 		the worst <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> for smog is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico City</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		the most polluted <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> in the world
 		
 
 	
 	
 		huh you learn something <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		is that crazy
 		yeah i know that they've they're looking at uh um
 		you know uh you know better running automobiles
 	
 	
 		uh-huh yeah i've seen that
 	
 	
 		um
 		some things they do <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one one one one</NUMEX> of them is they're using <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">corn</ENAMEX> in fuel
 	
 	
 		huh i huh-uh
 	
 	
 		you ever heard of that yeah Methanol
 	
 	
 		huh no
 	
 	
 		yeah well that's big up here because of the  they grow a lot of corn
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh
 		yeah that's one thing that they do and at at that it's pretty easy to do and the uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		unfortunately it still contributes to global warming cause you have to wipe you know wipe out forest to grow corn and things like that it doesn't make sense
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true
 	
 	
 		uh  but it's you know one of the most uh productive <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">crop</ENAMEX> in the world is corn
 	
 	
 		right
 		huh
 		and of course i doubt if there's any you can buy regular anymore you buy unleaded right
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		huh
 	
 	
 		drive <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> with catalytic converters and all that
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		it's interesting they're they're looking at at
 		there's some work being done on uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">automobiles</ENAMEX> that are electric powered
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh they're looking at where you have a battery operated car basically but it has a a engine in the back that charges it so the engine kicks on when the batteries need power and it turns off
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		interesting thing about <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas</ENAMEX> is when i mean about battery powered <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> is when you're at a stop light you're not using energy any energy
 	
 	
 		huh that is good
 	
 	
 		unlike a car where it's running
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">electric</ENAMEX> car it's on demand i mean it's either on or off basically
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		huh
 	
 	
 		you don't have to shift
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so you <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> become very simple all of a sudden too
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh
 	
 	
 		very interesting
 	
 	
 		that would be nice
 		i think i saw that on TV <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time they maybe it was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> where they were demonstrating that or something similar to that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		there's a there's a race in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX> with solar powered <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Motors</ENAMEX> and all those compete
 	
 	
 		but what what what i think that was a setback a a setback that they i don't know they went i don't know how many <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">miles an hour</NUMEX> i think like <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		was was that something maybe it was i don't know
 	
 	
 		yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GM</ENAMEX> uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler</ENAMEX> announced that they're going to they're well they actually have an electric minivan
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		yeah their their Caravan
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		but it costs uh fifty <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">thousand dollars</NUMEX> right now
 	
 	
 		yeah and they're they're very expensive too
 		i was gonna
 	
 	
 		to operate yeah
 		but you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are buying them you know whose buying them the power company
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		free you know free for them
 	
 	
 		well yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		kind of interesting so see
 	
 	
 		well it doesn't make sense because if they want <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to convert you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they should make it worthwhile
 	
 	
 		yeah it's top speed is something like <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">eighty miles an hour</NUMEX> so it's a good good vehicle
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah hum
 		well i'll tell you sometimes it's it's pretty bad here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> i think it was pretty bad i don't know if it was if it's just uh <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">allergies</ENAMEX> or what but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">some days</TIMEX> it's really it's very nice here downtown and other <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> it's just really bad
 		so
 		i don't know
 		so what what kind of things did you experience in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LA</ENAMEX> when you were there or can you remember were you there at a
 	
 	
 		oh i wasn't there too long ago um
 	
 	
 		cause i haven't been there probably
 	
 	
 		well you know you going over the hills you know coming into the valley you can see that horrible horrible brown haze
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well we were there when they had a
 		
 		
 	