
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guy Reading Mike Gerson</ENAMEX>'s Speeches

            It was the criticism of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s big speech on education <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> that got
all the attention. Far more interesting, though, was the idea of conservative
activist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> that the shrub articulated. "Our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Founders</ENAMEX> rejected cynicism
and cultivated a noble love of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. That love is undermined by sprawling,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">arrogant</ENAMEX>, aimless <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. It is restored by focused and effective and
energetic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">W.</ENAMEX> said. "And that should be our goal: a limited
government, respected for doing a few things and doing them well."

            This phraseology recalled a series of articles written
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Brooks</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Kristol</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly</ENAMEX>
Standard in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> calling for what the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> dubbed "national greatness
conservatism." The echoes of their writing in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s speech were very clear
indeed. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brooks</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kristol</ENAMEX> cited examples of this kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Theodore Roosevelt</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>, citing the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Homestead Act</ENAMEX>, the national
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">parks</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Panama Canal</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> used the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidents</ENAMEX> and the same
examples. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kristol</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brooks</ENAMEX> called for "limited and energetic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> called for "effective and energetic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>."

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brooks</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kristol</ENAMEX>: "Instead of arguing that government
should be limited ... [<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>] have often argued that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is itself
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">evil</ENAMEX>."

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>: "Too often my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> has confused the need for
limited <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> with a disdain for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> itself."

            

            What this shows, I think, is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> wasn't simply
"triangulating" or "pushing off" right-wing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Bork</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom DeLay</ENAMEX>. He was tapping in (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> being allowed to plagiarize from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX>) to a line of intelligent, moderate conservative argument about the
federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s rightful responsibilities. But the question arises: How
did W. come to adopt the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brooks-Kristol</ENAMEX> concept of national-greatness
conservatism? Or perhaps the question should be how the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brooks-Kristol</ENAMEX> concept
found its way into his speech.

            The answer is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s chief <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speechwriter</ENAMEX> and senior
policy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adviser</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Gerson</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gerson</ENAMEX> is an evangelical <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> and one of the
original <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">champions</ENAMEX> of "faith-based social programs," an idea he promoted when
he worked for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Coats</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gerson's</ENAMEX>--I mean <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coats</ENAMEX>'--idea, was to
allow tax credits (and not just a deduction) for contributions to charities.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Speechwriter Gerson</ENAMEX> is also credited with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX>'s attack on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> as well as the address <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Forbes</ENAMEX> gave to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian Coalition</ENAMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>, the one that convinced the religious right to accept <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX>' conversion
from the supply side to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lord</ENAMEX>'s side. After a stint working as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX>
for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX> , he joined the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">campaign</ENAMEX> this
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gerson</ENAMEX> didn't return my phone calls, but the assumption that he is
responsible for most of the intellectual and historical references in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s
speeches--such as a tribute to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albert Shanker</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Federation of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Teachers</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s address--is widespread among conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">insiders</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> doesn't mention <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Shanker</ENAMEX> when speaking off the cuff.

            Of course, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> is not the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX> who uses a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">speechwriter</ENAMEX>. What's troublesome is the evidence that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> has an unusually
distant relationship to the material in his speeches. Did <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> even read the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brooks</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kristol</ENAMEX> articles? His boast to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few months ago</TIMEX> that he doesn't waste his time
reading policy tomes, combined with the way he delivers his speeches, might
lead you to suspect otherwise. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> squints into the teleprompter, sounding out
the words streaming by as if encountering them for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time. In his
education speech, he tripped over the term "exemplary," which came out of his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mouth</ENAMEX> as "exemplarary," and he referred to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter Sisulu Children</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Academy</ENAMEX>, a charter <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> named after the late <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ANC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>, as "Sizzle-oo." He
called the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Manhattan Institute</ENAMEX>, one of the more influential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservative</ENAMEX> think
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">tanks</ENAMEX>, simply "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Manhattan Institute</ENAMEX>," without the definite article, a
minor-seeming mistake that suggests he doesn't fully grasp what he's
saying.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bennett</ENAMEX> unwittingly provided some additional
support for this suspicion when he appeared on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the</ENAMEX>
Press on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> and tried to defend <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> from the charge of
conservative-bashing. Asked about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s slight against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bork</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX> described
it as "unfortunate." He continued:

            

               And I, as somebody who read that speech beforehand--and
I will take some responsibility for not seeing that. The line is "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>
who talk as if we're slouching toward <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gomorrah</ENAMEX>." It was to represent a line of
thought, not a personal attack on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Bork</ENAMEX>'s book. But that's the title of the
book. I think notes are going to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Bork</ENAMEX>, saying, you know, "It wasn't about
you, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Bork</ENAMEX>, it was about a certain line of thinking."

            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett assumes Bush</ENAMEX> himself wouldn't know--and
couldn't be expected to know--that someone named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bork</ENAMEX> wrote the book
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slouching Toward Gomorrah</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> referred to. He
makes it sound as if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> has no more responsibility for what he says in a
speech than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Brokaw</ENAMEX> does for a report he delivers on the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nightly</TIMEX> news.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX> doesn't even think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> is the one who owes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bork</ENAMEX> an apology!

            So who does? Must be <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Gerson</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
