
   
   
      
         
            Do the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Right Thing in Pakistan</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Steve</ENAMEX>:

             <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wow</ENAMEX>, I'm still reeling over
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s military coup in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>. Less than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks ago</TIMEX>, my film critic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pal</ENAMEX> and I were quaffing sodas (no <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beers</ENAMEX> in this <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">republic</ENAMEX>, remember?)
poolside at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pearl Continental Hotel</ENAMEX> in downtown <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rawalpindi</ENAMEX>, running around
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gilgit</ENAMEX> in disputed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kashmir Province</ENAMEX> and fending off aggressive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">beggars</ENAMEX> on the
overnight sleeper <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">train</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Karachi</ENAMEX>. Certainly there were lots of signs of
political and economic instability: Some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> recommended in our
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lonely Planet guide</ENAMEX> had closed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last year</TIMEX>, inflation was literally eating
away the rupee by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the hour</TIMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pakistanis</ENAMEX>, described universally as cheery to
the point of being irritating, were cranky and mean--especially when they heard
our <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> twangs.

            But as I reported on my radio show for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time
back then, the big news is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Pakistani</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> has apparently signed
a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">devil</ENAMEX>'s bargain with the militant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taliban</ENAMEX> from neighboring <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>.
They've opened the border between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Pakistani</ENAMEX>-held <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kashmir</ENAMEX> to let
mujahadeen guerillas in to fight the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indians</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all summer</TIMEX> long. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taliban</ENAMEX>,
who've earned a reputation as the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khmer Rouge</ENAMEX> by stoning adulterers to
death and denying medical care to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, aren't the most subtle <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> in the
world--heavily armed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">goons</ENAMEX> have set up checkpoints along the main highway
between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kashmir</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> and now occupy <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">between a third</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kashmir</ENAMEX> on
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Pakistani</ENAMEX> side of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Line of Control</ENAMEX>; the only thing saving <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cole</ENAMEX> and me
from a night as the star attraction at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Talidrome</ENAMEX> was our <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bus</ENAMEX>'s own heavily
armed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guard</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">That same week</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> major <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Pakistani</ENAMEX> political parties
called for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taliban</ENAMEX>-style rule in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> to bring stability and "real" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Islam</ENAMEX>
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masses</ENAMEX>. What you have to understand about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> is that it's a
democracy in name only; even before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> it was a barely disguised
military <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">junta</ENAMEX> backed with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> tax dollars. (Are we ever not on the wrong
side overseas?) Now the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taliban</ENAMEX> are trying to take over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>, an incredibly
strategic juncture between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">East</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West</ENAMEX>, continent and subcontinent. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Department</ENAMEX>, by backing the coup, is defending the very same <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX> that has
invited the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taliban</ENAMEX> into its territory--and setting us up for a potential
nuclear hot flash in a big way. Having just returned from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>, I am very
seriously frightened, despite <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s insipid headlines saying that things are
peaceful; if you'd seen what I'd just seen, you'd feel the same way. The truth
is, this is the calm before the shit-storm.

            So what to do? The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> ought to
break off formal diplomatic ties with this illegal military <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> until a
true democratic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX> comes to power. Right now, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX> runs everything
from road repair to tax collection, and there's no room for free speech in such
a place. As they said back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '60s</TIMEX>, you're either part of the problem or
part of the solution, and we're clearly a big part of the problem. But don't
count on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clintonites</ENAMEX> to do the right thing; they never ever do.

            Very truly yours,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
