
   
   
      
         
            The <i><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX></i> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leading Indicator</ENAMEX>

            Chatterbox, ever alert for signs of when the next recession will come, tries
always to read the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> very closely. It is a superb
publication (full disclosure: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> used to work there). During the last
few <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX>, however, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> has been a little pressed for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">time</TIMEX> amid the
hurly-burly of domestic life (the refrigerator broke down, the Chattersitter
smashed up the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Taurus</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">wagon</ENAMEX>), and he's been looking for shortcuts. The best
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, of course, is to read 
                  Slate
               's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>"
feature. But another technique is to count the number of sections the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> comes in. Lately, it's often come in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> (front section;
international news and editorials and the politics-and-policy "back page";
marketplace section; and money and investing section) rather than the customary
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>. In addition to making it more difficult to find the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> 's
tendentious editorial page, more <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sections</ENAMEX> have the added benefit of
demonstrating that the business sector has more money to spend on Wall
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Street Journal</ENAMEX> ads. When the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>-section Journal s stop appearing
(or when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> managing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Steiger</ENAMEX> changes his mind and
decides he wants to quit after all--according to press reports,
he said no <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late last week</TIMEX> to becoming the new <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Lou Dobbs</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNNfn</ENAMEX>) you'll know
the economy is about to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tank</ENAMEX>.

            Another sign might be the disappearance of ads like the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> in the latest
issue of Talk that shows a gorgeous model pouring <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Evian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> into a
goldfish bowl. Come to think of it, this ad may be a sign that a stock market
crash is imminent.

         
      
   
