
   
   
      
         
            Round <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC News 2</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metabolife</ENAMEX> 0

            Chatterbox completely forgot
to watch <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20/20</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>! He'd been meaning to
watch it, or to tape it, so he could compare <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arnold Diaz</ENAMEX>'s report on the herbal
diet <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">supplement Metabolife</ENAMEX> to the full transcript of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diaz</ENAMEX>'s interview with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metabolife</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Ellis</ENAMEX>--which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metabolife</ENAMEX> had mischievously posted (along
with a streaming video of the interview) on a special "kiss my butt, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC News</ENAMEX>"
Web
site. (See "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Metabolife: Read This</ENAMEX>! No, Wait, Don't Read This!,"
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Metabolife's Lawyer Assures C'box He Won't Sue</ENAMEX>," and
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Round One</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC News 1</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metabolife</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">0</ENAMEX>.") But when the
hour arrived, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>, having spent a pleasant <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX> 'round the hearth
with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pappy</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mammy Chatterbox</ENAMEX>--who were
visiting from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>--was preoccupied, along with Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>, by the
somewhat arduous task of tucking the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterkinder</ENAMEX> snugly into their beds. The
potential dangers of diet <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pills</ENAMEX>, and the potential irresponsibility of any TV
news coverage of same, slipped entirely from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>'s mind.

            Fortunately, in this age of cyberjournalism, everything
is retrievable. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC News</ENAMEX> was kind enough not only to e-mail <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> a
transcript of the broadcast but also to post the transcript, along with a streaming video of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">segment</ENAMEX>, on the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20/20</NUMEX> Web site, so that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who don't work for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX> can retrieve it, too.

            Having now both watched and
read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diaz</ENAMEX>'s report, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> pronounces it ...
quite fair. It begins with a favorable testimonial
from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Skeens</ENAMEX>, who says she lost <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> pounds by taking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metabolife</ENAMEX>.
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Admittedly</ENAMEX>, the testimonial's credibility is undermined somewhat by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Skeens</ENAMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">princessy</ENAMEX> claim that she isn't willing to exercise and is "physically incapable
of dieting." On the other hand, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Skeens</ENAMEX> is precisely the sort of person
Metabolife markets its product to.) This is followed by an unfavorable review from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julie Cunningham-Potier</ENAMEX>, who claims that
Metabolife caused her to suffer <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> seizures and slip into a coma (she is now
suing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cunningham-Potier</ENAMEX>'s claim is followed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metabolife's Ellis</ENAMEX>
saying, on camera: "There's nothing in the medical records that indicate that
her condition was caused by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metabolife</ENAMEX>."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diaz then</ENAMEX> says that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20/20</NUMEX>
conducted a "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four-month</TIMEX>" investigation (TV <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> like to brag about how
long they spend on a story, a statistic that by itself means nothing) and was
"surprised at what we found" ("surprised" is a TV-news euphemism for
"appalled"). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diaz</ENAMEX> hits <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metabolife</ENAMEX> for saying that its product was determined by
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX> "to be safe." Not true, says <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Gwirtsman</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanderbilt</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Heymsfield</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Luke</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roosevelt</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX>, who helped conduct
the tests. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gwirtsman</ENAMEX> says the study he worked on involved <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> who took
Metabolife for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heymsfield</ENAMEX> says, "These
products may be safe in some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, but not all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>," and that side effects
such as <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">heart palpitations</ENAMEX> and sleeplessness may be harbingers of "potentially
more dangerous side effects, such as increases in blood pressure and pulse,
that in turn may led to problems like <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">heart attack</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stroke</ENAMEX>."

            At this point, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diaz</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Metabolife</ENAMEX> claims <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gwirtsman</ENAMEX> and
Heymsfield weren't principal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> in the
studies, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diaz</ENAMEX> goes on to say that their participation was confirmed by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanderbilt</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Luke's</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> never really thought they were making it
up) and that both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX> "requested that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metabolife</ENAMEX> stop using their
studies to claim the product is safe." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diaz</ENAMEX> saves for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">later in the</TIMEX> segment
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metabolife</ENAMEX>'s other significant counterattack, that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heymsfield</ENAMEX> is "a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">trustee</ENAMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slim-Fast Nutrition Institute</ENAMEX>," and that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slim-Fast</ENAMEX> is a Metabolife
competitor. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diaz</ENAMEX> counters that with a quotation from
a letter <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heymsfield</ENAMEX> wrote to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Luke</ENAMEX>'s general <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> that denies any bias
(not that anyone would expect him to admit any) and asserts that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metabolife</ENAMEX> is
"trying to suppress information regarding a potentially unsafe product."
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Incidentally, Chatterbox</ENAMEX> should confess here that in an earlier item, he said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellis</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diaz</ENAMEX> that "some of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diaz</ENAMEX> cited had economic ties to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metabolife</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX>; on closer
inspection of the raw transcript, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> now realizes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellis</ENAMEX> made that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">accusation</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">only about Heymsfield</NUMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metabolife</ENAMEX>'s
repetition of the reference to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heymsfield's Slim-Fast</ENAMEX> link, in notes
interspersed throughout the manuscript, tricked <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> into thinking,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mistakenly</ENAMEX>, that there was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Metabolife</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> who was receiving
payment from a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Metabolife</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rival</ENAMEX>.)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diaz</ENAMEX> then juxtaposes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ellis</ENAMEX>' assertion that a certain
health claim for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metabolife</ENAMEX> is "not on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metabolife Web</ENAMEX>--Web page," with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ellis</ENAMEX>' subsequent embarrassed admission, when presented with contrary evidence,
that "I don't know my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> Web site. ... I haven't even looked at it."
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> would have preferred <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diaz</ENAMEX> to use this marginally more embarrassing
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ellis</ENAMEX> quote, spotted in the unedited interview transcript: "You know, to be
honestly fair with you, I do not know what our Web site looks like.")

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diaz</ENAMEX> then trots off to interview <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stark</ENAMEX>, whom <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Metabolife "</ENAMEX>insisted we interview." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stark</ENAMEX> says that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metabolife</ENAMEX> is
"safe as--as any other <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">herb</ENAMEX>--or dietary product," but that larger studies are
needed to prove its safety. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diaz</ENAMEX> also gets <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stark</ENAMEX> to say that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metabolife</ENAMEX>'s
labeling "could be misleading" because it downplays the fact that it's been
tested on <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">lab animals</ENAMEX>, not <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX>. "Remember," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diaz</ENAMEX> gloats (who can blame
him?), "he's the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Metabolife</ENAMEX> referred us to."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diaz then</ENAMEX> says that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Food and Drug Administration</ENAMEX>
wants to impose "strict limits on the daily dosage" of ephedrine, the key
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ingredient</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Metabolife</ENAMEX>, though he concedes (as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ellis</ENAMEX> prodded him to do in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">unedited</ENAMEX> interview transcript) that "another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government agency</ENAMEX>" (he means the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Government Accounting Office</ENAMEX>) has criticized the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX>'s scientific findings.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diaz</ENAMEX> saves the nastiest part for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">next-to-last</TIMEX>. "[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">W</ENAMEX>]hat
do we know about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> behind <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Metabolife</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellis</ENAMEX> is a former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police officer</ENAMEX>
and real estate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> [this last strikes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> as a cheap shot] who, it
turns out, is also a convicted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">felon</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diaz</ENAMEX> says that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellis</ENAMEX> was arrested in
methamphetamine bust in history" (an interesting statistic that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diaz</ENAMEX> failed to
drop in his interview with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ellis</ENAMEX>), and that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ellis</ENAMEX> "pleaded guilty to a reduced
charge, using a telephone 'to facilitate a drug trafficking offense.' And got
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX>' probation."

            Oddly, this part of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20/20</NUMEX>
segment isn't quite as damaging to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellis</ENAMEX> as the raw interview transcript was.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diaz</ENAMEX> points out that ephedrine is "also a main ingredient in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Metabolife</ENAMEX>,"
though he duly notes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellis</ENAMEX>' claim that this is mere coincidence (he fails,
however, to repeat <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellis</ENAMEX>' assertion, apparently backed up by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DEA</ENAMEX>- and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX>-certified <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">labs</ENAMEX>, that you can't actually make
methamphetamine out of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metabolife</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diaz</ENAMEX> does not
quote, at full embarrassing length, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ellis</ENAMEX>' explanation that he got mixed up
with the wrong folk because one of them was "like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> to me." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diaz</ENAMEX> also
doesn't say, as he said in the raw interview transcript, that the lesser
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">offense Ellis</ENAMEX> pleaded guilty to was a felony. And--this is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellis</ENAMEX>' biggest break
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 20/20</TIMEX> segment--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diaz</ENAMEX> doesn't quote <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellis</ENAMEX>'
astonishing admission that until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a year ago</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fellow</ENAMEX> who was "like a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> to me," convicted with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ellis</ENAMEX> in his methamphetamine bust, was a partner
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Metabolife</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> had felt certain this damning fact would make the
cut, but it didn't.

            The segment wraps up with a review of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metabolife</ENAMEX>'s Web
campaign against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC News</ENAMEX> and gives the final word to the formerly comatose
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cunningham-Potier</ENAMEX>: "I wouldn't have taken it if I'd known the side effects,
because I almost didn't make it. I almost died."

            So who wins <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Round Two</ENAMEX>? It depends on how you score it.
If the question is whether <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC News</ENAMEX> ran a fair-minded expose, then <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC News</ENAMEX>
wins. If the question is whether <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metabolife</ENAMEX>'s online intimidation campaign got
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> to pull a punch or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> ... well, you could argue that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metabolife</ENAMEX> wins. If
the question is whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Metabolife</ENAMEX>'s raw transcript will come
away with a more favorable view of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> than if they just watch
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20/20</NUMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Metabolife</ENAMEX> clearly loses. And if the question
is whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> (who could stand to lose <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a few pounds</NUMEX>) will now ever be
tempted to try <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Metabolife</ENAMEX> as a product, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC News</ENAMEX> wins big.

         
      
   
