
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Meaning of the IBM Sell-Off</ENAMEX>
            

            It's hard to tell if this is still the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Era of Stock Market</ENAMEX> Good Feeling or
if a combination of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Y2K</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX>, rising interest rates, misreadings of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX>, and conventional "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX> is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a bad month</TIMEX> for stocks" has brought it
to a sudden end. What we seem to be living through right now is a strange time
in which the market is simultaneously being excoriated as overvalued and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hysterical</ENAMEX> and being described as being in a slump that forebodes bad
things ahead. Can't win for losing.

            As evidence of investor hysteria, the financial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> often point to things
like the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$40 billion</NUMEX> market-cap hit that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX> took at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of last week</TIMEX>,
after it announced that it would have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>, and perhaps <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>, disappointing
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">quarters in a row</TIMEX> because its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> were cutting back on spending in order
to take care of potential <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Y2K</NUMEX> problems. Momentum <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> pile into a stock,
the narrative goes, and then pile out of it without paying any attention to the
fundamentals, so that good buy-and-hold <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> get whipsawed for no good
reason.

            But what happened to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, far from being evidence of a flighty
stock market, was instead a sign of just how discriminating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> have
become. If stock prices really were being driven solely by inflated margin
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">balances</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">overconfidence</ENAMEX> bred by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20 percent</NUMEX> plus returns, you'd
expect <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> to be forgiving. In fact, they are more punitive then ever.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Investors</ENAMEX> are willing to pay high prices for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> that deliver consistent
above-average cash-flow growth. But if there are signs that a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s ability
to deliver that kind of growth may be faltering--and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX>'s announcement was a
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vegas</ENAMEX>-style neon sign to that effect--then the market will pummel a stock
quickly.

            The speed with which a negative earnings report can vaporize a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s
market cap is also sometimes held up as problematic. But here again, it's no
surprise that in a world in which trading costs are minuscule, the diffusion of
information nearly instantaneous, and trading volume immense, prices will
change very fast in the wake of significant news. This just means that markets
are more efficient, not less, in the sense that they establish a new
equilibrium price--or as close to it as they can ever get--in the space of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">day</ENAMEX>, and not a week. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX>'s stock price bumped up a little bit on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, but
stayed steady <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, which suggests that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>'s sell-off was not some
massive overreaction.

            The most important thing about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX> sell-off, though, was what it
wasn't , namely an impetus for a more general sell-off in technology. In
the past (and even the recent past), we've seen announcements like the one that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Blue</ENAMEX> made have a ripple effect on tech stocks across the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX>, as momentum
and program <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traders</ENAMEX> bailed out of anything that might suffer from association
with a big name's blowup. But <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> rather quickly recognized
that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX>'s problems seemed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>-specific, and that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> that had
reported excellent earnings during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX>--like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX>--should be bought, not
sold. In other words, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> rewarded the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> that should have been
rewarded and punished those that should have been punished. Capital was
allocated sensibly, rather than hysterically.

            There are, of course, always going to be under- and overreactions, like the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> that victimized <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tyco</ENAMEX> or the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> that sent the stock of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cisco</ENAMEX> (which I own shares of) plummeting on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>
after an unsubstantiated rumor that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> would miss estimates hit the
Street. But what <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s action suggested is that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> (or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">10</NUMEX>, or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">17</NUMEX>,
depending on how you're counting) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> of a bull market have not made
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> careless or blinded by success. Eternal vigilance ... Well, something
like that.

         
      
   
