
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bushes: A Whole New Teeming Clan</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Ted</ENAMEX>:

             Thinking about all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cult-</ENAMEX>of-celebrity
stories <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are writing now and how frightened <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> are at the prospect of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">wrestlers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">developers</ENAMEX>, and movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> entering politics. I remember all the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Murphy</ENAMEX> and early <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> jokes (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jack Warner</ENAMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">No</ENAMEX>, not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy Stewart</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX> as his best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>").
When you think about it, none of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> current "serious" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> arrived at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fame</ENAMEX> through public-policy acumen. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> had famous (eponymous)
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">daddies</ENAMEX>. And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> was a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">hoop wizard</ENAMEX>. Once in the public eye, these fellows
parlayed their chips. It's like all of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> society, really. Privilege has
its advantages, as they say. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Famous sons</ENAMEX> of famous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> are remarkable when they
don't take their place at the top of things. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">JFK Jr.</ENAMEX> was remarkable for not
being remarkable. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Folks</ENAMEX> couldn't get over that he wasn't in office or, at
least, in the movies. His death reminded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later</TIMEX> chapters of his
life were not going to play out as they had dreamed them. I don't think we ever
completely got over the allure of royalty. Our favorite soap operas seem to be
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about dynasties</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generations</ENAMEX> handing down traditions of abuse and debauchery of
various kinds.

             So, I think Georgie excites us with the notion of
the whole teeming <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clan</ENAMEX> moving back into the limelight. It won't be the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">stale Bush</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> we knew. We now have a panoply of archetypes we know
and are, I think, already responding to. The young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slacker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>, called by his
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, avenging his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> against the sinful pretender. The ardent, pious
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, taming the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prince</ENAMEX>, guiding him to his glorious destiny. The
chuckle-headed old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX>, jumping from <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX>, bouncing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandchildren</ENAMEX> on his
knee. The powerful and benevolent queen mum. The equally ambitious younger
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> who will not take a cabinet post (will there be family rivalry?). And
finally, the two beautiful twin <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX>. Who will date and/or bed them and
move in to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">circle</ENAMEX>? Ah, we breathlessly await the next exciting episode.

            How could <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren Beatty</ENAMEX>, let alone any of the others compete, with that? You
say it's policy you want to discuss? Campaign-finance reform? Welfare? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAFTA</ENAMEX>?
What <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX> are you watching?

            Don't wake me,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
