
   
   
      
         
            Word Wars
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Dennis</ENAMEX>,

            The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last few weeks</TIMEX> have been good ones for popular discussion of language.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> is suing a TV show for using his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>'s name to
refer to a sex act; a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> chosen to run one of the world's largest law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX>
has decided to refer to herself as "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX>"; and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Helms</ENAMEX> used the
delightful word "floccinaucinihilipilification," the longest word in the first
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>.

            I hope we can talk about some of these issues <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>. But the one thing
that's been most striking recently is the response to an "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">On Language"</ENAMEX> column
by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Margalit Fox</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Magazine</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ms Fox</ENAMEX>, filling in for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Safire</ENAMEX>, wrote about a common "language myth": that some dialects are
intrinsically better than others.

            Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fox</ENAMEX>, citing various linguists and explaining things quite clearly, said
that negative reactions to nonstandard dialects are the result of social
factors, not linguistic ones; the dialects--whether "ebonics," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brooklynese</ENAMEX>, or
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Jennings</ENAMEX>'--are just as regular and logical as any other variety of
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>.

            To us, as linguists, this is familiar and noncontroversial. I had thought
that Ms <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX>'s presentation would be viewed by the general <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> as
noncontroversial as well, but I was mistaken: The letters column <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> had
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">no fewer than six</NUMEX> angry letters, calling us "intellectual diddlers" and
"well-paid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">academic theorists</ENAMEX>" who "confine" our "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> to minimum-wage
jobs." It was even implied that considering dialects to be linguistically equal
was a "pernicious threat to common sense, logic, science and our basic
political freedoms." (Who knew?)

            It would seem that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> of such letters themselves lack common sense,
or at least the ability to understand simple language. Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fox</ENAMEX> was very clear
that languages were considered equal "on purely linguistic grounds," and that
value judgments were "socially determined." The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">linguists</ENAMEX> who spoke in favor of
diversity were certainly not advocating the abandonment of language teaching,
just a better understanding of how language works.

            It's too bad that a genuine effort to spread this understanding has to meet
with such hostility, don't you think?

            Best,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
