
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX>?
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Clark</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dennis Rodman</ENAMEX>: I like that analogy of yours, but I also think
that in using it, you've stumbled across the biggest problem with <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The New</ENAMEX>
New <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Thing</ENAMEX> . (See? There I go again.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dennis Rodman</ENAMEX> is (or, rather, was) the
most colorful, bizarre and interesting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> in professional <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX>--and
he was also a helluva <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">talent</ENAMEX>. You could undoubtedly write a more interesting
book about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodman</ENAMEX> than you could about, say, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Jordan</ENAMEX>--who, despite being
the greatest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> of all time, is bland as toast off the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>, and a tougher
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">nut</ENAMEX> to crack in any case. It takes a lot of work to write about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jordan</ENAMEX>. Even
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Halberstam</ENAMEX>, who wrote a book about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX>'s exploits during his last
season, couldn't wrest an interview from him. But if you were to decide that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodman</ENAMEX> was your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subject</ENAMEX>--and why not, since he's so much more fun to write
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about</TIMEX>, and since he's also much more accessible than <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jordan</ENAMEX>?--could you then
say that your book was about <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Man Who Single-handedly Changed Professional</ENAMEX>
Basketball? Nobody would dare make such a claim, would they?

            Yet isn't that what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Lewis</ENAMEX> has done here? His main <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>--nay,
his only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>--is truly fascinating. He's deeply eccentric. He
boils over with absurd resentments. He bubbles over with interesting ideas. He
spends half the book building the biggest <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">yacht</ENAMEX> in the world. He must have been
a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">ton</NUMEX> of fun to write about. (And he was accessible to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>!) But can it
truly be claimed--as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX>, in fact, claims--that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Clark</ENAMEX>, more than any
other single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>, shaped the current ethos of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Silicon Valley</ENAMEX>? Or is it more
likely that having landed his subject, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> created a thesis to justify his
choice?

            My own suspicion is that the truth is closer to the latter than the former.
This is not to say that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX> isn't a big deal, but there are others who are
bigger deals, and have done more to change the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX> than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX>. The venture
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">capitalist John Doerr</ENAMEX> springs instantly to mind. In addition, there are a ton
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> at play that conspired to create modern <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Silicon Valley</ENAMEX>. My guess is
that the various changes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> documents would have happened with or without
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Clark</ENAMEX>.

            Of course, the biggest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">force</ENAMEX> was (and is) the Internet. Here <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> would
probably point out that as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-founder</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Netscape</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX> played a
singularly important role in making the Internet a mass-market medium, which is
what changed everything. (And oh, how I longed for a detailed inside history of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Netscape</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The New New Thing</ENAMEX> . But, alas, it was nowhere to be found. As
you correctly pointed out, once <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX> loses interest, so does <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX>.) But
Mosaic, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> browser, had already been invented by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marc Andreessen</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-founder</ENAMEX>. And as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> himself points out, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX>'s greatest
contribution with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Netscape</ENAMEX>--the actual thing he did that made the biggest
change in the way <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Silicon Valley</ENAMEX> works--was to take it public before it was
profitable. Once that offering took off, it was as if a light bulb went off all
over the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">YOU DIDN'T HAVE TO HAVE A PROFITABLE COMPANY TO GET RICH</ENAMEX>! What
an insight! What caused <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX> to have this insight? Here, I'm afraid, is where
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> loses me completely. He says that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX> pushed for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Netscape</ENAMEX> IPO because
he wanted to build a new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX>, and this was the only way he could think to pay
for it. I'm sorry, I just couldn't buy that one. Could you?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX>, in fact, is such a one-of-a-kind <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> that he doesn't really
stand in for any <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Silicon Valley</ENAMEX> "type." "I can't be a venture capitalist
because I'm not that kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX> tells <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point. "And I
can't be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX>, because I'm not that kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>. All I can do is start
them." That's the claim <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX> makes for himself. But then <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> goes on to
write, "His role in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX> was suddenly clear: he was the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> of the
story. He was the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> with the nerve to invent the tale in which all the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>--the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineers</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VCs</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bankers</ENAMEX>--agreed to play
the role he assigned to them." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Clark</ENAMEX>? Maybe you could say that about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">J.P.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morgan</ENAMEX> once upon a time. (Or is that journalistic myth-making, too?) But that
kind of claim for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX> just doesn't hold up, at least not to my mind.

            There is one way <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX>. In his open lust for
money, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX> is willing to say out loud what everyone else there thinks--but
doesn't dare say. And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> captures that exquisitely. There is another of
those wonderful <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> scenes in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX> is saying that if only he can be
richer than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Ellison</ENAMEX>, who's worth <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$9 billion</NUMEX>, he'll stop. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> reminds
him that not long ago, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX> had said he would be satisfied with "<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 billion</NUMEX>
after taxes." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX> just shrugs. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> asks him if he wants more than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX> laughs off the suggestion as ludicrous. But <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a few minutes</TIMEX> later he
adds, "You know, just for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one moment</TIMEX>, I would kind of like to have the most.
Just for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> tiny moment." Beautiful.

            I wind up thinking that to really enjoy <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The New New Thing</ENAMEX> , you have
to forget about the claim the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> is making for his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subject</ENAMEX> and simply revel
in scenes like that one. But for me, at least, that's awfully hard to do. I
keep seeing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dennis Rodman</ENAMEX> being described as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Jordan</ENAMEX>.

            P.S.: I realize that we haven't yet talked about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">MyCFO</ENAMEX>, and I promise to get
to that tommorrow. In the meantime, though, I couldn't help noticing that just
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX> brought on a senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Charles Schwab</ENAMEX> to be the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX>.
Betcha they're already planning the IPO.

         
      
   
