
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cartoon</ENAMEX> Mayor
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Steve</ENAMEX>:

            I couldn't agree with you more about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX> and
his hollow showboating regarding the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brooklyn Museum</ENAMEX> controversy. While much of
what passes for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 th -century</TIMEX> modern art is
absolutely horseshit--painting an entire canvas red is mere laziness, and
claiming that it has meaning doesn't make it so--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX> seems determined to
base his whole political career on crushing the messy process that is popular
culture and scapegoating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> too weak to defend themselves.

            As <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">New Yorkers</ENAMEX> will recall, he launched his career by
going after homeless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> who spritz your windshield at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">intersections</ENAMEX> and
demand a buck to finish the job. OK, so they were annoying, but there are crack
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> that have enjoyed continuous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX>
has been after the squeegee <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>. Then he put all the accouterments of street
life out of business--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newsstands</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hotdog</ENAMEX> stands, street <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">vendors</ENAMEX>--all of which
gave <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sidewalk</ENAMEX>-level buzz that separated it from your average
suburban <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mall</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX> he attacked <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">taxi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX> with fines for
speeding--frankly, any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cabby</ENAMEX> who can speed in these
choked <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> gets an extra tip from yours truly--and an array of nuisance
regulations designed to make their lives impossible. I drove a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cab</ENAMEX> for years
and thought it was too hard for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$150</NUMEX> a shift; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> you're lucky if you
make <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$60</NUMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">12 hours</TIMEX> of backbreaking through the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX>. What
kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bully</ENAMEX> picks on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> who earn <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five bucks an hour</TIMEX>?

            More frightening, he's turned <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Times Square</ENAMEX> and its
menagerie of wonderful filth and decadence into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney World North</ENAMEX>. The porn
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> are all but gone, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">nightclubs</ENAMEX> find it nearly impossible to function after
getting busted all the time, and now he's stopping the rent check to the
biggest cultural <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brooklyn</ENAMEX>. What always made <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> great was
its anarchic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">brew</ENAMEX> of mayhem and energy; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX> is determined to replace both
with sterility and bourgeois consumerism.

            OK, back to comic strips. After <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s missive, a
number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> e-mailed me to remind me of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott Adams</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dilbert</ENAMEX> --and of course, it's a great <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">strip</ENAMEX>. It speaks to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">cubical</ENAMEX> culture in which many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>, including me until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years ago</TIMEX>,
spend <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two-thirds</NUMEX> of their waking <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX>, and does so with consistently funny gag
lines. Still, there's quite a bit of repetition there, too, which I think is
inevitable. How can anyone draw <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">365</NUMEX> cartoons a year for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 years</TIMEX> or more and
have each idea be original? I think that's why recent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">giants</ENAMEX> like Watterson
( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Calvin</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hobbes</ENAMEX> ) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larson</ENAMEX> ( The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Far Side</ENAMEX> ) quit after roughly <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a decade</TIMEX> each--you get pretty
tapped out at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3,000-plus</NUMEX> ideas, and they had the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> to recognize that.
Moreover, the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> are constantly shrinking the space available for
comic strips, which means that it's impossible to stretch out artistically.

            Ah, I'd forgotten all about editorial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cartoonist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ranan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lurie</ENAMEX>, for whom I once toiled as a graphics <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assistant</ENAMEX> (wage: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5</NUMEX> an hour, no
benefits, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX>) for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two months</TIMEX>, until you retrieved my repressed memories.
Fortunately, I don't read papers where he appears, but his work is trite,
appallingly apolitical, and graphically bereft of any character whatsoever.
Even worse, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> never paid me for thinking up ideas, crosshatching,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">etc.</ENAMEX>--yo, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ranan</ENAMEX>, with interest that comes to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> the value of your <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trump</ENAMEX> Tower
apartment now. I need the cash for drawing lessons, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>.

            But the greatest conflict in cartooning is about which
is more important: Ideas or drawing. It helps when a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">creator</ENAMEX> enjoys both a muse
and a good hand (as you do, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX>), but the vast majority of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cartoonists</ENAMEX> are
lucky to have one or the other. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Editors</ENAMEX>, it seems, lean more to the graphics
side, but I think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larson</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Thurber</ENAMEX> prove that you can draw
great cartoons with lousy art. I have yet to find a great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cartoonist</ENAMEX> with bad
or nonexistent ideas. In my case, I know that the art has always been my weak
point, which is why I developed a highly stylized drawing style (it also helps
to set it apart from the donkey-and-elephant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> of editorial cartoonists)
and why I still take drawing lessons and study everything from old woodcuts to
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cuban</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">comics</ENAMEX>. I can't understand gifted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> who intentionally draw less
well than they're able to; it's a form of self-mutilation. As for the ideas,
either you have them or you don't, and there isn't much you can do about it
either way.

            Speaking of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Max</ENAMEX>, I hear he's made sort of a
comeback on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '70s</TIMEX> nostalgia bandwagon--he even had some show <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years</TIMEX>
back in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Des Moines</ENAMEX>, of all places.

            Very truly yours,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
