
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Busting Bush</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Biographer</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fortunate Son</ENAMEX>:

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> and the Making of an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>
By <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J.H. Hatfield</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Martin's Press</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25.95</NUMEX>

            The newest <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biographer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J.H. Hatfield</ENAMEX>, claims to
have the goods on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">front-runner</ENAMEX>'s druggie past. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>-based
free-lance <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> alleges that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> was arrested for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX> possession in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1972</TIMEX>, but that his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daddy</ENAMEX> got a friendly state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> to expunge the record in
exchange for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">W.</ENAMEX>'s performing community service in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> mentoring program
called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">PULL</ENAMEX>. The author writes that he discovered this scandal only after his
book was in galleys, which is why the accusation is tacked on as an afterword
to what is otherwise a shoddy clip job with no fresh news.

            Should we believe this story? I don't think so. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>, who has written for various B-list <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX> and previously
published a biography of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Star Trek</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patrick</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stewart</ENAMEX>, has no actual evidence to support his charge. And while essentially
asking us to trust him, he provides a multitude of reasons for thinking he
should not be trusted. ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Editor</ENAMEX>'s note : On
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Martin's Press</ENAMEX> announced it was "suspending" publication of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fortunate Son</ENAMEX> because of questions about the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">afterword</ENAMEX>'s accuracy and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>'s criminal record. Click here for more.)

            For starters, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hatfield</ENAMEX> lacks all the kinds of details
that might make it possible to check the story. Among other things, he is
missing the name of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> who supposedly let <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> off, the name of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">arresting officer</ENAMEX>, the police <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">station</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the date</TIMEX> and circumstances of the
arrest. What he claims to have are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>. Naturally, they're all
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">anonymous</ENAMEX> (making this a good example of the kind of story that wouldn't meet
the evidentiary standards of the cheesiest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> but that presents no
problem for a "reputable" book <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publisher</ENAMEX>). When I reached <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hatfield</ENAMEX> at his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">publisher</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>, he told me that these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> are all old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> who have
contemporaneous, independent knowledge of the alleged arrest, but that none
would provide specifics for fear of being identified by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>. Here's how he
describes them in the book:

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. A "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classmate</ENAMEX>" and "family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>" who "partied
with the future <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> and presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late sixties</TIMEX>
and early seventies in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX>."

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. A "longtime <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> and unofficial political
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adviser</ENAMEX> who had known the presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several years</TIMEX>."

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. A "high-ranking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adviser</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> who had known the
presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several years</TIMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hatfield</ENAMEX> says this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">source</ENAMEX> agreed to
confirm information in the book and spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three days</TIMEX> bass fishing with him in
Eufaula, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Okla.</ENAMEX>

                

            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hatfield</ENAMEX> writes that he contacted these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> after
reading a story in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Salon</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX> reporting on an e-mail rumor. Salon amplified its own unsubstantiated gossip by reporting on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hatfield</ENAMEX>'s unsupported charges with another uncritical story <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>. But
what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hatfield</ENAMEX> claims these "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>" told him is implausible. Why would three
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> want to supply a hostile <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> with information that would
destroy their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>'s candidacy? More significant, when I questioned <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hatfield</ENAMEX>
about his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>, he acknowledged that some of what he says about them in the
book isn't true.

            For example: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hatfield</ENAMEX> recounts calling Source No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> to
ask him to confirm the story he has from the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>. His "Eufaula
Connection" calls him back <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">half an hour later</TIMEX>. Here's what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hatfield</ENAMEX> writes
about what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eufaula</ENAMEX> told him:

            

               "I can't and won't give you any names, but I can confirm
that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">W.</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> remains the repository of any evidence of the
expunged record. From what I've been told, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> is the one who advised
him to get a new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX>'s license in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> when a survey of his public records
uncovered a stale but nevertheless incriminating trail for an overly eager
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> to follow," he said, pausing occasionally to spit <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco juice</ENAMEX> into
the ever-present <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Styrofoam cup</ENAMEX>.

            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Spitting tobacco juice</ENAMEX> into the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Styrofoam cup</ENAMEX> is a nice
detail. But how, I asked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hatfield</ENAMEX>, could he see his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX> doing this in what
he described as a telephone conversation? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hatfield</ENAMEX> made a spitting noise into
the phone, and said that he knew the source chewed <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco</ENAMEX> because he had spent
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> with him. But then he added: "I might have put that in to protect him. He
doesn't chew <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco</ENAMEX>--I had to help him out a bit." This is quite an admission.
Nowhere in the book does <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hatfield</ENAMEX> warn the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> that he has altered details
or created composite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> to protect his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>. His admission about
Source No. 3 raises the question of what else in his book is fictional.

            Or what, if anything, in the book isn't fictional. Anyone with a nose for cooked quotes should be able
to detect the distinct odor of journalistic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jambalaya</ENAMEX> coming from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hatfield</ENAMEX>'s
book. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">All three</NUMEX> of his arrest-story "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>" speak in a stilted,
too-perfectly-advancing-the-story-line way, telling the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> more or less the
same thing, and congratulating him on his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX> in ferreting out this facts.
Here are some of their quotes.

            

               Source <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>: "I was wondering when someone was going to get
around to uncovering the truth," he replied, surprisingly unruffled by my
direct approach. ... "There's only a handful of us that know the truth."

               Source <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>: "Take this any way it sounds, but do you think
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX> would take time out from speeding around <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> in his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TR-6</ENAMEX> convertible
sports <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>, bedding down just about every single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>--and few married
ones--and partying like there's no <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX> to go work full-time as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mentor</ENAMEX> to
a bunch of streetwise black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>? Get real, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, this is a white-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> from
the other side of town we're talking about. ... The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>, a good ol' <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>
and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX>'s politically influential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daddy</ENAMEX>, purged the record. It
happened a lot in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX> damn sure wasn't the first rich
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> who got caught with a little snow and because of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>'s connections
had his record taken care of by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>."

               Source <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>: "Be careful and watch your back every step of
the way," he warned, speaking almost in a whisper. "Without sounding paranoid,
I think I would be amiss if I didn't remind you that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX>'s old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> was
once <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>. Shit, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, they named the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> after the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> not
too long ago. Besides, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">W.</ENAMEX>'s raised almost a staggering <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">sixty million dollars</NUMEX>
for his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> run in a matter of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only a few months</TIMEX> and his corporate
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sponsors</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> fat <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX> aren't going to roll over and play dead when you
expose the truth about their investment. ... You know what makes me sick about
all this shit? It's the hypocrisy. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Cocaine</ENAMEX> use is illegal, but as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>, he's toughened penalties for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> convicted of selling or possessing
less than a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">gram</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">coke</ENAMEX> (a crime previously punished by probation). Ok'd the
housing of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixteen-year-olds</TIMEX> in adult correctional <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> and slashed
funding for inmate substance abuse-programs. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas</ENAMEX> currently spends <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over one</NUMEX>
point <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five million dollars</NUMEX> per day keeping <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offenders</ENAMEX> behind bars and
another <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty</TIMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">eight thousand dollars</NUMEX> a day incarcerating young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on drug
offenses," he said angrily.

                

            

            You can't prove that someone made up quotes from an
anonymous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX>, just as you can't prove you never got arrested and had the
record expunged. But these passages sound about as authentic as a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>-dollar
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bill</ENAMEX>. The anachronistic colloquial expressions ("bedding down," "a little
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">snow</ENAMEX>," "shit, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>"), the insertion of gratuitous detail ("his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TR-6</ENAMEX> convertible
sports <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>," "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five million</NUMEX> dollars"), and the utterly
non-conversational tone ("raised almost a staggering <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">sixty million</NUMEX> dollars")
all make me suspicious. Another tip-off is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hatfield</ENAMEX> doesn't discuss his
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> high-level, inside-the-enemy-camp <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> of the book, which
was already in galleys when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> made his "discovery."

            The story reminds me, in fact, of another great episode
in left-wing wishful thinking involving the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>--the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX> Surprise.
That scandal, you may remember, featured the elder <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> secretly flying not to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> but to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 1980</TIMEX> to cut a deal with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iranian</ENAMEX> mullahs so
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hostages</ENAMEX> would not be released before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Election Day</TIMEX>--thus,
according to the theory, ensuring <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX>'s victory over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy Carter</ENAMEX>.
Like that story, this one comes replete with a cloak-and-dagger fantasy in
which the truth-seeking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> (in this case the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> of the
X-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Files Encyclopedia</ENAMEX> ) faces danger from shadowy
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conspirators</ENAMEX> for attempting to expose the truth.

            What the two fantasies have in common is that neither
can be either confirmed or proved definitively false. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Reporters</ENAMEX> can't
double-check <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hatfield</ENAMEX>'s work, because he offers nothing but anonymous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>.
And while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> can deny <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hatfield</ENAMEX>'s accusations, as he already has (calling them
"totally ridiculous" and "not true"), he can't prove that something never
happened <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">27 years ago</TIMEX>.

            In fact, we should credit the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">campaign</ENAMEX>'s denial.
Why? Because if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> was arrested in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1972</TIMEX>, any number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would have to
know about it--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one or more</NUMEX> police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>, and so on. There's no way <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> could be sure that someone with actual
evidence wouldn't come forward. And while he might survive an admission of
guilt about something stupid he did <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">27 years ago</TIMEX>, he would be far less likely
to get away with a cover-up in the midst of a campaign. In other words, if the
story had any truth to it, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> would be fatally compounding his problem by
pulling a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> really is on an accelerated schedule. He already
has his <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Aldrich</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
