
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Que Happenin</ENAMEX>'?
            

            Good <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse</ENAMEX>:

            It's no surprise to me that there are language issues in the news. In my
experience, everybody--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> and amateur alike--has something to say about the
state of the language.

            For example, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> has a story on the need to know <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> if
you live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> (front page, above the fold)--can it be that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> is
replacing <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> as the prestige second <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">language</ENAMEX>? And <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Education Week</ENAMEX>
is planning to test <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">schoolchildren</ENAMEX> on their knowledge of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAEP</ENAMEX> regularly tests reading, writing, and math, issuing national report cards
on how our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> are doing in these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX>. The "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">1998 Writing Report Card</ENAMEX>,"
which came out just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX>, reported this scary news: The writing ability
of half the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">schoolchildren</ENAMEX> is below average! Anyway, the proposed test
of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> will be the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAEP</ENAMEX>'s first foreign-language test. Other minority
languages are also in the news. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arizona Republic</ENAMEX> reports on the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> urban high-school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Navajo</ENAMEX> language, a move to stem the loss
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navajo</ENAMEX> among the young <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Native Americans</ENAMEX> who move to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yesterday</TIMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> carried an article on minority-language revival in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Europe</ENAMEX>--particularly <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Breton</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Academy</ENAMEX> objects
that this will only dilute the purity of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX>). And the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chronicle</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whatshappenin</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX> is suing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quepasa</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> for trademark
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">infringement</ENAMEX>, arguing that "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Que pasa?</ENAMEX>" has become so transparent that we all
know it means "What's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">happenin</ENAMEX>'<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>" As a predictable response to this resurgence
of interest in minority languages, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Toledo Blade</ENAMEX> runs a letter
urging that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> become the official language of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. As if a law
could get <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to alter their language.

            But back to your comments. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yesterday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ran another
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>, and on political slang in general. And I know that you
commented on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> in a recent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Post</ENAMEX> story. Speaking of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>, I happened by sheer accident to be spacing out in front of the TV
last night watching a rerun on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Network of Law</ENAMEX> & Order: Special
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Victims Unit</ENAMEX> , when I heard the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> reference that sparked the senior
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s lawsuit. I found it amusing that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> of this new series
chose a euphemism where elsewhere they have been much more blunt. (Of course,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">series</ENAMEX> title, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Special Victims Unit</ENAMEX> , is itself a euphemism: It refers
to sex crimes, something that didn't occur to me till I saw the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> episode.)
Clearly they used "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>" for political shock value, and to draw attention
to their new show--and why, I ask you, is a brand-new show already in reruns on
a competing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX>? Anyway, I don't think "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>," as a verb or a noun, has
the staying power of something like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heimlich</ENAMEX>, another eponym (word named after
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>, for those who are reading over our shoulders) involving <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>
doing something physical to another. Of course, while a future episode of
Special <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Victims Unit</ENAMEX> may choose to become more explicit about this
maneuver, you won't see diagrams of how to perform a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX>
all over the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>.

            As for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Margalit Fox</ENAMEX> article you mention, I did read it and found it an
interesting summary of what we might call "the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">linguist</ENAMEX>'s dilemma": <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> want
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">linguists</ENAMEX> to tell them how to be correct, but at the same time, they resist
intervention, taking the attitude, "Who are you to tell me what to do?" It may
seem like a no-win situation for us. But it's also possible to see this as a
natural part of the linguistic give and take (or what a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">theorist</ENAMEX> might call the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">social</ENAMEX> construction of language).

            I missed the angry response letters to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX> essay. Maybe they didn't
print them in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Midwest</ENAMEX> edition of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , or maybe I was absent
that day. But they don't surprise me. I get angry mail every time I try to
point out <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s inconsistent language attitudes. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last month</TIMEX> I wrote an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Op-Ed</ENAMEX>
piece about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisiana</ENAMEX>'s new law requiring <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> to call their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> "Sir"
or "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Ma'am</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisiana</ENAMEX> state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX> who drafted the law said there
was a similar requirement in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prisons</ENAMEX>, and he thought it worked so
well he wanted to extend it to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>. In my essay I pointed out that
language is difficult to regulate: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> just don't want to use language the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> tell them to. I also observed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> used to want schools
to be less like <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prisons</ENAMEX>, but that now the trend seems to be to make them more
like <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prisons</ENAMEX>, adding language regulation to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> control, uniforms, metal
detectors, and locker searches. In response, I got an angry letter from a
reader telling me I ought to be in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> for writing what I did.

            So I have come to realize, over a long career of such angry letters, that
part of my job is to encourage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to look critically at language use, and
part of my job is to get <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> angry.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dennis</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
