
   
   
      
         
            Welcome to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Economy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dow Jones</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kicking</ENAMEX> and screaming, the Dow Jones Industrial Average is slowly finding
its way into the late <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 th century</TIMEX>, even as the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">st</ENAMEX> gets
set to arrive. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s announcement that, as of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union Carbide</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sears</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chevron</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goodyear</ENAMEX> will be replaced by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Home Depot</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SBC Communications</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intel</ENAMEX> (the latter <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> being the first <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nasdaq</ENAMEX> stocks ever to
appear in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dow</ENAMEX>) is fine testimony to what all of us already knew: that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> economy has changed dramatically in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last two decades</TIMEX>, and that former
industrial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">powerhouses</ENAMEX> have been superseded by the avatars of the New
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Economy</ENAMEX>.

            Actually, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dow</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> are avatars of the old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Economy</ENAMEX>, since there's nary an Internet or telecom-equipment manufacturer among
them. But when you consider that it took <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dow Jones</ENAMEX> until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> to take <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bethlehem</ENAMEX>
Steel, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> whose industrial fortunes peaked sometime back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1930s</TIMEX>,
out of the index, getting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> in there <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13 years</TIMEX> after it went public has
to be seen as a minor success. Of course, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> also has the largest market
capitalization of any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> in the world. So the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dow</ENAMEX> isn't exactly going out
on a limb.

            The striking thing about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s announcement is that changes in the Dow
still make headlines, not because they happen so often (actually, they happen
very rarely) but because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dow</ENAMEX> is such an arbitrary collection of names to
begin with. Any index is arbitrary in its inclusion and exclusion of names. But
the Dow's size--it has just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>--magnifies the effect of its
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">arbitrariness</ENAMEX>. Looking to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> to decipher the underlying health of the
stock market, let alone of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> economy as a whole, is senseless. Yet it
remains true that for many, if not most, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>, the stock market is
the Dow.

            That's had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> contradictory consequences in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX>. On the one hand,
it's led <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to overestimate the nature of this bull market, especially in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>. The average <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Stock Exchange</ENAMEX> stock, for instance, is now <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX>
percent off its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">52-week</TIMEX> high, while the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">S&P 500</ENAMEX> is up <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">just 5 percent</NUMEX> for
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX>. The Dow, however, is up <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">12 percent</NUMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX>, and when it hit
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11,000</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> everywhere proclaimed--depending upon their bullishness and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bearishness</ENAMEX>--this a milestone. In reality, it was a milestone only for this
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX> stocks (and a changeable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> at that). There are no broader
conclusions to be drawn from their performance. And the same will be true if
the Dow slips below <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10,000</NUMEX>.

            The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> consequence is that the focus on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dow</ENAMEX> has led <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to
underestimate the performance of corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>. There are a lot of terrific
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dow</ENAMEX>. But if you just look at the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> that will be
leaving on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> and the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> that will be arriving, there is simply
no comparison between them in terms of business fundamentals. The incoming
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> have rapid growth in revenue and in cash flow, and extraordinarily
high returns on invested capital. The outgoing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> have slow growth and
low (in some cases, perhaps even negative) returns on invested capital. Was the
Dow overvalued at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11,000</NUMEX>? I don't know, but I'm sure it's a lot less likely to
be overvalued with its new lineup in there.

            This is not news to the stock market as a whole. The outgoing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> have
an average market capitalization of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$21 billion</NUMEX>, while the incoming companies
have an average market cap of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$236 billion</NUMEX>, even though the average revenues of
the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> are not that distinct. You could see this as yet more evidence
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> are too reckless. But it's better evidence that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dow Jones</ENAMEX> is
only now realizing what the market as a whole has understood for most of this
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decade</TIMEX>.

         
      
   
