
   
   
      
         
            Are Some <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Languages Dangerous</ENAMEX>?
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse</ENAMEX>:

            Yes, it's ironic, but predictable, that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> express
ambivalence toward <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> or heritage languages: They attack languages such as
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Spanish</ENAMEX> that they perceive as a threat, while defending "cute" languages like
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boontling</ENAMEX> (you and I are may be the only ones in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> who know what
that is) or "antique" languages like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cornish</ENAMEX>.

            Yet even that picture is not so clear: If <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anglo</ENAMEX> parents
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> are choosing to have their very young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> begin the study of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX>, as the article in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
indicates, does this mean, as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> suggests, that they have come
to value multilingualism, or does it mean they are just being practical? And
how does that stack up against research indicating that second-generation
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Latinos</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Latinas</ENAMEX> are often monolingual <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speakers</ENAMEX>? I've collected lots
of anecdotal newspaper stories in which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miami</ENAMEX>, for example, claim
they can't find <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speakers</ENAMEX>, let alone bilinguals, to hire to deal with
their <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish-speaking</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clientele</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navajo</ENAMEX> has long been touted by sociolinguists as a
language whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speakers</ENAMEX> maintain a great deal of language loyalty, that is, the
Navajo are reluctant to give up their heritage language. Yet the need to
establish a high-school <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Navajo</ENAMEX> class suggests that off the reservation, that is
exactly what young <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Navajo</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speakers</ENAMEX> are doing. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hasidim of New York</ENAMEX> and the
Amish are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> known for preserving their speech--when, that is,
they maintain their social isolation from the mainstream. But once that
isolation is gone, language may soon follow.

            Cultural-loyalty movements like the class in Navajo
tend to spring up when cultural preservation is in danger, and their record of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">success</ENAMEX> is not impressive. Here at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Illinois</ENAMEX>, we run special
sections of <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>- and second-year <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX>-heritage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>, and
the reason is that their <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> is too weak to meet academic requirements.
That in turn means they may be able to speak <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Spanish</ENAMEX> (even that is often not
the case); but they can't read it well or write it fluently, and their grasp of
its grammar may be weak, since they haven't actually studied it as a language.
They may speak some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX>, but they can't pass a test in it. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Students</ENAMEX> also
use college language <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">classrooms</ENAMEX> to try to recapture the heritage languages they
may have lost (for example, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hindi</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Urdu</ENAMEX>), or ones they may never have
acquired (<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Yiddish</ENAMEX>).

            What interests me about these minority language and
dialect matters is why ebonics was perceived as so great a threat when the
whole issue arose in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late 1996</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oakland</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX> We are living in a time when
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">English</ENAMEX> serves as an international language. Furthermore, living as we do in a
(largely) postcolonial world, we tend to recognize that each national variety
of <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>, that of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>, of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nigeria</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX>, has its own local standards, and we (that is, linguists)
have begun talking about <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">world Englishes</ENAMEX>, not simply world <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>, to
emphasize this fact. Yet within a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> variation in standards still
tends to be rejected or regarded with suspicion. Hence ebonics was seen by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> at large as a declaration of independence in need of quashing,
an internal threat, a wild mistake, while <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American English</ENAMEX>, itself a partly
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">revolutionary</ENAMEX>, postcolonial product, is seen as simply "the way things are"
(that is, unless you're <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prince Charles</ENAMEX>).

            Someone posted an e-mail response to your morning essay
asking whether it's true that ebonics <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speakers</ENAMEX> can't do math because their
language isn't capable of rendering the subtleties of math. Sometimes it seems
to me that every language except my own is capable of rendering those
mathematic subtleties, and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> in math sometimes insist that the
subtleties of math cannot be rendered into <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>, or at least <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> that is
understandable by anyone unfamiliar with math. A high-energy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicist</ENAMEX> once
told me, when I asked her what she was working on, "I couldn't possibly put it
into words"--yet she continues to receive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NSF</ENAMEX> funding, which suggests someone
understands what she is up to on her grant applications. The math case may
really be what the computer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> call <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">COIK</ENAMEX>, "clear only if known." But this is
the kind of thinking about language that pervades our society. How would you
answer that question about ebonics and math? Language varieties are flexible
and adaptable. But they also exist in contexts, and while these contexts don't
necessarily bind them, they do affect them. So if the context that some ebonics
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speakers</ENAMEX> exist in is one that does not bring them up against the differential
calculus, what follows? Low math <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scores</ENAMEX>, for one thing. But that's not the same
as saying ebonics <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speakers</ENAMEX> can't do math because they can't speak math.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dennis</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
