
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blow Book Blows</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads with a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">rocket</ENAMEX> attack on
Grozny, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chechnya</ENAMEX>, that killed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 100</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>--mostly
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX>--and wounded <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">several hundred</NUMEX> more. The assault is also the top
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nonlocal</ENAMEX> story at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> . It is carried inside elsewhere. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">LAT</ENAMEX> leads with news that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> scandal is mushrooming,
based on a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>'s unadvertised attendance at a special briefing for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAPD</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> at which they were told that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> are now looking into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX>
questionable shootings of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angelenos</ENAMEX>, and into the police theft and resale of
street <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> leads with the latest evidence of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
military's recruiting difficulties: the cost per enlistee is now at an all-time
high. This is, the paper points out, money therefore not available to spend on
service <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>' training or housing. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> front is a campaign
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX>'s dream: The lead is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>'s vow <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> that if elected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>,
he would ban offshore drilling for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX> along both the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> coasts (the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> policy is a mere moratorium), and
nearby is a reefer reporting that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> advocated attacking
child poverty by raising the minimum wage, increasing child-care spending, and
providing working <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> with various tax benefits. Pictures of the candidates
dominate the page.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> goes bottom front with a dispatch about how the batch of
appropriations bills currently on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>' plate are salted with discreet
little money <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">plums</ENAMEX> for business: for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">auto</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, defense <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contractors</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">utilities</ENAMEX>, agribusiness, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shipbuilders</ENAMEX>, chemical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, and even an
ammunition <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Bennies</ENAMEX> like the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$15 million</NUMEX> for research on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">supersonic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> noise reduction, a subsidy that will help Gulfstream
develop a supersonic business jet, apparently to meet the pressing national
need for fat <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> in loud pants to get to golf tournaments quicker.

            The WP front reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> operating as part
of the peacekeeping <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Timor</ENAMEX> are beginning to arrive at an
understanding of why, despite eyewitness accounts of the mass murder of
independence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>-affiliated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">militias</ENAMEX>, they have found very
little murder evidence. They now believe, says the paper, that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">militiamen</ENAMEX> took pains to cover their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tracks</ENAMEX>, in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> case burning their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX> and then dumping the ashes into crocodile-filled lakes, in another
putting bodies in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> and sinking it at sea. "In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>, they didn't care
what the world saw," <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigator</ENAMEX> is quoted saying. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indonesians</ENAMEX> are
extremely concerned about saving face. They want to be able to deny any of this
happened."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> go inside with a new study of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>' investment practices. The big news: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nearly half</TIMEX>
of all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> are in the market now, compared to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">just 19 percent</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1983</TIMEX>.
The other major finding: far more <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> practice buy-and-hold investing
than all the headlines about day <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traders</ENAMEX> would suggest, with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">55 percent</NUMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> not making a single trade <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>. And <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 11 percent</NUMEX> made trades
over the Internet. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> reports that a survey of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly 400</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> indicates that corporate profits are up huge: their aggregate
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">quarter</TIMEX> total is <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">27 percent</NUMEX> ahead of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> fronts and the rest of the papers go inside with what is
perhaps the world land speed record for credibility disintegration: not only
does that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Martin's Press</ENAMEX> book alleging that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> has a coke
conviction in his past not contain a shred of convincing evidence, but it turns
out that the book's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> is apparently a convicted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">felon</ENAMEX> who did a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five-year</TIMEX>
stretch for attempted murder. Confronted with the blow up, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Martin's</ENAMEX> pulled
the book <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>. As 
                  Slate
               's 
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Weisberg</ENAMEX> was the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> to point out, the incident reminds that
quality control in the publishing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> lacks <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only two</NUMEX> things: quality and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
