
   
   
      
         
            Why Down't You Lose Some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weight</ENAMEX>?

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> front the incorporation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intel</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> into the Dow
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jones</ENAMEX> industrial average starting <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next Monday</TIMEX>, a story fronted (above the fold)
by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times and reefered by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> leads with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> scoop: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Today</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> will
propose sweeping privacy protections for medical records, stricter than those
included in the recent bill deregulating the finance industry. Both <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
proposal and the finance-industry bill would require insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> to
share their privacy rules with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s proposal would bar
these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> from sharing customer information with other insurance
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> without the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">customer</ENAMEX>'s explicit permission.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> 's headline, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dow Adds Microsoft</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gets Less Industrial</ENAMEX>,"
encapsulates the thrust of the stock-index change: new
money (tech stocks) is pushing out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the old</TIMEX> ("smokestack" stocks). Besides <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intel</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dow</ENAMEX> is adding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Home Depot</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SBC Communications</ENAMEX>; it is booting
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chevron</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sears, Union Carbide</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goodyear</ENAMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intel</ENAMEX> is to the economy what <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
Steel was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50 years ago</TIMEX>," a stock <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analyst</ENAMEX> says in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> . "It's the
producer of the product that's ubiquitous in a lot of other products." The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> calculates that if the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> had been added in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>,
the index would have risen <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">71 percent</NUMEX> since then--better than the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">62 percent</NUMEX>
performance of its leading <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitor</ENAMEX>, the more tech-rich <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">S&P 500</ENAMEX>, over the
same period. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dow</ENAMEX> actually rose <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">49 percent</NUMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that period</TIMEX>.) The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> notes that while the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">S&P 500</ENAMEX> is more popular with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$700 billion</NUMEX> is invested in portfolios mimicking the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S&P</ENAMEX>, while
only <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$165 million</NUMEX> tracks the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dow</ENAMEX>--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dow</ENAMEX> has a bigger influence on investor
psychology. (Both get license fees for the tracked portfolios.) (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">For Moneybox</ENAMEX>'s
take on the Dow change, click 
here.)

obesity, lands on the fronts of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> . Every paper spins it differently. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> story is the
most comprehensive. Under the headline "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">As Obesity Rate Soars, Hormone Offers</ENAMEX>
New <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hope</ENAMEX>," the paper lists <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JAMA</ENAMEX> 's sobering statistics: The percentage
of obese <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>--those <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">30 percent</NUMEX> heavier than their ideal body weight--has
increased <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">nearly 50 percent</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '90s</TIMEX>, from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">12 percent</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17.9</NUMEX>
percent in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Obesity</ENAMEX> now kills <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least 280,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>, making it
the highest preventable cause of death after smoking.  However, obese people
given injections of the hormone <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">leptin</ENAMEX> in a study lost weight proportionate to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dosage</ENAMEX> and lost fat cells only (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">25 percent</NUMEX> of weight loss from diet and
exercise is bone and muscle).

            But what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> does not report, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> seizes on: Under the headline "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hormone That Slimmed Fat</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mice Disappoints as Panacea in People</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gina Kolata</ENAMEX> (who <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> came under
fire for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over</NUMEX> -hyping a <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> study) gives a dour prognosis. Leptin
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> lost a "moderate amount of weight at best" and many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX>
receiving the highest--and most effective--doses tired of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> injections
and dropped out of the study. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> does not mention the national
obesity figures at all. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> --"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Hormone Helps Obese Lose Weight:</ENAMEX>
[But] <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Study Finds Leptin Has Drawbacks"</ENAMEX>--paints the leptin results more optimistically than the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> ; it, too, neglects to mention the obesity figures. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> , by contrast, mention the
obesity figures but not the leptin study.

            In an almost postmodern bit of media-criticism-cum-self-confirmation, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> runs an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Associated Press</ENAMEX> story in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ariz.</ENAMEX>, accuses
the presidential campaign of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> of "planting" a story critical of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">... Monday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX> duly notes that in the original
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> story, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporter</ENAMEX>, had argued that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> was too sensitive to personal criticism. "It's totally ridiculous to
think that we control what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> writes," a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">spokesman</ENAMEX> said. Question: Would the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> run an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX> story in which a
government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> claimed to identify an anonymous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX> for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>
story?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX> may no longer be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>, but he still can't
escape the press. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yesterday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> reported that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX>--who is accusing his recently dumped
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Marianne</ENAMEX>, of mishandling their money--spent <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$450</NUMEX> for a bottle <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1983</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Chateau Latour</ENAMEX> while dining with his new squeeze, a former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX>. Today,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marianne</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> tells the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> that she is "delighted to hear that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt</ENAMEX> is now making enough money to share with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marianne</ENAMEX>."

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">edition, Today's Papers</ENAMEX> confused the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> associated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russian</ENAMEX>
money-laundering investigations with his own. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> associated with the
money-laundering investigations is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bank of New York</ENAMEX>. TP regrets the error
and has fixed it in the text.

         
      
   
