
   
   
      
         
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dow</ENAMEX> finished down <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2.85%</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, and was down <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5.9%</NUMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX>,
its worst showing since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">All three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> also front the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nobel Peace Prize</ENAMEX>
news: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doctors Without Borders</ENAMEX> won the cherished award.

            Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> cite <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> reasons for the market's downturn: an unexpectedly
large increase in the product price index (generally a harbinger of inflation),
and comments by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Greenspan</ENAMEX> warning <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> to keep plenty of
reserves. It is widely agreed that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> will raise interest rates when they
meet in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> points to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a third</NUMEX> cause for the dive,
superstition: many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> are selling because they know that the market has
suffered horrible crashes in <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Octobers</ENAMEX> past. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> runs a related front
page article explaining the product price index, which measures inflation
"before it reaches the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumer</ENAMEX>." The index rose by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1.1%</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX>, the
largest <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one-month</TIMEX> jump in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a decade</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> 's coverage is the most
bearish, emphasizing that much of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dow</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASDAQ</ENAMEX>'s impressive performances
have been the result of a handful of bluechip stocks. This disparity, according
to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analyst</ENAMEX>, creates a "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">stealth bear</ENAMEX>" market, where, despite a rosy overall
appearance, most stocks are quietly tanking. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> dutifully reminds
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> that it's misleading to judge a dip's severity by points rather than by
percentages. Then, without missing a beat, it breathlessly reports that this
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">630</NUMEX>-point drop was the biggest ever!
            

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> editorial applauds the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nobel Committee</ENAMEX>'s choice of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Doctors</ENAMEX>
Without Borders. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> sends medical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX> to troubled areas
throughout the world. Rejecting the political neutrality of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Red Cross</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX> is often outspoken about the injustices its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> see; the organization
was expelled from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ethiopia</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985</TIMEX>, and withdrew from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rwanda</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> because
aid was being misused. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> sees the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> as emblematic of a new
trend, where media-savvy non-governmental <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> use press coverage to
broadcast their views and help shape the international diplomatic agenda. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DWB</ENAMEX>,
it notes, was the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> to call the massacres in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rwanda</ENAMEX>
"genocide." <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nobel</ENAMEX> also-rans included <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>, and a pair of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dissidents</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> investigates the ascendancy of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Majority Whip</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom DeLay</ENAMEX>,
which it attributes to his "unabashed devotion to political money." <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>'s premier fundraisers, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeLay</ENAMEX> has raised <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">an estimated $11 million dollars</NUMEX>
for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>, and gives away <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">as much as 90%</NUMEX> of his own campaign funds.
He's also been involved in a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25 million</NUMEX> fund drive for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> that's "a
mirror image of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">A.F.L.-C</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">I.O.</ENAMEX>" This has proved controversial because the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX>, which rallies conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> to fight labor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX>, is non-profit,
and thus prohibited from "coordinating" with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madeleine Albright</ENAMEX>'s upcoming <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> tour prompts a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> primer on
strife in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sierra Leone</ENAMEX>, where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albright</ENAMEX> will stop <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> in this
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">diamond</ENAMEX>-rich <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> has battled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">insurgents</ENAMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>, with mining
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">conglomerates</ENAMEX>, mercenaries, and other outside interests supplying <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX>, money,
and expertise to both sides. The ensuing clashes were particularly brutal,
according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX>, because the "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sponsors</ENAMEX>" had little motive to limit
the destruction. The warring <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">factions</ENAMEX> signed a peace treaty <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this summer</TIMEX>.

            For the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nearly a decade</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marine</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corps</ENAMEX> is charging a commanding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> with negligence in a training death. An
investigation discovered that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> marched his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> faster than was
recommended and ignored other safety procedures during a training exercise this
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX>. A reservist, who had begun vomiting early in the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">eight-mile</NUMEX> hike,
wandered off after the hike's end, and expired of a "heat illness." If
convicted, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> could receive a dishonorable discharge and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">almost four</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">WP Style section</ENAMEX> mourns the passing of a cultural icon. Loved by
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX>, this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> gave his life trying to protect the ones he loved, after a
lifetime devoted to fighting tyranny in all its guises. In a novel released
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chewbacca</ENAMEX>, the lovable <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Star Wars Wookiee</ENAMEX>, perishes when a
moon collides with a planet he was trying to save. The plot twist was approved
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Lucas</ENAMEX>, who created the Star Wars saga. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Fans</ENAMEX> of the series have
responded with characteristic level-headedness, clogging the Internet with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">eulogizes</ENAMEX> and declaring a fatwah on the book's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
