
   
   
      
         
            Reporting <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tips From the Big Boys</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> is impressed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert G. Kaiser</ENAMEX> (former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managing editor</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> ) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Janeway</ENAMEX> (former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> of the just-released <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Republic of Denial</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Press</ENAMEX>, Politics and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public Life</ENAMEX> at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Millennium</ENAMEX> ) managed to conduct an entire interview with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry McPherson</ENAMEX>
without once uttering the word "<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco</ENAMEX>."

            The interview, occasioned by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McPherson</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">70 th</NUMEX> birthday, appeared
in the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Style</ENAMEX>" section of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 20</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> . McPherson was
introduced, quite properly, as an important former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lyndon Johnson</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> of a "much-praised" memoir, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A Political Education</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> will even go along
with the interview's overall tone of deference (headline: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Long View of a</ENAMEX>
Changing <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capital"</ENAMEX>); from a distance, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McPherson</ENAMEX> has always struck <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> as
a kind, thoughtful, and (for the most part) honorable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>. The facts that
McPherson was an old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kaiser's</ENAMEX> and a former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Janeway's</ENAMEX> were
noted prominently, and did not strike <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> as disqualifying.

            But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> is at a loss to explain how anyone but a pair of formerly
high-ranking newspaper <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> could conceive of interviewing McPherson
without grilling him about his representation of the tobacco industry, which in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> transformed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McPherson</ENAMEX>'s law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Verner, Liipfert</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bernhard</ENAMEX>, McPherson
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Hand</ENAMEX>, into a gaudy lobbying powerhouse (at least in terms of billable
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX>). An appropriately tough <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Monthly</ENAMEX> * article by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amanda Ripley</ENAMEX> about
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McPherson</ENAMEX>'s tobacco sellout reports that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Verner, Liipfert</ENAMEX> raked in
more revenue than any other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lobby firm</ENAMEX>. According to the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monthly</TIMEX> piece, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Verner, Liipfert</ENAMEX>, though hired to help sell to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>
the settlement reached between state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys general</ENAMEX> and the tobacco industry
(without, of course, letting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> make the minimal improvements required to
make it even a marginally acceptable deal), was in fact mostly selling its
reputation. The substantive negotiations were conducted by others; the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>'s
apparent role (mostly in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Mitchell</ENAMEX> but also through
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McPherson</ENAMEX> himself) was to lend prestige to the tobacco industry's side. In the
words of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Verner, Liipfert</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> quoted in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monthly</ENAMEX>
story: "They were getting paid more for who they were than what they did."

            Here is the bold way <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kaiser</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Janeway</ENAMEX> approached this issue in their
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McPherson</ENAMEX> interview:

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Q</ENAMEX>: Some would say that money talks loudest of all in the business you're
now in. What about your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">practice</ENAMEX> and this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">practice</ENAMEX>? Can you represent
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> based on some ethical or political judgment about how much they deserve
your representation, or is it really just a question of selling yourselves to
the highest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bidders</ENAMEX>?
               

            

            Despite <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kaiser</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Janeway</ENAMEX>'s invitation to answer this question with breezy
generalities, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McPherson</ENAMEX> (to his credit) answers by getting into specifics about
his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>'s tobacco business:

            

               
                  A: Well, you hope that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you represent will be those that you
feel ought to prevail or at least ought to be protected. Let me take something
that has been an issue with our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> and with me personally. I've taken a fair
number of hits for being one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who signed on to represent the
tobacco industry when they started their negotiations with the state attorneys
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">general</ENAMEX> and the health <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>. The initial contact with our firm
was made with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Mitchell</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mitchell</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> of tremendous
integrity and intelligence.
               

            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> translation: "Don't blame me. It was that greedy bastard
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mitchell</ENAMEX>'s idea."

            

               
                  He was invited to involve his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>, my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>, in representing the tobacco
industry as it began a negotiation in which it was prepared to pay an enormous,
an unbelievable amount of money to various state coffers, which could be used
for anti-smoking campaigns and all manner of such things. It was prepared to
make all kinds of changes in its behavior--the way it advertised, particularly
toward young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. In exchange for that, it was hoping to get protection from
bankruptcy, which it feared would come if some of the state suits that had just
been fashioned [had succeeded].
               

            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> translation: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Like</ENAMEX> I said, it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mitchell</ENAMEX>'s idea."

            

               
                  Our job in this law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> was never to go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX> or to the executive
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">branch</ENAMEX> and say smoking doesn't cause <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">illness</ENAMEX>. It was never to say the tobacco
industry is being mistreated. It was simply to say the industry is prepared to
make revolutionary changes in its behavior if it gets some protection from
these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">giant</ENAMEX> suits, and this is a good deal for the public.
               

            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> translation: "Of course tobacco <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> represent
something close to pure evil. But the real dirty work had already been done. We
could present ourselves as the good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX>--midwives to a historic settlement of
health claims--while downplaying the role we played in minimizing (on our
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX>'s behalf) whatever sacrifice <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Tobacco</ENAMEX> had to make. And if, as
ultimately happened, no settlement resulted, we could shrug our shoulders, say,
'Hey, we tried,' and act like unsuccessful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brokers</ENAMEX> to an honorable peace."

            

               
                  Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> wrote scathingly of me, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mitchell</ENAMEX>, [former <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX>]
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ann Richards</ENAMEX> [also <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McPherson</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX>], because we had agreed to do that. We
agreed to do it because we thought it made a lot of sense in terms of the
public interest and, secondly, because it was very handsomely compensated
work.
               

            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> translation: "See how easy that is? Look, we can even
concede publicly that we were getting paid a lot to do this--better that
we should point that out, rather than you --and still make
our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> look like a bunch of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">braying jackals</ENAMEX>. I bet you aren't even going
to ask me a follow-up question."

            And they didn't.

            * <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> should here disclose that he is a contributing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> at
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monthly</ENAMEX> . On the other hand, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kaiser</ENAMEX> gave Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> her start in
journalism.
            

         
      
   
