
   
   
      
         
            Rule No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>: Don't Follow All Rules
            

            In late <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September of 1908</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Giants</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Cubs</ENAMEX> were
tied for <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National League</ENAMEX> pennant race with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a week</TIMEX> to
go in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the season</TIMEX>. (This was in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the days</TIMEX> when there were no divisional playoffs,
let alone wild cards. If you won the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">regular season</TIMEX> title, you went to the
World <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Series</ENAMEX>.) The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> met for a game at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Polo Grounds</ENAMEX> and went to the
bottom of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">ninth</NUMEX> tied <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>-1.

            With <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> outs and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moose McCormick</ENAMEX> on <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Giants</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">first baseman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred Merkle</ENAMEX>
singled to right field, sending <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCormick</ENAMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>. The next <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">batter</ENAMEX> then lined
a single up the middle, scoring <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCormick</ENAMEX> with what should have been the
winning run and putting <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> into <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>. But there was a catch. Merkle, who
was digging hard for <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> base, swerved away (he never touched <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>) and
started running for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Giants</ENAMEX>' locker <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> in center field as soon as he saw
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McCormick</ENAMEX> touch the plate. As was their wont in those less orderly <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Giants</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> immediately came swarming onto the field when their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> won, and Merkle
wanted to get a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> start on the happy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mob</ENAMEX>.

            This, then, was what's known in <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Merkle's Boner</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Refrain</ENAMEX> from
all vulgar snickers, please.) According to the rules of <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX>, the game
wasn't actually over until <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Merkle</ENAMEX> touched <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> base. Cubs <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> baseman
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnny Evers</ENAMEX> (of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tinkers-to-Evers-to-Chance</ENAMEX> fame) realized this, tracked down
the ball (actually, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who were there say he got another ball from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dugout</ENAMEX>, since the original ball had disappeared into the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX>), grabbed an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">umpire</ENAMEX>, and stepped on <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> base, which in theory completed a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> play on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Merkle</ENAMEX>. After much discussion, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">umpires</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Merkle</ENAMEX> out and declared the
game a tie that would have to be replayed. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A week or so later</TIMEX>, it was, and this
time the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cubs</ENAMEX> won, sending themselves to the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Series</ENAMEX> and consigning <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Merkle</ENAMEX> to
permanent notoriety.

            There's no question that according to the rules as written, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Merkle</ENAMEX> did have
to touch <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> base. But according to custom in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1908</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">runners</ENAMEX> who were on base
when a game-winning run scored in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">ninth</NUMEX> tended not to touch the next
base and instead headed for their clubhouses. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A month or so</TIMEX> before, in a game
against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnny Evers</ENAMEX> had tried the very same trick against a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pirate</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">runner</ENAMEX> who had left the field at game's end, but that time the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">umpire</ENAMEX> had
rejected his appeal.

            In suddenly invoking the letter of the law, then, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">umpires</ENAMEX> were requiring
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Merkle</ENAMEX> to act in a way that he had no reason to believe he was supposed to act.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX>'s understanding of the rule that a runner must always touch the
base to which he is forced was that this rule didn't apply when a game was won
in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">ninth</NUMEX> inning. What <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Merkle</ENAMEX> did, then, was what the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> expected him
to do. This may not mean he was right to do what he did. But there's an
argument to be made that when custom systematically changes the meaning of a
law--in this case, changes it by adding an important exception--it's a mistake
to invoke the original meaning arbitrarily and without warning.

            All of which brings us back to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>'s crackdown <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> against
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who double-<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> while their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> are being cleaned. This form of
double-parking (which is clearly distinguishable from double-parking in
shopping or business <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">districts</ENAMEX>) is customary throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>. On my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX>,
there's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who will double-park your <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> for you and then return it to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">curbside</ENAMEX> when the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three-hour</TIMEX> street-sweeping period is over. It's been
understood that double-parking is technically illegal but that this is an
orderly and systematic community response to the reality that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> need a
place to put their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> while the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> are being cleaned.

            By descending on selected residential neighborhoods and ticketing all those
double-parked <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>, the cops have pulled a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Johnny Evers</ENAMEX>. They're just enforcing
the law as written. But by doing so without notice, they're catching people
breaking rules that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> had, in a sense, decided didn't need to be
enforced. (I exaggerate here, since the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX>" is the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> of car
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX>.) And insofar as much of our everyday lives depends on knowing that
certain rules count and others don't--like laws banning cursing out loud, or
spitting in public, or oral sex--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudy Giuliani</ENAMEX> is making everyone feel very
unsettled.

            Actually, though, the unannounced war on double-parking is not really
characteristic of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX>. Most of his previous Jesuitical
initiatives--against jaywalking, speeding, gridlock, and the failure to wear
seatbelts, among others--have been announced well in advance, so that notice
was served that as of a certain date, things were going to be different. And if
you're going to hold <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to the letter of the law, that seems like the way
to do it, because it'd be hard to have any sympathy for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred Merkle</ENAMEX> if before
that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX> game the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">umpires</ENAMEX> had told both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> to make sure they touched
all the bases in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">ninth</NUMEX> inning.

         
      
   
