
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coming Desperate Political Upheaval</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Ted</ENAMEX>:

            All right, I could understand that you'd hate the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">test-ban</ENAMEX> treaty for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>'s reasons, but to say that we can't put the nuke
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">genie</ENAMEX> back in the bottle because we act badly in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> and that all pacts as a
rule fail sounds like circa<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-1952</TIMEX> cold-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">warrior rant</ENAMEX>. The facts don't support
that. Nukes have been around since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1945</TIMEX>, and since the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX>, not one
has been fired in anger. That's an amazing record for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX> that can be
counted on for the worst behavior all the time. The treaty didn't alone arrange
for that. It was a part of humanity's desire to step back from the brink and
cool the madness. Unless that idea has salience in the future, we can kiss our
sweet planet good-bye. It'll be a bit of bad news <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cartoonists</ENAMEX> won't be able to
draw about. Instead of trashing this treaty because it doesn't do everything,
we ought to be working on how to go further in the direction of international
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> of all nukes. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Einstein</ENAMEX> said that humanity doesn't have a prayer without
the advent of a world federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. The whole process of killing the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Earth</ENAMEX> (which is our big issue every news cycle,
regardless of what the suits tell us) won't be brought to heel without strong
international agreements ... and I'm not referring to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mercedes</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler</ENAMEX>.
Who will lead this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">movement</ENAMEX>? Will they be successful? How far will they get
before we see we're really doomed? We'll find out deep in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next century</TIMEX>. It
really will be crunch time. A time of desperate political upheaval, calling for
a focused and educated world population. But let's leave that to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and
enjoy our happy fin de siècle with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Ventura</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudy Giuliani</ENAMEX> and
his Blessed Virgin <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">JonBenet Ramsey</ENAMEX> (still dead, huh?).

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted</ENAMEX>, you seem itching to get down to cases on the
subject of cartoons and satire. OK, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spiegelman</ENAMEX> aside, whom do you love and whom
do you hate? And why?

            By the way, do you want to hear my <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phil Harris</ENAMEX> theory
of politics?

            Peace now,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
