
   
   
      
         
            Everyone's an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Expert</ENAMEX> ...
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Dennis</ENAMEX>,

            Forgive me if I don't have much spring in my step <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX>. I was just
reading the new issue of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harper</ENAMEX>'s , and started a piece by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Gass</ENAMEX>
in appreciation of the printed book. He makes the usual comments about how
wonderful books are, and how an ideal <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> would have walls full of books, and
then I got to this: "Every real book (as opposed to dictionaries, almanacs, and
other compilations) is a mind, an imagination, a consciousness."

            Sigh. As a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dictionary editor</ENAMEX>, it is frustrating enough to be thought to be
producing interchangeable and useless material, but for a respected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> to
regard dictionaries as mere compilations with no mind or imagination behind
them is especially bad.

            Your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user</ENAMEX>-vs.-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> situation is right on target here. It's not just my
experience; it's pretty much universal that language is thought to be a subject
that anyone can comment on because everyone uses it. Unlike math, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX>, or
even some sports, which require deep knowledge to approach, language is wide
open. Everyone has a pet <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">peeve</ENAMEX>, be it a misused word, an unusual pronunciation,
or what have you.

            For lexicographers, this manifests itself most annoyingly in the poor state
of dictionary reviewing. Most new dictionaries are not reviewed in the
mainstream <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX>, and even when they are, they are not reviewed by linguists or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">lexicographers</ENAMEX>. They are reviewed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>, on the grounds that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who
use the language professionally must be qualified to critique books devoted to
it.

            As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sidney Landau</ENAMEX> points out in his excellent book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dictionaries: The Art</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Craft of Lexicography</ENAMEX> , this is much like assuming that anyone who lives
in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> is qualified to be an architecture <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX>. The result is that when
dictionaries are discussed in the press, only the most superficial issues are
given attention--the novelty of the new words entered, the number of usage
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">notes</ENAMEX>, the number of illustrations. Important considerations, such as the
quality of the definitions, are ignored. And those writing dictionaries are
encouraged by their marketing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">departments</ENAMEX> to add ever more flashy features to
give the press something to focus on.

            I find that much of the time <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> have a very strong sense of what they
like and dislike in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">language</ENAMEX> and are unwilling to let any so-called experts
influence them. Nor would I necessarily want to; a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s aesthetic sense is
not to be tossed away lightly. But I do wish that they would at least consider
what we have to say, since they might learn something on occasion.

            Perhaps Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gass</ENAMEX>, whose own vocabulary is so rich, could also still learn
that dictionaries are more than dull compilations. They are even, sometimes,
"real books."

            Best,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
