
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buckley</ENAMEX> and Quotas at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicholas Lemann</ENAMEX>'s absorbing new history of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">meritocracy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">The Big Test</ENAMEX> , contains an interesting anecdote about
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William F. Buckley</ENAMEX>'s inadvertent role, while an undergraduate at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale</ENAMEX> during
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late 1940s</TIMEX>, in helping that university restrict the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Catholics it</ENAMEX> admitted. Here is how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lemann</ENAMEX> tells the story (on page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">142</NUMEX>):

            

               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">One year</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Connecticut</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">legislature</ENAMEX> got the idea of forbidding
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX> to ask for information about the religion of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">applicants</ENAMEX>. [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">A. Whitney</ENAMEX>] <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Griswold</ENAMEX> persuaded the student <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale</ENAMEX>
Daily <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William F. Buckley, Jr.</ENAMEX>, to go up to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hartford</ENAMEX> and testify
against the bill; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Griswold</ENAMEX> told him such information would be indispensable for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale Archives</ENAMEX> (though <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buckley</ENAMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponent</ENAMEX> of government regulation, didn't
need to be persuaded very hard). <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A few days later</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buckley</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> chaplain about his political mission, the chaplain broke the news to
him that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale</ENAMEX> maintained a ceiling of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">13 percent</NUMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholics</ENAMEX> and on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> and
that was why they needed to ask the question.
               

            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lemann</ENAMEX> got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> detail wrong: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Griswold</ENAMEX> didn't become <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> until a
few <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buckley</ENAMEX> graduated, so the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> in question would have
been <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Griswold</ENAMEX>'s predecessor, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Seymour</ENAMEX>. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> asked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buckley</ENAMEX>
about this intriguing story--which apparently has never been told before,
except in a footnote to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan A. Oren</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985</TIMEX> book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Joining The Club: A History</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale</ENAMEX> --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buckley</ENAMEX> was a little hazy about the details:

            

               
                  I met with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Seymour</ENAMEX>, ex officio as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale</ENAMEX>
News , once <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every week</TIMEX>. I can't exactly remember whether it was he who asked
me to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hartford</ENAMEX> or whether it was [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frederick</ENAMEX>]
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wiggin</ENAMEX>. I do remember at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seymour</ENAMEX> telling me that it was ridiculous
not to ask an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">applicant</ENAMEX> what religion his was, since "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX> are historical
research <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX>." I exactly remember going to see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX>, the
formidable Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wiggin</ENAMEX>, who asked why I opposed the law. I gave the libertarian
answer and he said, "You're wrong. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">legislature</ENAMEX> can do anything it wants to
do provided it isn't unconstitutional." He instructed me, in effect, not to
stress my own libertarian line, but simply to say I had no reason to suppose
that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale</ENAMEX> had quotas.
               

            

            Even granting that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buckley</ENAMEX>'s libertarian opposition to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Connecticut</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fair</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Education Practices</ENAMEX> bill, which never did pass, would not likely have been
altered by the discovery that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale</ENAMEX> did indeed have quotas, it appears that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buckley</ENAMEX> was duped--either by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wiggin</ENAMEX> or by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seymour</ENAMEX> or by both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>--into
repeating a lie that helped <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale</ENAMEX> restrict the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholics</ENAMEX> (of whom he
was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> who got in. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oren</ENAMEX>'s book, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wiggin</ENAMEX> assured <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buckley</ENAMEX>
that there were no quotas. But there were quotas. Whether these were
formal quotas can't, perhaps, be proved. But against <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> there were,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oren</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>, "admissions guidelines and understandings, 'informal
quotas' that had the same net effect," and these "were not relaxed until the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early '60s</TIMEX>." Against <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholics</ENAMEX> there's less direct evidence of 'informal
quotas,' but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oren</ENAMEX> got some former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale</ENAMEX> admissions <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> to admit that their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> discriminated against <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholics</ENAMEX> during this period. And at least
according to the testimony of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chaplain</ENAMEX> (as recounted by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buckley</ENAMEX>), "it was a funny 'coincidence' that exactly the same number of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholics</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> were admitted into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale</ENAMEX>."

            What <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> wants to know is: Why are we learning about this only now?
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William F. Buckley</ENAMEX> is not only a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX>, but a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> who has written
extensively about his own personal experiences; moreover, the first book
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buckley</ENAMEX> ever published, God and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Man</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale</ENAMEX> , was, in part, an argument that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale</ENAMEX> should uphold its antique tradition of inculcating <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> values and
beliefs. In taking this position, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buckley</ENAMEX> ought to have noted the inconvenient
fact that historically, running a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> college (which to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale</ENAMEX> really meant
a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Protestant</ENAMEX> college) meant excluding, to some extent, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholics</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>--and
that, a mere <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two or three years</TIMEX> before publishing this book, he himself had
encountered some evidence that systematic exclusion might still going on.

         
      
   
