
   
   
      
         
            Dueling Dictionaries
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Dennis</ENAMEX>,

            I may have spoken too soon in my earlier message. After
I wrote it I went back and finished the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Gass</ENAMEX> piece and found a curious
volte-face near <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX>: "I have rarely paged through one of my dictionaries (a
decent household will have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a dozen</NUMEX>) without my eye lighting, along the way, on
words more beautiful than a found fall leaf ..."

            So he does appreciate dictionaries after all, even if
he somehow thinks that they simply spring into existence with no help from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX>.

            You are of course right that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who use things, be
they books or kitchens, have a real stake in how they decide to use them. The
poor ink-stained <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wretches</ENAMEX> working in the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Condé Nast</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
know that the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> is an architectural disaster, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herbert Muschamp</ENAMEX>'s
glowing review of it in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> won't change
that. But it would be nice if a user's needs coincided with the expressed
purpose of an item. Thus even if dictionaries were used chiefly as booster
seats, it would behoove a reviewer to address their real purpose. An office
building that functions poorly as an office <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> but looks impressive
should be criticized, just as a dictionary that has impressive photos and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">presses flowers</ENAMEX> well but has poor definitions and etymologies should be
criticized.

            Speaking of criticizing dictionaries, it seems we have
a difference of opinion about the Encarta
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dictionary</ENAMEX>. For once the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> got things right, and largely because they
bothered to call lexicographers for opinions. This wasn't a case of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">misinterpretation</ENAMEX>--the book has very severe problems, which were barely touched
on even in the harsher newspaper reviews (which, in any event, are unlikely to
have much effect on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Encarta</ENAMEX> 's sales). I'm very fond
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anne Soukhanov</ENAMEX>, professionally and personally, but I think she realizes the
flaws of the work. Still, the book is another one out there without "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Webster's</ENAMEX>"
in the title! You're quite correct that most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> view that word as a generic
for "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">dictionary"</ENAMEX> (although it is defined in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX>--I put the definition
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Random House Webster</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">College Dictionary a</ENAMEX>
few <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years back</TIMEX>). There are no trademark worries--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> ruled that
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Webster</ENAMEX>" was generic as far back as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1911</TIMEX>--but there are real marketing
concerns. On the one hand, many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> think that "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Webster</ENAMEX>" means "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">dictionary</ENAMEX>,"
and thus any good dictionary must have "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Webster</ENAMEX>" in the title. On the other,
you want to differentiate your dictionary from your similarly named
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX>. Nothing is more frustrating than spending <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an hour</TIMEX> on the phone
with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> and then seeing an article with your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitor</ENAMEX>'s name in
place of your own.

            I'd very much like to talk about the implications of
new technologies on the study of language, but right now I have to run--my
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5-week-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> needs some attention. I'll try to get in an extra message
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX>.

            Till then,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
