
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metabolife</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Lawyer Assures C'box</ENAMEX> He Won't Sue

            
               A warning to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fray</ENAMEX>: This <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">item</ENAMEX>, like its 
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">predecessor</ENAMEX>, will 
               not inform you
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about</TIMEX> whether <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metabolife</ENAMEX>'s herbal diet <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">suppliment</ENAMEX> is safe and effective, or
unsafe and ineffective. If you want that kind of consumer information, try this
piece in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX>. 

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> spent most of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> continuing to quake with fear at the prospect
of getting sued for doing precisely what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Metabolife</ENAMEX> says it wants everyone in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> to do: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Namely</ENAMEX>, log on to its Web site. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> explained
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> (see "Metabolife:
Read This! No, Wait, Don't Read This!"), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metabolife</ENAMEX> makes a diet <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pill</ENAMEX> that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC News</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">20/20</ENAMEX> is expected to
report on in a forthcoming (but as yet unscheduled) report. Believing that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">20/20</ENAMEX> is out to do a story that is
both highly critical and unfair, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metabolife</ENAMEX> put its own videotape of the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">unedited 20/20</NUMEX> interview on a
special Web site
and (in an advertisement in the New York
Times ) urged the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> to compare that with "what is actually broadcast"
when the program airs. But when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> actually went to the Web site, he
was confronted by an elaborate "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user</ENAMEX> agreement" that essentially threatened to
sue anyone who used the information on the Web site for journalistic purposes.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> then phoned <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metabolife</ENAMEX>'s public relations <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>, and was told to
ignore the bullying legal language and proceed.

            But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> wasn't going to do anything without talking to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>. He
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">phoned Metabolife</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Mansfield</ENAMEX>, who works for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Akin, Gump</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Angeles</ENAMEX>. Did <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mansfield</ENAMEX> intend to sue <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> if he quoted from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Metabolife</ENAMEX> Web site?  "I shouldn't be in a position of providing legal advice
to you," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mansfield</ENAMEX> said. "I don't think that's appropriate for you and for me."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> explained that he couldn't very well take up <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metabolife</ENAMEX>'s invitation
to consider the information it had gone to some expense to publicize without
some assurance that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Metabolife</ENAMEX> was not going to punish him for sharing said
information with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mansfield</ENAMEX> said he would have to check with the
other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> and get back to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>.

            When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mansfield</ENAMEX> phoned back, he said, "You can certainly quote portions of
the transcript under the fair use doctrine, and you also can certainly take
still frames, make still frames, of the videotaped interview under the fair use
doctrine as well." He said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> could also link to the Web site, which
was a great relief to hear, because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> had already done that in the
earlier item. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mansfield</ENAMEX> declined, however, to tell <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> what the
rationale was behind all the legal mumbo-jumbo on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metabolife</ENAMEX>'s Web site, or why
Metabolife was (according to its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PR</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>) unwilling to let <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC News</ENAMEX>' broadcast
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rivals</ENAMEX> help themselves to the unedited videotape of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 20/20</TIMEX> interview, or how <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metabolife</ENAMEX> could own
the copyright on an interview conducted by someone else (incorporating,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> might have added, audio fed to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metabolife</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">technicians</ENAMEX>).
To do so, he said, would violate attorney-client privilege.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> couldn't resist asking: How much did <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Akin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gump</ENAMEX> charge Metabolife
to write up the elaborate legal warning on its <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20/20</NUMEX> Web site, which he was now more or less
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">telling Chatterbox</ENAMEX> to ignore?

            "I don't know what possible basis you would have for that question," he
said.

            Was it <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $5,000</NUMEX>?

            "I'm not going to respond to that," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mansfield</ENAMEX> answered.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mansfield</ENAMEX> called back a little later to tell <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> that the legal
language on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Metabolife</ENAMEX> Web site hadn't kept it from receiving more than a
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX> hits on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first day</TIMEX> it was up. He also said that if 
                  Slate
                was going to criticize the legal
terminology on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metabolife</ENAMEX>'s Web site, it ought to acknowledge its own "much
lengthier, more intimidating set of disclaimers that goes on page after page
after page." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> had no idea what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mansfield</ENAMEX> was talking about (which
should give you some idea about how little prominence 
                  Slate
               's table of contents page gives
these "terms
of use"; look for the teensy blue type at the very bottom). <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Mansfield</ENAMEX>
acknowledged 
                  Slate
               's growly
legal language was much harder to find, but said that when you read it, it was
"frankly more ominous" than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metabolife</ENAMEX>'s growly legal language. Well, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> for
yourself. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> thinks that the few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">obsessives</ENAMEX> who wander onto this page, which
enunciates terms of use for all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> Web sites, and not just 
                  Slate
               , will realize that 
                  Slate
                is out to protect its published
material from being stolen or
plagiarized , but, like every other
publication in the world, on the Web or elsewhere, is more than happy to have
its published material quoted in
accordance with fair use.

            By now it was dinnertime, and Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterchildren</ENAMEX> were
urging <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> to come home. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> will report on his visit to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metabolife</ENAMEX>'s Web site <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX>.

         
      
   
