
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McCivil Disobedience</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Steve</ENAMEX>:

            OK, OK, I'll admit that nuclear war sucks. I'll come right out and say it: I
personally oppose the intentional release of radiation near human skin, unless
that skin happens to belong to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> I don't personally like. But the bottom
line is that you can't put the nuke genie back in the bottle because human
behavior inevitably declines to its lowest common denominator--in other words,
we all act like the meanest, stupidest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> in whatever <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> we happen to be
in. So these pacts will inevitably disintegrate to the worst behavior of their
signatories in the long run.

            I dunno, I have a fond spot in my anti-free-trade heart (ever notice how the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only</NUMEX> thing "free" about free trade is the average salary the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> have
in mind for the rest of us?) for that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>. He should have got sued,
sure, and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">jail</ENAMEX> was entirely appropriate for this particular act of civil
disobedience, but as an occasional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customer</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Golden Arches</ENAMEX> (personally, I
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">prefer Wendy's</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> dual national, it's splendid to see someone
willing to take a risk for their principles <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now and then</TIMEX>, particularly when
it's a blow against a monolithic transnational <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporation</ENAMEX> that built itself up
by underpaying <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> who ought to be at home studying for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next day</TIMEX> of
school rather than learning the mysteries of deep-frying <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">every night</TIMEX>.

            By the way, it only seems appropriate to include a little cartooning
commentary here. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Post</ENAMEX> cartoon by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sean</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Delonas</ENAMEX> depicts a recently divorced <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Jackson</ENAMEX> out on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> ogling
stripping <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX>. Is it just me, or is this more boring than offensive? Second
question: Does anyone other than the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brits</ENAMEX> call <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Jackson</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Jacko"</ENAMEX>?

            Just asking.

            Ciao,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
