
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Midas Touch</ENAMEX>
            

            I had a great time with the tremendously entertaining <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">New New Thing</ENAMEX> ,
and it has taught me a lot. (You've been following <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Silicon Valley</ENAMEX> for some
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>; I've mostly been living in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 19 th century</TIMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">J.P. Morgan</ENAMEX>
for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past 15 years</TIMEX>, and keeping up only from a distance with what one of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> calls "the greatest legal creation of wealth in the history
of the planet.") So, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX>' account of the wild and uncannily shrewd <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Clark</ENAMEX>
is among other things a terrific introduction to the ongoing revolution in
information technology, to its transformation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> economy, and to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX>-rush combination of optimism and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">insanity</ENAMEX> in the current marketplace for
Internet ideas. Just for the record, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX> founded <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Silicon Graphics</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Netscape</ENAMEX>,
and then <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Healtheon</ENAMEX>, which you've already mentioned, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this spring</TIMEX> he was
worth <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3.2 billion</NUMEX>. I've been tempted to characterize him as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dennis Rodman</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Silicon Valley</ENAMEX>, but his scoring record is closer to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jordan</ENAMEX>'s.

            Like you, I found a number of annoying and frustrating things in the book,
but I'll talk about the good parts <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> has such a fantastic eye for
funny, telling moments that he often doesn't have to "tell" much around
them--such as that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Spielberg</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Lucas</ENAMEX> saw the possibilities of
three-dimensional computer graphics (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX>'s first <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Idea</ENAMEX>) long before
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lockheed</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX> did. Or the sense of technological magic that drew other
brilliant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineers</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim</ENAMEX> was building the coolest stuff," says
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>--"You wanted to be around just to see what was going to happen next." Also,
not everything <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX> touched turned to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> enhances the drama by
showing the mistakes. At a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX> conference, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX> predicted that personal
computing would link up with personal communications once the PC became fun to
use--for instance, through computer games like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nintendo</ENAMEX>. That was wrong (the
games part), but as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> observes, "he was groping toward a mass market." (It
is amazing to think of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX> as ancient history, and to watch these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> groping
toward what we know will become the Internet.) Next, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX> thought that the new
new thing would be linking the computer to television, and got <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Warner</ENAMEX> to
put up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> to build interactive TV. Other major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> jumped on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bandwagon</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billions of dollars</NUMEX> followed, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX>'s best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineers</ENAMEX> put <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> of
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">18-hour</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> into the project--but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX> lost interest and turned his attention
to a piece of software called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mosaic</ENAMEX> that enabled its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> to travel around
the Internet. With the help of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mosaic</ENAMEX>'s young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designer</ENAMEX>, he set up what became
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Netscape</ENAMEX>. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">herd</ENAMEX>," as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> puts it, had followed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX> into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ITV</ENAMEX>, while
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX> headed off in a new direction: "It was one of the greatest unintentional
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head fakes</ENAMEX> in the history of technology."

            There's lots more that's good in here, but we've got <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two more days</TIMEX> to talk
about it, and I want to answer some of your questions and outline some of my
own reservations. Yes, I think it's possible that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> has too much talent for
his own good. He's in fact so deft with the "telling" incident that he doesn't
bother to fill in facts you really want to know. I did notice that he never
explains what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Healtheon</ENAMEX> is going to do--which contributes to the hilarity of
the scene in which the venture <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">capitalists</ENAMEX> and Wall Street <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wizards</ENAMEX> throw money
at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clark</ENAMEX> because they're terrified of missing out on the new new thing. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX>'
attitude here seems to mirror <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX>'s--once the deal is done and the IPO
billions have been made, it doesn't matter what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> is or does.
Whatever. Well, it would be useful to know how--or if--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Healtheon</ENAMEX> is actually
going to "fix the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> health-care system" and take control of a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.5 trillion</NUMEX>
industry.

            About the amount of time <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lewis</ENAMEX> spends on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">155-foot</NUMEX> (though sometimes
it's <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">157-foot</NUMEX>) computerized sailboat, I thought it was fun to read but too
much. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> story nicely emphasizes the idea of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX>'s lust for grandiose
risk, and sets up a neat contest between computer engineering and "real world"
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">engineering</ENAMEX> (in this context, real world wins so far). And there's a funny
moment, halfway across the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Atlantic</ENAMEX>, when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">captain</ENAMEX> gets the news by computer
that @<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Home</ENAMEX> has just bought <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Excite</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX> goes on about stocks and taxes
the way the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">athletes</ENAMEX> in those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schwab</ENAMEX> ads currently on TV talk about p/e ratios.
But there is too much boat stuff, and though as always with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lewis</ENAMEX> it's very
well written, it feels like filler. Substantive reflections on history and on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> might have been a better use for some of these pages--but I'm
running out of space here, so I'll continue with those thoughts <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sometime</TIMEX> before we end this conversation, I'd love to know what you make of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX>'s latest idea--to create a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cartel</ENAMEX> of "high-net-worth <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>" and
engage in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">billionaire</ENAMEX> collective bargaining.

         
      
   
