
   
   
      
         
            Somebody <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">To Lean On</ENAMEX>
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> issue about masculinity that intrigues me revolves around the experience
of dependence. Traditionally in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, dependence was dishonorable for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>;
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> were allowed to be taken care of, as part of caring for others; men
instead have been pushed to become self-reliant. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Manly</ENAMEX> equals self-reliant. In
fact, this traditional image of masculinity is nonsense. Imagine, for instance,
someone at the beginning of an affair declaring, "Don't worry, I can take care
of myself, I will never lean on you." You would soon lose interest; after all,
you wouldn't really matter in the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s life. But <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, in my
experience, have a great deal of trouble saying "I need you." It seems weak,
and so shameful.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Faludi</ENAMEX>'s interviewees hew to this silence, and I wonder if that isn't part
of their trouble. Again, I think economics matters in this silence <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. The
ideology of work in modern society puts great emphasis on independence, on
treating oneself entrepreneurially--but if you treat yourself as an independent
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX>, you don't establish much emotional connection to other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. It's the
same problem: If you don't acknowledge you need them, they are not going to
care much about you. Unlike <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shoshana</ENAMEX>, I don't see the modern economy in fact
giving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> more independence; as she herself has shown, experiences such as
working from home via the computer often plunge <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> into situations where
they are more tightly monitored than if they were working in a traditional
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>. So perhaps part of the trouble with conceiving of strength as autonomy
is that it makes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> feel actually worse about the tangled web of
dependencies that in fact rule their lives. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Men</ENAMEX> in particular.

            This insight isn't really mine. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychologist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carol Gilligan</ENAMEX>, in her fine
book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">In a Different Voice</ENAMEX> , has probed the destructive consequences of
manly silence--for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> themselves as much as for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> who
fall under the spell of this silence. In fact, making issues of dependence
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">overt</ENAMEX> and legitimate requires a great deal of personal strength: You need to
know what you need, and you need to figure out whether someone else can help
you. I missed at the end of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Faludi's</ENAMEX> study a discussion of this dynamic of
masculinity, though the problem surfaces in her interviews again and again.

            I'd like to end this discussion, however, by saying that, perhaps unlike
Shoshana, I think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stiffed</ENAMEX> is an admirable, serious, and humane book. It
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">records</ENAMEX> the dead-end society has put <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> into as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stiffed</ENAMEX> is blessedly free of jargon, and full of telling
detail. Its analysis is meant to provoke debate, and will continue to do so. I
think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> should read it and argue with it.

         
      
   
