
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Magna Jakarta</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> lead with the
surprising result of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> truly contested presidential election in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nearly 50 years</TIMEX>: the victory (in a vote taken in the national <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">legislature</ENAMEX>, not
among the general <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>) of a first-time <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">holder</ENAMEX>, an aging, frail, and
nearly blind <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> cleric named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abdurrahman Wahid</ENAMEX>. This is also the top
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nonlocal</ENAMEX> story at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX>
puts <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX> deep inside and leads instead with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Justice</ENAMEX>
documents made public <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> showing that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOJ</ENAMEX> believes the clemency
release of convicted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Puerto Rican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>
increases the threat of violence posed by their separatist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FALN</ENAMEX>. The
paper also reports that documents made available <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> show that the DOJ
weighed in with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> against clemency in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> runs a
similar story inside. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front-page story based on those same
documents paints a diametric picture, reporting that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX> took extraordinary
steps to maximize the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX>' chances for clemency, including the highly
unusual step of making their applications for them and having supporters
persuade them to write statements of repentance.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wahid</ENAMEX>'s victory came despite his having only recently declared his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">candidacy</ENAMEX>, at the expense of the prohibitive favorite, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nation</ENAMEX>'s founding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sukarno</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wahid</ENAMEX> was, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> report, sworn in
almost immediately after the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">legislature</ENAMEX>'s vote. Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> note that he is a moderate, with the LAT stating he has
something that will be much needed as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX> tries to dig itself out of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
solid years of political upheaval and economic failure--good relations with all
the major blocs of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> society: the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX>, former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidents</ENAMEX> Suharto
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Habibie</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>. That said, the coverage still notes
the outbreak of street violence upon the announcement of the election outcome,
although the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> says it didn't approach what was feared if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sukarno</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> lost. (Thanks to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , by the way, for answering a question
nobody asked: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wahid</ENAMEX>'s favorite all-time hit is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janis Joplin</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Me</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bobby</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McGee</ENAMEX>.")

            Everybody fronts (with accompanying photos) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Dole</ENAMEX>'s announcment
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> that she was abandoning her presidential campaign. The papers all
basically credit <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>'s explanation: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Money</ENAMEX> has come to mean too much in
presidential politics and she had too little of it. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports
inside that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> seized on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>'s announcement to take a shot at
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>, calling him the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> in the history of the modern
era who's given up federal funding so that he could raise an unlimited sum of
money, something <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> says he'd been urged to do in the past but did not
because it "wasn't fair." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> notes a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokeswoman</ENAMEX>'s response: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">We</ENAMEX>
appreciate the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>'s advice. ... But we don't intend to use him as a
model for how <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Governor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> will raise money or lead the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>." The
Times sees in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s comment the strategy of provoking <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> so <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> doesn't have to.

            The LAT front turns in an exclusive on a topic it first broached a
few <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks ago</TIMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New England Journal of Medicine</ENAMEX> 's apparent violation
of its own ethical policies requiring the disclosure of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX>' possible
conflicts of interest. Out of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">36</NUMEX> recent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NEJM</ENAMEX> drug reviews examined, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> finds <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> reviewed a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX>'s performance but
had undisclosed ties to its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX>.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> feature flagged in its
front-page news box explains how the recent settlement between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Tire</ENAMEX> and
the union <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workforce</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.C.</ENAMEX>, is the wave
of the future: the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX> set up a Web site to give the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX>'s take and also
made it easy for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strikers</ENAMEX> to e-mail company <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX> and at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>. And in chainlike fashion, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> at
other tire <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> were notified about the strike and its issues and encouraged
to email their solidarity to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HQ</ENAMEX> as well. It's called, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> ,
cyberpicketing, and it takes a lot of the logistics out of doing a labor
action.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> report that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX> issued a cease-and-desist order against <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> for trying to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sell</ENAMEX> securities on the Internet. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> agreed to stop and as a result are
not facing criminal charges. And <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">eBay</ENAMEX> reacted by banning stock auctions at its
site. But neither story explains why stock sales are wrong at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">eBay</ENAMEX>, but right,
say, at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Datek</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> suggests the key factor is ensuring that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> have access to good information regarding any stock to be purchased.
But doesn't this imply that if an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">eBay</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">seller</ENAMEX> were to post a prospectus along
with his sales offer he'd be in compliance?

         
      
   
