
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekend Cocktail Chatter</ENAMEX>
            

            It was a mood-swing week on Wall Street, though I don't think there's anyone
left out there who feels confident enough to tell you what the market's going
to do next. (Well, it will fluctuate, of course.) Beaten down by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s
producer price index number and the myriad 
misreadings of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Greenspan</ENAMEX>'s comments, stocks came roaring back this
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX> after the consumer price index for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX> was reasonable and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>
reported blowout numbers--no doubt all due to 
                  Slate
               , in some
complicated way that not even we can fully comprehend. But then <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX> came in on
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> with a melancholy forecast for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next six months</TIMEX>, which sent
stocks tumbling for much of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> until they just stopped. It was actually
an impressive feat of discriminating between good and bad stocks on the part of
the market, instead of the perhaps more common "Kill 'em all and let God sort
'em out" approach.

            I hope nothing else important happens between the time I write this and you
read it, but if it does, just ask the closest <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7-year-old</TIMEX> about it. He'll
probably give you a version much like the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> in the previous paragraph. And
so, on to the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cocktail Chat</ENAMEX>!

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX> announced that it would be investing <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$800 million</NUMEX> in PC maker
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gateway</ENAMEX> , and that it would be entering a partnership with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gateway</ENAMEX> that
should give <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX> easier access to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who buy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gateway PCs</ENAMEX>, and Gateway easier
access to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>. Since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gateway</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> mascot is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cow</ENAMEX> ,
speculation has immediately arisen that its version of the online service will
be called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">America MOOnline</ENAMEX>."

            1a. "Think of that as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Henny Youngman</ENAMEX> joke for the age of the New
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Economy</ENAMEX>."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX> met Wall Street estimates but saw its market capitalization drop
by a staggering <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$40 billion</NUMEX> after it warned that its sales in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the next two</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">quarters</ENAMEX>, well into <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>, would be sharply lower because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> are so
worried about the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Y2K</NUMEX> problem . Curiously, other tech <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">giants</ENAMEX>, like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsystems</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EMC</ENAMEX> have said that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Y2K</ENAMEX> concerns are having little
or no effect on their business. But this does raise an interesting question:
What will be the latest date that a company mentions Y2K as a reason for poor
performance? I'm guessing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 2002</TIMEX>."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. "Tobacco <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>' stock prices dropped yet again, with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Philip Morris</ENAMEX>
plummeting <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">24 percent</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two days</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">R.J. Reynolds</ENAMEX> falling <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">15 percent</NUMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Mann</ENAMEX> must be astonished at the powerful effect the
early screenings of his <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-</ENAMEX>tobacco<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">-company</ENAMEX> movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Insider</ENAMEX> have had.
Though it's possible that a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> jury handing down a verdict in a
class-action suit that could mean the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> will be shelling out even more
multibillion-dollar payments might have something to do with the downturn."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gillette</ENAMEX>, which in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past year</TIMEX> has made a habit of letting Wall
Street down , did so again <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> when it announced that sales in the next
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">quarter</TIMEX> would be lower because it was going to trim its inventory of razor
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">blades</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gillette</ENAMEX> also said it was contemplating selling off some of its
poorly performing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">divisions</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reuters</ENAMEX> reported that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gillette</ENAMEX>'s shares were
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'bludgeoned'</ENAMEX> in after-hours trading. Presumably with a 'blunt, heavy
object'<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>"

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. "A bus-stop ad for a personal-injury <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brooklyn</ENAMEX> tells
potential <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> to call this number: <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">'1-877-I-CAN-SUE</ENAMEX> .' Doesn't
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matlock</ENAMEX> have that on his business card, too?"

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha Stewart Omnimedia</ENAMEX> went public <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> and nearly doubled
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">its first day</TIMEX> of trading, after some dubious trading shenanigans in its
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hour</TIMEX>. According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> , 'The offering was hot in
large part because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founder</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> is so well known .' Ah,
yes. I'd almost forgotten that legendary chapter in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Graham</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dodd</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Security Analysis</ENAMEX> : 'On the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Importance of Fame</ENAMEX> in Valuing Stocks.'"

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">maker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eli Lilly</ENAMEX> saw its profits rise <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">15 percent</NUMEX> in the most
recent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">quarter</TIMEX>, meeting estimates, but its shares fell nonetheless when it
announced that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Prozac</ENAMEX> sales were down significantly. Count depression as
yet another casualty of the booming <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> economy."

         
      
   
