
   
   
      
         
            Beyond the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX> of the IPOs
            

            Good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> and bad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX>? I hadn't thought about
The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">New New Thing</ENAMEX> in those terms, since it seemed
to me that even though <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX> had spats with various <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>--and even though he
looked at money <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, in particular, as vermin--all of them, even the vermin,
were his co-conspirators. Everybody involved in this story was in this thing
together, thinking and acting in this new way, trying to reinvent the business
world and perhaps even trying to redefine the nature of capitalism itself. (Can
you really generate a net worth of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2.3 billion</NUMEX> without
ever doing any work ? Certainly that has to rank as one of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Clark</ENAMEX>'s more
audacious experiments in capitalism!)

            Ultimately, every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> in the book is going to
turn out to be a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>--or they're all going to turn out to be bad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX>.
Let's remember, again, why we both thought so highly of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The New New Thing</ENAMEX> : It offers an astonishingly vivid description of
what <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Silicon Valley</ENAMEX> is like at this moment in history. From my vantage point on
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Coast</ENAMEX>, it seems crazy out there--and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> has that craziness nailed.
So let's suppose for a second that this ... this ... anarchy, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> calls
it, turns out to be the future of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> business--which of course is what
most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX> firmly believe. If that turns out to be the case,
we're going to look back on this book <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 years from now</TIMEX> and say, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Clark</ENAMEX> and
those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The New New Thing</ENAMEX> , they showed us the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX>. They are true <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroes</ENAMEX>." But now let's suppose that <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Silicon Valley</ENAMEX> at the
millennium turns out to be what the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">1960s</NUMEX> were when we were in college: an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intoxicating</ENAMEX> flash-in-the-pan. That is, all that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Clark</ENAMEX>-style anarchy
ultimately falls by the wayside, much of the wealth evaporates, and one day
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> wake up and wonder, "What were we thinking?" In that case, we'll look
back at <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The New New Thing</ENAMEX> and say, "What a bunch of
idiots those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> were! Couldn't they see that it was all about to collapse?"
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weirdly</ENAMEX>--and this is <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The New New Thing</ENAMEX> 's real mark of greatness--the
book will hold up no matter how this story plays out.

            There is no dissenter in The
New <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">New Thing</ENAMEX> , no <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Coast</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sage</ENAMEX> shaking his head sadly and warning that
it is all going to turn out badly. And that is perfectly appropriate for this
book, because there really is no dissent in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX>. But reading the book
provoked in me, at least, the lingering thought that it can't last. There is
too much venture capital money chasing increasingly marginal business ideas--as
exemplified by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX>'s going in to see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Doerr</ENAMEX>, uttering one sentence, and
getting funding for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MyCFO</ENAMEX>, an idea that may or may not have merit. (As usual,
it's impossible to know from the scenes in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The New New</ENAMEX>
Thing .) There is an increasing lack of rigor in Internet startups. Catch
phrases such as "business <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">models</ENAMEX>"--which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> knowingly mocks--have replaced
actual business plans. Nobody seems to even care about profits anymore. All of
these things can be found in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The New New Thing</ENAMEX> . You
just have to come to the book predisposed to look for them.

            Which, I admit, is my general bias. Yes, I believe the
Internet will be huge and potentially transformative--and might even make some
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> profitable some day in the distant future. But no, I don't think
what's going on in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Valley</ENAMEX> right now is sustainable. What was that line you
quoted? "In this new world skepticism was not a sign of intelligence. It was a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sin</ENAMEX>."

            That's me, a sinner. Care to join me in hell?

         
      
   
