
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Gore Slug It Out Over Poverty</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">BROOKLYN</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.Y.</ENAMEX>--In the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> primary, revised version, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> plays
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Avis</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hertz</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> was scheduled to give a major address on
child poverty at a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Baptist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bedford</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Stuyvesant</ENAMEX> neighborhood of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brooklyn</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. So <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> cobbled together his own proposal and launched a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">preemptive</ENAMEX> strike at a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Methodist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> in a black neighborhood in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>. This new <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> is a cheeky bastard. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX> even showed up
at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> campaign's pre-address press briefing to hand out fact sheets
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">criticizing Bradley</ENAMEX>'s anti-poverty record.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Irksome</ENAMEX> as the feisty new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al</ENAMEX> is to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Team Bradley</ENAMEX>, his aggressiveness is
already making for a better and more interesting campaign. When both candidates
lay out their proposals on a given subject at the same time, we <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> are
impelled to compare and contrast them. And in this case, the exercise is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">illuminating</ENAMEX>. What the two anti-poverty proposals make clear is that while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>
may be trying to steal <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s thunder, he isn't imitating his proposals at
all. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> agree about some of the main points--increasing the minimum wage,
expanding the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Earned Income Tax Credit</ENAMEX>, and fully funding Head Start. But they
have fundamentally different attitudes about how the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> should
go about helping poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.

            The most striking difference is in the way the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> frame the
problem. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> takes a thoroughly <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintonized</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Democratic</ENAMEX> approach to
poverty, emphasizing the need for personal responsibility and New
Covenant-style reciprocity between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and benefit-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipient</ENAMEX>. He cast
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>'s proposal as the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Next Step in Welfare Reform"</ENAMEX>--an effort to "Strengthen
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Families</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Reduce Child Poverty, Promote Responsible Fatherhood</ENAMEX>." The nuances of
language are significant. Note that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> avoids separating out his proposals
for helping the poor. Subscribing, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>, to the idea that suburban
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> don't like <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> enamored of liberal spending programs, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>
sandwiches his generosity toward the poor between more middle-class friendly
ideas. The objective of reducing (not eliminating) poverty comes attached to
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> other ideas--"helping <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> make time for their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>" and what he
characterized in his speech as "cracking down on deadbeats who abandon their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s proposal is filled with coercive and punitive mechanisms. He
would require poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> to sign "individual responsibility plans." He would
require <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fathers</ENAMEX> who owe <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> support to go either to work or to jail.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>, by contrast, talks like an only slightly chastened <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mondale</ENAMEX> liberal.
His "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Child Poverty in America</ENAMEX>" speech (available at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">billbradley</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>) offers
the soaring aspirations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LBJ</ENAMEX>'s war on poverty--though without the
programmatic reach or generous funding. "I am issuing a simple challenge
today," he said. "Let us eliminate child poverty as we know it in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> by
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the next decade</TIMEX>." In place of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clintonian</ENAMEX> buzzword
"responsibility," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> calls for "justice." Where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> favors "tough love,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> offers "unconditional sympathy." And instead of proposing coercive
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">systems</ENAMEX> to make poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> work and poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> support their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>
suggests various ways of raising their incomes to the poverty line. In other
words, where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> views poverty as partly a moral failing, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> views it as
simply a lack of money. If in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX> he doesn't offer very much money to
address the problem, it's because he knows that any <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> president
elected in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> would lack the political capital for more than a modest
"down-payment," which is how he described his plan.

            There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> specific areas that highlight these differences in approach.
Perhaps the clearest difference is on the issue of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> welfare-reform
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bill</ENAMEX>, which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> supported and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> voted against, on his way out of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>. "As a result of welfare reform, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> have moved
from the dependency of welfare to the dignity of work," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> said in his
speech. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>, on the other hand, didn't refer at all to the welfare-reform
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bill</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, which required <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> to adopt time limits and work requirements.
Asked what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> thinks now of welfare reform, his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press secretary</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hauser</ENAMEX>, said "that it had some fundamental flaws in terms of the federal
government simply handing money over to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>" and that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> continues
to harbor "some doubts about its long-term viability." The problem for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bradley</ENAMEX>
is that welfare reform is working remarkably well. Someday soon, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> will club
him over the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> with this issue, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> will deserve it.

            A similar distinction in tone and approach marks what the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> have to say
about "deadbeat dads." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> takes a kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ad Council</ENAMEX> approach. In his
speech, he called on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fathers</ENAMEX> to realize "that having a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> is a lifetime
commitment." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> would give them no other option. He wants to take away their
credit cards, on top of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX>'s licenses and passports, while attaching
their bank accounts and garnishing their wages. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> then proposes throwing
them in jail if they refuse to work. Somewhat comically, he follows this call
for relentless harassment and involuntary servitude with a proposal to
"encourage more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fathers</ENAMEX> to acknowledge paternity."

            In general, I think both <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s approaches are somewhat
flawed. Many of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s ideas seem gimmicky and poll-driven. There's a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dick</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Morris-1995</ENAMEX> flavor to the inventive punishments applied to absent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fathers</ENAMEX>, the
public <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX> who have no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>. The more substantive part of what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>
proposes--an increase in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EITC</ENAMEX>, marriage-penalty relief, an expanded
family-leave act--is fine, but unduly modest in its ambition. There are other
things we as a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> can do about poverty: offer last-resort jobs to welfare
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> and replace public housing projects with more humane alternatives.
But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> seems to lack the guts to confront the issue of poverty directly. And
despite his reputation for wonkery, most of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s ideas are far too
vague--much more so than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s. His fact sheet doesn't explain how his
measures would really work. Nor does it acknowledge how much they would cost or
say where the money would come from.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s plan has many of the opposite defects. His rhetoric is bold and
sweeping but bears little relation to the substance of his <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$9.8 billion</NUMEX> plan,
which is modest and incremental. Eliminating child poverty in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a decade</TIMEX>, which
is what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> says he can accomplish (albeit with the old "as we know it"
hedge), is simply an absurd goal. It's war-on-poverty-style over-promising
without any war-on-poverty cavalry to back it up. Continuing to reduce poverty
at the rate it has been dropping during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past eight years</TIMEX> would be a far
more plausible aspiration.

            Since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX>, the conventional wisdom has been that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> who are too
interested in helping poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> get their heads handed to them. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s
problem is that he seems to believe this. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s problem is that he seems to
believe it, too, but pretends he doesn't.

         
      
   
