
   
   
      
         
            Keep the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dung: It's Good Fertilizer</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Ted</ENAMEX>:

            Your trip sounds wonderfully dangerous. Looks like you
got your story. So are you going to do it up for someone? Could even be a book
(you might know I'm a fan of art journalism and don't pass up a chance to
promote the idea). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taliban</ENAMEX> is terribly important. A <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taliban</ENAMEX> with nukes is
even more so. Let us pray. And have a smart foreign policy. We here in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> don't think much about the rest of the world. As yet we don't
have much reason to think about them, except when we want to start bombing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> after they rise up against the awful regimes we support (saw the film
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Kings</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last weekend</TIMEX>. It makes that point
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">beautifully</ENAMEX>).

            Speaking of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taliban</ENAMEX>-type <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folk</ENAMEX>, that's what we're seeing
in Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX> here. How great for him to not only find another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> to
bully but also figure out how to get all the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholics</ENAMEX> to jump around wanting
to burn something. I think it's all right for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museums</ENAMEX> to have awful art. If
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudy</ENAMEX>'s reading this, please <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudy</ENAMEX>, open up the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX>
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Art and Leisure</ENAMEX>" section on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> and look at all the cultural stuff going on
that you never hear about or go to. It's amazing, isn't it? This, like it or
not, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudy</ENAMEX>, is a vibrant, alive, happening culture where all kinds of garbage is
allowed. And bless it. We need the crap. It's good <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fertilizer</ENAMEX>. Because a small
percentage of anything any culture at any time winds up qualifying as good. But
you need the bad stuff to keep the pipes clear. In this vast Times listing, how much contains sexuality, blasphemy, pornographic
violence, vacuous, gratuitous abuse of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> kind or another? A good amount. If
we want <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museums</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theaters</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">libraries</ENAMEX>, we have to fund them. If we want to
fund them based on a vote of how much we like and don't, then we have some work
to do. Let's start with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Public Library</ENAMEX>. You know there's plenty of
blasphemy there. Let's have <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cardinal O'Connor</ENAMEX> go through the books and pick out
the stuff he doesn't like and doesn't want us to see. Perhaps we can use that
percentage to cut the funding for that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX>. By the way, implied in all
this is, I think, the acceptance that the picture is of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Blessed Virgin Mary</ENAMEX>. I'm shocked to see <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholics</ENAMEX> all in
agreement on that point. What if I took a photo of a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">'56</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buick</ENAMEX> and called that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blessed Virgin Mary</ENAMEX>? Can we conclude that this is, to the non-museumgoing
public, all about a caption?

            More soon,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
