
   
   
      
         
            Do <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cellular Phones Cause Brain Cancer</ENAMEX>?
            

            Recent news reports out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> are giving credence to the theory that
cellular phone use increases the risk of brain <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>. What are the facts?

            Think of cellular phones as little radio <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX>, beaming voice and data to
the telephone network via electromagnetic waves called radiofrequency (RF)
radiation. Cell phones emit RF radiation with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">800-900</ENAMEX> MHz frequency, which is
close to the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,450</NUMEX> MHz frequency used by microwave ovens. The <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1,000-watt</NUMEX> power
of the average microwave oven, however, is significantly greater than a cell
phone's <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">0.6-watt</NUMEX> output. Exposure to high levels of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RF</ENAMEX>--many times the amount
emitted by cell phones--causes biological damage, but the effects of lower
exposure levels are not well established. Since this radiation penetrates the
human <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> theorize that cellular phones could cause physical damage
to cells--either through heating or another form of energy release.

            Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> dispute this hypothesis, arguing that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RF</ENAMEX> energy from
cellular phones is significantly weaker than the energy occurring naturally in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX>'s cells, and would therefore be unable to physically alter them. They
also contend that even after long exposure periods, the phones could only cause
a fraction of a degree increase in cell temperature--well within the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX>'s
normal range. In the absence of another plausible mechanism by which RF
radiation could cause damage, they say that cell phones should be presumed
safe.

            Most RF exposure studies are inconclusive. They either fail to find effects,
or have produced statistically insignificant findings. Selecting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX> for
ongoing cellular phone studies is a challenge, since the highly exposed
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">population</ENAMEX> remains relatively small, and many forms of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> may take <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> to
develop. But <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> recent <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> study found that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RF</ENAMEX> may cause brain <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cells</ENAMEX> to
react as if they were being heated (though no temperature increase was
observed), which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> hypothesized may damage cell function over long
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">periods of time</TIMEX>. Another found that cellular phone use was associated with an
increased frequency of a certain type of brain tumor (although the overall risk
of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> was not found to increase). Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> call for further research
and testing. Some cellular phone <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> are reducing possible risk by using
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">earpiece</ENAMEX> and microphone headsets that plug into the telephone and make it
possible to talk without the phone being held to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>.

            Regulatory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Food and Drug Administration</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communications Commission</ENAMEX> hedge on the issue, neither guaranteeing cellular
phones' safety nor recommending that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> stop using them. And the greatest
danger posed by cellular phones yet discovered is an increased likelihood of
car accidents involving inattentive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX>.

            (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to read the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 20</TIMEX> update on cellular phone
safety, and here to view the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX>'s RF safety guidelines. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Radiation Research</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> published a scientific assessment of the research to date into the cell
phone-cancer connection.)

            Next question?

         
      
   
