
   
   
      
         
            Only <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Losers Run</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Steve</ENAMEX>:

             Of course you're right about the
cult-of-celebrity politics; it's just that I still don't understand how the two
current <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">benefactors</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> obsession with that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrity</ENAMEX> got where
they are. On the one hand, you have <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Quincy Bush</ENAMEX>--and any romantic view
of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> unjustly toppled by a womanizing schemer is historical
revisionism, pure and simple (remember the last recession? went on for perhaps
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7 years</TIMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush Sr.</ENAMEX> acted like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hoover</ENAMEX>? didn't give a press conference for
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX>? couldn't put both nouns and verbs in the same sentence?). On the other
is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>, notable for (as you put it about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">JFK Jr.</ENAMEX>) not living up to his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fair</ENAMEX>
Deal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero father</ENAMEX>'s high standards of integrity and cojones . How can these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> turkeys be our leading <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> for
the highest office in the land?

            The answer, methinks, is that the presidency attracts
losers because it's not even in the top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500</NUMEX> highest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> of the land. The
top slots belong to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEOs</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> (and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gals</ENAMEX> who act like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX>) who really run
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyists</ENAMEX> write the bills, whose contributions fuel the
campaigns of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">lackeys</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX>. What did <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> ever do to deserve
this, anyway?

            By the way, there was a cool <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NPR</ENAMEX> spot on conspicuous
consumption <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX>. (I was too sleepy to note the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>'s name.) As
she went on and on <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $12,000</NUMEX> bottles of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1870</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX> (actually, I'd kind of
like to try <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>) and a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Park Avenue</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment building</ENAMEX> where the grungy units
start at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4 million</NUMEX> (why anyone would want to live on a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> where your
furniture shifts whenever the commuter <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trains</ENAMEX> rumble beneath is beyond me), she
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cleverly</ENAMEX> pointed out the analogies with the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">'80s</NUMEX> economic bubble and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">dot-com</ENAMEX> one ... the big difference now is that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only seven</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> ever benefited
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">from the '80s</TIMEX> boom. When this one heads south, it'll affect a lot more people
who think of themselves as middle-class.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> lead
may be the stupidest ever: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A PLAN IS IN WORKS TO PUT OFF A VOTE ON TEST BAN</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">PACT: Clinton Satisfies a Demand by Lott in Effort to Avert Showdown</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Gotta</ENAMEX>
get the crank out of the water supply down on West <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">43rd Street</ENAMEX>; what the hell
is wrong with the headline <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>? <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">First</NUMEX> of all, no one cares about the test
ban. Maybe they should, but they don't, and I don't blame them. We did the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold</ENAMEX>
War, and it was fine then, but now is now and even though the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX> still
have zillions of nukes pointing at us and nothing has really changed, it's
sooooo over. More important, how about something sexier? Try: "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NUKE VOTE NUKED</ENAMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton Sucks Up</ENAMEX> to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lott</ENAMEX>".

            And they wonder why the average age of a newspaper
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reader</ENAMEX> is deceased.

            Best Regards,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
