
   
   
      
         
            Stop Putting Words in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mouth</ENAMEX>
            

            Among the many factors that sent the stock market
tumbling <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Greenspan</ENAMEX>'s speech <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> to a
assuming that's the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Comptroller of the Currency</ENAMEX>, though I'm not
really sure what the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">comptroller</ENAMEX> of the currency, as opposed to a comptroller
of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, does.)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX>'s speech, which dealt with the "fundamental
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> of risk" and the limitations of the traditional risk-management models
financial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX> use, did not spook an already nervous stock market
because anyone actually read or listened to the speech. It spooked the market
because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX> mentioned the reality of market panics, and because he linked
"<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX> tulip bulbs" with "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> equities." God only knows what would have
happened had he mentioned "tulip bulbs" and "Internet stocks" in the same
phrase.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX> didn't make that connection, but a lot of
outside <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">observers</ENAMEX> did, leading to the inevitable conclusion that, in his
typically oblique way, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> was trying to talk down stock prices in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">general</ENAMEX> and Internet stock prices--which, though not quite as gaudy as they
were back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>, are still pretty hefty--in particular.

            This is the wrong conclusion. Although <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX> did
speak to the idea that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> are starting to see stocks as not much more
risky than bonds (an idea associated with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> of Dow <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">36,000</NUMEX> --see 
                  Slate
               's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Crapshoot</ENAMEX>" for a critique of this idea), the real focus of his
speech was something much broader, namely the way financial panics tend to
eradicate the delicate distinctions between different classes of assets,
distinctions that any market system needs in order to invest for the
future.

            The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> most striking things about financial panics, at
least in the modern economic world, are that they happen more often than one
would expect in a normal (bell-curve-shaped) distribution of events, and that
when they happen, they tend to spread rather than remain localized. What
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX> was arguing was that we have to take these considerations into effect
when we think about managing risk in the future. Specifically, he said, banks
have to set aside "higher contingency resources--reserves or capital," and
recognize the limits of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">models</ENAMEX> they're using. Panics can't be anticipated,
after all. That's what makes them panics.

            Now, you might say that this speech should have spooked the stock market, since the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> was
saying that sudden crises of investor confidence can descend without warning.
But that is something we all knew already. More to the point, saying a crisis
can descend without warning is not the same as saying that it can descend
without causes. Talking about the current stock market as a bubble without
taking into account the extraordinary performance of corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>--which
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX> himself cited in his speech--is to treat all episodes of investor
confidence as identical. They aren't.

            More important, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX>'s real point was that there
are few safe <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">havens</ENAMEX> once a financial crisis starts. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX>, for example,
during global crisis, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> flocked to the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30-year</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX> bond but were
totally unwilling to buy the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">29-year</TIMEX> bond, even though the difference in risk
between the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> assets was presumably minimal. In that sense, saying that
stocks are riskier than bonds because the stock market could crash is wrong. If
crashes determine risk, then there are very few assets that you can really call
safe. In that sense, if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX> was trying to talk down the stock market, he
was trying to talk down all markets. Which I think tells us that he wasn't
trying to do anything of the sort. His message was a simpler one: Be more
careful than you think you have to be.

         
      
   
