
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Death of the Comic Strip</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Steve</ENAMEX>:

            I'm kind of surprised that we never got down to discussing the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brooklyn</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum of Art</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sensation</ENAMEX>" show. Have you seen it? I haven't; just read the
usual reportage. As usual, I hate both sides of the debate--the conservative,
Bible-thumping <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">morons</ENAMEX> who hate anything other than their own racist and
homophobic rhetoric as well as the liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">simpletons</ENAMEX> who favor the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NEA</ENAMEX>.

            Back when I was a struggling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cartoonist</ENAMEX> trying to get my career off the
ground, I applied for a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10,000</NUMEX> NEA grant to allow me to cut my day job back to
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">20 hours</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX>; I wanted to focus on marketing and improving my cartoons so
that I could turn it into a full-time job. Guess what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NEA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> told me.
They liked my stuff, but: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cartoons</ENAMEX> are not an art form . Tell it to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill</ENAMEX>
Watterson, or for that matter to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Schulz</ENAMEX>. My response to them: Piss
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christ</ENAMEX> is? My objection to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brooklyn Museum</ENAMEX>'s show is that it's
provocation without <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">substance</ENAMEX>; it isn't so much offensive as it is dull and
predictable. But the bottom line is, post-Dada art is subjective, and there's
no way any group of government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> can render a fair judgment as to what's
good art and what isn't. Either give money to everyone who calls themselves an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>--hey, it's a better use of tax money than <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">B-2</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bombers</ENAMEX>--or don't give it
to anyone at all.

            OK, down to cartooning. I now officially pronounce the art of the comic
strip dead. Perhaps there's something running in some paper somewhere that I
don't get to read that's really great, but I haven't seen it. So as far as I
know, all comic strips seriously suck. (I would make an exception for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peanuts</ENAMEX> , which has become popular in the comics world to trash; if
that strip came out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> as is, it would be too weird and melancholy for daily
papers; it might run in a few of the more daring <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">weeklies</ENAMEX>.)

            Most of the interesting stuff is going on in the alternative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">weeklies</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruben</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bolling</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tom the Dancing Bug</ENAMEX>" is hands-down my favorite strip in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>. I'm
jealous of the ideas that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> comes up with--always topical, hilarious,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sardonic</ENAMEX>, smart. I always check out my friendly competitor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Tomorrow</ENAMEX>'s
This <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Modern World</ENAMEX> . And although I don't get to see it as much
anymore--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Press</ENAMEX> is very uneven about running it--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carol Lay</ENAMEX>'s
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Story Minute</ENAMEX>" is one of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s unsung gems--sad and ironic.

            Editorial cartooning, I assume you'll agree, has declined into stupid gags
about the news; my test for a good editorial cartoon is that you should be able
to tell the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>'s political affiliation and/or stance on an issue at a
glance. If you can't be absolutely certain, it's not an editorial cartoon--it's
a gag cartoon, in that they make me want to gag (well, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roz Chast</ENAMEX> is OK). The
brighter lights in the field, in my opinion, are the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lexington</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herald</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Leader</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joel Pett</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Philadelphia Daily News</ENAMEX> ' Signe
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilkinson</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Ohman</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oregonian</ENAMEX> , among others. Everyone
always talks about the genius of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Oliphant</ENAMEX>, and he is an amazing draftsman,
but he doesn't give a shit about anything, which makes his work soulless. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Post</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sean Delonas</ENAMEX>' work drives me nuts; the fact that such an
inept <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> and politically-dead <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentator</ENAMEX> is working full-time is an insult
to those of us who have been looking for full-time cartooning work for years
and been rejected for inane reasons--he is the worst of a lousy lot.

            The most depressing aspect of the profession for me is that the youngest new
hires at the big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dailies</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Generation Y</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">under 25</TIMEX>--are indistinguishable
from their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX>; they draw like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff MacNelly</ENAMEX>, but without
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MacNelly</ENAMEX>'s wit or intelligence. It seems that all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> want <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> is
cheap jokes without venom.

            I shouldn't leave out comic books; I like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Bagge</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Hate"</ENAMEX>), but I think
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ivan Brunetti</ENAMEX>, who does a filthy, rancid, brutal comic book called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Schizo</ENAMEX>" is
brilliant. He's so totally self-loathing I keep worrying that he'll kill
himself before he does the next <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, which would be sad since he's such a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX>. This stuff is not, however, for the faint of heart. Perhaps the most
overrated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">creator</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">comics today</TIMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Ware</ENAMEX>; his art is so-so, his
compositional skills are amazing, but he has absolutely nothing to say. It's a
cosmic joke that someone so talented is so utterly clueless about the real
world. I've read book after book by this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> in an effort to understand why
he's so highly regarded by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">comics critics</ENAMEX>, but I don't get it--maybe it's his
fondness for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">retro '20s</TIMEX> graphics. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> always relate to the familiar and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">iconic</ENAMEX> and reject what's truly new. (Journalistic conflict: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ware</ENAMEX> wrote a letter
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Voice</ENAMEX> tearing me a new bunghole over my <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Art Spiegelman</ENAMEX> piece. But
I always thought his work sucked; his letter merely reminded me of his
existence.)

            All superhero comic books are stupid, have always been stupid, and should be
banned by law--and all of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> over <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> should be deported to post-coup
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> for service in the coming war against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>.

            So who do you hate in cartooning? Love?

            And yes, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX>, I do want to hear your <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phil Harris</ENAMEX> theory of
politics.

            Very truly yours,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
