
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Deregulate New York City</ENAMEX>!
            

            The biggest news here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> was the sudden crackdown on
double-parking. Traffic cops descended on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Upper West Side</ENAMEX> neighborhoods and
midtown business <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> and issued a slew of tickets. Because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> are
accustomed to double-parking on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX>-cleaning takes place--you
double-<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11 a.m.</TIMEX>, blocking in all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are parked
legally--the crackdown was assailed as the effective criminalization of an
accepted social custom. (In some sense, it probably was, and in Moneybox
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX>, I'll have something on whether this matters.) But the more
interesting aspect of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudy Giuliani</ENAMEX>'s latest attempt to bring order to our fair
city was the way it showcased how little parking there is in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>.

            Now, as someone who drives fairly often into the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, I'm pleased by the
crackdown, since double-parkers have the magical ability to turn <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>-lane
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">avenues</ENAMEX> as wide as an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Interstate</ENAMEX> into slow-moving country <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX> will happily double-<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX>, even while they're in their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>, rather than
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">park</ENAMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> too close to a fire hydrant, even though doing the latter will let
traffic move smoothly. I'm hoping the recent crackdown will change this habit.)
And it's certainly true that most double-parkers are just <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> trying to
avoid paying for a parking <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">garage</ENAMEX>, or deliverymen trying to avoid having to
walk around the corner. So no pity for them. (Except when they're me or my
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>, of course.) But <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> want to avoid paying for a spot in a parking
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">garage</ENAMEX> because <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$8</NUMEX> seems a bit much for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a half-hour</TIMEX>. And, in any case, parking
garages are usually full. These <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> phenomena are not, needless to say,
unrelated.

            In fact, there are way too few parking <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">garages</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> relative to the
traffic, because the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, since the end of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX>, has limited the
number of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">garages</ENAMEX> that can be built. For the existing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">garage</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX>, this is a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">great</ENAMEX> deal, since it means that in most neighborhoods there's effectively no
competition. Parking real estate is not quite as valuable as land in the
Hamptons, but it has a similar characteristic: The supply isn't getting any
bigger, even as the demand grows.

            There was an idea behind the limits on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">garages</ENAMEX>, which was that if you make
it easier for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, you make it easier for them to drive
into the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, and "we" don't want that. But in a deeper sense, the limits on
garages are emblematic of the way successive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administrations</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> have
handled most things: They have consistently assumed that without a strong
managerial hand, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> would degenerate into chaos.

            Take <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">taxis</ENAMEX>. Why is it so hard to get a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cab</ENAMEX> in midtown, especially on a rainy
day? Because obtaining a taxi <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">medallion</ENAMEX> is next to impossible, and the price of
the medallions has soared out of sight. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cab</ENAMEX> fares are, of course, regulated,
but that means only that the pricing is determined by whatever
relationship--good or bad--exists between the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taxi Commission</ENAMEX> and the small
number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> it's dealing with. Opening the market to new competitors
would increase the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">taxis</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX>--that's the whole idea--and it
would drive down prices. The fear seems to be that if you opened the market,
you'd have a deluge of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cabs</ENAMEX>, marring the relatively pristine <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX>. And perhaps you would at <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>. But pretty quickly the supply of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cabs</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> would approximate the demand.

            A similar point can be made about rent control and about the haphazard
application of zoning ordinances to commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">establishments</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pace</ENAMEX> a
recent 
Chatterbox piece, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> is certainly an exception to his rule about
cheap movie tickets, and one reason is that there are too few movie <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theaters</ENAMEX>
here to meet the demand. That's partly because of the high cost of real estate,
but it's also about the sheer effort it takes to negotiate with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> to
build a movie <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theater</ENAMEX>.

            One might say, "Thank god someone is looking out for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> ,"
instead of letting it be taken over by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">developers</ENAMEX> and entrepreneurial
cab-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX>. In that sense, the implicit governing philosophy in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York</ENAMEX> has been "avoid the tragedy of the commons" (while also letting the people
on the inside wet their beaks over and over again). I don't really think a city
is a commons that will be destroyed if there isn't someone to tell us all what
to do. But if it is, then all those ticketed double-parkers are just necessary
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> on the continued path to order.

         
      
   
