
   
   
      
         
            The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">First</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> Debate

            The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> debates, which took place <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this evening</TIMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Durham</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.H.</ENAMEX>, was a little like a production of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hamlet without Hamlet</ENAMEX>.
If you tuned in to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">C-SPAN</ENAMEX>, you got to see what all the remaining minor
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> were up to. But absent the central reference point of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>
contest--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>--it was a performance of dubious value.  

            Here's how the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> who showed up were running:

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Bauer</ENAMEX> was running against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Forbes</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bauer</ENAMEX>, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX>,
wants to be the conservative alternative to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>. So right out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">blocks</ENAMEX>,
he laid into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forbes</ENAMEX>' flat-tax plan, criticizing it on the grounds that under it
some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rich people</ENAMEX> would pay no tax at all. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bauer</ENAMEX> hit him again on the issue of
most-favored-nation status for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, asking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forbes</ENAMEX> directly if he supported
keeping it. An agile debater, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bauer</ENAMEX> drew a bit of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> with these thrusts. His
other strategy for wooing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> was to mention constantly his
relationship with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX>, whom he served in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">eight</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX>'s low moment came at the end, when he made a craven plea to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX>. "I wish he would stay," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bauer</ENAMEX> lamented. "I certainly
want his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> to stay and quite frankly I'd like his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> to vote
for me."

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Forbes</ENAMEX> was running away from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Bauer</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX> appears to
believe, against all evidence, that he has a chance of winning the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>
nomination, so he doesn't want to be drawn into an intramural right-fringe
fight for <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> place. So he ignored <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX>'s attacks on taxes and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> and
tried to demonstrate his conservative credentials by getting as far to the
right on abortion as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Keyes</ENAMEX>. He did this by asserting that constitutional
protections should apply to fetuses from the moment of conception (thus
implying that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who use the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>-after pill as a form of birth control
should be prosecuted for capital murder). Despite the best coaching millions
can buy, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX> still comes across as a robot running low on battery power. He
emits his words metronomically. His hand gestures are dissociated from his
words. He raises his eyebrows and forgets to take them back down again. With
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$600 million</NUMEX> less, he would have been laughed off the stage.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX> was running against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> hopes to attract
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">independents</ENAMEX> who in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Hampshire</ENAMEX> can choose to vote in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> primary. His <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> answer, to a question about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> poverty,
decried the "growing gap between rich and poor in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> later
pointed out that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> don't have health care, which he called a
"disgrace." He also framed education as a "civil rights issue" and repeatedly
denounced corporate welfare, especially for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ethanol</ENAMEX>. Asked a blunt question
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about</NUMEX> abortion, he suggested continued, if tepid, support for overturning
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Roe vs. Wade</ENAMEX> . This ticked off <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keyes</ENAMEX>, who responded, "By the way,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX>, I think that the abolition of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Roe vs. Wade</ENAMEX> would deserve a
little louder affirmation that that." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> held his own, but his appeal
doesn't really come across in a debate format. He has <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX>'s problem. To
let fly with his caustic wit risks a boomerang effect. But restraining himself,
he seems too restrained.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Keyes</ENAMEX> was running against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vladimir Illych Lenin</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keyes</ENAMEX> thinks
that the other side actually won the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX> and that he is the only one who
knows about this. "We must get rid of the socialist <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structures</ENAMEX> that control our
government beginning with the income tax itself," he declared at the outset,
explaining that he would prefer to fund the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> with tariffs,
duties, and excise taxes. He then tried to pick a fight with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cokie</ENAMEX> about
whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catholic Church</ENAMEX> had gone socialist, too. Wearing a TV-unfriendly
blooming lilac tie and a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shirt</ENAMEX> that matched the color of his suit, he appeared
to be having some kind of fit through most of the debate. I'm not sure that his
technique of simply shouting over the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">moderator</ENAMEX> when his time is up is going to
be effective.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orrin Hatch</ENAMEX> was running for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hatch</ENAMEX> takes every
opportunity to praise his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">rivals</ENAMEX>, yielding time to his distinguished <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX>
as if they were all in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>. Mainly, though, he praised himself,
constantly reminding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> of the many important <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committees</ENAMEX> he has served on.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hatch</ENAMEX> also took credit for just about everything significant <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX> did
as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. "Frankly, if you look at it, we've had an unprecedented economic
expansion over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last number of years</TIMEX>. It's been primarily because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> got
marginal tax rates from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">70 percent to 28 percent</NUMEX> by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX>," he said. "I was one
of a handful who convinced him that should be done." More extraordinary was
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hatch</ENAMEX>'s claim that he was the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who talked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> into winning the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX>.
"I was the one who convinced <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> we should give the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Stinger</ENAMEX> missile to the
Mujahadeen," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hatch</ENAMEX> said, "now called one of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> reasons why the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX> came
down." I'd give <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hatch the Admiral Stockdale Prize</ENAMEX> in the debate--the prize for
having no idea why you're there.

         
      
   
