
   
   
      
         
            Read Any <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Good Dictionaries Lately</ENAMEX>?
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse</ENAMEX>,

            I agree that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> of our books read them
differently than we do. When the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Encarta Dictionary of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> was published <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX>, the press celebrated the event by listing
the dictionary's errors, which surely mortified <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anne Soukhanov</ENAMEX>, its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>. I
don't know if I'll ever get used to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> misreading what I write or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>
misinterpreting what I say. But it does happen all the time. I've come to see
this as a legitimate function of reading and writing. If <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gass</ENAMEX> characterizes
books as living in the mind, not on the page, he's saying to some extent that
books are the creation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> as well as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>. I know that when I
read, I turn the text into a world that is influenced by who I am, what I have
read or thought up to that point, what's going on in my life or around me. And
it doesn't matter whether I'm reading the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OED</ENAMEX> or
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Brideshead Revisited</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of my favorite
reads).

            You mentioned the example of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> living in houses
thinking they can critique <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> as if they were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architects</ENAMEX>. Well, not
everyone can design or build a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, that's true. But you know from your
experience living in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> that you might have laid out the kitchen
differently, or put the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">closet</ENAMEX> somewhere else, or made <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> smaller and
another larger. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Users</ENAMEX> of dictionaries get to use them any way they want to,
whether we like it or not. When I ask <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> how they use their dictionaries,
they tell me for spelling (now I suppose more and more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> just use spell
checkers for that), or sometimes to look up an unfamiliar word. But to some
extent they're saying this because they think that's how they're supposed to
use dictionaries. In fact many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> use dictionaries to press <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers</ENAMEX>, hide
money, or prop up uneven table legs. Or as booster seats for visiting small
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dictionary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> like you and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anne Soukhanov</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sidney Landau</ENAMEX> know
the fine distinctions that exist among dictionaries. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">end users</ENAMEX> often treat
dictionaries as interchangeable. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> popular meaning of the word "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Webster's</ENAMEX>" is
simply "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">dictionary</ENAMEX>." This is an indication of how <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people lump</ENAMEX> dictionaries
together. But I don't think any dictionary--even the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Encarta</ENAMEX> --defines "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Webster's</ENAMEX>" generically as "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">dictionary</ENAMEX>." I assume
that has something to do with trademark worries ("<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Webster's</ENAMEX>" is part of the
name of several dictionaries now), but it may also reflect an unwillingness on
the part of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dictionary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">makers</ENAMEX> to admit that the public doesn't discriminate the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">dictionary</ENAMEX> brands the way <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">marketers</ENAMEX> would like them to.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Users</ENAMEX> of language, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> living in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX>, often
wish things had been designed differently, and they often take a hand in
remodeling efforts (these may have amateurish effects, or they may be quite
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">professional</ENAMEX>). I like to ask <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audiences</ENAMEX> every chance I get, "If you were the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>, what would you change?" The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> most common answers I get
are still: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) I'd reform the spelling. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) I'd get rid of the meaningless
expression "You know." <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) There's too much swearing.

            The answers are a nice springboard for talking about:
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) how you go about reforming language, and what limitations you'd face (just
saying it won't make it so); <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) how expressions like "you know" actually
function linguistically (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> aren't saying "you know" just to annoy you,
even if that's the effect); and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) the nature of language etiquette, taboo,
euphemism, and context. (As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarence Darrow</ENAMEX> said in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Inherit the Wind</ENAMEX> , "I don't swear just for the hell of it.")

            But <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> more thing, to return to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Gass</ENAMEX>. I
thought, when I began reading your piece, that you were going to mention the
future of the book, that is, the question we hear a lot: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Will</ENAMEX> print books be
replaced by virtual books? I've been thinking about the effects of technology
on our reading and writing practices, and wonder if that might be something
you'd want to talk about--and speculate about. I myself see virtual text
expanding. I don't see us yet curling up with a virtual book, taking a virtual
book to the beach, browsing through musty used virtual book <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> looking for
that elusive something special. But I do see changes happening everywhere so
far as reading and writing are concerned, especially in my own literacy
practice. I'm perfectly comfortable composing at a keyboard. Though I love a
good fountain pen, I find that every time I have to write by hand on a pad of
paper, I'm annoyed at the inconvenience, plus my handwriting is shot through
lack of practice (not that it was very good to begin with). But I'm not yet at
the point where I'm entirely comfortable reading and editing my writing
on-screen. I'm getting there, though, and I notice I spend less and less time
printing things out, editing them at the desk, then keying in corrections.
That's what I mean by technology affecting our literacy practices.

            So how's by you?
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dennis</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
