
   
   
      
         
            Bombing the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Ban</ENAMEX>

            Everybody leads with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>'s rejection <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> of the comprehensive
nuclear test ban treaty, which needed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">67</NUMEX> votes but only got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">48</NUMEX>--a nearly
straight <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>-for/<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>-against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> vote. All the papers view the
vote as more about partisanship than nuclear policy, and all see it as
politically devastating for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> also see the vote as quite historical. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">headline</ENAMEX> says it evokes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>'s rejection of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Versailles Treaty</ENAMEX>, which
meant that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">League of Nations</ENAMEX> went forward without <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> participation.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
Today says the vote was the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time in history that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> has
voted down an arms control treaty. But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> is wrong about this, because
as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> points out, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Versailles pact</ENAMEX> was an arms
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> accord. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> also make the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Versailles reference</ENAMEX>. But
nobody quite connects the dots on what the comparison could mean for the
planet: The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Versailles</ENAMEX> vote is now considered to be one of the principal causes
of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War</ENAMEX> II. But this general level of gravity is apparent in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> 's quote from an arms control <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocate</ENAMEX> describing the "nuclear domino effect" that could have just been unleashed: "If
we don't ratify, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> won't either. And if they begin a
substantial testing program, that would push <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> to do the same. ... From
there, it is easy to foresee <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> following suit. Even <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> might think it
necessary to jump into the nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">arena</ENAMEX>." The lead editorials at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> deplore the vote-down.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> has the toughest reaction quote from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>:
"Never before has a serious treaty involving nuclear weapons been handled in
such a reckless and ultimately partisan way." And both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> go high up with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">determination</ENAMEX>: "I assure you the fight is far
from over." But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> points out that the treaty can only be brought up
again during this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Lott</ENAMEX> decides to do so.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> says, "The failure of the treaty to clear <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> raised
serious questions about its survival." But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> say
that to be implemented, the treaty must be ratified by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all 44</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">nuke-</ENAMEX>capable
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>, which implies that it is as of right now completely dead
internationally.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> says that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> wanted in return for deferring a treaty
vote an ironclad promise from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> not to bring the treaty up during
the election, but "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> feared making such a pledge would tie his hands in
the event of a diplomatic emergency." Without further explanation, this leans a
bit too pro-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> for a news <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">story</ENAMEX>--after all, although <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> might well
have that fear, he also surely wanted to have the treaty as an election
issue.

            In the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">JonBenet Ramsey</ENAMEX> case, no news is news. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> ,
and the LAT front the announcement that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boulder County</ENAMEX> grand jury
that has been examining the case for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13 months</TIMEX> has been dismissed without
handing down any indictments in the case. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> runs the story
inside.

            The LAT fronts the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Associated Press</ENAMEX>' follow-up to the story it broke
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks ago</TIMEX> about possible <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> atrocities against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX> during the
<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Korean War</ENAMEX>. The new news: There were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridges</ENAMEX> ordered blown up by
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> including an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> general even though <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Korean</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX> were
streaming across them at the time. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> runs the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX>'s story inside.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> report that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New England Journal of</ENAMEX>
Medicine features a study revealing that a big reason lung <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> is
deadlier for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> than for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX> is that the former are less
likely to have the cancer surgically removed while doing so would do them any
good. The usual socio-economic disparities between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX> don't seem
to explain this difference, because in the study racial comparisons were made
between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with similar access to health care.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> has an inspiring obituary: that of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">86-year-old</TIMEX> number one
lox slicer at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zabar's</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">deli</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Cohen</ENAMEX>, worked at the
store for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">46 years</TIMEX>, after barely escaping the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX>, which claimed most of
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>. Despite arriving in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1952</TIMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3</NUMEX> in his pocket, he
eventually, reports the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , put his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> through dental school
and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> through medical school.

            A letter to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> from a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman reader</ENAMEX> rejects the use of the term
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX>" by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> as part of their job titles, advocating instead
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairperson</ENAMEX>." <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Papers</ENAMEX> says go all the way: "furnitureperson."

            Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> report a major social change in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Reporters</ENAMEX>, just getting back to work after recovering from the grueling chef
riots there, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> inform that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> has given legal status to unmarried
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couples</ENAMEX>, including homosexual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couples</ENAMEX>, making it, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> the
largest <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> and the first <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roman Catholic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> to do so. The
headline over the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> 's online version doesn't mention the homosexual
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">angle</ENAMEX>, while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> 's headline--"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FRANCE LEGALIZES GAY UNIONS</ENAMEX>"--doesn't
mention the heterosexual angle. What's more, the latter reads more like it
slugs a story about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amalgamated Interior Decorators</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Salon Stylists</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
