
   
   
      
         
            <i><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fortunate Son</ENAMEX></i> Revisited

            It took me about an hour on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> to figure out that <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fortunate Son</ENAMEX> , the book that accuses <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">W. Bush</ENAMEX> of getting arrested for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1972</TIMEX>, was a crock (see "
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Busting Bush</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Biographer"</ENAMEX>). I say this not to congratulate myself (well,
not merely to congratulate myself) but to ask why <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Martin's Press</ENAMEX>, which
announced <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> that it was "suspending" publication of the book, was
unable to make a similar determination before shipping <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">70,000</NUMEX> copies to book
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX>--copies that it has so far not recalled, by the way. These people
evaluate books for a living. Why couldn't they smell the huge fish rotting in
the top drawer?

            The answer is that book <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX>, and especially some of those at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">St.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Martin's</ENAMEX>, are very skilled at holding their noses. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> often assume that
books are more reliable than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> because they are printed
on higher quality paper and bound between hard covers. Nothing could be further
from the truth. Book <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publishers</ENAMEX> have the lowest editorial standards in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">journalism</ENAMEX>, with the possible exception of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drudge Report</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Salon</ENAMEX> (which after putting the rumor into play in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX> and hyping the charges in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hatfield</ENAMEX>'s book , is now reporting on the scandal as a disinterested third-party
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">observer</ENAMEX>).

            In news journalism, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> assume a degree of responsibility for the
veracity of what they edit. If a newspaper <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> quotes anonymous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>,
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> will usually want to know their identity, so he can reach some
conclusion about whether they are trustworthy. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> employ
fact-checkers (whose work is premised on the books-are-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more</NUMEX>-reliable fallacy).
In book publishing, by contrast, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> avoid getting involved in issues of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reliability</ENAMEX>. Before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dallas Morning News</ENAMEX> exposed him as an attempted
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">murderer</ENAMEX> and he went underground, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J.H. Hatfield</ENAMEX> told me that his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> only
knew who one of his <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> alleged anonymous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> was. (I stipulate that I
have no idea whether this is true, since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Martin's</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> refused all
comment.) Nothing in a book is ever fact-checked. And when the contents of a
book are attacked, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> is not obliged to defend them or even to have an
opinion on the matter.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas L. Dunne</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Martin's Press</ENAMEX> under whose imprint
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fortunate Son</ENAMEX> appears, has taken this position explicitly in the past.
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, various <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> called upon <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Martin</ENAMEX>'s not to
publish a biography of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Goebbels</ENAMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">revisionist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irving</ENAMEX>. In defending his decision to publish the work (which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Martin</ENAMEX>'s
subsequently dropped), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dunne</ENAMEX> made it clear that he considered it absurd for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to expect him to judge the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>'s reliability. "I have been told,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dunne</ENAMEX> wrote in his press release, "that Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Irving</ENAMEX> is at the center of much
controversy of late and has been accused--and I do not know if this is true or
not--of denying the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX>." After making it sound like he knew about the
book only from reading about it in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dunne</ENAMEX> went on to assert that
for an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> to sit in judgment of his own books would be censorship!

            In place of editorial standards, book <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publishers</ENAMEX> have legal ones. While they
may not care whether what they publish is true or not, they do care whether
they can be sued. So <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers vet</ENAMEX> books like <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fortunate Son</ENAMEX> for libel. But
a good libel <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> doesn't charge his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$300</NUMEX> an hour to serve as a
fact-checker. He concentrates on the risk that a living <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> might actually
sue his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX>. And in an instance like this one, a libel <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> would say that
the chance of a lawsuit was next to nil, even if he suspected that Fortunate
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Son</ENAMEX> was fabricated out of whole cloth. Why? Because nonexistent sources
can't sue, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> don't sue. By filing for libel, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> or elected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> would open himself to an open-ended process of
legal "discovery." In this case, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> would be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fool</ENAMEX> to allow that
to happen even if he stood a chance of winning a judgment against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Martin's</ENAMEX>.
To sue would mean that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> would have to answer endless questions about his
past <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> use, among other things.  

            The lesson of this shameful episode is clear: caveat lector . And
caveat especially lectors of books published by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Martin's Press</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
