
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Potter</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> Caucuses

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This February</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from all over the small and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ethanol</ENAMEX>-subsidy-dependent
state of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> will gather to cast the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> votes in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>
presidential-nominating process. The method whereby this is done is understood
by almost no one (click here
for a summary of how the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> do it, and here
for a summary of how the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> do it), and has been subjected to much
intelligent criticism (click here
to read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>'s predecessor in this column, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mickey Kaus</ENAMEX>, on the subject).
But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> is not one to knock the status quo without proposing a practical
alternative. In that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spirit</ENAMEX>, he suggests replacing the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> caucus with a
Sorting Hat.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Readers</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">J.K. Rowling</ENAMEX>'s phenomenally popular <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Potter</ENAMEX> books will
recognize the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Sorting Hat</ENAMEX> as a magical wizard's hat, pointed and "patched and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">frayed</ENAMEX> and extremely dirty," that assigns new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hogwarts</ENAMEX>, the
boarding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> for aspiring <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wizards</ENAMEX>, to one of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gryffindor</ENAMEX>,
Hufflepuff, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ravenclaw</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slytherin</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gryffindor</ENAMEX> is where the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">series</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry</ENAMEX>, is assigned, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slytherin</ENAMEX> is where its murderous villain, Lord
Voldemort, was assigned when he was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> (it now houses <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry</ENAMEX>'s obnoxious
rival, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Draco Malfoy</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Malfoy</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>-wit sidekicks, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crabbe</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goyle</ENAMEX>).
Chatterbox may as well quote (from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Potter</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sorcerer</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stone</ENAMEX> ) the song the
Sorting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hat</ENAMEX> sings to the assembled new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> in full:

            

               
                  Oh, you may not think I'm pretty,
But don't <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> on what you see,
I'll eat myself if you can find
A smarter hat than me.
You can keep your bowlers black,
Your top hats sleek and tall,
For I'm the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hogwarts Sorting Hat</ENAMEX>
And I can cap them all.
Where you ought to be.
You might belong in Gryffindo
                     r ,
Where dwell the brave at heart,
Their daring, nerve, and chivalry
Set <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Gryffindors</TIMEX> apart;
You might belong in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hufflepuff</ENAMEX> ,
Where they are just and loyal,
Those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient Hufflepuffs</ENAMEX> are true
And unafraid of toil;
Or yet in wise old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ravenclaw</ENAMEX> ,
If you've a ready mind,
Where those of wit and learning,
Will always find their kind;
Or perhaps in Slytheri
                     <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">n</ENAMEX>
You'll make your real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>,
Those cunning folk use any means
To achieve their ends.
So put me on! Don't be afraid!
And don't get in a flap!
You're in safe hands (though I have none)
For I'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thinking Cap</ENAMEX>!
               

            

            The advantage of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Sorting Hat</ENAMEX> is that it doesn't tell you which candidate
is best; it merely sorts the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> according to their most pronounced
characteristics. Chatterbox can't know, of course, how the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Sorting Hat</ENAMEX> would
assign the current <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> primary races,
but in the spirit of political punditry offers the following prediction:



            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">gratefully</ENAMEX> acknowledges technical assistance for this item
from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosina B. Williams</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 11</TIMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jersey City</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.J.</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
