
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Al</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bounce</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Blue</ENAMEX>'s Plunge

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
Post leads with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s decision to hold his nose and sign
a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$268 billion</NUMEX> spending bill for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX>, a story fronted by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
and put atop the Wall
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Street Journal</ENAMEX> 's "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Worldwide</ENAMEX>" box. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> compromised with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>
because it was unclear whether congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> could have sustained a
veto and because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> wants to focus on other budget issues, like the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>' push for a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1.4 percent</NUMEX> across-the-board spending cut. (For a
budget <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">primer</ENAMEX>, click 
here.) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX>
leads with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX>'s decision to officially leave the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> for the
Reform <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Party</ENAMEX>--a story reefered by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> and fronted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , where it's the top non-local lead. The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">LAT</ENAMEX> leads with
the opening of a <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gaza-to-West-Bank</ENAMEX> travel corridor through <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>, a story
fronted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> , and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> (but not the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> ). Most travel was eastbound, from
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gaza Strip</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Bank</ENAMEX> (where there are more jobs and where it is
easier to sneak into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>). "The young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> aboard [a bus leaving <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gaza</ENAMEX>], with
duffel bags and packed falafel lunches, sang <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Egyptian</ENAMEX> pop songs, clapped, and
celebrated," writes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondent</ENAMEX>, who notes the
condescension many <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Bank</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX> have for their poorer, more socially
conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Gazan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">compatriots</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX>, a former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speechwriter</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry Goldwater</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Nixon</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX>, urged his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> to "save our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">republic</ENAMEX> before she disappears
into the godless New World Order that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elites</ENAMEX> are constructing in a betrayal
of everything for which our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Founding Fathers</ENAMEX> lived, fought and died." The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> note that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> criticized <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> for the first
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> after the announcement. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Choate</ENAMEX>, a former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reform Party</ENAMEX> vice
presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominee</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Buchanan supporter</ENAMEX>, said he hopes to schedule a
"series of debates" between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> and likely <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rival</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald Trump</ENAMEX>. Choate
tells the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ross Perot</ENAMEX> has decided not to run, but the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> still speculates that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Perot</ENAMEX> might jump in. A smart opinion piece
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> argues that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> is not an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populist</ENAMEX> so
much as a pre-war, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX>-style <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian Socialist</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karl Lueger</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vienna</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">turn-of-the-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX>. Lueger was a tribune of the lower middle
class and an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-Marxist</ENAMEX>--but also an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">capitalist</ENAMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberal</ENAMEX>, and a
mild anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Semite</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">For Ballot Box</ENAMEX>'s take on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX>'s decision, click 
here; to learn how the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reform Party</ENAMEX> picks its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominee</ENAMEX>, click 
here.)

            A new USAT -<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gallup</ENAMEX> poll shows <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore trailing Bush</ENAMEX> by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> points, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">52 to 43</TIMEX>--a big improvement over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX>-point deficit <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this month</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> also leads <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">57 to 32</NUMEX>, compared
with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">51 to 32 two weeks ago</TIMEX> (although <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> still leads in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Hampshire</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>). Buchanan lags at <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5 percent</NUMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> poll--cited in a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">separate Post</ENAMEX> story on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s first campaign
commercials--also puts the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX> just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX> points in back of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">49</NUMEX> to
40.

            Every paper fronts the death of golfing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">champion</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Payne Stewart</ENAMEX> in a bizarre
corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">jet</ENAMEX> crash. En route from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Learjet</ENAMEX> apparently
lost cabin pressure, at which point radio contact ceased. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F-</ENAMEX>16s
tracking the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> could only watch as it flew on autopilot for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over 1,000</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">miles</ENAMEX>, ran out of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fuel</ENAMEX>, and plunged into a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Dakota</ENAMEX> swamp. The LAT
says a loss of pressure at <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">39,000 feet</NUMEX> would drop cabin temperature to below
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">zero</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fahrenheit or Celsius?</ENAMEX>--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> doesn't say) and give the pilots <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">seconds</TIMEX> to affix oxygen masks before losing consciousness from hypoxia. (The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> says <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two minutes</TIMEX> until loss of consciousness--at
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">30,000 feet</NUMEX>--and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> says the loss of cabin pressure could have been gradual and
therefore virtually unnoticeable.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> says the crash may
"throw a spotlight on the widening popularity of corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">jets</ENAMEX>," but the same
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> notes that private <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> crashes have actually decreased over
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last five years</TIMEX>.

            All the papers front the death of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Chafee</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">R.I.</ENAMEX>, at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">77</NUMEX> from heart
failure. Chafee was a centrist deal-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">maker</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">champion</ENAMEX> of health care and the
environment ostracized by an increasingly conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> and an increasingly
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">partisan Senate</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> runs a first-rate analysis of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20 percent</NUMEX> drop in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX>'s
share price. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Sloan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's Wall Street <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondent</ENAMEX>, notes
that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s plunge came after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Blue</ENAMEX> announced that its mainframe
computer sales would be soft for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next six months</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sloan</ENAMEX> argues that stock
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> could have predicted this sales drop-off with a few phone calls to
mainframe <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">buyers</ENAMEX>. Yet a database search of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX> stock <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> shows that
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> had downgraded <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX> stock prior to the announcement. After the
announcement and stock plunge, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> of them downgraded. "This is what rural
types call locking the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">barn</ENAMEX> door after the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horse</ENAMEX> has been stolen," he observes.
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">For Moneybox</ENAMEX>'s take on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX> sell-off, click 
here.)

            A front-page LAT piece on the alleged <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bank of New York</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">money-laundering</ENAMEX> scandal argues that much of the suspicious <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> money is
owned by legitimate <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">businessmen</ENAMEX> who simply do not trust <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX>
or wish to avoid paying excessive taxes to a corrupt <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. "Safe
investments in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> are as rare as flamingos in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Siberia</ENAMEX>," the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> write.
"Most [<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Russian</ENAMEX>] <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> think that the only smart thing to do with their money
is to ... try to get it out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> examines the gentrification of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freehold</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.J.</ENAMEX> Once a
tight-knit but downtrodden blue-collar <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">hometown</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bruce</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Springsteen</ENAMEX> has become a wealthy, yuppified commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">district</ENAMEX>, with lots of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">jobs</ENAMEX>, high taxes, and a fleet of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SUVs</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> runs a correction that will make every high-school biology
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher cluck</ENAMEX> with disapproval: "An item on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Science</ENAMEX> page
incorrectly stated that mitochondrial <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> is found in the nucleus of cells. It
is in every <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX>'s cytoplasm."

         
      
   
