
   
   
      
         
            Do <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Statutes of Limitations Apply to DNA Cases</ENAMEX>?
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> reported that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milwaukee</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wis.</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> had filed rape and kidnapping charges against a "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Doe</ENAMEX>"
defendant identifiable only by the DNA code of his semen. (<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX>, like
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fingerprints</ENAMEX>, is unique to each individual.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> took this step
because the statute of limitations for the crime was about to expire and they
had no better way of identifying their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suspect</ENAMEX>. In cases where DNA evidence is
located, will statutes of limitations become irrelevant?

            Statute of limitations laws require <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">plaintiffs</ENAMEX> to take legal action within a
specified time in order for their claim to be valid. (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Murder</ENAMEX> is the one crime
exempted from statutes of limitations.) The purpose is to guarantee <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defendants</ENAMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Sixth Amendment</ENAMEX> right to a speedy trial and to ensure that they will not have
to defend themselves against stale evidence. (It would be difficult, for
example, to find <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> to corroborate an alibi <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many years</TIMEX> after the
fact.)

            In general, a warrant must be signed--or, in a civil case, a complaint
filed--before the statute of limitations expires. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wisconsin</ENAMEX>, where the
statute of limitations in rape cases is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six years</TIMEX>, a warrant requires a name,
an alias, or a physical description of the suspect that would allow him to be
arrested with reasonable certainty. This ensures that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> are charging
a specific suspect. It also prevents them from bringing charges in secret,
which would violate <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Fifth Amendment</ENAMEX> due process rights.

            Some defense <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> say that allowing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> to charge <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suspects</ENAMEX> by
their <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> would effectively suspend the statute of limitations because <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> is
recovered in a very large percentage of criminal cases. And if a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suspect</ENAMEX> can be
charged by his <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX>, why not charge other <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX> Does by their fingerprints, which
are ubiquitous at crime scenes, too?

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milwaukee</ENAMEX> case does not necessarily imply such an expansion of
prosecutorial discretion. In most crimes where <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> comes into play, its
presence does not definitively prove guilt. A trace of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> on a murder weapon,
for example, only demonstrates that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suspect</ENAMEX> touched it--not that he
actually committed the crime. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milwaukee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suspect</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> was extracted
from semen swabbed from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>' genitals on the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nights</TIMEX> of the attacks.
Arguably, few fingerprints (or other identifiers) would be sufficiently
persuasive for a warrant to be issued on their basis alone. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milwaukee</ENAMEX> case
would likely set a precedent only for the small set of cases where <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> is
overwhelming proof of guilt. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry Scheck</ENAMEX> took this position on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Burden of Proof</ENAMEX> . Click here to read a transcript of the discussion.)

            It could also be argued that charging an individual by his DNA amounted to
charging him in secret because few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would recognize their own genetic
code even if they read it in a newspaper. In any event, the statute of
limitations questions surrounding the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milwaukee</ENAMEX> case will be moot until
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> apprehend a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suspect</ENAMEX>, match his <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John Doe's</ENAMEX>, charge him with
the crime, and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> protest the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX>' strategy.

             

            Next question?

         
      
   
