
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social</ENAMEX> Insecurity

            Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> lead with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s announcement
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> that he plans to send a proposal for shoring up <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the week</TIMEX>. Yet the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> give the story wildly different
spins. While the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> paints <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s comments as a "concession" meant
to build bipartisan support for the measure, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">WP</ENAMEX> describes them as an
attack on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> and an example of "escalating rhetoric." The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times--which fronts the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> news in a story that splits the
difference between the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>--leads instead with a story about a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maryland</ENAMEX> biotech <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> that has made remarkable progress in cracking the genetic
code and is seeking patents for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6,000</NUMEX> of its research finds. The news has
raised fears among some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> that what the paper calls "fundamental
advances in a genetic revolution" will wind up being controlled by a handful of
for-profit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> have been trading barbs for several
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> about the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> legislation, which aims to confront a
looming shortage of funds when <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Baby Boomers</ENAMEX> retire. For a time <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> favored
investing <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">up to 15 percent</NUMEX> of current <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">S.S.</ENAMEX> reserves in the stock market as a
hedge against that future deficit, but in the face of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> opposition he has
withdrawn the idea. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> sees that as a significant olive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">branch</ENAMEX>. The
Post focuses instead on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s negative comments about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>'s own
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> proposal--and doesn't mention that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has abandoned the
stock market idea until the eleventh of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty paragraphs</TIMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> calls <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s comments part of "sparring" between the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>, and says he "returned to the political offensive <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>."  The paper
puts the news about the dropped stock market measure in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">seventh</NUMEX> paragraph,
and explains <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> opposition to that plan more succinctly than the other
papers, citing "fear that this could eventually lead to government control of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX>."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> 's off-lead reports that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Embassy</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX> is making
it increasingly difficult for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> to obtain visas to attend
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX>. The rejection rate for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> visas has doubled even as
the total number of applications has declined. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Embassy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> apparently
worry that chaos in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> economic and political life will prompt <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> to
stay on illegally in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> after their visas expire. This comes at a time,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> notes, when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> has been outspoken about the
need to bolster cultural ties between the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>.

            The WP fronts a story that examines the limits of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>'s
much touted "compassionate conservatism." <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Early this year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">legislators</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>--which has more uninsured <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> than all but one <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>--introduced a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bill</ENAMEX> designed to enroll poor <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX> in a federally funded health care
program. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>, worried that the law would also lead more <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> to
enroll in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX>, a program that requires a hefty state contribution per
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>, fought to limit eligibility for the federal program. The legislature
ultimately won the fight, "but the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> fought us tooth and nail," one
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">lawmaker</ENAMEX> is quoted saying.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front-pager reports that much of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX>'s early
fundraising success can be explained in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> words: Wall Street. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> has
amassed <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">nearly $20 million</NUMEX> in donations <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>, and the top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> of
that income are all investment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> was never particularly kind to
financial interests as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX>, the paper notes. But the relationships he
forged during his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18 years</TIMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate Finance Committee</ENAMEX>--plus a stint with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">J.P. Morgan</ENAMEX> after he left <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>--seem to have outweighed policy differences.
And the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBA</ENAMEX> championship rings <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> earned with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Knicks</ENAMEX> have
also helped, since so many on Wall Street are sports <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX>.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> front-pager reports that the newly elected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abdurrahman Wahid</ENAMEX>, is helping calm the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s unsettled political
climate with an avuncular style. But his grip on power, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> reports, may
be fragile: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wahid</ENAMEX> is frail and almost totally blind. (The story never gives his
age, though.) Even his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> began to worry when military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX> had to
help him sign his name after his inaugural speech.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> fronts the news that it's a good time to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">butler</ENAMEX> looking
for work in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> As the number of wealthy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> has soared--there are
now <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">275,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> with assets of more of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">than $10 million</NUMEX>, up
from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">just 65,000</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a decade ago</TIMEX>--demand for well-trained help has risen apace. In
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">household managers</ENAMEX>" (that's the favored term <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX>) now
command salaries <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">as high as $120,000</NUMEX> per year.

            In a lengthy cover piece in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Magazine</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Bennet</ENAMEX>
assesses the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reform Party</ENAMEX> as it stumbles toward the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> election. After
interviews with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reform</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veterans</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">newcomers</ENAMEX> alike--including <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Ventura</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ross Perot</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald Trump</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennet</ENAMEX> reports deep policy
divisions as well as plenty of eccentricities. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trump</ENAMEX> hates shaking hands, for
example, which might make pressing the flesh as a presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> a bit
difficult.) "The upshot," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennet</ENAMEX> writes, "is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reform Party</ENAMEX> is entering
a critical election torn by what is essentially a civil war."

         
      
   
