
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Men</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Work</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Shoshana</ENAMEX>,

            Let me first comment on the end of what you say--about
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> echoes of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Faludi</ENAMEX>'s findings. This shouldn't surprise you. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maine</ENAMEX> has
no global reach; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> does. When <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> feel out of it, by
comparison to those sleek, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">buffed males merchandized</ENAMEX> globally, the merchandise
that oppresses and obsesses them comes from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>.

            In a way, you are unfair to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Faludi</ENAMEX>; her interviews
reach beyond the style epicenters. But I think you are right on target in
pointing to the immense divide between wired-up, screwed-up <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> (which is
where the money is), and a quieter <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> may suffer far less from
identity crises because they are trying to get by rather than get ahead. When I
lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, it drove me crazy listening to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> complain about making
only <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100,000</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>; they suffered from epicenter-envy of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who made
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$200,000</NUMEX> and spent <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$300,000</NUMEX>. There's no gendering <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> in epicenter-envy,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX> female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hotshot</ENAMEX> is as obsessed about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who stand above
her as the male of this <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX>--which again is why I think the story Faludi
has told is about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> in capitalism, rather than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> as such.

            What her interviews show is a new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapter</ENAMEX> in the
subject <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> never talk about: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX>. Many of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Faludi</ENAMEX> interviewed
are being lumped into a new synonym for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX>; they are "losers." In the last
generation, as we know, the gap between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winners</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">losers</ENAMEX> has grown; the
wealth of the top <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20 percent</NUMEX> has expanded, the wealth of the middle <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">60 percent</NUMEX>
stagnated or declined, the resources those in the bottom <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20 percent</NUMEX> can command
has declined. As our society becomes more unequal, however, the imagery of how
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> ought to live, the ideals of self and mutual respect, are increasingly
defined by behavior and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">possessions</ENAMEX> at the top. Thus the gnawing sense of being
"out of it" that surfaces among the ordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people Faludi</ENAMEX> interviewed, the
fear of falling behind. This is how class works in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>: a shared imagery of
taste and behavior; a stark inequality of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">material</ENAMEX>, educational, and social
means in measuring up to the image of how you ought to be. And this is why,
when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Faludi</ENAMEX> uses the word "emasculation," what I think she is evoking is a fear
of diminished potency which is more economic than sexual.

            You attack, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Shoshana</ENAMEX>, the argument <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Faludi</ENAMEX> makes that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> suffer in large part from a crisis of masculinity because they have failed
"role models" in their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fathers</ENAMEX>--i.e., "My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> never taught me to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>."
I have to confess that this argument, which I've heard for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> applied to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX>, makes me, like you, deeply uneasy, though in my case for quite personal
reasons. I was raised by a resolutely single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> who in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1950s</TIMEX> was
subjected in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota</ENAMEX> to the widespread prejudice that by not living in a
nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, she was doing me untold psychic harm. In my own case, this
didn't prove so, but the prejudice in favor of nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> is deeply
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">engrained</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> life. Do you think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Faludi</ENAMEX> is reviving it?

            As you say, the myth of the strong <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> is one thing;
the reality is often quite another: often tyrants who are intimidating rather
than encouraging. My own experience of parenting is that adult firmness coupled
with irony and occasional bouts of silliness makes for sturdy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. Perhaps
what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Faludi</ENAMEX> was hearing when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> told her, in one way or another, "My father
never taught me to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>," was a complaint about <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> childhood. I know
of no <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> lead more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lonely</ENAMEX> isolated lives, isolated from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">social</ENAMEX> contact with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> unlike themselves and from adult society. You
can't be taught just by rules how to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> or a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>; you learn adulthood
for yourself, and to learn adulthood well you need far more exposure to real
life, its horrors and difficulties as well as its pleasures, than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">society</ENAMEX> makes available to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. This is why, I think, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> often
remark about <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> that they seem older, more self-possessed.

            My question to you about this book is, if <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>
are in the trouble <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Faludi</ENAMEX> thinks they (we) are, what's to be done about it?
You've written about cooperation in the workplace. Do you think the ills she
recounts might be righted if in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> there were more opportunities for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> to cooperate? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Faludi</ENAMEX> seems in part to believe a more interactive society,
less oriented to displays of potency, would ease crises of masculinity.

            My own views head off in another direction--but I'll
save that until I hear what you have to say.

         
      
   
