
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quayling</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>

            If to "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">bork</ENAMEX>" means to tar someone as a political
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">extremist</ENAMEX>, and to get a "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">lewinsky</ENAMEX>" means, well, you know, then to "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">quayle</ENAMEX>"
someone means to make some personal limitation seem so overwhelmingly
ridiculous that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> becomes a permanent national laughingstock. The
question of whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Quayle</ENAMEX> was, in fact, significantly denser than a lot of
other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> (I'd argue he was only somewhat denser) became irrelevant in
the face of an entertaining <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cliché</ENAMEX>. Try as he might, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quayle</ENAMEX> couldn't get anyone
to take him seriously as a presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>, because all that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">national</ENAMEX> press corps and the national joke-writing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">corps</ENAMEX> wanted from him was
material that confirmed his dumbbell stereotype.

            The same thing appears to be happening to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quayle</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">successor</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>'s case, the drubbing is for a slightly
more vague constellation of qualities such as dullness, starchiness, aloofness,
pomposity, condescension, privilege, and political klutziness. There's an
element of truth to these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criticisms</ENAMEX>. But by becoming a shtick, the observation
of these qualities threatens to obliterate not only <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s corresponding
virtues but also any hope of his becoming <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. Every minor misstep that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> makes becomes grist for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>-abuse <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mill</ENAMEX>. And whatever <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> does to try
to correct these flaws, whether it's playing along by mocking himself or trying
to demonstrate his authenticity and ordinary-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>-ness, only digs the hole
deeper. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> hires a bunch of inside-the-Beltway political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hacks</ENAMEX> and
pretends there's no contest for the nomination, he's a risible <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
stiff. When he upends his campaign, yanks off his necktie, and engages his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponent</ENAMEX>, he's a risible <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stiff</ENAMEX> trying to be what he's not. (For an
argument that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s makeover may be taking, see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Saletan</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Frame Game</ENAMEX>.")

            Here are a few examples of what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> is up against,
culled from <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">The</ENAMEX> Hotline over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last few days</TIMEX>.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff Greenfield</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>: "There is that problem that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>
has always had as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>, and so that when he doesn't wear a tie--and this
may be unfair, but I don't think so--you have the sense that somebody, some
clothing-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineer-consultant</ENAMEX>, said, 'Al, you know, use--we need the softer
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tones</ENAMEX>,' and then they take a focus <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>: 'You like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shirt buttoned</ENAMEX> or not?'
" ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Imus</ENAMEX> , <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10/14</NUMEX>)

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard Fineman</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> :
"He's sort of turning himself into a combination of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter Mondale</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dick</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gephardt</ENAMEX>, the lunch-bucket, street-corner <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX>--the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who grew up on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wisconsin Avenue</ENAMEX>." ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hardball</ENAMEX> , <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10/13</NUMEX>)

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">R.W. Apple</ENAMEX> of the New York
Times : "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Now</ENAMEX>, he says, he is trying to 'let it all hang out.' The very
phrase sounds unnatural coming from a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shoes</ENAMEX> are always polished,
whose hair is always combed, whose shirts and suits are always crisply pressed.
All? He doesn't even let his shirt-tail hang out." ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times</ENAMEX> , <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10/11</NUMEX>)

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jay Leno</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tonight Show :</ENAMEX>
"The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nashville</ENAMEX> are thrilled that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> has moved his campaign
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX> back there. ... Because with him there, that automatically
qualifies them for disaster-relief funds. ... Now, did you see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>?
He asked <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to join his new, this is what he called it, his new,
'rip-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tootin</ENAMEX>' campaign. ... If you believe he is going to win with that slogan,
you're either ripped or you've been tootin'." (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">10/7</NUMEX>)

            

            On the campaign trail, this mockery translates into a
damned-if-you-do, damned-if-you-don't dynamic. Take <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s endorsement
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFL-CIO</ENAMEX>. Had <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> failed to secure this <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prize</ENAMEX>, the story would
have been played as "more woe for the troubled <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> campaign" (or possibly,
"last <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">straw</ENAMEX> for troubled <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> campaign"). Gaining the endorsement, however,
merely made <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> into <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter Mondale II</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">establishmentarian</ENAMEX> whose
ability to lock up the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>'s offiical interest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> won't translate into
rank-and-file enthusiasm. Here's how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Jennings</ENAMEX> played the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFL-CIO</ENAMEX>
endorsement on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> last night: "In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>, good news--mostly--for Vice
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>, depending on how the political media spin it, in part." Memo to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Jennings</ENAMEX>: You are the political <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>.

            But there's a silver lining for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>: If the public
really demands <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> with a flair for schmoozing, smooth talk, and ersatz
empathy, then "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> fatigue" must be something of a myth.

         
      
   
