
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burgers</ENAMEX>, Not Bombs
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Ted</ENAMEX>:

            Screw the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>, and everything else for the moment.
Let's start with: The test ban is good. It's better than no test ban. And yes,
it's imperfect. And no, we won't be able to know everything everyone does in
the world. But knowing a lot of it and being able to nail a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> for
testing is better than "who cares." Fact is, we're moving away from arms
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX>. The real threat comes from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>, still. They have lots of plutonium
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> there are eating their <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX>. Someone, somewhere is converting
those bombs into ready cash. We need an all-out program to buy this stuff up.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is proposing something like that, but it needs to be the big
front-burner story for the world. Or are we counting on nuclear <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX> to
counteract global warming, producing mild temperatures along the Eastern
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seaboard</ENAMEX>?

             Also, wouldn't <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Helms</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Lott</ENAMEX> and pals
love to see the door open to testing for all kinds of Star Wars shit?
Call me a dopey <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">idealist</ENAMEX>, but I think there are still too many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who go
sick, hungry, and uneducated right here to be playing with these toys.

            How about the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> union <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> who is being celebrated by the press there
for bombing a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald's</ENAMEX>? Did somebody say globalization? Did he do it because
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald's</ENAMEX> is such a great repressive corporate octopus or it's just that they
wouldn't make him a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pâté burger</ENAMEX>?

            Yum,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
