
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linguistic Resuscitation</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Dennis</ENAMEX>,

            The issue of minority languages is one that I find very interesting, and you
raised some important questions. You have written quite a bit about bilingual
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">education</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>-only movements. But I wonder what you think about some of
the real minority languages.

            In your letter, you mentioned <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Navajo</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Breton</ENAMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Celtic</ENAMEX> language of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brittany</ENAMEX>); coincidentally, this morning I got a letter from a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleague</ENAMEX> who has
published an extensive dictionary of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hopi</ENAMEX> and is working with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">educators</ENAMEX> to help
Hopi <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> learn their ancestral language. It seems to me that such cases
are viewed rather differently in the mainstream than, say, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> have
a romantic attachment to these obscure languages, often for nationalistic
reasons. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Celtic</ENAMEX> languages are an especially relevant case--not only is
there renewed interest in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Breton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scottish Gaelic</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Welsh</ENAMEX>, but there
are revival movements for the extinct <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Manx</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cornish</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cornish</ENAMEX> revival
movement is, in general, supported mostly by middle-class <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cornwall</ENAMEX>, not the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">descendants of the Celts</ENAMEX> who originally spoke the language.)
Historical details often support these interests, as in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Navajo code-</ENAMEX>talkers
who played an important role in <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War</ENAMEX> II.

            The political movements that support <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> as an official language are not
threatened by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Breton, Basque</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boontling</ENAMEX> (a moribund argot spoken in a town
in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Northern California</ENAMEX>). They are threatened by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX>, mostly. Do you think
it ironic that there is interest in some of these languages at the same time
there is such hostility to other languages and nonstandard dialects?

            Back to "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>." While the name does have a little currency as a slang
term or euphemism for oral sex--more than I thought when I spoke to the New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Post</ENAMEX> --I agree that it won't have much staying power. The difference
between it and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Heimlich</ENAMEX>" or "sandwich," to take <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> more common eponyms, is
that there are many, many other terms for oral sex, but none for the Heimlich
maneuver or a sandwich. A good comparison is the use of "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">OJ</ENAMEX>" as a verb. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>
and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>, I collected a number of examples of "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">OJ</ENAMEX>" in the sense "to beat one's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX>," and debated entering the term in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> volume of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Random House</ENAMEX> Historical <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dictionary of American Slang</ENAMEX> , which I was
editing at the time. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX>, I thought that it was unlikely to last, and
kept it out. Based on the subsequent history, I think it was a correct
decision. It's likely that without the senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s calling attention to
this usage, it would have died a relatively natural death; instead it will be
remembered as a joke whenever her name comes up.

            Best,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
