
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Base Motives</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times lead with the decision by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> to
meet <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> in an attempt to resolve
the partisan budget differences which have left the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> operating under
a temporary spending bill, which expires <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX>
leads with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s announcement of new regulations for transplant
organ allocation, to take effect in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30 days</TIMEX>. The goal of the revision is to
eliminate, as much as possible, the current disparities in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipient</ENAMEX> waiting
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> from state to state and to maximize the chance for the sickest (but
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">salvageable</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> to receive organs <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>. The lead at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
administration's legislative proposal, sent to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, which would
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">steer Medicare</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">beneficiaries</ENAMEX> towards preferred <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> that have
agreed to offer discounted charge rates to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and to reduce patient
fees <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondingly</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> claim, says the paper, is that the
participating <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> would not be financially hurt by the scheme because of
increased patient volume. But, according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> object, fearing that such a plan will favor low cost over high
quality.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">WP</ENAMEX> leads report that the main reservation the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> have about jawboning with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> on spending is that in the past
whenever they have, they've gotten their heads handed to them. The big budget
issue, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> agree, is whether or not to tap into the current surplus
generated by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> taxes. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> quotes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> who think
that any subsequent budget agreement will tap in, but via "enough budget
gimmicks to obscure the picture."

            The LAT fronts, while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> run inside, a
report released <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rand Corp.</ENAMEX>, at the behest of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, which
says an experimental anti-nerve <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas medication</ENAMEX> given to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">up to 300,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> during the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gulf War</ENAMEX> may be the cause of the host of mysterious chronic
illnesses afflicting <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">tens of thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gulf</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veterans</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> say the report contradicts prior government findings on the
hypothesis, while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> says, "Compared to reviews done previously, it
gives somewhat more credence" to it.

            The LAT fronts and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> front-page news box features a mammoth
reorganization announced by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nissan</ENAMEX> (by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">COO</ENAMEX> sent over from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Renault</ENAMEX>, which
owns <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than one-third</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>): <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> plant closings, a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">14 percent</NUMEX>
reduction in payroll (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21,000</NUMEX> jobs), and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$9.48 billion</NUMEX> in cost cuts over the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next three years</TIMEX>. The good news: the Z <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> is coming back. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> carry the story inside.

            Everybody carries word that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Starr</ENAMEX> stepped down <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, replaced by
career <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Ray</ENAMEX>, whose big job will be producing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OIC</ENAMEX>'s final
report. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray</ENAMEX> obviously has a great sense of humor, thanking <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> for his
"extraordinary service to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> at great personal sacrifice over the past
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX>."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports that while in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> for a benefit for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organization, Calvin Trillin</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward Albee</ENAMEX> declined a proffered invitation
to meet with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarence Thomas</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trillin</ENAMEX> gave his reason: He didn't like being
told that he could speak to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX> only under certain conditions. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> 's fall-down here: the story doesn't tell the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> what those
conditions were.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> runs a front-pager reporting that a presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX> has
recommended that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> military be allowed to resume live firing exercises
on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy</ENAMEX> property in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Puerto Rico</ENAMEX>--for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next five years</TIMEX>. This in the face of
much <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Puerto Rican</ENAMEX> sentiment against the continued operation of the base, which
has been particularly strong since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>, when one <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Puerto Rican guard</ENAMEX> was
killed by a stray <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX> from a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Marine</ENAMEX> jet. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> story notes in its
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">seventh</NUMEX> paragraph that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX> registered disappointment in the
decision. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> inside effort on the bombing range puts <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> in
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> sentence. Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> make the connection between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HRC</ENAMEX>'s likely New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Senate</ENAMEX> run and her sudden interest in naval aerial training
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">facilities</ENAMEX>.

            A letter to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> makes an interesting claim about church donations:
A surprising percentage of donated monies end up supporting national
administrative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bureaucracies</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> states that his own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Methodists</ENAMEX>, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> paid <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.94 million</NUMEX> in salaries and benefits to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyists</ENAMEX>,
and another <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.6 million</NUMEX> on their conferences, travel, and office expenses.
This sum, he says, would enable the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Salvation Army</ENAMEX> to provide two meals a day
for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one year</TIMEX>, plus lodging, for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 2,800</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
