
   
   
      
         
            Don't Cry for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Menem</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Argentina</ENAMEX>

            Analyses of budget and spending battles lead at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> .
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> highlights a fringe benefit to the current spending impass:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">national</ENAMEX> debt repayment. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> notes the rise of "earmarking," a
popular form of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pork</ENAMEX> barreling, in this round of the spending fracas.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> focuses on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>'s proposed across-the-board spending cuts,
which the other papers covered on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>. The cuts are depicted as a measure
designed to leave <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> untouched and placate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">seniors</ENAMEX>. According to
another story on the USAT front, this is because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">seniors</ENAMEX> are the swing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> elections. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times leads with massive demonstrations in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colombia</ENAMEX>, where <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over 10</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> took to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> urging a swift peace between the ruling
government and leftist <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">insurgents</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> paints the debt reduction measures as a major policy event
brought about by default. Since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> can't agree on how
to spend budget surpluses, most of the money will likely go to pay off the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nation</ENAMEX>'s debt, including <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3.6 trillion</NUMEX> in public-owned <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX> bonds. This
component of the debt could be paid off in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10-to-15 years</TIMEX>, putting downward
pressure on interest rates and freeing up capital.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Earmarking</ENAMEX>, the process of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tacking pork</ENAMEX>-heavy provisions to spending bills,
is on the rise in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX>. Though most
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> say such measures benefit the majority, and help speed bills
through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> feel that earmarking undermines the
executive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">branch</ENAMEX>: By the time <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">administrators</ENAMEX> get ahold of discretionary funds,
most of the money has already been allocated, rendering the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">administrators</ENAMEX>
nearly powerless.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colombia</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> of the leftist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Revolutionary Armed</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forces of Colombia</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FARC</ENAMEX>) will try to hammer out agreements on such topics as
judicial reform, human rights, drug trafficking, and agricultural policy. The
conciliatory overtures began <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early this year</TIMEX>, after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nearly four decades</TIMEX> of
violence, when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> removed security <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> from a large
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FARC</ENAMEX>-controlled territory, but stalled when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> requested that an
international verification <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> monitor the zone. Talks began again on
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>, after the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> withdrew this request. 

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Buenos Aires</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fernando De la Rua</ENAMEX>'s projected presidential win is a
setback for the ruling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Judicialist/Peronist Party</ENAMEX>, but a victory, according to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">the Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> , for democratic capitalism.
The election marks the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peronist Party</ENAMEX> has lost power by popular
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mandate</ENAMEX> (as opposed to a coup). A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> below-the-fold article quotes an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">observer</ENAMEX> who claims that the election signals the "end of the era of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">caudillo</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strongman</ENAMEX>)." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">De la Rua</ENAMEX> has pledged to maintain the fiscal successes
of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">predecessor</ENAMEX>, included a fiscal policy that helped stem the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s
hyperinflation. He also pledges to combat the corruption and tax evasion that
have plagued previous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administrations</ENAMEX>, an angle emphasized inside the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carlos Menem</ENAMEX>, the current <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, did not seek re-election, but
is expected to remain a formidible force in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Argentine</ENAMEX> politics.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> related WP fronts discuss <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX>'s campaign. One paints
him as a reluctant but incredibly effective <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">fund raiser</ENAMEX>, whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">outsider</ENAMEX> image,
basketball <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">superstardom</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate Finance Committee</ENAMEX> background have activated
a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">super-rich</ENAMEX>, generally apolitcal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX>, including <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buffett</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rupert Murdoch</ENAMEX>. The other discusses how his committment to
old-guard liberal issues such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> poverty and health-care woes have helped
distance him from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>'s more centrist policies. The biggest problem with
these passions? There's little evidence of them in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s extensive
political past.

            
               Not exactly <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ossi and Harriet</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> runs a
front-page story that is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nearly a decade old</TIMEX>: the continued economic and
attitudinal rift between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Western</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Eastern Germans</ENAMEX> (known as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wessies</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ossies</ENAMEX>). The controversy re-emerged <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this summer</TIMEX> with a book written by a Wessi
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>, relocated to the east, who is very critical of her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ossi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX>. Aside
from lots of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ossi/Wessi</ENAMEX> name-calling (a phenomenon much older than the German
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">republic</ENAMEX>), the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> offers no evidence for its portentous claim that
nostalgia for the old <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Eastern Germany</ENAMEX> is spreading. Despite this mildly
alarmist tone, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> is quick to remind us that "There is nothing
inherently sinister about a unified <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>." One can almost hear <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Poland</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> sighing with relief.

            
               Stale gender roles: In one of its twin <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> articles,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> notes an interesting gender split in a poll of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">gentlemen</ENAMEX> preferred Bill <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">56 percent to 33 percent</NUMEX>, while <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> favored <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">48</NUMEX>
percent to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">29 percent</NUMEX>. Why? Maybe, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> suggests, because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bradley</ENAMEX>
is a former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pro ballplayer</ENAMEX>. It's an interesting assertion, but one that should
be supported by more than the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX>'s own sexist preconceptions. Without facts
to support their analysis, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> may as well argue that women
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">preferred Gore</ENAMEX> because of his sculpted jaw and tight buns.

         
      
   
