
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Unlucky Lady Liddy</ENAMEX>
            

            Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> is the presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">race</ENAMEX>, including <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Dole</ENAMEX>'s decision to
call it quits. Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>'s looming budget face-off with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>.

            Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> are skeptical of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>'s claim that she simply couldn't raise
enough money to compete with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>. She had "no message," repeat a
score of opinion <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">makers</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred Barnes</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News Sunday</ENAMEX> ), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Novak</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Hunt</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capital Gang</ENAMEX> ), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Page</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tucker Carlson</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s
Late <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Edition</ENAMEX> ), and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> ). (The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman president</ENAMEX> will, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Golda Meir</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret Thatcher</ENAMEX>, make no mention of gender, argues Capital
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gang</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kate O'Beirne</ENAMEX>.) On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">panelists</ENAMEX> agree that most of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> went to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> and note that nationally <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> leads his
challengers by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX> points. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Kristol</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> ) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hunt</ENAMEX> think
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX> could be competitive: The latest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Hampshire</ENAMEX> poll puts him only
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> points behind <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Gigot</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NewsHour With Jim Lehrer</ENAMEX> ) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George F. Will</ENAMEX> ( This
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Week</TIMEX> ) think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> could have stayed in the race had she not been handcuffed
by the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX>-per-head contribution limit imposed by the quarter-century-old
campaign-finance laws. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> may get the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice-</ENAMEX>presidential
nomination; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Roberts</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Late Edition</ENAMEX> ) notes that whatever money
problems she may have had, she was the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>'s best weapon against the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">26</NUMEX>-point
gender gap between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> has a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX>-point lead among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> a
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-point lead among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>). On the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> front, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gloria Borger</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Week</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Review</ENAMEX> ) observes a focus <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One third</NUMEX> of
those selected were <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX>, and one
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> undecided. By the end of the focus-group discussion, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Borger</ENAMEX> reveals,
nearly everyone had come around to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> un-telegenic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Speaker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dennis Hastert</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Whip</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Delay</ENAMEX>, make the talk-show rounds to support their party's budget strategy--a
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1.4 percent</NUMEX> across-the-board spending cut to avoid using the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>
surplus to balance the budget. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX>--such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carlson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Novak</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hunt</ENAMEX>--think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, as usual, has the upper hand, while some--such as
Page--think the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>'s across-the-board cut will win over the public. (A
bitter-sounding <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Novak</ENAMEX> says the "real, dirty little secret is that the
non-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> surplus has been spent for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> and there is no tax
cut and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> should be ashamed of themselves.")

            Appearing on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the</ENAMEX>
Press , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald Trump</ENAMEX> announces he will join the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reform Party</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> and
says there is "a very great possibility that I will run" for the party
nomination for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. "It's something I'm very serious about," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trump</ENAMEX> adds,
"and I wouldn't do it unless I thought I could win" both the nomination and the
presidency. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Russert</ENAMEX> grills him on the issues: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trump</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> a pre-emptive
his highest priority. He wants a "substantial tax cut in line with the top
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> numbers" and says he's opposed to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAFTA</ENAMEX>. Would he support gay
marriage and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gays</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX>? His instinct is yes, he says, but since he's
spent most of his life in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX>, he'd want to listen to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">heartland</ENAMEX> and to military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisers</ENAMEX> to get their views. He claims that his life
has been "a very, very open book"--both his personal life (which is always
under media scrutiny) and his financial life (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">casino</ENAMEX> and real-estate
industries are heavily regulated). The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> mostly snicker and scoff; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roberts</ENAMEX> calls <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trump</ENAMEX> a celebrity <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">airhead</ENAMEX> without ideas.

            Also on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Starr</ENAMEX> concludes that, in retrospect, a
separate independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> should have been appointed to look into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX>.
The broad scope of his investigation saved the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX> the cost of another
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> notes, but it hurt public confidence in his impartiality. He
also thinks that it was a mistake for him to continue practicing law while
serving as independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX>; he speculates that, had he not allowed himself
to practice privately from the start, he might not have been able to accept his
appointment as independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX>.

            

               Pensive Poppy
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX> conducts a charming interview with a reflective, avuncular
former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX>. He expresses regret that as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> he couldn't
communicate his sense of humor, his empathy, and his religious faith as well as
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">predecessor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>. He thinks there is no place for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a third</NUMEX>
party in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> politics; when asked whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ross Perot</ENAMEX> sunk his re-election
campaign, he says, "Yeah, yeah. Am I bitter about it? Not anymore. I didn't
like it [chuckling]." He claims "no animosity toward <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat [Buchanan</ENAMEX>]" ("you
can't help but like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>") and threatens to sue <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fortunate Son</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">author J.H. Hatfield</ENAMEX> for his "slanderous" charge that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> bribed a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> to
expunge his son's putative drug record. (To read <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ballot Box</ENAMEX>'s take on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">notorious Bush</ENAMEX> bio, click 
here.) He says the press has gone overboard in its investigation of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s personal life--although <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s lies in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Flytrap</ENAMEX> have only
justified the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>'s rapaciousness, he laments. He plans to parachute from a
plane again on his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">80th</NUMEX> birthday. His <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> jump "said to old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, 'Hey, you
can still do stuff--no matter what the stuff is.' " <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Interviewer</ENAMEX> (and former
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Administration</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Snow</ENAMEX> praises him for his "superhuman
humility."

            

               Last Word
            

            From <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX> 's interview with former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>:

            
               I had led a very sheltered life and my closest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> [upon joining
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy</ENAMEX>] was my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>. ... I think we lost <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX> out of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> original pilots
in our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">squadron</ENAMEX>. ... So it was traumatic. And then I saw, right in front of my
eyes, on the deck of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carrier</ENAMEX>, a chief petty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> sliced into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> parts
by a propeller blade. ... <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boy</ENAMEX>, it woke me up in a hurry. ...
            

            
               In our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> we have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX> in public life. Both of them can
interact with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> better than I did. ... I felt [<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">empathy</ENAMEX>] in my heart [as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>], but I didn't do it as well--outreach, showing compassion and
concern--as well as our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX> did.
            

         
      
   
