
   
   
      
         
            Who Runs <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Antarctica</ENAMEX>?
            

            An <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> was evacuated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> from an <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Antarctic</ENAMEX> research
station after treating herself for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five months</TIMEX>. Who lives in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Antarctica</ENAMEX>? What sort of research is done there? And who is in charge?

            At <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">5.5 million square miles</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Antarctica</ENAMEX> is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX> largest continent
(<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> are smaller), but its forbidding climate has kept the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> from exceeding <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4,000</NUMEX>. With a mean <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> temperature of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">70 degrees</NUMEX>
below zero <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">Fahrenheit</NUMEX> and a surface that is <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">98 percent</NUMEX> covered in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Antarctica</ENAMEX> has no indigenous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inhabitants</ENAMEX> and very few <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">native</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX>. Fossil discoveries suggest that it was part of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gondwanaland</ENAMEX>, the
single temperate continent, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">200 million years ago</TIMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Antarctica</ENAMEX> was unknown to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX> until <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sealer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Davis</ENAMEX> made
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">landfall</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1821</TIMEX>. For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next 100 years</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a dozen</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> shared the
continent. Some--like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Norway</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sweden</ENAMEX>--were interested in whaling and fur
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sealing</ENAMEX>. Others--like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>--were primarily concerned with
exploration and scientific research. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">First</NUMEX> to reach the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South Pole</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Norway</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roald Amundsen</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1911</TIMEX>. The continent was mapped in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 1920s</TIMEX>, setting off
an international land rush.

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1959</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> including the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> signed the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Antarctic Treaty</ENAMEX>. It guarantees cooperation and free movement among scientific
operations, prohibits military activities, and suspends indefinitely all
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">territorial</ENAMEX> claims. Under the treaty, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Antarctica</ENAMEX> is governed through
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">consultative</ENAMEX> meetings of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX>--now numbering <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">27</NUMEX>--that maintain extensive
Antarctic <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX>. Most meetings focus on environmental protections: In
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> banned <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mineral</ENAMEX> exploration for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next 50 years</TIMEX>. They
have also restricted fishing and banned sealing altogether. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> laws apply
to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nationals</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Antarctica</ENAMEX>, except when they are in foreign-operated
research <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX>.

            Since adoption of the treaty, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Antarctica</ENAMEX> has been inhabited exclusively by
scientific <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> and support <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Antarctica</ENAMEX> is uniquely suited for
many types of research, including astronomy, atmospheric science, meteorology,
oceanography, and geophysics. There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">80</NUMEX> research <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX> scattered across
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Antarctica</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 40</NUMEX> of which are active in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the winter</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McMurdo</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX>, run by
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>, is the largest, with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">80</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,000</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX>. The
settlements are isolated during the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight winter months</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX>,
when brutal weather makes air travel all but impossible. As a result, few
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> stay in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Antarctica</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than one or two years</TIMEX> at a time.

         
      
   
