
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan Cuts Hitler</ENAMEX> Another Break

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">revisionism</ENAMEX> has never taken the form of his denying
that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazis</ENAMEX> murdered some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>. Rather, he has consistently hinted,
indicated, and implied that that he thinks the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazis</ENAMEX> were somewhat less guilty
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> make them out to be. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s Good
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morning America</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> tried shifting the blame for the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> away
from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazis</ENAMEX> once again. Asked by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diane Sawyer</ENAMEX> about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald Trump</ENAMEX>'s comment
that he was a "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lover</ENAMEX>," the newest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reform Party</ENAMEX>
nomination had this to say:

            

               Well let me explain. In the book I wrote, I referred to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monster</ENAMEX>.
I say that he--he behaved like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Capone</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">his first days</TIMEX> in office and he and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stalin</ENAMEX> let loose their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SS</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NKVD</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">killers</ENAMEX> and set up <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Auschwitz</ENAMEX> and perpetuated
the massacre.

            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russian NKVD</ENAMEX> was the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">1930s</NUMEX> ancestor of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KGB</ENAMEX>. It helped <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stalin</ENAMEX> to kill
many <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">its day</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Auschwitz</ENAMEX>, however, were not among them.
To be more specific: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russian NKVD</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">killers</ENAMEX> did not help to "set up <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Auschwitz</ENAMEX>."
Nor did they "perpetuate the massacre" there. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Auschwitz</ENAMEX> didn't even begin
operating as a death <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1942</TIMEX>, long after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> ended his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">non-aggression</ENAMEX> pact with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stalin</ENAMEX> by invading the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX>.

            Claiming that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazis</ENAMEX> weren't solely responsible for <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Auschwitz</ENAMEX>
may be the single most extraordinary and outrageous thing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> has ever
said about the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX>. It isn't anyone's eccentric or revisionist view of
history. It's the fantasy of a disturbed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who thinks he can get elected
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> with the support of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Teamsters</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Duke</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lenora Fulani</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yesterday</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican Party</ENAMEX> ... today his faculties.

         
      
   
