
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lingua Europa</ENAMEX>
            

            Good <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse</ENAMEX>:

            The language front has been unusually quiet <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>: The only news I see is
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Union</ENAMEX> announcement (reported on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> Web site) that the year
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> will be <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> of language. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EU</ENAMEX> is urging everyone to learn at least
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> languages, arguing that bilingualism will better prepare <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> for the
international economy. I'm surprised no one is arguing for an international
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> language to match the uniform currency. In fact, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EU</ENAMEX> is struggling
with language issues, having authorized a set of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> languages and having
gone on record as supporting a variety of local languages as well. I assume the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EU</ENAMEX> regards an interlanguage as a crackpot idea; although there must be an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Esperantist</ENAMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> out there who will come forward to defend the idea, created
languages are difficult to spread. Quite a few universal languages have been
invented over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past few centuries</TIMEX>, and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX>, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Esperanto</ENAMEX>, have
dedicated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> even <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Esperanto</ENAMEX> serves as an auxiliary language--it's no
one's native tongue). But even if we had a universal language, it would soon
begin to break up into minority tongues. Babel myth notwithstanding, it's quite
possible that multilingualism has always been part of the human condition.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Union</ENAMEX> may value multilingualism as an economic asset, but
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> seem to think monolingualism is the way to go. We have a long history
of encouraging non-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speakers</ENAMEX> living or settling in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> to
give up their <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">language</ENAMEX>. Then we turn around and make them take a
"foreign" language in high school! I've seen it argued that the languages
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> give up are not useful ones, or ones with literary cultures worth
preserving. In the early part of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 th century</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychologists</ENAMEX>
argued that multilingualism was actually a cause of mental <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">retardation</ENAMEX>. Even
more thoughtful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">educators</ENAMEX> claimed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> should give up their language
for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> didn't have <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> in their heads for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than one</NUMEX>
language.

            For a variety of reasons, language has come to stand in for other issues: It
can mask xenophobia, signal patriotism, or reveal membership in an elite or a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">stigmatized</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> asks why we don't discuss how <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">advertisers</ENAMEX> twist language to get across their point of view or sell their
product. But in a larger sense, that is exactly what all of us do when we use
language. All words have spin: There is no strictly neutral or value-free way
of saying anything. It bothers most of us that not all language use is fair or
ethical, that it may be deceptive or an outright lie, or what we perceive as a
mistake or usage error. But lying, deception, and lack of ethics, not to
mention real and imagined mistakes, much as we may deplore them, are natural
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">human</ENAMEX>--and linguistic--phenomena. We can try to get <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to change their
language use, to make them more precise, to make them more honest, but it
doesn't help to blame the language for failings we perceive in language
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX>.

            In fact, there are many times when language should not be precise, or even
honest. Think about linguistic behavior at funerals, for example. There are
lots of times in our social interactions when if we told the truth, or spoke
precisely rather than in a more circumspect fashion, we would find ourselves
not socially interacting any more--in other words we'd get everyone so mad
they'd avoid us altogether. This too may be a goal of some language <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX>--to
anger our interlocutors may be useful, even unavoidable.

            Will there be a universal language? I don't think so. Will everyone become
bilingual? No. Will <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bureaucrats</ENAMEX> ever learn to write clearly? Don't get me
started! But none of those things is my ultimate goal. What I hope <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> will
do is what we're doing here--airing issues, exploring them critically,
interrogating our own preconceptions about language, broadening our
understanding about how we use language and how we'd like it to be used.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Ta,</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dennis</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
