
   
   
      
         
            Embarrassment of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Riches</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Lewis</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The New New</ENAMEX>
Thing is the best book ever written about <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Silicon Valley</ENAMEX>.

            There. I've said it. Said it to you (wondering, to be
sure, whether you agree--do you?); said it to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> of 
                  Slate
               ; but most of all, I've said it to
myself. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Lewis</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The New New Thing</ENAMEX>
is the best book ever written about <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Silicon Valley</ENAMEX> .
There. I've said it again. I suspect I'll be saying it a few more times before
our back-and-forth is finished <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three days</TIMEX> hence.

            From my point of view, the reason for keeping this
central truth front and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> at all times is that the book's flaws are the
kind that tend to drive me completely batty. And so my natural tendency is
going to be to harp on what he's done wrong rather than what he's done right.
And what he has done right is something big and important: He has absolutely
captured what <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Silicon Valley</ENAMEX> is like at this moment in history--how crazy it
is, how the old rules have been turned upside down, how it is filled with the
sense that anything is possible, and that everyone will soon be rich, if they
aren't already. You would think other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would have done this by now, but
they haven't. And that is because very few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX>' ability to
capture something deep with a few deftly written scenes.

            There is a wonderful scene, for instance, that comes
shortly after the book's central <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Clark</ENAMEX>, decides to start a
health-care Web site, eventually named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Healtheon</ENAMEX>. Now, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> point, of
course, is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX> doesn't really have a clue what this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> is going to
do. Doesn't matter: The venture <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">capitalists</ENAMEX> are practically pleading with him
to be allowed to invest in it.

            Then he goes out and hires <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineer</ENAMEX> he
knew back at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Silicon Graphics</ENAMEX> (which he also founded). That night the engineer
goes home only to find that his fax machine is already overflowing with résumés
from all the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineers</ENAMEX> who want in--not even caring what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> will
do. All they know is that it's an Internet startup headed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Clark</ENAMEX>--the man
with the magic touch, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> describes him--and that's all they need to know.
And then, after that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineer</ENAMEX> has hired a handful of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buddies</ENAMEX> to start the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, they fly to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> to meet with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bureaucrats</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blue Cross/Blue</ENAMEX>
Shield to explain how they're going to transform the health-care system. Which
they know nothing about. "We sat up <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">all night</TIMEX> reading all this literature about
health care," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> quotes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Healtheon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX> as saying. "We asked, 'What's
the problem we are going to solve here?' " Even more amazing, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX> by then has
largely wandered off. After all, his job (in his view) is to come up with an
idea, however unformed, and then cause money and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to coalesce around it.
("The trick," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> writes in one of those wonderful <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Lewis</ENAMEX> sentences,
"was for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Healtheon</ENAMEX> to get itself designated by the financial markets as the
Official <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health Care Sponsor of the Miracle Economy</ENAMEX>.") For this, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX> reaps
billions once the IPO takes place (as it inevitably does), and gets to be
viewed as great <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Silicon Valley</ENAMEX> visionary. It's all quite mind-boggling, and as
I say, I really think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> has done a terrific job rendering this new world in
all its insane particulars. (There is another scene I feel compelled to
mention--the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> in which the investment <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bankers</ENAMEX> and the company <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX>
meet to decide about taking <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Healtheon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>--that is, by itself, worth the
price of the book.)

            And now please allow me to gripe for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a few minutes</TIMEX>. Is
it possible that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Lewis</ENAMEX> has too much talent for his own good? After
reading this book, I think it is--and that's what made me so nuts as I was
reading <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The New New Thing</ENAMEX> . There is no problem he
can't solve, no hole he can't fill, with a graceful turn of the phrase. But
that also means that when confronted with the choice between doing a little
extra digging and writing his way around a problem, he chooses the latter every
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>. The thing that struck me particularly in this regard was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Healtheon</ENAMEX>'s IPO.
The original IPO was canceled, because at the time it was scheduled to take
place, the market was tanking, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s road show had been a bust. But
then, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">some months later</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Healtheon</ENAMEX> goes public and is a huge success. What
happened in the interim? We have no idea, because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> never bothers to tell
us. All he says is, "No one asked how a company the stock market deemed
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">unworthy</ENAMEX> was now, suddenly, desirable. It just happened." Well, that may be
nice writing, but it's pretty unsatisfying journalism.

            In fact, I don't know if you noticed or not, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX>
never once explains what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Healtheon</ENAMEX> is supposed to do. It is supposed to somehow
insert itself in the system--but how? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> has a lot of fun showing how fuzzy
the concept is at the beginning, but by the end of the book, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Healtheon</ENAMEX> is an
actual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> with an actual product that does ... what, exactly? I couldn't
begin to tell you.

            Of course, maybe the problem is that this book was
written with great haste. There seems to be a belief among <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publishers</ENAMEX> that if
you don't get your <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Silicon Valley</ENAMEX> book out fast, it will be outdated before
it's published. And maybe they're right. What do you think? And what do you
think of the amount of time <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> lingers over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX>'s damn <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX>? I'll be happy
to tell you what I think about that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX>, though I guess I've already
tipped my hand.

         
      
   
