
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekend Cocktail Chatter</ENAMEX>
            

            Is it a stock-market correction yet? Don't you think
everyone would feel better if there were an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> that could actually step
forward and say, "We are now officially in a correction," the way the
government does with recessions? Or would everyone feel worse? Regardless, the
market did take it on the chin <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>, battered by the combination of
earnings disappointments from a couple of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bellwethers</ENAMEX> and, above all, by the
soaring yield on the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30-year</TIMEX> bond. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Reserve</ENAMEX> rate hike on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 16</TIMEX> is
now a foregone conclusion, and there may already be a rate hike after that one
priced into the market.

            Of course, that means that if you're in the market, now
is most definitely not the time to sell. Instead, it's a moment to remember
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kipling</ENAMEX>. No, not <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Jungle Book</ENAMEX> . And it's a time
to wonder: Why is it a correction when the market drops by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX>, but not
when it rises by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX>? The lower price isn't any more of an equilibrium
state, and it's not necessarily any more accurate. So let's call it a
dislocation instead, and imagine that someday soon all our shoulders will be
back in their sockets. Right where they belong. On to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>'s Cocktail
Chat.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. "In a decision that will help <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AT&T</ENAMEX> expand its national cable reach , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX> affirmed an
old rule limiting any one <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> from serving <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">more than 30 percent</NUMEX> of all
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cable</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX>, but changed its definition of 'cable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX>' so that any
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> can now serve <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">36 percent</NUMEX> of the market .
Is this what they call quantum math<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>"

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. "Con <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed</ENAMEX> agreed to buy
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northeast Utilities</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3.3 billion</NUMEX> . Oddly, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bronx</ENAMEX> cheers that have greeted recent megamergers in the
telecommunications industry were absent when this deal was announced. I think
that's because no one <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">under 65</TIMEX> owns stock in power <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> anymore."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. "This is from a full-page <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intel</ENAMEX> ad in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX>
               
(punctuation duplicated exactly): <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">'from</NUMEX> a dedicated oc48 <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fiber</ENAMEX> optic ring that
can to scale to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">oc192</TIMEX>, providing network connectivity to multiple <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carriers</ENAMEX>. to
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">as many as 10,000</NUMEX> stacked servers.' It's like <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">e.e. cummings</ENAMEX> meets the biggest
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">geek</ENAMEX> in the world. And hey, what about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">oc193</TIMEX>, anyway<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>"

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. "Least surprising headline of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">'Steelmakers Are Expected To Post Weak Results</ENAMEX> .'
"

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. "Shares in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abercrombie & Fitch</ENAMEX> were
smoked for a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20 percent</NUMEX> loss <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> after the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> announced that its same-store sales for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the most recent quarter</TIMEX> would
come in slightly below Wall Street expectations. This came as something of a
shock to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Merrill Lynch</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analyst</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Friedman</ENAMEX> , who
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> boosted his rating on the stock after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> assured
him that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> was right on track. I guess the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s sales on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> were just so awful that they wrecked the whole
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">quarter</TIMEX>."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Motorola</ENAMEX> agreed to put <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">America Online</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Instant Messenger</ENAMEX> software in its next generation
of cell phones and pagers . This is the greatest
news I've heard in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX>. Now you can be hunted down and annoyed when you're
offline, too. Thought not giving out your cell phone number would keep you
safe? Well, in this brave new world, if you have a screen name, you're fair
game."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Philip Morris</ENAMEX> has
finally admitted that smoking does cause lung
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diseases</ENAMEX>. Next, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">makers</ENAMEX> will admit that caffeine
makes some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> jittery, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nabisco</ENAMEX> will admit that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">peanut butter</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ritz</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">crackers</ENAMEX> are just a match made in heaven."

         
      
   
