
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> Debate

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HANOVER</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.H.</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> performed <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this evening</TIMEX> on a
stage at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dartmouth College</ENAMEX>. He told jokes, blasted his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">rival</ENAMEX>'s proposed
health-care reform proposal as too costly, expressed "disappointment and anger"
at <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, and kissed up shamelessly to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> was also present at the event. 

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> arrived on stage like some sort of feral animal
who had been locked in a small <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cage</ENAMEX> and fed on nothing but focus <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> for
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several days</TIMEX>. Upon release, he began to scamper furiously in every direction at
once. Assuming his stool <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">20 minutes before showtime</TIMEX>, he volunteered to take
extra questions from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>. At <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the end of the hour-long</TIMEX> non-debate, he
promised to stay and answer even more. As of this writing (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10:30 p.m.</TIMEX>) he's
still at it, sitting on the edge of the stage with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, talking about
human rights in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX> and offshore oil drilling in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gulf of Mexico</ENAMEX> with a
few dozen <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Hampshirites</ENAMEX>. 

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> came across as a kind of manic political
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vaudevillian</ENAMEX>. He oozed empathy from every pore, getting all over every
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">questioner</ENAMEX> like a cheap suit. First he would ask the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> about his
circumstances, his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, or his job, in a desperate effort to bond. Then he
would respond with an explosion of gesticulation, sympathy, and agreement. At
the very first question, which referred to "behavior by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of your
administration," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> came out with a blast of empathy for emotions the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">questioner</ENAMEX> never expressed. "I understand the disappointment and anger you feel
toward <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>," he proclaimed. "I felt it myself." In fact, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">questioner</ENAMEX> didn't even mention <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> directly. Not content with the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>
debates <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> has already agreed to, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> challenged his opponent to debate
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every week</TIMEX> .

            At first, you think: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hey</ENAMEX>, this new <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>'s not such a
stiff after all. Then you think: This new <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> is a bit over the top. By the
end of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an hour</TIMEX>, the impression is of someone as desperate as he is unable to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">achieve Clintonian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX> with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>. "Tell me about your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>," he
asked a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">questioner</ENAMEX> who asked him what he was going to do about school violence.
"I have one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17 months old</TIMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>," she answered. "Which <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> do
you have the most trouble with<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> joked, smarmily.

            A clinical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychologist</ENAMEX> who asked about the problem of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMOs</ENAMEX> limiting coverage for mental-health <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> also got a full <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>-bombing.
"I guarantee you I'm committed to it," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> said.
"Give me a chance to roll up my sleeves and go to work on this. This is one I
want to fix for you ." He then told a strained
joke about managed care: An <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX> who arrives at the pearly gates and is
told by <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">St. Peter</ENAMEX>, "You can come in, but you can only stay <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three days</TIMEX>." This
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elicited</ENAMEX> groans in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> where <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">several hundred</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> watched the debate
on video monitors, as did <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s fulsome expression of thanks to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Hampshire</ENAMEX> for the wonderful lessons they had taught him.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s problem, I think, is that he has watched Bill
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven years</TIMEX>, so he knows just how seamlessly a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX> can bond
with an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>. But even as he copies the steps, he lacks the music. When he
tries to emulate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>-meld technique, he overdoes it, grossly.
The problem isn't that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> can't be personal and expressive. It's that as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">performer</ENAMEX>, he has no emotional range. When he pumps up to the volume, he always
turns it up to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>. This makes him seem insincere, inauthentic, and just
generally fake, in a way <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> seldom does. Television somehow heightens
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s plasticity. I saw him in person after the debate, when he sat on the
stage answering questions. He was calmer and seemed much less phony.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX>, by contrast, makes almost no personal
impression. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dowdily</ENAMEX> dressed and gravel-voiced, he is as close to affectlessness
as anyone who I can remember running for high office. Aside from one direct and
passionate defense of gay rights, which got the biggest applause of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night</TIMEX>,
I've already forgotten most of what he said. Challenged repeatedly by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> on
the high cost of his health proposal, he finally responded by uttering, in his
unmodulated, low mumble: "I want to make one clarification. We all have our own
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX>. I dispute the cost figure that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al</ENAMEX> has used." Other than that, he
didn't rise to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s bait.

            But running against the world's most eager <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">salesman</ENAMEX>,
refusing to market oneself may be a plausible stance. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> doesn't have
to win you over with his charisma. He just has to wait for you to get sick to
death of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
