
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Clark</ENAMEX> Is No <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">J.P. Morgan</ENAMEX>
            

            Yes, I guess I'm with you among the damned. I felt distinct relief whenever
somebody in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The New New Thing</ENAMEX> expressed a measure of skepticism. When
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX> offers a job at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Netscape</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alex Slusky</ENAMEX>, the young <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">venture</ENAMEX> capitalist
assigned to sleep under his bed, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slusky</ENAMEX> declines, saying, "He was just too
volatile for me. I couldn't live like that." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert</ENAMEX>, the hands-on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineer</ENAMEX> of
the computerized <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">yacht</ENAMEX>, thinks Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> are mad, observing that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allan</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">captain</ENAMEX>, "just sits there <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all day</TIMEX> thinking about his money.
But if you ask him what any of these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> do , he has no idea." And
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stuart Liroff</ENAMEX>, who made <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$8.5 million</NUMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Healtheon</ENAMEX> IPO, says, "History will
document this as the largest financial bubble in the history of the world
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">economy</ENAMEX>."

            I can't help trying to picture <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">J.P. Morgan</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Silicon Valley</ENAMEX>, and you can
probably guess what I think he'd think. He spent most of his life trying to
impose order on the chaos of the emerging <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> market--partly because the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> was still dependent on foreign capital, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>
tended to yank their money out whenever things got too crazy here. As <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s
unofficial central <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banker</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morgan</ENAMEX> tried to rein in the excesses of the business
cycle, stifle speculative manias, control corporate competition, keep the
currency "sound," and stop panics. But he was also looking for the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19 th century</TIMEX>'s new new things. The technological changes he helped
underwrite transformed that world as dramatically as the Internet is
transforming ours, though much more slowly. The transatlantic cable and the
railroads are the most obvious examples, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morgan</ENAMEX> bank also furnished
early venture capital for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Edison</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carnegie</ENAMEX>--and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morgan</ENAMEX> later organized <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GE</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Steel</ENAMEX>. When he bought <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carnegie</ENAMEX> out in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1901</TIMEX> to put together the giant
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Steel</ENAMEX>, he paid <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$480 million</NUMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about twelve</NUMEX> times earnings. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A few weeks</TIMEX>
later he capitalized the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporation</ENAMEX> (which included other steel <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mills</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">railroads</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mines</ENAMEX>, steamships, and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ore</ENAMEX> lands) at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.4 billion</NUMEX>, about twice the
value of its tangible assets. Nobody thought in terms of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billions</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1901</TIMEX>. The
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.4 billion</NUMEX> figure was equivalent to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 7 percent</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> GNP--a
comparable percentage <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> would be <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $400 billion</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Adams</ENAMEX> said,
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pierpont Morgan</ENAMEX> is apparently trying to swallow the sun." Other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> said
that the stock not based on tangible assets was "aqua pura." In fact, however,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morgan</ENAMEX> was doing something financially new--capitalizing future earnings--and
within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporation</ENAMEX> was earning profits and paying
dividends.

            But I know, that's the old old thing. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">ClarkWorld</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morgan</ENAMEX> would probably
be one of the suits trying somehow to harness new ideas, fascinated by their
revolutionary potential but appalled at the idea of throwing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">billions</NUMEX> at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> that exist only "in a state of pure possibility." Like you, I greatly
admire the portrait <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> has drawn of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Silicon Valley</ENAMEX> and don't think this
state of things can last. I wish I believed in the "new paradigm" that says
we're beyond the business cycle and will not see another recession. According
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> capital markets have acquired the personal predilections of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Clark</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Terrifying</ENAMEX> thought.

         
      
   
