
   
   
      
         
            You Auto Know

            Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
lead with the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> moves of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>'s new military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>: his announcement
of a unilateral pull-back of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>'s border and the establishment
of a combined military-civilian <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">council</ENAMEX> to run the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> fronts <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> but goes instead with the
hard line the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> is taking with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> on spending (made clear by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffers</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> chat shows), which will include <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s veto
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> of a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$12.7 billion</NUMEX> foreign aid bill and his refusal to sign other key
money bills until <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> assure the protection of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>
surplus. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> plays <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> on Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> and leads with the changing taste of car
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thieves</ENAMEX>. According to an insurance industry report out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Honda</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Accord</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toyota</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Camry</ENAMEX> remain the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> most often stolen, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pickups</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">minivans</ENAMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SUVs</ENAMEX> are moving up fast. The story also reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMWs</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mercedes</ENAMEX>
Benzes are not prime theft targets (there aren't enough <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the market
for them), and that car theft has been trending down since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>. Nobody else
fronts the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">WP</ENAMEX> leads.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> off-lead is slugged "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">HIS TERM FADING, A WISTFUL CLINTON</ENAMEX>
LOOSENS UP," but it doesn't really deliver much about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s inner
thoughts. With these possible exceptions: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> remains concerned about
what he believes is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>'s troubled <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">campaign organization</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) For
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several months</TIMEX> after the impeachment trial, an air of sadness hung over <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
(or so says <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> unnamed former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adviser</ENAMEX>).

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> and the LAT front stories about the latest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> crime statistics, released <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> effort emphasizes the drop in the murder rate--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6.3</NUMEX> per <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100,000</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>, the lowest since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LBJ</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> stresses the drop
in juvenile crime--although its discussion seems to take a leap since the story
mostly reports on declining numbers of juvenile arrests and hence doesn't
address the possibility that increasing numbers of juveniles are committing
crimes but just aren't getting caught. An inside <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> story goes high
with the drop in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX>-related felonies. And the inside <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> piece dwells
mostly on the absence of a clear explanation for these decreases, while also
noting <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> retrograde movements: There hasn't been a significant crime drop
among white suburban and rural <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-agers</ENAMEX>, and cities <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">between 10,000 and 24,999</NUMEX>
have experienced a murder increase.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> uses its front-page "cover story" to go long with a flight safety piece:
about how the failure of a radar-based altitude warning system was probably the
cause of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> air crashes (total death toll: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">246</ENAMEX>) that federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX>
have been attributing to pilot error. The story says that the system has failed
widely, including along some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s busiest <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airport</ENAMEX> approach
paths.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> story makes a powerful case for wondering why the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> is
backing a peace accord in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sierra Leone</ENAMEX> that provides a general amnesty for
rebel war <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> and indeed, will put <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> of them in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cabinet</ENAMEX>. After all, notes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebels</ENAMEX> there routed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2 million</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX>--twice as many as in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>--and are ultimately
responsible for the deaths of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20,000</NUMEX>. And why, pray tell, is this story on Page
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13</TIMEX>? Was that story on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> front about how some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commuters</ENAMEX> actually
like to commute really more important?

            In a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> commentary, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Helms</ENAMEX> defends
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>'s defeat of the comprehensive nuclear test ban treaty. His key
claim: Nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX> are coming into the hands of more and more <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> not
because of the absence of such a treaty but because of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
administration's failed nonproliferation policies. "This <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helms</ENAMEX>
writes, "in its shameful effort to curry favor with <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Silicon Valley</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX>,
has loosened export controls on supercomputers, putting them in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> nuclear
weapons <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factories</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> has decontrolled <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">satellite</ENAMEX> launches,
helping <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> improve its nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missile</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">force</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> has looked
the other way as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> has been repeatedly caught assisting both <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>
in their drive to build <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> of mass destruction."

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> item mentions in passing that since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Moyers</ENAMEX> has been
drawing <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$200,000</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> from an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> trying to change campaign finance
laws, which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moyers</ENAMEX> describes as having turned politics into "an arms race for
money." Here in a nutshell is the difference between a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX> and a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX>: If a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX> tries to get money out of politics, it's a career
risk. If a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> does, it's a career.

         
      
   
