
   
   
      
         
            Coup's on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First</ENAMEX>?

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX>
lead with the aftermath of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s defeat of the nuclear test ban
treaty by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>. Like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s bold headline ("<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Evokes Versailles Pact</ENAMEX>
Defeat"), <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> headline also spans <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> columns and gives a
distinctly pro-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> spin ("<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton Says 'New Isolationism</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Imperils</ENAMEX> U.S.
Security"). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> 's headline announces the international "rebuke on
[the] test ban vote" received by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>, while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times --which off-lead the story--note merely that "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton Fumes</ENAMEX> at
[the] <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>" ( LAT ) and "<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Fault</ENAMEX>[s] <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Partisanship</ENAMEX>" ( WP ). The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> lead with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX>'s tightening grip on
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Islamabad</ENAMEX>, a story off-leaded by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and stuffed by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> .

All the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> run roundup articles assessing the defeat of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Comprehensive</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Test Ban Treaty</ENAMEX> in terms of international prestige, foreign policy, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s legacy, and the presidential campaign (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> aired a TV ad on the
issue--his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> note, appeared angry at a
press conference, resolving to continue <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven-year-old</TIMEX> ban on nuclear
tests and warning that the election of a pro-test <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> could
provoke tests by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>. On the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> op-ed
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">page</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Byrd</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">W.Va.</ENAMEX>, explains why he abstained from a vote for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time in his
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">41-year</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> career: because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> didn't debate long enough to allay
his doubts about the treaty, but it was too important to vote down.

<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pervaiz Musharraf</ENAMEX> consolidated power in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> by imposing martial law,
dismissing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parliament</ENAMEX>, suspending the constitution, and proclaiming himself
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief executive</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> note that although many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> and some
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> welcomed the coup on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> (see "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International</ENAMEX>
Papers"), on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Pakistani</ENAMEX> stock market fell <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">7.4 percent</NUMEX> and the
central <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> froze foreign capital for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX>. Taking advantage of its later
deadline, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> reports that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Department</ENAMEX> finally recognized
the coup, a decision that legally cuts off <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> aid (though at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5 million</NUMEX> a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>, it's chump change). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> gets a nice detail: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nawaz Sharif</ENAMEX> fired <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Musharraf</ENAMEX> as he was
flying back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and forbade his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> to land; as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> ran low
on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fuel</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> commandeered first the air control <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tower</ENAMEX> and then the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> quotes a "senior [<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Pakistani</ENAMEX>] army <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX>" saying, "There
is no doubt in our minds that the world will never accept military rule, but we
are in for the long haul." He adds: "We have decided we must cleanse a
political system that allows corrupt <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to decide the destiny of our
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">A. M. Rosenthal</ENAMEX>--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s former <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South Asia</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondent</ENAMEX>--argues that the coup underscores the poverty of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s policy
in the region, which has long favored the efficient <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> to the chaotic,
but truly democratic, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>.

<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> medical stories in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> are like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX> and night.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> fronts what it claims is an <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">earth-shattering</ENAMEX> discovery: A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researcher</ENAMEX> experimenting on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">monkeys</ENAMEX> has determined that their brains add neurons to the cerebral cortex
even in adulthood. Such a finding would uproot <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX> of conventional wisdom,
which holds that higher mammals add brain cells only in childhood. If the
discovery translates to the human brain (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> is optimistic), it
will revolutionize our neurobiological understanding of memory--which might
turn out to be a long string of continually produced neurons that record
experience through time like a tape recorder--and promise cures for
degenerative <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diseases</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Parkinson's</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Alzheimer's</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stroke</ENAMEX>-induced
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">dementia</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , however, is skeptical. It runs the story on page <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A02</TIMEX> and warns that
"it's unknown whether the new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> are even functional. ... What's clear is
that any regenerative potential in the brain would have to be massively
stimulated in some way to be of clinical use."

The LAT fronts and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reefers the latest merger in the
aerospace industry, between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DaimlerChrystler</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aerospatiale Matra</ENAMEX>. It will become the world's <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>-largest aerospace <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>,
behind <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boeing</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lockheed</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin</ENAMEX>, and will own <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">an 80 percent</NUMEX> stake in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Airbus</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Industrie</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boeing</ENAMEX>'s main <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitor</ENAMEX> in the commercial passenger<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">-jet</ENAMEX> market. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> says the merger is a blow to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX>, which had been trying
to forge cross-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Atlantic</ENAMEX> mergers, while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> points to the increasing privatization of subsidized
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">industries</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Airbus</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> says the merger represents the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> have
integrated large parts of their defense industries--an integration made
necessary, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> argues, by technical inefficiencies revealed during the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> bombing of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>. All the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> note <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boeing</ENAMEX>'s announcement of

The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> front <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s attempt to have <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> cut
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>'s proposed budget for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX>'s anti-trust
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">division</ENAMEX>--an odd lobbying effort that, even if successful, will not affect the
government's suit against the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> notes that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MS</ENAMEX> also gave <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">an expense-paid</NUMEX> junket to several
non-profit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>, who are now pressing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> for the same DOJ
cuts.

The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> runs a long portrait of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s service in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>. True to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> struggled with his decision for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many months in the summer</TIMEX> of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1969</TIMEX>, seeking the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>, his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>, and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX>. He was
opposed to the war but worried that if he opted out a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tennessee</ENAMEX>
would die in his place. With his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> seeking re-election to his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> seat
that fall, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore Jr.</ENAMEX> enlisted in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> and served as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>. Army <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buddies</ENAMEX>
say he took some risks, but was kept out of harm's way by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brass</ENAMEX> and never
saw combat. "When and if I get <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>," he wrote a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>, "I'm
going to divinity <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> to atone for my sins." (He did, for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>.) During
his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX> presidential run, he often implied he saw combat, although he does not
do this anymore. 

On the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> 's editorial page, famed evolutionary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">theorist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jay Gould</ENAMEX> announces that he has finally found God. "This is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX>--and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nonbelievers</ENAMEX> cannot know
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spirit</ENAMEX>," he preaches. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gould</ENAMEX>, it turns out, worships at the altar of ...
Major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">League Baseball</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Red Sox</ENAMEX> victory over the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yankees</ENAMEX> in the playoffs and
over the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mets</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World Series</ENAMEX>, he says, would redeem the fallen <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">century</ENAMEX> of ill treatment by the sinners of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> and "restore the earth's
moral balance just before our great calendrical transition. ... Nothing can
explain the meaning and excitement of all this to nonfans," he says of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentacostal</ENAMEX>--er, pennant season. "No sensible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> would even try. One can
only recall <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louis Armstrong</ENAMEX>'s famous statement about the nature of jazz: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">'Man,</ENAMEX>
if you gotta ask, you'll never know.' "

         
      
   
