
   
   
      
         
            To <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Analysts</ENAMEX>: Margins Aren't Everything
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nasdaq</ENAMEX> sell-off was relatively steep (although you have to remember
that with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nasdaq</ENAMEX> near <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3,000</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">71</NUMEX> points is just not panic-inducing). And
while picking proximate causes for market movements is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fool</ENAMEX>'s game, I'll be a
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fool</ENAMEX> and point to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> important reasons: bond prices and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intel</ENAMEX>.

            With the yield on the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30-year</TIMEX> bond now at a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two-year</TIMEX> high, at <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">6.3 percent</NUMEX>,
bonds are looking like a tastier investment, and there's still a lot of concern
Neither of those things are good for stocks. As for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intel</ENAMEX>, it came in with
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">quarterly</TIMEX> numbers that were a couple of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">cents</NUMEX> shy of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX>' expectations and
got crushed as a result, with much of the rest of the tech sector falling in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sympathy</ENAMEX> (or empathy, or whatever you want to call it).

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intel</ENAMEX> is a true tech bellwether, since its chips go into most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCs</ENAMEX> in
the world, meaning that if it's having trouble, a lot of other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">companies</ENAMEX>
probably are, too. And given that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past few months</TIMEX> expectations for the
semiconductor industry have risen sharply, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intel</ENAMEX>'s failure to blow away
estimates--something it hasn't done, by the way, for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of years</TIMEX>--came as
a shock. But there are good reasons to think that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s sell-off was overdone
and that whatever trouble <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intel</ENAMEX> is having has less to do with the "tech sector"
(whatever that mythical <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">beast</ENAMEX> is) in general and more to do with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intel</ENAMEX> in
particular.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, for instance, took great pains to point out that demand for its
chips was not the problem. In fact, in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">curiously un</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intel</ENAMEX>-like performance,
it was manufacturing the chips, especially its newest chips, that tripped the
company up. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intel</ENAMEX> delayed the release of its highest-powered Pentium <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">processor</ENAMEX>,
Coppermine, and a new chipset for memory chips because it couldn't hit the
production schedules its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> needed. Had they shipped as planned, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intel</ENAMEX>
would have had no trouble meeting estimates. Traditionally, it's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intel</ENAMEX>'s
competition, most notably <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Advanced Micro Devices</ENAMEX>, that finds deadlines
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bothersome</ENAMEX>. But apparently even <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masters</ENAMEX> of manufacturing can trip up.

            There's a bigger point than just manufacturing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mishaps</ENAMEX> at stake in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intel</ENAMEX>
sell-off, though, and that's what you might call the "fetishization of margins"
problem, which I touched on in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s 
discussion of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX>'s zShops initiative. Nearly all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX>
who marked down <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intel</ENAMEX> today emphasized that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s gross margins--which
equals revenue from products minus the cost of sales for those products--fell
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the most recent quarter</TIMEX>. Now, they fell <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.2 percent</NUMEX>, from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">58.9 percent</NUMEX> to
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">58.7 percent</NUMEX>, which is statistically insignificant. But the important point,
for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX>, was that they didn't rise.

            What this demonstrates, supposedly, is the impact on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intel</ENAMEX> of having to sell
so many more of its cheap chip--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Celeron</ENAMEX>--rather than its higher-priced
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentiums</ENAMEX>. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> have got used to the sub-<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX> PC, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intel</ENAMEX> has had to
make chips that cater to that market, and naturally they earn less profit on
the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$80</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Celeron</ENAMEX> than on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">$250 Pentium III</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Analysts</ENAMEX> see this as a slippery
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">slope</ENAMEX>, so that pretty soon <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intel</ENAMEX> will watch its margins driven down to a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sliver</ENAMEX>.

            Well, maybe. But somehow I doubt it. In the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intel</ENAMEX>'s margins are
still remarkably high for a manufacturing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> (and would have been much
higher had they shipped <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coppermine</ENAMEX>). More to the point, falling margins are
not, in and of themselves, evidence that things are falling apart. If you do
things right, turning inventory more rapidly, you can make it up on volume. The
value of a business depends not on how hefty its profit margins are but on how
efficiently it uses capital, and you can use capital efficiently by setting up
a revolving door of low-margin products (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wal-Mart</ENAMEX>), a steady stream of
high-margin products (most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX>), or a mix of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> (which is where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intel</ENAMEX> is
going). So let's wait a little while before deciding that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intel</ENAMEX> is really on
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> to destruction.

         
      
   
