
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Write Off Tice</ENAMEX> on Tyco
            

            With absolutely no malice aforethought (honest, it's just happened this
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moneybox</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> has been devoted to the thoroughly scintillating
issues of double-parking and corporate accounting. I promise <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX> to
return to our usual diet of sex and scandal. But in any case, class, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s
topic is "write-off charges after acquisitions: good or evil<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>"

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hey</ENAMEX>, you in the back row, stop snoring! And you, put down that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Game Boy</ENAMEX>!

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ahem</ENAMEX>. Actually, write-offs have been in the news <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all week</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intel</ENAMEX>
reported its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">third-quarter</TIMEX> results, which included a hefty write-off related to
its acquisition of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Level One Communications</ENAMEX>, upon which some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentators</ENAMEX> cast
a jaundiced eye. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Motorola</ENAMEX>, meanwhile, announced that it would be taking a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$700</NUMEX>
million write-off because of its investment in troubled satellite-phone company
Iridium, and added that it might have to take <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">an additional $350 million</NUMEX>
write-off in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next quarter</TIMEX>. Those write-offs were generally described as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sensible</ENAMEX>, since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iridium</ENAMEX> may very well turn out to be a complete bust, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Motorola</ENAMEX> needs to make sure it has enough money on hand to account for its
losses from the investment.

            The biggest write-off-related news, though, has to do with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tyco</ENAMEX>, which until
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> has been one of the hottest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> and hottest stocks in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>.
This is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tyco International</ENAMEX>, not <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tyco Toys</ENAMEX>. Along with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GE</ENAMEX>, it's one of the few
truly successful industrial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">conglomerates</ENAMEX> left in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, with lines of
business ranging from disposable medical products to underwater
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">telecommunications</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tyco</ENAMEX> has turned itself into a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$30 billion</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> through
an aggressive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">program</ENAMEX> of acquisitions (a total of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">110</NUMEX> in the last <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven years</TIMEX>),
acquisitions that it has done a rather remarkable job of integrating into its
broader management structure.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This week</TIMEX>, though, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Tice</ENAMEX>, who runs the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudent Bear Fund</ENAMEX> out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>,
issued a report calling into question "the quality of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tyco</ENAMEX>'s earnings," which
is a nice way of saying <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tice</ENAMEX> is suggesting that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tyco</ENAMEX>'s acquisition-driven
strategy may be a way of masking slow growth in its underlying business. In
particular, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tice</ENAMEX> pointed to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tyco</ENAMEX>'s hefty write-offs of its acquisition costs,
write-offs that have totaled something like <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3.9 billion</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the last four</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Companies</ENAMEX> take one-time write-offs because they're better than having to
write off a little bit <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each year</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Investors</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> tend to treat large
write-offs as one-time events, and therefore disregard them. Skeptical
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tice</ENAMEX>, don't like this, especially when--as in the case of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tyco</ENAMEX>--a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> is taking large write-offs <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year after year</TIMEX>. The write-off, in
the minds of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bears</ENAMEX>, can be a way for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> to hide the costs of
acquisitions.

            This critique of write-offs is completely wrongheaded. If the cost of
acquisition is hidden by a write-off, it's hidden in plain sight, since the
company announces it quite publicly. And while it's possible that there are
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> who get tricked by write-offs into believing that an acquisition was
free, it's also true that there are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who still believe their fates are
governed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Companies</ENAMEX> are no more responsible for the former than
the latter. The market as a whole cannot be systematically deluded by
accounting gimmicks, as long as the gimmicks are publicly disclosed.

            Here, though, we get into the other potential problem with write-offs.
Essentially, when a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> takes a write-off with regard to an acquisition,
it's setting aside a reserve of money that it says it believes it will need to
complete the acquisition. The danger is that an unscrupulous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> will set
aside too much money--since with a big write-off <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> tend to disregard
the hit to earnings--and then use the excess to make its bottom line look
better in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">future years</TIMEX>. In other words, I set aside <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3 billion</NUMEX> to pay for the
acquisition of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Company X</ENAMEX>, but in reality it only costs me <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2.8 billion</NUMEX>, giving
me <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$200 million</NUMEX> that I can feed back into my income statement in upcoming
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. You need a couple of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">pennies</NUMEX> of income to meet Wall Street estimates?
You got 'em.

            This, for instance, is exactly what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sunbeam</ENAMEX> did when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Dunlap</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX>.
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dunlap</ENAMEX> denies knowing about the shenanigans that took place under his watch.)
And although <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tice</ENAMEX> hasn't come out and said it, this is what he's implying may
(or could) be happening at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tyco</ENAMEX>. The charges have had a dramatic effect,
driving the stock down <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">6 percent</NUMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> and another <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX> on
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, even though the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> denounced the charges as utterly
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">baseless</ENAMEX> and just about every Wall Street <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> reiterated "buy" ratings on the
stock.

            Looking at the numbers, I think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tice</ENAMEX> is completely off base about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tyco</ENAMEX>. And,
in theory, feeding a write-off reserve back into operating income shouldn't
even be possible. The reality, though, is that this kind of stuff still happens
all the time (even though eventually everyone does seem to get caught). And
Tice was onto <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunbeam</ENAMEX> before almost anyone else. But to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> with a hammer
everything looks like a nail. Write-offs themselves are not the problem. It's
the lack of transparency in the way that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>--like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sunbeam</ENAMEX>, and not like
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tyco</ENAMEX>--use them that is.

         
      
   
