
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Clark</ENAMEX>, Ubergeek
            

            Nice work with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodman-Jordan</ENAMEX> analogy: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thanks</ENAMEX>. I think you're right that
the central problem with <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The New New Thing</ENAMEX> is the exaggerated claims it
makes for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Clark</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Man Who Single-handedly Changed</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Silicon Valley</ENAMEX>--and
therefore modern economic life. Clearly, as we've both been saying, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Clark</ENAMEX>
played an astonishing and fascinating (and probably not-yet-finished) role in
what has happened. But my guess, too, would be that the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">cyber-revolution</ENAMEX> would
have happened sooner or later anyway, maybe in somewhat different form, with
other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX>. Your suggestion that the venture <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">capitalist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Doerr</ENAMEX> may have
done even more to change the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX> than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX> would probably enrage the
latter, since he seems--at least as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> tells it--to regard the money <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> as
lower forms of life ("the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sucker fish</ENAMEX> of economic growth").

            To make his case, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> offers up some big pronouncements. For instance,
summarizing the New Growth Theory devised by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Romer</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lewis</ENAMEX>
says that now "wealth came from the human imagination," and concludes that "the
new theory conferred a stunning new status upon innovation." Am I missing
something? Is this news? What about the old-fangled <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eli Whitney</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Edison</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander Graham Bell</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andrew Carnegie</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> goes on:

            

               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prime Mover of Wealth</ENAMEX> was no longer a great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">industrialist</ENAMEX> who rode herd
on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of corporate slaves, or the great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX> who rode <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">herd</ENAMEX> on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nation</ENAMEX>'s finances, or the great Wall Street <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tycoon</ENAMEX> who bankrolled a new
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">enterprise</ENAMEX>. He was the geek holed up in his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">basement</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all weekend</TIMEX> discovering
new things to do with his computer. He was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Clark</ENAMEX>.

            

            There is of course a huge difference between a physical light bulb and an
abstract computer idea, and the revolution in information technology really
has, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Greenspan</ENAMEX> puts it, "altered the structure of the way the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">economy</ENAMEX> works." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX>, representing the technogeeks, is now able to dictate
terms to venture <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">capitalists</ENAMEX>, but as you pointed out <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX>, the biggest
change in the way <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Silicon Valley</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">works</ENAMEX> seems to have come with the Netscape
IPO, which proved that you don't have to earn profits before taking take a
company <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>. Later, regarding the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Healtheon</ENAMEX> IPO, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> writes, "In this new
world skepticism was not a sign of intelligence. It was a sin." Actually, it
probably just meant missing out on all the money.

            I think there's another big problem here as well, connected to the question
you asked about the motive <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis ascribes to Clark</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Netscape</ENAMEX> IPO--that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX> did it only because he wanted money for his new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX>. I don't buy that
either. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> says about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX> at the outset that "you didn't interact with him
so much as hitch a ride on the back of his life"--and that "the only way to
spend time with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Clark</ENAMEX> was to leap onto one of his machines." He gets a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">great</ENAMEX> ride, and so do we, but it's impossible not to want to know more about
what is going on under the surface--about why some of these things happen--and
on the subject of "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>," this book is odd. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> says that the only
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">creatures Clark</ENAMEX> really trusts are machines. It would have been interesting to
hear from or about his <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wives</ENAMEX> (one of them current: Her name comes up just
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of times</TIMEX>, and she never enters the story). Maybe <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wives</ENAMEX> were declared
off limits; if so, that would have been useful to know. After the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>
left him, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX> went through a severe-sounding depression. Trying to explain
how he made the leap from (in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lewis</ENAMEX>' words) "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty-eight-year-old</TIMEX> unsuccessful
college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> with a warning label on his forehead to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founder</ENAMEX> of a
multibillion-dollar <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporation</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX> says he developed "this maniacal
passion for wanting to achieve something . I guess it was a little bit of
self-imposed psychology." That, like the "reason" for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Netscape</ENAMEX> IPO, is
it.

            Still, to revert to our basketball analogy, it would be hard to get inside
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dennis Rodman</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> times <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> tries to tell us something quite
surprising about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX>, but we never actually see it: Faced with a new
situation, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX> "wanted badly to do what was expected of him. It was only
after he determined that this was somehow impossible that he went ahead and did
whatever he wanted." "Very deep inside him <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX> harbored the desire to be a
good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>." "He really did feel some strong impulse to meet other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s
expectations of him." I'm not sure what we're supposed to make of this. Near
the end, having brought out in a scene you've described that no amount of money
will ever be enough for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> concludes with a poignant but still opaque
image that "the best and most lasting motive for wanting to change the way
things are is to be unhappy with the way things are. ... No matter how well <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jim</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX> did for himself, it was always <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX> in his heart, and he
was lying awake."

            Maybe <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more tomorrow</TIMEX> on the good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> and the bad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> in this story?

         
      
   
