
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bennett</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cultural-Decline Decline</ENAMEX>

            What's a conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeremiah</ENAMEX> to do? Violent crime is down, divorce is
down, the welfare rolls are dwindling, fewer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> are having abortions, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SAT</ENAMEX> scores and charitable giving are on the rise. This is the dilemma facing
former education <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> and drug <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">czar</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Bennett</ENAMEX>, who this morning held
a press conference in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> to unveil the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> edition of his book
The Index of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leading Cultural Indicators</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX> is
battling the inconvenient onslaught of good news with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">strategems</ENAMEX>-- retreat , partisanship , and dishonesty .

            

               
                  <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. Retreat. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX> concedes in the new book that since the
appearance of his first Index in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>, "there have been many significant
positive developments," and he cites them. He also tells <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>, "I have
amended some of my own prior views about the efficacy of politics and public
policy."

               In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1994</TIMEX> edition, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX> wrote:

               

                  
                     <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> of social decomposition are challenging--and in some
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">instances</ENAMEX>, overtaking--the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> of social composition. And when decomposition
takes hold, it exacts an enormous human cost. Unless these exploding social
pathologies are reversed, they will lead to the decline and perhaps even to the
fall of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> republic
                      [italics <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX>'s] . ... They seem
impervious to government spending on their alleviation, even very large amounts
of spending.
                  

               

               The new edition is considerably more sanguine (it could hardly be gloomier).
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX> writes, "It turns out that some social pathologies are less resistant
to legislative action and political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> than I once thought." This
follows a trend in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX>'s thinking traceable to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at least 1997</TIMEX>, when he told
a gathering of his fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> that "these are times in which
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> are going to have to face the fact that there is some good news
on the landscape. We're going to have to live with it." (The quote is from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Whitman</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Optimism Gap</ENAMEX> .) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Earlier this month</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX> spoke
in a similar vein when he defended an offhand swipe at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Bork</ENAMEX>'s sourpuss
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tome Slouching Towards Gomorrah</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> made
in a recent speech on education. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX> had reviewed that speech before <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>
gave it, though he emphasized at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s press conference that he didn't
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">insert the Bork swipe</ENAMEX>, and that when he read it he didn't really think
of it as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bork</ENAMEX> swipe so much as a "synecdoche" for the excessive social-issues
pessimism that is common among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX>. (For a fuller discussion of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Slouching Towards Gomorrah</ENAMEX> flap, click 
here.)

               
                  <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Partisanship</ENAMEX>. Although <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX> now concedes that many social
problems have eased since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>, he takes care not to give the credit to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, who has occupied the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>. How could he? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX>,
after all, nearly became <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Committee</ENAMEX> a few
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years back</TIMEX>. At <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s press conference, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX> cited as examples of the
"progress on key social indicators" during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1990s</TIMEX> the drop in violent crime
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> and the drastically reduced welfare rolls in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wisconsin</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michigan</ENAMEX>. It was hard not to notice that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governors</ENAMEX> who
presided over these jurisdictions for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last several years</TIMEX> were <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>.
When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> asked about any contribution the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>
may have made, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX> said "I think most of the action we talk about has been
at the state and local level." He then conceded that the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> welfare-reform
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bill</ENAMEX> was significant, and said, "I will give credit to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> for
signing that welfare legislation." But in the next breath he said that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
"didn't want to sign it" and was pushed to do so by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>-controlled
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>.

               
                  <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. Dishonesty. There remain, of course, a few social problems that
really have gotten worse in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last few years</TIMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX>, of course, eagerly
cites them: a rising percentage of births to unwed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX>, rising marijuana
consumption by high-school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">seniors</ENAMEX>, a growing and possibly indiscriminate
tendency for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> to prescribe <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Ritalin</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> suspected of suffering
from attention deficit disorder. (This last social problem wasn't discussed at
all in the previous edition.) In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>'s book, none of these is nearly so
serious a problem as that of growing income inequality; but inequality isn't
the sort of thing <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">conservatives</ENAMEX> fret about, and, in his book, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX>
doesn't.

               Given this paucity of bad-news material to work with, it's understandable
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX> would be tempted to find some way to move the goalposts he set
down in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>. In <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> instances, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX> gives in to that temptation.

               The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> instance concerns <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX>'s discussion of teen-age
pregnancy . Unlike unwed pregnancy, which is rising ,
teen pregnancy is sharply declining . But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX> leads off his
chapter on "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Youth Behavior</ENAMEX>" with the shocking news, presented in large boldface
type, that "[b]etween <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990 and 1996</TIMEX>, the percentage of all teen-age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> who
are unmarried has increased <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">12 percent</NUMEX>." This is an accurate but not enormously
significant statistic. In effect, it's a way of saying that the venerable
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">institution</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">shotgun</ENAMEX> marriage is in decline: Teen-age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> who get
pregnant are less likely to get married than were teen-age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> who got
pregnant during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX>.

               But the more important question is: How many teen-age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> are getting
pregnant in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place? The answer, which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX> mentions only in
passing, is that the teen-age fertility rate is down <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">roughly 13 percent</NUMEX> since
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>. The teen-age fertility rate has been dropping for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several decades</TIMEX>--a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tribute</ENAMEX>, no doubt, to contraception--though for most of that time the teen-age
out-of-wedlock birth rate was increasing. Thus the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1994</NUMEX> chapter on "Youth:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pathologies</ENAMEX> and Behavior" led off with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> big charts on teen-age
out-of-wedlock birth rates since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1960</TIMEX>, which were shown to be rising
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">impressively</ENAMEX>.

               But now the teen-age out-of-wedlock birth rate seems to be leveling
off--reflecting, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> supposes, some hard-won equilibrium between
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-agers</ENAMEX>' greater use of contraceptives, on the one hand, and their greater
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">disinclination</ENAMEX> to marry their high school sweethearts, on the other. Since
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>, teen-age out-of-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">wedlock</NUMEX> births have actually decreased very slightly.
This is mentioned in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> edition, but only in passing.

               The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> instance of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dishonesty</ENAMEX> concerns incarceration .
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1994</TIMEX> volume, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX> defines the incarceration problem as the failure to
imprison <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX>. "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Nearly three</NUMEX> out of every <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> convicted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> are not
incarcerated," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX> writes. "Fewer than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> serious crimes results in
imprisonment." The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> edition does note, in passing, that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
incarceration rate, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4.55</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> per <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100,000</NUMEX>, is "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> times higher than that of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sweden</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Netherlands</ENAMEX>." But the overall thrust of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">incarceration</ENAMEX> section of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> edition is that too many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> are
avoiding jail sentences. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapter</ENAMEX> ends with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three tough</TIMEX>-on-crime quotes, all
of which harp on this theme. Here's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminologist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John DiIulio</ENAMEX>:
"There is so much crime without punishment in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> because recent
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generations</ENAMEX> of social and political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elites</ENAMEX>, both liberal and conservative, have
liberated themselves from the belief that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> are free moral <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> and
that publicly sanctioned punishments are what they justly deserve."

               Now take a look at the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> edition. This time out, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX> features in
large, boldfaced type the statistic, "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Between 1990 and 1997</TIMEX>, the rate of
sentenced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> increased <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50 percent</NUMEX>." This is
followed up with statistics about the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in federal and state
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">prisons</ENAMEX> and local <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">jails</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1.8 million</NUMEX>); the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> with the fastest-growing
prison <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisiana</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX>); the likelihood
(<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX>) that any given <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> will do prison time; and so on. The chapter
fairly screams, "There are too many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> nowadays." Which is odd,
considering that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years ago</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX> was fretting that there were too
few.

            

            The Index seemed a smart bit of ideological entrepreneurship when
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX> started it in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 1990s</TIMEX>: Using as a baseline <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year 1960</TIMEX>, when
all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> agree the world went to hell in a handbasket, it was able to
document vividly the rise in all sorts of societal ills. By now, however, it
has clearly outlived its usefulness. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> predicts a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> edition will
never see the light of day.

         
      
   
