
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tubular</ENAMEX>, Dude!
            

            Good <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Eliza</ENAMEX>. I think I pulled my quad.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Readers</ENAMEX> should know that, in the interest of providing an experiential base
for our "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eating Club</ENAMEX>" on sports <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eliza</ENAMEX> and I jogged across the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brooklyn</ENAMEX>
Bridge and back <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX>. Prior to the run, we gathered at my
apartment to eat various sport/fuel/energy/nutrition/performance <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">snacks</ENAMEX>, all of
which came in bar form.

            I <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> sampled the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TwinLab Ironman Nutrition Bar</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cookie Dough</ENAMEX> flavor.
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">First</NUMEX> off, isn't cookie dough the wrong <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">association</ENAMEX> for someone who presumably
wants to work out and stay fit and healthy? <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX> off, ewwww! Who wants to eat
cookie dough right before running? This bar possessed a floury dryness that
induced slow cud-chewing. It was work to eat. It tasted bad. But it did have
the coveted <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40-30-30</NUMEX> ratio, which I will let you explain, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Eliza</ENAMEX>.

            We tried several other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bars</ENAMEX>, too. I'll let you get into the details on them,
but for my money they were all bad, and mostly in the same way as the cookie
dough: chalky, a chore to get down, bland tasting, eliciting tremendous
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">belches</ENAMEX>. I do want to give special notice to the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> entry from TwinLab: The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ironman Nutrition Bar</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Cookies 'N Creme</ENAMEX> flavor. This was everything that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cookie Dough</ENAMEX> was and more. So much more, in fact, that I spat it out before I
swallowed it. I rarely, verging on never, spit out <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>, yet this was so
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">repulsive</ENAMEX> in its texture (mucousy sludge) and taste (not exactly sure what it
was, but not <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cookies 'n creme</ENAMEX>, I can for sure tell you that) that I could not
countenance digesting it. By far the worst bar we tried.

            The run was lovely--cool breeze, sparkling skyline--and I actually felt
quite good, energy-wise. I'm not entirely willing to ascribe this to the sports
bars we ate, but it can't be ruled out. Halfway through the run, I tried our
next sport-food <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contestant</ENAMEX>: Power Gel from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">PowerBar</ENAMEX>, a little packet of goo
that one is meant to squeeze into one's mouth in the midst of an exercise
session. Power <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gel</ENAMEX>'s consistency was like a more viscous yogurt. I ask you, can
there be any food one wants less in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the middle of a long</TIMEX> jog than yogurt, only
more viscous? Answer: No, there cannot.

            Post-run, we tried <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Ultra Fuel</ENAMEX> sports <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drinks</ENAMEX>. Mine was grape. It was pretty
good, and refreshing. Not much different than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gatorade</ENAMEX>. Maybe a little sweeter,
definitely a little thicker in consistency. We also tried the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Jog Mate Protein</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tube</ENAMEX> (the one you thought smelled like <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eliza</ENAMEX>). Jumping on the recent
food-in-a-tube fad, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Jog Mate</ENAMEX> "supports muscle recovery." It directs you to
"consume entire tube contents within <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 minutes</TIMEX> after exercise." It resembles
nothing so much as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pudding</ENAMEX>, in a tube. Actually, more like just pudding skin.
Lots of it. Compressed together. In a tube. It wasn't bad, and in general I'm a
big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> of the food-in-a-tube movement.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> I feel pretty good, other than the quad. I guess most of my muscles
recovered, perhaps thanks to the tube. But what I want to know is, is there any
reason to eat an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Ironman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX> instead of a granola <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX>, or drink <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Ultra Fuel</ENAMEX>
instead of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Snapple</ENAMEX>? And how are your quads?

            As ever,
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Seth</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
