
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate Stays Soft</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times lead with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s procedural votes in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> that
effectively ended any chance of passing campaign finance reform <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> runs the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> results on Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>, leading instead with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>'s
quiet efforts to warn local police about the possibility that anti-government
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">militias</ENAMEX> and hate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> will become increasingly dangerous in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the coming year</TIMEX>
because of the apocalyptic significance some of them attribute to the new
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">millennium</ENAMEX>.

            What happened in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> report, is that in successive votes
to force floor consideration of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> campaign reform measures--one simply a ban
of the unregulated campaign use of donations made to the national political
parties ("soft money"), the other a broader bill that also would have tightened
rules about "issue ads" that actually function in support of particular
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>--the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pro forces</ENAMEX> achieved slim majorities, but fell short of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX>
votes required to cut off a filibuster against the measures. After these votes,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Majority Leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Lott</ENAMEX> quickly tried to move on to other business,
prompting complaints from the pro-reform <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> led by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX> that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lott</ENAMEX> had broken his promise to allow extended floor debate. But the WP
cites <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> saying <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lott</ENAMEX> will prevail <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX>.

            Everybody quotes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s reaction: "Once again, a minority in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> has blocked bipartisan campaign finance reform." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> called the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> impasse "a victory for the politics of cynicism." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> claims
that despite these remarks, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has not thrown his full weight behind the
issue, although the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> provides no evidence of this, noting only that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is a prodigious money <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">raiser</ENAMEX> within the current rules. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>
goes high with the observation that the outcome keeps the special interest
money issue alive for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>'s presidential campaign. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and
WP emphasize that the campaign reform cause's outcome was very similar
to what happened <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>, but only the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> claims that actually this
is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the fourth straight year</TIMEX> that campaign reform has died in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tarnishes</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reformer star</ENAMEX> a bit with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">companion</ENAMEX> piece
(based on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Common Cause</ENAMEX> investigation) to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> vote lead reporting that
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this year</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commerce</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> backed off tough new regulations
protecting airline <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> in favor of a much weaker bill after airline soft
money flowed into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> coffers. Although <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> denied knowing about the
rush of money, he admits in the story that "Big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have access to my office
that ordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> don't have. That's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> reason we need reform."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front the latest political news
from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>. And <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> runs it inside. But only the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> seems to
get the emphasis in the story just right. True, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B.J. Habibie</ENAMEX> has
apparently decided not to run to remain in office, but the bigger news that
affects many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and concerns the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> currently supplying
peacekeeping <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Timor</ENAMEX> is that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">legislature</ENAMEX> has formally
relinquished the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s claim to the region. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> makes this the big
print headline. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> relegates it to smaller type beneath a header
about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Habibie</ENAMEX>. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> headlines are all about
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Habibie</ENAMEX> and don't mention <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Timor</ENAMEX> at all.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> slugs a story about corruption in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> thusly: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GREASY PALMS</ENAMEX>
ARE RAMPANT IN <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">RUSSIA</ENAMEX>. Even if there were a widespread corruption scandal in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>, say, would the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> ever use <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">GREASY PALMS ARE RAMPANT IN L.A.</ENAMEX>? Of
course not.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> front <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s federal
indictment of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonnell Douglas</ENAMEX>, now part of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boeing</ENAMEX>, and a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airline</ENAMEX> it
did business with on charges of diverting high-tech manufacturing tools to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s military. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> is alone in emphasizing that the case could
complicate the current effort by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> to
complete a trade agreement that would bring <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Trade</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Organization</ENAMEX>.

            Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> go inside about a study--based on redacted <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> government documents--being
published <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists</ENAMEX> that is the
most elaborate accounting yet of the secret deployment by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> during the
<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX> of nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> in foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>, many of which have policies
strictly banning a nuclear presence. The only real remaining mystery, say the
study's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX>: What's <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the blacked-out</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> alphabetically between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX> that had <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> nukes foisted on it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 1956 and 1965</TIMEX>?

            Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> 's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Heard on the Street"</ENAMEX> column and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> 's front page "cover story" report on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the whiz-bang first day</TIMEX> for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha Stewart</ENAMEX>'s IPO, which, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> informs, made her "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">America's Newest</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Billionaire</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stewart</ENAMEX> was on hand at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYSE</ENAMEX> to ring the opening bell for her
big day, after, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> , serving the money <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> a breakfast of
scones, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">croissants</ENAMEX> and fresh-squeezed orange juice. A question: Who decides who
gets to ring the opening bell? And shouldn't IPOers be excluded from clanging
since the decision is tantamount to pouring <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">millions</NUMEX> into their stock?

         
      
   
