
   
   
      
         
            The Spread of Goo
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Eliza</ENAMEX>,

            The last time I had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drinks</ENAMEX> in different colors was this one <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vegas</ENAMEX> ... but that's neither here nor there. Last night I reprised our run over
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridge</ENAMEX>, trying several new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bars</ENAMEX>, a different brand of goo, and a couple of
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drinks</ENAMEX>.

            My clearcut taste <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX> among the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bars</ENAMEX> was the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grabber Energy Bar</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wild Mountain Berry</ENAMEX>. Grabber must have some sort of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> affiliation, as it's
labeled "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barre D'Energie</ENAMEX>" and its ingredients list is bilingual. Leave it to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">frogs</ENAMEX> to produce a tasty sports snack--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grabber</ENAMEX> had the taste and
consistency of a thicker <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Fruit Roll-Up</ENAMEX>. And it's all-natural real fruit.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Drawback</ENAMEX>: I don't quite understand why it's an energy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX>, since it has barely
any <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> or fat. It does have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">153</NUMEX> calories and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">36 g</NUMEX> of carbohydrates.

            I also tried the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Clif Bar</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Apricot</ENAMEX> flavor, which basically tasted like
dried apricots, but mushier. Not bad. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">250</NUMEX> calories and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2g</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fat</ENAMEX>. I liked it
better than the crunchy <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Clif Bar</ENAMEX> we tried <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>. After this I went to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HardBody Energy Bar</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Honey-Almond</ENAMEX> flavor of this was yummy--I'd actually
eat it as a snack even if I weren't exercising. Not surprisingly, it was a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">280</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">calories</ENAMEX> and a whopping 7g of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fat</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chocolate Truffle</ENAMEX> flavor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">HardBody</ENAMEX> had
the same stats, but was less enjoyable. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chocolate Truffle</ENAMEX> is way too rich to be
eating before or during exercise.

            During my run I felt good and energetic, and midway through I paused to try
a different goo packet from the PowerGel I tried last night. This one is called
Gu, and it was much more satisfying. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Texture</ENAMEX> was like a nice custard, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">flavor</ENAMEX> ("banana blitz") was mild and delicious. I actually felt better after
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gu</ENAMEX> than before. This may have something to do with its potassium, which
helps maintain fluid balance and stop cramps. The goo packet market is
exploding right now. The latest entry is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clif SHOT</ENAMEX>, from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Clif Bar</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clif SHOT</ENAMEX> has potassium as well, and cuts out the maltodextrin (<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sugar</ENAMEX>) that Gu
loads up on, but it also boasts caffeine, which I'm not sure I want during
exercise. The great thing about the goo packets is portability. They're a real
boost out on a run, and they're easier to carry and keep better than a
banana--you can stick a goo packet in your sock if you need to.

            After the run I tried a couple of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Gatorade drinks</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Riptide Rush</ENAMEX> was
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">delicious</ENAMEX>. A light grape flavor--not too light to seem watered down, just light
enough to be truly refreshing. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gatorade</ENAMEX> has potassium, too. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lemon Ice</ENAMEX>
flavor I tried next was a disappointment. It had that very weak lemonade
taste--highly disagreeable after a workout.

            Well, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Eliza</ENAMEX>, it's been great fun eating goo with you. I'm not sure we
determined anything conclusive, but I guess we can heartily recommend the
Powerbar Harvest flavor, at least on grounds of taste. And the goo packet
concept is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX> in my book. But if this is the general future of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>, I'll
have the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">lobster</ENAMEX>. For quick reference, here's a chart of our reactions to the
bars we were both able to sample:



         
      
   
