
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shattering Glass-Steagall</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> plan to cut
Government spending across-the-board by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1.4 percent</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> contend
that cutting <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4.5 billion</NUMEX> from federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> and delaying <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.3 billion</NUMEX> in
health spending will fill the hole in their budget. Administration <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>
argue that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> plan does not add up and that the proposal would
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">force</ENAMEX> layoffs and harm military readiness. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Majority Leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Armey</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tex.</ENAMEX>) explained his vision of how the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense Department</ENAMEX> could cut <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.4</NUMEX>
percent from its <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$260 billion</NUMEX> budget: "Instead of having <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> colonels to hold
your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>, you'll have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> major." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and the LAT
carry the story inside.

<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> lead with the product of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX> of debate and intensive
lobbying--an agreement to transform <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> banking laws.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> resolved to repeal the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Depression-era</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Glass-Steagall</ENAMEX> law, which restricted the cross-ownership of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">brokerages</ENAMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">insurers</ENAMEX>. If the accord is enacted, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> analysis forecasts that
financial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX> will agglomerate into "universal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX>" to provide
one-stop financial shopping. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Consumers</ENAMEX> could benefit from reduced costs. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> notes that the bill will prohibit nonfinancial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> from buying
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX>.

            Even though <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> acceded to a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> provision that will
prevent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> with unsatisfactory lending records from moving into other
financial services, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> for disadvantaged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">borrowers</ENAMEX> argue that the
agreement fails to strengthen fair lending laws. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yesterday</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> was
able to squeeze early news of the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 a.m.</TIMEX> agreement into a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">late edition</TIMEX>. Today,
the story is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> 's off-lead. All papers report that the stock
market soared over <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">172.5</NUMEX> points on news of the accord.

            The LAT fronts a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations Security Council</ENAMEX> vote to send <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6,000</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peacekeepers</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sierra Leone</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> story explains that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peacekeepers</ENAMEX>
will disarm <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sierra Leone</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebels</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> will contribute logistical
support to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX>, but no combat <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Security Council</ENAMEX>
is expected to approve sending <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Timor</ENAMEX>. The new
commitments will double the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peacekeepers</ENAMEX> in the field. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> is
also considering sending <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">as many as 20,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peacekeepers</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Congo</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> fronts <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s acceptance and disavowal of
responsibility for the bombing of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chechen</ENAMEX> market. The incident cost <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over 100</NUMEX>
lives. Among the dead are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> said
that special <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> bombed the market because it was actually an <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX> bazaar.
But <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Minster Vladimir Putin</ENAMEX> claimed that the explosion was caused
by warring <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chechen</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebels</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> carry the story
inside. All papers assert that evidence points towards a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> bombardment.
According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> , as violence spreads <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Chechens</ENAMEX> are
fleeing into the neighboring <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">republic</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ingushetia</ENAMEX>, where it is estimated that
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">185,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX> are seeking refuge.

            All the papers bury their coverage of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Hampshire</ENAMEX> debate among
the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> "virtually ignored" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">front-runner</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> and focused
on criticizing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> asserts that after the debate the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> attending <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> blasted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> by arguing that his absence from the
stage was an affront to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>. "I think he was the big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">loser</ENAMEX> here <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX>,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Forbes</ENAMEX> said of the absent <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>. (
                  Slate
               's 
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Weisberg</ENAMEX> analyzes the debate and highlights its stranger
moments.)

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> piece reports on a particularly creative Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">start-up</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RonsAngels</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX>, the brainchild of former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Playboy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Harris</ENAMEX>, auctions
the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eggs</ENAMEX> of fashion models to the highest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bidder</ENAMEX> (presumably infertile
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couples</ENAMEX>.) Even though the site will not premiere until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron</ENAMEX> has already
received a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$42,000</NUMEX> bid for one of his angel's <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eggs</ENAMEX>. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ethicists</ENAMEX> are troubled
by the combination of e-commerce, eugenics and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">egg</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pimping</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
