
   
   
      
         
            There <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ought To Be a Law</ENAMEX>! Not!
            

            Good <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse</ENAMEX>,

            The language news <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> is big: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quebec Superior Court</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danielle Cote</ENAMEX> has struck down as unconstitutional a section of the
language law, la <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Loi 101</ENAMEX> , that requires <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> to
be predominant on commercial signs. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> ruled that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> antique dealers
didn't violate the law by hanging a sign outside their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> on one
side and <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> on the other, with lettering that is the same size.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La</ENAMEX> loi <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">101</NUMEX> , passed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1977</TIMEX>, provided that signs
could be only in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX>. That provision was ruled unconstitutional in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX> and
was replaced with a requirement that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> have "greater visibility" or
"marked predominance" on signs.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Quebec</ENAMEX> government argued in this case that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">French</ENAMEX>
still needs protection in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">province</ENAMEX>, while the judge sided with the defense,
holding that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> had made great strides and is not threatened. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Goupil</ENAMEX> plans to appeal, while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Provincial Liberal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jean</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Charest</ENAMEX> claimed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Quebec</ENAMEX>'s linguistic peace will be threatened by the new ruling.
The defense <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> said he would fight any appeals all the way to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nations</ENAMEX>.

            The application of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Quebec</ENAMEX> language law to business
signs has often been controversial. Government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspectors</ENAMEX> went around with tape
measures to make sure <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> lettering was larger than <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX>. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Quebec</ENAMEX>
government complained that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Anglophone</ENAMEX> business <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> sought to evade the law
by having larger <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> letters on their signs, but in the faintest of colors
so they couldn't be seen.

            I happened to be in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Montreal</ENAMEX> during the
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">20 th</NUMEX> anniversary of the passing of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Law 101</ENAMEX>. A
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">young CBC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> assured me that language was a political issue only for the
older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, that the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anglophone</ENAMEX> and Francophone
alike, were all pretty much bilingual and were generally bemused by all the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">squabbling</ENAMEX>. In the countryside, of course, everyone spoke <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX>, and there was
no language issue there. But older <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anglophones</ENAMEX> assured me they felt constant
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">linguistic</ENAMEX> pressure, and that many middle-class <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speakers</ENAMEX> had fled the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">province</ENAMEX> because their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> had been required to attend <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>, and
as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anglophones</ENAMEX> they'd have no economic opportunities in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">province</ENAMEX> after
graduation.

            When the issue of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Puerto Rican</ENAMEX> statehood referendum
was debated in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of years ago</TIMEX>, someone wrote to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> warning that statehood for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Puerto</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rico</ENAMEX> would mean creating "our very own <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Quebec</ENAMEX>" unless the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commonwealth</ENAMEX> adopted
an official <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> policy. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Quebec</ENAMEX> is often held up as a warning by supporters
of official <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX>. But in fact the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Quebecois</ENAMEX> want to protect <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> just as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> of official <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> want to protect <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>. The problem is that
language legislation frequently creates more problems than it solves. And
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> doesn't need protection.

            Even though <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> maintains its dominance in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Quebec</ENAMEX>,
radical <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Francophones</ENAMEX> feel threatened. Even though <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> are abandoning their <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> languages for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> faster than ever
before, to the point where <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">97 percent</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> reports
speaking <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> well or very well on the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Census</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> of official
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> maintain the language is threatened.

            What about the linguistic violence of multilingual
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX>? you may ask. Where violence does occur, it's because language
rights have been taken away, not because minority languages have been
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tolerated</ENAMEX>. Official <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> is unnecessary.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Non-English-speakers</ENAMEX> already know how important <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> is for survival.
Furthermore, establishing an official language in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> will drive a
wedge between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">English-speakers</ENAMEX> and non-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Anglophone</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX>, making it harder,
rather than easier, for them to assimilate.

            Official-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> maintain that language is
the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glue</ENAMEX> that holds us together. I think there'd better be a whole lot more
than language holding this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> together. A common language can be a
unifying <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX>, but it doesn't have to be one: Look at the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX>, at the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Croatians</ENAMEX>, at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speakers</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hindi</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Urdu</ENAMEX>, at all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peoples</ENAMEX> of the
world separated by a common language.

            If <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Puerto Rico</ENAMEX> does consider statehood, language will
certainly be an issue. But if you want to create "our very own <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Quebec</ENAMEX>," go
ahead and pass an official <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> law. That should really stir things up.

            Best,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dennis</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
