
   
   
      
         
            Economic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Data</ENAMEX>: An <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Infinite Loop</ENAMEX>
            

            Everyone knows--or at least we're supposed to know--that the market for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
stocks <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> is dominated by momentum <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traders</ENAMEX>, day <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traders</ENAMEX>, and technical
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traders</ENAMEX>, none of whom are paying attention to the underlying fundamentals of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> whose shares they're buying and selling, and all of whom are
putting the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> economy at risk by converting the stock market into an
elaborate shell game/pyramid scheme.

            As it happens, this is wrong. There are lots of momentum <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traders</ENAMEX> and day
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traders</ENAMEX> and technical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traders</ENAMEX>, but there always have been, and in any case the
increased volume on the stock market and the greater number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traders</ENAMEX> has
almost certainly made stock prices more efficient and more accurate indicators
of underlying value than they once were.

            What's interesting about this, though, is that the same picture is very
rarely drawn of the bond market, even though if you talk to (or listen to) bond
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traders</ENAMEX>, what you mostly hear is a host of technical information--stuff about
the trend of bond prices over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last month or last week</TIMEX>, about support levels
that bond prices have to hold or break through, and about overbought/oversold
indicators that are or are not flashing green or red. And you also get a lot of
rapid reaction to things like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Greenspan</ENAMEX> speeches or employment-cost-index
numbers. The conventional image of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bondholders</ENAMEX> is that they're conservative,
long-term, careful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>. (Why else would you be content with a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">6.3 percent</NUMEX>
yield for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30 long years</TIMEX>.) But bond <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traders</ENAMEX> are as <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">manic</ENAMEX>--no, more manic- than
their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counterparts</ENAMEX> in the equity market.

            This doesn't mean that the bond market is any less efficient than the stock
market, though it does seem a bit curious. But what bond <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traders</ENAMEX>' reliance on
technical analysis--the idea that future price movements can be deduced by
studying the patterns of past price movements--speaks to is just how impossible
it is to successfully predict a market in which every piece of potential
information seems to point in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> different directions at once, and in which
there seems to be nothing that doesn't count as potential information.

            Take <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s trade-deficit number. Although it was the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> worst in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
history, it was still weaker than expected and smaller than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX>'s trade
deficit. That was good news for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> dollar, which rallied, and since bonds
have--at least recently--been following the dollar, it might have been good
news for the bond market. On the other hand, a weaker trade deficit meant that
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> exports were up sharply, which means that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were working more and
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factories</ENAMEX> were producing more, which probably means higher growth and,
potentially, higher inflation. That seems like it would be bad news for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bondholders</ENAMEX>, who hate inflation.

            But then you had to consider that imports actually rose <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2 percent</NUMEX>,
suggesting that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> consumer is still buying foreign goods freely and
that potential inflation from the weaker dollar (which would drive up the price
of foreign goods) hasn't had much of an impact. So maybe inflation is still
really just a mirage. But wait. If <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> exports are up, that must mean that
foreign demand is rebounding, and since the slump of the rest of the global
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">economy</ENAMEX> has helped keep commodity prices down, a global rebound could have
inflationary implications. So that could be bad news.

            Then you have to divide the import side of the trade deficit ledger into
non-commodity and commodity goods, particularly since oil-price hikes had a big
impact in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last month</TIMEX>. And you probably want to take a look at capital
flows, too. And then there's ...

            This is all fascinating (no, really, it is), but it is also a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Moebius</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">strip</ENAMEX>,
in which it's difficult to tell where anything begins or ends. And we haven't
even taken into account that the bond market needs to interpret not only all
these numbers but also what impact the numbers will have on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>, and then
in turn what impact the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>'s interpretation of the data will have on future
numbers.

            Given all that, it's not too surprising that the bond market preferred to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">meander</ENAMEX> around <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, basically ending where it began. Set yourself the
impossible task of predicting a macroeconomic future, and your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> will start
to hurt, too.

         
      
   
