
   
   
      
         
            Wilted

            Everybody leads with the bloodless military overthrow of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>'s
background: While army <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commander Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pervez Musharraf</ENAMEX> was out of the country
(in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sri Lanka</ENAMEX>), the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilian prime minister</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nawaz Sharif</ENAMEX>, fired him.
Thereafter army <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> quickly took to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> and overran key government
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">facilities</ENAMEX>. ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> front the same
picture of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> going over the fence at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> TV station, mooning
the world in the process.) Then <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Musharraf</ENAMEX> returned, and after placing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sharif</ENAMEX>
and several other top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> under house arrest, announced that he was in
charge.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> also agree on the main background factors: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> had been
upset that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this past summer</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sharif</ENAMEX>, bowing to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> pressure, had called for the
withdrawal of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Pakistani</ENAMEX>-supported <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guerrillas</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kashmir</ENAMEX>, where they had been
in a shooting war with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forces</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> has the most fine-grained causal list,
adding as factors <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sharif</ENAMEX>'s failure to authorize a military response to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>'s
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX> shoot-down of a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Pakistani</ENAMEX> navy training flight, his promise to consider
signing the comprehensive test ban treaty, and his plans to divert money from
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX> to housing for the poor. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> also mentions the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">distaste for Sharif</ENAMEX>'s attempts to cut ties to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Taliban</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">militia</ENAMEX>.
Only the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> includes anything negative about <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sharif</ENAMEX>,
noting that he has jailed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dissidents</ENAMEX>.

            The papers report that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> went on high alert upon hearing of the coup.
Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> report that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> had
warned in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent weeks</TIMEX> against any extra-constitutional ouster of the
government. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> says that there is no immediate concern in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> regarding <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>'s nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX>, because, explains
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> , they have been presumed to be in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX>'s hands all along.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> says that if the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> confirms the coup, it will no
longer conduct business as usual with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> adds: If that
happens, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> law requires cutting foreign assistance. (It would have been nice
if the paper had said what law. How long has it been in existence?) The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , in case you had doubts, passes along word that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Musharraf</ENAMEX> "has
a reputation as a tough, no-nonsense <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldier</ENAMEX>." Just once <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX> wants
to read about a soft, all-laughs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldier</ENAMEX>!

            Perhaps it comes as no surprise what the sports-addled press views as the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">day</ENAMEX>'s other big story: the death, at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 63</TIMEX>, from an apparent heart attack, of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilt Chamberlain</ENAMEX>. Every paper fronts this, with USAT
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> putting it top-front. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> 's piece puts <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chamberlain</ENAMEX>'s
claim to have slept with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">seventh</NUMEX> paragraph of its
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX>-paragraph story. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> puts it in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX> paragraph out of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX>;
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX> paragraph of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">59</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front-page effort
never mentions the alleged feat. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> runs a story inside by one-time
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">biographer David Shaw</ENAMEX> that provides a bit of evidence for the claim: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shaw</ENAMEX>
writes of a time that he was out at a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chamberlain</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chamberlain</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">date</TIMEX> when the player excused himself to get the phone number of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> at another table. And another time, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shaw</ENAMEX> says, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chamberlain</ENAMEX> ushered him
out of his hotel <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> in order to entertain <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> simultaneously. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shaw</ENAMEX>
doesn't say if he put these stories in his book.)

            Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> report inside that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> civilian
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX> killed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two days ago</TIMEX> was probably assaulted by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanians</ENAMEX> after
he responded to a question they posed to him in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> with an answer in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Serbian</ENAMEX>. Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> also report that in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Burundi</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, several civilian
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> were murdered by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hutu</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebels</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> front-page news box dutifully reports
that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dow</ENAMEX> dropped <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">231</NUMEX> points--a reduction in value of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.2</NUMEX>
percent--on, it says, inflation worries. What's particularly noteworthy, and a
sign that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> are maturing when it comes to market swings, is that, on a
relatively slow news day, no other paper fronts the story.

            The USAT front-page "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Snapshot</ENAMEX>" gives an economic picture, based on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Census Bureau</ENAMEX> stats, of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">estimated 44 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> without health
insurance. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">More than a quarter</NUMEX> of whom, says the chart, earn more than
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50,000</NUMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> runs an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX> report inside about the first documented actual Y2K glitch. It seems that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maine</ENAMEX> state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> has issued, according to a computer's instructions,
titles for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">model year 2000</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trucks</ENAMEX> identifying the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicles</ENAMEX> as
"horseless carriages," a designation meant to be reserved for vintage vehicles
produced before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1916</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> has spent, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> in an effort
to make its computers Y2K-compliant.

         
      
   
