
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		tell you what this is later
 	
 	
 		all right
 		um well
 		personally with me
 		i think we ought to introduce it to the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> but i don't think you can force it upon them because if you force it upon them
 		they
 		i don't know i it wasn't forced upon me and i i with it beings more my idea it i tend to just stick with it a little bit longer
 	
 	
 		yeah i'd say <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years</TIMEX> is a good while especially do is yours on a renewal basis is it
 		do you have to renew <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each year</TIMEX> or
 	
 	
 		no i i just i go through and i i work on like a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">monthly</TIMEX> basis
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i do you know like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one weekend a month</TIMEX> type thing
 	
 	
 		uh do you have a do you have a minimum requirement for your community service is there a commitment like a term commitment
 	
 	
 		no
 		no um well what i do is i work uh i volunteer with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Red Cross</ENAMEX>
 		and i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of their disaster team
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		and so i pull call once a month to do disaster work such as single family fires
 		and then for national jobs they call me when they need me
 	
 	
 		gosh that must of you must have seen a lot of exciting
 		things and i think that would be good for youth because it would
 		just
 		be an experience that they it would be difficult to get under a lot of circumstances unless you're involved in some kind kind of
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right right if you find your niche um you know and and i worked with a lot of of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> that you know have been working to get young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> more involved in what we do and um
 		if you can if you can find help them to find their niche you know they'll they'll really grow to love it but if you force them in to something that they're not real keen on they'll rebel on it and at least the ones i've seen
 		you know and and they and they they struggle against it and they want out of it as fast as they can
 	
 	
 		yeah i could see that happening um i i would think with enough publicity there's got to be a wide enough variety of
 		uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> that they could volunteer with that they if they didn't find their niche in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> if if they're if
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> were enough were publicized enough they could just know what they could know what their options were for other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> to try
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and other services to contribute
 	
 	
 		right
 		and something i don't know the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace Corps</ENAMEX>
 		signing up and going away  i mean i've got a real good support system with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and such like that
 		you know and and they're the ones that you know i i i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> can make a really big difference in in sticking something out
 	
 	
 		oh absolutely
 	
 	
 		you know and so you know as long as you don't pull them away from their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> to to to take them off <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">somewhere</NUMEX> to do something you know you've got a better chance of making it work
 	
 	
 		yeah i think the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace Corps</ENAMEX> would be uh scary for a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> because of that isolation  even if they were in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> it would be
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		a little more conducive i think to a to a fellowship feel in that could they could draw a support from
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but i understand that a lot of them are uh well i certainly don't know any statistic but
 		that a lot are are working individually and um
 		i guess that'd be it it i would find i find it hard to imagine maintaining an incentive i or maybe not
 		incentive but uh
 		just
 		keeping a focus on the goal
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well i'd
 		i i had never i didn't know that they were
 		trying to push through a law or anything to make <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> do this
 		i that whenever they brought this up that kind of caught me off guard you know i think you know the way i got into <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX> was they did it it they started it in junior high school and it could just be like an extracurricular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX> that you could become involved in
 		and you could do as little or as much
 		and you decided how much involvement that you got which you know a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> dropped out but we have a lot we have a large number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that were it was introduced to that way that has stayed with it and had grown with the organization
 		does that make sense
 	
 	
 		yeah i think that does make sense um
 		you'd have to uh i think having having the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> who's volunteering set their own pace
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		for development in the program would
 		would be key to just staying staying away from that feeling of being forced into it whether they were officially forced into it or just the pressure was so high to stay in or meet a
 		you know minimum requirement of time commitment that uh
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know uh but then i think you almost reach a point where
 		if if you pad everything too much it kind of takes away
 		the experience i mean the experience of sacrificing i guess is what i'm thinking
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		does making of going overboard overboard overboard almost
 	
 	
 		right well that's true um
 		and and it <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> other thing you've got to really look at is uh depending on what age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> you're going to involve you know be it high school or whatever you've got to have good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adult mentors</ENAMEX>
 		you know
 		because otherwise you get into this situation of you're too young to do any of this
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 		
 	