
 
     		
 	
 		okay uh well what do you think is there something wrong with public schools
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well
 		i'm not so that i am not willing to send my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> to them
 	
 	
 		oh is that right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah now that's partly because i want my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> to have a religious education uh which a public school can not and should not
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		offer uh but it's also because
 	
 	
 		right
 		you feel they get a better education
 	
 	
 		i fill that they'll get a better education i fill that i have more control over
 		uh the type of social
 		pressure that they get expose to because i can choose
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know if the kinds of essential not only am i choosing the kind of schooling that they're getting but i am also choosing the other kinds of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> who are going to be there because
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		it works both you know because not only am i doing this but presuming the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> are doing the same thing
 	
 	
 		right
 		right they have the same motivation for sending their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> their well i think there is a problem with with the public school education system and i
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i think it is demonstrating by the fact so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> uh graduating from high school and can't even uh perform
 		some simple uh math problems and uh or or even read a a decent uh book uh or geography i mean some of them can't even identify the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> or various places in the world so
 		i think that we are sending uh some some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> out into the world with a very poor education <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundation</ENAMEX> and i think that the problem started when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Education Association</ENAMEX> stop being
 		for education and really became more of a labor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX> and only put their main entrance in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> pay like education like money was the the solution to every thing
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i think that the i think the answer is something what you are doing right now i think that a voucher system or some competition between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> to give uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> a choice of where they send their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and allowing
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> to compete with one another the become better i think that is the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> way
 	
 	
 		well i think i i think that that works too uh
 		you know i
 		i sometimes wonder there a a school system near me that they actually a fairly good one what they've done is they had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> school that was
 		because of the neighborhood the neighborhood school system basic the school system basically and they put their talented and gifted program in the poorest school district you know the or the poorest poorest elementary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">district</ENAMEX> that was part of this larger district
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		and um they allowed any of those neighborhood <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> who wanted to stay there to stay and then they didn't it wasn't that they had the talented and gifted program just housed in this building
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		all of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classes</ENAMEX> were based on talented and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gifted</ENAMEX> and all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> were treated the same way and as a result this is now the best <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> in the school district which is really kind of interesting
 	
 	
 		that's
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		a magnetic school
 	
 	
 		well it's essentially a magnetic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> that's right but it's also a neighborhood <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> you know and
 		the neighborhood there are some of the neighborhood <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> who can't manage and
 		the talented and gifted program because
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i think it's more case of
 		you know there are some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in this world who i accuse of perhaps  you know and and they just
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		not only can not compete they simple didn't you know those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> really felt uncomfortable but the majority of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> if they're taught the way that they teach talented and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gifted kids</ENAMEX> it turns out the majority of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> really are that way
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know each <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> a little bit different but each one has a lot to offer so that's a public school that works but then there are other public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> in that same district that really don't work
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and
 		and unfortunately even that school although it seems to be working academically has
 		some um some real race problems that uh which is real unfortunate because most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> who comes in are white and most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> who are there are black or
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		i think part of the problem with the education system really isn't the education system but it really has to do with the loss of the family <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and the loss values of
 		uh you know the guidance that went along with the stable family <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX> isn't isn't there for all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> like it use to be
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah i think you right i think you right and i think that a caring teacher
 		can do a lot to change that but then you are not talking about is it a public school is it a private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> is it you talking about you know are you and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are going to be lucky enough to hit the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> who can get home
 		
 		
 	