
 
     		
 	
 		oh sure i guess this sort of relevant for me because i'm a college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> so you know i would have been affected by it you know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple years ago</TIMEX> i guess probably or after i graduate i don't know how it would be set up
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		um i have sort of mixed feelings about the whole thing i mean i think it would sort of be
 		uh sort of a bonding experience in a sense for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and the you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of of uh sort of all different uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know socioeconomic racial uh you know geographic even uh you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> who would be mixed together and would sort of work together which i think would be a positive thing
 	
 	
 		that would be a good coming of age experience
 	
 	
 		yeah i mean i you know i think i think that that that would be a very probably the most positive part of it
 		and you know it's also good to do uh to do volunteer work
 		but on the other side i sort of you know wonder whether or not the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> uh would run a program like this intelligently i mean
 	
 	
 		yeah that's a really big problem and that's my main objection to something like that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> looking at uh the track record on um you know responsible management i'd really have to say that i think it'd be guaranteed that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> would have a real problem
 	
 	
 		yeah i mean the for example the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace Corps</ENAMEX> has been a real success i think but the problem with that is that
 		uh you you know it's a it's a small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">program</ENAMEX> and i don't know whether they could find worthwhile work um for everyone in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> sort of uh and also you know and still still manage it well i think they might be tempted for example to
 		to not spend as much money as they should i mean they'd say look we have all this free labor let's not spend any money and so they would end up using <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and their talents very inefficiently
 	
 	
 		um-hum yeah
 		yeah that is a big problem especially with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> get bigger and bigger but there are a lot of little little problems like uh illiteracy
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh some other things that could stand having some manpower thrown at it
 	
 	
 		yeah i mean i think yeah again if it if the if it was used efficiently and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you know worked on on real problems as opposed to just sort of make work
 		then uh i think it could have very positive impact
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um i just i haven't seen i haven't seen any of the detailed proposals for that i don't have you
 	
 	
 		no i have no idea
 	
 	
 		i mean i know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> sort of floated the idea around but um
 		i don't really know that much about it
 	
 	
 		in the early eighties um for economic reasons and wanting money to go to school i went into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marine Corps</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX> and
 		the mismanagement and the waste there was really disgusting totally really disturbing
 		remember uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first year</TIMEX> that i paid a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">thousand dollars</NUMEX> in federal income tax i watched that <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">thousand dollars</NUMEX> wasted that day
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		there were some radios that um had been sitting on a shelf and they had some schedule or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every eight months</TIMEX> they had to be checked whether they were used or not and that's a practical idea but before i left i saw those very same radios rotate through again
 		and they'd been through many times before
 		
 
 		items that have been contracted out and paid for and that that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX> hadn't been built to specifications all kinds of stuff like that that was really disturbing
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		for you know a big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> like that that a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> go off and do the kind of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">coming of age</TIMEX> thing as well
 	
 	
 		yeah and the part of the problem i mean even even i think probably a little bit of the problem with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX> is that you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> only stay for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years</TIMEX> a lot of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and so there's not
 	
 	
 		
  
 		yeah and a lot of them want out because it's so disgusting
 	
 	
 		yeah and there but there's no sort of continuity to it i mean you don't have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that sort of feel responsible for uh you know the area they're working or whatever i think you'd have that problem even worse if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were only in for a year
 	
 	
 		
  
 		yeah <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>'s too short for any kind of continuity you're absolutely right
 	
 	
 		and they probably wouldn't
 		yeah and they and they probably wouldn't hire enough permanent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX> to really you know make the glue to keep the whole thing functioning well
 		um so i yeah i i don't know i mean i i think if if it could be made to work well it would be a good idea if it would just be sort of a giant waste of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s time
 		then i think it would be you know exactly that a waste of time and money
 	
 	
 		yeah i wish our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> had better memory of things like the uh the New Deal and all the things that went on then when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roosevelt</ENAMEX> had uh all kinds of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> working in
 		they were getting paid but it was a uh you know building <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">highways</ENAMEX> and stuff like that
 	
 	
 		yeah i
 		yeah i do think i mean i do think that's that's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> part of it you would have to pay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i mean
 	
 	
 		yep absolutely
 	
 	
 		and either that or you know sort of like the military i mean the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX> doesn't pay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> very much but you know they provide <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">housing</ENAMEX> or whatever i mean
 	
 	
 		yeah there's got to be enough compensation for you to survive for a year
 	
 	
 		yeah you've got to be able to you know to pay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to live more or less i mean you can't expect them
 	
 	
 		yeah this isn't the ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> where you if you have the money you go in
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah you need you need to uh you need to provide a way for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to live so for that reason alone it would be it would be expensive
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> and so maybe that's almost one of the big drawbacks to it
 	
 	
 		yeah that and especially with the the things uh money running the way it is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> and the federal
 		
 		
 	