
 
     		
 	
 		music yeah
 	
 	
 		music huh
 		
 
 	
 	
 		always an interesting topic
 	
 	
 		oh yeah i uh i have a little bit of an interesting experience with music i've been a part-time disc jockey uh
 	
 	
 		so
 		oh wow
 	
 	
 		work for a a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> a little <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> that does uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DJ</ENAMEX> stuff for weddings and uh birthdays and things like that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so we've uh  we've had to play quite a bit of of music uh over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past several months</TIMEX> so it's interesting to see what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like and that sort of thing
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		are you involved at all in music or uh
 	
 	
 		um uh uh a strong appreciator of it um yeah i i did the typical piano thing back uh when i was young and i even played trombone in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX> for a number of years
 	
 	
 		um-hum hum
 		ah
 		hum
 	
 	
 		um but i don't actively uh play anymore i just listen and spend too much money on discs
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		um-hum right
 		yeah it's interesting now there all going to uh CD's now also
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i uh have a little bit of an involvement in uh
 		in square dancing and and round dancing and that's all all all still on <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">forty</NUMEX> fives
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and uh so they're  they're having an interesting problem when it comes to the music for that because the uh
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">forty fives</ENAMEX> are generally played on a variable speed turntable so you can speed it up or slow it down for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dancers</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so now they're wondering how they're going to do that with CD's  it's going to be a little tougher if if it ever goes to CD's it's not it hasn't converted over yet
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i think the only <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> who even use <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">forty fives</ENAMEX> for music anymore
 	
 	
 		um yeah yeah that's interesting
 	
 	
 		yeah i think that even the aerobics <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are using uh all their music is on cassettes or CD's
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah well that you know technically it shouldn't be difficult to uh modulate the the speed on a compact disc yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 		yeah i should be able to and cassettes i know that they do have some that are variable speed
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh i think those are machines for for aerobic instructors
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		so uh and uh
 		i found that uh at least at the things i've DJed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like things they can dance to  if you can get them to dance
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		it's kind of the hard part uh at these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> they tend to want to sit around or stand around and talk or uh <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drink</ENAMEX> and talk or whatever and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then getting them to dance and then they they have different taste in dance music some of them like the fast stuff and some the slow
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		we're kind of uh into oldies right now in our in our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> for some reason we're most of what we listen to is oldies
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">hum-um</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so  and yourself you you just mostly listen then yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah um i guess i'm towards the uh other end of the spectrum um i listen to a lot of uh
 	
 	
 		
  
 		hum hum
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">techno</ENAMEX> dance um you know electronic compilations things like that uh really alternative and and progressive music
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
  
 		hum
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um so
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		it's kind of the other end of the spectrum for you
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i got uh some albums i've picked up that i've kind of recently gotten interested in it's uh
 		the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> music
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh there's a a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Simon</ENAMEX> has uh featured uh well on his album Graceland
 	
 	
 		right right
 	
 	
 		it's called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lady Smith Black Membazo</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and they're a uh <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> that sings a cappella
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and um
 	
 	
 		yeah they're a very good group
 	
 	
 		um-hum much of their music is sung in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Zulu in the Zulu</ENAMEX> language so that's uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's a an interesting and uh i guess it kind of falls into the
 		i guess the reggae category uh whatever that is  i'm not quite sure what reggae is actually
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah that that
 		
 
 		um that's that's more like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Marley</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whalers</ENAMEX> um a lot of the other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jamaican</ENAMEX> uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> it's so it's a strongly <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jamaican</ENAMEX> based music
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		ah ha uh-huh
 		hum
 	
 	
 		um but it it it's interesting too i'm not terribly familiar with with
 		reggae itself i know it's influenced a lot of of stuff especially some of the more modern dance stuff they take a lot of the more complicated rhythm structures
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> from reggae and try to translate that into uh more current hits
 	
 	
 		you ever hear of a musical from called Zydeco
 		i had never heard of it before
 	
 	
 		um i've heard of it but i couldn't give you a definition of it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		we had uh what were we doing we were <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DJing</ENAMEX> a uh
 		i think it was a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company party</ENAMEX> and they had gotten a request for some of that
 		so i did a little research on it it's uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Louisiana</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> uh <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cajun</ENAMEX> music
 	
 	
 		oh okay okay yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah and that's that's called Zydeco i'd never heard of that term before
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and uh and i i was able to listen to a few
 		tapes from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> of of what it was like and it was definitely different  <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cajun</ENAMEX> type music i'd never actually even heard it before
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		um-hum yeah
 		
 		
 	