
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay so we are talking about recycling
 	
 	
 		recycling yeah
 	
 	
 		i i just move down from uh up near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh you did
 	
 	
 		yes and up there they're doing quite a bit
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they they one of the thing that they've tried doing is they've had it they got a uh deposit on all uh plastic container you know bottle what not
 		and
 	
 	
 		you mean like bottles of what kind
 	
 	
 		i mean like <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Coke</ENAMEX> bottles things like that uh and also cans so it's a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five cent</NUMEX> deposit on all of those uh which you know encourage some what for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to bring them back
 	
 	
 		oh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coke</ENAMEX> bottle okay yeah
 		oh that terrific
 	
 	
 		there also in area up their that mandated uh separating your garbage
 	
 	
 		yeah so you have to separate separate the glass from the plastic from the
 	
 	
 		uh
 		from the paper i believe even right
 	
 	
 		from the paper oh that's really
 	
 	
 		so i know that they're doing and up there and several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> down here they're not doing a hole lot down here uh their actually are some <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> where they mandating that uh most i think it's aluminum from everything else
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and also it's against the law anywhere in the county down here to uh deposit uh yard trash like you know clippings and stuff in the trash
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		so that's what they're doing here what are they doing there
 	
 	
 		well i i'm very interested in this because i think it's it's extremely necessary and i i've tried to you know from the beginning i i started you know um trying to recycling even before they had any program
 		you know they they just sort of had voluntary trash uh you know bins you could put your plastic in and now they it's they're trying to have um
 		a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> wide program where they're actually have special <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trucks</ENAMEX> to pick up your separated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">um plastic</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glass</ENAMEX> and uh newspapers
 	
 	
 		but it
 		but it still voluntary
 	
 	
 		but well they've they've got <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trucks</ENAMEX> for part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> and and they haven't gotten enough <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trucks</ENAMEX> you know manufactured yet to take care of the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of Plano
 		so some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plano</ENAMEX> do have that recycling and it's pick up at their door and you know at their driveway and we don't
 		so we still have to take it voluntarily to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> where they have the you know glass bin and the and the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">aluminum</ENAMEX> and and uh but there they don't take plastic
 	
 	
 		what of the other thing that there was been done up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX>
 		that was very good well several of the grocery <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store chain</ENAMEX> were uh instituting a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five cent</NUMEX> credit if you brought back your bags and reuse them
 	
 	
 		oh that's great
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		see we're we don't have that either yet either i'm trying you know i keep trying to remember to bring my little canvas bag into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> with me but i can't remember to do it
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		it's real hard to break that habit
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		you know just going into the grocery for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> thing and then you get in there you think why i don't have the bag with me you know
 	
 	
 		you haven't seen any i haven't seen any of that down here
 	
 	
 		but we have you know a lot now i saw <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> not to long ago with <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five or six</NUMEX> of those canvas bags and she had them all with her and she took her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">grocery home</ENAMEX> in those which i thought was great
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		but nobody does that i mean it's
 		you you just never see anybody with them
 	
 	
 		right my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> uh live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Little Rock Arkansas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so
 		oh they did yeah that's not to
 	
 	
 		yes well they do and they uh and i i sent my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> a couple of those canvas bags just so she can do that because they you know they look at her like she was crazy there
 	
 	
 		oh they do okay
 		yeah well good for you
 		yeah yeah they they really we we need to encourage i mean i know in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX> where i'm from
 		originally i'm from there and you know they've been doing um the glass you know the pickup of separating trash and mandatory for a long time they've they've been doing it for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> or two
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		but um but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Plano</ENAMEX> needs to get more of these trucks
 	
 	
 		unfortunately i think that what we are seeing though is like areas like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plano i</ENAMEX> where it is not <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">densely</ENAMEX> populating uh you know the whole area
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		that it is a lot easier for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to uh you know ignore the landfill problem where as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey Massachusetts</ENAMEX> you know <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New England</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		see they have to do it yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX> especially i mean that a really populated highly populated state i guess <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX> is to
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX> is getting there well  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston</ENAMEX> is like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX> is very heavily populated you know western <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX> is not
 	
 	
 		is not is that where you're from originally is that where you were born
 	
 	
 		no no actually not i was i was born in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alabama</ENAMEX> and i lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX> where we didn't do any recycling i lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas Massachusetts</ENAMEX> now <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Florida</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah so you've been around
 	
 	
 		so <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX> is probably like like i said the best of what i seen there
 	
 	
 		well it's i just i just think the more you you know you just each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> have to consciously think about doing of something little or something big whatever you can do
 	
 	
 		sure
 		well  there's there's actually some other good ideas that have come up where for example i think this was actually originated in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX> city on the uh where they scrap the uh top of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX> off and they actually remixed that and use it again
 	
 	
 		but
 	
 	
 		you know for the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">asphalt</ENAMEX> they having to uh you know trash out
 	
 	
 		oh yes
 		oh that's a neat idea i never would have thought of that
 	
 	
 		so why don't <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX> city thought of that
 	
 	
 		well that's the that's the thing that there are thing you can do that you can't you know nobody thinks about
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		there are these thing that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would get their minds working and just you know brainstorming that you just it's a whole new way of thinking
 	
 	
 		sure
 		i i believe in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore</ENAMEX> they're recycling <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glass</ENAMEX> and using it as part of the asphalt
 	
 	
 		are they really well that's neat
 	
 	
 		yes which they also think it is good because it make the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX> prettier
 	
 	
 		oh for heaven sakes that's right that's amazing because we use to live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because they sparkle
 	
 	
 		we lived there for a while before we came down and we lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX> and then we came here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about fifteen years ago</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> is born in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		she was where she was at what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		born in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore</ENAMEX>
 		i i don't know
 		
 		
 	