
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		all right uh what did you look for when you were looking for child care
 	
 	
 		well we uh we needed you know something that was kind of convenient to uh
 		to getting you know because uh usually in the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">mornings</TIMEX> things are pretty rushed
 		so that that was a consideration
 		um
 		uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> went over to the
 		uh to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> who keeps uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helen</ENAMEX>
 		and uh they you know before uh took her over uh actually took her over but before
 		we signed up for it and uh
 		just kind of looked around you know and talked to her for awhile
 		watch how all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> interacted with her and they all seemed to like her so we uh
 		we went with her and we've been we've been really happy with her
 	
 	
 		i guess that's an important uh
 		uh uh i haven't thought about that as much as i
 		it uh
 		when we did it  we we didn't really have child care we had uh like
 		uh day school
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh yeah</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so they're <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> before they went to school and
 		well what what we had done was talk to the parents and of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> that were there
 		and uh all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> were very enthusiastic so we thought well that's a that's a good point and then we visited once and seemed like they were pretty
 		uh
 		but i guess there is a difference between
 		uh
 		day care for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> that are
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">couple years</TIMEX> away from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and and uh
 		child care for now you you and your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> both work right
 	
 	
 		um-hum yeah
 		yeah the uh  the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> who keeps she keeps uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and uh she she really recommends to that uh
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		when when like when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helen</ENAMEX> gets
 		a little closer to starting kindergarten that she'd be you know put into a regular
 		um day care so that they can they can learn more
 		uh uh like the alphabet and the numbers and all that stuff uh although she's she's really good she uh
 		uh she makes little uh like handprints
 		you you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helen</ENAMEX>'s hand and then puts little designs on them you know and you know so she uh she takes a pretty active role and and uh
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		um our little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> she was uh premature and so she had um she was on a monitor
 		uh heart <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monitor</ENAMEX> and uh that was no problem you know with the uh with the babysitter she you know took it right in stride
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		she
 	
 	
 		i i guess with the right <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> if uh as opposed to some of these day care <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> where they have
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two hundred</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> or something like that or i don't know how many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> they've got but where they have lots and lots of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> it's  it's much tougher to uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		to rely on
 		it's much easier to rely on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> if they're good they're good and if they're bad well you know
 	
 	
 		yeah that's that's that's the the finding a good one that's that's the hard part
 		um i think you probably have a better
 		chance with a day care they're they're probably
 		it's more of an average so that that there's less chance of having a a bad one yeah
 	
 	
 		well on the average on the well on on the average they might do uh
 		uh
 		gosh how should i say this
 		you're going for the average the average <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> is going to be treated better but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but you won't have the the uh
 		you won't have the risk of getting a real bad one everybody everybody knows that they've got a a bad one on the other hand uh that's with uh with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who's taking care of them in their own <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> that's
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		if they're good like i say you can be pretty sure that they're good and uh so i if they're not so good if they're kind of lazy why the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>'s probably
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> could tell you i i personally would rather have my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 		uh stay with uh
 		you know with an individual than i would with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> because with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> if they lose if they have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two or three</NUMEX> good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and they lose one you'll never know it you just pick your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> up from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh and see the other question i had is uh
 		so do you plan on on uh keeping her in day care until she goes to school
 	
 	
 		i think uh well i think we're going to keep her where she's at now until she's about uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three and a half</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> and then move her into <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a regular day</TIMEX> care
 		that has uh more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 		and uh and also where they have like the pre kindergarten
 		type of uh environment
 	
 	
 		does does this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> have any help or does she do it all herself
 	
 	
 		uh she she has like uh occasional help that comes in
 	
 	
 		okay i i wondered about that because uh i know some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that do that and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know moms can never get sick well a  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a day</TIMEX> care <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>  uh can never
 		
 		
 	