
 
     		
 	
 		so what do you sell them or what
 	
 	
 		
 
 		uh don't don't bit your tongue no no actually i'm a system <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineer</ENAMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		
  
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i i'm sitting right know before there my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mac</ENAMEX> is at my right hand and my
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOS</ENAMEX> machine is at my left hand and
 	
 	
 		
 
 		alright i've got a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mac</ENAMEX> in front of me as well
 	
 	
 		good for you
 	
 	
 		yeah well i
 		it's weird um where i came from they were all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX> oriented because i'm a doctoral <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UCF University of Central Florida</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and
 		i <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX> got to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campus</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">first a long time ago</TIMEX> and established themselves so i was real <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX> format when i came up here to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but now up here everybody at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Honeywell</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Macintosh</ENAMEX> oriented or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Silicon Graphics</ENAMEX> or what ever
 	
 	
 		give me a graphical interface <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">any day</TIMEX> huh
 	
 	
 		well i don't know yes yes and no in a way
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i find almost that i am slower on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">graphical interface</ENAMEX> than i am on textural
 	
 	
 		yeah it seems to be the great equalizer that's one thing that i've notice is uh you you put uh open windows on a sun and i don't see amazing power from it it doesn't degrade as much under a load as a typical
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		like an intel chip would but uh it it like i said i i i consider <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GUIs</ENAMEX> as a great equalizer you know they help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> work but they seem to bring all of the machine to there knees
 	
 	
 		right
 		so because
 		yeah that true actually i'm i'm kind of interfacing interested in uh i'm a human factors person
 	
 	
 		
  
 		oh really that's interesting work
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah that's what my doctorate degree going to be in so i'm kind of interested interested in the interface of the whole anyway you know but uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		that would be um
 	
 	
 		who who do you work for
 	
 	
 		this is a great time for you to be into it you know
 	
 	
 		well yeah yeah i hope so actually interfacing is not really my forte i'm more into uh aircraft displays and controls
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh heads up this ways and such
 	
 	
 		well yeah stuff like that generally i'm right now my dissertation is more into auditory display but uh you know things like beats and buzzers and tones and stuff
 	
 	
 		oh so are you a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Star Trek fan</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh yeah actually
 	
 	
 		i've heard a lot of really uh good thing from human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">factor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> about the way that they
 		you know the the the bridge of the new enterprise
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah yeah that that seems to be a pretty good pretty good thing as for as i can tell who who do you work for in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rochester</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i work for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Western New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Computing System</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty year old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> and uh we are affiliated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MicroAge i</ENAMEX> know that
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 		
  
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		makes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> squeamish but uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well not me
 	
 	
 		yeah uh you know it's a it a it's fascinating work and uh
 	
 	
 		it would
 	
 	
 		never never a dull moment you know
 	
 	
 		yeah i can say you know for me
 		shoot in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last five or six years</TIMEX> if i hadn't had access to a computer i would really be screw in a big way  you know because i've
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i had a i use to have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX> compatible and i got my my thesis done and actually my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX> degree on it and now that i'm trying to work on my dissertation you know it just
 		it's really good that i've access to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mac</ENAMEX> and stuff so
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah it's helped
 	
 	
 		on yeah you can just you know you can just type type type type get it all in there and make it look really excellent and uh some of some of the checkers and thing they have nowadays or
 	
 	
 		you bet
 		yeah
 		yeah you can build the fancy art work and stuff
 	
 	
 		are a real benefit
 		oh yeah sure i even seen uh you can download a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> dimensional
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">uh Chemical</ENAMEX> CAD
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		small package that lets you draw molecule in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> dimension and huh scary stuff you know
 	
 	
 		well that's pretty nifty
 		yeah well what do you think about Unix in terms of it's popularity if do you think that is going to blossom or what
 	
 	
 		well i'm a little worried about um you know uh what do they call it a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> poses
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but um because it could it could fragment it but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> has brought into that type of operating system know and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> seem to derive
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh you know there is a whole other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offshoot</ENAMEX> people <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> will developing for that market and then turn around and sell those products into the commercial markets and so i think were going to see a lot in there it's got a lot of promise i don't
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		i mean it's it it's been underrated um you know you can you can scale the Unix system
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		to fit the need you know you can go all the way from a desktop to a mainframe
 	
 	
 		yeah now that's that's the real good thing is the versatility and everything i i've got a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> that work at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASA</ENAMEX> and uh and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cape Kennedy</ENAMEX> and things and there all really like
 	
 	
 		on Unix
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		really pro Unix and like that's the future of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mankind</ENAMEX> in computing you know type of thing and i'm not i'm not real certain that i agree with that but
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well i i'm i use to be um a very strong <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporter</ENAMEX> and i was a little worried about this unholy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alliance</ENAMEX> that they have entered into with no with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
  
 		with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>
 		or with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		but um you know there there there's a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Talogent</ENAMEX> that's uh
 		<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> spin off of both of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> it's like there there spawn  and uh there working on an object oriented operating system that is going to hold a lot of promise
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		hum
 		no uh
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		that's
 		
 		
 	