
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		okay
 	
 	
 		okay okay okay i'm uh
 		well i do work for a large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> uh large meaning <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about twelve twelve thousand</NUMEX> people
 	
 	
 		that's big
 	
 	
 		and uh it use to be twice as big
 		could've been uh could've been better i'll put it this way when i came to work here it was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty five thousand</TIMEX> and now it's <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">twelve thousand</NUMEX> and dropping
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh the advantages of a  how how big is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> you work for
 	
 	
 		uh less then <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred</NUMEX> people
 	
 	
 		okay less then <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		some of the same thing still applies i've work for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s uh your size before
 		and some of the same thing still applies though uh one of the things is
 		like i know a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> that gone to work for his self
 		and
 		and uh after a while he became
 		isolated
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah he was he craved uh  yeah
 	
 	
 		interaction yeah
 		
  
 	
 	
 		and uh that's one of the nice thing a about a company uh interaction with other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> access to internet uh
 		do you have internet how did you get hook up to this
 	
 	
 		uh well i have an internet uh through another i have another internet connection through another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> but we're in the process of
 		establishing our own internet feed internet feed
 		um
 	
 	
 		so thing like that the internet uh access internet access to a library
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um
 		gee how do i say it uh
 	
 	
 		well i think the diversity of a large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> is a strong thing for it um the the fact that there are so many different ways that uh working for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> could take you a a large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> um
 		granted if your skill your skill were like nuclear physics so you pretty much narrow to to uh
 		
 
 		your choices are narrowed but
 		i can see someone with on doing what i do going into many different sort of venue i guess you'd call them in a larger company
 		um
 		i'm a system <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineer</ENAMEX> and i basically
 		design <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX> um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so for our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">end user</ENAMEX> and our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customer</ENAMEX> i'm you know uh
 		i'm pretty much limited to that that's what that's what i do
 	
 	
 		the
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the advantage of uh of a uh larger <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> and the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundred</NUMEX> is uh could be consider a larger <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> is
 		is access to other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that do the same thing
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		if you're the only computer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">programmer</ENAMEX> in your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> then it's it's it is kind of isolated
 		and uh
 		so that one of the advantages of there's a lot of disadvantage of course but uh
 	
 	
 		yeah i think one of the disadvantages is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bureaucracy</ENAMEX> that props up as a you know necessity for almost anything getting anything done at all you have to
 		uh
 		many layers to go through
 	
 	
 		yes and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> other thing that that uh tends to happen
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		in in a larger <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> is uh
 		oh how do i say it uh lack of access to uh
 		to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> they they tend to departmentalize and and uh move away where as in a company your size
 		uh let see <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred</NUMEX> or so it i in the pass had access to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who had access to just anything anything anything and everything was uh was available
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		where as in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> like this it's very fragmented
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and i'm i might be
 	
 	
 		um-hum and you have the typical pyramid structure of organization many work group <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> on top or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> um and middle <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> and the whole <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">nine yards</NUMEX> right
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah and so well i can be <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> feet away from somebody that is doing the same thing
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		we are structure in the uh
 		in uh in uh bubble
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh structure
 		we are many different work group however we work together
 		um that's by design we've had the same <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX> for basically for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years</TIMEX>
 		and uh it allows us to do many interesting thing we have many facet to our organization
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and we are able to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mix</ENAMEX> and match and bring different facet into play as they're need so we we basically cover the whole spectrum of computing uh for our for our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		i i have one fear here i i don't know if i push the one button long enough
 	
 	
 		i think you did
 	
 	
 		do you think you can hear that huh okay because i
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 		i haven't they haven't said that we're out of space yet maybe they deleted their temp directory
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well in the past they've it they seem to shut us off fairly quickly so i i was wondering about that let me try it once more here
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well um you know we can talk as long as we like or until they tell us i've usually hit the marker to
 		um we are not suppose to be talking about this anyway uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so we're  we're in a we're in a bubble diagram and uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		okay
 	
 	
 		that's that's a really effective and i think that is a very nineties kind of thing like i say we've had it for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty something years</TIMEX> and so we are really good at it but uh
 		
 
 		
 		
 	