
 
     		
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		did you attend public school
 	
 	
 		i did attend public school for all but <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one year</TIMEX> i uh
 		went to a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one year</TIMEX> found that uh it did not agree with me or i did not agree agree with it and uh spent the rest of my education in public schools
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh i had mixed feelings on it uh because i thought that there was a greater range of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> that a public school has to uh
 		has to address
 	
 	
 		yes that's true they can't root out the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troublemakers</ENAMEX> as easily
 	
 	
 		right and and the the programs have to be wider uh when i went to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> high school uh there was nothing but a college preparatory course
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		and in the public school there were uh a couple of different courses the uh
 		the the so-called business course uh the college prep course and then there was the uh  the uh the the basic uh gas station <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> track uh  you know
 	
 	
 		yeah i never
 		yeah
 		yes vocational education we called it
 	
 	
 		right
 		and  i'm not sure
 		that uh
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> prep course was any worse in a public school than it would've been in a private school
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i think that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> were spread a little more thin because they weren't always able to focus on the areas that they taught best
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		and by spreading thin you mean they too many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> or too many subjects per <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> or
 	
 	
 		well a little bit of both uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> wasn't very crowded when i went there although it's since gotten it's since gotten worse but uh there were
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		there were some very good math <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> there there was one uh
 		a science <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> in particular there who ended up having to teach a i i can't remember what course it was but it was really unsuitable uh it was some sort of uh
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">shop</ENAMEX> or mechanical drawing class and he just
 	
 	
 		oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		he know he didn't know much about it but they figured he was a warm <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> in a room
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		that's kind of technical so he could
 		him it was him yeah
 	
 	
 		right right
 		and i don't think that uh
 		i don't i don't think that there are the resources in most public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> to be able to say well what we need here is a
 		trained machinist to teach teach the metal shop course let's go find one they just say well you know we have this course we need a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> for it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> were already paying this guy
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah uh
 	
 	
 		did you go to a public school
 	
 	
 		i did i did and uh
 		i felt i got a very
 		i mean i feel i got a very poor education in general uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i think that i knew other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from other public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> who got better educations
 		um uh in our case it think it was
 		you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> uh again spread thin but maybe in terms of just having too many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> to really
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		do the job um
 		i'm sort of i have a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two year old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> now and so i'm starting to think about
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		education you know more critically and trying to figure out what we want to do and i'm just sort of turned off by the whole uh
 		the whole system where everyone sits facing the front of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> as quiet as possible while the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> lectures uh especially for small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		sure
 	
 	
 		uh it just seems like it's not the way they're going to learn best but when you have one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> what else can you do
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know i mean it seems like the the style of teaching that we we have grown to think of as normal i think is dictated by economics
 		in just in terms of uh student <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> ratios um
 	
 	
 		um-hum so have you started looking into uh alternative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> like Montessories
 	
 	
 		um no so far i'm just whining
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i haven't done anything constructive yet uh we fantasize about homeschooling
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh
 		we probably won't
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		although i could see where that would be that could be a lot of fun
 	
 	
 		i can see a lot of advantages to homeschooling but uh
 		there's it's it's interesting there's uh someone here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rhode Island</ENAMEX> who is very disgusted with the school system
 		
 		
 	