
 
     		
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
  
 		
  
 	
 	
 		okay i think we're all set there hopefully
 		
  
 	
 	
 		well uh care of the elderly is something that is hitting pretty close to home at me uh right now my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father-in-law</ENAMEX> has uh
 		been diagnosed with terminal cancer
 		and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother-in-law</ENAMEX> is in a wheel chair so this is something that i've been thinking quite a bit about lately
 		and uh
 		i'm i feel pretty strongly and the rest of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> does that is long as someone is able to care for
 		uh someone else
 		that they shouldn't be put in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> but there's there's a very hard question of of what happens when someone isn't able to provide that care for themselves
 		um
 		in the case of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother-in-law</ENAMEX> she's not able to to bathe herself but she's sharp as a tack at this point and
 		what sort of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> are available for that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> it's hard because you think of a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> and you're really thinking of
 		of uh old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> left somewhere to uh you know fairly forgotten and that's
 		that's that's a hard thing and i'm sure not all of them are like that
 	
 	
 		well unfortunately that's the typical picture though
 	
 	
 		
  
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		so it's it's very hard to find a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> that would allow uh allow someone of fair degree of autonomy in their life
 		but yet would still be there to help provide some of the basic services
 		
  
 	
 	
 		is your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother-in-law</ENAMEX> currently uh living in a nursing home or anything
 	
 	
 		no she's not um
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		she's still at home and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> has has moved back into the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> uh which which was not as inconvenient as it sounds because uh
 		um my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father-in-law</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother-in-law</ENAMEX> have a dental <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lab</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">basement</ENAMEX> so he was working out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> anyway
 		uh so it it's a little less
 		uh it's it's not all that inconvenient for him
 		but
 		the rest of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are scattered uh throughout the northeast
 		and he doesn't want to feel that he's
 		uh he's going to be completely responsible for this only because he happens to live right there with with my in-laws
 		
  
 	
 	
 		have you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> thought about the financial burden
 		of caring for
 		your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother-in-law</ENAMEX> as far as putting her in a nursing home down the road
 	
 	
 		that that has we've all thought about that fortunately uh that doesn't seem to be a big problem but
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		that we there's some thought that has to be given to to uh
 		to the property for instance they have <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about four three or four acres</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Connecticut</ENAMEX>
 		and what no one wants to see is uh that land having to be sold off simply to keep her in a in a nursing home what we'd like to do
 		is uh find the sort of place where i try described before where  she'd be able to have uh a place of her own but yet also have someone come in a couple of times a day to help her with various
 		various things and have someone there in case she falls or something
 		
  
 	
 	
 		well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> is in a place similar to that where she has emergency buttons throughout the throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> or actually the apartment
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
  
 	
 	
 		and she's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about eighty one</NUMEX> and she lives she has her own little area for gardening and so forth it's in the  housing authority up here
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
  
 	
 	
 		and it's
 	
 	
 		that's great
 		
  
 	
 	
 		when she first moved up here she ended up living in  uh tall apartment <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> a complex that was very similar to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
  
 	
 	
 		a very negative feeling when you walked in the building
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and now she's been very fortunate
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		in that she's almost almost like living in a small home
 	
 	
 		that's that's great
 	
 	
 		and she she still has an a large maintenance <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> take care of the place look after her
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		provide uh
 		basic busing services and travel
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		i'm hoping that the trend is toward places like that
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		as
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> uh
 		lives for a longer period of time uh
 		i i guess <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty years ago</TIMEX> when when you were that age and you weren't able to really care for yourself
 		you really weren't going to uh you know be around that much longer and so the level of care required
 		was was different but now <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are are living longer and can uh
 		can have injury
 		
 		
 	