
 
     		
 	
 		i think i'm probably somewhere around a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> on the scale they gave uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		um i don't like the idea of you know anyone being able to just sort of go up to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> and buy a hand <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> for about uh you know <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">forty dollars</NUMEX> or whatever and go out and shoot someone
 		but i also think that uh hunting is a legitimate use for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> and uh i also sort of believe that
 		although you know certainly our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is is very nice now it it probably doesn't hurt this sort of ultimate back up to have some some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> to have <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> if for some reason
 		something ever happened and our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> was run by someone who decided to make it non democratic well that's a very farfetched and you know sort of
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		you know paranoid if you will possibility but you know it i guess it's it's
 		i think it's it's always sort of a bad idea when the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that have <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> are the military and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> since
 	
 	
 		well you're right there and uh i just think they should have a little more restriction on who buys guns
 	
 	
 		yeah i mean i i
 	
 	
 		instead of just being able to walk into a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> and buy a gun they should have a waiting period
 	
 	
 		yeah i agree completely there should be a waiting period and they should be able to do a background check on you
 	
 	
 		exactly
 		and i and as far as hunting i'm sure you know this is the same thing and if if you are a a you know a legitimate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hunter</ENAMEX> or you just need a handgun or something like that a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two week or three week</TIMEX> wait period is not going to make any difference
 	
 	
 		yeah i mean most
 		yeah i agree completely
 	
 	
 		if your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminal</ENAMEX> and you need a gun for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">that night</TIMEX> it's going you know it's going to make you a little bit mad
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		but they should you know they should have some kind of restrictions and i think everybody should have to have a permit
 		they don't require everybody to have a permit
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		and i think they should if you're going to have a gun you need to to you know register it and and
 		have a legitimate reason as to why you have it
 	
 	
 		yeah that's a reasonable
 	
 	
 		and it i i don't even think they do that in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> do they
 	
 	
 		yeah uh i don't think so
 	
 	
 		i don't think so either
 	
 	
 		you need a permit to carry a concealed handgun i think in some <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> i think <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> might be one of those but to just carry you know one in the open or whatever is no problem
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um yeah although i one thing is i think no matter what rules you set unless you sort of had uh good enforcement of it it wouldn't matter i mean the types of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that cause trouble with handguns aren't the sort to care what the law is anyway
 	
 	
 		
 
 		that's true
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> and i'm sure they would certainly attempt to buy them on the black market so you'd need uh you know a good method of ensuring that they weren't available there which
 		given the success or rather lack there of of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> in controlling the market in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> i sort of wonder uh you know really how effective it would be but i don't i don't mean that
 	
 	
 		i know it'd just make it it would make it harder for them to get them but they still could but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah i mean i don't mean it as an argument to not have waiting periods and that sort of thing but i just you know i just i think it's
 		something to be aware of that it probably would not be the the ultimate solution that would solve all crime problems
 	
 	
 		but you're right they're always gonna yeah
 		hum-um because they're always going to be able to get them
 	
 	
 		um yeah
 		uh do you do you have any sort of
 		you know real real life experience with uh you know either <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> owning <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> being uh you know assaulted with uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> or anything like that
 	
 	
 		no not not really my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daddy</ENAMEX> was always a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hunter</ENAMEX> so we always had <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">rifles</ENAMEX> or shotguns or things around the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> but you know he was responsible with those and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um there was never an accident or anything like that and we've never been robbed or mugged or anything like that
 	
 	
 		yeah my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> hunted when he was young although he didn't um
 		by the time i came along so we didn't we didn't have <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> in in our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> he left them at uh his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> house so you know i got to see them or whatever
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh i do uh uh another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> who i didn't know personally
 		at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rice</ENAMEX> uh but uh it's not that small that uh large a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a week</TIMEX> ago
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh</ENAMEX> was shot in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> with a gun  yeah um he was you know going home sort of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">late at night</TIMEX> after studying and uh
 	
 	
 		oh my goodness
 	
 	
 		you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">robbers</ENAMEX> said you know i guess he was on a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">motorcycle</ENAMEX> and he had a his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">motorcycle helmet</ENAMEX> on which saved his life um because
 	
 	
 		my oh my goodness
 	
 	
 		they said you know we want your money you know we have gun or whatever so he was like okay here have my money you know i'll lie on the ground i'll do whatever you say i'll i'm not going to put up any fight whatsoever
 		and uh apparently there were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> and one of them was really kind of jumpy and the other seemed kind of uh relaxed so he said to the relaxed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> hey you know please tell your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> not to shoot me you know but uh apparently the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> for whatever reason uh shot him anyway
 	
 	
 		oh my goodness
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		thanks to the fact his his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">motorcycle helmet</ENAMEX> was made out of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Kevlar</ENAMEX> which is the same thing that bullet proof vest are made out of and so uh you know he was shot in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> but he was unharmed you know i mean i think i think he might've gone to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> anyway just to you know be looked at but
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh my goodness
 	
 	
 		um he didn't even have a concussion or or anything like that
 	
 	
 		oh how frightening
 	
 	
 		but uh
 		so it's kind of scary
 	
 	
 		it really is
 	
 	
 		living at um <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX>'s got a lot of crime
 	
 	
 		but they you know and they have when my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> when she was going to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Texas</ENAMEX> she had
 		
 		
 	