
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay um
 		Bryan you've said you have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> right now have you had any problems with day with child care services
 	
 	
 		yes
 		well yes uh yes in fact we have had a uh a minor problem we've we tried to use the child care <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> at the tennis <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">club</ENAMEX> that we belong to and just didn't feel that it provided the kind of quality care that that we want for our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> at this point
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um so it is in fact difficult to find uh quality services
 		uh
 	
 	
 		did you utilize utilize that full-time while you were working
 	
 	
 		no um my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> doesn't work so we were just uh planning on trying to use that as a as a break in our activity and to give her a little more free time
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but the uh the the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> that we went to had we've felt like uh had too many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> for each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counselor</ENAMEX> and so you know any any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> that had any kind of problem or was just upset wasn't going to receive the kind of attention that we wanted our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> to have
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh i'm i'm sure that's that's the problem with many uh care <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> like that
 		it's uh a difficult task to provide you know reasonable cost child care
 	
 	
 		what type of costs were you facing excessive or
 	
 	
 		no it was uh i think it was <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">four dollars</NUMEX> an hour
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		what i was what i was thinking of was that you know for the
 		for the uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sitter</ENAMEX> to be able to provide low cost care they you know they can't pay too much for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counselors</ENAMEX> and
 		can't provide too many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counselors</ENAMEX> per child
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but it's you know we're we're used to
 		used to just uh just felt more comfortable
 		with uh
 		you know with more of a babysitter situation where the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> has has the full attention of someone
 	
 	
 		yeah we're at a stage in our life where we don't have any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yeah but we're approaching that point where we're going to have make a decision as far as
 		does does my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> continue to work or do i continue to work to uh
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		make ends meet and do you put <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child child</ENAMEX> in day care somewhere along that lines and the reality is that we'll probably have to have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> in day care
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and uh been thinking about how much that's going to cost it's uh
 		rather frightening figure you really cuts into your income
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the things we have at our my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> is uh day care reimbursement program we actually put money away into a tax free
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> program
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> and they it's you're reimbursed out of that out of that funds provided it's used specifically and only for day care
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		it's probably one of the few programs that i've seen uh that accomplished that
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		it it helps out a little bit
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		but unfortunately i'm not you know able to tap into that until we have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> so that's down the road a little bit
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but i do have some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> who are
 		struggling as as as it is right now to make ends meet
 		and they're also very uncomfortable with the idea of day cares
 		but they're forced into that situation right now
 	
 	
 		yeah it's it's difficult i i don't know whether we'll find it easier when when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> gets a little bit older say <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one year old</TIMEX> when it doesn't seem quite so vulnerable
 		to uh you know to the outside world and my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> keeps wondering how you know how how anybody can turn the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> over to uh
 	
 	
 		what's
 	
 	
 		day care and i just tell her that you know it's just it's not a matter of choice for most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> we're fortunate we we have a choice
 	
 	
 		you know most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i know who have had to make that decision
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouse</ENAMEX> usually the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> in situations that i can think of have been in tears they've dreaded the moment
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		for throughout most of the pregnancy knowing that they'd have to eventually go back to work
 		and uh when the time actually came to send your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child child child</ENAMEX> to day care
 		it was
 		basically a very traumatic moment
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		in my i see my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> nodding in the corner
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		as she dreads that date too i imagine
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but it uh unfortunately it is a reality you just can't get by without
 		well very few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> can get by without <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> incomes
 		um
 	
 	
 		yeah it's  true
 	
 	
 		least especially in the early stages of a career
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah it it does make it difficult to because now our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six months old</TIMEX> and
 		you know essentially my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> hasn't been away from him from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">more than a few hours</TIMEX> at a time
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so that takes its uh emotional toll on her
 	
 	
 		do you find any uh that there would be any benefits to a day care such as exposure to uh unlimited basis
 		exposure to other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> um
 		developing social interaction
 	
 	
 		yeah we think so we we we think that is important we're just not not sure at what
 		
 		
 	