
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah so what do you think about that
 	
 	
 		um i i have i get frustrated sometimes with our legal system i think it's a bit lenient um giving giving in in most in a lot of cases the the criminal the benefit of the doubt
 		or the i guess the criminal you can't say they're criminal yet but they would be the uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">defendant</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah the accused
 	
 	
 		the accused right and if you um if you require the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> to be unanimous
 		i'm afraid there'd there'd be a lot of there'd be a lot of cases where just a single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> is being stubborn and um
 		and someone would would get off when they really shouldn't
 	
 	
 		yeah i hear that
 		the uh  my problem with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> and the that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">systems</ENAMEX> is just the fact that it's almost completely broken down
 		most cases that go on aren't even tried but are plea bargained so that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> can get off a certain amount of time in exchange for not spending time in the courts
 		but the uh
 		the worst part is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">jails</ENAMEX> are being filled with political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> i mean since nineteen <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty six</NUMEX> we've been undergoing a major witch hunt in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> were the question isn't who's hurt anybody but uh is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> has been engaged in unauthorized behavior
 		and we are now ahead of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Africa</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> in locking up a higher percentage of our citizens
 		than any other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> on this planet we've beat even beat out the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> something is major wrong here and uh we can trace it to the right wing witch hunt there isn't any room for the real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		what what's a political criminal
 	
 	
 		uh it's when uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> decides that a certain behavior uh shall not be authorized anymore and that anybody who is then caught doing it is guilty of violating the crime
 	
 	
 		like what
 	
 	
 		when in fact nobody has actually been hurt
 		oh <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">smoking weed</ENAMEX> growing marijuana patronizing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prostitutes</ENAMEX> things like that
 	
 	
 		oh i see okay you're calling them political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well that as as as opposed to the kind of the more <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX> where someone actively uh speaks out and opposes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> if if if if a crime involves no complainant
 		then it's the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> doing the complaining and that sounds political to me
 	
 	
 		okay yeah i understand i uh
 		actually actually for my perception is that most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> having having to do with those things you mentioned seems like they tend to get off most of the time
 		i don't really have a lot of data but that's my perception
 	
 	
 		um
 		it depends on what and who uh the largest number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are convicted of various crimes and in jail <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> are drug crimes that are not accompanied by other crimes
 		it's sort of a thing that because someone who is inclined to use some of the nastier <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> will then also go out and commit other crimes
 		that that means that the other crimes are no longer a valid point of contention it's sort of like saying somebody should be able to do all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coke</ENAMEX> they want
 		but as soon as they violate any other law and actually hurt somebody whether it's stealing money to get the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coke</ENAMEX>  loosing control and beating someone up
 		that they should be treated the same way as someone who looses control and beats someone up without being under the influence of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemicals</ENAMEX> whose they can't use it as an excuse
 	
 	
 		i certainly agree
 	
 	
 		but the way that it's come <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> to the the trials and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> it's  it's it's almost completely manipulated uh in in favor of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s position
 		so uh while i'm willing to sacrifice the danger of having a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a few</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are guilty getting off because it's far to easy when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> decides someone did it hey they did it
 		and if it and whether the innocence or guilt is true or not becomes irrelevant in fact <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> has gone totally crazy on this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> has a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> on death row now and
 		the convicted convicted of a crime that someone else has come out and admitted to
 		and that story has been corroborated but they're still arguing whether that's grounds for uh commuting his sentence or not because guilt or innocence is not a constitutional question
 		so <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> could conceivably it's that close execute someone who they know didn't commit the crime
 		because of the points of law involved
 		so there there's a point that's left logic and reason and broken down completely
 	
 	
 		huh what do you think do you think the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> ought to do the sentencing or the judge
 	
 	
 		oh the jury definitely and uh whether it's unanimous or not i think that it could be uh
 		there there there needs to be lots of evidence for appealing um
 		i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> who uh took his trial by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> and that's the worst mistake anyone can ever make because at least with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> even though you're going to be tried by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six or twelve</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who weren't able to get out of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> duty
 		that's an old joke but it's still true a lot of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who you would want to have on your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> don't want to have anything to do with it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so it's risky real risky
 		but still i take my chance with the odds of twelve
 		and we have to sacrifice letting a few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> get away with things because eventually they're going to be caught then
 		for my personal risk of being in the wrong place at the wrong time
 	
 	
 		yeah i disagree i actually disagree on both of them
 		
 		
 	