
 
     		
 	
 		well i'm not much on colors for every right season i kind of wear whatever i want to wear um
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i uh i buy workout clothes um i'm into fitness a lot and so i i spend money on that that gets kind of expensive
 	
 	
 		do you wear those um Lycra
 		fitness clothes
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of my house <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mates</ENAMEX> has some of those things
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		uh-huh she seems to like them because they stretch a lot and and give a lot when she rows
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh did she she rose oh that's interesting
 	
 	
 		um-hum rowing is a real popular fitness activity in here <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		on my goodness well do are you into working out or anything
 	
 	
 		not very much my main
 		focus right now is getting my dissertation finished and so my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workouts</ENAMEX> tend to be limited to going swimming
 	
 	
 		oh
 		right well what kind of clothes do you wear to work or to school
 	
 	
 		
 
 		to school i generally wear blue jeans and uh depending on the temperature a sweater and then uh a cotton polo shirt
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		is the weather pretty cold
 	
 	
 		it's been pretty cold lately it's snowing today
 	
 	
 		oh my goodness it it's probably <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about sixty uh sixty five degrees</NUMEX> here
 	
 	
 		it
 		
 
 		oh i would trade
 	
 	
 		yeah it reached eighty degrees <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two days ago</TIMEX> and i was in shorts and a T-shirt and i went running
 	
 	
 		oh my goodness
 	
 	
 		uh yeah  and i had the wrong shoes i've just started running i i been into weigh lifting and all and i just started running and i had the wrong tennis shoes
 	
 	
 		oh now tell me about the tennis shoes for running and how what a difference that makes
 	
 	
 		well um i found out what a difference it makes i just had <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">regular</TIMEX> walking shoes that i was running in
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it didn't give me the support i needed i had too much shock and too much jolting on my knees and my ankles and my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">joints</ENAMEX> and my lower back
 	
 	
 		do you go running down the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sidewalk</ENAMEX> or down the street
 	
 	
 		oh well um down the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sidewalks</ENAMEX> and uh on the side on the grass the side roads
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but um i was running on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">track</ENAMEX> and it's just carpet with uh a little thin thing of padding and then concrete and in those tennis shoes i had <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reebok</ENAMEX>'s on and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reebok</ENAMEX> walking shoes and they just did not do the job at all
 		so <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a week</TIMEX> after i started running my shin started hurting i got shin splints
 		so i went to <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Athlete</ENAMEX> a shoe <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> here in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tyler</ENAMEX>
 		and tried on several different pairs of shoes i tried <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Asics</ENAMEX> and uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nike Air</ENAMEX> and uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Balance</ENAMEX> and some different type of tennis shoes that are running
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh finally got some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nike Air</ENAMEX> because they have the the air pockets in the front and the back
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and i didn't think that it would make any difference you know i thought well that's just a sales pitch you know and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nike</ENAMEX>'s real expensive because they're always putting out new things and you just pay for the brand
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 	
 	
 		but i tried on i compared the way that felt to all the other brands and the prices difference difference wasn't that much you know maybe <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten</TIMEX> dollars difference
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and so i finally bought some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nike Air Skylon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2</ENAMEX> and so it it they just are wonderful it it i can run further now because i'm not in pain
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right now my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">housemate</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boyfriend</ENAMEX> just got he's training for a marathon and he just got some
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nike Air</ENAMEX> shoes and he says that you can also run a lot further in those because you save a lot of more energy
 	
 	
 		oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		sure
 	
 	
 		my shoes i just got some new ones my old ones had blown out and my new ones are <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reebok</ENAMEX> basketball shoes
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i picked them out mainly because they were on a big sale
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shoes</ENAMEX> are blue so the uh
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		the blue shoes the green shoes and the red shoes were about about fifteen dollars or a little bit more than fifteen dollars less than the white shoes
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		so i went ahead and got a blue pair of sneaks
 	
 	
 		oh well that's good
 	
 	
 		so at my house <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of my old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">housemate</ENAMEX>'s i was just was watching her give a talk over at the business college <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> she's um looking for a permanent job <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">right now</TIMEX> but she
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> was talking about loss aversion which is when you hate to give something up
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that you already have so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		somebody like you that's used to having good quality sneaks would really hate to give up um good quality sneaks for a better price
 		but somebody like me who's not used to having good quality sneaks would hate to pay more for better quality sneaks
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 		well <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> when it comes to clothing like above the ankles
 		
 		
 	