
 
     		
 	
 		uh actually it took me quite a while to get someone uh <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about six minutes</TIMEX> so i have had some time to think about this and you know what is been done and what's could be done and should be done
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 	
 	
 		um
 		i think up to this point and time the problem with uh recollection or waste what ever
 		is that it is sort of on a voluntary uh <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bases</ENAMEX> were you know have to actually  except
 		personal effort to make it happen you know like take your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> to the
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
  
 	
 	
 		uh recycling <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> you take this uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> place or another and um in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Portola Valley</ENAMEX> where i live
 		the i gets  i use  garbage <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> i don't know what they do in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mountain View</ENAMEX> but uh
 	
 	
 		yeah we have our own
 	
 	
 		uh they have a program that uh they send a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> through
 		basically you don't have to do anything all you have to do is put your papers
 		uh out put your bottle out in a bag put your paper out in a bad and they do the recollection for you basically they come by in a cycle quite a bit like garbage pick-up
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> and in fact
 	
 	
 		yeah that that that also what they do here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mountain View</ENAMEX> in fact there is um uh for each <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">area</ENAMEX> like for our area there is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who a recycling block <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> where i don't know if it's that way were you where they put up a sign
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		um telling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> that it's uh
 		the recycling day coming up <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next day</TIMEX> so that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are aware of it and so <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are it's a reminded to tell people to do that and yeah where even uh an official recycling block black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liters</ENAMEX> of
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i see
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		for our area the other i now some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> living in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX> and they said where they live
 		um its mandatory that you do recycling and if the garbage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and i don't know how thoroughly they they check this but if they find certain essentially contra banned um
 	
 	
 		the garbage is  inspected
 	
 	
 		things in your  uh
 		yeah basic basically your garbage is being inspected if they find certain contraband things in there you can be fine for it  it
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 		oh that's interesting
 	
 	
 		yeah i i thought that was really amazing and it uh it's sort of another way of uh uh encouraging or try new uh enforce that that type of um proper behavior
 	
 	
 		well i think the only way to make it really successful is to make it as easy as possible for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and i i think that uh practice here uh you know i lived previously in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> up to uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year or so ago</TIMEX> practice here of
 		sort of making it an automated part of garbage pick-up uh seem to be a step forward
 	
 	
 		yeah i think it i think it's true and i think that um
 		do you think it would help if there were um financial incentives like
 		you know were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> bring the um uh there cans and um and you get <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a penny</NUMEX> a can or something do you think those type of uh remediation are to
 	
 	
 		well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister-in-law</ENAMEX> lives in northern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wisconsin</ENAMEX> and they have a financial system there actually i can't recall exactly what it is but you have uh sort of a free pick up of sorted garbage if you sort it and it's actually pretty tedious
 	
 	
 		
 
 		sorted or sorted
 	
 	
 		sort of sorted not  free pick-up the uh free pick-up of sorted garbage uh but you its actually pretty
 	
 	
 		
 
 		probably some of that to
 	
 	
 		nitpicking how you have to sort it uh and for sorted garbage uh indiscriminate garbage there is a fee oh a rather exorbitant fee
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh really if you mix and match things improperly
 	
 	
 		uh
 		well uh uh uh it i guess in it this is also a subject inspection as you well mention but uh i a it basically on an all name basics if you this the
 		uh sorted stuff that you put out is uh quite a healthy fee for for picking that up and i think it's free or something like that for the stuff that is sorted
 	
 	
 		huh
 		yeah around here also i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mountain View</ENAMEX> and i presume in
 		this whole area i expect that the kind of pick-up that that you have in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Porta Valley</ENAMEX> and we have here are now very common uh at least in this area and we also have um uh day when there's um
 		uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two days a year</TIMEX> when there's hazardous waste
 		um drop-off were we've dropped off things like cans of paint that are in or <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">garage</ENAMEX> and drop-off um other things
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and its a different sort of recycling but it's also uh very helpful to keep stuff from going down the drain and into the water system and
 		wherever else that goes and i don't know what they do with the one that happen seems like it's a uh significant problem for thing that you don't won't <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to put down the drain and i don't i don't know if those go into landfills or
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		i don't know
 		landfills  actually don't seem like a good solution either for them
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah it would be nice if we had a continuing cycle here where every
 		
 		
 	