
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so how do you like the benefits of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um well actually to tell you the truth uh not very well i resigned from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Instruments</ENAMEX> not shortly
 	
 	
 		oh that's right yeah
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ago</TIMEX> and found that my uh after having worked there for
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">twenty one</NUMEX> years
 		
 
 		my vested interest in my
 		pension fund was amounted to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">less than three quarters of a year</TIMEX> of salary
 	
 	
 		yeah that's that's one problem with uh engineering jobs is
 		it's you you really need some sort of more flexible or portable pension you know something more like a
 		either 401K well i guess you get part of into <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">401K</NUMEX> one oh 401K
 		but what what is the uh key health plan that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are privately employed use
 	
 	
 		
 
 		um i don't know uh the the uh i guess i guess the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that</TIMEX> that issue was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> retirement uh benefit is it is what they call a defined a defined benefits program which means if you retire you get benefits
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		um
 		if you don't retire you get shit
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh but i think the government sort of passed some kind of legislation some long time ago that said well you can't do that you can't just kiss them off if they don't retire
 		and so there's some nominal uh
 		amount amount that has to be vested with the employee
 		but uh in this modern day and age where there is job mobility i mean
 		uh it's time for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> to stop screwing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> out of their retirement benefits by
 		invoking this uh defined benefits plan
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		what also seems like a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> set the benefits based on
 		your last salary when you left the company
 		so you know let's say you've worked there for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		you stopped working there you go work for somebody else for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fifteen years</TIMEX> and because of inflation alone
 		um you know your <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years</TIMEX> is worthless just because it's it's not an index to fund it's based on the actual dollar amount of when you worked there
 	
 	
 		right
 		which is all the more reason i think that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX> should have control over his pension account
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um of course the initial question that was asked related to uh actually i can't remember anymore but to
 	
 	
 		it benefits benefits in general
 	
 	
 		it related to what do you look for in a position other than salary and i guess my mind before it referred to benefits my mind was not thinking a long the with the ideas lines of benefits at all but rather
 		um
 		career gratification gratification and you know that kind of thing
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well that's one thing you do get with a large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> they're
 		you know it's well it's actually can go both ways something some ways you have
 		more opportunities because there're so many things going on within the company
 		but you also may get key holed and you are a ex type <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> therefore you should only work on this type project
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and that i guess to some extent depends on the philosophy of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> and whether they pigeon hole <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> or allow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to go in to to any area they want to
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		boy i there there were some something happened to your signal your signal at that point did you notice it
 	
 	
 		yeah there there was some clicking on the line i'm not sure what
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		whether that's local or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">somewhere</NUMEX> in the long distance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> between
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX> and wherever you are
 	
 	
 		in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> okay
 	
 	
 		or whether it's part of the uh switchboard system
 	
 	
 		this is also possible
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		somewhere between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well  party of my part of my reason for coming to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh it is it i love it it's a wonderful place but the the price of housing is
 		is just totally
 		looney
 	
 	
 		well it depends on where you go if you go up uh far enough north it doesn't
 		it gets cheaper again but then again there's you you
 	
 	
 		well that's true up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Redding</ENAMEX> uh the housing prices are probably comparable to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> where i came from but down here the housing prices are
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about</NUMEX> a factor of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> higher which is really ridiculous
 	
 	
 		yeah i know <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX> is
 		just slightly above the national average which was yeah it's about twice the price of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		at any rate
 	
 	
 		but uh the housing the housing prices have definitely dropped
 	
 	
 		so i guess one of the things you look for in a job uh is um
 		affordable cost of living
 	
 	
 		yeah cost cost of living cost of housing is the salary enough to allow me to do the activities i want to do
 	
 	
 		of course the most wonderful thing for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> and the most wonderful thing for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX> too is if what you want to do is to work
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		not so great for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> but uh
 		
 		
 	