
 
     		
 	
 		well i have a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a couple of of</NUMEX> of small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		one is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> uh the other one's an infant
 		and when we were looking for care for the older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> when he was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about nine weeks</TIMEX> or so
 		i uh i i had to go back to work i wanted to find someplace with a very uh low ratio of of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> to to care <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">giver</ENAMEX>
 		so that the so that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">infant</ENAMEX> could could really receive a lot of attention
 		and
 		for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">that first couple of</TIMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> i was able to find that in in a family setting
 		uh  uh a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a day</TIMEX> care <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">provider</ENAMEX> offering services out of her own home
 		but her circumstances circumstances changed and she lost the the help that she had uh so that they were really now quite a number of of demands on her time
 		and we switched over to to a uh a commercial day care service
 		which actually is the best of of both worlds it's it's not a a big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX> and they do have separate <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> for the the different developmental ages so it
 		the the youngest <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> now the the the new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">infant</ENAMEX> still receives personalized care
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh but at the same school his his older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> is receiving uh basically pre kindergarten
 		care
 	
 	
 		my situation is a little bit different but it still covers the same type of problem
 		i am a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> but i'm also employed but my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandson</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> moved back in and lived with us for about a year
 		and so and he was <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about four</NUMEX>
 		so it was sort of like another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> raising a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a</NUMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> and we're all working <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX>
 		so it i have some of the same problems it's no longer a problem now that he is older and in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> but this has been a problem no matter what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> you're in
 		and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the things that and then also in the setting where i work i see a lot of uh young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> especially uh young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 		who have to take time off because of problems with the babysitting or child care services
 		and i think uh one of the things that and also when i had the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandson</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandson</ENAMEX> here that we were keeping care of him
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the main problems that affects work and affects the care too is when you're as any when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> is the least bit sick
 		uh uh the you have to come get them there's a problem and one of the things i would like to see would be a type of day care service
 		where there is uh at the same place where they're care for as a well child they have facilities for uh sick care
 	
 	
 		i i i know i i've had the problem myself where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> might might begin to run a a low grade fever
 		and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> calls up and says come get your come get your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> uh your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> looks like maybe he has conjunctivitis come get your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> immediately whether or not
 	
 	
 		come get him
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it's really true uh come get your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> immediately uh it and that's it's it is a big disruption uh it's particularly bad in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first year</TIMEX> if you're back to work and
 		you know how frequently that you have to go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> for the little ones just for checkups alone in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> year
 		uh sometimes your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> doesn't think that that's
 		really terrific
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		but you have to take time off and and go take your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> to to well baby care on top of that now the the general cold and sniffles and and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first year</TIMEX> illnesses
 		and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> doesn't want to want to keep your child
 		we do have up here um and some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> do this as a way of defraying their costs they run day cares for sick <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 		out of their hospital <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> but
 	
 	
 		well that's an interesting yeah
 	
 	
 		that it and it's it's an interesting way to approach it but there's a problem
 		i don't know how many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> would be willing to take their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 		to a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a</NUMEX> a location a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> has never seen
 	
 	
 		oh that's that's another reason why i would preferred it to be with the same services
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> that i work with is a large <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> and they're looking at day care now and i would love to see day care on site
 		where if you have lunch you can go over and spend it with a child
 		uh if you have and i would like a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty four hour day</TIMEX> care and it's big enough where it could do that
 		where if you worked different shifts uh you could uh uh
 		bring the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> in
 	
 	
 		and but yeah
 	
 	
 		for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night</TIMEX> where you know they would be there with you and you can stop in at anytime on your break so that your the check and balances of the type of care is subject to anybody stopping in anytime
 	
 	
 		i i know we we would've liked to
 		
 		
 	