
 
     		
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um um</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		so child care do you have any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no no i don't
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh do you
 	
 	
 		yeah we have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> we have uh a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four year old</TIMEX> and a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two year old</TIMEX> at least they will be in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX> i'm getting used to calling them that since they're all prepared for their birthdays
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		are they are they in any sort of child care
 	
 	
 		
 
 		uh yes and no uh and my <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three almost four year old</TIMEX> is been in a preschool <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> a day uh since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX> it's a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Montessori</ENAMEX> school
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and in a sense that's a day care although we don't use it for day care we chose it because of the educational features of the school
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh prior to that we had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> come over uh one or <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two afternoons</TIMEX> a week
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh provide in home day care uh more or less to give my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> you know a break in the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoons</TIMEX> to uh go out and run errands and do things um but care for us the the problematic time is in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the evening</TIMEX> uh just finding babysitters because of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the ages</TIMEX> we don't really
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		um but care for us the the problematic time is in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the evening</TIMEX> uh just finding babysitters because of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the ages</TIMEX> we don't really
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		it's not that we don't trust but we just don't feel comfortable with uh  uh younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> uh early teens
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh we've been pretty fortunate we've had babysitters that tend to be in their late <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teens</ENAMEX> they drive over in their own <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh the older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who watches the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> sometimes comes over in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the evening</TIMEX>  so
 	
 	
 		oh that's nice
 	
 	
 		i i've been saved i've only had to take babysitters home twice i guess which isn't bad but we have uh all all of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saint Louis</ENAMEX> so the normal family infrastructure that uh a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have just isn't there for us
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		all all of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saint Louis</ENAMEX> so the normal family infrastructure that uh a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have just isn't there for us
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right right
 	
 	
 		we don't have uh i mean  my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> has a younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> who's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years</TIMEX> younger but has <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> the same age as
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and we were asking <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Denise</ENAMEX> one time well how much do you pay for babysitters she goes i don't know i've only paid <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> once
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		yeah and that was you know after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX> but she just has in-laws and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">siblings</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		wow
 		oh okay i see
 	
 	
 		uh you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> that that watch and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> she lives in a neighborhood that has a lot of uh young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> and our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> seem to be mostly retired
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		plus it's harder to to impose on uh you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> uh they're willing to take the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> but it's it feels difficult to impose when they don't have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> themselves
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah right
 		my
 	
 	
 		do you ever do any babysitting yourself
 	
 	
 		oh yeah i i uh
 		my my job pretty much my junior year in high school was sitting uh for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> that lived uh right next door to me they uh
 		and i did i did that everyday
 		until uh their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> got home
 	
 	
 		um-hum it's a it's a great job
 	
 	
 		uh
 		it is
 	
 	
 		uh you know for the most part uh especially you know in our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> it's
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's clean and neat and the refrigerator's stocked and most the time when they come over in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the evening</TIMEX> it's you know an hours worth of of real care and then the rest is just taking responsibility for sleeping <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		right
 	
 	
 		we did have uh one occurrence that was kind of interesting we had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> that came
 		alternatively uh when our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> was about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one year old</TIMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it wasn't a problem situation but it was one that just made my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> somewhat nervous the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> wasn't quite together she was easily distracted
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		she was nice enough the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> uh you know my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> liked her but we ended up uh choosing not to to have her on a regular basis making a conscious decision and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it was a tough one because it was convenient for us she was dependable in in that she would show up but we just didn't feel comfortable and we see our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> who have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> the same age making more easy decisions uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		um
 	
 	
 		meaning that uh they're they seem to be pretty lax in in who comes in and who watches them
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 	
 	
 		we have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> who has a large <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and they have uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> under <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years old</TIMEX> they have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">twins</ENAMEX> and they're in
 		they have a live-in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">housekeeper</ENAMEX> and it just isn't a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> that we would have even to our home on a a regular basis much less on a
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> live-in basis just different value systems and uh different
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		different attitude towards child rearing
 	
 	
 		um-hum yeah my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX> um
 		she's she's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> and so she works you know everyday <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> and uh she keeps <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">really long hours</TIMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> and uh
 		she's got a little <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two year old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> and she now has a live in
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	