
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		what do you feel about it
 	
 	
 		uh
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		well let's see um generally i don't think there should be much gun control uh i like to i like to do a lot of hunting and i have my own <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> at home and stuff but
 		uh the older i get i think the more i believe there ought to be gun control
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		for instance uh just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> i go out my front door and somebody had shot a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> out of their front door their subdivision and the thing kind of wound up right where my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> get picked up at the bus stop
 	
 	
 		oh really that's kind of creepy
 	
 	
 		so uh
 		yeah it is creepy you know and uh you know it makes me think hey you know there's a lot of a there's a lot of nutcases you know living even in you know in your subdivision and i mean
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well what do you think about like automatic <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> and stuff i mean those can't be used for hunting
 	
 	
 		yeah see yeah you look like look at automatic <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> and things like that and uh you know clearly they have no no useful hunting purpose and uh
 	
 	
 		yeah unless you're really bad
 	
 	
 		yeah even then if you're that bad it probably wouldn't help any anyway just uh it'll help you kill like i mean up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hunters</ENAMEX> get killed anyway just with shotguns you know so i can't imagine what it'd be like if they're doing it with automatic weapons
 	
 	
 		
  
 		oh really
 		what kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> do you use when you hunt
 	
 	
 		uh when i hunt i use a twelve gauge <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">shotgun</ENAMEX> it's uh actually a lot of heavy broacher so it's kind of a short range kind of thing
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh really what kind of stuff do you hunt with it
 	
 	
 		uh well i the last time i hunted i hunted <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">turkey</ENAMEX> actually and uh you know it's
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		i wasn't too successful but  i would've shot <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> if i'd see one  so and
 	
 	
 		was that
 		yeah
 		when you use a shot gun do you have to like pick uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pellets</ENAMEX> out of the  when you're i mean
 	
 	
 		
  
 		oh yeah well you're supposed and yeah you're supposed to sure you have to try to get it out of there
 	
 	
 		shot
 		
  
 		but
 		yeah i guess i could you could probably hurt your tooth or something
 	
 	
 		uh
 		well it's actually uh i don't know if this is true anymore but it's lead shot saying that you don't want to
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		you don't want eat a piece of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">lead</ENAMEX> but um
 		yeah i think uh you're supposed to do that also you have to be real careful uh about what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animal</ENAMEX>'s been eating you know like uh if you ever hunt pheasant you know sometimes they get into <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">corn</ENAMEX> that's been uh like you know has mercury on it or something and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 		ugh
 	
 	
 		and uh to keep the because the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">corn</ENAMEX> gets treated to keep uh insect dusts away so so if you go in and you dig into the pheasant yeah you can get mercury poison
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh so there's i mean there's sort of some risks to that actually uh let me think  gun control uh i i generally generally actually since i live so close to <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX> and since it's the murder capital of the world and you know the
 	
 	
 		anyway
 		yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX>'s not far behind
 	
 	
 		yeah well they have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> i mean i guess they have this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX> too but i mean they got <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> you know running around you know driving down the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> with sub <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">machine guns</ENAMEX> and stuff and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know i don't even let my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> go down there anymore unless you know i'm with them or something and then we just stick strictly to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mall</ENAMEX> area you know we never never <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">venture</ENAMEX> outside of that area so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well i mean i feel as if nobody you know if there weren't already hand hand so many hand <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> and everything prevalent you wouldn't need you know you wouldn't need one for self-defense but it seems like there's so many of them
 		uh that it's really impossible you know it'd be impossible to it'd be impossible to do anyway i mean <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would buy them regardless whether it was uh legal or illegal illegal i think
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		doesn't that kind of strike you as  especially in big <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> that uh you know the law enforcement <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> aren't really capable of of providing the kind of protection that you they should be able to provide
 	
 	
 		no not at all our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> as a matter of fact there's some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> that walked in and stole one of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">roommate</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bikes</ENAMEX> while he was in the shower just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX> and that's kind of creepy to we live i live right down <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> and uh if they'd wanted to you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		coming at  or something you know
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah if they wanted to shoot me or something there there wouldn't have been any problem i mean they just it was in broad it was during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> too so obviously they don't have a whole lot of fear of uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
  
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		being caught by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> in anyway anyway
 	
 	
 		yeah i
 		you know i feel like like you know the when they when they interview these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> you know the burglars and things they that the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> things that they say keep them out of a house best are <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> because they
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
  
 		yeah we're getting a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> as a
 	
 	
 		yeah so they know there's a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> there they know there's a gun there you know they're probably not going to rob you they'll probably go to the next house
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh if they if they suddenly pass a really global law that says you can't have any <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> you know there i mean there's guaranteed to be a higher percentage of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> just breaking in assuming that these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> don't have any <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		it's just crazy i've seen the statistics statistics on the number of deaths by hand <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> compared with like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX> and and it's just uh i mean they have like you know a handful a year
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and it's just outrageous  how much how many we have here but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i don't i don't know if there's anything that can be if gun control would solve that problem
 	
 	
 		yeah contributing maybe contributing factors too nobody nobody knows about yeah i'm i'm usually pretty skeptical on that kind of stuff these studies
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		and besides that i don't think i think the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NRA</ENAMEX>'s got such a big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lobby</ENAMEX> that i don't think  they'd be able to
 	
 	
 		yeah clearly they have some other motive you know i mean their their argument used to be you know the communist were going to take over or something well they aren't anymore you know so what's the argument now well
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 		
 	