
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well um i live at the beach and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and we don't really have a lot of recycling here
 	
 	
 		well yeah
 	
 	
 		but you have do you have a lot in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rochester</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		we have a lot of recycling in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rochester</ENAMEX> they do uh what they call curb side pick up
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		and so they come by and they'll pick up uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> and cardboard and uh different colors of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glass</ENAMEX> and uh
 		see what else tin cans and uh plastic like you know your milk jugs and you know <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">soap soap soap</ENAMEX> bottle uh jugs and all that type of stuff
 	
 	
 		oh so they just pick up everything
 	
 	
 		yeah so do they do any uh any sort of recycling back down where you are
 	
 	
 		well i think they do some voluntary on the beach but i live in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartments</ENAMEX> and we don't have it here
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		okay
 	
 	
 		um
 		in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wilmington</ENAMEX>
 		they have it there more i think and that's like the big <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> near us
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but um
 		i really wish they would have it
 	
 	
 		okay do uh
 		i mean what do you think they ought to be doing down there in terms of doing more recycling and things like that
 	
 	
 		well sometimes i don't feel so bad
 		i mean it's really i mean it this is really sad too because we have a big dumpster at our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartments</ENAMEX> and there's this little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> that goes through our trash all the time to get the cans out
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh wow that's really unfortunate
 	
 	
 		i know
 	
 	
 		well they do a whole lot of recycling here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rochester</ENAMEX> i'm kind of hard pressed to say they ought to do more because i don't know what else they'd pick up i mean you know they
 		they say things like you know they want all the little uh you know those little recycling symbols like the number ones and the number twos and all those things
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well they you know they say they'll pick up anything with number <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> but they <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> who are uh picking it up are are kind of  i don't know i guess they aren't well trained
 		because like they say they also say they won't pick up you know the you know like you buy a uh uh uh a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pack</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pop</ENAMEX> and you know the plastic rings that they come in
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well nowadays those are coming with a little recycling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">symbol</ENAMEX> on them you know with the number <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> but they won't pick it up because they say well no we don't pick up that we only pick up you know like the milk jugs and soap jugs and stuff like that
 		so i think they could be doing more if they here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rochester</ENAMEX>
 		if they just uh
 		quit doing uh you know so much based on what the container is in terms on what used to have in it or something and if they did more on
 		you know what the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">material</ENAMEX> is
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so uh i don't know so they don't do any recycling hardly at all down there
 	
 	
 		well i mean they do some but none of it's mandatory
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and like i said i live in an apartment <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so they don't do it for us
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		but some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> i've seen some of the bins around some of the houses
 	
 	
 		okay well do you have any place you could take stuff if you wanted to
 	
 	
 		there is a place
 		but it's in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wilmington</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		and so it's like a a big hassle you know to try to get everything together and i mean uh you'd have to save it up and have all that stuff lying around your apartment
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		well that's wild i mean like well how far is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wilmington</ENAMEX> from there
 	
 	
 		it's <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">um about twenty minutes</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh wow so you'd have to get everything together and take it over there that'd be a real pain they ought to do the curb side stuff
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		i know but i just think it's it must be hard to do in an <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> thing like this
 	
 	
 		they do it here i mean they they have it here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rochester</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartments</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you know they have to do some special stuff but you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment complex</ENAMEX> it's not the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> see here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rochester</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> does it
 	
 	
 		really
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it would like i i own my own <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> so the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> comes by and they pick up you know
 		the stuff on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the same day</TIMEX> they pick up the trash
 		but for the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartments</ENAMEX> all the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> places you know pay somebody to pick up all the trash
 		and so the apartment <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you know the the the waste disposal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have to come up with their own system but we passed a law here and they said you just got to do it there's no choice because all the you know all the landfills up here are full
 	
 	
 		yeah now see that i think that's why it's not as strict in the south it's because we still have have a lot of land left
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh wow
 	
 	
 		so i mean but i mean <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> do need to realize that that there's not always going to be land
 	
 	
 		but that's going to change
 		yeah
 		yeah that's going to change at some point you know  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of years ago</TIMEX> nobody around here talked about it and then <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> everybody just kind of woke up and said gee you know we're we're in trouble and we got to fix this problem
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		but i know i went to see my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX> and he
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		was in a voluntary program
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	