
 
     		
 	
 		you know about computers
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well i'm sitting in front of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> right now
 	
 	
 		you are
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah i just logged off when i got this call
 	
 	
 		oh
 		well good you can talk about it more than i can i i don't own a computer but um i'm in college <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">right now</TIMEX> and uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> has an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX> that she has me type letters on a lot and i do a lot of merging with addresses and letters and
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		that's basically the only information i have on computers  i think i'd it would be good for me to have a laptop computer for for for college
 	
 	
 		oh i see
 		that'd be handy in college
 	
 	
 		but um basically my knowledge is limited
 	
 	
 		huh well so uh what uh word processing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">program</ENAMEX> do you use on that machine
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh WordPerfect</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		ah okay yeah that's the most popular one
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah i use <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> Word which is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> most popular one
 		partly because uh
 		oh i i live and work right right near <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> and uh it's just real handy to call them up for help or anything kind of a local product
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh
 	
 	
 		so uh yeah they're real handy i got uh
 		got mine <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years ago</TIMEX> uh gee maybe it was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> i'm not sure but
 	
 	
 		uh-huh what do you do for a living do you use it in that
 	
 	
 		well just for a little bit of typing and stuff i work for i do tech support for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that makes telephone equipment
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and uh so i use it for uh
 		oh memos and for communications uh i have a modem on my uh computer
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i use it for electronic mail and for uh sending faxes
 	
 	
 		oh
 		i i joke around about being a mechanic on the printers i uh  i dropped uh one of the paper the paper <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">holder</ENAMEX> on that that connects to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">printer</ENAMEX> on the floor <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX> in my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX>'s office
 	
 	
 		hum
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and it broke into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> pieces  it comes in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> pieces but it separated  and there was there was a little little piece of it that broke off
 	
 	
 		uh oh
 		oh i see did you get it put back together
 	
 	
 		so i panicked called the main <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> borrowed their's so i could go ahead and print out the the documents
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		and then i compared the broken pieces to the good piece the the good paper uh paper <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">holder</ENAMEX> that was together that i borrowed and put it all back together and  huh
 	
 	
 		hum
 		did it take glue
 		did it take glue
 	
 	
 		no no it didn't it it needed it needed uh uh some <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glue</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glue</ENAMEX> back the broken piece off but it works fine without it so i left a note to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> am i out of hot water now
 	
 	
 		it just popped apart huh
 		oh well that's good
 		you were probably in a bit of a panic
 	
 	
 		i was i i was panicking  i skipped my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> to fix that
 	
 	
 		huh
 		so what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> do you go to in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tyler Junior College</ENAMEX> right now in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tyler Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tyler</ENAMEX> okay
 	
 	
 		but um i'm interviewing i interviewed i had an i'm i'm a music major and i had an audition <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baylor University</ENAMEX> it's a private <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Baptist Christian</ENAMEX> School
 	
 	
 		oh really
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Waco</ENAMEX> and so uh that went real well
 	
 	
 		well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">roommate</ENAMEX>'s a music major
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		and i work with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seattle Opera</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh my goodness
 	
 	
 		when i'm not working as an engineer
 	
 	
 		are you so you're into music
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh a bit yeah yeah i i actually got into uh opera through an interest in acting but uh i'm getting more interested in singing
 	
 	
 		oh my goodness
 	
 	
 		so uh yeah i'm in <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about four operas</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> up here and we're just i just finished <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ballad of Baby Doe</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's great
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		which was uh written in the early fifties by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Douglas Moore</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's a true story of a uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> in the late <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighteen hundreds</NUMEX> who became <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fabulously</ENAMEX> wealthy from uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">silver</ENAMEX> mining yeah uh but anyway it was a really great show it was kind of like doing it was more like doing a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX> musical than a an opera it was all in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> and it was uh it reminded me of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 		i love that
 	
 	
 		and
 		and then before that i was in uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nutcracker</ENAMEX> with uh <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pacific Northwest Ballet</ENAMEX> i've been doing that for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a number of years</TIMEX> playing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX> in the party scene and then before that i was in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Phedalio</ENAMEX> which is uh the only opera ever written by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beethoven</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh my goodness
 	
 	
 		so uh it's a lot of fun
 	
 	
 		well well did you take music <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classes classes</ENAMEX> in college
 	
 	
 		well i started uh no i didn't um but i've uh started voice lessons recently with uh a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who's a a principle <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singer</ENAMEX> around here for
 		she's in a usually in a couple of operas a year
 	
 	
 		well my goodness that's wonderful i hope well
 	
 	
 		so yes so my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">roommate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Candice</ENAMEX> in uh uh music <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> at uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Washington</ENAMEX> and uh she's uh
 		uh doing student teaching right now teaching music in junior high schools
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		so does she want to do that or does she want to get into opera
 	
 	
 		i think she wants to do that she also sings in a chorus
 	
 	
 		oh okay see what i'm i want to do is uh get my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Bachelor</ENAMEX>'s in music theory possibly music theory and uh if not that then music education
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	