
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well um
 		do you ever watch Wall Street Week
 	
 	
 		no i don't watch that one um i get a lot of my news from uh
 		odd <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> if it isn't uh public radio or the local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">listener</ENAMEX> supported station i get a lot of it off of the uh the nets <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Usenet BBS</ENAMEX> networks
 		and uh
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">monthly</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> and newsletters
 	
 	
 		what kind of magazines
 	
 	
 		you ever heard of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Mondo</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		fairly obscure it's published out of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Berkeley</ENAMEX> it's a futurist magazine
 		apparently i heard about it later the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> started it
 		as a on inheritance money he just wanted to have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> of his own and he wanted to be future oriented
 		so it's really fringe science um new <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemicals</ENAMEX> brain enhancement technologies virtual reality all that stuff that we're just starting to hear about this whole <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> covers it
 		and then from that i can follow up on other sources and a lot of the stuff in there turns up on bulletin boards as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> talk about it
 	
 	
 		well i mean do you think that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> is credible
 		or
 	
 	
 		uh depends on what it's about and who's writing a lot of this stuff is just reporting somebody may be developing some new technology and they'll be talking about the plans for the use of it
 		it's not the kind of thing that would be really talent you know it's not something that's questionable like political opinions
 		it's sort of a state of technology and what are we going to do with this and what do you suppose would happen if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> got ahold of it and you know that kind of thing
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		and then uh you know the the the best source of news the comic strips  not really
 	
 	
 		wait so so you're you're a a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm follower</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Doonesbury or</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah absolutely
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bloom County</ENAMEX> now Out <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Land</ENAMEX> and all the rest of them
 		but yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doonesbury</ENAMEX> is great i mean
 		sometimes he that doesn't even try to be funny he just puts stuff in that <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">strip</ENAMEX> that we're not going to see anywhere else
 		and uh uh like when he was quoting an entire week from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s speeches and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> was completely incoherent
 		i think that's when it finally they had to issue a press release that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> was under the effect of this weird <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> that uh has been banned in some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> and that it was affecting his speech
 	
 	
 		of uh
 	
 	
 		yeah that's the one
 	
 	
 		oh
 		but um
 		anyway well um
 	
 	
 		go back to
 	
 	
 		so you
 		well do you ever watch any network news or
 		anything like that at at
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">60 Minutes</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">60 Minutes</ENAMEX> i always watch <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">60 Minutes</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah i watch <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">60 Minutes</ENAMEX> and i watch <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20/20</NUMEX> sometimes
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i used to watch them but then i caught them in a bald face lie and i had didn't really care anymore
 	
 	
 		what lie did you catch them in
 	
 	
 		it was a long time ago they just did a hatchet job on ultra light <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> and i used to fly one
 		so i knew what i was talking about and they really i mean it was a classic case of what the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> accuse the liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX> of doing you know they fabricating uh
 		making making one
 		picking an item out of context and blowing it up i mean it was just such a classic
 	
 	
 		oh really <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20/20</NUMEX> did that
 	
 	
 		yeah they did that it who damn themselves
 	
 	
 		oh that's so
 		that's so funny because um
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20/20</TIMEX> they had <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane Polly</ENAMEX> talking about how she had been exploited by the tabloids and what a travesty it was that the press would fabricate stories
 	
 	
 		yeah really
 		and then there they are doing it too
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so you just have to watch you know you have to assume that with every story you're watching or everything you're reading what what special interest could they possibly have that they would make them slanted this particular way
 	
 	
 		so
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		if you assume they're biased and then look for some opposite biases you get a fairly good idea of what's going on
 	
 	
 		i know and it's like especially like if with the network news they always comment about everything and their comments are always biased
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know just like all the presidential
 		um
 		campaign things that have been going on
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		if you can just you get a different slant if you just listen to the comments and a lot of times they don't even show you all of what happened
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		sound bytes all they'd rather do is give you a little sound bytes
 		they do it's it's so funny they talk about the liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX> but
 		most most every well virtually every TV station and almost every <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> is owned by conservative well off white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">businessmen</ENAMEX>
 		and they have to be conservative because they have this <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">multimillion dollar</NUMEX> investment to protect
 		and they're beholding to their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">advertisers</ENAMEX> they have to be conservative but the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> i mean if you're going to be in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> of reporting if you're a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> uh you get cynical
 		and uh cynicism can sometimes be confused with liberalism
 		
 		
 	