
 
     		
 	
 		have any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		no uh i'm single and but i've i been keeping an eye on what the child care situation is and i have several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> that do have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well what do you think about child care i mean i don't have any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 		so
 	
 	
 		well it's it's uh it's
 		i i feel that uh regulation uh uh whether be at the state or federal level is a must so we can have some sort of standards from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> place to another uh
 		that uh in terms of cleanliness uh the ratio between the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> is maintained uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> and so on
 		i don't think <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adult</ENAMEX> should have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">like twenty</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> to keep after
 	
 	
 		well
 		well do you think that how many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> do you think they should be allowed
 		or should be in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time
 	
 	
 		well the facility i i don't have a problem with it's just how many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> or how many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> to an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adult</ENAMEX> and if if i remember correctly um
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adult</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> was very good
 		for around here and was more twelve to twelve <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adult</ENAMEX> was about the average
 	
 	
 		but then and well in public school um you have one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> for every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> kids
 	
 	
 		and so on but the but in day care usually the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> is not able to um
 		function totally on his own whether if it's if it's uh a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">toddler</ENAMEX>
 		uh diapers have to be changed uh must be tended to constantly
 		for fear that they might get into something
 	
 	
 		well um do you think
 		that there is enough child care available in your area
 	
 	
 		i think there is it's just that sometimes location makes it difficult if if if i was married there is no place between my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and work
 		that is convenient that i could uh use as for child care
 		they're usually in areas where they can they can afford to set up shop and not where it's convenient for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are working
 	
 	
 		um-hum well do you think that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> should provide child care
 	
 	
 		well some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> i've noticed will provide the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> and then let a let a uh a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> come in and provide the child care while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employer</ENAMEX>'s just providing providing the the facility
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		in many cases like in large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> that becomes a perk to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> where they're able to get reduced child care and in and in the case of uh new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> they're able to go
 		uh instead of a cigarette break they can go see their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ten minutes</TIMEX> and then go back to work
 		you have a better retention then of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">um people</ENAMEX> by not having them go on sick leave or uh paid <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">holiday</TIMEX> to take care of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and so it saves the company money it's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">in the company's best interest</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well i think that really am i am
 		all for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> providing some kype type of child care
 		or at least the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> and i don't think we really have enough of that
 	
 	
 		no it's it's it's a relatively new idea from what i understand
 		it's has uh enough <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> haven't gotten on the bandwagon they where they could see a realization and um savings of money <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">right now</TIMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> being at work and not taking off and being at home
 		if you make it convenient for them <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> will stay uh stay
 		or stay with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> if you if there're more perks like that you can give them
 		it's not just money it's it's everything about it and child care is a big issue
 		it's important to me if i was married and had children
 		i'd want to be as close to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> as i possibly could
 	
 	
 		oh i know and i think that if i had <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and i couldn't find adequate child care i probably wouldn't want to work
 	
 	
 		i'm the same way but then again how do you provide for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> when you can't work
 	
 	
 		you you i know you really don't have a choice
 		but then um
 		i'm my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> had
 		a case where um
 		his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> got sick in child care
 		and um
 		all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX> at the child care place that he went to all came down with an ear infection and that's
 		i think there should be some kind of um health regulation or or
 		some kind of i don't know how bad i mean i can see how it could happen with all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> there together
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	