
 
     		
 	
 		hi this is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hi Lee</ENAMEX> from  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lee</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		okay
 		uh
 	
 	
 		yeah it snowed this morning and it was all gone by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh wow so it's getting warmer up there then huh
 	
 	
 		well i don't know yeah i guess it's not really cold
 	
 	
 		it's it's cooling off down here it's going to get down to probably around <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixty</TIMEX> tonight so
 	
 	
 		oh shucks
 	
 	
 		yeah just as beautiful during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> though
 		
 
 		i work down here for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pratt Whitney</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		and i heard about this over the TechNet
 		on the uh on the computer there at work we get uh electronic mail all the time
 	
 	
 		like the usenet news groups
 	
 	
 		uh not news <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> no not really i'm an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineer</ENAMEX> there
 	
 	
 		oh yeah i saw it on uh something called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Comp DCom Telecom</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		okay
 		yeah and what do you do
 	
 	
 		um i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">county</ENAMEX> engineer i look mostly at sewage
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 		okay well it's getting kind of late so you want to get started here we're going to talk about taxes i guess
 	
 	
 		uh oh yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		you probably talk <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">all night</TIMEX> about this okay
 	
 	
 		well we'll see
 	
 	
 		
 
 		okay then uh you want to go ahead and start or do you want me to go ahead and start when we
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hey</ENAMEX> whatever you like
 	
 	
 		okay i'll i'll i'll let you go ahead and start and then i'll i'll press the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> now are you ready here we go
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		all right taxes well
 		i think uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are not getting the money's worth and number <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> aren't willing to pay good money for a decent value
 		so i got to blame everyone on that
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh you why why do you think uh we're not getting our money's worth
 	
 	
 		well i think there's uh some entrenched greed in general mismanagement in government
 		hey i work for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>  i
 	
 	
 		you probably see the waste first hand then
 	
 	
 		well we've you know we've got a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are dedicated and trying to do a good job but we've also got a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that think the world owes them a living and you know they don't want to do anymore than they've
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know than they did <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> or they don't want to do any more than the least they can possibly do they have no pride no pride at all
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right well the the thing that makes me angry about paying taxes i don't mind paying it for services you know for defense
 		uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and uh and and for services like <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX> and for sewage and and for basic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> and stuff but when we got to pay for uh some of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are on welfare and stuff that's when i get uh i get pretty mad
 		uh i mean i think a lot of that is wasted
 	
 	
 		yeah well there's a lot of money in that and where there's a lot of money there tends to be a lot of uh
 		what is it uh greed deceit mismanagement
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah right i it
 	
 	
 		who was it who wrote <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Animal Farm George Orwell</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		absolute power corrupts absolutely
 	
 	
 		yes
 		yeah that's that's that's that's true uh i'm not sure what to do about it though uh you know this is a big <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">election this year</TIMEX> and everything we all these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> running for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i
 	
 	
 		uh it seems to me that there's this uh basic idea that you shouldn't let <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> starve to death
 		and that you should have some sort of
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">charity</ENAMEX> toward them
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		and that uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> just aren't willing to let <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> starve to death in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> if they don't want to work
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh therefore they're not willing to change the systems
 		i got another theory if you want to hear it it's not really mine just that the uh the powers that be mainly you and me
 	
 	
 		what's that
 	
 	
 		are keeping this whole class of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people poor</ENAMEX> and helpless just so they're out of the way
 	
 	
 		no no i don't i don't think we are
 		do do
 	
 	
 		well we're definitely keeping them poor and down trodden and helpless
 	
 	
 		um i i don't agree with that
 	
 	
 		you don't think the welfare system fosters a whole class of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that
 	
 	
 		oh you mean by us paying taxes is a poor step we are doing that indirect oh yes i agree i think that's the way the well yes i i do agree with that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i i mean it it it
 		okay  light misunderstanding
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah i i thought you  but i personally was doing that  no i  i don't think we're standing in the way but i think that the way the welfare system is set up yes it does kind of foster that kind of an attitude with people
 	
 	
 		whoa
 		
 
 	
 	
 		when they can just sit around their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">porches</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all day</TIMEX> and uh still get a check at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the week</TIMEX> i think that's uh pretty pitiful especially when they're able bodied people
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah and uh you know i sort of i feel a bit guilty about that because uh you know i vote
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and uh i'm not agitating against it i'm not agitating for it that's for damn sure can i say that on this
 	
 	
 		yeah well the you know the the thing is we get these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in there that are like career <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> and they're grieved by so many people
 		and they're
 		
 		
 	