
 
     		
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
 
 		okay well let's see invasions of privacy actually um
 		i can't think of too many except uh oh occasionally my employer
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		or um
 		sometimes it seems of a bit of an invasion when i when i get calls from phone solicitors
 	
 	
 		yeah that's that's one of the that's also that's also for me invasion of privacy that's also a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of my pet peeves
 	
 	
 		well i get i've uh figured out someways creatively as to fight back with phone <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">solicitors</ENAMEX> though
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		like um well
 		i i've discovered it's kind of fun to try to
 		take control of the conversation
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh like you know typically
 		they're reading from a script
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		so if you start asking questions right away
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		or do anything that's a little out out of the ordinary they get really thrown
 	
 	
 		oh i see
 	
 	
 		so like often what i'll do is i'll call up and say
 		hi i'm <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carla</ENAMEX> from XYZ <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> and i'll say  excuse me uh what's your name again and uh act like i'm writing it down and  could i have your last name <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carla</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and what's the name of your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> you know and this by this time they're really shook up and then um
 		i ask her uh uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carla</ENAMEX> could i have your home telephone number please
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and and they go  well uh no i go well why not i said well i don't give out my home number as well why not i mean you're calling me at home i ought to be able to call you at home and that really shakes them up
 	
 	
 		well that's good you have a good sense of humor with it i i would do something like talk to them for like <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two minutes</TIMEX> or something and then say uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> to talk to isn't isn't isn't here right now wait a minute i think they're just just a minute let me see if they're here and then you leave
 	
 	
 		yeah right or put them on hold yeah
 	
 	
 		and see how long yeah see how long they'll wait but
 	
 	
 		yeah well another thing you can do is you can pretend that you got them on call waiting
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		say i'm on long distance on the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">line</ENAMEX>  or you can just say no thank you and hang up
 	
 	
 		yeah right well i
 		yeah well one of my
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tad T</ENAMEX> A <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX> okay uh one of my things one of my pet <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">peeves</ENAMEX> is social security numbers
 	
 	
 		ah
 	
 	
 		and that is um
 		i'm an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adult</ENAMEX> but i'm going back to school and everywhere on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campus</ENAMEX> where i write a check it's they want social security numbers on everything and i just go bananas
 		because it's just it's number one it's none of their business and it and it doesn't have they want it they want it to be put on your check
 	
 	
 		yeah and those are used as pin numbers a lot like with my bank uh
 		uh if i want to move money around over the phone or check my balance or anything the pin number they want is the last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> digits of the social security
 	
 	
 		right
 		exactly
 		and plus in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> they have this new thing where they have the magnetic stripe on the back of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX>'s license i don't have one yet yes
 	
 	
 		really
 		i didn't know that huh
 	
 	
 		yes and that's another thing so they think they can plug you in for a profile see and i
 	
 	
 		well now where where do they use the stripe
 	
 	
 		in a a reader
 	
 	
 		oh you mean like when a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cop</ENAMEX> pulls you over he runs it through a reader
 	
 	
 		or something right exactly
 	
 	
 		well that's amazing
 	
 	
 		but see what's happening though is that it's starting be integrated to going they're going to try to integrate it into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> too
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		so so but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> can't get all the information
 	
 	
 		yeah well like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> can probably develop their own databases but they can't get into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> of motor <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicles</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		i'll bet that's it
 	
 	
 		but the yeah but in other words so they can verify they can go in and and get the card and get information off it
 		but the the police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> could get more information you might say
 	
 	
 		yeah because they could
 	
 	
 		but i i just i don't i i don't like the idea i don't like the idea of business
 		and information you know and in the world is coming to is is is information
 	
 	
 		well then you know about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">caller</ENAMEX> ID
 	
 	
 		oh exactly oh yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hey</ENAMEX> did you get uh did you get the number for this off of the internet
 	
 	
 		yeah i did
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		are you an internet man
 	
 	
 		yeah most of the uh most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i talk to on here are on internet
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah did you get it off of uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telecom Digest</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		oh yeah i read that constantly
 	
 	
 		so do i yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah i post on there from work under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Cook</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Proctor and Associates</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		and at home as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tad Cook</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i see
 		yeah
 		yeah i have an account at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> so i'm able to do that
 	
 	
 		oh yeah well i got <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX> from a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of mine uh owns a Unix consulting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> and gave me a free account there <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years ago</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh i see
 	
 	
 		so i can just dial it up and
 	
 	
 		so you have a free dial you dial in free yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah it's real neat
 	
 	
 		yeah what is it is it <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight hundred</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">number</ENAMEX> or you just happen to be within the boundaries
 	
 	
 		oh i'm with yeah we're in actually almost exactly the same exchange i'm real near his office
 	
 	
 		oh okay right yeah
 	
 	
 		but it's uh it's it's pretty neat he doesn't have a full <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UUCP</ENAMEX> fee but i
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		well if you if you're on you're on the usenet groups you might try uh alt privacy
 	
 	
 		i yeah i'm on this uh moderated <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> a mailing list uh
 		that's  uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telecom</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	