
 
     		
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan</ENAMEX> um
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		it seems to me that most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> rather make a decision between going all out
 		particularly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">males</ENAMEX> go all out on the career or they go or they spend some real quality time with their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> when their when their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are still young and and are willing to spend time with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> what do you think about that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		uh
 		yeah that's an interesting point i work in uh the computer business which tends to be pretty
 		high pressure and time consuming and i work with a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> who are just now having <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and it's interesting to see how they handle it because in a lot of cases they're still trying to put in the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> but they're also trying to spend a lot of time at home
 		and in many cases they've got <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouses</ENAMEX> who work so it's it's an interesting juggling pattern i
 		my impression is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> try to uh to do both if they can as tough as that is
 	
 	
 		do you think it's possible
 	
 	
 		uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> that's a good question i've my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight and a half</NUMEX> and
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six now</TIMEX> and i've been working in this business you know while they were growing up and you know it's  it's tough uh there have been plenty of times where i've had to
 		work <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">long hours</TIMEX> so that you know during a particular week i might not see them as much as i wanted to
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i i do sense that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s expectations <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> are often different than they were maybe in my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX>'s generation where
 		you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> raising was kind of seen as the
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>'s responsibility and if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> had to work <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">extra long hours</TIMEX> or travel you know that's just the way it was i think
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> have somewhat different expectations when they try to tailor their schedules as much as they can
 	
 	
 		i got uh my office <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mate</ENAMEX> um he he got divorced and and uh
 		he was talking about that the thing that he was gladdest about in in the relationship that he was in before that uh he spent like
 		a lot more time than the average <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> i mean he took his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> out um ice skating and water skiing and and i mean just if there was something that that he could think of to do with them he went out and did it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and now now that he's he's no longer the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> has custody of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> he still has a good relationship with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		which you know a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> even in marriages that stay together try to all of the sudden get to know their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> when they turn eighteen or something like that
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		but but i think i think he did the right thing is is making sure that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> really
 		i mean they might get mad as heck at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">at</TIMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> but making sure that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> know from you know one <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two three</NUMEX> that that there's no one that loves them as much as uh as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> and mom
 		you know
 	
 	
 		yeah i think there's a lot to that you you really have to establish the relationship early on
 		yeah certainly read a lot or heard a lot of stories about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who grow up saying i felt i never really knew my father
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and i you know it's it's hard to say i don't
 		travel in a wide social circle but it's my impression that a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> are are trying to change anyway
 	
 	
 		i think it has been changing over the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generations</ENAMEX> you know i see my granddad
 		now and and it's really it's really way too late i i mean my granddad grew up in the military you know he was always the never show your feelings but it seems like he tries real hard now to to try let his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX> know that that he loves them and it's
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		i mean to some extent it's too late
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> i'm sorry go ahead
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah i was just saying yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> um
 		i always knew that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> loved me he but he never really said it until uh
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		oh i don't know i think i was in college the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time i actually heard him say it
 		but uh i always knew it i mean he always he always did things so that i knew it
 		but i think i i mean granted it's easy to say i don't have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> but uh i i i think that's one of the things i really want to make sure that i do a lot is is say it
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		as many times as as just so that they get oh you know come on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> stop that but you know i mean you know i don't know
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah actually i've heard a lot of that from uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> who you know goes through periods were he's particularly
 		attached to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> and when i say i love you you know he says i hate you
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and things like that not just kidding around not really meaning it but you know not as comfortable with uh an overt display of affection from me anyway
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		um what kind of stuff do you do with them
 	
 	
 		uh try to uh plan outings to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> say take them to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">playgrounds</ENAMEX> you know <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> in the back yard that kind of thing a lot of times following his lead he's currently obsessed with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legos</ENAMEX> i mean he he
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	