
 
     		
 	
 		well <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doug</ENAMEX> what are they doing in your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX> about recycling
 	
 	
 		
 
 		okay
 		well some stuff
 		i go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Penn State</ENAMEX> up here and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> recycles quite a bit actually they collect curbside
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		gone <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> that the garbage goes
 		and they recycle um tin and aluminum cans and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glass</ENAMEX> and newspaper basically
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		so the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have to separate it out is that
 	
 	
 		um
 		no actually the um garbage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX> does that you just put a
 		you know plastic plastic recycling bin out on the curb <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every week</TIMEX> and now except for having the paper bundled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't really separate at all
 	
 	
 		oh
 		yeah
 		how about at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Penn State</ENAMEX> do they recycle things like uh computer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> and that sort of thing
 	
 	
 		um yeah they do although there's just recently been a problem with them
 		uh like saying that they weren't able to afford recycling everything anymore
 		so that they um they stopped recycling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campus</ENAMEX> for instance
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		they stopped recycling <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glass</ENAMEX> so they're only doing cans and white paper now
 		which i think is kind of insane
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		because it's really not that expensive
 	
 	
 		well what i've uh learned about recycling is that it's almost impractical to recycle newspapers
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		which is sad
 		and and as a matter of fact i'm <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of a civic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> where we had someone from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> come talk to us about recycling and the whole key to recycling is demand
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the supply is there <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are willing to do it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but for example until they figure out how they can strip the inks off of  used <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> effectively cost effectively
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		then it's not gonna happen
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and and there are whole huge <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">warehouses</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> full of used newspapers
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and i think they actually are building some sort of a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> where they can strip the ink off
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		i see
 	
 	
 		i know at work we recycle white paper and cans like you said
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plano</ENAMEX> is actually doing quite a bit they recently started picking up um
 		glass <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">aluminum</ENAMEX> and and they will take <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> too
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		and it apparently doesn't have to be sorted they haven't quite reached my neighborhood yet but they're doing all sorts of smart things uh
 	
 	
 		i see
 		
 
 	
 	
 		they no longer allow grass clippings to be bagged up in plastic bags and put out by the trash
 	
 	
 		um yeah that's definitely good
 	
 	
 		yes if you want to bag you know if you if if you don't want the clippings left on your lawn you can bag them in biodegradable bags which means paper
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		which you can buy from the city
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and and they're great until it <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rains</ENAMEX> and then they start biodegrading
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but they are uh contracting with someone to turn all these clippings into mulch
 	
 	
 		oh  that's great
 	
 	
 		and i don't know whether i don't know whether it'll be available to the to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> or whether it will just be used in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX> and recreation <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> or something i i don't know i guess it really doesn't matter
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		but
 		it's uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> since they won't take any yard waste it's that's in plastic bags it's a little bit annoying when you're you know pulling up your vegetable garden at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the season</TIMEX> and that sort of thing
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and you don't have any of the their special paper bags on hand because you haven't bagged your clippings at all you just let them recycle themselves
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i she see
 	
 	
 		
 
 		but uh i don't i this for a rather small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> well <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundred thousand</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> or so i guess this pretty progressive community
 	
 	
 		um-hum uh is it happening much in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX> like it in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 		i don't know about statewide i think i think in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> area there are few other uh suburbs <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plano</ENAMEX>'s a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">suburb</ENAMEX> that uh are doing things about recycling
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but it in order for it to be cost effective you have to have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> for it you have to have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> say i won't have i won't buy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> unless it's recycled
 	
 	
 		right
 		right right because
 	
 	
 		i mean
 	
 	
 		right the plan of the state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> originally was that the recycling would pay for itself and all that and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s garbage rates would actually go down and of course if hasn't happened that way
 		
 		
 	