
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		hi what kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pets</ENAMEX> do you have
 	
 	
 		yes
 		well let's see i've got a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a</NUMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Great</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dane</ENAMEX> actually use to raise <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Great Dane</ENAMEX> when i was in college uh in graduate school
 	
 	
 		that interesting
 	
 	
 		and uh sold them sold them for a pretty handsome profit <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about four hundred dollars</NUMEX> a piece
 		and uh help me pay my uh pay for my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh i've got to uh <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Scottish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Fold cat</ENAMEX>
 		cats which are uh pretty unusual cats
 	
 	
 		are they short hair or
 	
 	
 		there median hair uh their like their hair length is like a tubby but uh and actually they're closer related to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> tubby
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		okay
 	
 	
 		but they have uh they call them folds because they have this genetic anomaly that make their ears fold over and so they look like they're they're snarling all the time
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and uh which is it's a pretty it's a pretty cute look you know on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat uh</ENAMEX> that after after they you know when their little especially but uh you know now ours now ours is getting a little bigger bigger <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">almost a year</TIMEX> old
 	
 	
 		so their their full grown <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX> at this point their almost
 	
 	
 		yeah just the yeah just to basis and uh their extremely docile i mean their the most
 		their their so calm actually one of them um it so calm we actually thought it had some brain damage or something you know because it just
 		pretty much sleep like a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> all the time you know we did know we what was going on thought it should be you know running around you know scratching up furniture something but uh
 	
 	
 		um
 		does it seems to be okay though
 	
 	
 		yeah the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> said it was fine and uh
 		you know
 	
 	
 		does the
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah it was just it was good i mean the actually since i've got a i've got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> so they uh you know spend all there time playing with these things so i'm kind of glad that it's not a very active cat
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		it's more of a uh you know it can take a lot of punishment and doesn't seem to get to excited about it so
 	
 	
 		you also have less breakage
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		fewer thing get broken around the house
 	
 	
 		yeah now do do you have <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> to
 	
 	
 		yeah um their's a couple of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX> one of them is name <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Jimmy</ENAMEX>
 		and he's he's uh mostly black but he has some orange and white
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh he's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about three three and a half year old</TIMEX> now
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		he's sitting here looking at me
 		and um the other one is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tiffany Tiffany</ENAMEX> is actually a male
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but
 		at the time that we got <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tiffany we</ENAMEX> name him before we realize what his sex was
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because he you really can't see to well what his you know
 	
 	
 		pretty  yep
 	
 	
 		i mean it wasn't like very obvious and so we name him <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tiffany</ENAMEX> because he seems like a pretty prissy little <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> and we thought it was a she
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and uh anyway so <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tiffany's</ENAMEX> name stuck even though his sex change
 	
 	
 		look at look at <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Johnny Cash song  yeah</ENAMEX> that's
 	
 	
 		yes
 		and uh then there's a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> name <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Taylor</ENAMEX> he's uh uh Doberman
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and he's about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten months old</TIMEX> now <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tiffany</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Taylor</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Taylor</ENAMEX> are about are about the same age
 	
 	
 		yeah we had a we had a red uh doberman uh a long time ago
 		and we call we we named it uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mistral</ENAMEX> as in as in the music you know like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wondering Mistral</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		but uh and not real realize because we were you know  we just didn't realized what it was going to sound like you know when we went out the back door
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		you know and scream you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mistral Mistral</ENAMEX>  wish i could have saw our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX> like what the hell going on over there
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and we didn't realized for the longest time why everybody thought it was so funny until we finally picked up on it but
 		anyway the
 		it really was a good dog i was amazed at the uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		the energy that doberman have i never realized it compared to <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Great Dane i mean Danes</ENAMEX> are like just really slow moving <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Taylor</ENAMEX> is pretty quick he's real springing uh he just kind of like
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		just bong up in the air
 	
 	
 		pounds along or something i don't know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		he he he really um it's interesting to which him walk he's he loves everything i mean he he really would love to get closer to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX> but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX> think he's way to big
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh you you know like oh my gosh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		what's this big thing doing putting it's paws right next to my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> here
 	
 	
 		it we had it when when we <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> got the uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Great</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dane</ENAMEX> was standing in the living room
 		and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX> you know literally were out the out the bag you know they just came out and their wondering around and one of them wonders in to the leg of the dog
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and it the the dog doesn't move you know and you can see the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat the cat</ENAMEX> kind of looks at it really think you know this must be a chair leg or something you know
 		and it kind of  if it looks up higher and higher until it looks up and then there this gigantic face you know right in front of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX> face
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 		
 
 	
 	
 		it really it really freaked out the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> face it's like
 	
 	
 		
 
 		boom oh my gosh what was that
 	
 	
 		exactly but that was that that was one of the funnier uh things that happen
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hey Sammy</ENAMEX> come over here and look at this thing
 	
 	
 		yeah  but uh their
 		
 		
 	