
 
     		
 	
 		going to talk about clothing and how we dress for work
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yes i must admit i'm pretty boring
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		i just wear some uh you know old dress pants and a button down shirt just about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every single day</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
  
 		well i'm sure that you select different colors everyday and your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shoes</ENAMEX> probably you you have you rotate your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shoes</ENAMEX> around
 	
 	
 		oh the shoes are just about the only thing that doesn't get rotated
 	
 	
 		okay
 		like brown with um if you wear black with brown pants
 	
 	
 		yeah well i just wear blue gray and black blue gray and
 	
 	
 		oh
 		okay you just
 	
 	
 		what else is there there's another color dark gray that's it
 	
 	
 		
  
 		they're gray okay so you don't have to worry about the shoes then
 	
 	
 		
  
 		i do once in a while i wear brown but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		what can you do right
 	
 	
 		well i mean
 		i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> look very nice i i think that they're much better off than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> are as far as their clothes go because i think um
 		i think
 		um uh and it's true that uh you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> are attracted by what they see and of course the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> always um
 		either she's pleasing her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boyfriend</ENAMEX> or she's pleasing her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mate</ENAMEX> or she is looking for a a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>
 		and she of course
 		in the work field if she's single she dresses
 		you know
 		i don't dress for um i dress for myself i always like to look nice i want to look uh professional and so i i make an a big effort to do that
 	
 	
 		okay you
 		that that
 		that that agrees with what most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> tell me is that they dress to please themselves and you know who cares what these other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> think
 		and you know they have their own idea of what looks good
 	
 	
 		uh-huh well and there's some that really are on target and then there's some that are kind of way out in left field
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i don't appreciate the real short dresses and uh
 		and then to sit sprawl legged i think that's very offensive and um
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i don't know how they feel about it but it surely doesn't
 		uh i think i think even the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> are offended by that too
 		if it's not you know if you're out in public and you're
 		you don't watch how you sit i think that's very um
 		inappropriate
 		for uh a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> to act like that
 	
 	
 		where what sort of a do you work in an office or
 	
 	
 		
  
 		yes i do
 		yes i do i work in an office
 	
 	
 		and is it pretty well integrated as far as are you know positions of power or you know where i work
 		just about every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> is a secretary
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		except for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		and uh
 	
 	
 		yeah it's pretty
 	
 	
 		there are no male <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretaries</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		there it's pretty much like that where i work i was very offended by one of the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ladies</ENAMEX> who is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> and plus she's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> by what she wore and it looked like she just had and she's
 		she's very lean you know it's a very lean <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> but she really offended me by her dress i mean it was like she forgot to dress
 		it was like she was wearing uh um
 		
 
 		golly how do i want to phrase that it looked
 	
 	
 		like sweat suits or something
 	
 	
 		yes a wet suit you know
 		i thought that is not the appropriate attire for an office environment
 	
 	
 		you think it was distracting
 	
 	
 		i yeah because everybody was turning their heads sure enough  everybody you know everybody you know you just take a double look and they'll say is that really what she's wearing yeah that's really what she's wearing
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 		okay well okay so so she wasn't just floppy and like put on some loose floppy stuff you know cotton  uh weave thing not knit something
 	
 	
 		
  
 		oh oh no no no she yeah
 		
  
 		something that you'd wear doing doing the garden maybe uh no it was
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		
  
 		i thought what is this now
 	
 	
 		definitely designed to catch the eye
 	
 	
 		yes it was it was definitely designed if you could see almost every fold of her body
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so
 		i thought that was very offensive and i i made a loud remark about it
 		in fact i complained to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supervisor</ENAMEX> about it
 		and he agreed
 		and she has never worn it since
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hey</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i think you have to take some action like that maybe she
 		didn't realize
 		you know
 		how she came across
 		some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are oblivious as to what kind of reactions they can cause
 	
 	
 		yeah well
 		right or perhaps
 		
 		
 	