
 
     		
 	
 		so tell me where do you get most of your uh news information from
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well i i subscribe to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> different <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gwinnete Daily News and the Journal</ENAMEX> so <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning and afternoon</TIMEX> and
 		i guess that's where i get most of it and then i always whenever i'm in the car i'm listening to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WGST</ENAMEX> or WSB and uh read the news uh reports on the computer networks and uh
 		uh i'm kind of addicted to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Headline News and C-SPAN</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> so i get it from everywhere i guess but most of the details from the newspapers
 	
 	
 		yeah sounds like it
 		yeah a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> uh don't get any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> and you're getting <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> that's uh definitely kind of shows your interest in it
 	
 	
 		yeah  um
 	
 	
 		so do you do that for uh because um <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journal paper</ENAMEX> is got more of uh a liberal or type bias
 	
 	
 		oh pretty much uh yeah i you know it in terms of the choice between the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> i'd take the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> because it carries <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more</NUMEX> of the conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnists</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> and also
 		didn't want to take two morning papers and since since i live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gwinnete County</ENAMEX> i want to take the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily News</ENAMEX> to get their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gwinnete</ENAMEX> coverage and it doesn't make sense to take <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		taking the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journal</ENAMEX> in the afternoon means you're get some of the some of the news up until their deadline which is about <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven or eleven</NUMEX> AM or <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX> uh which you wouldn't get uh until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next day</TIMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Constitution</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 		so the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Gwinnete</ENAMEX> paper that's owned by uh is it <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> okay
 	
 	
 		and uh so
 		
 
 		it's kind of strange they they're they're they're generally uh fairly conservative but some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> they they publish are from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">syndicate</ENAMEX> and from other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> owned by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so it's
 		uh they tend to be really
 		uh really liberal
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and i i i actually think probably uncharacteristic for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gwinnete County</ENAMEX> but it it's still interesting to hear or to to read uh you know different perspective on issues
 	
 	
 		um-hum so this something that you do uh just for your own personal interest it doesn't have anything to do with your job you're not in a job where you need to keep up on these current events
 	
 	
 		well i do keep up on current events in the high tech industry particularly data communications for my job but uh main reason i keep i keep up on current events is because of my interest in politics
 	
 	
 		okay
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i'm you know active in politics and uh uh
 	
 	
 		oh really
 		you going to run for elected office
 	
 	
 		well i ran for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Representative</ENAMEX> in the election in nineteen <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ninety</NUMEX> and running for probably going to run for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Labor Commission</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		kind of ambitious but
 	
 	
 		yeah that's good how did you do in you your first uh run election
 	
 	
 		well i um i i was i run as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Libertarian</ENAMEX> and uh it was a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> way race i got <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">eight percent</NUMEX> of the vote which is not bad for a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> in a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> way race
 	
 	
 		um
 		yeah for a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> right
 		yeah and you probably uh you know more and more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are probably leaning toward that <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> now the way things are going
 	
 	
 		well i hope so the way  that's becoming pretty clear that the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> aren't doing that great of a job
 	
 	
 		huh
 		right hum
 	
 	
 		so where do you get your news
 	
 	
 		uh i guess newspapers uh i get i subscribe to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX>  um the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		publication uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journal publication</ENAMEX> for uh i guess that would be more of keeping up in terms of the work that i do
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 		magazines <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US News and World Report Time magazine</ENAMEX> uh a lot of
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah i subscribe to several <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> too
 	
 	
 		uh-huh yeah and you know things like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sports Illustrated</ENAMEX> uh computer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> uh uh i don't know if you read the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Review</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		i subscribed to it at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time um but there was a period uh
 		where i really felt that i was reading too much now now now i've got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a fifth</NUMEX> on the way now and it's hard to find time to read as much as i did
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh wow
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so i've cut my <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">monthly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> back to just uh oh i guess <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three or four</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		things like uh uh Reason which a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't even they don't even know what it is it's a it's a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Libertarian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> but it's uh has a lot to do with uh free markets and privatization and things of that nature
 	
 	
 		i i don't know what that is no
 		um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Freeman</ENAMEX> which is another uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Libertarian</ENAMEX> uh more of a philosophical uh type <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journal</ENAMEX> rather than a uh news sort of thing
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh oh a couple of others but uh i don't tend to subscribe to the the major news <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> or things like that
 	
 	
 		um-hum so uh what you're in the you're an engineer
 	
 	
 		yeah i work for uh uh
 		
 		
 	