
 
     		
 	
 		what are your views Mister
 	
 	
 		
 
 		uh  i think <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Vietnam war</ENAMEX>
 		was justified
 		but it was carried out badly
 		unfortunately <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX> got a hold of it
 		and it was a military victory but it was uh
 		i'd say uh a political defeat
 		what what what do you think about of world i mean the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Vietnam War</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well i'm just not really still not really sure why the war started
 		uh there was a conflict with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Vietnamese</ENAMEX> had conflict with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> i  i know that and they've been in a war like state for seems like most of
 		the time that their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> been prospering so they're just award tarnation
 	
 	
 		no uh from what i remember was uh
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">French</ENAMEX>
 		had a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">colony</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then after the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">war World War II</ENAMEX>
 		uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> wanted to become independent of of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">France</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so they started an up rising and that was the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">French</ENAMEX>
 		and oh <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> War
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and and uh basically
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Vietnamese Vietnamese</ENAMEX> where beating the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> so we took over because we had our containment policy
 		and uh the north side of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>
 		went to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> for military aid
 		and so  we didn't want
 		so we didn't want  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>  become communist
 		so that's why we started supporting the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">South Vietnamese Vietnamese</ENAMEX> that's how the war started
 	
 	
 		does <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX> come into the equation all of that is there oil in that area see <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX> is a a motivating factor for most of the
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		altercations that go on in the world
 	
 	
 		but it's not necessarily oil i i i know you are talking about like uh natural resources but i don't think they had that much of a natural
 	
 	
 		exactly
 	
 	
 		to much natural resource it's just like i said our we had a containment policy and if we didn't help the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">South Vietnamese</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">North Vietnamese</ENAMEX> would have definitely won and then our views in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">those days</TIMEX> they would have become communist or pinko
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so we didn't want that so we got into the war
 	
 	
 		what about what do you think about strategic location just as
 		if you think about it
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> has <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX> which is an island outside the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> has <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> that's right out side of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX> it it does <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> have a any strategic location
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		uh
 		actually i i i really haven't considered that much
 		<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about</NUMEX> a strategic location
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		hum uh
 		other than it being another <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> falling to the
 		to pinkos or the communist
 		no not to much real strategic
 		location
 		it's just
 		uh for for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> to continue it has to expand if it doesn't expand it'll collapse
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so by doing our containment policy
 		we're defeating
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russia</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i don't know if uh if that containment policy was was right or the best
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but
 		that was our our little view then
 	
 	
 		i sort of believe that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> because of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Vietnam war</ENAMEX> and the
 		the way that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> exited from it that that has brought on other scrimmages and i i thinks that that's
 		some what related
 		to the
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gulf War</ENAMEX> because
 		it makes the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> keep safe face
 	
 	
 		uh
 		i i i agree partial with you the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Vietnam War</ENAMEX> made us loose
 		loose faith uh politically
 		and and that and and to the fact that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> public
 		can't stomach war or high causality
 		so we aren't really steadfast in that regard but military we unquestionably you know unquestionably quick ass in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 		it might have had
 		probably did have some repercussions repercussions towards now you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> do
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enemy</ENAMEX> does know if the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> takes high causality it will leave
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		just like in uh
 		uh that uh a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> bombing or <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">three hundred marines</NUMEX> were killed and we just got the hell out
 	
 	
 		from
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		um-hum is this is this something in your
 		in your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX> in your military training that that uh suggests that that is  a um procedure of the
 		of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> way of war
 	
 	
 		uh what what is uh low causality or high causalities
 	
 	
 		right is there you know like there
 		
 		
 	