
 
     		
 	
 		okay um we're talking about uh trial by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> and whether or not we thought it was a a fair way to do it do you think that they ought to have the uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> do the sentencing to try to make it more uniform or more fair or or what do you think
 	
 	
 		uh
 		well um
 		i think that uh when you're tried by a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> of your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peers</ENAMEX> they probably uh the collective
 		mind of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> is probably a better vehicle for sentencing than the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> himself uh because then there's the consensus thing rather than a uh a single person
 	
 	
 		well there there is an argument in that uh a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> has seen a lot more cases and you know perhaps he sees one crime
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and and he can compare that crime to you know his long history of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">of</NUMEX> of dealing with with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the the jury you know this is you know maybe they've sat on sat on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> once before maybe this is their very first time the only they've really seen is like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gaudy</ENAMEX> on TV or something like that you know and and they just you know they just kind of
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know making guesses how bad they think it is
 	
 	
 		yeah well i would i could i would argue back that uh
 		a a single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> being able to pass a sentence on someone um leaves it open to his or her own uh biases and they may consider
 		arson to be a heinous crime and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> molestation to be less severe so the sentence wouldn't be all that uniformed i mean obviously it would be uniform within the parameters of that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> himself him or herself
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah as as uniformed as i mean he would he would
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		figure out the severity based upon his own personal scale the only thing i worry about is like one
 		um <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">murderer</ENAMEX> or or let's say <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thief</ENAMEX>
 		um getting like
 		a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">tenth</NUMEX> of the penalty of of another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thief</ENAMEX> simply because perhaps he impressed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> more or or you know just because because his presentation was better
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah that's a that's one of the biggest uh biggest problems i think in our society is that uh the the justice system
 		uh basically goes by who's got enough money for the best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> and uh the presentation is is everything um so you know you you could have a real dirt ball
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		be portrayed by his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> as a loving family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> and and uh color the color the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX>'s opinions but um i don't know
 	
 	
 		exactly
 		see i would almost argue i would consider i i i don't understand i don't know i haven't thought it out long enough to figure out all the ramifications but getting rid of the entire trial by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> and and having the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> decide guilty or not guilty
 	
 	
 		well we could do that or we could explode it to it's logical extreme or it's or
 		ridiculous extreme and
 		take uh the new interactive television uh
 		technology that's coming forward and uh have everybody in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> or everyone who chose to tune in
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		decide guilt or innocence and then uh have a sliding scale of you know the fifty <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">nine percent</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> said you were guilty that means you get the life in prison you know um
 	
 	
 		oh  oh man
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wheel of Justice</ENAMEX> we could have a game show you know we no there there it it does need reform uh i would worry about a single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> uh
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		passing sentence uh especially in in a more involved trial uh
 		i i don't know i think that the founding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fathers</ENAMEX> had a great idea and the reason the reason that we went away from the single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> or the the the triad i guess of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> that they have uh in some systems it just um
 		you know they become instruments of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		yeah but i think the the we the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that that our founding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fathers</ENAMEX> were talking about were rich white males
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i mean i don't think
 		i i don't think they had a real high opinion of of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masses</ENAMEX> i mean <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hamilton</ENAMEX> was was a prime case you know he he didn't i think he referred to them as the mindless masses he didn't want them to vote he didn't want them to have any say in government
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh yeah that's why they uh made <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">election days</TIMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX> you know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> was a work day and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX> was a real pain to travel in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX> back in what <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seventeen eighty three</NUMEX> um
 	
 	
 		right
 		you know that never occurred to me
 	
 	
 		so i you know they sort of arranged it so that and you know and the electoral <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> is all rigged anyway i mean in theory they have to vote for  whoever the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">delegates</ENAMEX> choose but  it's you know it they don't have to um
 	
 	
 		
  
 		well i mean <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> sense it seems like a needless step but i think there's only been <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who haven't voted as he was voted into or there's only i think only been <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> electoral vote that was not not voted at in the electoral college
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		as the propular as the popular vote was voted
 	
 	
 		um-hum well we're straying from our topic of jury
 	
 	
 		so
 		
 		
 	