
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah well i i can tell you here's an interesting interesting story uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> uh when we first had our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> decided to home school our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> it would is isn't that against well in in is that is is that within the law in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and
 		yeah it's it's interestingly uh there're a couple of different categories categories of home school uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 		uh a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> take religious exemptions
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and those are the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you probably read about all the time in the news you know somebody's somebody's trying to you know get rid of evolution or something and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and you know so they don't want their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> to go to school to find out that you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> really comes out of the cabbage patch
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but uh  but in our case uh we actually did it uh we took uh educational you know whatever
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> because we both had advanced degrees and so we just said uh hey look you know we have enough education to to school our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 		and the idea was when we first started was to just do elementary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> uh level instead of the public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and do that at at home uh <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">eight six uh eight seven and four</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		how old are your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 		okay
 	
 	
 		uh so pretty young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and so anyway my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> did all of this all of this schooling
 		and uh you know she had curricula that she bought that they actually sell which we never knew of um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know it was really complete i mean uh it matched up pretty well with with uh actually matched i thought was better than a lot of the public school curricula but
 		anyway you know you could if you were really religious of course you could get all uh sort of a religious stuff with all the the creation and stuff slant on it
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but uh there's actually a lot of uh to us anyway there's a lot of other good stuff out there too
 		so we got a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> actually bought a couple of these programs and for grades you know one through <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">six</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		so like prefab school
 	
 	
 		yeah exactly exactly
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh so you know went through it
 		and uh anyway my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> got to the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> grade point with my with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four year</TIMEX> old
 	
 	
 		and the oldest <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight year</TIMEX> old
 	
 	
 		oh uh-huh
 	
 	
 		got to the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> grade point
 		and it was just too much i mean it was just the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> were just
 		you know they needed they just needed other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> to be learning with you know and uh also it was a tremendous amount of work
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 		sure i i imagine it it it it it really was because see you had to do run <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least three curricula three</NUMEX> separate curricula in parallel and uh-huh
 	
 	
 		right
 		exactly
 		now it was easier it was actually easier as the younger ones got older because she could just you know kind of take what she had before just the same the same thing that public school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> do now i mean the
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but it it was
 	
 	
 		how how long did you do this for
 	
 	
 		uh she did it for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX> okay
 	
 	
 		and and actually the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> did really you know uh if you if you believe the tests that uh the state hands out here you know they're supposed to test your uh your
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh so so <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> had to do like some kind of a test to be sure that okay
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right they took a standardized test and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they they always did really well uh and they never seemed to have any problem with it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i can see in a lot of cases like it it we didn't in a case where you've got <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> at home where they don't for for you know almost the you know political reasons or whatever they don't want their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> to go to school
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i mean that testing can be really bogus you know because we knew <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in uh the home schoolers <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX> there that just they were just blatant <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cheaters</ENAMEX> and i mean if their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> didn't do well yeah i mean they just filled it out themselves it was absurd you know
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh you mean you didn't have to take them to like a central location and
 	
 	
 		oh no no they sent them to you
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh they sent them to oh boy yeah um-hum
 	
 	
 		yeah so you know for us we actually sat our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> down and timed them and everything you know just make it seem like like the real pressure you'd be under
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh you know we heard stories we heard all kinds of stories of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you know it's like well if my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> doesn't do well on it i'll just write in the answers you know uh
 	
 	
 		why why why did you decide i mean did did you decide like to to do that home schooling because you didn't think the your local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> were were good enough  or
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yes we did that yes that was the reason but we did that out of total ignorance
 		because we never went to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> to find out what they really were doing
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh oh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it was just sort of it was just sort of uh you know hey we remember what public school was like and it was really crappy my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> actually was she's from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bronx</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> so you know
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		she knew that public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> could be pretty bad
 	
 	
 		yeah did um well what did you think about like you you know you obviously paying taxes for for the for for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> did i mean did
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		yeah
 		oh actually we didn't really begrudge that you know because i mean it's like you know  me i mean it's good it's good that uh
 		to you know my opinion is that they should there should be a public school
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		they they shouldn't make everybody go to it i mean you should be able to go to other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> or if you know if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have the credentials to home school well leave them alone but but uh you know as far as the taxes go i mean i don't yeah yeah big deal nah
 	
 	
 		uh
 		you didn't worry about it what uh eventually you put your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> back in back in to public school how did that
 	
 	
 		right
 		
 		
 	