
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		so
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		what
 	
 	
 		
 
 		uh how do you feel about capital punishment
 	
 	
 		uh tough question i mean it it's
 		i was actually kind of thinking about it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX> someone was talking about it how uh a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who takes someone else's life he was saying should should not deserve the right to have to keep their own life
 		it's kind of it's it's it's <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a really</TIMEX> you know it's a moral dilemma i don't know um
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		i think that i i forget what the law is in my <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> i mean my home <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> i'm from i'm from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah i have no idea what the law is anywhere i've ever lived i just
 	
 	
 		and i just
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i don't know so
 		i i personally uh even though
 		i understand the principle behind capital punishment i don't agree with it ever applying applying capital punishment to anyone
 		um because i sort of believe that if we've got a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> arrested that sure we can uh we can say you know it's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">murderer</ENAMEX> he's done heinous crimes
 		but we can keep him in jail for the rest of his life and not give him a terribly pleasant existence
 		and uh there's just no reason to justify killing a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> and you know there may be an economic reason but i don't think that's sufficient to justify uh killing someone
 		if you believe that killing is wrong you you might as well apply that to you know even that stays stays true even if you're punishing someone i know that's how i feel
 	
 	
 		yeah i mean it kind of seems going back to uh eye for an eye hand for a hand kind of thing
 		maybe
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i don't know it's like uh
 		you kind of wonder do you want someone like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeffrey Dahmer</ENAMEX> alive or not
 		oh or or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Manson</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well
 		it's just that i feel like they don't really pose a threat if they're imprisoned you know sufficiently and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know i i i guess it would be bad if the politics ever changes and they got out for some reason but
 	
 	
 		i don't see it happening
 	
 	
 		uh
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		like i don't see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Manson</ENAMEX> i think he'll never get out he's
 		he's probably going to be up for parole in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year or so</TIMEX> but he's not going to it's not going to happen
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		but the thing is you know when these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> get out it can be so quiet you may not notice i mean if the public doesn't hear about it
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		for some reason i mean the thing is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Manson</ENAMEX> was really publicly well know but
 		if it's somebody who's you know a serial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">killer</ENAMEX> but he never was really in the media a lot then when he gets out he still won't be in the media
 	
 	
 		this could be
 	
 	
 		yeah so i you know
 		uh it could be bad if somebody got out i guess
 	
 	
 		yeah i i still i think even if they aren't in the media i don't know if it would happen unless maybe it was
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">uh</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bureaucracy</ENAMEX> that got pushed aside
 		and someone said ah we'll let them out
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i don't know someone i don't know i mean i guess there's are probably are small time serial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">killers</ENAMEX> that you don't hear about
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		something um
 	
 	
 		well there have to be because
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh uh i don't know there's like
 		well i don't know the numbers but i mean there's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least dozens</NUMEX> of capital punishments every year
 		from what i that's what i think it is
 		and you know you don't hear about all of those
 	
 	
 		i don't know um because i think i don't think they actually execute <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX> very too often because there's i mean there's death row
 		there's a lot of time where uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX> are kept on death row for a long time i mean yeah there was uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Bundy</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		there was uh i mean there was such an outcry to um to execute him because it i mean he was the the crimes he did were just so heinous
 		um
 		now i i think that there's it's just such a controversial thing that it doesn't happen too often i'm not so i i don't at least at least i don't hear about it that often
 	
 	
 		right yeah i don't i don't know either
 		so
 	
 	
 		um
 		nah i don't think there's been an execution in my <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time</TIMEX> that i know of
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and i know that like
 		um
 		uh one of the one of the things that that's that's one of the things that the that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amnesty International</ENAMEX> is against in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> is capital punishment yeah
 	
 	
 		they're against capital punishment
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		of any of any kind so that's the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> the one thing they have against the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> one of their gripes
 	
 	
 		well
 		aren't do a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries countries</ENAMEX> not have capital punishment
 	
 	
 		uh
 		i don't know there might be some that don't
 	
 	
 		that'd be interesting to find out who doesn't
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		tough to uh
 		to um what's word i'm looking for uh to justify
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		i guess
 		i kind of waver i guess sometimes
 		it's like
 		someone like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeffrey Dahmer</ENAMEX> you kind of want
 		
 		
 	