
 
     		
 	
 		yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim</ENAMEX> uh so uh how many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> do you have and what are their ages
 	
 	
 		
 
 		uh we have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> they're going to be <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years old</TIMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and that's after uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty one years</TIMEX> of marriage  so so we we've had quite an experience over the last <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX> of readjusting our time in terms of spending with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> how about yourself Frank
 	
 	
 		oh is that right wow
 		i imagine
 		we have uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> but they're all grown and out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> now
 		but we still uh spend a a lot of time together really it's a it's a close family uh
 		we have one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> that's going to college uh in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> and uh we don't see uh you know an awful lot of her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every couple of weeks</TIMEX> uh we manage to get together maybe <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three weeks</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i've got uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> that lives uh <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about ten miles</NUMEX> north of us and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a couple</NUMEX> other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX> that live uh <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about an hour</TIMEX> away a piece they they live in the same basically in the same area <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about an hour</NUMEX> away from us
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i would say that every uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">couple of weeks</TIMEX> uh we're together with one of the you know one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> sometimes we have uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> get togethers probably every oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> of months
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so it's kind of a different situation are you do you have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> two boys <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> girls
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> girls yeah yeah and  my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and i are both from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saint Louis</ENAMEX> and we've been in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX> now for uh eleven years
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> girls uh-huh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so we've been away for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time</TIMEX> and when it was just the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of us we'd go back about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> but now that we have the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> we try to get back twice a year
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because we both grew up with uh family all around us and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekend</TIMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cousins</ENAMEX> and
 		uh both of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> have uh we have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">siblings</ENAMEX> that have lots of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we miss that environment but and i think partly because of that because our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a thousand miles</NUMEX> away
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we might even overcompensate
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we uh pretty much uh between between that <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">thousand mile</NUMEX> distance from uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> and the fact that we had uh uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eighteen years</TIMEX> together
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		married life uh before our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX> were born and uh we we pretty much it it seems like our whole life is devoted to the girls
 		i mean from  waking until
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh till <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> time we we literally have <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an hour and a half</TIMEX> to ourselves <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">every night</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		i i know what you
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		no uh does your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> work or not
 	
 	
 		no she stays at home uh and
 	
 	
 		okay that's good uh
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> uh one of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX> i should say that uh had been married for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nine years</TIMEX> just had a a uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> uh back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July last July</TIMEX>
 		and you know they were getting pretty set in their ways after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nine years</TIMEX> and uh it was quite a readjustment for them so i imagine after uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eighteen years</TIMEX> it really was a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a</NUMEX> a an adjustment in your lives
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		it wasn't it wasn't um uh partly because we had all that time together we're ready to focus on a family so and of uh course the changing economy you know helps focus on the the home life also
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um i mean our lifestyle changed drastically we went from two incomes and no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> so we had <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Caribbean</ENAMEX> vacations and new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> and expensive <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> down to
 	
 	
 		um
 		right
 	
 	
 		one income <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and uh the total uncertainty of the job market now so we we pretty much stay at home
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		focus we we do have our older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> in a preschool a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Montessori</ENAMEX> and that's quite expensive and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		in fact my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> just joined the uh was just elected <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> of the school
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so she's spending quite a bit of time in fact she's on the other line right now doing school <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> talk
 	
 	
 		oh is that right huh
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so it it seems like even our leisure time it's been focused more centered around the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		what do what do you find is the trend amongst <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> in your observation for how they spend their time together what activities they're doing and how they spend the time do you think they have more or less or what
 	
 	
 		uh
 		it seems to me uh that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> are spending more fractional time together
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that maybe one <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> will go off with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> and another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> will go off with the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um rather than</ENAMEX> and focusing more on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s activities rather than family activities and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		i think with so with so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> working both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> that it's difficult to find time for everybody to be together
 	
 	
 		yes and partly because of that working phenomena then the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> end up getting their lives scheduled with
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ballet</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football and soccer</ENAMEX> i mean we we live in an area that uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">soccer and football</ENAMEX> is just taking off phenomenally
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh we we have terrible problems with scheduling soccer <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">fields</ENAMEX> and finding enough land to even to build new football <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">fields</ENAMEX> that they need
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and part of that phenomena is the dual working household and i think
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		rather than spending the time in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the evening</TIMEX> with family activities
 		
 		
 	