
 
     		
 	
 		what kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> do you have
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well at the moment i got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> one voluntary and the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> involuntary i have a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ninety</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Taurus</ENAMEX> and a nineteen seventy <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> Dart which i've been trying to sell for over a year
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah how do you like your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh it's been fine it hasn't caused very much trouble it was a lot better than that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dart</ENAMEX> was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first year</TIMEX> and it lasted for eighteen um the
 	
 	
 		oh maybe that's a good sign
 	
 	
 		yeah maybe you never can tell i've uh uh you know it it got better as it got older really um it was quite reliable when it was less than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years old</TIMEX> it started to get a little bit less reliable once it passed its <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">tenth</NUMEX> birth date but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah i think they have that tendency i've got a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford Ranger</ENAMEX> that i drive and uh
 		i just had it uh oil oil change and lube done to it but before that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about two weeks ago</TIMEX> somebody busted out my window my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passenger</ENAMEX> window so i had to go get it replaced
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		somebody busted it out so they do that in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minneapolis</ENAMEX> too i just yesterday
 	
 	
 		well yeah i they uh i had a uniform my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">band</ENAMEX> uniform hanging in there and they stole that so that was kind of
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		kind of a bad thing but
 	
 	
 		well it's it's probably easy to catch you know if it's the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX> is distinctive
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		it's pretty distinctive i don't know what in the world they wanted with it i think it was just <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> you know neighborhood <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> or something
 	
 	
 		right so right here i have a list of my repairs oh i i do uh actually why didn't i bring this up i
 		i i write a newsletter at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas time</TIMEX> and i had an article on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> and i can just look at that if i can find it before our time expires um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah actually uh
 	
 	
 		but it had an analysis of the cost of my uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eighteen year old</TIMEX> car versus my newer car uh let's see there oops trying to yeah real time this is interesting looking up things in real time here um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		all right
 		well actually with regard to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX>
 		the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> has not been too bad to me
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i don't like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX>
 		at at all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> itself
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because i did have a few problems and they've been utterly non responsive
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		so whoever i meet i always tell that to them just to make sure everybody knows how i felt
 	
 	
 		i've gone through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dealership</ENAMEX> and it <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dealerships</ENAMEX> used to have a bad reputation for not wanting to do service on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> that they hadn't sold but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		the local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dealership</ENAMEX> here which which is not one that sold me the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> they've been very good in doing the repairs not that they got the fixed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first time</TIMEX> but
 	
 	
 		yeah that
 		that's great is is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Raleigh</ENAMEX> so big or or or or is it so busy that you can that that you can't get in very well or or how does that work there
 	
 	
 		but uh
 		
 
 		no i well i i call them and say which day you know i'd like to bring it in on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> that's usually <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the best day</TIMEX> and see if they're if it's okay and it usually is and
 	
 	
 		hm
 		that's good
 	
 	
 		you know i ask them what time and they tell me
 	
 	
 		see i i live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Orlando</ENAMEX> generally but i'm up here for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> and then i go back down to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Orlando</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i see uh-huh
 	
 	
 		and down there there are no appointments you go first come first serve which makes it really kind of difficult if you work
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but uh no down there i haven't had much luck except for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dealership</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gainesville Florida</ENAMEX> that's really very good
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		that's a long way from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Orlando</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		Gainesville
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		oh you mean <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minneapolis</ENAMEX>' a long way
 	
 	
 		no no no no Gainesville i know <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Orlando Orlando</ENAMEX> aren't they about <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an hour and a half</TIMEX> drive
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two two and a half a two and a half</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> and a half okay so if you live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Orlando</ENAMEX> and you go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gainesville</ENAMEX> for repairs you must be an
 	
 	
 		well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> lives in Gainesville
 	
 	
 		ah okay
 	
 	
 		so occasionally i go up there and and it it happened it so happened that my gear shift lever broke off at the stem when i was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gainesville</ENAMEX> so i i had to i had to drive it <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about fifteen miles an hour</NUMEX> all the way to
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dealership</ENAMEX> but kind of an interesting thing
 	
 	
 		ooh
 		yeah okay so i find that that my total auto expenses uh dropped from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty</TIMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">four hundred dollars</NUMEX> to eighteen <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">hundred dollars</NUMEX> when i when i went from my old <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> to my new car repairs went down from
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven hundred ten</NUMEX> dollars <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty eight to ninety nineteen ninety</NUMEX> average to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred ninety four</NUMEX> dollars in nineteen <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ninety one</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">wow</ENAMEX> and the first
 	
 	
 		uh that was uh that was from backing into a post it was well hidden in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> in a uh a gas <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX> uh
 	
 	
 		oh
 		the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> figure you gave me <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty four hundred</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		excuse me yeah <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty four hundred</TIMEX> was the expenses uh that was that that that included gasoline repairs maintenance fees and insurance and other expenses
 	
 	
 		i've got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> for you if you uh reverse the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> digits of that and make it forty <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two hundred</NUMEX> that's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">approximately</NUMEX> what i spent in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> on a seventy <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Volvo i</ENAMEX> had it was constantly giving me problems
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">wow</ENAMEX> and when you when you say you spent it do you mean does that include <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gasoline</ENAMEX> or is that just repair
 	
 	
 		no this is strictly uh structural and engine repairs things that had to be done
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		like new new transmission things like that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i was really upset because i was a an undergrad college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> at the time and not making a whole lot of money
 	
 	
 		right oh yeah
 	
 	
 		so uh it was
 		that was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> that i really i liked it a real love hate relationship with it i liked the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> because it felt good and it and it drive it drove well when i drove it but then again it had all these problems so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it uh was kind of a bitter sweet relationship i guess
 	
 	
 		i was uh kind of sorry i got rid of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> when i did well now i'm not because it's much
 		
 		
 	