
 
     		
 	
 		what kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> are you driving now
 	
 	
 		
 
 		no i'm well driving a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hyundai</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Sonata</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh-huh do you like that one
 	
 	
 		no we like it real well
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah we haven't had the only problem we've had is the valve cover gasket leaking other than that it's been working real good
 	
 	
 		how long have you had it
 	
 	
 		uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh-huh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> that was the main problem i've ever had with it is
 		i guess twice i've had to get the valve cover gasket replaced and once the gasket around the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">the um oil</ENAMEX> pan
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's uh nineteen <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cutlass Sierra</ENAMEX>
 		and it still drives pretty well though i had kind of low mileage on it
 	
 	
 		yeah well this um like i said we've had this for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> and it almost got <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">forty five thousand</NUMEX> on it
 	
 	
 		wow that's a lot of driving
 	
 	
 		yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> does a lot of driving  she she uses it a lot and then we have the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicle</ENAMEX> the
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nissan</ENAMEX> pickup
 	
 	
 		uh-huh i think that um i might've done better to get a pickup for the use that i've put <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX> to
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but um i didn't get it i didn't get that i got a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and that's
 		there have been times when i was glad to have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> but most of the stuff i've done has been hauling around and i've been better off to have a pickup
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well our next <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicle</ENAMEX> is going to be a a full size truck well we're kind of getting little
 	
 	
 		a full size pickup
 	
 	
 		yeah uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nissan</ENAMEX> is just a a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mini truck</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it's not real big for a family so
 	
 	
 		right what do you think you'll get a um step side or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a</NUMEX> a smooth split side
 	
 	
 		i'll probably get a fleet side
 	
 	
 		yeah my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daddy</ENAMEX> use used to always get a step side and because he has <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cows</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cows</ENAMEX> he can
 		with a step side you can haul <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cows</ENAMEX> in the back because there aren't those humps for the tires
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but
 		this last time he decided to still get a step side even though he couldn't find a step side in the long full length they only had them in the short length
 	
 	
 		yeah that's that's all they make them in now i think
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so he was disappointed in that but he still went with the step side because he thought it was easier to get in and around it and take things off the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> and so on without always having to come out the back
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but he uses it on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farm</ENAMEX> and he built himself a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cow</ENAMEX> trailer so it he didn't need the length so much anymore
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah yeah like i say like i'm we're kind of moving out in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mini truck</ENAMEX> and into the full size will be the next one so
 	
 	
 		do you just use it for your own purposes and hauling your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> around
 	
 	
 		oh yeah plus you know i help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> move here and there and stuff and we kind of
 		getting to the point where it's it's we're going to do a lot of camping and stuff during the summertime and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mini truck</ENAMEX> just doesn't  work very well so
 	
 	
 		right do you have if you're going to go camping are you going to have to drive you car to take your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> camping plus drive the truck
 	
 	
 		oh no no um
 		the
 		what we'd probably do right now is just use the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and try to put everything in it that we can
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and then later on we're going to try to get a uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">camper</ENAMEX> trailer
 		once we buy a new truck
 	
 	
 		well even though i could've probably used a truck better the last time around i probably will still get a car the next time around figuring that'll be more useful in the future
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so
 		i don't know i'll probably look for something that has a
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealer</ENAMEX> everywhere i would like to drive
 	
 	
 		oh yeah i can understand that
 	
 	
 		that'll be the main criterion
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i guess the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">makes</ENAMEX> though do are starting to have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealers</ENAMEX> all over though i don't know about how the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hyundai</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dealer network</ENAMEX> is
 	
 	
 		well its pretty good uh we had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and then he closed and now we got another one here right near us so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's it's all right uh like i said the only problem we really had with our <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> just a valve cover gasket leaking and since they fixed it under warranty it was we haven't had any problem with it
 	
 	
 		that's true that's a good point i remember
 		a long time ago my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> got a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler</ENAMEX> but the nearest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler Chrysler</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealer</ENAMEX> to them was <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">over fifty miles</NUMEX> away
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and it weren't all that good of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> they had pretty many trouble with it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		pretty much trouble so whenever it would break down and take it back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealer</ENAMEX> they'd have to
 		to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurse</ENAMEX> it along
 		
 		
 	