
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so uh what do you wear to work
 	
 	
 		uh well uh traditionally i wear a pair of blue jeans and a dress shirt
 	
 	
 		all right
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh and</ENAMEX> and uh uh leather shoes it's pretty casual
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well that's good where do you work
 	
 	
 		uh at the for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy</ENAMEX> i work in uh research right right
 	
 	
 		NTSC
 		huh i used to work in that building right right before i worked at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Honeywell</ENAMEX> i worked at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ARI</ENAMEX> which is on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PM</ENAMEX> trade side
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right right
 	
 	
 		all right imagine that
 		
 
 		there's all kinds of uh coincidences here um yeah that's that's a pretty good environment actually when i worked for ARI they made me wear uh well they didn't make make wear anything but they prefer that i wore something almost tieish
 	
 	
 		yeah real close there
 		yes it's uh it depends upon the interaction you have with the outside world and i have several suits that if i'm going to interact with the outside world or with upper management that i will dress accordingly
 	
 	
 		right
 		right okay
 	
 	
 		but for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX> to day work uh it's pretty casual
 	
 	
 		all right what kind of research do you do <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kyle</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> flight simulation
 	
 	
 		get out are you kidding me
 	
 	
 		nope yeah that's what i do
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i'm uh i'm working with flight controls and displays up here at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Honeywell</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		um in fact my dissertation will involve uh auditory warnings
 	
 	
 		well that's interesting
 	
 	
 		eye cast things like that so uh yeah it's amazing
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um no up here at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Honeywell</ENAMEX> we generally it's real real laid back in terms of dress uh most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have never seen a tie i don't think unless they're meeting with a with a customer
 	
 	
 		right i should've remembered that the last time i was up there
 	
 	
 		yeah and oh you were up at oh that's right you said you'd spend some time up here at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Honeywell</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah i went up there it's been <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about three four years</TIMEX> now
 	
 	
 		do you remember which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> or which branch you were at
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		probably not huh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">uh Minneapolis</ENAMEX> whoever makes the
 	
 	
 		okay yeah i'm not real sure about that i've only been up here a little while so i'm still kind of getting the hang of it but actually i'll be back down in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX> to finish my degree so uh that'll be good
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		do you have much connection with the human factors <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> down there
 	
 	
 		uh in fact yes i do uh as soon as i get out of some work i'm doing right now i'll be talking to them uh uh and getting some low cost uh uh equipment together to do some uh human factor studies
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		all right great well i'll probably be using some of it i hope when i get back give me a good vehicle to do my dissertation on maybe but uh yeah actually that it's  and all those people
 	
 	
 		
 
 		right i'll be working with uh uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carolyn Carolyn Prince</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh okay right great but uh no aside from that i don't think i've worn a tie more than about once here and that's uh
 	
 	
 		well it's pretty casual here
 	
 	
 		yes they kind of had to twist my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX> to do that because i wasn't meeting with a customer but you know how that works
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh
 	
 	
 		oh the jeans are new i mean it's not like they're they're bleached out or
 	
 	
 		well yeah  it sounds like you got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all</NUMEX> holes over the place now the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> that
 	
 	
 		no no no
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> that i'm working with here the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> that i work directly with uh in my office he usually comes in in real ripped jeans he's pretty uh real casual in fact almost too casual
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i'm not quite that bad
 	
 	
 		plus uh
 		yeah i was kind of surprised to see that actually
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		so uh where else did you work before that
 	
 	
 		i've been i've been working here for the center for uh uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nine years</TIMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> plus <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> now
 	
 	
 		yeah all right you like it
 	
 	
 		yeah it has it's it's it's you know it had it's had its good times and bad times but for the most part yeah i think it's pretty good
 	
 	
 		yeah i i liked it too it it's kind of weird that that environment is is different than a lot of other environments just because you're in in a little maze of cubicles you know and it's kind of it's just
 	
 	
 		yeah it's kind of like being in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX> trap
 	
 	
 		yeah it is in a way and
 	
 	
 		and i keep on wondering where the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cheese</ENAMEX> is
 	
 	
 		
 
 		presumably that's supposed to be the paycheck right but who's to say
 	
 	
 		well that's awfully small <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cheese</ENAMEX> if you ask me then
 	
 	
 		yeah no kidding but uh now that the whole idea of them pumping white noise over the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speakers</ENAMEX> to mask out the telephones and things like that it's kind of interesting
 	
 	
 		yeah there was a lot of uh thought put into that because i i i because when i go to other new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> whether it be uh uh uh uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald Douglas</ENAMEX> some of the other new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> i've been to there's
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and little things that they point out to me when i was walking around well this was done because of this or this was done because of that
 	
 	
 		so they're actually kind of thinking it through huh
 	
 	
 		yeah oh well the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX> tries to throw it in but uh sometimes i wonder when they put back the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that's supposed to be monitoring the building
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh how much reins they got
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but they give them an award
 	
 	
 		well that's i guess that's the important part for them but uh
 		so what do you uh do you think you're going to stick around there for a while or do think
 	
 	
 		uh yeah yeah there's there's uh prospect job <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prospects</ENAMEX> with another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that i should know uh more we've been talking back and forth for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a year and a half</TIMEX> now
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah i've actually i'm actually kind of looking for work when i get back
 		
 		
 	