
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		do you listen to TV mostly or radio or newspaper
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well for myself it's the printed media um only on occasion do i i watch the television for any news because by that time it's so glossed over it's not even funny
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um the radio i've yet to find
 	
 	
 		but it's also little sound bites on TV they don't really tell you much
 	
 	
 		so true so true
 	
 	
 		except except for giving you sports and weather and telling you the story is going to be coming just after this commercial
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		that's right you know details at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> while the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">earth</ENAMEX> is cracking in half
 	
 	
 		yes yes
 	
 	
 		you know um but myself i go for the printed media and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">well one one</NUMEX> new show which i do watch on occasion is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McNeal Lehrer</ENAMEX> on public television
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and that's because they can take the time to get into the new story and they don't go for the hype and all that stuff
 		it appears to me that the news media for the most part is uh doing its darndest to appeal to the lowest common denominator and
 	
 	
 		um-hum have you ever picked up a copy of uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh buddy
 	
 	
 		news McNuggets
 	
 	
 		oh yeah there you go
 		
 
 		so true so true
 	
 	
 		no personally i listen to radio mostly hit the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NPR</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX> and in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the evening</TIMEX> coming home
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah i always liked all things considered
 	
 	
 		yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">All All Things Considered</ENAMEX> and uh <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning edition</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it's like you know just have that on <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">in the morning</TIMEX> while i'm going through the normal routine or driving <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah same story here i uh happened to cross that that beauty of a of a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX> when uh
 		i was with a new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and all i had was an AM radio and i cursed the time for a while and then i found that and i didn't want to go back to FM
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah but uh
 	
 	
 		well out here we get it uh both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AM</ENAMEX> and FM
 	
 	
 		oh you lucky dogs we get it out of the
 	
 	
 		though though the FM cuts off at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX> and then you have to switch over to AM if you want to continue listening to the news
 	
 	
 		oh
 		well you get it one way you get it another
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah but myself well like for example with this you know the democratic race we got going here
 		the different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> we got all this other stuff all i'm seeing are a couple of yahoos and uh no issues so to speak
 	
 	
 		oh yeah yeah definitely definitely haven't been any issues and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">ninety percent</NUMEX> of the stories you hear
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		even you know
 		you know i i we got the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX> news wire at work which is also a very good source of news
 	
 	
 		ah
 	
 	
 		and most of the stories there are how well each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> did in which place and where they  and you know what's the latest scandal but nothing about what they stand for and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh yeah i mean heard more i heard more about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer Flowers</ENAMEX> than i heard i have heard <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>'s uh <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">platform</ENAMEX> on health care
 	
 	
 		issues or
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX> forget it
 	
 	
 		oh yeah thank you
 	
 	
 		he doesn't have a platform
 	
 	
 		yeah that's right well as i always like to say back when he was talking <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about a thousand</NUMEX> points of light that's a nice way of saying our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">platform</ENAMEX> is full of holes
 	
 	
 		no no that's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a thousand</NUMEX> pointless lies
 	
 	
 		hey there you go
 		i'll make that into a tag line in my system
 		all right
 		oh goodness but i don't know for the most part
 		i see the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> for the most part pandering like i said to the lowest common denominator because when it gets down to the nitty-gritty and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brass</ENAMEX> tacks it gets real unpopular
 	
 	
 		well it it
 	
 	
 		and it looses <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">advertisers</ENAMEX> and it looses starts hurting in the budget so it has to cater somewhere
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah news news is entertainment
 	
 	
 		yeah infotainment
 	
 	
 		no not even infotainment entertainment
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i mean the largest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">segments</ENAMEX> are sports and weather
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true
 	
 	
 		and there's there's not really that much of what's going on and the only stories that really get talked about are the ones that have good video clips to go with them
 	
 	
 		um-hum yeah and it's been a long time since i've seen any  you know source of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> do anything gutsy
 		we had a situation here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Des Moines</ENAMEX> when um it was right after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeffrey Dahlmer</ENAMEX> had been apprehended
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		that um the animal rights <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> ran an ad which  excepted
 		which depicted the  of animals very much akin to the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeffrey Dahlmer</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well the register ran it which i think was the right role and privilege and i would be packing pulled out <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a quarter of a million</NUMEX> in advertising
 	
 	
 		yes
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know socked it right to them
 		and that's i guess uh
 		something that distresses me when they have to cater to all these different special interest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> we're not going to get the news
 	
 	
 		well that's one nice nice thing about the public radio and public television is for the most part they're some what distanced from that but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well
 	
 	
 		unfortunately not completely <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> since that's where a lot of their funding is coming from is corporate underwriting
 	
 	
 		yeah and that's unfortunate
 	
 	
 		but they at least make the effort to be
 		distance themselves from that
 	
 	
 		yeah they they've got to work harder because right now
 		when you challenge funding for public radio or public television you're no longer being typecast as trying to kill big bird
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know they're uh
 		i
 		
 		
 	