
 
		
 			
 				you have any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 			
 			
 				
 				yes i have three
 			
 			
 				oh okay any college age
 			
 			
 				uh
 				no well um the youngest just finished medical school
 			
 			
 				oh okay so you actually are probably pretty uh
 			
 			
 				
 				and so i feel like i'm kind of home free now
 			
 			
 				uh great i'm on the uh the other end of the spectrum actually i'm uh
 				uh
 				<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX> into a doctoral program and i am working on my dissertation right now
 			
 			
 				oh well i envy you i wish i had the courage to go back and do that
 			
 			
 				
 				it
 			
 			
 				but i have afraid i have trouble remembering my own name now much less trying to do a dissertation
 			
 			
 				
 				oh
 				yeah well it it it's a rough <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> as i'm sure your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> probably can can attest to as well
 			
 			
 				yes but it's it's very worthwhile when you're finished
 			
 			
 				
 				yeah yeah that's  that's true
 			
 			
 				well what did you look for when you were getting ready to go to a college to a university
 			
 			
 				well
 				to be honest with you i'm not i'm not sure that my
 				my feelings back then are valid or are to be modeled because i was so young um i guess
 				i guess if i had to look at it again i would probably want want to pick a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> that
 				<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh</ENAMEX> number one had a good financial aid <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> uh the school i've been at does not i mean yeah it's okay but
 			
 			
 				<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 				it's not great
 			
 			
 				well they they tend to lose things
 			
 			
 				oh well that's wonderful news
 			
 			
 				yeah uh they lost my transcripts <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about four</NUMEX> times and
 			
 			
 				
 				oh
 				that's painful
 			
 			
 				yeah that's real frustrating um that's that's one aspect of it i think something that's really important is for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> to have a good library
 			
 			
 				yes
 				oh i think that is of the utmost importance
 			
 			
 				yeah
 			
 			
 				uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> chose to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A&M</ENAMEX> here he uh graduated valedictorian of his high school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> so he had you know quite a choice but he wanted a good what he considered one of the best science departments
 			
 			
 				<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 				<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">great</ENAMEX>
 				sure
 				
 			
 			
 				and he wanted to practice in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> so he chose <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">A&M</ENAMEX> and uh they were kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pioneers</ENAMEX>
 			
 			
 				yeah uh-huh
 			
 			
 				in their science <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> in that you could choose the whichever <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> you felt was the would be the most enlightening for what particular field you were going into
 			
 			
 				true
 				<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 			
 			
 				and they listed them in a pamphlet that you received so uh
 			
 			
 				so you actually got some kind of feel for what the faculty
 			
 			
 				yes so that you could now you didn't have to report to i mean you didn't have just one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor professor</ENAMEX> that you had to be with if you were in engineering <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> you might want to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX>
 			
 			
 				histories were
 				right
 				<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 			
 			
 				and if you were going to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> an <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MD</ENAMEX> you might want to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> and then um
 			
 			
 				right
 			
 			
 				and amongst all those listings they had also classified which what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> were the better ones
 			
 			
 				<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 			
 			
 				for each particular segment of that field like one might be better in organic chemistry and one might be better in electrical engineering so uh
 			
 			
 				sure
 				right
 				sounds similar to what most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> do in in on a graduate level
 			
 			
 				<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 			
 			
 				um where as it sounds like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">A&M</ENAMEX> does it more or does it also on an undergraduate level
 			
 			
 				yes and they uh several of the other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX> were using them as a model and going to try it because they felt that
 			
 			
 				so
 			
 			
 				<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> too often said well the reason i didn't do well on that test is my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX>'s harder so basically they all gave the same test
 			
 			
 				right
 			
 			
 				and you could uh you were assigned to a particular place and time to take your test but that was the only time
 			
 			
 				
 				<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 			
 			
 				now of course that's what i i marvel at some of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youngsters</ENAMEX> that i see talk about going off to college that have no self-discipline that
 			
 			
 				yeah
 			
 			
 				you know they're never gonna make it
 			
 			
 				exactly
 			
 			
 				because no matter where you go you there isn't going to be uh mommy to get you up or anything else you know
 			
 			
 				yeah that's that's another thing i wanted to emphasize is that
 				if and if and when i ever get to the point to where i'm looking for schools
 				uh
 				i think i'm <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gonna</ENAMEX> opt for a larger one
 			
 			
 				<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 			
 			
 				just because i i think it forces <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people forces students</ENAMEX> to be a little more independent i know that i myself went to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> as an undergrad
 				one was small one was not small
 				and
 				i really think i learned more at the one that was not small because so much of the things i had to do on my own
 				and i learned a little bit more about the system in general
 				and more about myself um being able to handle the situations that i came into
 			
 			
 				i would think that would be true you would also you know be totally on your own where you if you need help you're going to be the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to search it out
 			
 			
 				right um-hum
 			
 			
 				it isn't gonna just be sitting there and life is something that you have to search out everything you're going to do
 			
 			
 				exactly it's it's an active state it's not something that you can kind of you know be passively involved in and expect to do
 				any good really i don't think
 			
 			
 				no i don't think so either <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> of course uh
 			
 			
 				yeah
 			
 			
 				uh i like i came from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">midwest</ENAMEX> so i'm very partial
 			
 			
 				<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 				
 			
 		
 	