
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yes uh i think a lot of the problems whether they be in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> or in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> in discipline has a part is rooted in the amount of time <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> spend with their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah i i don't think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> spend enough time with their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> these days
 		i remember my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> used to help me with my homework and stuff like that you know make sure that i had
 		that i understood what i was trying to study and everything like that
 	
 	
 		now my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> were the same way uh they they took uh interests in everything that i did not just the things that interested them or when they felt like uh i wanted to spend time which was uh
 		uh when they wanted me get out get me out of the door to school in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		right  well we used to take family vacations which i always used to love we'd travel by <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> to all these different <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh see these you know really nice things and they were not the typical things like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disneyland</ENAMEX> or whatever
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		was more like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> for the mountains or something like that
 	
 	
 		yeah that's essentially what we did uh i look i came from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">midwest</ENAMEX> and we went to the neighboring <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> to uh little known places that i have yet to find anyone else that's ever been to these places
 	
 	
 		yeah exactly i i'm from the midwest myself from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michigan</ENAMEX> and we'd we'd go as far as like oh
 		oh places like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> we went to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX> very frequently and  the the biggest thing was that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> did things together you know we didn't just like separate and go our separate ways when we got there
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we'd always go out and do things and spend time with each other
 	
 	
 		yeah so i i used to babysit uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> when i was a lot younger and um
 		it was essentially they'd they'd get <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> from work the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> would they stick the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> in front of the TV set until it was time to go to bed and never did anything as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> together
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">yep</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> ended up the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">losers</ENAMEX> i think
 	
 	
 		yeah they they became uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brats</ENAMEX> and juvenile delinquents
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> just didn't want to really put the time and effort into uh uh
 	
 	
 		its
 	
 	
 		making them making a family <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> it was like they were single but they're they were still a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a</NUMEX> a single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> but uh they had kids
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> were just a nuisance
 	
 	
 		they they got in the way they cost money and they get they're that's the attitude that a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> and it's one of the reasons why the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> don't do well in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and don't
 		are carrying <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> to school and stuff like that because they don't feel like anybody cares
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh
 	
 	
 		and in some in a lot of cases uh very few or the only the uh only the wrong people care
 		the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who should care don't
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right that's correct
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		um have have you uh have you uh worked around <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> quite a bit
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> at work
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		uh
 		
 
 	
 	
 		not directly huh
 	
 	
 		no no not not in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah i haven't worked i haven't worked around <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> too much either i used to live in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> that had a day care down in the basement
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i'd go down there and play with some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> at times and it was really kind of enjoyable to just they you know they were younger like <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two and a half to five</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and um it was enjoyable because they would they liked just liked being with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i mean it really didn't matter what you did with them as long as you did something with them
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		exactly
 	
 	
 		oh you know let's play with the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen</ENAMEX> or or let's let's play with you know read me a book or you know do something
 	
 	
 		the only problem i had with that and i had i talked to another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who had the same thing when you start actually playing with them you take on the same uh
 		uh sometimes you take on the same mentality of like it's mine
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and i said wait a minute wait a minute i i'm i'm beyond this and i'm acting just like they are
 	
 	
 		you
 		you speak in simple sentences huh
 	
 	
 		yeah all the words have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> syllable
 	
 	
 		do you have a boo boo
 		that doesn't go across very well when you're uh talking to your coworkers
 	
 	
 		right
 		
 
 	
 	
 		do i have a what
 	
 	
 		you know a boo boo an owie
 	
 	
 		i think i'm going to go to the potty now
 	
 	
 		excuse me
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		but uh oh well it sounds like you and i have uh similar opinions on this topic
 	
 	
 		yeah it's it's it's just uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> today are it's they want everything if if it can't be done in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five minutes</TIMEX> don't bother me with it
 	
 	
 		yeah yep no attention no attention span
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then especially if it can't be solved in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a half hour</TIMEX> with ads in between you know
 	
 	
 		right it's the it's the television mentality all problems are created and solved in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a half hour</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yep
 		and uh then you go on to the next set of problems and solve them in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a half hour</TIMEX> too
 	
 	
 		yep well things just and therefore you have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> that um
 		
 		
 	