
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		okay
 	
 	
 		were you drug tested when uh
 	
 	
 		well actually interestingly enough a lot of times
 	
 	
 		oh where where do where do you work at
 	
 	
 		well i just retired from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years</TIMEX> of uh active uh service uh uh retired out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX>  and because of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> that i was in in the military
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and the jobs that i held and particularly because of the security clearances that i had we had first of all we had regular random testing just because we were in the military
 	
 	
 		just because you were in the service yeah
 	
 	
 		right and then because of the security clearances that i held i also had uh other regular random uh drug testing for that as well that i actually had to sign an agreement saying that uh
 	
 	
 		were they like urine tests or were they blood
 	
 	
 		yeah it was all urine testing
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it was mainly because of their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> because <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> use is illegal
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and of course addictive uh it's a perfect thing uh for blackmail for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with high security clearances and so i've kind of over the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty year</TIMEX> period of time i've gotten kind of accustomed to it and
 	
 	
 		that's right
 		that's right
 		oh okay so it doesn't really bother you that much or
 	
 	
 		doesn't bother me uh uh because i've always been in sensitive positions that i understand the
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		the problems that can results uh as far as compromise and espionage and uh addiction and blackmail that that has never bothered me
 	
 	
 		
 
 		exactly yeah i work for a defense <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contractor</ENAMEX> down here uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pratt Whitney</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> and i work for a defense <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contractor</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Network Solutions</ENAMEX> we uh uh we actually operate the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NIC</ENAMEX> for the internet
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		yeah you probably got uh uh information about this program through the internet
 	
 	
 		that that's exactly where i got it from
 	
 	
 		right all of us did
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">yep</ENAMEX> so uh now we don't have any <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> testing out there
 	
 	
 		uh
 		oh okay so yeah at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pratt Whitney</ENAMEX> you do it's the you you have to pass your drug test in order to do uh to get employed there you have to pass it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh it's for the same reasons uh you hold you hold a i have a secret clearance and uh
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know i guess they just want to make sure that uh like you said that nobody can uh hold anything against you you know make  information and then say well we'll turn turn you in for these <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> if you unless you do this and that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right exactly i guess so there's uh still a good bit of discussion and controversy about whether it's an invasion of your privacy and uh that sort of thing
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah there is and i and i can see why you know especially especially if you do do especially especially if you use illegal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> i can see why you wouldn't want it it to happen to you and yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 		right especially right you don't want to get caught
 	
 	
 		and even if you don't you know it's like well geez you know what else what else could they use this stuff for you know and if it is kind of an invasion of privacy it is an invasion of privacy
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah as a matter of fact uh that's such a difficult question to to answer because on the one hand sure uh uh drug testing is an invasion of property or of privacy but yet on the other hand
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right
 	
 	
 		for example these uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> that drive these <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trains</ENAMEX> and that sort of thing that uh have been high and uh killed a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> yeah it's it's uh right
 	
 	
 		that's right you
 		i know it
 		see what a small price to pay to to save some lives it saves us <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> life you know drug testing it's worth it but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right and i think for the most part the general <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> tends to support it but uh i'm sure <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Civil Liberties  Union</ENAMEX> uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACLU</ENAMEX> probably have their
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		and they're worried about abuses of it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">sure</ENAMEX> and that that can really happen
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and that sort of thing not just drug testing but  lots of other things uh for example blood tests that determine whether you have particularly <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diseases</ENAMEX> or not like <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> uh can be construed to be an invasion of property or of
 		of privacy because it effects your insurance and your employability and
 	
 	
 		yes that that that stuff should be kept confidential far as that goes
 	
 	
 		yeah and it's it but yet if that's that's in any kind of a computer database  somebody's going to get access to it that and uh real easy to abuse so
 	
 	
 		it's accessible that's right
 	
 	
 		it's one of those problems that  it's really hard to come up with an answer to
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh
 	
 	
 		yeah you have you ever heard of anybody cheating on those uh urine tests
 	
 	
 		yeah oh yeah in
 	
 	
 		i know i know a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who was who cheated and got in out there at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pratt</ENAMEX> and uh he took somebody else's with him and just
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		put it in there so it you you can get around them if you have to
 	
 	
 		oh yeah there were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX> that were selling their own urine
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		because they uh just had to be careful that they didn't do the test and uh show that you came up pregnant
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		depending on who you got your sample from it that could be really bad  so  but uh
 	
 	
 		oh that could be real embarrassing
 		then you could be caught real bad
 	
 	
 		and they were really protective
 	
 	
 		what do they what do they do to you in the military if you get caught what do they do to you if you get caught
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well it depends now if you have a you know that was the other funny thing if you had a high security clearance like my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> had
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and you got caught and these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> were shift <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> it really worked out well for them because of course the first thing that happened was that their security clearance was suspended and then they were removed from access to sensitive information which means they got <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a straight day</TIMEX> job at the company
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		so it it was really to their advantage to get caught and
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> but it wouldn't didn't look good on their record though of course
 	
 	
 		yeah and in the long run of course uh that was a problem and it kind of depended also on  on how often they uh were caught whether they were in a rehab program and
 		
 		
 	