
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		so you're looking for a car
 	
 	
 		well actually not but i'm all ways looking at them  you know you know yeah it uh
 	
 	
 		yeah i know that feeling
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mines</ENAMEX> about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years old</TIMEX> now so debating weather to run it into the ground
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		put up with those headache or get something new
 	
 	
 		hum
 		you know am convince that um it's always cheaper to repair than replace
 		and uh you know if you replace there are other reason for doing it
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		like you want you know my my answer to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> is it's okay if it ugly um it okay depending on the amount  there is a bunch of other things that okay that it is it got to be reliable there is no excuse for that
 	
 	
 		right that's number one well that and safety
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		safe and reliable
 	
 	
 		um-hum well safety is subjective i think um you know one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> criteria of safety is maybe a little different from another person
 	
 	
 		well i think yeah that's true but reliability you know if it's not reliable it's not safe
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well the you know not reliable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> it it will never start in which case extremely safe
 	
 	
 		well may be not if you're on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Trans Alaska</ENAMEX> highway
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah that's true there are places where you can starve or freeze to death if your <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> want start
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		um for a while i was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">proponent</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saab</ENAMEX>'s and um i have had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of them and one was a tremendous one disappointment from a reliability view point
 		and um
 		basically i decided to get rid of it before the warranty ran out
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		and i think i was cured of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> motoring mystic
 		at that point
 	
 	
 		well the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saab</ENAMEX> does have a lot of good features and the reliability is uh like one of the few things i worry about with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saab</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um have you own one or
 	
 	
 		no i haven't but uh you know look looking around it does seem like a roomy
 	
 	
 		
 
 		guess i'm
 		
 
 	
 	
 		good handling
 	
 	
 		you know if it weren't for the reliability in every other respect the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> was wonderful drove great ton of room very very safe but front wheel drive which with me a plus but i just keep having um string of minor malfunctions
 	
 	
 		yeah exactly
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and um just the process of have to pay for these thing you know also the increments is what <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred</NUMEX> and fifty dollars <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two hundred</NUMEX> fifty every time you take it to a mechanic and touch it <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">hundred dollars hundred dollars hundred dollars</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		well that's
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yeah that's the other drawback of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saab</ENAMEX> is that they are not really cheap
 	
 	
 		yeah its can of funny because um i was having it repaired at this place called Import Only
 		and um this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>'s comment was
 		and i asked him you know you you repair them all what do you think is best kind of reliability and he kind of get a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> car
 		um that starting to fall out of fashion these days
 	
 	
 		oh yeah a lot of flag waving going on
 	
 	
 		uh
 		yeah you know i'm convince that well you it kind of interesting is what i'm driving right now is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">Probe</ENAMEX> which is manufactured in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mazda</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factory</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so i'm not sure weather it's an import or not
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well that's a serious problem if your concerned with that i don't its possible the where things are built anyone
 	
 	
 		yeah it's fake it's fake because see i mean even if i i'm sure the um
 		you know if you take the most Americanized in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> and you know pry open one of those computer you will find a computer chip that were assemble in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Singapore</ENAMEX>
 		and so forth uh it's just difficult difficult
 	
 	
 		oh yeah you know
 	
 	
 		i mean it's got funny  coming once just before and um
 		equal the orange juice was label concentrate manufactured in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX>
 		who would have though of it apple say orange <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">apple apple juice</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">turkey</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah its probably own by a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> country <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that's employing <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		very probably you know its um yeah i think the ideal of um yeah its interesting because you know the location um
 	
 	
 		you you know
 	
 	
 		don't seem to uh you know you you can work over <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">several thousands of miles</NUMEX> not like it once was
 		use use to be they request uh penalty for  uh doing it but i don't think it's true any more
 	
 	
 		yeah it seems like a
 		oh well transportation does still cost
 	
 	
 		and so
 		yeah absolutely um you know but there may be other bigger factors so if you decide to replace this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten year</TIMEX> vehicle what what is the prime <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contender</ENAMEX> right know
 	
 	
 		well uh i was i was actually thinking of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saab</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine thousands</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah i own one
 	
 	
 		but there's a there's a few other hatchbacks
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		no well i have it a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toyota</ENAMEX> and i like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toyota</ENAMEX>'s
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		um which kind
 	
 	
 		it's a a Supra
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so it handles really well so i'm reluctant to get anything that handles poorly
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		uh you would like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saab</ENAMEX> have you driven one
 	
 	
 		um i drove a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nine hundred about five years years ago</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it was very nice
 	
 	
 		well i had had a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">nine hundred</NUMEX> which i replaced <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">the nine thousand nine thousands</NUMEX> is the one that gave me a lot of problems
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		um
 		i happen the think the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine hundreds</NUMEX> is a uh i like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the nine hundred</TIMEX> better it it had more of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saab</ENAMEX> weirdness which really attracted me
 	
 	
 		yes uh i don't mine ugly
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		um you know it's um
 	
 	
 		in fact i really don't
 		
 		
 	