
 
     		
 	
 		all right well i've been to a couple we've uh we just had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> recently for my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX>'s birthday that all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> got together
 	
 	
 		all right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		where was that
 	
 	
 		in in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wyoming Sundance</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		where in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wyoming</ENAMEX>
 		oh i've been through <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wyoming</ENAMEX> but and uh
 		i uh when uh on our way to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Montana</ENAMEX> so that's a bit sure is pretty <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> up there
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		and we just kind of we kept uh kind of uh it was a surprise birthday <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> for her was what it was
 	
 	
 		wow how old was she
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">sixty five</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh i bet she just uh was pleased
 	
 	
 		oh yeah she
 		she didn't know what was going on or anything
 	
 	
 		oh that's great
 	
 	
 		
 
 		but my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> had a knew uh what was going on but she didn't and
 		several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in town knew what was going on but they never did tell her so
 	
 	
 		uh that's uh that's that's quite a feat to be able to do that
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh yeah because we figured somebody'd probably tell her sooner or later
 	
 	
 		relatively small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> it uh it would be pretty easy
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah it
 	
 	
 		so how many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> were up there
 	
 	
 		well we just had uh just immediate family just uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">grandkids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah my well what it was was just
 		huh let's see it was uh just my sisters me and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> and then uh our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>'
 	
 	
 		oh neat
 	
 	
 		so uh it was pretty good
 	
 	
 		well i bet
 		did you take a lot of pictures
 	
 	
 		yeah we even had some video taken so
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		got all the big eyes and surprises huh
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		we had a surprise party uh for uh for my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> once and uh she they're in they're in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lubbock</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh
 		she has uh
 		oh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about eight</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandkids</ENAMEX> and we
 		hid them all through a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>'s house
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh she walked in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> and all of a sudden these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandkids</ENAMEX> started popping up out of furniture and behind doors and
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 	
 	
 		she just uh was speechless for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about fifteen or twenty minutes</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		really caught her off guard it's it's really fun to have a
 		have a have uh that sort of uh
 		surprise to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> members
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah do you have a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort Worth</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh no it's it's me and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and son
 	
 	
 		oh how uh  are you where's your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> from
 	
 	
 		she's from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Antonio</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh that uh that's quite uh
 		quite a spread to get uh
 		everybody together it's hard <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now and days</TIMEX> actually
 	
 	
 		oh yeah well we go to you know we go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Antonio</ENAMEX> a lot to be with them during like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thanksgiving</TIMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> so
 	
 	
 		unless
 	
 	
 		that's kind of our family reunions with them
 	
 	
 		now we uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		we have our uh our side of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> really is pretty spread out so we we're we have to uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 	
 	
 		have a reunion maybe every other year
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		we all uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh gather uh
 		uh at a place just north of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX> which is fairly convenient for everybody we've got <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El Paso</ENAMEX> to
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Waco</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> so that uh uh
 		trying to trying to make it
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> make everybody work a little bit i guess that's the deal that way no one feels like they're being
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah make everybody feel like well you're not at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">just one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> so you don't really have to  you kind of all stay in in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">motels</ENAMEX> and stuff
 	
 	
 		taken advantage of
 		
 
 		yeah one of the uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one one</NUMEX> of the rules is that if you're not at the reunion you have to plan the next one
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> that's a pretty
 	
 	
 		so that's that's worked out that that that that brought a lot of people
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah i never thought of that that'd probably work
 	
 	
 		well that uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		it it uh it's been successful so far and you know we after the reunion it's uh it's so funny because you'd say well uh we ought to do this twice <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> we had so much fun and it it it's too bad you can't
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know used to be i guess with uh family reunions where they just sort of came in from the surrounding <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX> uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh it was a lot easier but <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now and days</TIMEX> we've
 		got <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> scattered all over the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and it's
 		that's really tough
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		to get <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> together
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		it's not they don't want to but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah it's that's the problem with us i'm down here and
 		and then i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		ooh
 	
 	
 		and then the rest of my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> live right around <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sundance</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		what brought you uh down from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wyoming</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh i'm in the service
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		i'm in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX> so that kind of
 	
 	
 		how we uh
 		we used to live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort Worth</ENAMEX> actually and
 		we lived over by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carswell</ENAMEX> and i just love watching those <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX> come by
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it's it's it's really pretty
 	
 	
 		well i just before i came here i was stationed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lubbock</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah i was there for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX> and then i got down here
 		
 		
 	