
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay uh what's done in your area
 	
 	
 		well in our area we uh
 		had basically a road side pick-up for uh aluminum cans plastic
 		um that's about it if you want to participate with paper um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">wood</ENAMEX> and other products alone that line uh different types of plastic you have to bring physically down to the dump
 	
 	
 		uh different types of plastic other than food types container plastic
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		um what about glass
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">um glass</ENAMEX> actually that's handle on the road side too
 	
 	
 		so along along with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> or or or the plastic and the
 	
 	
 		along with no <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glass</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">aluminum</ENAMEX> together
 	
 	
 		yeah okay that's that's the way we do it here uh we have the addition thing of uh newspaper pickup
 		but it doesn't include uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> or telephone books or just plain regular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> like computer print out just only for news print only
 	
 	
 		what about cardboard
 	
 	
 		that's not included that's that's completely different
 		uh
 		i feel you know it's kind of ridiculous you know you're only allowed to pick-up one sort of paper when you have something such as phone books which contributes a lot to uh waste paper they should pick that up as well
 	
 	
 		what do you think about the value of of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> as you mentioned
 	
 	
 		yes that that would be good if they can if they would pick it up i i i put them in too because  so much of the uh junk mail that you get is made of the same type of uh print uh wax print
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		that's makes it hard to recycle
 	
 	
 		well in our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> we've imposed um
 		basically a  sign that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces people</ENAMEX> to recycle you have to pay for all your trash all your trash bags
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		there's no more municipal trash pick-up
 	
 	
 		i see
 	
 	
 		and that intricate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> encourages them to uh reduce there waste
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> and that actually had a pretty good result so for
 	
 	
 		so do you feel <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are uh hoarding  their garbage
 	
 	
 		no there um  a lot of them are recycling by trying to compress their trash into the bags as much as they can
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um but for the most part it it's been a big boost to the recycling effort
 	
 	
 		i see
 	
 	
 		it was uh much contested because no one likes to have to pay a dollar fifty a bag
 	
 	
 		rather steep i guess
 	
 	
 		it it is very steep but it really forces you to think about what you're throwing out
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		hum well what what we have you just instituted here was a um uh biodegradable type pick-up
 		uh once a week they'll come by and out of a container that you've mark only for biodegradable <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">plant clippings lawn</ENAMEX> clippings
 		uh it has to be decomposable matter no uh dirt uh no bricks or anything like that
 		uh they'll pick that up once a week and we are not allowed to put that in normal trash
 	
 	
 		hum
 		well that makes good sense what did he do turn into compose or
 	
 	
 		that's right yeah they turn it to compose and where they put that i have the foggiest idea
 		because i don't see at along side the road
 		uh it got to be this big huge pile somewhere in the city
 	
 	
 		hum yeah we don't have anything like that around here or at least that i am aware of
 	
 	
 		or they just
 	
 	
 		but that does sound like it could be beneficial especially in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the fall</TIMEX> when you've got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about twenty</NUMEX> bags of leaves out on the side of the road
 	
 	
 		yes
 		um what what do you fill would be a good idea to encourage more recycling
 	
 	
 		um in our area as as as i mention <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX> if you force <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to pay for their trash they're going think twice about what they're throwing out
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they're going to look at everything closely i know i go out of my way to recycle what ever i can
 		um part of it is because  my environmental
 		belief but  the main part is uh
 		you know avoid paying more than they have to pay
 		and uh i think if more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> to make that type of decision you know as far as the pocket book they're going to recycle
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		what about the idea of um that some <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> have about force deposit on say beverage containers
 		you think that's a good idea
 	
 	
 		no i think that
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> uh
 		that that that hurts <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> economically and i don't think that really benefits the overall recycling effort
 		um because i know a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> just throw out there cans anyway regards weather it's a nickle a dime for a bottle
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> and i'm just not a big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">believer</ENAMEX> in that type of text which is how i view it
 	
 	
 		i say
 		um that interesting because i i i  personally like the idea
 		uh if i had uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five hundred</NUMEX> cans saved up between <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">soda</ENAMEX> and other beverages uh
 		uh
 	
 	
 		what i think you run into a problem there is then you have to bring the cans down to a department a a pick-up center
 	
 	
 		well if they did like what they did when i was younger were all <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">soda</ENAMEX> bottles were returnable for the most part
 		um every store had where you turned in the bottles and the manufacture
 		
 		
 	