
 
     		
 	
 		all right
 	
 	
 		gun control means using <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> hands
 	
 	
 		
  
 		yeah uh
 		well i fill
 		like uh there should be some gun control but
 		uh i don't fill like you know um
 		uh just regular normal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> that just using it for hunting and stuff shouldn't have to pay for other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> mistakes
 	
 	
 		oh i agree i mean i don't see any particular sporting purpose in anything that explodes when it arise
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and i can't quite understand what i do you know what you a rational for a machine gun
 	
 	
 		that's true
 	
 	
 		but
 		i mean to say that the quote assault <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">rifle</ENAMEX> is
 		you know a bad thing
 		all that is is a change in a stock configuration
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		if you think about it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well that's true
 	
 	
 		because you know they been making semi automatic
 		classically style if you will
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rifle</ENAMEX> for years
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and the and the only thing between the assault <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">rifle</ENAMEX> and that is a stock is a stock change
 	
 	
 		yeah that's for sure
 	
 	
 		what can i say right
 	
 	
 		
 
 		uh
 		yeah and uh well the uh
 		huh
 		i'm trying to think what to say here
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 		yeah i just uh you know i just can't quite understand it's interesting is uh i get down to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> quite a bit
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh you know it's interesting how when you get away from
 		you know north of the middle of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		how altitude change
 	
 	
 		yeah  different different altitude different places you know it's it's just like well i'm originally from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wyoming</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		out there you always see <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> because of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ranchers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX> use them all the time you know it
 	
 	
 		well i'm from central <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> and it's
 		you know it's
 		not uncommon at all to drive down the road and you know there's a you know the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">shotgun</ENAMEX> is in the back of the pickup
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and so it just you know what you get up here it gets really weird
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 		it's well that's the way it is around here you know especially you know you get  closer to uh bigger <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> and stuff and it's
 	
 	
 		right where where are you from in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well i'm
 	
 	
 		i mean from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i'm at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort Worth</ENAMEX> which is right out right to the west of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay
 		yeah i flown into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas Fort Worth</ENAMEX> a bit so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		uh
 		but you you know they they all have there problem down here too you know with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> gun control and stuff
 		
 
 		uh
 	
 	
 		but it's you know it's
 		it's significant i just detected a significantly different altitude
 		like up here
 		you would find it very difficult to go to like
 		most of the sporting good <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> up here hardly they may carry firearms but would have to hunt for them
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and you go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> and that's just part of the store
 	
 	
 		yeah oh i see what you are saying so
 	
 	
 		yeah you know i mean you might go you would to you know go to a major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX> like a KMart
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		is you will have a hard time up here in a KMart finding somebody to sell you a gun if they may have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three or four</NUMEX> of them on display
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		when you go to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KMart</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> in you know that's a major section of the sporting good section that all the difference i'm saying
 	
 	
 		oh well so when it
 	
 	
 		they don't even  totally different
 	
 	
 		yeah so in in other words they they make you wait or you
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh Virginia's</ENAMEX> by county
 		is there's no wait for a long gun
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		there's in some <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">county</ENAMEX> it's whatever the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">county</ENAMEX> wants
 		statewide there's no wait
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		which is stupid because if i don't want to wait <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three days</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">county</ENAMEX> that i live in i'll drive to the next <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">county</ENAMEX> there isn't a wait
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know
 	
 	
 		yeah i see what you are saying there
 	
 	
 		you know  i mean that you know it's uh
 		in fact they got big trouble is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX> is got total <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX> on firearms
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you can't own one
 	
 	
 		well yeah they've
 	
 	
 		but they're killing each other by you know <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five and six</NUMEX> a night in that city
 	
 	
 		yeah because because they get them form the black market and stuff
 	
 	
 		well but you understand what i'm saying is is their gun control is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred</NUMEX> percent but it doesn't work so now they say well we got to you know they're saying <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> got to have gun control so they can't you can't buy <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun gun</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> and bring them to <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 		but they're still going to have problems though
 	
 	
 		no they just steal them
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well they break into somebody <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and just take their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh they don't break into to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> houses they
 		
 		
 	