
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		okay well
 	
 	
 		yep
 	
 	
 		i guess if i was going to advise a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> on um
 		well you know maybe how to help their their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> choose a college the first thing i'd be interested in is what's the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> interested in doing i mean do they have a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a</NUMEX> a major that they'd want to be interested in you know courses that they'd want to be taking um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> thing i'd probably look at is uh what they can afford
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know in terms of you know how much money do they have or does the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> have to pay are there any scholarships or anything that they could uh
 		manage either you know through maybe an open system or maybe from a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> itself
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then kind of go from there you know that's kind of where i'd start
 	
 	
 		yeah that's that's uh those are some good thoughts i
 		i found for myself that to start off at a junior <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> in your local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> and find
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that way what you do is that you find what topics you're interested in because you really you can project say a you know uh a say
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> out of high school they might think that they have some interests but they haven't explored everything so they don't really know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so if they go to a junior <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> and and start taking some general education classes and things if they look through the catalog and think they find things that they're interested in
 	
 	
 		um-hum yeah
 	
 	
 		well then they can they really they can really find what they're interests are and then it plus it's also a lot more more inexpensive to do it that way
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah that's true
 	
 	
 		and be and then
 		then then they can choose a college and then they can they can transfer
 		yeah i guess uh the location is um is something you know it's uh whether they want to be close to their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> or whether you know uh farther away or something
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		um-hum i think those are good points i think one thing i might i might differ with or or maybe we would agree on this is that uh i think there's some i think there some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> who who probably don't really know what they want to take
 	
 	
 		right right
 	
 	
 		you they don't have any work experience or whatever maybe they've taken some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classes</ENAMEX> in high school or something like that i think the advice you give is is excellent for that i think on the other hand there are there are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> there are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> out there who know what they want to take
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh i might advise them to jump right in and
 		and find you know a good <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> that they you know that has good standing uh in that area you know has a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faculty</ENAMEX> has a good reputation
 	
 	
 		oh sure
 	
 	
 		uh that's what i did
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		i knew what i wanted and i was i was i was exactly almost exactly right
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		it just that just helps the decision process when you know what's available because when you're when you're a a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> in school <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">high school</ENAMEX> and stuff like this is it you're only
 		cognizant of sort of your immediate area environment and surroundings so you just don't know what's there you might just you know like go oh wow that's neat you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but another another thing and this is i think is really important is that the college hype okay
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they send this they send these brochures and uh pamphlets and stuff to the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> and you know send us this money and we're going to give you these services and things like that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		that isn't so they they're they're they're <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> horses of of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> different colors and i had an experience uh i had to i stayed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dormitory</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i they forced you to have a mean plan okay and so you were forced to go to the dining <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> was terrible you were you were treated like a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> rate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">human being</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dormitory</ENAMEX> was hinged on a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> concentration camp
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		okay
 	
 	
 		and you just you just really didn't have any you know any rights and you just just it's just really structure like that and so one of my main suggestions would be to
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> to go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> and just
 		spend some time and talk to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> if they want to send their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> to the dorm well go to the talk to some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in there you know talk to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and get the true information because as i said it's it they're just that's just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> different things
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah i knew uh
 		i i think that's a good idea and in general i think it's a good idea to to go to the school i mean once once you've narrowed down
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> or to to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two or three</NUMEX> or whatever number you know go visit the school <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> you know both the parents and and the student
 	
 	
 		right
 		alright but don't fall for the you know the the student the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> tour and and all the hype don't fall for it because that's that's not because once you get in there sometimes you you make these commitments and you're not able to change them you know commitments so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah i mean and that's the thing you have to sit down and look at the uh
 		at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> needs you know i've you know there there some there some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> who even as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">freshmen</ENAMEX> would be ready to go live in an <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> and and start cooking there own meals and everything but there some who wouldn't be
 	
 	
 		oh exactly
 		exactly
 	
 	
 		i had a very good experience i was in the dorms for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three or four</NUMEX> out of my <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh i had a really good dorm experience
 		
 		
 	