
 
     		
 	
 		hey um generally i am majority majority majority of the news that i get is from uh AM radio in the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">mornings</TIMEX> but going to and from work i we have like uh a a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WCBS</ENAMEX> station which which just kind of fires through all the top topics
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		how do you uh how do you generally find out what's going on in the world
 	
 	
 		oh i don't know
 		oh i listen in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> but my commute is only <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">only a mile</NUMEX> so
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh but uh you know i have the uh radio wake me up in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX> so i get i get some headlines there
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		i read the usenet news
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		uh
 		really i'm not getting the good quality news that i want
 		and i i bought a TV last year
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but but i don't really watch it
 	
 	
 		you're behind
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		oh and i don't i don't believe
 		i don't get any in depth stuff
 	
 	
 		i used to have uh i used to have cable and uh the thing that i really miss um
 		since uh since i lost cable and there's that not that much on there that i miss but uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Headline News</ENAMEX> was always good because i could get a quick roundup of whatever the top topics were in in like a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">half hour</TIMEX> span and in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Around the World in Thirty Minutes</ENAMEX> i think was their big thing
 		and the other thing i used to i uh i miss is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN um CNN</ENAMEX> used to go a little bit more in depth um you would get uh like <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Crossfire</ENAMEX> you would get you know different different perspectives from usually from like the left and the right liberal and conservative
 		arguing the various uh
 	
 	
 		oh <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Crossfire</ENAMEX> yeah i saw that a couple of times
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patrick Buchanan</ENAMEX> who's now running for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> used to be the uh conservative side for that
 	
 	
 		who did they have i've my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> who watch <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> all the time they like knew these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i can't think of the name of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> that represented the left
 	
 	
 		yeah uh i saw the uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McLaughlin</ENAMEX> had a similar type of a program on
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i guess <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> retired from that also
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that that's a good show i like that one a lot
 	
 	
 		yeah that's actually on a network isn't it
 	
 	
 		yeah it's on i guess it was on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> for a while
 	
 	
 		that's exactly right
 	
 	
 		probably still is
 	
 	
 		and and uh see because i've run into that a couple of times on accident and uh ended up watching it for like extended periods of time but that's how i get most of my news is is
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS PBS PBS</ENAMEX> uh you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">MacNeil Lehrer</ENAMEX> or uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NPR</ENAMEX> usually have some decent in depth stuff
 	
 	
 		i tried listening to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NPR</ENAMEX> but uh uh i mean in the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">mornings</TIMEX> i don't in the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">mornings</TIMEX> i want i want a little i want you know the the yeah the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> feed you know  give me a couple of color graphs and uh and i'll be happy
 	
 	
 		headlines
 		
 
 		oh God i hate that
 		yeah we have uh you know the local newspaper is is pretty weak
 	
 	
 		uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh
 		and i once in a every once in a while like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every six months</TIMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every three months</TIMEX> i read the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> is pretty good
 	
 	
 		the only thing that scares me about um the way i do news is
 		getting it from like these pre digested <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> you know like the like the
 		typically what i've heard maybe it's just the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i hang around with but typically i hear <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> saying that like uh
 		the news on TV and what not tends to be um more on the left hand side it tends to be a little bit more liberal and if nothing else it does tend to be more editorialized than these are the facts
 	
 	
 		well not only that but it's so little there's no background
 	
 	
 		true too
 	
 	
 		uh you know i rely a lot to tell you the truth on uh you know when i was growing up i learned geography i'd read the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> a lot so you know and every every
 		day there'd be an article on some country you know what's doing in that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know because there's enough <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> that uh you know there'd be something interesting happening
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		pretty much and i got a pretty good feel for
 		you know and um that and taking some economics classes you get a pretty good feel for how the world works
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so when you hear a story then you say well what aren't they telling you
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and then you start conjecturing and that's where i hate i hate it because you know i can guess what's happening but i don't know the real truth
 		and uh they just they leave out so much
 	
 	
 		
 
 		but see i think you and i perhaps i i think uh well i get the feeling that that you and i perhaps might might take the time to try and figure out exactly what really happened as opposed to what they're telling us even though they maybe close
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but i wonder how much of the rest of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> takes the time to to stop with just the the straight spoon fed you know
 	
 	
 		huh you can stop wondering
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		they don't care
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah well especially when you figure what <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a third</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that bother to vote always vote <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that always that bother to vote always vote <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	