
 
     		
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">okay Michelle</ENAMEX> well since i started off i uh since i called in i guess i'll state my opinion first
 	
 	
 		
 
 		okay
 	
 	
 		and uh i i guess i'd fall in the same category that i don't think there should be any restrictions i think that if unless a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapon</ENAMEX> is self-propelled or has to be towed <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> should be able to own it
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay
 		um i really don't know exactly where i stand just to be honest i have mixed feelings about it and i've thought about both positions i would like to have the freedom
 		to own a firearm um i am currently married and that makes me feel more secure but if i were single i would definitely want to have a firearm
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh of course i think it should be locked up you know so that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> can not
 	
 	
 		absolutely
 	
 	
 		get
 		their hands on it
 	
 	
 		i agree i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> should be held responsible if their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> gets a hold of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> or either injures injures another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> or or themselves
 	
 	
 		um-hum definitely definitely
 	
 	
 		i also am in favor of a check i i think the criminal record system in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> should be brought up to snuff so that they can run a computer check as easy as they do when you run a credit card through so they can see if a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> insane or is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">felon</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right now i've heard a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> say that that wouldn't do any good but i really think that it makes a lot of sense
 	
 	
 		i don't
 		it wouldn't do any good right now because the criminal record systems are a mess you know i mean there really isn't any any system as such but if there were and if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> were to invest in that then there wouldn't be any problem they'd
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they'd be able to identify those that shouldn't have
 	
 	
 		what do you mean the criminal records are a mess
 	
 	
 		well there isn't any computerized system that can tell you you know
 	
 	
 		by the push of a button
 	
 	
 		yeah i mean in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> has done it by the way reason i i'm a life member of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gun Owners</ENAMEX> and i am sure no longer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NRA</ENAMEX> so i i'm kind of into this but <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia Virginia</ENAMEX> does have an instance check uh system
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they do have their records within a state computerized and it seems to be working well
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and if it could be done on a federal basis
 	
 	
 		hm
 		are they the only state
 	
 	
 		the only <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> that i'm aware of
 	
 	
 		gosh
 	
 	
 		that's done that
 	
 	
 		so what has to take place them to to make this happen to other states
 	
 	
 		well uh
 	
 	
 		that makes a lot of sense
 	
 	
 		yeah it really you know it's it should be done on a national basis because on the statewide basis you just get those that have violated state laws but
 	
 	
 		you're right right
 	
 	
 		yeah and some there are federal you know violators too
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so it would require an investment on the part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> to to bring their records up to shape but i think it's uh probably a good investment anyway uh
 	
 	
 		um-hum so you're from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Hampshire</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes um-hum
 	
 	
 		i'm not even i hate to admit uh that familiar with what the laws are here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> regarding purchasing a firearm um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i guess you heard about the
 		the massacre in  that's <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">only about an hour</TIMEX> in fact that's where all my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousins</ENAMEX> live i used to go down there every <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">summer</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yes
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so that was a real shocker
 	
 	
 		you know uh in that case uh in particular that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fellow</ENAMEX> that did that had owned those <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> a long time
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true
 	
 	
 		so i mean it's not like he went in and picked them up and uh then went off on a shooting spree
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		um-hum um-hum yeah so it um it couldn't have been avoided by you know any type of law being
 	
 	
 		and
 	
 	
 		uh set
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		but
 	
 	
 		unfortunately whenever something like happens that happens uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> tend to blame the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> and not the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> it is it's it is the person
 	
 	
 		yeah this is true
 		
 
 		yeah oh i tend to agree with you in in that i believe that
 		that that
 		like you're saying the majority i believe would be responsible with with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapon</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lord</ENAMEX> knows with the crime rate the way it is
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we need to have something to protect ourselves
 	
 	
 		yeah i feel that you should be you know you uh if you were single should be allowed to have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapon</ENAMEX> to  yourself
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but if it
 	
 	
 		yeah i know how to use it
 	
 	
 		um-hum but if there were a total ban you know who'd have the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah oh sure
 	
 	
 		it wouldn't be it wouldn't be the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who'd go to buy them honestly
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yeah it would be the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that you know could
 		get in touch with the underground or something and i mean they have ways
 	
 	
 		right
 		that's right and gun control laws don't stem them because uh they don't they don't most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> don't go buy their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> uh from a gun <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> anyway
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		they get them through the through the black market
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah you're right that's what i was thinking
 		well
 	
 	
 		well it's uh it's certainly a a lengthy subject and there's a lot of
 	
 	
 		it is it's very complex
 	
 	
 		there's a lot of uh discussion about it and what and now and then it becomes a heated argument in both sides but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i i've i just feel that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founders</ENAMEX> of our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> the constitution <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that wrote the constitution didn't intend for us to not have a means to protect ourselves either either from without the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> or from within the country
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah do you do a lot of hunting
 	
 	
 		no i don't i used to i i used to now i'm just a target <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shooter</ENAMEX> yeah i used to go uh
 	
 	
 		with your <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX>
 		are you
 		so do you
 		
 		
 	