
 
     		
 	
 		kinds of music are you into
 	
 	
 		
 
 		uh well i i like lots of different kinds of music
 	
 	
 		yeah same here
 	
 	
 		uh
 		my uh my uh
 		upbringing was in classical music but um i really enjoy um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		all all different kinds of music for example
 		i i really get a kick out of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rush</ENAMEX> and uh and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pink Floyd</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		they just played here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX> not too long ago
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		they played uh with uh Primus
 		have you heard of them
 	
 	
 		um no i don't think so
 	
 	
 		yeah i didn't i didn't get to go to it then
 		i know some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that did and they they said it was a really great show
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah i'm sure it was um i also like jazz
 	
 	
 		uh-huh what kind like modern or
 	
 	
 		and
 		um well yeah well yeah i like Fusion but i also like uh the classics
 	
 	
 		
  
 		yeah i'm kind of i'm more into the the traditional like um
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flonies Smunk</ENAMEX> and uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cole Don Cole Train</ENAMEX> maybe
 		uh i like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Winten Mersalis</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah he's great
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		he is he's very good
 	
 	
 		he was i think he's i read in the paper i was thinking about going down to the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Jazz festival</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Orleans</ENAMEX> it's like a i think might be <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of April</TIMEX>
 		but um
 		i think he's supposed to be playing there he played in he played in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> in here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX> a little while ago too but
 		i didn't have the money  it was like eighteen bucks or something
 	
 	
 		yeah now i saw him along time ago before he had achieved fame at the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">uh Jazz Festival</ENAMEX> they had in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cleveland</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh really
 		oh really God that must've been great
 	
 	
 		yeah he he is really good um i i i even enjoy uh some of the old timers like even uh uh from like the big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX> era like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennie Goodman</ENAMEX> or
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh i saw him play uh when i was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> also uh of course he by that time he was he was an old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> but it was still fun to uh fun to listen too him
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah that'd been weird
 		seems like a that seems like a long time ago
 		i'm i'm kind of i don't know i'm into a lot of different kinds of music too i like that kind that kind of jazz and
 		um
 		a lot of different kinds of rock music not really pop type music you know like radio
 		a lot of radio play like the stuff i listen to but it's not you know strictly alternative either
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		it's kind of
 		i like um
 		let's see there's some local bands from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX> like have you ever heard of uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fuller</ENAMEX> for Now they're
 		they're real new
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		they've they've they've gotten in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rolling Stone</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a couple</NUMEX> times
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		but uh they just put an album out
 		um
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Red Hot Chili</ENAMEX> Peppers
 		uh
 		Fishbone they've got they've got some horns i i like i like bands with horns
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		that rock with horns it sounds really neat
 	
 	
 		yeah i did too i i i one of the things given given my classical background uh one of the things that really turns me on is uh when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">musicians</ENAMEX> are are creative with their instrumentation
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> as well as you know the typical creative lyrics or or or melodies i also like that's one of the reasons for example that i like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rush</ENAMEX> is because it's not always
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> or in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> even meter you know it they they they mix it up they they do interesting things with rhythms and they do interesting things with
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drummer</ENAMEX>'s unbelievable
 	
 	
 		yeah and also um <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Getty Lee</ENAMEX> on the base
 	
 	
 		yeah uh-huh
 	
 	
 		um it's not just a straight base line that just repeats over and over and over again like on the pop tunes it right it it it it it changes up
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		definitely
 		do you play any instruments
 	
 	
 		um yeah i play i play uh uh oboe and <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> horn in fact um i've actually started playing again
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		uh i played when i was uh up through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">my first year</TIMEX> of college and uh uh then college got the best of me and then i got married and had <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and and i really haven't had very much time to play but uh i have i found a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> who
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i met somebody in town who had <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> became friendly with and discovered that we both played oboe in college so we've been trying to uh get together once <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX> or once every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">couple of weeks</TIMEX> and
 	
 	
 		well that's good
 	
 	
 		and and play a little bit mostly uh it's mostly remedial work for us because we we we're both out of shape
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah i bet
 		i i'd never played really anything throughout school
 		i never i don't know i never got in it i thought it would take too much time and all that then i
 		i um
 		i started getting into uh drums i got this bongo that someone had left at our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and i sort of play on that and i got i got a drum set like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three months</TIMEX> ago
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh cool
 	
 	
 		and i've we've got extra <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> in our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and i've been driving all my roommates crazy playing on that but i really need to
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		get like i know this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> that i think i'm going to try to get to uh give me lessons and stuff because there's lots of stuff that i don't i mean i could i'm improving but slowly and i think i could you know
 	
 	
 		yeah well also if you if you take lessons you might be able to uh
 	
 	
 		learn a lot
 	
 	
 		nip bad habits before they start
 	
 	
 		yeah it's true
 		which i probably already have because i've been playing for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three months</TIMEX> but um it's never too late i guess it's not too late to change yet
 		but uh
 		it's been that's been a lot of fun and it makes me listen more a lot more too to when i'm listening to bands and music and stuff
 		uh i mean i i play a lot more attention
 		to what they're doing and
 		i i appreciate you know a a lot of what the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">musicians</ENAMEX> are doing
 		
 		
 	