
 
     		
 	
 		i'll start in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place i don't have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and i don't have a budget
 	
 	
 		
 
 		okay
 		i don't either
 		neither do i  it's called scraping together
 	
 	
 		and
 		it's called what
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">scraping</ENAMEX> together
 	
 	
 		yeah in my case um i i turns out that i have a pretty good job <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">right now</TIMEX> but i grew up in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> that was fairly poor my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> was a college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> and a high school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> and we weren't really destitute but
 		we never really had a lot of money so i never really got in the habit of spending a lot of money
 		and so now
 		i just it turns out that i spend less than i make so i never really bother to keep a budget
 	
 	
 		well i
 		i
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> was
 		they were okay because i mean my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> uh he um was in the military and then he also had like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> other jobs so we lived comfortably i'd say but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um i pretty well i i get paid i work for the state um i get paid like once a month so i i kind of learn to to set aside a certain amount of money it you know that i could spend <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each week</TIMEX> for like lunch and all this other kind you know
 		expenses and pay the bills with the rest of it
 	
 	
 		so you don't keep actual records of what your expenses are and what your income what you income is and stuff
 	
 	
 		uh well i know what my income is but uh uh my but as far as keeping records i i i have a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a</TIMEX> ledger that will uh uh
 		how much i owe <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> whatever and i deduct it out of that
 	
 	
 		oh so you do keep track of it
 	
 	
 		yeah i i i keep i i keep track of it
 		uh i'm not exactly accurate of it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every month</TIMEX> i mean  but you know i keep up with it like once every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">other month</TIMEX> or so get it caught up
 	
 	
 		do you actually balance it at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the month</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh yeah
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		i'm not real good about uh keeping <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">track</ENAMEX> in checks and stuff like that but uh uh i always keep track of of the ledger who i pay and when and whatever and what the balance is
 	
 	
 		well i just started balancing my checkbook for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time in my life since i've had a checkbook and i'm i'm <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty two now</TIMEX> so
 		for i guess <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fourteen or fifteen years</TIMEX> i've had a checking account but i've never actually bothered to balance it i just always made sure there was enough of money in there
 		if i wrote out a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five hundred dollar</NUMEX> check i'd transfer <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five hundred dollars</NUMEX> in
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and i never actually checked to see if my balance matched the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX>'s and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX> i was well <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple months ago</TIMEX> i started thinking
 		you know i should really do that
 		and i had just learned learned how to use <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lotus</ENAMEX> on a PC
 		and uh with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lotus</ENAMEX> it was pretty easy to set up a a little checking program so i could so it'd keep the balance for me
 	
 	
 		well i work with uh i'm work with an an accounting uh section of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Corrections</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		in in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> so i i work with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lotus</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DataEase</ENAMEX> a lot so i i'm real familiar with that
 	
 	
 		so that comes second nature to you
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah my i still haven't balanced
 		i figure if i keep doing keep this up long enough eventually someday it'll balance and then at that point then i can try to keep it balanced
 	
 	
 		well i <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wachavia</ENAMEX> and they have this
 		system of of where you can call a number you can call and get all your checks and what your balance is and
 		and what checks is cleared <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that month</TIMEX> or whatever and i do that like maybe twice a month i check to see what you know what checks i've written and always write paid on it when it's paid so i get an idea
 		you know subtract what  what what i have in you know in the in my account and what i've i've written checks for that haven't been cleared or whatever so i keep up with it that way too
 	
 	
 		yeah well you spend more time on it than i do that's for sure
 	
 	
 		uh i wouldn't say that i just you know i just i just don't want to write bad checks
 	
 	
 		does your balance match balance match the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> at the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at the end of the month</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		um for the most part yeah i i i've got a real good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">banker</ENAMEX> uh personal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bankers</ENAMEX> i mean if if i do if i am ever overdrawn she always calls and tells me
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and tells me i need to get the money in or whatever so i say okay and i get it to her
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh i don't get that i just get a letter that says we just charged you ten dollars please take care of this
 	
 	
 		oh i wish i wish mine'd only charge me <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> dollars or here they charge eighteen
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighteen</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		oh so you get a personal call but you also get the charge
 	
 	
 		well not not all the time it's it's like uh this time i i i filed electronically my taxes and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i didn't have quite enough for my mortgage payment and um
 		i told her and i said i'm waiting for them to file that and they said if the mortgage payment you know check gets that before that and i said but it should be you know i it should be deposited before it hits but
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and it it didn't the mortgage check hit before but she told me that if it did not to worry about it that she would just uh she she wouldn't charge me she since i let her know a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of time that
 		i was waiting on that and whatever so but the the mortgage payment was due so
 	
 	
 		yeah you like to live on the edge i see
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well sometimes yeah
 		uh uh i believe in that philosophy of of praying that it don't hit the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> before the check does or deposit does
 		if i want something bad enough i i'll do it but normally i don't do that but in case it's something that's
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	