
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		hi um i'm <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralph</ENAMEX> um <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cincinnati Cincinnati</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hi Ralph</ENAMEX>
 		um uh the the machine said that the topic was uh taxes
 	
 	
 		yeah um weather we pay too much or uh maybe we got back what we
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> because we got i guess to die for what we paid
 	
 	
 		okay well i'm i'm ready anytime that you want to start
 	
 	
 		okay
 		um let's see i guess we got one
 		oh
 		
 
 		okay
 		um
 	
 	
 		oh yeah go head
 	
 	
 		well let's see i guess uh since i'm in the process of filling them out i guess i kind of fill like uh
 		um
 		it's it is too much but i don't know what i uh cut out i guess
 	
 	
 		no i i know what you mean we're in the process of doing ours and
 		it it it does seems  like a lot uh
 		i wish i had a better feeling for
 		uh a better breakdown rather than oh well you know <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">X X</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billions of dollars</NUMEX> go to defense and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">X</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billions of dollars</NUMEX> go here
 		it it it's hard i i have a hard time conceiving of any larger amount of money then say uh really a couple <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">thousand dollars</NUMEX> every thing else is
 		is like Monopoly money it it's so larger you don't really have a personal feeling for it if you go to by a new car
 		you get a better feeling for for what's going on but even then it usually most of that is is finance through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> and you not actually holding the money in your hands
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh
 		i
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> in general well
 		i i would like to see a little bit better return for the the social program i actually don't mind paying taxes for things like social programs helping <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> out
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		because my basic philosophy is that that most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are out to mess with the system most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> actually
 		generally want to work or want to to make themselves better and they are not lazy i don't believe that everybody is out there to rip of the system
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but there is a hold lot of bureaucracy and so many places for the money to fall through the cracks that
 		after a while it becomes to easy and and and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> uh
 		say well oh sure well we we haven't plan ahead so we could spend twice as much as as what we really need that's okay we will just let it go and
 		and then it comes down to the crunch and crisis management and oh well just spend <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">another few thousands dollars</NUMEX> and
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		so there there's no good handle on it no one i guess feels really responsible in those situation and all that money adds up and you have enormous cost in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> get angry and upset
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		that's interesting but uh i guess that's uh something that happen when there is so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> involved
 		each <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> fill like they
 		take a responsibility for
 		um
 		making sure that thing work the way there suppose to or something
 		but um i never really thought of it that way but
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		i guess there  seems like their some programs that are more valuable
 		and other that be
 		that be useful to have more uh
 		sort of tax <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">payer</ENAMEX> involvement in some of that decision making
 		
 
 	
 	
 		oh sure yeah i know i agree with you on that what  sort of a involvement with with something like maybe oh a defenses a little hard but
 		but what sort of involvement uh
 		would we be able to do what type of oversight would you like to see on that
 	
 	
 		
 
 		um
 		i know maybe just in the point of you know having focus <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> with uh or elected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX> will be one
 		solutions where they actually
 		maybe they do have more in some area of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> then then where i'm from but it's
 		i think it's rare to actually no
 		like you can influence what uh your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX> is really doing because if you know if even if there's even a lot of writing campaign chances are there'll be a lot of letters on both sides of the issue
 		particularly if if it is a controversial bill or something like that
 	
 	
 		huh yeah
 		well here it here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX> i mean we have a just like the rest of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> we have a a server budget problem and
 		and often here uh people
 		are are angry about their taxes being so high
 		and the ideal of the higher taxes is help us to pay off the high deficit in the state
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> fall back on well there's money there's a lot of money being misspent its all there we do have to do anything except well it's all out there somewhere
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and the the next step is to identify where
 		
 		
 	