
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">hello</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		this is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tad</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">hello Tad</ENAMEX> this is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glenn</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Portsmouth New Hampshire</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		ah
 		well i guess i had to wait <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time</TIMEX> till they found somebody
 	
 	
 		uh
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		how long were you hanging around for
 	
 	
 		oh i don't know quite a while i was about to go to sleep
 		
 
 		well you ready
 	
 	
 		well i'm glad you hung in there
 	
 	
 		okay you ready okay
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		
 
 		okay well um
 		provocative topic as usually
 	
 	
 		oh capital punishment definitely
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have very strong opinions about it
 		usually on both extremes though
 	
 	
 		yeah i uh well
 	
 	
 		what about yourself
 	
 	
 		i'm kind of um
 		waffling i don't know i i uh i don't really like the idea
 		but then occasionally i hear about a heinous crime where i think well if we're going to have public capital punishment then
 		you know this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> should definitely get it one thing that bugs me about it is the uh
 		finality of it i mean occasionally they make a mistake and send the wrong <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> to prison
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sometime later</TIMEX> they you know figure it out and they release him
 	
 	
 		um-hum well
 	
 	
 		and uh it bugs me that uh you know this is the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> kind of punishment that they definitely can't reverse
 	
 	
 		well i think there's got to be clauses as far as in capital punishment that
 		you can not execute anyone that there's not absolute positive identification
 		and
 		a lot of crimes you
 		uh that a a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> is convicted they rely on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s eye <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX> testimony
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		something like that i don't think would be substantial enough
 		uh you know somewhere where <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">twenty</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> saw watched <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person mowed</ENAMEX> gunned down you know <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> people
 		that's a clear case of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who should be executed
 		and i unfortunately that that is not the situation right now those kinds the punishment is not set up in most states
 		you know because as you stated earlier there are some crimes that's so barbaric
 		they uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> that perpetuates the crime deserves to be uh punished
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah i uh
 		course usually the case where there's a bunch of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> and they see <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> uh mow down a bunch of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and those cases the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> usually turns the gun on himself anyway
 	
 	
 		yeah but unfortunately not in all cases
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		that is really the sad part about it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh the case in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> uh shot the restaurant
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i guess it's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruby</ENAMEX>'s or someplace like that
 		he ended up killing himself but if he had survived
 		uh
 		by some chance i think it would have been criminal if our system had allowed him to live in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> for life
 	
 	
 		well but um
 		if uh if you don't execute sick people
 		um
 		for acting out their sickness
 		uh how by definition can you execute anybody who pulls off a crime like that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i mean since they're obviously insane
 	
 	
 		well i don't think they're necessarily insane
 	
 	
 		course i guess there's a definition of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">insanity</ENAMEX> of whether they or not they knew what they were doing that's a little different than what i'm talking about
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i i think some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> can
 		fool the system into believing that they're truly insane
 		it and i'm i even if they are insane yeah i'm sort i'm sort really sort of a hard core on this well uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dahmer</ENAMEX> as an example
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah there are probably <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seventeen or so</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> of his crimes
 		we're going to take care of him in prison
 		uh for an indefinite period of time you know mental <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> and so forth rehabilitation
 		and that's going to cost us a lot of money
 		and i don't really think that we should be doing something like that
 		you know whether he was uh whether he was ill or not
 		um the crimes were heinous
 		uh
 		yes it's uh it's a good example of where capital punishment would come in handy
 	
 	
 		yeah but uh it it
 		there's a case where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>'s obviously ill
 		i mean a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> that opens up <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s brains and performs lobotomies
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		amateur lobotomies i mean is obviously not rational
 	
 	
 		well then
 	
 	
 		i don't know i don't know whether you can you know morally take the power of the state
 		to end that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>'s life i i don't know i maybe that's a good reason to end his life
 		if  if he's that irrational
 	
 	
 		well it it i mean what what what would make him rational <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years</TIMEX> of rehabilitation
 		is it really worth spending all that time effort to rehabilitate someone who you may never ever be able to rehabilitate
 		and who it's questionable whether you should be rehabilitated them in rehabilitating them in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place
 	
 	
 		well yeah i don't know that there's any hope of rehabilitating him but the but then the question comes up does the does the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> have the right to do you know essentially the same what he did
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well i think the state you know it's one thing to torture someone
 		when you're ending their life
 		which uh was done in the ancient times it's another thing to
 		relatively relatively painlessly inject someone with with uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medication</ENAMEX> to
 		
 		
 	