
 
     		
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joan</ENAMEX> uh you live in a in a big <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">city Dallas</ENAMEX> huh what's i guess crime is is a problem there or a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> isn't it
 	
 	
 		
 
 		right
 		um-hum a big one it is and and uh getting out to the suburbs heavily
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		it is
 	
 	
 		yeah and i work in a high school here and we're just starting to see <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">high school</ENAMEX> in the suburbs and that's scary
 	
 	
 		uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		what do you think is uh
 	
 	
 		much different situation than we had even <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years ago</TIMEX> you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well you know we we i live in a uh in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> that's uh <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty five about twenty five thousand</TIMEX> and it's in the northeast and we really don't have a
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		a crime problem and we have the burglaries and the occasional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> robbery and things like that but nothing uh real serious nothing like a big <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> crime
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but from my observations it seems to me that uh that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> seem to be the engine driving crime in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> today what do you think
 	
 	
 		right i think it's the basis for every for it all really it's a big part of what our problem is and this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">gang</ENAMEX> situation which is which
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		the need for money
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		comes from you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> are involved in it but it the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">gang</ENAMEX> situation is very serious here also
 	
 	
 		uh-huh i guess that's serious in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> too in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> and some of the other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> there
 	
 	
 		right
 		right but even in our suburbs here and in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">our school</TIMEX> we're you know we're
 		it's not a noticeable down the hall thing you know yelling in our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">suburb</ENAMEX> but it's still is
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		enough that you know which one's you pretty well pick out which ones are in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">gang</ENAMEX> type
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		and are the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gangs</ENAMEX> uh selling are they in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enterprise</ENAMEX> are they selling <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> is that one of the reasons for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gangs</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well one one of it right but another thing is just territory you know they just want to
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> things
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		but <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> is a major is is the major i would say
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		problem of them all all of our crime you know the basis of it
 	
 	
 		right i think if somehow or other we can
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		continue to crack down on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> uh that i think it will help reduce the crime because the need for money and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and also the lack of judgement that comes from using <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> uh
 		you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i think have a diminished capacity to know right from wrong when they're using <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's true
 		that's true
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but um
 		we also have um
 		oh we have a lot of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">um counselors</ENAMEX> and all they've come up with so many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> that they didn't use to have to have you know as far as the counseling and coming up with the student <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups student</ENAMEX> help groups
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and um
 		of course the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">the</ENAMEX> say no to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> and this and um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Students Against Drunk Driving</ENAMEX> is very big in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">our school</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's big up here to and and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SADD</ENAMEX> which is very big
 	
 	
 		right
 		right and i think that's an effective program
 	
 	
 		i do but uh us all that basis that they start but i i think they're probably finally
 		uh realizing that they have to start in the primary grades
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		training these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and i some of the programs you see on the TV i haven't seen a whole lot of them in our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> here
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but um some of the programs that they're showing in the primary where they're starting out right in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first second</NUMEX> kindergarten grades
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		having the um
 		plays you know plays the whole thing role playing
 	
 	
 		
 
 		teaching the dangers of it uh-huh
 	
 	
 		um-hum but they off <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> i think it's a good situation
 	
 	
 		yeah i think that's that's true i think
 	
 	
 		and i think it's going to have to start there because it's not working you know it overall it's such a large payola and all in the actual when it when it gets up to the
 		older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and the um law enforcement and all that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i think that's being paid off big time
 	
 	
 		do you have a program called DARE down there also right well that's that's uh active up here
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right but that's all recent you know that's all been in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last three about four years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that they've come in with all of those
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and had to so and and the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> is a big there another big you know well the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> is part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> but i mean <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> is also a major problem  these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> that are you know
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tenth graders</ENAMEX> come into school all all ready loaded that's pretty scary
 	
 	
 		sure is you find that uh do you find is it your observation that most of the crime is in a certain age group
 		certain range of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ages twenty five</TIMEX> something like or
 	
 	
 		um
 		yeah not not really necessarily no not necessarily anymore yes it used to be
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		but anymore you'd find a lot of the younger <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">thirteen</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fourteen</TIMEX> in that age group
 	
 	
 		oh is that right um
 	
 	
 		is um starting heavily into it
 	
 	
 		how about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">gang</ENAMEX> membership that seems to be mainly teenagers
 	
 	
 		caliber
 		and that's mainly uh so far
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's pretty well into the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teenagers</ENAMEX> you know in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teenagers</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they usually start that around junior
 		
 		
 	