
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John um</ENAMEX>
 		what things in your life do you find to be invasion of privacy
 	
 	
 		oh uh lots of things <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">salesman</ENAMEX> uh
 		keeping records of everything that's sadistic on me i consider that to be an invasion of privacy privacy and i find that it's
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i guess not not to the extreme of wanting to to to drop out of society and not have credit cards and not have
 		uh you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> or credit credit cards or anything uh uh i deal with it but i do considered that it has it's uh potential
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		negative side
 		with a
 	
 	
 		um
 		i was thinking about it you know when i was waiting waiting to talk to you and i couldn't think of any any real um
 		anything that really bothered me in everyday life um although the thing you mention probably or probably everything about them probably would be true but um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> of things though that i did think of there where um
 		a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of you you your live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgia</ENAMEX> also so um  you know how what if you if you if you get pull over to get and you get a ticket
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the um
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cop</ENAMEX> will staple your the ticket to your license so you know when you go to court you will be able to get your license back um  someone point it out to me you know that
 		a lot of cops when they pull you over will
 		seal
 		your um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">driver</ENAMEX> license
 		to fill how many how many um staple holes are in it
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yeah you know usually you know and and well you know
 	
 	
 		that's how they give you a ticket or not give you a ticket
 	
 	
 		yeah they say you know you know how weather weather weather weather you you you've been sited how you know that many time or not you know and someone pointed it out to me that you know yeah that that is really an invasion of privacy in that you know you weren't necessarily convicted for any of those offenses you know
 	
 	
 		um-hum well you know that uh
 		for all we know we don't know what's on what's on their data base before all we know when actually call uh call in to check on us uh there may be a little print out says that uh arrested <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> times convicted none
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i mean there maybe maybe that kind of detail involved  he may be called upon it may uh the next
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true
 	
 	
 		the next move is to have terminals in their in their uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well i think some <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> actually have them
 	
 	
 		i know well i'm just saying uh universal
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i mean that
 		that and and i well i in fact actually i consider radar detection to be sort of an invasion  i think that that uh we have uh entirely to much uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		regulation i think that
 		if you take the old philosophy of you know when you when you catch him you convict him that's a healthy philosophy then well we know that you are going to do it so were going to watch you all the time
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		um-hum yeah that presume guilt really bothers me
 	
 	
 		well the thing is that even though  even though i will probably do that even though i am guilty uh if someone uses uh uh human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">judgement</ENAMEX> instead of just making the rules they find out that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i don't
 		put any risk
 		to other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in certainly not any any risk comparable to
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh let's say granny out on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> driving forty <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> and pulling into my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lane</ENAMEX> when i'm beside her
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 		i could drive <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred and ten</NUMEX> and be safer than most of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunday</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX> on their
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i mean i mean <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred and ten</NUMEX> relative to everybody driving fifty <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> that's how that's how bad of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX> are out there now that have license
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's the other  uh problem of privacy i i i think uh i think that uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s intend uh tend to have to much
 		uh they want to know to much about you
 		and i really think they are only right
 		is
 		weather or not i do my job
 	
 	
 		yeah um  you know i i'm i'm about to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduate</ENAMEX> and i'm still trying look for a job
 		and you know it really offends me you know that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> are drug testing you know not that i have any thing to worry about but just
 		the actual invasion of my privacy you know and that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i mean it seam like they don't they don't want want you know hire me they want to own me
 	
 	
 		that yeah that that has been the present philosophy
 	
 	
 		i mean
 	
 	
 		uh i think something that kind of bother me that this is not a privacy i don't think this is a privacy issue but i'm not sure
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh i don't like morals uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s uh
 		i guess i should call it <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southern Baptist</ENAMEX> morals
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		that determine whether or not someone can go to a club
 		weather it it not that it's legal or not legal anymore now its
 		uh
 		and i i give the the example is news <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX> says that they just
 		regulated by not allowing them
 		
 		
 	