









the look of architecture






one
dressing up


Architecture is hard to define. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goethe</ENAMEX> called it music frozen in space, which, while it captures a sense of rhythm, is too one-dimensional. And it relegates the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> of the arts to an inferior position; just as well to describe music as melted architecture. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nietzsche</ENAMEX> believed that architecture reflected his pride, man‚Äôs triumph over gravity, and his will to power. This notion applies to many <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>, from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gothic</ENAMEX> cathedrals to skyscrapers, but it is too, well, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nietzschean</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edwin Lutyens</ENAMEX> referred to architecture as a sort of play: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>ÄúIn architecture, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palladio</ENAMEX> is the game!‚Äù Le <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Corbusier</ENAMEX> described his art as <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">‚Äúthe masterly</ENAMEX>, correct and magnificent play of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masses</ENAMEX> brought together in light,‚Äù which is a good description of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of his own <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>. I am partial to Sir <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Wotton‚</ENAMEX>Äôs definition. Wotton, who lived a long time in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Venice</ENAMEX> and was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lover</ENAMEX> of architecture though not an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX>, published a treatise on the subject in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1642</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚ÄúIn Architecture</ENAMEX>, as in all other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Operative Arts</ENAMEX>, the end must direct the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Operation</ENAMEX>,‚Äù he wrote. ‚ÄúThe end is to build <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">well</ENAMEX>. Well-building hath <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> conditions: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commoditie, Firmeness</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Delight</ENAMEX>.‚Äù
Sir <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry‚</ENAMEX>Äôs description, which was based on the writings of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Roman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vitruvius</ENAMEX>, appeals to me because it emphasizes the complexity of the building art. To begin with, architecture has not one but <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> distinct purposes: to shelter human activity (commodity), to durably challenge gravity and the elements (firmness), and to be an object of beauty (delight). Architecture is always a synthesis of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>. However, the fulfillment of one purpose does not guarantee the satisfaction of the others. There are homely sturdy <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> and beautiful flimsy ones. A well-planned <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> can be ugly just as a beautiful <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> can function poorly. Form does not, contrary to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louis Sullivan‚</ENAMEX>Äôs hoary maxim, follow function.
Not only are function and form separate, over their long lives <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> can successfully accommodate a variety of uses. For example, some of the most famous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museums</ENAMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Louvre</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hermitage</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Belvedere</ENAMEX>) started life as royal <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palaces</ENAMEX>; the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Uffizi</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florence</ENAMEX> is so named because it originally housed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX>; and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prado</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Madrid</ENAMEX> was designed to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> of science, not art. The acclaimed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mus√</ENAMEX>©e d‚ÄôOrsay in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> is housed in a railroad <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> of my favorite small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museums</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Frick Collection</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Phillips</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Collection</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>, were built as <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">residences</ENAMEX>. As historic preservation and adaptive reuse demonstrate, you can shop in a renovated <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">warehouse</ENAMEX>, do office work in a converted <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">loft</ENAMEX>, or live in a barn. Assuming, of course, that the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">warehouse</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">loft</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">barn</ENAMEX> were well built. The material fabric of old buildings‚Äîthe heavy beams, rough brick walls, and solid woodwork‚Äîis one of their chief pleasures. That is why we feel cheated by hollow walls, flimsy doors, and shaky balustrades. <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Buildings</ENAMEX> should last and feel as though they will.
One might assume that just as the highest-rated cars‚ÄîMercedes-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Benz</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMW</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lexus‚</ENAMEX>Äîrepresent the highest standards of automobile technology, the most admired architecture would be the best built. This was generally true in the past, but in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the twentieth century</TIMEX>, when new materials and new aesthetic theories often have driven <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architects</ENAMEX> to cavalier experimentation, even celebrated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architects</ENAMEX> have fallen short in that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Le Corbusier‚</ENAMEX>Äôs white suburban villas, for example, were crudely finished in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cement plaster</ENAMEX> on top of brick, and since the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX> usually ignored (for aesthetic reasons) intrusive metal flashing and coping strips, the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">crude ‚Äúmachines</ENAMEX> for living‚Äù often aged poorly. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Lloyd Wright</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> have leaky skylights, sagging <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">overhangs</ENAMEX>, and defective heating systems. This does not make them any less delightful to visit, but it must make them considerably less delightful to inhabit. Perhaps the most dramatic example of failed experimentation in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Centre Georges Pompidou</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>, which opened in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1977</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> was widely praised for its architectural <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">innovation‚</ENAMEX>Äîthe <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> periodical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Architectural Design</ENAMEX> called it ‚Äúa seminal building of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Modern Movement</ENAMEX>.‚Äù The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architects</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Renzo Piano</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Rogers</ENAMEX> turned the building literally inside-out. They dramatically hung pipes, ducts, fire stairs, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">elevators</ENAMEX>, and escalators from the exterior structure. These previously hidden <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elements</ENAMEX> were now exposed in plain sight‚Äîand exposed to the elements. The result might have been foreseen: after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only twenty years</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> was obliged to close the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a two-year</TIMEX> renovation. Although the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> maintained that the renovation was required because of the unexpectedly large number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX>, according to Le Monde <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">almost half</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$90 million</NUMEX> budget was spent on refurbishing the fa√ßade.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Pennsylvania</ENAMEX>, where I teach, is the site of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Louis I. Kahn‚Äôs A. N. Richards Medical Research Laboratory</ENAMEX>. This structural tour-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">de</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">precast concrete</ENAMEX> and brick brought its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designer</ENAMEX> international acclaim. I remember traveling from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Montreal</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> to see the building <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years</TIMEX> after it was built. My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classmates</ENAMEX> and I particularly admired the exposed concrete structure and the explicit separation of what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kahn</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">‚Äúservant‚Äù and ‚Äúserved‚Äù</ENAMEX> spaces‚Äîmassive brick ventilation shafts and delicate, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glass</ENAMEX>-enclosed individual <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">laboratories</ENAMEX>. However, The latter proved to be unpopular with their occupants. The large windows let in too much light (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, most are papered over with aluminum foil), cement dust from the exposed concrete beams falls on the lab tables, and the rigid plan has proved inflexible to changing needs.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Richards Laboratory</ENAMEX> was built <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only 35 years ago</TIMEX>. It is next to a student <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dormitory</ENAMEX> known as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quad</ENAMEX>, a picturesque <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Jacobean Revival</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> planned around a series of courtyards. This handsome <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> has been doing yeoman service for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">almost a century</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quad</ENAMEX> was designed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter Cope</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Stewardson</ENAMEX>, whose work at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Pennsylvania</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Princeton</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bryn Mawr</ENAMEX> was largely responsible for the popularity of so-called Collegiate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gothic</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pleasing</ENAMEX>, well-loved‚Äîand well-built‚Äîthe <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quad</ENAMEX> is architecture of the highest order. Yet my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classmates</ENAMEX> and I did not pay any attention to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dormitory</ENAMEX> when we visited <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX>. We had never heard of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cope & Stewardson</ENAMEX>, despite their achievements and wide cultural influence. The architecture <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historians</ENAMEX> whom we studied‚ÄîSiegfried <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Giedion, Nikolaus Pevsner</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Marston Fitch‚</ENAMEX>Äîfavored <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">innovators</ENAMEX> and experimenters, even if the innovations and experiments often failed. Put another way, most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historians</ENAMEX> of modern architecture gave precedence to Delight over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Commoditie</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Firmeness</ENAMEX>. This may be because the appearance of a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> was easier to assess (especially at a distance) than either its functional performance or material durability. Or maybe they were attracted chiefly to the aesthetic qualities of architecture. In any case, ‚Äúimaginative, inventive, and revolutionary‚Äù were more likely accolades to be showered on important <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> than ‚Äúaccommodating, dependable, and sound.‚Äù
This is not to say that good architecture is merely utilitarian. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the grandest spaces in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX> is the concourse of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Thirtieth Street Station</ENAMEX>, which was built in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1934</TIMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pennsylvania Railroad</ENAMEX> by the accomplished <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architects</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Graham</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anderson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Probst & White</ENAMEX>, the successor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel H. Burnham</ENAMEX>. The magnificent <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">290 feet</NUMEX> long and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">almost 100 feet</NUMEX> high, is covered by a flat coffered ceiling decorated in red, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cream</ENAMEX>. Diffused light streams in from tall windows on both sides. Almost nothing in this memorable space‚Äîthe gilded <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Art Deco</ENAMEX> chandeliers, the travertine walls, the massive Corinthian columns at each end‚Äîwas a product of its rather mundane function: to provide a waiting space for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, before they descended the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">staircases</ENAMEX> that led to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">platforms</ENAMEX> below. But the railroad <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX> concourse in the heyday of railroad travel, was more than merely a place to get on and off <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trains</ENAMEX>. It was a gateway to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, as well as a symbol of unreserved faith in modern transportation‚Äîand in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pennsylvania Railroad</ENAMEX>. That is why it was appropriate for delight to take precedence over commodity.
Yet delight is not uniform. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Main Concourse</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grand Central Terminal</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>, for example, offers different pleasures than <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Thirtieth Street Station</ENAMEX>. The monumental spaces are comparable in size and function. They are both well built. Similar spaces, similar materials, yet the experience of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concourses</ENAMEX> is different. Both <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> are inspired by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Classical</ENAMEX> architecture of the past, but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grand Central</ENAMEX>, which opened in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1913</TIMEX>, is a modified version of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beaux-Arts Classicism</ENAMEX>, whereas the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX>, despite the Corinthian columns, is simplified, abstracted, and stylized, what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historians</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">‚Äústripped Classicism</ENAMEX>.‚Äù As a result, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grand Central</ENAMEX> is dramatic, visually rich in its details, almost <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wagnerian</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Thirtieth Street</ENAMEX> is equally dramatic but in a way that is coolly geometrical and sleekly urbane‚Äînot <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wagner</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cole Porter</ENAMEX>. Style is evident in the smallest details. It ensures a continuity between the great vaulted sky of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grand Central</ENAMEX> and the ticket counters, or between the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Thirtieth Street</ENAMEX> chandeliers and the announcement <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX> at each track stair. It is the visual language of a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>. Architectural style is the manner in which the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX> communicates a particular kind of visual delight, in large ways and small.
Commodity, firmness, and delight are never evenly weighted. Sometimes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> predominates, sometimes the other. Sometimes a waiting room needs to be a triumphal celebration of arrival and departure‚Äîsometimes it is just a waiting <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>. Sometimes it is necessary to compromise structural simplicity to achieve an esthetic effect. Sometimes functional requirements override other considerations; a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">laboratory</ENAMEX> that does not serve its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> is a failed work of architecture, no matter how beautiful its design. A banal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> is a greater failure than a banal <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factory</ENAMEX>. The art of building requires judiciously balancing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wotton‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> conditions.
The end must direct the operation. That is what distinguishes architecture from the fine arts of painting and sculpture ‚ÄúAn <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> can paint <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">square</ENAMEX> wheels,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù Paul Klee</ENAMEX> once observed, ‚Äúbut an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX> must make them round.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚Äù Architecture</ENAMEX>, in this respect, is no different than other <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">‚Äúoperative arts‚Äù</ENAMEX> such as cooking. The creativity of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chef</ENAMEX> is likewise circumscribed by factors outside his control‚Äîthe natural <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ingredients</ENAMEX>, the human palate, the chemistry of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">foods</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dish</ENAMEX> must be at once nourishing (commodity), cookable (firmness), and, of course, tasty (delight). (It should also look good, although the contemporary trend toward visually extravagant dishes seems to me an aberration). The art of cooking, like the art of architecture, lies in knowing how to establish the appropriate relations between the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> conditions.

The experience of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> is sensual. It is also first-hand. That is, while it‚Äôs fun to read recipes and look at photographs of table settings in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gourmet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>, no one I know considers this a substitute for eating. The experience of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> is sensual, too. Yet, many of us get our <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> glimpses of buildings‚Äîparticularly celebrated buildings‚Äîas images in books, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>, public lectures, and exhibitions. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the most famous <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Modern</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">movement</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ludwig Mies van</ENAMEX> der <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Rohe‚Äôs Barcelona Pavilion</ENAMEX>, was known almost entirely through photographs since it was built for an exhibition that lasted <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">only</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven months</TIMEX>. Before photography, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paimio Tubercolosis Sanatorium</ENAMEX>, located in a remote part of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Finland</ENAMEX>, would have remained obscure; as it was, its stunning images brought the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alvar Aalto</ENAMEX> worldwide recognition. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sydney Opera House</ENAMEX> is another world-famous <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> that, at least outside <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX>, relatively few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have seen first-hand. Yet photography tells us very little about how a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> fulfills its function, or about how it is built. For example, the handrails in the often-photographed stairway of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paimio</ENAMEX> sanatorium look like standard <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Style</ENAMEX> metal pipes. In fact they are wood‚Äîmuch more pleasant to the touch‚Äîpainted to look like <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">metal</ENAMEX>. Well-known photographs of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Barcelona Pavilion</ENAMEX> show <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> free-standing columns supporting a flat slab, and free-standing marble screens that carry no loads, a prototypical <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">International Style</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX>. In reality, there are columns concealed within the screens, which are not slabs of marble but thin marble sheets attached to a masonry back-up wall. In other words, this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1929</TIMEX> building is an example of traditional layered construction, not of modernistic structural purism<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.1</NUMEX>
In photographs, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> are forever young. The ravages of time, weather, and use are banished. It is a shock to come across a revered architectural icon and to find the concrete stained, the painted window frames chipped, the tiles cracked. Of course, all <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> age, but some age more gracefully than others. A <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">450-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palladio villa</ENAMEX> retains its beauty, despite peeling <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">plaster</ENAMEX> and mossy stonework (perhaps it even looks more enchanting). Most modern <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>, on the other hand, lose their potency if they are not gleaming and machinelike.
Obviously, photography highlights the visual qualities of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> and ignores commodity and firmness. Yet photography cannot completely communicate delight. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitor</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seagram Building</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, for example, is surprised to discover the subtle relationship between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mies‚</ENAMEX>Äô bronze <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tower</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Renaissance</ENAMEX> fa√ßade of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McKim</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mead & White‚Äôs Racquet and Tennis Club</ENAMEX> on the other side of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Park Avenue</ENAMEX>. Equally deceptive are photographs of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Lloyd Wright‚</ENAMEX>Äôs work in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oak Park</ENAMEX>, since they give no hint of the comfortable suburban surroundings of his so-called prairie <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX>. As I student, I studied the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Le Corbusier</ENAMEX> in black and white photographs, which did not prepare me for the shock of experiencing his often wildly polychrome interiors. Nor can photography communicate movement, which is such an integral part of the architectural experience (film is better at this, but not much). Nothing conveys the actual experience of a building like the real thing. To paraphrase <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Hughes</ENAMEX>, a photograph of architecture is to architecture as telephone sex is to sex.
Never is modern architectural photography more misleading than in its portrayal of domestic interiors. Interiors are usually photographed empty or with minimal furnishings, before the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> have had the opportunity to move in and (presumably) defile the purity of the design. But even if the space is occupied, strict conventions prevail: furniture must be lined up just so; there must be no distractions, no half-empty <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tea</ENAMEX> cups, no crumpled <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>, no abandoned children‚Äôs toys. Books on shelves are arranged to create interesting patterns, personal mementos are temporarily banished‚Äîeverything must be neat. I once observed a photographer‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assistant</ENAMEX> during a photo shoot comb out the fringe of a rug. Such primping and visual editing sets off the architecture to best advantage. It also‚Äînot coincidentally‚Äîgives the impression that the designed interior is autonomous and self-contained: in other words, that it is a work of art. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Markedly</ENAMEX>, these photographs never include human <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figures</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> would be the greatest distraction of all.
The world of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> depicted in books and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> is a scaleless, self-sufficient place. The absence of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in architectural photographs has several effects. In the past, the proportions and dimensions of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> were based on the human body. While this was done for philosophical reasons, it also ensured a direct relationship between architecture and people‚Äîit is why even very large <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Classical</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> feel comfortable. By removing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>, architectural photography makes it possible to regard architecture as an abstraction, unrelated to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX>. It is not merely that the conventions of modern architectural photography ideally communicate the intentions of most modern <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architects</ENAMEX>, it is also that they validate those intentions. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX>? Who needs them?
While I was writing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Home</ENAMEX>, I discovered that the most useful historical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> for information about how <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> furnished and decorated their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> were often paintings. Not paintings in which the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> was the subject, but portraits and domestic genre scenes. An example of the latter is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Tissot‚Äôs</ENAMEX>, ‚ÄúHide and Seek,‚Äù which shows <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> at play in a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Victorian</ENAMEX> sitting <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>. The d√©cor is exotic, an eclectic mixture of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Persian</ENAMEX> rugs, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">porcelain pots</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">tiger</ENAMEX>-skins and others furs scattered over the furniture.
Tissot was a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">painter</ENAMEX> who settled in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1871</TIMEX>. An easel in the corner suggests that this is his own <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, in which case, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> sunk deep into an easy chair, reading a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> may be his <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mistress</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Singer Sargent‚</ENAMEX>Äôs masterpiece, ‚ÄúThe <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Daughters</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward Darley Boit</ENAMEX>,‚Äù painted in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1882</TIMEX>, likewise shows <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry James</ENAMEX> described it as ‚Äúthe happy play-world of a family of charming <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>,‚Äù but the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> can hardly be said to be playing. Properly dressed in white pinafores, black socks, and patent leather shoes, they form a motionless tableau. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>, in an <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>, is stylishly bare, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">unadorned</ENAMEX> except for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> immense <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> vases and a red screen. The mood is entirely different in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Swedish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">painter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carl Larsson‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">playful ‚ÄúMother‚Äôs</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Cherubs‚Äô Room</ENAMEX>,‚Äù which was included in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Larsson‚</ENAMEX>Äôs famous book <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ett Hem</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">At Home</ENAMEX>), published in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1899</TIMEX>. The walls of his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wife‚Äôs bedroom</ENAMEX> are wooden <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX>, whitewashed and decorated with a painted frieze of ribboned garlands; the ceiling, likewise <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wood</ENAMEX>, is painted green with red trim. The simple furniture is also painted in bright colors. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Karin Larsson‚Äôs</ENAMEX> bed is separated from the children‚Äôs cots by a striped woven curtain. We see <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Larsson</ENAMEX> girls in various stages of dress‚Äîand undress. That is appropriate, too, for naturalism and artlessness permeate this charming scene.
Such paintings are more faithful depictions of domestic surroundings than modern architectural photographs. For <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> thing, they are full of the signs of everyday life. A coat is thrown casually over a chair, there are crumbs on the table, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tissot‚</ENAMEX>Äôs little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> playing on the floor rumples the carpet. Moreover, in these interiors the architecture is in the background. It is a setting for human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">activity‚</ENAMEX>Äîjust as it is in real life. Paintings also convey something about the atmosphere of the interior. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX> seventeenth<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-century</TIMEX> domestic paintings, for example, exude a prosperous air of bourgeois comfort and propriety. A <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">hundred years later</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fran√ßois Boucher</ENAMEX> painted a middle-class <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> gathering for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> coffee in a little room with japanned woodwork and gilded moldings. There is a sweet intimacy here that is absent in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX> interiors. An interior of the same period by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Walton</ENAMEX> shows an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> gentleman at breakfast. He is sitting in a relaxed posture, wearing a riding-coat and boots, accompanied by his <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX>. The ambience is one of informal and relaxed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> life.
As I studied such paintings, I started to see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX> between the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inhabitants</ENAMEX>. The legs of the mahogany furniture in an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> country <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> were as straight and unadorned as their owners‚Äô riding boots. The arabesques and curlicues of the moldings and architectural ornaments in a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">salon</ENAMEX> mirrored the flouncing ribbons that adorned the women‚Äôs dresses and the frills of the men‚Äôs shirts. The proper black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">broadcloth</ENAMEX> and white lace collars of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> echoed the spotless black-and-white checkerboard marble <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">floors</ENAMEX>. I became convinced that a strong connection exists between the way that we decorate our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> and the way that we dress ourselves.
There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> distinct reasons for the intimate relationship between dress and d√©cor. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> is technical. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D√©cor</ENAMEX>, like dress, incorporates fabrics. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Curtains</ENAMEX>, swags, and window-treatments are made of silk, damask, satin, brocade, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wool</ENAMEX>, muslin, and velvet‚Äîso is clothing. Woven materials are used in tapestries, wall-hangings, carpets and upholstery as well as coats and skirts. Inevitably, the dressmaker‚Äôs techniques of embroidering, gathering, pleating, and trimming find their way into d√©cor. This is why furniture skirts recall women‚Äôs skirts, and why the fringes, cords, and bobbins of nineteenth<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-century</TIMEX> drapery recall ladies‚Äô ballgowns. The delicate lace curtains and the billowing baldachin over a bed in a ladies‚Äô boudoir matched the clothes in her dressing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>.
The connection between d√©cor and dress can be even more intimate, for architecture sometimes directly mimics dress. The garlands in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eighteenth-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> are sculpted or painted versions of the sashes and flowered ornaments worn by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>. The ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greeks</ENAMEX> incorporated elements of dress in temple architecture. This is most apparent in colonnades, which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vincent Scully</ENAMEX> has likened to hoplites massed in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">phalanx</ENAMEX>.2 There is no doubt that Classical columns were given human attributes. Ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> likened the vertical flutes to the folds in a chiton, or tunic<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.3</NUMEX> Columns have capitals‚Äîthat is, heads. The moldings of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Doric</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capitals</ENAMEX> were sometimes painted to resemble headbands; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ionic</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Corinthian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capitals</ENAMEX> incorporated carved head garlands, and the curving tendrils of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Corinthian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capitals</ENAMEX> often look more like <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hair</ENAMEX> than foliage. Indeed, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vitruvius</ENAMEX> considered the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Corinthian order ‚Äúfeminine,‚</ENAMEX>Äù as opposed to the sturdy masculine <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Doric</ENAMEX>. Sir <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Wotton</ENAMEX> went so far as to call the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Corinthian order ‚Äúlascivious‚Äù and ‚</ENAMEX>Äúdecked like a wanton <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">courtesan</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">‚Äù4</ENAMEX>
The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> connection between dress and d√©cor is social. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1890s</TIMEX>, the famous <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alfred Marshall</ENAMEX> observed that as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> earned more money, they wanted better food, better clothes and larger homes‚Äîboth for social standing and comfort. Since <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> and clothes are timeworn ways in which to convey status, there is a conformity in the types of materials and symbols used to convey social standing. If family coats of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX> are displayed, they will be seen on wall medallions as well as on blazer buttons. If gold is treasured, the wealthy will wear gold braid and surround themselves with gilt moldings. If this is considered too flashy, other materials can convey status: stainless steel <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen</ENAMEX> appliances and stainless <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">steel</ENAMEX> watch bracelets. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Diamonds</ENAMEX> may be forever, but fashions change. Today, leather is considered a luxury material, and is used both for expensive clothing and expensive sofas. A <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">hundred years ago</TIMEX>, leather was considered utilitarian; <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">leather aprons</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vests</ENAMEX> were worn only by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workmen</ENAMEX>, and leather easy chairs were only found in smoking <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> and men‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clubs</ENAMEX> since <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">leather</ENAMEX> was less flammable than <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fabric</ENAMEX>. But it was never used in salons or drawing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX>. When corduroy, originally used only in workingmen‚Äôs dress, became accepted by the middle class, it also showed up as upholstery. The current fashion for <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúnatural‚Äù dress fabrics‚Äîcotton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wool</ENAMEX>, linen‚Äîhas a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counterpart</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">‚Äúnatural‚Äù d√©cor</ENAMEX>: exposed brick, oiled <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wood</ENAMEX>, polished concrete.
In a more general sense‚Äîand this has nothing to do with conspicuous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumption‚</ENAMEX>Äîboth <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> and clothes convey values. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carl Larsson‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> was a statement of both his and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Karin‚</ENAMEX>Äôs naturalistic aesthetic ideals, so was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Tissot‚</ENAMEX>Äôs exotic sitting <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>. Whether or not we are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX>, our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX>, like our clothes, communicate who we are, or at least how we wish others to perceive us: starchly formal or comfortably casual, intensely <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">avant-garde</ENAMEX> or resolutely traditional, bohemian or conservative, cosmopolitan or down-home. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Che Guevara</ENAMEX> poster on the wall and the embroidered denim jacket convey <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> set of values; Colonial break-fronts and penny loafers, another. That is why it is disconcerting if dress and d√©cor are not in harmony. Sweat shirts and running shoes in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louis Quinze</ENAMEX> drawing room send a decidedly mixed message, as does a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>-piece suit on the deck of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malibu</ENAMEX> beach <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bungalow</ENAMEX>.
The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> connection between dress and d√©cor concerns perception. Architecture, interior decoration, and fashion design are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> distinct fields, yet we experience them with the same eye. Whether we look at dress or d√©cor, we bring the same visual bias, the same sensibility, the same taste. This sensibility is not constant. Sometimes we appreciate simplicity, sometimes complexity. Fashionable seventeenth<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> eyes, for example, favored floral decorations and embroidery, and introduced the custom of having vases of fresh <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>. English eyes in the midst of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Neoclassic</ENAMEX> revival sought fundamental simplicity and sobriety in men‚Äôs clothes as well as in architecture. Victorian eyes fancied dense patterns that were likely to show up in waistcoats and on wainscotting. Parisian eyes, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 1900s</TIMEX>, admired the same neo-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Empire</ENAMEX> motifs in dress and d√©cor.*
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Early twentieth-century</TIMEX> eyes had their own particular sensibility. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the great interiors of this period is the main living space of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tugendhat House</ENAMEX>, designed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mies Van der Rohe</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1928</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> stands outside <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brno</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Czechoslovakia</ENAMEX>. The exterior is a low-key <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Style</ENAMEX> white box, but the interior is astonishing. The public <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> are contained in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> large open space. A curved wall of macassar <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">ebony</ENAMEX> defines the dining <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>, and a straight free-standing wall of onyx dor√©e separates the music <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> from the living <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>. The space is punctuated by slender cruciform columns covered in chromed metal. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">east</ENAMEX> and south walls are floor-to-ceiling glass‚Äîa precursor of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mies‚</ENAMEX>Äô famous glass <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>. The sense of openness is heightened when, at the touch of a button, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">fifteen-foot</NUMEX> sections of the glass wall sink into the ground.
I have never seen the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tugendhat House</ENAMEX>, except in a handful of black-and-white photographs (the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> was severely damaged during the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War</ENAMEX>). This is another case where photographs are a poor substitute. They do not convey the rich <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">textures</ENAMEX> of the raw silk and velvet draperies, nor the vivid colors of the upholstery: emerald green leather and ruby-red velvet. Nor do they capture the sumptuous range of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">materials</ENAMEX>: onyx, pearwood, handwoven <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wool</ENAMEX>, chromed metal and (surprisingly) a linoleum floor. Since the surviving photographs do not show any human <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figures</ENAMEX>, they heighten the impression that the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> was built <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, especially as the furniture, designed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX>, is still in production.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mies van der Rohe</ENAMEX> appears in a photograph taken in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1926</TIMEX>. The place is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Stuttgart</ENAMEX>, the site of the famous <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Weissenhof</ENAMEX> housing exhibition, which he planned, and where he brought together the leading exponents of the soon-to-be-christened <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Style</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of these was Le <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Corbusier</ENAMEX>, who is also in the photograph. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> firebrands, who will soon set the architectural world on its ear, are deep in conversation. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Le Corbusier</ENAMEX> smokes a pipe and sports a jaunty derby and a loose, short tweed coat. Mies, looking older than his <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">forty</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, wears a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Homburg</ENAMEX>, a long dark ulster, and spats. This photograph puts the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tugendhat House</ENAMEX> in context. However ‚Äúmodern‚Äù the airy <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> appears to my eyes, it contained a considered and formal way of life that is as remote from me as waxed moustaches, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Homburgs</ENAMEX>, and spats. It is in that context that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mies‚</ENAMEX>Äô curious combination of ordered simplicity and sybaritic luxury must be understood.
Nothing could be less similar to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tugendhat House</ENAMEX> than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Moore‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekend</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> that he built for himself in the hills above <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Berkeley</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>. I saw it in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer of 1964</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> after it was built. While the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tugendhat House</ENAMEX> appears sexy and glamorous, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moore</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> is at <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> glance downright rustic, a little <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">barn</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">twenty-six feet square</NUMEX>, capped by a saddle roof. It is an elegant little <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">barn</ENAMEX>, however, with white-painted walls and large windows that open up the corners, not by disappearing into the ground but by sliding sideways like barn doors. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-room interior contains a grand piano and a sunken bath that looks vaguely <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roman</ENAMEX>, perhaps because the skylight above it is supported by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> solid fir Tuscan columns (found by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moore</ENAMEX> at a demolition site). <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Four</NUMEX> similar columns support a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> skylight over a sitting area.
I admire the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tugendhat House</ENAMEX>, but I could not imagine living in it. That is, I could not imagine having to dress up sufficiently to feel at home. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moore</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, on the other hand, reflects a more compliant sensibility. Its floor-to-ceiling windows, spare detailing, and open interior mark it as a successor to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Style</ENAMEX>. Yet the shingled roof and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tuscan</ENAMEX> columns hearken back to older traditions. The little building manages to be comfortable, relaxed, archetypal, and vaguely ironic, all at the same time. The eclectic, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Californian</ENAMEX> setting is both informal and formal. Put another way, it is a place where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who wear tweed jackets with jeans, or silk skirts with canvas espadrilles would fit right in.
The little <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moore</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">barn</ENAMEX> is an historic <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>. Together with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Venturi‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanna Venturi House</ENAMEX>, which was designed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the same year</TIMEX>, it marks the advent of an architectural style that became known as Postmodernism<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.5 One</NUMEX> of the celebrated <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postmodernism</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Stirling‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Neue Staatsgalerie</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Stuttgart</ENAMEX>, which was completed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1984</TIMEX>. Stirling vastly expands <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moore‚</ENAMEX>Äôs eclecticism, combining a bewildering mixture of forms; a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Doric</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">portico</ENAMEX>, a staid neoclassical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wing</ENAMEX> that matches the existing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Egyptian</ENAMEX>-looking curved cornice, a colorful <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> Constructivist entrance canopy, a curving steel-and-glass <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wall</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> huge blue ventilator <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">funnels</ENAMEX> lifted straight from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Centre Georges Pompidou</ENAMEX>. The monumental fa√ßade of alternating bands of travertine and sandstone is undermined by oversized <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fiberglass handrails</ENAMEX> that look like pink sausages. I couldn‚Äôt understand this design, except as a tour-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">de</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX>, until I visited the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>. It was a wintry <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Staatsgalerie</ENAMEX> was packed‚Äîit is one of the most popular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museums</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>. Now the architecture made sense. This <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX>-cum-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">discotheque</ENAMEX> was the perfect setting for the eclectic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX>. We were wearing every type of dress imaginable: casual wear, business suits, ski parkas, work clothes. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> dressed up for a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> visit to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX>, some dressed down. Stirling‚Äôs lively collage absorbed us all. I did not see any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gentlemen</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Homburgs</ENAMEX> and spats, but they would have fitted in, too.
A number of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> I accompanied the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Diamond</ENAMEX> on a visit to a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> that he had just completed at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York University</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Toronto</ENAMEX>. It was a student <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">center</ENAMEX>, containing a food <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lounges</ENAMEX> on the main level and student <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization offices</ENAMEX> on the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">floor</ENAMEX>. The exterior of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> was decidedly traditional. Facing a landscaped common, the well-proportioned fa√ßade consisted of a colonnaded brick <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">base</ENAMEX> supporting a row of double columns capped by a deep <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">copper</ENAMEX>-lined cornice. Behind the colonnade, which was fitted with retractable glass panels that could be opened during warm weather, was a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-story-high hall lit by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> large skylights. The exterior had a simplicity that reminded me of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McKim</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mead & White</ENAMEX>, albeit without Classical ornament.
The interior was different, with many hallmarks of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Style</ENAMEX>: no decoration, bare concrete, exposed structural beams, factory sash glazing and steel pipe railings. I assumed that the stark simplicity was the result of a restricted budget, and a desire to use materials that would withstand wear and tear. It seemed pretty banal to me, and although I didn‚Äôt say anything to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX>, I was disappointed. Yet as we walked around, I changed my mind. Although the d√©cor was tough and unsentimental, it was not <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">crude</ENAMEX>. There were sleek <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">stainless-steel</ENAMEX> pendant lighting fixtures with suspended glass diffusers and stylish easy chairs covered in canvas. In the food <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX> and counter tops were marble, the dining tables solid <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">maple</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Students</ENAMEX> were gathered around tables, lounging on the staircase, sprawled on the floor. The atmosphere was hard to pin down. This was not the precious, corporate modernism of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Meier</ENAMEX>, nor the contrived, technological wizardry of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman Foster</ENAMEX>. It was certainly not the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Calvinist</ENAMEX> minimalism that I associated with many trendy younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architects</ENAMEX>. I couldn‚Äôt put my finger on it until I realized that the functional but chic d√©cor reminded me of the no-nonsense styling of a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Benetton</ENAMEX> clothing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX>.
I happen to like <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Collegiate Gothic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>. I like their dark <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> with wood paneling, hammer-<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">beam</ENAMEX> ceilings, and traditional oak furniture. But seeing the York student <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">center</ENAMEX> made me realize that whenever I walk through these old <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> I also experience a nagging dissatisfaction. It has to do with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>. The young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in baseball caps, shorts, stenciled sweat shirts, and iridescent nylon windbreakers just don‚Äôt fit in. They should be wearing boaters and blazers, tweeds and flannels. Of course, no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> that I have ever seen‚Äîincluding at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oxford‚</ENAMEX>Äîdresses that way. I may deplore the loss of decorum, but as an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX> I can‚Äôt do anything to change it. It is the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> that must do the accommodating.
If the relationship between dress and d√©cor is intimate, it is also one-sided. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Interior</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">decorators</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architects</ENAMEX> will bridle at this, but there is no doubt that dress comes first. ‚ÄúPeople have always worn what they wanted to wear,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù</ENAMEX> writes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anne Hollander</ENAMEX>, ‚Äúfashion exists to keep fulfilling that desire.<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">‚Äù6</ENAMEX> And architecture must follow. For the truth is that a building‚Äîno matter how useful or <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">well</ENAMEX> built or beautiful‚Äîthat is not sympathetic to the way that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> dress risks looking not merely anachronistic, but downright silly. Like it or not, architecture cannot escape fashion.




