








two
in and out of fashion


<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bryant Park</ENAMEX>, in midtown <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX>, is the site of a bi-<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> fashion show. Twice <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>, in large white <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tents</ENAMEX> crammed with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">photographers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrity guests</ENAMEX>, models parade designers‚Äô wares on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">runway</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bryant Park</ENAMEX> is also a good place to observe an architectural fashion show. A row of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Twenties</TIMEX> beauties lines <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">40th Street</ENAMEX>, along the south side of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">First</NUMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ely Jacques Kahn‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">French Renaissance</ENAMEX> office <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>, originally the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scientific American</ENAMEX>. Its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX> is the stately <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Classical Engineers Club</ENAMEX>. Then comes a flapper, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Raymond Hood‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Radiator Building</ENAMEX>, whose black brick and gold trim sets it apart from its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Rich‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bryant Park Studios</ENAMEX>, an elegant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">survivor</ENAMEX> of the late <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gilded Age</ENAMEX>, is at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Sixth Avenue</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">corner</ENAMEX>. The large north-facing windows and glazed <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">penthouse</ENAMEX> are a reminder that this <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> was originally intended for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bryant Park Studios</ENAMEX> is built in an architectural style that was originally called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Modern French</ENAMEX> but <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> is commonly referred to as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beaux-Arts</ENAMEX>, in recognition of the influential <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ecole des Beaux-Arts</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>. Starting with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Morris Hunt</ENAMEX>, during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the second half of the nineteenth century</TIMEX> many of the best <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architects</ENAMEX> were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduates</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ecole</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">H. H. Richardson</ENAMEX> and his prot√©g√© <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Follen McKim</ENAMEX> were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alumni</ENAMEX>, as well as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McKim‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assistants</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John M. Carr√</ENAMEX>®re and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Hastings</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carr√®re</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings</ENAMEX> were the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architects</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Public Library</ENAMEX>, whose stately presence commands the east side of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Bryant Park</ENAMEX>. Narrow strips of windows indicate the book-stacks, above them <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> thermal windows signal the vast reading <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>. In typical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beaux-Arts</ENAMEX> fashion, the fa√ßade manages to appear both grandly monumental and coolly rational, except for a curious row of little doorways high up the wall, which lack <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">balconies</ENAMEX> or even railings and open into mid-air. The strange little sky-exits, which a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> who works at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> claims are for staff <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defenestration</ENAMEX>, provide a fanciful note to the great marble <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">fa√ßade</ENAMEX>.*
A row of no-nonsense <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">1970s</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> blocks lines <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Sixth Avenue</ENAMEX> on the west side of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX>. The largest is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Telephone Company Building</ENAMEX>, whose banal fa√ßade of gray-tinted <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glass</ENAMEX> and vertical strips of marble fills the block <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 41st</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">42nd Street</ENAMEX>. The north side of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> is dominated by the fifty-story <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">W. R. Grace Building</ENAMEX>, designed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gordon Bunshaft</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Skidmore</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Owings</ENAMEX> & <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Merrill</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1972</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">swooping travertine fa√ßade</ENAMEX> appears to have been inspired by the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bras√≠lia.</ENAMEX> This bit of tropical flash is flanked by an undistinguished mirrored glass <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tower</ENAMEX>, and a generic brick-and-<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Colonial</ENAMEX>-trim box. Built <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50 years</TIMEX> apart, these commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> blocks share a balefully functionalist approach to architecture. They are strictly off-the-rack <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> that only a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">developer</ENAMEX> could love.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bryant Park</ENAMEX> also offers distant views of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Manhattan‚</ENAMEX>Äôs most distinctive skyscrapers: the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler Building</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Empire State Building</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler Building</ENAMEX> started life as a speculative office <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1927</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Van Alen</ENAMEX>, influenced by the recent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parisian</ENAMEX> exhibition of the arts <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">d√©coratifs</ENAMEX>, designed a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">skyscraper</ENAMEX> in a style that has come to be known as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Art Deco</ENAMEX>. When the plans were finished, but before construction had begun, the design and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building site</ENAMEX> were bought by the automobile magnate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter P. Chrysler</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler</ENAMEX> wanted the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> to serve as a billboard for his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Van Alen</ENAMEX> obligingly grafted on eagle-head gargoyles (based on hood ornaments), winged radiator caps, a frieze of steel hubcaps, and black brick accents that suggest running <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX>. The tower‚Äôs most distinctive feature was its stainless-steel cap, which held the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cloud Club</ENAMEX>, a private dining <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX>. Today, the flamboyant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler Building</ENAMEX> is considered a brilliant emblem of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Jazz Age</ENAMEX>, but it was not an instant success. When it was built it was roundly criticized as frivolous and flashy. ‚ÄúA stunt design,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù</ENAMEX> sniffed The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> likewise derided the blatant commercialism of the architecture.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler Building</ENAMEX> had the distinction of being the world‚Äôs tallest <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building‚</ENAMEX>Äîfor <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few months</TIMEX>, until it was surpassed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Empire State Building</ENAMEX>. Although designed at the same time as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Empire State</ENAMEX> is quite different in appearance. Its exterior is the architectural equivalent of a gray flannel suit. There is no decoration. The plain limestone walls lack even traditional cornices; chrome-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">nickel steel</ENAMEX> mullions extend uninterrupted from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 6th</TIMEX> to the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">85th</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">floor</ENAMEX>, accentuating the building‚Äôs height. ‚ÄúOrnament is crime‚Äù <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Adolf Loos</ENAMEX> had proclaimed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years before</TIMEX>, but the stripped-down appearance of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Empire State Building</ENAMEX> owed more to an accelerated building schedule‚Äîconstruction took <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">less than eighteen months‚Äîthan</NUMEX> to architectural ideology. In fact, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architects</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">skyscraper</ENAMEX> considered themselves <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traditionalists</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richmond H. Shreve</ENAMEX> worked for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carr√®re & Hastings</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Public Library</ENAMEX>, where he met <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Lamb</ENAMEX>, a recent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ecole</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduate</ENAMEX>. After <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carr√</ENAMEX>®re‚Äôs unfortunate death in an auto accident and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hastings‚</ENAMEX>Äô retirement, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shreve</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamb</ENAMEX> took over the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> (for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several years</TIMEX> it was called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carr√®re & Hastings</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shreve & Lamb</ENAMEX>) and were eventually joined by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arthur Loomis Harmon</ENAMEX>, who had worked for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McKim</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mead & White</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metropolitan Museum of Art</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Despite‚Äîor</ENAMEX> rather because of‚Äîtheir solid <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Classical</ENAMEX> roots, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Shreve</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamb</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harmon</ENAMEX> designed a beautifully proportioned <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> that became the most famous <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">skyscraper</ENAMEX> in the world.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Empire State Building</ENAMEX> has one whimsical touch. The final plans called for the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">skyscraper</ENAMEX> to end with a flat roof over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 85th</TIMEX> floor‚<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">Äî1,050 feet</NUMEX>, precisely calculated to be <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">two feet</NUMEX> higher than the top of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Building‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">spire</ENAMEX>. Then, before construction began, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> decided that <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">two feet</NUMEX> was not enough, and ordered the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architects</ENAMEX> to add a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">200-foot</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tower</ENAMEX> to the top of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>.* This was to be not merely a decorative <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">spire</ENAMEX> but a functioning symbol of the modern age, a mooring <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tower</ENAMEX> for airships. Instead of dropping transatlantic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">travelers</ENAMEX> off at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lakehurst</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.J.</ENAMEX>, the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">thousand-foot-long</NUMEX> dirigibles would fly right into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX> and hook themselves up to the top of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Empire State Building</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Passengers</ENAMEX> would disembark to an observation <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">platform</ENAMEX> and descend by elevator to a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lounge</ENAMEX> and customs area on the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">86th</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">floor</ENAMEX>. Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX>, including <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hugo Eckener</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commander</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Graf Zeppelin</ENAMEX>, doubted that it could be done. It was hard enough to dock the unwieldy leviathans at ground level, never mind <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1,250 feet</NUMEX> up in the air. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> proved to be right, and no airship <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> ever landed atop the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Empire</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX><NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.1</NUMEX> Yet the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">rocket</ENAMEX>-shaped <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tower</ENAMEX>, with its cast <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">aluminum buttresses</ENAMEX> and gleaming conical top, is the perfect fanciful crown for this rather solemn <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">skyscraper</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Whimsy</ENAMEX> is absent from the tops of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1970s</TIMEX> office <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">blocks</ENAMEX> around <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Bryant Park</ENAMEX>. They look as if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architects</ENAMEX> had lopped them off on a whim: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>ÄúI can do <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">floors</ENAMEX>, or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">42</NUMEX>, or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">45</NUMEX>. Just tell me when to stop.‚Äù More recent skyscrapers around <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Bryant Park</ENAMEX>, no doubt emboldened by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Philip Johnson‚Äôs Chippendale</ENAMEX> top on his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AT&T Building</ENAMEX>, have more animated crowns. The hipped roof of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fifth Avenue Postmodern</ENAMEX> high-rise adorned with circles and squares peeks out above the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX>. The top of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Bertelsmann Building</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">slender spike</ENAMEX>. The new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cond√© Nast</ENAMEX> office <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tower</ENAMEX> has tilted forms resembling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX> cabinets on its roof. Pretty tame stuff compared to the more fanciful crowns of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">1920s</NUMEX> buildings‚Äîneo-Gothic spires, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Romanesque</ENAMEX> tile roofs, copper <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">domes</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">58</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">floors</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Fifth Avenue</ENAMEX> (at the corner of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Fifth Avenue</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">42nd Street</ENAMEX>), which was designed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shreve & Lamb</ENAMEX> prior to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Empire State Building</ENAMEX>, step back dramatically as they reach the building‚Äôs apex. Spiky, wrought-iron finials enliven the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">chateau</ENAMEX>-like roof of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scientific American Building</ENAMEX>. An animated silhouette of black brick with gilded and red highlights crowns the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Radiator Building</ENAMEX>. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hood</ENAMEX>, the dramatic effect (floodlit at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>) suggested a ‚Äúpile of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coal</ENAMEX>, glowing at the top.‚Äù
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Raymond M. Hood</ENAMEX> was the outstanding commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1920s</TIMEX>. He and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John Mead Howells</ENAMEX> won a celebrated international architectural competition for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Tribune</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tower</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> with a handsome <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gothic</ENAMEX> design based on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Butter Tower of Rouen Cathedral</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Tribune</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competition</ENAMEX> led to several <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">commissions</ENAMEX>, including the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Radiator Building</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily News Building</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McGraw-Hill Building</ENAMEX>. With these designs, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hood</ENAMEX> developed the distinctly <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> approach to skyscrapers that would influence <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Van Alen</ENAMEX> and a generation of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">skyscraper</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designers</ENAMEX>: tall <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> conceived as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nietzschean</ENAMEX> symbols of corporate power or, to put it more mundanely, architecture as advertising. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hood</ENAMEX> once pointed out that since modern office <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> would be amortized in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only 20 years</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architects</ENAMEX> had an opportunity to experiment. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily News</ENAMEX> is a robust pinnacle, with alternating vertical strips of masonry and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glass</ENAMEX>. His final <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">skyscraper</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McGraw-Hill Building</ENAMEX>, is a witty blue-green take on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Style</ENAMEX>, complete with the company‚Äôs name in huge ‚ÄúBroadway‚Äù style lettering on the top. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hood</ENAMEX> was also one of the key <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designers</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architects</ENAMEX> responsible for <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Rockefeller Center</ENAMEX>. His influence is felt in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centerpiece tower</ENAMEX>, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">70</NUMEX>-story cliff-like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RCA Building</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This twentieth-century</TIMEX> abstracted version of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medieval verticality</ENAMEX> is one of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York‚</ENAMEX>Äôs most evocative skyscrapers, unsurpassed since it was completed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1934</TIMEX>.

<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bryant Park</ENAMEX> chronicles <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a hundred years</TIMEX> of changing architectural fashions. <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Buildings</ENAMEX> are sometimes referred to as timeless, as if this were the highest praise one could bestow. That is nonsense. The best <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>, like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Public Library</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RCA</ENAMEX>, are precisely of their time. That is part of the pleasure of looking at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> from the past. They reflect old values and bygone virtues and vices: the self-confidence of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX>, the cheerful boosterism of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler</ENAMEX>, the sobriety of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RCA</ENAMEX>. Even the bland goofiness of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grace Building</ENAMEX> recalls the na√Øve optimism of an earlier <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">era</TIMEX>. That is why old <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> are precious, that is why we fight to preserve them. It is not only because we think them beautiful, or significant. It is also because they remind us of who we once were. And of who we might be again, for old <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> also inspire. The ruins of ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX> inspired the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Renaissance</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architects</ENAMEX>. The palazzos of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Renaissance Italy</ENAMEX> inspired <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles McKim</ENAMEX>. And the memory of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">McKim‚Äôs Pennsylvania Station</ENAMEX> inspired <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Childs</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Skidmore</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Owings</ENAMEX> & <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Merrill</ENAMEX> to transform <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McKim‚</ENAMEX>Äôs old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post Office Building</ENAMEX> into a projected railroad <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">terminal</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>.
Sometimes old <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> inspire us, sometimes the opposite is true. We look at an old building and ask ourselves, ‚ÄúWhat on earth were those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> thinking of?‚Äù I cannot warm to heroic public <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1960s</TIMEX>, for example. It is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than 35 years</TIMEX> since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln Center</ENAMEX> was built, enough time for the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> to mellow, yet I can‚Äôt summon any sympathy for the colonnaded brutes. The idea of putting <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theaters</ENAMEX> under <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> roof must have been compelling at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time, but when I visit the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Kennedy Center</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>, all I see are <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">miles</NUMEX> of red carpeting in those <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Brobdingnagian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lobbies</ENAMEX>. Yet, who knows? Perhaps <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> a future <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> will see something in these <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> that eludes me.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Kennedy Center</ENAMEX> was criticized from the start, but the dazzling d√©cor of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Radio City Music Hall</ENAMEX>, which opened in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1932‚</NUMEX>Äîin the midst of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Depression‚</ENAMEX>Äîguaranteed its immediate success. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Radio City</ENAMEX> became the most famous <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">theater</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockettes</ENAMEX> the most famous chorus line, ‚Äúlive from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Radio City‚</ENAMEX>Äù the most famous dateline. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 1950s</TIMEX>, when I visited <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Radio City</ENAMEX> was still one of the obligatory tourist sites. What I don‚Äôt remember is ever learning about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Radio City</ENAMEX> as an architecture <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX>. According to the reductive standards of my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Style</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX>, its opulent materials, its glowing colors, and its very theatricality disqualified <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Radio City</ENAMEX> as architecture (never mind that it was a technologically sophisticated ‚Äúmachine for entertainment‚Äù). It was dismissed as kitsch. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1978</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Radio City</ENAMEX> had lost its glamour, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockefeller Center</ENAMEX> decided to demolish the aging <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hall</ENAMEX>. Thanks to preservationists‚Äô efforts, the hall was saved from demolition and granted landmark status. Now, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 years later</TIMEX>, freshened by a masterful restoration, it is once again acclaimed as a masterpiece.
Radio <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">City Music Hall</ENAMEX> is a reminder that it is not <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> that change, but architectural fashions. What seemed exciting in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one decade</TIMEX>, looks gaudy, if not downright embarrassing, in the next‚Äîor simply boring. When old <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> are torn down, the motive may be expediency or crass commercialism, but it may also be a desire for something new. This is as true of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> as it is of women‚Äôs hats, pace Le <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corbusier</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">‚Ä¢‚Ä¢‚Ä¢</ENAMEX>
Fashion has increasingly‚Äîand restrictively‚Äîbecome a term used in connection with women‚Äôs dress, as in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúfashion designer‚Äù</ENAMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>Äúthe fashion industry.<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">‚Äù The Oxford English Dictionary</ENAMEX> defines fashion more broadly as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äúthe</ENAMEX> mode of dress, etiquette, furniture, style of speech, etc., adopted in a society for the time being.‚Äù <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> have to cut their hair, eat, clothe themselves, decorate their homes‚Äîfashion affects how they do these things. According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fernand Braudel</ENAMEX>, fashion affects everything. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚ÄúIt</ENAMEX> covers ideas as much as costume, the current phrase as much as the coquettish gesture, the manner of receiving at table, the care taken in sealing a letter.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚</ENAMEX>Äù2 There is no reason to think that architecture is immune.
If style is the language of architecture, fashion represents the wide‚Äîand swirling‚Äîcultural currents that shape and direct that language. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Gothic</ENAMEX> architecture originated in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the twelfth century</TIMEX>, and remained in fashion in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next three hundred years</TIMEX>. It was used in the great cathedrals, and in such secular masterpieces as the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Doge‚Äôs Palace</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Venice</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Westminster Hall</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the last great <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> Gothic <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Milan Cathedral</ENAMEX>, begun in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1385</TIMEX>. It was so large that the domical <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">vault</ENAMEX> and crossing were not built until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">55 years later</TIMEX> by the great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Filippo Brunelleschi</ENAMEX>. By then the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Renaissance</ENAMEX> was well under way, thanks to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brunelleschi‚Äôs Foundling Hospital</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florence</ENAMEX>, generally considered the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> designed in the revived Classical style. With the rediscovery of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roman Classicism</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gothic</ENAMEX> became distinctly unfashionable. The old monuments were preserved, but they were not admired. ‚ÄúA fantastical and licentious manner of building,‚Äù is how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Wren</ENAMEX> characterized <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Gothic</ENAMEX> architecture. So general was the dissatisfaction, that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gothic</ENAMEX> came to stand for anything that was considered wild, barbarous, or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">crude</ENAMEX>.
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid-eighteenth century</TIMEX>, the term Gothic reappeared, not in architecture but in literature. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gothic</ENAMEX> romance, a type of novel, was usually set in the medieval past and involved the fantastic and the supernatural. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane Austen‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroine</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northanger Abbey</ENAMEX> is a devotee of such books and spends <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">many hours</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">‚Äúthe</ENAMEX> luxury of a raised, restless, and frightened imagination over the pages of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Udolpho</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù Austen</ENAMEX> is referring to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anne Radcliffe‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Mysteries of Udolpho</ENAMEX>, one of the most popular <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Gothic</ENAMEX> romances of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>, whose setting is a mysterious <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">castle</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apennines</ENAMEX>. Such surroundings‚Äîmonasteries, dungeons, castles‚Äîfigured prominently in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gothic</ENAMEX> tales ever since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Horace Walpole‚</ENAMEX>Äôs The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Castle of Otranto</ENAMEX>, which was published in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1764</TIMEX> and is generally considered the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gothic</ENAMEX> romance.
In her novel Austen pokes fun at the genre. The abbey of the title is not a haunted ruin in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> but a converted <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">medieval building</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gloucestershire</ENAMEX>, complete with modern fireplaces, comfortable furniture, and other domestic conveniences. This is a reminder that by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1798</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northanger Abbey</ENAMEX> was written, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Gothic</ENAMEX> fashion had embraced architecture. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Horace Walpole</ENAMEX> was responsible for that fashion, too. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1750s</TIMEX>, he had begun a project to enlarge <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Strawberry Hill</ENAMEX>, his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thames</ENAMEX>-side <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">villa</ENAMEX> near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>. While his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contemporaries</ENAMEX> built stately <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> in a delicate Classical style that was popularized by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Adam</ENAMEX>, the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walpole</ENAMEX>, who had an independent frame of mind, looked elsewhere for inspiration. He had been an undergraduate at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">King‚Äôs College</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambridge</ENAMEX> and admired its extraordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Gothic chapel</ENAMEX>. The exterior of his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> was battlemented like a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">medieval castle</ENAMEX>. The interior combined historicism with a playful eclecticism. Motifs copied from medieval altar screens ornamented the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rooms‚Äîstained glass</ENAMEX> was used in windows and papier-m√¢ch√© <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX>-vaults covered the ceiling. Walpole‚Äôs extensive collection of historical and modern books, paintings, and curiosities was also mixed in.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walpole</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fourth</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Earl</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Orford</ENAMEX>, spent his entire life enlarging his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>. He eventually added a cloister, a gallery, and a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tower</ENAMEX>. As he was an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> and a public <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figure</ENAMEX> who corresponded with a wide circle of literary and artistic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> throughout <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gothic</ENAMEX> design of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Strawberry Hill</ENAMEX> became famous among connoisseurs. (It also became a tourist attraction, much to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Walpole‚</ENAMEX>Äôs chagrin.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Architects</ENAMEX> and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> now saw <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">medieval buildings</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> of inspiration, just as they had once looked to ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greece</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gothic</ENAMEX> style became an established alternative for building <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">country houses</ENAMEX>, and pointed arches appeared in d√©cor and furniture. Gothic was ‚Äúin‚Äù again.
The revived interest in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the Middle Ages</TIMEX> was complicated, for fashion is rarely one-dimensional. Gothic meant different things to different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> (sometimes different things to the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spooky Gothic</ENAMEX> novels appealed to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>. Medieval <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> appealed to the current taste for the romantic and the picturesque. Goethe‚Äôs <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1772</TIMEX> essay on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Strassburg Cathedral</ENAMEX> pointed the way; he admitted to being ‚Äúa sworn enemy of the tangled arbitrariness of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gothick</ENAMEX> ornament,‚Äù but found himself overcome by the grandeur and mystery of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>, which he described as ‚Äúa most sublime, wide-arching <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">Tree</ENAMEX> of God.‚Äù The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> architectural <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">theorist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eug√</ENAMEX>®ne <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Viollet-le-Duc</ENAMEX>, on the other hand, was attracted by what he interpreted as the rationalism of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gothic</ENAMEX> construction. So was his <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counterpart</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Gilbert Scott</ENAMEX>, who considered <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gothic</ENAMEX> more <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúmodern‚Äù</ENAMEX> than Classical architecture, hence a more appropriate model for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architects</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Augustus Welby Pugin</ENAMEX>, who worked on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British Houses</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parliament</ENAMEX>, saw a moral dimension to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gothic</ENAMEX>. He considered medieval architecture to be the ideal of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> civilization, much as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greece</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX> had been admired as the cradle of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">classical‚Äîbut pagan‚Äîcivilization</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Ruskin</ENAMEX>, too, considered <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gothic</ENAMEX> a moral <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX>, but since he also loved <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Venice</ENAMEX>, polychrome <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ruskinian Gothic</ENAMEX> has many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">overtones</ENAMEX>. This incongruity is particularly striking since in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> especially (but also in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>), the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gothic</ENAMEX> style was considered a homegrown product‚Äîas opposed to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mediterranean Classicism</ENAMEX>. This was another cultural appeal of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gothic</ENAMEX>: at a time of growing nationalism in northern <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, it conveniently provided a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúnational‚Äù</ENAMEX> style.
In <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North America</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gothic</ENAMEX> was, if anything, even more popular. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Canadians</ENAMEX> chose a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gothic</ENAMEX> style for their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Houses</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parliament</ENAMEX>, which stand on a dramatic bluff overlooking the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ottawa River</ENAMEX>. Anglophile <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> built <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Collegiate Gothic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campuses</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gothic</ENAMEX> parish <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX>, and a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Gothic National Cathedral</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D.C. Ralph Adams Cram</ENAMEX>, who was devoted to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High Gothic</ENAMEX>, built the nave and west front of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York City‚Äôs Cathedral Church of St. John the Divine</ENAMEX>, the largest <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Gothic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX> in the world. Cram‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bertram Goodhue</ENAMEX> used a looser <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gothic</ENAMEX> style in the military <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">academy</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Point</ENAMEX>, as did <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cass Gilbert</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Woolworth Building‚</ENAMEX>Äîthe so-called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cathedral of Commerce</ENAMEX>. By then the cultural attributes of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gothic</ENAMEX> had worn thin. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hood‚Äôs Chicago Tribune Building</ENAMEX>, completed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1924</TIMEX>, was one of the last prominent <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> designed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gothic</ENAMEX> style.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gothic</ENAMEX> has not‚Äîso far‚Äîcome back into fashion. Early in his career, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Rudolph</ENAMEX> designed a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wellesley College</ENAMEX> that attempted to relate architecturally to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Collegiate Gothic</ENAMEX> surroundings. It was his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">commission</ENAMEX>, and it was not a success. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚ÄúWellesley</ENAMEX> shook me,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù Rudolph</ENAMEX> later recalled, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">‚Äúand I</ENAMEX> returned to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">International Style</ENAMEX> in my next <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">‚Äù3 Eero Saarinen</ENAMEX> built a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gothicized</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dormitory</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vasser</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Philip Johnson</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Burgee</ENAMEX> designed a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gothic</ENAMEX>-inspired <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">skyscraper</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX> that was a giant abstracted glass version of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British Houses</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parliament</ENAMEX>. This was one of several stylistic forays that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burgee</ENAMEX> made in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX>, including a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chippendale</ENAMEX>-top <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">skyscraper</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Provincial</ENAMEX> high-rise in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>, and a neo-Burnhamesque <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tower</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>. None is particularly satisfactory, perhaps because they lack conviction. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moshe Safdie‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Gallery of Canada</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ottawa</ENAMEX> is more successful. It mimics the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gothic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapter house</ENAMEX>-cum-library of the adjacent parliament <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> in a crystalline structure of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">steel</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glass</ENAMEX>. This episode in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Safdie‚</ENAMEX>Äôs oeuvre was unique, however, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gothicized</ENAMEX> forms do not reappear in his later <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Classical</ENAMEX> style has proved more durable. This has something to do with its remarkable adaptability. Whether building an administrative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">center</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British Raj</ENAMEX> or designing a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pennsylvania Railroad</ENAMEX> workable solutions can be devised in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Classical</ENAMEX> tradition. The cultural overtones of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Classical</ENAMEX> style are even richer than those of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gothic</ENAMEX>; they include not only the ancient civilizations of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greece</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX>, but also <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Renaissance</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> humanism, seventeenth<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parisian</ENAMEX> splendor, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Georgian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> elegance, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> country-house comfort. During <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the immediate postwar period</TIMEX> monumental Classical <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> also acquired authoritarian <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX>, since they had been fashionable in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nazi Germany</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Stalinist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX>. If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gothic</ENAMEX> was considered a national style by some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architects</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1800s</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Classicism</ENAMEX>, rooted in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early days</TIMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Republic</ENAMEX>, has a claim to being America‚Äôs national style. This is most evident in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX> Except for brief flirtations with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Victorian</ENAMEX> Gothic (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Smithsonian</ENAMEX>) and functionalist modernism (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air and Space Museum</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Classicism</ENAMEX> has remained in fashion for federal <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> ever since the construction of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palladian White House</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Washingtonian Classicism</ENAMEX> has taken many guises, ranging from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jefferson Memorial</ENAMEX> (a small version of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pantheon</ENAMEX>), to the severely abstract <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Reserve Board Building</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Triangle</ENAMEX> and the recent <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald W. Reagan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Building</ENAMEX> are modern interpretations of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Classical</ENAMEX> tradition.
While the architecture of federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington</ENAMEX> sometimes overwhelms foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX>, it is comfortably familiar to most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> because of the popularity of a simplified version of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Classicism‚</ENAMEX>Äîthe so-called <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> Colonial style, which could more accurately be called <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American Georgian</ENAMEX>. In furnishings, d√©cor, and above all in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> design, this has been the dominant domestic fashion for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last hundred years</TIMEX>. The origin of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> Colonial can be dated with some accuracy. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 1874</TIMEX> was the inaugural issue of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The New York Sketchbook of Architecture</ENAMEX>. It was edited by a youthful <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles McKim</ENAMEX>. The purpose of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McKim</ENAMEX> wrote, was to document in sketches and photographs, ‚Äúthe beautiful, quaint, and picturesque features which belong to so many <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>, now almost disregarded, of our Colonial and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Revolutionary Period</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù McKim</ENAMEX> and his new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partners</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">William Mead</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanford White</ENAMEX>, made several sketching trips in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">New England</ENAMEX>. They were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designers</ENAMEX>, not preservationists, and their interest was the inspiration found in old <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>. White clapboard walls, black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shutters</ENAMEX>, and pedimented <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">porches</ENAMEX> started to appear in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McKim</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mead &</ENAMEX> White <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX>. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1876</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Centennial</ENAMEX> celebrations made the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> public aware of its ancestral past. On a practical level, the understated, comfortable Colonial style was well-suited to prevailing domestic taste. It was also easily‚Äîand inexpensively‚Äîadapted to small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Colonial</ENAMEX> remained the height of fashion until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1940s</TIMEX>. In a simplified form‚Äîthe <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Cape Cod</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cottage‚Äîit reappeared</ENAMEX> in postwar <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Levittowns</ENAMEX>. It continues <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, although the clapboard siding may be vinyl, the columns polystyrene, and the stamped metal shutters more likely symbolic than real.

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚ÄúThe Tribune</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Radiator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Buildings</ENAMEX> are both in the ‚Äòvertical‚Äô style or what is called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">‚ÄòGothic‚Äô</ENAMEX> simply because I happened to make them so,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù Raymond Hood</ENAMEX> once <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">flippantly</ENAMEX> explained. ‚ÄúIf at the time of designing them I had been under the spell of Italian campaniles or <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pagodas</ENAMEX>, I suppose the resulting compositions would have been ‚Äòhorizontal.<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äô ‚Äù4 Hood</ENAMEX> was no more comfortable discussing style than other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architects</ENAMEX>. He left unexplained the question of what had put him ‚Äúunder the spell‚Äù of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gothic</ENAMEX> in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place. It had happened <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early</TIMEX>: Hood‚Äôs senior thesis at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">M.I.T.‚Äîhe</ENAMEX> later also studied at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ecole‚</ENAMEX>Äîhad been a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gothic</ENAMEX> style; his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employer</ENAMEX> was the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gothicist Ralph Adams Cram</ENAMEX>; and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hood assisted Bertram Goodhue</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Point</ENAMEX>. Later in life, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hood</ENAMEX> occasionally returned to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gothic</ENAMEX> style, notably in the handsome <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Masonic Temple</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scottish Rite Cathedral</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scranton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX>, but he never explained what broke the spell and led him to a more abstract style.
Like any successful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hood</ENAMEX> had a strong sense of his changing time. It is easy to misunderstand the nature of that change. The abstraction that characterizes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily News Building</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RCA Building</ENAMEX> has little to do with new technology or changing functions. Those <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> are not any more <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúmodern‚Äù</ENAMEX> than the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Tribune</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tower</ENAMEX>, which had gargoyles and flying buttresses but was an advanced <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> in terms of planning and technology. Indeed, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hood‚Äôs Gothic</ENAMEX> design was more functionally advanced than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eliel Saarinen‚</ENAMEX>Äôs stylistically progressive second-place entry. It was not commodity and firmness that drove the changing aesthetic, but fashion. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> had a taste for simpler, forward-looking design, of which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Style</ENAMEX> was but one expression. Art <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deco</ENAMEX>, streamlined modern, and stripped <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Classicism</ENAMEX> were evidence of the same changing taste. Many industrial products of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">1930s</NUMEX> displayed the same chic simplicity: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Raymond Loewy‚</ENAMEX>Äôs curvilinear Coldspot refrigerator, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter Dorwin Teague‚</ENAMEX>Äôs popular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kodak Brownie</ENAMEX> camera, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Dreyfuss‚Äô Bell</ENAMEX> telephone, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Loewy‚</ENAMEX>Äôs redesigned <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Coca-Cola</ENAMEX> bottle and the sleek <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Zippo</ENAMEX> cigarette lighter.
The medieval inventors of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gothic</ENAMEX> style were likewise influenced by fashion. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the twelfth century</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cathedral builders</ENAMEX> abandoned the tried-and-true round arch in favor of the pointed arch. This change cannot be explained by functional or structural requirements, since the pointed arch provides only marginal structural advantages; and round-arch technology is perfectly capable of building tall naves, as <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Durham Cathedral</ENAMEX> and other magnificent <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Romanesque</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX> demonstrate. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Cathedral builders</ENAMEX> obviously found something delightful in the pointed arch, which they used not only as a structural form, but in window tracery, in wood paneling, and even in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">choir</ENAMEX>-stall furniture and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">liturgical</ENAMEX> accessories. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚Äú</ENAMEX>[<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Gothic</ENAMEX>] was seized upon as essential not because it was materially essential, but because the pointed arch struck that note of fantasy which was what the mind of the age desired,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù</ENAMEX> explains <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Summerson</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚ÄúIt</ENAMEX> willfully destroyed the discipline of the round arch, which had become an incubus and a bore.‚<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Äù5</NUMEX> A note of fantasy? A bore? At this point, the eminent architectural <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> sounds like a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Harper‚Äôs Bazaar</ENAMEX> fashion <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX>.
Architectural reputations, as well as architecture, come under fashion‚<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">Äôs</ENAMEX> sway. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hood</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ely Jacques Kahn</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralph Walker</ENAMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irving Trust Building</ENAMEX> on Wall Street), all small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, were dubbed the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">‚ÄúThree Little Napoleons of Architecture‚Äù</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX>. Riding high in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1920s</TIMEX>, their careers were cut short by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Depression‚ÄîHood‚Äôs</ENAMEX> more so, since he died in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1934</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only 53 years old</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockefeller Center</ENAMEX> continued to be admired by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>, but because of his freewheeling approach to design, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hood</ENAMEX> was marginalized by modernist architectural <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historians</ENAMEX>. He was never forgiven for winning the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Tribune</ENAMEX> competition and beating not only <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saarinen</ENAMEX>, but such <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">avant-gardists</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adolf Loos</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruno Taut</ENAMEX>, and even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter Gropius</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founder</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauhaus</ENAMEX> and the guiding light of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Style</ENAMEX>. Yet if I compare <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Hood‚Äôs RCA Building</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gropius‚Äôs Pan Am</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> MetLife) <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Building</ENAMEX>, there is little doubt who was the more creative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designer</ENAMEX>.
Looking at that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">monolith</ENAMEX>, bestriding <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Park Avenue</ENAMEX> without charm or grace, it is easy to forget that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gropius</ENAMEX> was once considered one of the great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architects</ENAMEX> of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twentieth century</TIMEX>. Architectural memory can be fickle. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Ustick Walter</ENAMEX> is not a household name, but it should be‚Äîhe was the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Capitol</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dome</ENAMEX>, probably one of the most powerful symbols of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> democracy. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln Memorial</ENAMEX>, designed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Bacon</ENAMEX>, is another famous architectural icon. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bacon</ENAMEX> died in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1924</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only two years</TIMEX> after the memorial was dedicated, so he did not see the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Classicism</ENAMEX> that he had learned at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McKim‚</ENAMEX>Äôs knee slip out of fashion. At least <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter and Bacon</ENAMEX> were feted during their lifetimes. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward Durrell Stone</ENAMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Style</ENAMEX> wunderkind, developed an unfashionable interest in decoration at a time when architectural austerity was in vogue. And although he received large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">commissions</ENAMEX> (including the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kennedy Center for the Arts</ENAMEX>), he finished his career ignored if not actually ridiculed. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid-1960s</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Rudolph</ENAMEX> was probably the most promising young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. His robustly monumental <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Art and Architecture Building</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale</ENAMEX>, where he was also <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX>, reinvigorated postwar <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> architecture. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A decade later</TIMEX>, heroic monumentalism was out and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Postmodernism</ENAMEX> was in. Although <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rudolph</ENAMEX> continued to receive commissions in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX>, he was slighted in his own <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contemporaries</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gordon Bunshaft</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Roche</ENAMEX> were awarded the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pritzker Prize</ENAMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudolph</ENAMEX> was passed over. By the time he died in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>, he was virtually forgotten.
Yet <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudolph</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gifted designer</ENAMEX>, may be admitted to the architectural pantheon <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX>. Architectural reputations can rise and fall and rise again. The nineteenth<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Furness</ENAMEX> designed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ruskinian Gothic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> whose lively eclecticism anticipates <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Stirling</ENAMEX>. Furness, an exceptional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> who won a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congressional Medal of Honor</ENAMEX> during <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">the Civil War</ENAMEX>, dominated the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX> architectural scene for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 years</TIMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1891</TIMEX> he completed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Pennsylvania Library</ENAMEX>, a widely acclaimed brick and terracotta <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> with a dramatic <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>-story-high reading <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>. After the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">turn-of-the-century</TIMEX>, with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Classicism</ENAMEX> all the rage, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Furness‚</ENAMEX>Äô idiosyncratic brand of architecture became unfashionable. Although he lived until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1912</TIMEX>, his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">practice</ENAMEX> languished. In time he was entirely forgotten, many of his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> were demolished, others insensitively altered. As for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX>, its tall reading <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> was crudely truncated by a suspended ceiling. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1950s</TIMEX>, there was a revival of interest in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Furness</ENAMEX>, which narrowly saved the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> from demolition. Today, after a careful restoration, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> is unquestionably the best-loved building on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Pennsylvania</ENAMEX> campus‚Äîsomething about the spiky decoration and the willfully manipulated forms appeals to current sensibility. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Furness</ENAMEX> has found an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> again.
The fate of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rudolph</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Furness</ENAMEX> is a reminder that although architecture is susceptible to fashion, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architects</ENAMEX> are not fashion <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designers</ENAMEX>. ‚ÄúI do not design a new architecture every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù Mies van der Rohe</ENAMEX> is reputed to have said. This is often taken as a reflection of his serious commitment to his art. It was that, but it was something else, too. He might as well have said, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚ÄúI</ENAMEX> cannot design a new architecture every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>.‚Äù The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seagram Building</ENAMEX> is a masterpiece, not because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mies</ENAMEX> had a sudden inspiration, but because he had spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX> learning how to bring commodity, firmness, and delight into his particular version of balance; how to attach the travertine to the wall to create a particular effect; which metal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">fabricator</ENAMEX> could make a certain kind of handrail; and exactly how deep to make a window mullion to cast the right size of shadow. <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Buildings</ENAMEX> are extremely complicated artifacts, and the time necessary to cultivate and refine a particular manner of building cannot be underestimated. This is especially true when the manner of building is personal or unusual, as it was in the case of both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Furness</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudolph</ENAMEX>. They were not simply being stubborn or high-minded when they refused to adapt to changing fashions, they were being realistic.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris Lapidus</ENAMEX> is an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX> who has lived long enough to see architectural fashions come full circle. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1950s</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lapidus</ENAMEX> designed many of the largest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miami</ENAMEX> area: the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fontainebleau</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americana</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Eden Roc</ENAMEX>. His flamboyant, eclectic designs were ridiculed by the architectural <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">establishment</ENAMEX>, although they were popular with the public. Today, in a period of so-called entertainment architecture, when the world‚Äôs most celebrated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architects</ENAMEX> design theme <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">casinos</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lapidus</ENAMEX> seems less like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">maverick</ENAMEX> than a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pioneer</ENAMEX>. ‚ÄúThe <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> of us all,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù Philip Johnson</ENAMEX> called him, with only slight exaggeration.
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">‚Ä¢‚Ä¢‚Ä¢</ENAMEX>
Architecture changes at a bewildering pace. Consider <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only the last 50 years</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> design. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">National Gallery of Art</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1937-41</TIMEX>) in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum of Modern Art</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1937-39</TIMEX>) in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> are almost exact <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contemporaries</ENAMEX>. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">MoMA</ENAMEX> design, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Philip L. Goodwin</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward Durrell Stone</ENAMEX> ignored the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Classical</ENAMEX> tradition represented by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Russell Pope‚</ENAMEX>Äôs masterpiece. MoMA‚Äôs entrance was not up a broad flight of exterior steps but through a revolving door. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goodwin</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stone</ENAMEX> replaced the monumental rotunda by a nondescript <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lobby</ENAMEX>, the lofty <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">galleries</ENAMEX> by low-ceilinged <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">loft</ENAMEX> spaces, and limestone and marble by stucco and plasterboard. MoMA was to be the last word in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">avant-garde International Style</ENAMEX>, but it was scarcely finished when it was challenged by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Lloyd Wright‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guggenheim Museum</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1943-58</TIMEX>), which rejected the banality of the white <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">box</ENAMEX> by squeezing the entire <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> into a dramatic sculptural spiral. Nothing could be further from the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">International Style</ENAMEX> than the mollusk-like exterior (especially if it had been tinted rose-red, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wright</ENAMEX> initially wanted). In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale Center for British Art</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1969-77</TIMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louis I. Kahn</ENAMEX> likewise incorporated central <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">skylit</ENAMEX> spaces, but he disavowed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wright‚</ENAMEX>Äôs loud anti-urban exterior by hugging the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sidewalk</ENAMEX> and clothing his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> in drab stainless <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">steel</ENAMEX> panels. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kahn</ENAMEX> preached taming technology by consigning it to so-called <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">servant</ENAMEX> spaces; in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Centre Georges Pompidou</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1971-77</TIMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Piano</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rogers</ENAMEX> stood Kahn‚Äôs dictum on its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> and gave the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">servants</ENAMEX> the run of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Neue Staatsgalerie</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1977-83</TIMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Stirling</ENAMEX> cheekily lifted architectural elements from both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pompidou</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guggenheim</ENAMEX> and combined them with a variety of historical styles. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">I. M. Pei‚</ENAMEX>Äôs impeccably crafted <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">East Building of the National Gallery of Art</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1976-78</TIMEX>) in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>, had not one exposed bolt, not one allusion to the past. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pei</ENAMEX> rejected both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stirling‚</ENAMEX>Äôs eclecticism and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Piano</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rogers‚</ENAMEX>Äô technological posturing. Instead he relied on abstract geometry for architectural effect. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank O. Gehry‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">California Aerospace Museum</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1982-84</TIMEX>) in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> is no less abstract and geometrical, but his forms bump and grind into each other almost as if by accident. ‚ÄúI really enjoy the awkwardness with which [the forms] touch,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù Gehry</ENAMEX> observed, ‚Äúas it reminds me of the cities we live in and the kind of awkwardnesses of city <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> sitting next to each other.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚</ENAMEX>Äù6 The cost of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">East Building</ENAMEX> was <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$94.4 million</NUMEX>; the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aerospace Museum</ENAMEX> was built on a tight budget of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">only $3.4 million</NUMEX>. Lacking money for refinement, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gehry</ENAMEX> turned awkwardness into a virtue, and in the process disowned <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pei‚</ENAMEX>Äôs fastidious brand of modernism. He was carefree where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pei</ENAMEX> was careful, spontaneous where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pei</ENAMEX> was studied, brash where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pei</ENAMEX> was genteel. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aerospace Museum</ENAMEX> was clearly not a cheaper version of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">East Building</ENAMEX>, it was something different.
‚ÄúFashion is also a search for a new language to discredit the old,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù</ENAMEX> writes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fernand Braudel</ENAMEX>, ‚Äúa way in which each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> can repudiate its immediate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">predecessor</ENAMEX> and distinguish itself from it.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚</ENAMEX>Äù7 This puts fashion in the right light: it may be fleeting, but it is not frivolous. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Braudel</ENAMEX> suggests, changes in fashion imply not only the creation of something new, but the destruction of something old. That is why new fashions are inevitably upsetting. Whether one is wearing a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lounge</ENAMEX>-suit instead of a frock coat, or turning a baseball cap backwards, someone else is bound to be insulted. No less so in architecture. Replacing an <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ionic</ENAMEX> column with a steel I-<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">beam</ENAMEX>, or exposing air-conditioning ducts, or using common <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">materials</ENAMEX> in uncommon ways are calculated affronts to honored conventions. ‚ÄúWe are not like our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fathers</ENAMEX>,‚Äù the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architects</ENAMEX> say, ‚Äúwe are different.‚Äù




