








<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three</TIMEX>
style


When an architectural <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competition</ENAMEX> was announced for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Public Library</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 21, 1897</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Shaw Billings</ENAMEX>, the library‚Äôs executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>, was determined that in his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>, design would not triumph over function. He had in mind Boston‚Äôs newly built public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX>, a beautiful but in his opinion poorly functioning <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>. Billings, an ex-army <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physician</ENAMEX>, was responsible for organizing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Surgeon General‚Äôs Library</ENAMEX> and a celebrated medical index. He was also an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> in hospital design, and was thus familiar with <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> construction. He drafted a plan for the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> whose most unorthodox feature was the location of the main reading <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>. It was not located near the main entrance, as was common practice, but on an upper floor, above the book stacks.
The terms of the architectural competition were strict and included detailed floor plans that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX> were required to follow. There were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> stages, intended to attract new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">talent</ENAMEX> as well as established <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX>. First, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architects</ENAMEX> were chosen from an open competition. These <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> then advanced to a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> stage, where they competed against <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> invited <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> that included not only <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McKim</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mead & White</ENAMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architects</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Public Library</ENAMEX>), but also such <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">luminaries</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peabody & Stearns</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George B. Post</ENAMEX>, and an up-and-coming young <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carr√®re & Hastings</ENAMEX>. The up-and-comers carried <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McKim</ENAMEX>, much to his chagrin, not only lost but placed <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> behind <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard & Cauldwell</ENAMEX>. It was his own fault, since he imperiously ignored the suggested plan and substituted his own arrangement. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carr√®re & Hastings</ENAMEX> conscientiously followed <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Billings‚</ENAMEX>Äô requirements.
The projected budget for the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> was not large (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.7 million</NUMEX>) and Billings expected a relatively modest <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>.* That was not what he got. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">All three</NUMEX> designs were monumental. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carr√®re & Hastings</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard & Cauldwell</ENAMEX> used the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Modern French</ENAMEX> style, which was more ornate and allowed for more articulation to the fa√ßade than the austere Classical style that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McKim</ENAMEX> opted for. All incorporated giant columns rising the full height of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> floors‚ÄîCorinthian in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">McKim‚Äôs</ENAMEX> case, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ionic</ENAMEX> in the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> (the completed <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corinthian</ENAMEX>). The compositional strategies were roughly similar: a monumental stair led to an elevated main floor; the entrance was placed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> (more understated in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">McKim‚</ENAMEX>Äôs elegant design); statuary and urns adorned the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">attic</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">All three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entrants</ENAMEX> shared a sense of what was beautiful and what was appropriate, and all were concerned with conveying the same message of permanence, dignity, and of culture rooted in the past.
I mentioned the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Public Library competition</ENAMEX> when I gave a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> lecture in connection with a recent architectural competition for the new <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Salt Lake City</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public Library</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library board</ENAMEX> had conducted a national search for an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX>, visited new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">libraries</ENAMEX> across the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, and solicited proposals from prominent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architects</ENAMEX>. They had narrowed their list to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Gwathmey</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Siegel</ENAMEX> are respected <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architects</ENAMEX> with a long record of university <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museums</ENAMEX>, including a new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> of science, industry, and business for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Public Library</ENAMEX> system. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moshe Safdie</ENAMEX> had built major civic <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, and recently completed the public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vancouver</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">British Columbia</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moore Ruble Yudell</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> founded by the late <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Moore</ENAMEX>, with whom <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Ruble</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buzz Yudell</ENAMEX> built several <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university libraries</ENAMEX> and a public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Berlin</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Will Bruder</ENAMEX>, the least well-known of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>, is a southwesterner and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX> of the new, well-regarded <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Phoenix Public Library</ENAMEX>.
I told my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> that I thought that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Salt Lake City</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library board</ENAMEX> would have a more difficult choice than their nineteenth<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">counterparts</ENAMEX>. It was not a question of function. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Salt Lake City</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">librarians</ENAMEX> had prepared an equally exhaustive program of requirements, so whichever <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX> was chosen commodity probably would be well served. As for firmness, I was reasonably sure that any of these experienced <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> would build soundly. It was the consideration of delight that would make the selection harder. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gwathmey</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Siegel</ENAMEX> design crisply detailed, understated <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> in a latter-day version of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Style</ENAMEX>. Safdie, too, is a modernist, but he follows in the footsteps of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pei</ENAMEX>, and his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> are frankly monumental‚Äîthe <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vancouver</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> had been likened to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Roman Coliseum</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moore Ruble Yudell‚</ENAMEX>Äôs work is different. Informal and animated, their eclectic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postmodern</ENAMEX> designs are likely to include ornament and architectural motifs drawn from their surroundings. Bruder, on the other hand, designs chic <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> that incorporate exposed structural elements, rough industrial materials, and sleek details. Building on the same site, fulfilling the same functional requirements, and using the same up-to-date construction technology, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> would produce <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">libraries</ENAMEX> that would look different.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library board</ENAMEX> awarded the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">commission</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moshe Safdie</ENAMEX>, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year later</TIMEX> the plans for the new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> were unveiled. The new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> will feature an unusual triangular-shaped main <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> and a curving wall-like structure that encloses a public <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">square</ENAMEX>. A <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">hundred years ago</TIMEX>, it was taken for granted that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Public Library</ENAMEX> would be designed in some variant of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Classical</ENAMEX> style. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> a public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> can take many guises. It can be relentlessly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">avant-garde</ENAMEX>, like the new <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.5 billion</NUMEX> national <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>, where the books are housed in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> L-shaped <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22</NUMEX>-story glass <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">towers</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> are lodged in underground <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX>, which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">London Times</ENAMEX> described as ‚Äúa series of rectangular <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">salons</ENAMEX> (identical of course) where you can admire the ultra-smooth gray concrete, steel grille ceilings and the expanses of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veneer</ENAMEX>.‚<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Äù1</NUMEX> A new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> can be comfortably <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Modernist</ENAMEX>, like the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British Library</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>, which the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Independent humorously</ENAMEX> described as ‚Äúa <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">giant</ENAMEX> municipal <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> that has made its way from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Scandinavia</ENAMEX>, having crashed headfirst through an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> brickworks on the way.‚<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Äù2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Beeby‚</ENAMEX>Äôs handsome <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harold T. Washington Library</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>, on the other hand, is distinctly old-fashioned, with rusticated stone walls and carved brick ornaments that are a literal evocation of the city‚Äôs nineteenth<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-century</TIMEX> architectural tradition. Instead of trendy <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">plastic</ENAMEX> or metal chairs, the reading areas are equipped with solid <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wood</ENAMEX> tables and traditional courthouse chairs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Ingo Freed‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Main Public Library</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX>, on the other hand, is both old and new: the imposing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">granite</ENAMEX> and stainless <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">steel</ENAMEX> exterior is more or less Classical on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> fa√ßade, and more or less Modernist on another.
The coexistence of different architectural styles is nothing new. In a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1913</TIMEX> essay titled ‚ÄúStyle in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Architecture</ENAMEX>,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù Ralph Adams Cram</ENAMEX> identified no less than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> contemporary styles, although he called them ‚Äútendencies.‚Äù Five were traditional: McKim‚Äôs pure <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Classicism</ENAMEX>; the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beaux-Arts French Modern; Colonial</ENAMEX>, which was associated with <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> but was also appearing in larger <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> such as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johns Hopkins University</ENAMEX> campus; Cram‚Äôs own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High Gothic</ENAMEX>; and a looser interpretation of the medieval style as practiced by his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goodhue</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> were new: <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">steel</ENAMEX>-frame construction, which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cram</ENAMEX> described as an enfant terrible; and what he called the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secessionists‚</ENAMEX>ÄîFrank <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lloyd Wright</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greene</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pasadena‚</ENAMEX>Äîwho exhibited ‚Äúa strongly developed enmity to archaeological forms of any kind.<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù Cram</ENAMEX> was not sanguine about the future, but he nevertheless concluded: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>ÄúChaos then confronts us, in that there is no single architectural following, but legion; and in that fact lies the honor of our art, for neither is society one, or ever at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> with itself.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">‚Äù3</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cram</ENAMEX> is right: most historical periods are marked by stylistic confusion; it is stylistic consensus that is unusual. There was such a brief consensus in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 1890s</TIMEX>, when both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architects</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>, under the influence of the immensely popular <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">World‚Äôs Columbian Exposition</ENAMEX>, embraced <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Classicism</ENAMEX>, at least for public <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>. That unanimity lasted long enough for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Public Library competition</ENAMEX>, but it began to unravel shortly after, as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cram‚</ENAMEX>Äôs essay makes clear. There was also a consensus in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1920s</TIMEX>, at least among progressive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architects</ENAMEX>. That consensus did not last either. After <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1940</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mies van der Rohe</ENAMEX> gave up the free-flowing plans and asymmetrical massing that had characterized the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Barcelona Pavilion</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tugendhat House</ENAMEX>, and began designing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> whose details and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">materials</ENAMEX> were <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Modern</ENAMEX> but whose layout and composition were distinctly Classical. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1920s</TIMEX>, Le <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Corbusier</ENAMEX> proclaimed the ‚ÄúFive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Points</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Architecture‚Äù</ENAMEX>: the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> raised on stilts; the roof garden; the frame structure that allowed a free plan; the free fa√ßade; and the horizontal ribbon window. He, too, had second thoughts. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thirty years later</TIMEX>, his wonderful chapel at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ronchamps</ENAMEX> had massive sculpted wall that concealed a concrete frame; the roof, far from being flat, resembled a billowing nun‚Äôs coif. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Le Corbusier</ENAMEX>, who had coined the famous expression, ‚Äúa <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> is a machine for living in,‚Äù <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> adopted distinctly un-machinelike building materials such as crudely finished concrete, exposed brick, roughened stucco, and fieldstone. This volte face gave rise to the so-called <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brutalist</ENAMEX> style, which had a worldwide influence, shaping the work of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architects</ENAMEX> as dissimilar as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Stirling</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Rudolph</ENAMEX>, and ultimately opening the door to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postmodern</ENAMEX> stylistic experiments such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Moore‚</ENAMEX>Äôs little <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Berkeley</ENAMEX> hills.
The inconstancy of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Style</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">practitioners</ENAMEX> should have been expected. The history of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Western</ENAMEX> architecture is of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architects</ENAMEX> searching for rules, only to bend and break them. Even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Classicism</ENAMEX>, which appears at <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> glance to be highly regimented, is not immune. As far as we know, the ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greeks</ENAMEX> used only <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> orders: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Doric, Ionic</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Corinthian</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vitruvius</ENAMEX> describes them, and also refers to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tuscan</ENAMEX> order, which is a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Roman</ENAMEX> invention. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roman</ENAMEX>, too, is the so-called Composite order, an ornate blend of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ionic</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Corinthian</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">vault</ENAMEX>, the arch, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dome</ENAMEX>, unknown to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greeks</ENAMEX>, were other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Roman</ENAMEX> additions to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Classic canon</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Architects</ENAMEX> have been stretching Classical rules ever since: breaking pediments, flattening pilasters, magnifying and shrinking columns, rusticating masonry. A <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixteenth-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Philibert de l‚ÄôOrme</ENAMEX>, invented a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> order; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edwin Lutyens</ENAMEX> devised an order based on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mughal</ENAMEX> precedents for the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Viceroy‚Äôs House</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Delhi</ENAMEX>; more recently, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allan Greenberg</ENAMEX> created an order for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary of State</ENAMEX> that incorporated the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great Seal</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Graves</ENAMEX> designed Classical caryatids (columns carved in the shape of human <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figures</ENAMEX>) to support the pedimented front of an office <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Walt Disney Company</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Burbank</ENAMEX>. While the supports of the porch of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Erechtheon</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Athens</ENAMEX> take the form of graceful maidens, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Graves‚</ENAMEX>Äô caryatids are the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seven Dwarfs</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> whose logo is a pair of mouse ears obviously demands a different decorum from a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX>. In the past, religious <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palaces</ENAMEX> required a narrow stylistic range. As architectural <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">commissions</ENAMEX> grew to include civic and commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">warehouses</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factories</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> and cinemas, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> and weekend houses‚Äîevery sort of building‚Äîa single style no longer sufficed. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gothic</ENAMEX> is an evocative style for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX>, but despite <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Walpole‚Äôs</ENAMEX> efforts it is ill-adapted to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Romanesque</ENAMEX> makes imposing city <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">halls</ENAMEX>, but is too heavy to be applied to skyscrapers. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Style</ENAMEX> makes striking small <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> but monotonous large ones. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shingle Style</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cottages</ENAMEX> are pleasing; a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shingle Style Home Depot</ENAMEX> is ridiculous. As <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cram</ENAMEX> wisely observed, ‚ÄúArchitecture is nothing unless it is intimately expressive, and if utterly different things clamor for voicing, different also must be their architectural manifestation.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">‚Äù4</ENAMEX>
The great architects‚ÄîBrunelleschi, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palladio, Wren</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richardson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lutyens‚</ENAMEX>Äîregularly looked to the past for inspiration. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1965</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Meier</ENAMEX> built the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Smith House</ENAMEX>, which has been called the first <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">International Style revival</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>. Like all revivalists, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Meier</ENAMEX> picks and chooses. At <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> glance, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Smith House</ENAMEX> has all the stylistic hallmarks of a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Le Corbusier villa of the 1920s:</ENAMEX> a free plan, flat roof, white walls, pipe railings, horizontal ribbon windows, a ramp. Yet it is built out of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wood</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">steel</ENAMEX>, not masonry. The white walls are painted wood siding, not stucco; the details are more refined, the plate-glass sheets are larger, the structure lighter. The result is an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Style</ENAMEX> that is filtered through <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> consciousness and shaped by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> technology. It is like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Jefferson</ENAMEX> building Classical columns out of wood‚Äîthe same, but different.
Although art <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historians</ENAMEX> use terms like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gothic Revival</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek Revival</ENAMEX> to distinguish later reincarnations of styles, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architects</ENAMEX> look at history differently. ‚ÄúFor the serious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX> the past exists not as a legacy to be possessed through a self-conscious act of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äòmodern‚Äô</ENAMEX> will,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù</ENAMEX> writes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Scruton</ENAMEX> in The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aesthetics of Architecture</ENAMEX>, ‚Äúbut as an enduring fact, an ineliminable part of an extended present.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚</ENAMEX>Äù5 That is why <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architects</ENAMEX>, whether they are <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Inigo Jones</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louis Kahn</ENAMEX>, make architectural <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pilgrimages</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mediterranean</ENAMEX> roots of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Western</ENAMEX> architecture. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sketchbook</ENAMEX> in hand, they plumb the secrets of the master <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">builders</ENAMEX> of the past. Consciousness of the past may also explain why <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architects</ENAMEX> tend to resist being categorized according to style; they instinctively understand that the history of architecture‚Äîincluding the present‚Äîis a continuity rather than a series of episodes.
Stylistic consistency is much admired <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, but it was not always so. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1419</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Filippo Brunelleschi</ENAMEX> began the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foundling Hospital</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florence</ENAMEX>, whose delicate arcade of Corinthian columns surmounted by pedimented windows is generally considered the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Renaissance</ENAMEX>. At the very same time, he was building a great <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dome</ENAMEX> over the crossing of the cathedral of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florence</ENAMEX> in a style that was not Classical but distinctly <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Gothic</ENAMEX>, pointed arches and all. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karl Friedrich Schinkel</ENAMEX> is best known for his severe Classical public <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> such as the superb <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Altes Museum</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Berlin</ENAMEX>, but he also worked in other styles: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gothic</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX>, and picturesque <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italianate</ENAMEX> in villas. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McKim</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mead & White</ENAMEX> favored the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Classical</ENAMEX> style for public <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> and palatial <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">residences</ENAMEX>, but built <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman</ENAMEX> parish <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shingle Style</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> retreats, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">French Renaissance</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mansions</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> Colonial country <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Russell Pope</ENAMEX>, an eclectic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX>, designed beautiful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">picturesque</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tudor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Georgian</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Colonial</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country estates</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edwin Lutyens</ENAMEX> was another <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Classicist</ENAMEX> whose residential work was eclectic.
Domestic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architects</ENAMEX> had to be adaptable, because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> styles changed according to fashion. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tudor</ENAMEX> was popular in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1900s</TIMEX>, as was the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Free Style; Cotswold</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Provincial</ENAMEX> appeared in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1920s</TIMEX>. After <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1930s</TIMEX>, influenced by the restoration of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Williamsburg</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> Colonial returned to favor. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cotswold</ENAMEX> style, with its relatively severe details and blunt forms, created a very different setting from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Provincial</ENAMEX>, which tended to have more delicate details, from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Free Style</ENAMEX> with its almost rustic atmosphere, or from sturdy Colonial. Since historic styles carry cultural overtones, using different styles was also a way for architects‚Äîand <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients‚Äîto</ENAMEX> say different things.
If architectural style is a language‚Äîan analogy that is deeply flawed‚Äîit is closer to slang than to grammatical prose. Architectural styles are mutable, unregulated, improvised. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Architects</ENAMEX> break the rules, and invent new ones. In part, this is simply the irrepressible urge of creative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>. In part, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architects</ENAMEX> break stylistic rules because they can. After all, most of the rules that govern building design‚Äîfire codes, building codes, zoning laws, budgets, programmatic requirements, engineering norms‚Äîare outside the architect‚Äôs control; stylistic rules are firmly within <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">his purview.</TIMEX> Since architecture is so intensely competitive, doing something unexpected, unusual, or just different is a way to be noticed, to rise above the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX>.
In addition to historical styles, there have also been styles associated with individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architects</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Palladian</ENAMEX> style made its way from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrea Palladio</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Inigo Jones</ENAMEX>, from him to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Colen Campbell</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lord Burlington</ENAMEX>, and thence to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Jefferson</ENAMEX>. It reappears in the work of contemporary <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Classicists</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allan Greenberg</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">H. H. Richardson‚</ENAMEX>Äôs influence was considerably shorter-lived, but for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at least 20 years</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Richardsonian Romanesque</ENAMEX> rolled over the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> like an <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">‚Äúaesthetic Juggernaut,‚Äù in Cram‚</ENAMEX>Äôs colorful phrase. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mies van der Rohe‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">steel</ENAMEX>-and-glass style likewise prevailed for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than two decades</TIMEX>, and his characteristic I-beam window mullion can still be seen in contemporary curtain walls.
Buildings like <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Jones‚Äô Palladian Queen‚Äôs House</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greenwich</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adler</ENAMEX> & <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Sullivan‚Äôs Richardsonian Romanesque Auditorium Building</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gordon Bunshaft‚Äôs Miesian Lever House</ENAMEX> are not copies but satisfying originals. However, most personal styles are not easily adaptable. A <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wright‚</ENAMEX>Äôs unmistakable <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Prairie</ENAMEX> style, for example, simply looks like a knock-off. Some personal styles are simply too obsessive, which is probably why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Furness</ENAMEX> and the equally idiosyncratic <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Barcelona</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Antonio Gaud√≠</ENAMEX> never attracted a following.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Inigo Jones</ENAMEX> consciously based his work on the architecture of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palladio</ENAMEX>, but he did not think of himself as working in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Palladian ‚Äústyle</ENAMEX>,‚Äù any more than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palladio</ENAMEX> would have referred to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Classical ‚Äústyle</ENAMEX>.‚Äù Although <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Renaissance</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architects</ENAMEX> described their architecture as all‚Äôantica‚Äîin the antique <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">manner‚Äîthey</ENAMEX> took it for granted that the history of architecture was a progression: the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Romans</ENAMEX> improved on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greeks</ENAMEX>, and they would improved on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Romans</ENAMEX>. According to the architecture <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Collins</ENAMEX>, the use of the word style to designate the architecture of a particular period or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> is relatively late. He cites <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Stuart</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicholas Revett‚Äôs Antiquities</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Athens</ENAMEX>, published in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1762</TIMEX> and credited with inaugurating the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Classical Revival</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX>, both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architects</ENAMEX>, referred to <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">‚Äúthe Grecian</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Roman</ENAMEX> style of building.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">‚Äù6</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin</ENAMEX> root of ‚Äústyle‚Äù is stilus. A stilus was the sharp-pointed tool used to write on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wax tablets</ENAMEX> and, by inference, stilus also referred to the way that something was written. This sense of technique carried over to <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>, and the original meaning of style was those features of literary composition that belonged to the form rather than to the substance of the matter being expressed. The seventeenth<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> musical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">composer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Samuel Wesley</ENAMEX> put it neatly: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>ÄúStyle is the dress of thought.<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù Jacques-Fran√ßois Blondel</ENAMEX>, who was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Louis XV‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX> and who founded the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> full-time <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> of architecture in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1750</TIMEX>, adopted this literary meaning as a metaphor and described architectural style as a building‚Äôs character‚Äîfor example, rustic, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">regal</ENAMEX>, or heroic. ‚ÄúStyle in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> of fa√ßades and in the decoration of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> is the poetry of architecture,‚Äù he taught his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>, ‚Äúwhich alone makes all the architect‚Äôs compositions truly interesting.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">‚Äù7</ENAMEX>
Literary style described the way that something was written, expressed, or performed. Architectural style, in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Blondel‚</ENAMEX>Äôs sense, describes the way that something was built. Although architecture is often defined in terms of abstractions such as space, light, and volume, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> are above all physical artifacts. The experience of architecture is palpable: the grain of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wood</ENAMEX>, the veined surface of marble, the cold precision of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">steel</ENAMEX>, the textured pattern of brick. But exactly what do we see when we look at brickwork? We see the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">joints</ENAMEX> between the bricks and the mortar (which can be flush, or scraped out to create shadows; the bonding patterns; the way that the bricks turn the corner; the surrounding of openings; and the connection between the brick wall and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundation</ENAMEX> or the eaves. What we see are details.
Details are a major preoccupation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX>. Once the overall form of a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> is determined‚Äî‚Äúthe masterly, correct, and magnificent play of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masses</ENAMEX> brought together in light‚Äù‚Äîthere remains the question not only of what materials are to be used and how these will be assembled, but also of how the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of parts of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> are to be designed: from the door frames and the window sills to the railings and the baseboards.
The function of a baseboard is to cover the joint between the wall and the floor, and secondarily to protect the wall from scuffing. There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of ways that this can be done. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baseboards</ENAMEX> can be prominent or discreet, a complicated assembly of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX>, cap and base, or a simple strip of hardwood. Or nothing‚Äîmany modern <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architects</ENAMEX> dispense with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">baseboards</ENAMEX> altogether. The baseboards in my living <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> are <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">twelve inches</NUMEX> tall. They are not wood but cast iron, since they are really disguised radiators. My <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> was built in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1908</TIMEX>, influenced by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British Free Style of Voysey</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Baillie Scott</ENAMEX>, and to further preserve a simple, rustic atmosphere the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX> had the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baseboards</ENAMEX>/radiators painted to resemble <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wood</ENAMEX>.
Railings have a simple function‚Äîthey must be sturdy enough to support us if we lean on them, and they must provide a secure hand-hold: if railings are open, the spaces between the supports and the rails should be small enough to prevent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> from falling through. Classical railings, developed during the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Renaissance</ENAMEX>, consist of balusters supporting a handrail. Balusters‚Äîlittle columns‚Äîcan have a single or a double swelling curve, or a vase shape. Fabricated in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wood</ENAMEX> or masonry, they can be round or <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">square</ENAMEX> in cross-section, and plain or highly ornamented. Railings can be replaced by parapets with pierced screens. These can be stone or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">metal</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bronze</ENAMEX>, wrought, or cast iron. The screens can be simple <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">X</NUMEX>-shapes, intertwining geometrical patterns, or complicated floral figures as in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Art Nouveau</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">staircases</ENAMEX>. Perhaps the simplest open railings are those of the great <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adirondack</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">camps</ENAMEX>, whose <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">builders</ENAMEX> mimicked <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">X</NUMEX>-shaped wrought-iron railings in unpeeled rustic <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree trunks</ENAMEX>.
Modern railings are usually metal. In his early villas, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Le Corbusier</ENAMEX> used white-painted pipe railings to create a nautical image; in later <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carpenter Center for the Visual Arts</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX>, flat steel bars take the place of pipes. The railings in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mies van der Rohe‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> usually have only a single intermediate rail, located precisely halfway between the handrail and the floor; the vertical stanchions, the handrail, and the rail are made of identical square steel bars. The railings in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louis Kahn</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> tend to be parapets, but where he is obliged to use an open railing the design is as simple as possible. I have seen a short stair railing that consisted of a single bronze <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX>, bent at each end to form the uprights. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Meier</ENAMEX> uses metal railings, too, but because there are sometimes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">as many as six</NUMEX> horizontal rails, the visual effect is more pronounced‚Äîthey resemble <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffs</ENAMEX> in sheet music.
When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brutalism</ENAMEX> was in fashion, railings were correspondingly heavy: <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">concrete</ENAMEX> beams, wide enough to sit on but unpleasant to the touch, or massive wood balustrades, as solid as fenders on a truck dock. The vogue among many younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architects</ENAMEX> today is toward lightness and exposed construction, and railings reflect that fashion, too. The screens of the railings of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Rose‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Canadian Center for Architecture</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Montreal</ENAMEX> are industrial-looking perforated sheets of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">anodized aluminum</ENAMEX>, prominently bolted to the stanchions. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bernard Tschumi</ENAMEX> substitutes steel cables (complete with turnbuckles) for the intermediate horizontal rails of the ramp railings of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lerner Hall</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia University</ENAMEX>, another nautical reference, but to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">yacht</ENAMEX> rather than a steamship. These solutions appear mannered compared to the simple railing that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">I. M. Pei</ENAMEX> designed for the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">East Building of the National Gallery</ENAMEX>. The stainless <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">steel</ENAMEX> handrail highlights the solidity of the rose-colored <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tennessee</ENAMEX> marble by appearing to float in mid-air, since it is supported by continuous sheets of tempered glass embedded in the floor.
The transparent railings of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">I. M. Pei‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">East Building</ENAMEX> are understated, elegant, and luxurious‚Äîlike the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚ÄúBeauty</ENAMEX> will result from the form and correspondence of the whole with respect to the several parts,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù</ENAMEX> taught <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palladio</ENAMEX>, ‚Äúof the parts with regard to each other, and of these again to the whole.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚</ENAMEX>Äù8 The successful relationship of the details to each other, and to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> is governed by the architect‚Äôs sense of style. That is why the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX> of my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> painted the radiators to resemble <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wood</ENAMEX>; a technologically inclined <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX> might have painted them silver; a minimalist would dispense with baseboards and hide the radiators in the wall. The role of details is not to complement architecture; details are architecture. ‚ÄúThe aesthetic understanding [of architecture],<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù</ENAMEX> writes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Scruton</ENAMEX>, ‚Äúis inseparable from a sense of detail.<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">‚Äù9 Mies</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">van der</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Rohe</ENAMEX> is supposed to have said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚ÄúGod</ENAMEX> is in the details.‚Äù* He did not mean that details are functionally important (although they are), or that good details prolong the life of a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> (although they do). He meant that details are the soul of architecture. That is why, just as an archaeologist can reconstruct a pot from a few shards, or a paleontologist can surmise the form of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">prehistoric animal</ENAMEX> from bone fragments, it is possible to divine the architect‚Äôs idea of a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> by examining its details.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Venturi</ENAMEX> built for his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1964</TIMEX> shook the foundations of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Style</ENAMEX>; much of this effect was the result of details. Although <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Venturi</ENAMEX> obviously was working in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Modernist idiom‚</ENAMEX>Äîthere is a strip window and a steel-pipe railing‚Äîhe also incorporated distinctly un-Modernist features such as trim, both inside and out. Classical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architects</ENAMEX> use a large variety of moldings‚Äîfillet, astragal, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">egg</ENAMEX> and dart, ogee‚Äîthat can be combined and recombined to great decorative effect. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Style</ENAMEX>, in its effort to do away with ornament, outlawed trim. Walls were flat <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX>. Windows had no frames. Joints between materials were simply hairline cracks. The conspicuous exterior dado, the baseboards, and the chair-rails in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Vanna Venturi House</ENAMEX> were hardly Classical moldings‚Äîthey were merely boards with chamfered edges‚Äîyet they challenged the assumption that trim and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Modernism</ENAMEX> were incompatible.
Coming through the front door of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanna Venturi House</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one</TIMEX> immediately senses that it is an unusual place. A broad stair rises beside the fireplace, then peters out to almost nothing. The fireplace looks like an abstract sculpture, but it has a traditional mantelpiece. A free-standing column √† <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">la Corbusier</ENAMEX> stands beside a chair-<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">rail</ENAMEX>. Then there is the furniture. Ever since the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tugendhat House‚</ENAMEX>Äîfor which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mies</ENAMEX> had designed the furniture‚Äîit was taken for granted that modern <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> required modern furniture. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Venturi</ENAMEX> has explained that ‚ÄúI designed the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> so my mother‚Äôs old furniture (c. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1925</TIMEX>, plus some antiques) would look good in it.<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">‚Äù10</ENAMEX> Instead of the iconic bent-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tube Breuer</ENAMEX> chairs, there are homely ladderback chairs around the dining table; instead of an <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Eames</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lounge</ENAMEX> chair and ottoman, a comfortable stuffed sofa. It is a contradictory atmosphere‚Äîthe <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Style</ENAMEX> willfully distorted through the lens of traditional bourgeois domesticity.
Whether one is looking up at the tall <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dome</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pantheon</ENAMEX>, descending the spiraling vortex of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wright‚Äôs Guggenheim Museum</ENAMEX>, or standing in the living room of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Venturi‚</ENAMEX>Äôs small <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, the experience of architecture is above all the experience of being in a separate, distinct world. That is what distinguishes architecture from sculpture‚Äîit is not an object but a place. The sense of being in a special place that is a three-dimensional expression of the architect‚Äôs imagination is one of the distinctive pleasures of architecture. To create a strong sense of place, the surroundings must be all of a piece; space, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mass</ENAMEX>, shapes, and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">materials</ENAMEX> must reflect the same sensibility. That is why details are so important. A jarring detail or an <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">inconsistency‚Äîsomething ‚Äúout</ENAMEX> of place‚Äù‚Äîand the fantasy begins to crumble. Yes, fantasy. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Illusion</ENAMEX> has been a part of architecture ever since the ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greeks</ENAMEX> made columns with a gently swelling taper to deceive the eye. This is not to say that architecture is stage d√©cor. When the wind blows, the canvas scenery blows over; the building resists the elements. Architecture surrounds and shelters us. It is the real world but it is also a vision.
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">‚Ä¢‚Ä¢‚Ä¢</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postmodern</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">movement</ENAMEX> that followed the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Vanna Venturi House</ENAMEX> was relatively short-lived but it had an important consequence: it broke the stranglehold of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Modernism</ENAMEX>, leaving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designers</ENAMEX> free to explore other forms of expression. The profusion of styles that ensued is demonstrated by the work of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gifted</ENAMEX> but vastly different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architects</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allan Greenberg</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hugh Newell Jacobsen</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Enrique Norten</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allan Greenberg</ENAMEX> is a confirmed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Classicist</ENAMEX>. He does not consider this an anomaly. ‚ÄúTo be truly modern,‚Äù he writes, ‚Äúmeans finding the dynamic balance between eternal human values and the specific demands of the present. Classical architecture provides the means to achieve this balance because it is the most comprehensive architectural language that human beings have yet developed.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚</ENAMEX>Äù11 Although <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenberg</ENAMEX> looks to the past, his is not the attitude of an archeologist. Like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carr√®re & Hastings</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generations</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architects</ENAMEX> before them, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenberg</ENAMEX> approaches <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Classicism</ENAMEX> as a tradition to be studied, absorbed‚Äîthen extended.
Early in his career, after emigrating to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Africa</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenberg</ENAMEX> was employed writing design standards for <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courthouses</ENAMEX>, which led to an unusual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">commission</ENAMEX>: the conversion of an empty supermarket into a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courthouse</ENAMEX>. He gave the commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manchester</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Connecticut</ENAMEX>, a new fa√ßade dominated by a large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arch</ENAMEX>, over-scaled voussoirs, and a pediment. Inside, the barrel-vaulted ceiling of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lobby</ENAMEX> was supported by a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tuscan</ENAMEX> order. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenberg</ENAMEX> had graduated from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1965</TIMEX>, and like many of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contemporaries</ENAMEX> was experimenting with the new freedom offered by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postmodernism</ENAMEX>. However, unlike <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Venturi</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moore</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenberg</ENAMEX> was not coyly introducing Classical elements into a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Modernist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>; he was returning to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Classical</ENAMEX> roots. From this modest beginning, over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next two decades</TIMEX>, came a variety of commissions: a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">suite</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary of State</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States Department of State</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>, several <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> and university <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>, and a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roman Catholic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX>. His commercial work included a newspaper office <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Athens</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgia</ENAMEX>, a new entrance for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bergdorf Goodman</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Fifth Avenue</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX>, and a flagship <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tommy Hilfiger</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beverly Hills</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenberg</ENAMEX> is also known for large country <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX>, both in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>. Like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lutyens</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Russell Pope</ENAMEX>, he ventures stylistically farther afield in his residential work‚Äîusing <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Georgian</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> Colonial styles. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of his early <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> was inspired by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mount Vernon</ENAMEX>, another by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palladio‚</ENAMEX>Äôs unfinished <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Villa Thiene</ENAMEX>. Several are picturesque rambling affairs whose relaxed informality recalls the best work of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McKim</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mead & White</ENAMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of my favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenberg</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> is a cottage set among windblown dunes on the eastern seaboard. Completed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">low-lying building</ENAMEX> is shingled, but it is not exactly <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Shingle Style</ENAMEX>. Recent <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Shingle Style</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> are often broken down into many small parts, giving them a fussy and nervous appearance. Such seaside <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cottages</ENAMEX> look as if a good wind could blow them away. Greenberg‚Äôs aim here is to make a heavyweight <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> of great solidity that is rooted firmly in the dune scrub. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-story <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Atlantic</ENAMEX> fa√ßade is almost perfectly symmetrical: a large arched window flanked by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> semi-circular bays, rotund sentinels standing against the ocean winds. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-story landward side is more informal, ringed by a sheltered porch. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Massivity</ENAMEX> informs the details: sturdy Tuscan columns, a heavy cornice at the eaves of the large roof, rugged window frames. The sense of robustness is accentuated by occasional delicacy: the arched window incorporates scrolled brackets that support an elegant reverse ogee molding at the eaves. Inside, the fireplace has a brick <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hearth</ENAMEX>, a slate lintel, and a wood surround, whose almost modern simplicity is softened by a cavetto molding beneath the mantelpiece. The ceiling is supported by exposed trusses of rough, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">reused timbers</ENAMEX>. Although most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would describe this <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> as ‚Äútraditional,‚Äù this is not an exercise in a particular historical style. There is a nod here to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British Arts and Crafts</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX>  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. F. A. Voysey</ENAMEX>, and it is obvious that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenberg</ENAMEX> has looked at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lutyens‚Äô</ENAMEX> country <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX>. But this is a modern <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, although designed by an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX> with a Classical sensibility. It admirably fulfills <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palladio‚</ENAMEX>Äôs call for a correspondence of the whole with the parts and the parts with the whole.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hugh Newell Jacobsen</ENAMEX> studied at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale</ENAMEX> under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louis Kahn</ENAMEX>, worked for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Philip Johnson</ENAMEX>, and opened his own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1958</TIMEX>. He established himself as a premier residential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX>, winning commissions in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and abroad and receiving numerous design awards. Several of the awards were for restoration of historic <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>, notably the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Renwick Gallery</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">H√¥tel Talleyrand</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>. A Modernist by training and inclination, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacobsen</ENAMEX> was, nevertheless, affected by the winds of change unleashed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Venturi‚</ENAMEX>Äôs little <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX>. Starting in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX>, he evolved a hybrid style in which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX> regional forms and materials are combined with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Style</ENAMEX> precision, spareness, and simplicity. A <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nantucket</ENAMEX> in shingles and white trim looks vernacular until one notices the careful proportions and refined, elegant details such as tall <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> doors in the living <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> that slide into wall pockets that also conceal shutters and screen doors. A post-and-beam <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Caribbean</ENAMEX> guest <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> with broad overhangs has the ingenuous simplicity of a beach shack. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palladian</ENAMEX> plan and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX>-like pavilions of an <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">residence</ENAMEX> pay homage to the local <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek Revival</ENAMEX>. An <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">country house</ENAMEX> recalls a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX>-and<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">-batten Gothic Revival</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farmhouse</ENAMEX>. ‚ÄúI endeavor to design <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> that express a sense of belonging,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù Jacobsen</ENAMEX> says, ‚Äúbuildings that reflect or abstract the nearby architecture and the traditions dictated by the climate and local materials.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">‚Äù12</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palmedo House</ENAMEX>, built in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>, reinterprets the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> Colonial architecture of its location‚<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ÄîLong Island</ENAMEX>. At <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> glance, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> pavilions resemble a little <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">village</ENAMEX>, a little <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Amish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">village</ENAMEX>, judging from the austere white <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wood</ENAMEX> siding, the prim details, and the identical pitched roofs. Each <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pavilion</ENAMEX> is a perfect little <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúhouse‚Äù</ENAMEX> with identical <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">square</ENAMEX> and vertical multi-paned windows (that open by sliding into cunning wall pockets). This sounds precious, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacobsen</ENAMEX> is not a romantic. The central <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">‚Äúhouse‚Äù</ENAMEX> contains the living room, a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">three-story</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">space</ENAMEX> open to the roof. Although the multi-paned windows are present at an upper level of the wall, the corner of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> is glazed with large, mullionless sheets of plate glass, offering dramatic views of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Long Island Sound</ENAMEX>. This is an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International</ENAMEX> Style device, as is the economy of detail and the clean, cool, atmosphere of the interior. On the other hand, the fireplace, which in an orthodox <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">International Style</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> would be painted brick or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bush</ENAMEX>-hammered concrete, is decorously built into the wall, which gives the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> a traditional, civilized air. The chief idea here is to highlight the tension between old and new, between the traditional clapboarded architecture and the demands of modern life. Whereas <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenberg</ENAMEX> seamlessly resolves this tension, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacobsen</ENAMEX> allows it to surface. If this sounds like textbook <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Postmodernism</ENAMEX>, it is not. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacobsen</ENAMEX> artlessly combines new and old without the slightest hint of irony.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jacobsen</ENAMEX> reacts to the collapse of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Modernism</ENAMEX> by seeking a compromise position, while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenberg</ENAMEX> anchors himself in the certainties of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Classicism</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Enrique Norten</ENAMEX>, the youngest of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>, takes a different course‚Äîhe is trying to put <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Modernism</ENAMEX> back together again. Norten, who studied at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cornell</ENAMEX>, established his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> in his native <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico City</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985</TIMEX>. In a relatively short time he produced an impressive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> of work that includes institutional, commercial, and residential <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>. His major projects are a services building for the media <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">giant</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TELEVISA</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National School of Theater</ENAMEX>. Both incorporate bulging, metal shell-roofs that recall the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">1950s</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect-engineer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jean Prouv√©</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prouv√©</ENAMEX> was intent on applying new methods of construction, particularly industrialization and prefabrication. His <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>, extremely light and assembled from standardized elements, were real ‚Äúmachines for living.<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù Norten</ENAMEX>, too, is preoccupied with industrial <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> technologies, the lighter the better. Double-tensed glass curtain walls are mysteriously supported by a steel-frame. Roofs hang by steel cables from steel masts. Slender, canted columns brace a glass-roofed <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">portico</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Railings</ENAMEX>, in a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Norten</ENAMEX> design, are almost always opportunities for structural legerdemain: suspended sheets of glass, stretched steel cables, perforated metal screens.
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Norten</ENAMEX> built a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> for himself and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> on a tight urban site in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico City</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>-story <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> fa√ßade is mostly a blank concrete wall; the wall facing the interior walled patio is entirely glass. The main living <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">floor</ENAMEX> is open, except for the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen</ENAMEX>; the upper <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedroom floor</ENAMEX> is shaded and given privacy by a redwood, louvered screen. A functionalist style pervades the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>. The clinical <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cabinetwork</ENAMEX> is white-painted <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wood</ENAMEX>. A concrete wall in the dining <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> is bare save for the regular pattern of the formwork ties and the pour lines marks. The windows are large sections of plate glass in simple aluminum frames; a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10-foot</NUMEX> section slides aside to entirely open the dining <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> to the patio. The sliding wall recalls the disappearing windows in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mies</ENAMEX> van der <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Rohe‚Äôs Tugendhat House</ENAMEX>, but the resemblance ends here. Mies‚Äô spare interior is opulent and assertive; Norten‚Äôs is austere, almost monastic: a neutral background for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> life. This is an unsentimental idea of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>. Not exactly a ‚Äúmachine for living,‚Äù but certainly machinelike in its precision and rational layout.
Like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenberg</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacobsen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Norten</ENAMEX> reflects on the past. Although his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> has little to do formally with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Style</ENAMEX> of the flat-roofed stucco <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">villas</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1920s‚Äîexcept</TIMEX> for the white-painted circular steel columns‚Äîit shares that period‚Äôs ambitions; it is highly abstract, idealistic, technophile, and lacking in applied ornament. Decoration results not from trim, but from the surface quality of the different materials‚Äîconcrete, red oak flooring, etched glass‚Äîand from the relentless articulation of structural connections. Norten‚Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> exhibit another feature of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Style</ENAMEX>: they are placeless. That is, while they carefully respond to the specifics of the program and the site, they do not explicitly acknowledge their immediate regional context. Whether they are in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Mexico‚Äîwhere Norten</ENAMEX> is building a heritage center‚Äîthe style is the same: understated, coolly competent, cosmopolitan.
Whether <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> prefers the work of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenberg</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacobsen</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norten</ENAMEX> is a matter of taste (I happen to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">like all three</NUMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> are different, yet the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architects</ENAMEX> have something in common. They are serious about what they are doing, that is, their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> exhibit a strong sense of conviction. They pay enormous attention to details. They are disciplined, but they understand their self-imposed rules well enough to occasionally break them. Moreover, while their architecture is built with a great sense of style, it is never merely stylized. That is because in their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>, style‚Äîthe manner of expression‚Äîis always in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> of content‚Äîthat which is being expressed. Style without content quickly degenerates into caricature, like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX> who makes grand gestures and rhetorical flourishes, but has nothing to say. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenberg</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacobsen</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norten</ENAMEX>, on the contrary, have a great deal to tell us about our past, our surroundings, and ourselves.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenberg</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacobsen</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norten</ENAMEX> do not describe what they do in terms of style. I think that there are a number of reasons that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architects</ENAMEX> are uncomfortable talking about the subject. A suspicion of style is a heritage of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Modern Movement</ENAMEX>, which preached against the arbitrary dictates of style and fashion, while maintaining an unspoken but rigid stylistic consistency. So deep-rooted is this teaching that it remains a moral stricture on most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architects</ENAMEX>, whether or not they are <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Modernists</ENAMEX>. Perhaps another reason for the reluctance to discuss style is fear. Fear that being linked to a particular style is to be put in a box‚Äîlike most creative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architects</ENAMEX> dislike being categorized. Also fear that talking about style will make architecture‚Äîa serious business‚Äîsound frivolous. Better to leave that to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">interior decorators</ENAMEX> and fashion <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designers</ENAMEX>, professions that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architects</ENAMEX> regard with a mixture of disdain and envy. Finally, there is an unspoken fear of style because it is subject to the whims and the fancies of fashion. That fear, at least, seems to me to be ill-founded. An architecture that recognizes style‚Äîand fashion‚Äîwould not be an architecture that is introspective and self-referential, as are so many contemporary <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>. It would be part of the world‚Äînot architecture for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architects</ENAMEX>, but architecture for the rest of us. And that would not be a bad thing.

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coda</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Morris Hunt</ENAMEX> was the most celebrated <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX> of the late <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nineteenth century</TIMEX>. His preeminence is reflected by his appointment as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> important national works: the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centerpiece building</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago World‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Columbian Exposition</ENAMEX>, and the pedestal for the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Statue of Liberty</ENAMEX>. He was feted at home and abroad. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hunt</ENAMEX> was the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX> to receive an honorary doctorate from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX> and the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> to receive a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gold Medal</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royal Institute of British Architects</ENAMEX>, and he was made an honorary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Acad√©mie</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Chevalier of the Legion of Honor</ENAMEX>. A <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">hundred years later</TIMEX>, his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counterpart</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank O. Gehry</ENAMEX>. Since being awarded the prestigious <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pritzker Prize</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gehry</ENAMEX> has gone on to win more honors than any other living <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX>, including such major arts awards as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dorothy</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lillian Gish Prize</ENAMEX> (a non-architectural award of which he is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipient</ENAMEX>) and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> Praemium Imperiale, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nobel</ENAMEX> of the art world. Even the staid <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Institute of Architects</ENAMEX>, which had previously shunned <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gehry</ENAMEX> in lieu of more mainstream <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">practitioners</ENAMEX>, awarded him its top accolade, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AIA Gold Medal</ENAMEX>.
No pair of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architects</ENAMEX> could be more dissimilar than this distinctly odd <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX>, the proper <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High Society</ENAMEX> favorite of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gilded Age</ENAMEX> and the untidy bohemian from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Monica</ENAMEX>. Yet they bear comparison. They were both late bloomers. Gehry was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">48</TIMEX> when he gained national recognition. Until then, he had been running his own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">almost twenty years</TIMEX>, building shopping <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX>, suburban <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX>, department <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartments</ENAMEX> in competent but unremarkable renditions of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">L.A.</ENAMEX> modern. The project that brought him to national attention was his own remodeled <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>: a nondescript bungalow encased in an unsettling Cubist composition of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">unpainted plywood</ENAMEX>, corrugated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">metal</ENAMEX>, and chain-link fencing. The odd shapes and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">unorthodox materials</ENAMEX> marked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gehry</ENAMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">maverick</ENAMEX>. That was in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1978</TIMEX>. Unexpectedly, he attracted a broad range of commissions, not only residential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>, but also <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museums</ENAMEX>, public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">developers</ENAMEX>, and not only in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> but around the world.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hunt</ENAMEX> was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">43</TIMEX> when he came into his own. He had established an architectural <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">practice</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1855</TIMEX>, almost immediately on his return from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ecole des Beaux-Arts</ENAMEX>. He was moderately successful, achieving local renown for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tribune Building</ENAMEX>, an early <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">skyscraper</ENAMEX>. Despite his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parisian</ENAMEX> background, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hunt</ENAMEX> worked in the prevalent <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ruskinian Gothic</ENAMEX> style. Of his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Presbyterian Hospital</ENAMEX> in downtown <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX>, the architectural <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Montgomery Schuyler</ENAMEX> wrote: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>ÄúThe <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> is of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gothic</ENAMEX> design with very red brick, and very irregular stone <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dressings</ENAMEX>, which, it must be confessed regretfully, are not pleasing to the eye.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚</ENAMEX>Äù3 For his next project, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lenox Library</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hunt</ENAMEX> tried something different. He borrowed from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> Neo-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grec</ENAMEX> style, popularized by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labrouste</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Biblioth√®que Sainte Genevi√®ve</ENAMEX>, adding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Renaissance</ENAMEX> details and his own characteristically vigorous surface modeling. The result was a startling departure from convention, a monochrome limestone block of imposing dignity. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lenox Library</ENAMEX> (which stood on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Fifth Avenue</ENAMEX> on the site of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">present-day</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Frick Collection</ENAMEX>) marked a shift in architectural taste, away from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruskin</ENAMEX> to a grand and frankly aesthetic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Classicism</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">1880s</NUMEX> was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a decade</TIMEX> of great prosperity, and newly wealthy <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">New Yorkers</ENAMEX> eagerly sought out <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hunt‚</ENAMEX>Äôs architectural blend of good taste and ostentatious display. He obliged them in a string of high-profile commissions: magnificent <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mansions</ENAMEX> along <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Fifth Avenue</ENAMEX>, country <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Long Island</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">palatial ‚Äúcottages‚Äù</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Newport</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rhode Island</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hunt</ENAMEX> died in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1895</TIMEX>, but in the last <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven years</TIMEX> of his life, he completed more than fifty projects.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Biltmore House</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Asheville</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX>, is a good example of his stylistic prowess. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hunt</ENAMEX> modeled the design of this <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">250</NUMEX>-room <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">residence</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ch√¢teau de Blois</ENAMEX>, whose style is not the severe <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Classicism</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Renaissance</ENAMEX> favored by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architects</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles McKim</ENAMEX>, but the more ornate and picturesque <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">French Renaissance</ENAMEX>. To a modern <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitor</ENAMEX>, the spires, turrets, and steep slate roofs of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Biltmore</ENAMEX> recall <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Disneyland‚Äôs Sleeping Beauty Castle</ENAMEX>, which is not surprising since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> also used a <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Loire Valley</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">chateau‚Äîthe Ch√¢teau d‚ÄôUss√©‚</ENAMEX>Äîas his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX>. But the comparison does <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hunt</ENAMEX> an injustice, for his design is neither prettified nor quaint. His client, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Vanderbilt</ENAMEX>, was a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bachelor</ENAMEX> (he married soon after the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> was finished), and for him <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hunt</ENAMEX> created an architecture that is robust, masculine, and immensely self-assured, not in the least like a fairytale.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vanderbilt</ENAMEX> was drawn to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">French chateaux</NUMEX>, which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hunt</ENAMEX> showed him during a whirlwind <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> tour, since young <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wealthy family</ENAMEX> imagined themselves <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> aristocrats. There are coats of arms bearing Vs all over the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hunt</ENAMEX> provides his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX> with an imagined regal setting, but deals with the past in his own peculiar way. Although he modeled the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blois</ENAMEX>, he makes no attempt to create a replica of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixteenth-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">chateau</ENAMEX>, but draws details from other <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> of the period and recombines them into an original whole. Nor does he try to create the illusion that this is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sixteenth-century building‚</ENAMEX>Äîthere is no artificial weathering, no aging effect no simulated historicism. The interior is modern, bright, and open. The focus of the main floor is a glass-roofed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">conservatory</ENAMEX>, a common nineteenth<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-century</TIMEX> feature. The stonework of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> is impeccable, much crisper and more sharply defined than at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blois</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hunt</ENAMEX> was no antiquarian, and modern <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> technology abounds. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">floors</ENAMEX> of fireproof hollow tile are supported by steel <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">I-</ENAMEX>beams and the steep slate roofs by <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">steel</ENAMEX> roof trusses. Cast iron replaces wrought iron and high-quality bricks, fired in the estate brickworks, back-up the limestone walls. Equally novel are the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">elevators</ENAMEX> and telephones, electrical lighting, hot and cold running <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>, and forced air central heating. There is no doubt that for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hunt</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Biltmore</ENAMEX> is an up<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">-to-the-minute</TIMEX> modern <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>. That is part of its style, too.
Like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hunt</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Gehry</ENAMEX> enlists novel materials in his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guggenheim Museum</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bilbao</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX>, for example, is clad in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">titanium</ENAMEX>, previously used chiefly for building <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX>. The metallic walls curve, twist, and turn. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> slides under an <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">adjoining</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridge</ENAMEX>; another emerges from a reflecting pool. Bilbainos refer to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> as the ‚Äúartichoke,‚Äù which comes close to describing it, if you can imagine a gleaming, metallic artichoke <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">more than two hundred feet</NUMEX> high. The seeming disorder‚Äîa chaotic collision of forms‚Äîhas no architectural precedent. This is not sculptural architecture, it is walk-in sculpture.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚ÄúThe</ENAMEX> plan is the generator‚Äù preached <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Le Corbusier</ENAMEX>, but with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gehry</ENAMEX>, the plan is the result. He appears to design from the outside in. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> as a composition comes first, the interior spaces follow. This implies that he shoehorns functions into the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>, which is not the case. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guggenheim</ENAMEX> has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> distinct types of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">gallery</ENAMEX> spaces: traditional, skylit <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> for displaying its permanent collection of early <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Modernist</ENAMEX> art; a long boat-like space for temporary installations; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">galleries</ENAMEX>, each with its own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>, each dedicated to the works of a selected living <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>. The artichoke accommodates them all. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> may appear offhanded, but there is nothing haphazard about the way it is organized.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gehry‚Äôs</ENAMEX> talent is his exceptional formal imagination; his skill as an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX> is to reconcile the forms he imagines with the functional demands of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX>. And, of course, to find ways to build those forms. This is generally done without fuss. The titanium sheets simply follow the churning surfaces like shingles on a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Shingle Style roof</ENAMEX>; limestone is used in a similarly unaffected fashion, without articulated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">joints</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gehry</ENAMEX> shares a minimalist approach to details with the early <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architects</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Style</ENAMEX>, but he deploys these details to different ends. By removing familiar elements such as coping strips, fascias, and trim, he accentuates the sculptural quality of his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>. There are no roofs or walls or windows in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guggenheim</ENAMEX>, there are only swirling and twisting <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">metal</ENAMEX>, stone, and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glass</ENAMEX>. An architecture <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> once described <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gehry</ENAMEX> as ‚Äúa smart <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>,‚Äù which nicely captures the architect‚Äôs blend of exuberant showmanship and canny behind-the-scenes savvy.
Although sophisticated building techniques and innovative materials play a major role in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gehry‚Äôs</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hunt</ENAMEX>, he keeps technology off center stage. In that regard, he repudiates the mannered industrial style that pervades the work of many contemporary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architects</ENAMEX>. Neither is he nostalgic about the past. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Gehry</ENAMEX> rejects both the moralistic functionalism of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Style</ENAMEX> and the traditions of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Classicism</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Architects</ENAMEX> have broken rules in the past, but rarely this unequivocally and totally.
Gehry, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hunt</ENAMEX>, has changed the course of architecture. That is, he has made us look at our surroundings in a different way. The world of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gehry‚</ENAMEX>Äôs <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> is, at <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> glance, an odd place. The line between order and disorder is a thin one, and it is difficult to know what is intended and what is accidental. But his colliding forms and agitated architecture are curiously unthreatening. This is the way we live <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gehry</ENAMEX> seems to be saying, why not enjoy it?




