
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">187</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">&quot;Photo Fun&quot</ENAMEX>;

            

               I give the caption, you briefly describe the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Associated Press</ENAMEX> photo:
"Protesting the export of trash by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">demonstrators</ENAMEX>
gathered outside a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Harrisburg</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pa.</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> to assail <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudolph</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">W. Giuliani</ENAMEX>, who was inside at a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> dinner."
            

             

            by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> to e-mail your answer to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            

               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>'s question (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 186</ENAMEX>)--" <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">'s Cool":</ENAMEX>
            

            

               
                  
                     
                        Joining a national trend, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">superintendent</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Greenwich</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">R.I.</ENAMEX>, ordered these turned off during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>.
What?
                     
                  
               
            

            "Moral
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">compasses</ENAMEX>."--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer Miller</ENAMEX>
            

            "Those
lunchroom slot machines that the gambling industry had such high hopes
for."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jay Majors</ENAMEX>
            

            "Really
big pagers, set on 'vibrate.' "-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dianne Carter</ENAMEX>
            

            "The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>' libidos, as per <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">the instructions</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wendy Shalit</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Narver</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Darren Thorneycroft</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carrie Rickey</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Colleen</ENAMEX>
Werthmann , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlie Glassenberg</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aaron Schatz</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brad</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spencer</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Thomas</ENAMEX> had similar answers.)

            "The
natural spark of joy within young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Radosh</ENAMEX> (similarly,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Finkle</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gabriel Nelson</ENAMEX> [grade <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>], <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Charles Star</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ballard</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judith Spencer</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Milner</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Krause</ENAMEX> ,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marshall Efron</ENAMEX> [Sponsored <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pedigree Dog Food</ENAMEX>. "Recommended
by top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">breeders</ENAMEX>."])

            Click
for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more</NUMEX> responses.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
            

            The atmosphere is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soul-deadening</ENAMEX>, the young are armed and bored, their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elders</ENAMEX> are armed and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">feeble</ENAMEX>, and everyone is in a constant state of sexual arousal. Life aboard ship
is tough; no wonder <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recruiters</ENAMEX> have trouble meeting their staffing goals.
Coincidentally, this is also the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Quiz</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">participants</ENAMEX>. Although a few of you target drug-dealing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>, by far the
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">predominant attack</ENAMEX> is directed at unimaginative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX>, stuffy
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">administrators</ENAMEX>, and private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> exploiting a captive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. I've never felt prouder to be associated with a group of strangers
identifiable only by their (no doubt spurious) e-mail addresses.

            
               Effervescent
Answer
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Soda</ENAMEX> machines are turned off during school
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX>.

            "In health <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classes</ENAMEX>, we're teaching <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> one
thing about nutrition," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Superintendent Robert Hicks</ENAMEX>, "and they leave those
classes and go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lunchroom</ENAMEX>, and we're promoting candy and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">soda</ENAMEX> sales. We
should live our words better."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> can still buy <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cookies</ENAMEX>, chips, and ice cream
at the school snack bar; federal law does not ban their <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">lunch hour</TIMEX> sale at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> receiving food aid.

            Many school districts,
short of revenue, have made deals with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">soft drink</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>. Average
consumption is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">868</NUMEX> cans a year for teen-age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">600</NUMEX> cans for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX>. Both
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oregon</ENAMEX> have begun restricting soda machines.

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last Week</TIMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shooting Percentages Extra</ENAMEX>
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Knicks</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Orlando Magic</ENAMEX>

            (season opener)

            Shots taken: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">74</NUMEX>. Shots made: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35</NUMEX>. Percentage: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">47</NUMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Police Department</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amadou</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diallo</ENAMEX> (unarmed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">West African</ENAMEX> with no police record)

            Shots taken: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">41</NUMEX>. Shots
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">made: 19</ENAMEX>. Percentage: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">46</NUMEX>.

            
               Race
Results
            

            Top <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">target</ENAMEX>:
Spirit-crushing pedagogy.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Disclaimer</ENAMEX>: All
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">submissions</ENAMEX> will become the property of 
               
                  Slate
               

               and will be published at 
               
                  Slate
               
               's
discretion. 
               
                  Slate
                
               may publish your name on its
site in connection with your submission .

         
      
   
