
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">184</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">&quot;Post-Game Blame&quot</ENAMEX>;

            
               Fill in the blank
on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Falcon</ENAMEX>'s analysis of his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Super Bowl</ENAMEX> loss. "Instead of
getting mentally ready for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Broncos</ENAMEX>, we were ___________."
            

             

            by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">p.m. ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> to e-mail your answer to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            

               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s question (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 183</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Three Times To":</ENAMEX>
            

            
               The answer, from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Clarke</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s counterterrorism <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coordinator</ENAMEX>, is: "To extort
us, to intimidate us, to get us to abandon our foreign policy."
            

            

               What's the question?
            

            "Why do
black college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> play their big, expensive stereos so loud around

                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffers</ENAMEX>?"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katha Pollitt</ENAMEX>
            

            "Why
are so many of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> starving to death?"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Sullivan</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Can</ENAMEX>
you give examples of a direct object in an infinitive phrase<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brooke</ENAMEX>
Saucier
            

            
"There's no question. This is an excerpt from the voice-over credo read in the
opening credits for the new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">UPN</ENAMEX> series <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Star Trek: Pitiful Helpless</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Giant</ENAMEX> , starring former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary of State</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Shultz</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Diamond</ENAMEX>
            

            "Why
would <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Flatley</ENAMEX> threaten to perform an all-nude version of
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Riverdance ?</ENAMEX>"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Davis</ENAMEX>
            

            Click
for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more</NUMEX> responses.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
            

            Which aspect of our
foreign policy does <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Clarke</ENAMEX> most fear will be abandoned--standing around
while <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX> are slaughtered in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rwanda</ENAMEX> or standing around while <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX>
are slaughtered in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>? Or does <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarke</ENAMEX> burn to preserve our more activist
policy, promoting the suffering of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX>? Perhaps when the unworkable
but stylishly nostalgic Star Wars anti-missile system is deployed, a part of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s request for the biggest increase in the military spending
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarke</ENAMEX> will lose his fear of abandonment. Or maybe he should switch
to chamomile <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tea</ENAMEX>.

            
               All Too Hackable
Answer
            

            Why would cyberterrorists want to assault <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">911</ENAMEX> system, inquired <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Weiner</ENAMEX>.

            "It's as bad as being attacked by bombs," says
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarke</ENAMEX>, with the characteristic enthusiasm that once fueled his psychological
war efforts against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Libya</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarke</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX> plan included setting off scary sonic
booms near <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Muammar Qaddafi</ENAMEX> to ... well, scare him. The plot collapsed when
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarke</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sponsors</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> got caught planting lies in the
Wall Street <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> about <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Libyan</ENAMEX> support of terrorism.

            Currently working out of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oliver North</ENAMEX>'s old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarke</ENAMEX> maintains a lighthearted attitude toward the
law that has not discouraged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> from expanding counterterror
activities into an <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$11 billion</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> endeavor.

            
               Civil Disobedience
Extra
            

            Match the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> response
to the demonstration.

            
               Riot
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Police</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A. Police</ENAMEX> fire tear <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B. Soldiers</ENAMEX> fire tear <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">C. Police</ENAMEX> throw tear gas <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">grenades</ENAMEX>, pound nightsticks
on shields.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">D. Police</ENAMEX> use tear <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas</ENAMEX>, batons, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water canon</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">E. Police</ENAMEX> fire rubber-coated steel <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pellets</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">F. Troops</ENAMEX> brandish <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Galil</ENAMEX> assault <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">rifles</ENAMEX>; vigilantes
use <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">rifles</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pistols</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">machetes</ENAMEX> to kill <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">45</NUMEX> suspected looters.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G. Police</ENAMEX> use attack
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX>, pepper <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">spray</ENAMEX>, fire hoses.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Demonstrators</ENAMEX>
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Romania</ENAMEX>, stone throwing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">miners</ENAMEX> march
toward <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bucharest</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kenya</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> protesting unrestrained
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">development</ENAMEX> plant <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kauru</ENAMEX> forest.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Palestine</ENAMEX>, after a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">funeral</ENAMEX> for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX> killed
by a rubber-coated steel pellet, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rioters</ENAMEX> hurl <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">stones</ENAMEX> and firebombs at <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Armenia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rioters</ENAMEX> fight for relief
supplies.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Grand Junction</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colo.</ENAMEX>, celebrate the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Broncos</ENAMEX>' victory.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Broncos</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greeley</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colo.</ENAMEX>, pelt cops with rocks and bottles.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Denver</ENAMEX> fans celebrate a <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Super Bowl</ENAMEX> win by overturning <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>, breaking windows,
setting fires.

            

               Answers
            

            
               A-6,
B-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C-7</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">E-3</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F-4</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G-5</ENAMEX>.
            

            
               Race
Results
            

            Replies referring to actual events in the world:
23.

            Replies referring to movies, television, etc.:
14.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ambiguous</ENAMEX> replies: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Disclaimer</ENAMEX>: All
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">submissions</ENAMEX> will become the property of 
               
                  Slate
               

               and will be published at 
               
                  Slate
               
               's
discretion. 
               
                  Slate
                
               may publish your name on its
site in connection with your submission .

         
      
   
