
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Parkersburg</ENAMEX>

            To hear the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX> read
"<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Parkersburg</ENAMEX>," click .

            I will
arise now and put on a black baseball cap and go
to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Parkersburg</ENAMEX>. It will fit me,
the cap will, and it will be black,
the sneakers on my feet will be purple,
and I will not have shaved for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three days</TIMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">The day</TIMEX> will be rainy and cool
and I will wear an old jacket of pale <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wool</ENAMEX>
that was once my <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Uncle Lew</ENAMEX>'s.
And go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Parkersburg</ENAMEX>.

            On a
bus I may go
or in an old car full of tapes--
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Elmore James</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred McDowell</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kinks</ENAMEX>. Into the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Parkersburg</ENAMEX>
on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a day</TIMEX> so rainy and cool. And I will be
terrifically untroubled if anyone thinks I am strange,
in fact everything about this day will be a ratification
of how I am not them; and my manner, though courteous,
will tend to make them suspect that they are boring.
They will wonder why they have no purple sneakers. Cool

            and
lightly rainy in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Parkersburg</ENAMEX>
and me <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all day</TIMEX> there exactly as if my belief
had long been <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>; not forgetting for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one minute</TIMEX>
how I felt listening to "I'm <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Different</ENAMEX>" by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy Newman</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> and the sacred tears in my eyes at that time.
I and my black baseball cap will enter a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tavern</ENAMEX>

            and there we will read a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX> with such concentration
it will be like I am that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>. Then pretty soon
in another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tavern</ENAMEX> it is a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX> whom I read
with similar effect. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parkersburg</ENAMEX>!
Oh my <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Parkersburg</ENAMEX> ... And I swear,
though I might not meet a lonely marvelous slim woman
with black hair, it will still be as if I did.

         
      
   
