
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past year and a half</TIMEX>, several pieces have appeared in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>
that delve into the cultural and political dimensions of race in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>. In honor of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Black History Month</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> is proud to present a few
of these pieces, most of which have only been available to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subscribers</ENAMEX>.
            

            Not Just
Talk

            A
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>-point program for better race relations.

            
               By
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Weisberg</ENAMEX>
            

            To the growing legion of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> cynics, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s race-relations initiative, unveiled last
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">weekend</ENAMEX>, is an exercise in cheap talk. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liberal</ENAMEX> and conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX>
disagree about affirmative action and welfare reform, but concur that a series
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> meetings, an advisory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX>, and an eloquent report are sorry
substitutes for decisive action.

            If they were talking
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> reform, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> might have a point. There, endless
calls for more study postpone necessary but unpopular changes in policy. But
when it comes to race, the power of words should not be so lightly dismissed.
If <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> can use his rhetorical gifts to change attitudes on both
sides of the divide, he will be accomplishing something of great significance.
It's also all he can really hope to do right now. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>'s current
skepticism about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activist</ENAMEX> government stymies new initiatives. Having screwed up
his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> term by misjudging the public demand for reform in the far less
difficult area of health care, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> would be foolish to present a
costly multipoint program on race.

            But if we had the money--and the will--what would we do
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about</NUMEX> race relations? <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A few years</TIMEX> of peace, prosperity, and balanced
budgets--and a deeper awareness of just how bad our race problem is--may create
a climate where such a program could succeed. When that moment arrives,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, or his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">successor</ENAMEX>, should have a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>-point plan ready.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">De</ENAMEX> facto segregation
exists throughout society. But the essence of the problem is the condition of
the worst-off <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> in the urban ghetto. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">White</ENAMEX> fears of the urban underclass
are distorted into broader stereotypes about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> as a whole, which poison
relations between the races at all levels. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Next week</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dateline NBC</ENAMEX> will
report on the south <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> suburb of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Matteson</ENAMEX>, which is tipping from an
upper-middle-class white <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">suburb</ENAMEX> into an upper-middle-class black <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. Matteson
ought to be an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">integrationist</ENAMEX>'s paradise, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX> are fleeing because of
their concerns about crime and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gangs</ENAMEX>, declining <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>, and falling home
prices. In reality, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>, safety, even the property values haven't declined.
But fear that these things will happen is not purely irrational. If the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX>
all leave, decline may become a self-fulfilling prophecy. Thus subtle racism
and a rational urge to self-preservation are bound up together. Unmaking the
underclass would answer white fears while giving lower-class <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> a chance
they are now largely denied: that of assimilating into the mainstream of an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">integrated</ENAMEX> society.

            Perhaps the most important difference between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who
live in the ghetto and those who live outside it is that most of the former
aren't employed. Breaking down the underclass will require finding new ways to
draw unemployed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ghetto residents</ENAMEX> into the culture of work. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> will remain
out for some time on the effects of the welfare cutoff signed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>. But even with the jobs provisions included in that bill, it's evident
that there still aren't sufficient jobs in the inner <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>, especially when
you consider the prospects of unemployed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, who aren't eligible for welfare.
In his latest book, When <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Work Disappears</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Julius Wilson</ENAMEX> argues
that there is a "spatial mismatch" between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> and jobs in
the suburbs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilson</ENAMEX>'s answer is a transportation program to get <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> to where
the jobs are, and a big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WPA</ENAMEX>-style jobs program (the details of which he borrows
from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mickey Kaus</ENAMEX>). These sub-minimum-wage jobs--doing basic
neglected work like repairing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridges</ENAMEX>--would constitute the missing
bottom rung on an economic ladder.

            The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> step is to
address the extreme isolation of the inner-city <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poor</ENAMEX>. This means a housing
strategy that shifts more decisively in the direction it has been inching under
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. Instead of trying to tame inner-city housing projects with different
kinds of architecture, lower density, and income mixing, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Housing and Urban Development</ENAMEX> should redefine its purpose: to help its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tenants</ENAMEX>
escape the ghetto. It should take a sledgehammer to every high-rise
under its control and instead provide vouchers. But these vouchers can't be the
kind <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> prefer, which are sharply limited in value so as to
forestall real integration while directing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tenants</ENAMEX> toward private-sector slums.
Vouchers need to be worth enough to afford real avenues of escape. They should
also steer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">beneficiaries</ENAMEX> away from other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">beneficiaries</ENAMEX>, to keep pockets of
concentrated poverty from re-emerging farther from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s core. An easy way
to do this would be to enforce strict limits on the percentage of voucher
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tenants</ENAMEX> allowed in any <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>.

            A less obvious factor fostering residential segregation is
the boundary between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">suburb</ENAMEX>. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX> flee the central <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>, they
take with them most of the tax revenue, and leave behind a downward spiral of
city services. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Rusk</ENAMEX>, a former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Albuquerque</ENAMEX>, argues in his
book, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cities Without Suburbs</ENAMEX> , metro-wide <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> where the suburbs
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> are joined tend to be more racially integrated, and better off in
various other ways as well. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> can't erase jurisdictional frontiers,
but it can encourage metropolitan <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> via tax incentives and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cheerleading</ENAMEX>. Such a policy would displease many black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>, since it
stands to diminish black political representation in the short run. But this is
a trade-off well worth making.

            All of these measures
together will not cause the ghettos to disappear. Providing escape routes from
the inner <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> may make the ghettos worse by depriving them of their most
competent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX>. What's needed, alongside an evacuation plan, is a
realistic program to stabilize conditions for those left behind. The goal
shouldn't be to make the desert bloom. It should be to create zones where
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> can raise <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in safety even if they must travel elsewhere to work.
To accomplish this, a strategy would need to focus on crime and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>.

            Of course, neither law enforcement nor education is
principally a federal responsibility. But in both cases, the feds can help. On
crime, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has had basically the right idea with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX>-policing
initiative. Cops walking the street create a sense of order and provide good
role <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">models</ENAMEX> for young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX>. This program should be expanded, perhaps with
incentives for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> to live in the neighborhoods they patrol full time.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Schools</ENAMEX> are a harder nut, but not an uncrackable one. There are a few good
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>, even in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Harlem</ENAMEX>, which have succeeded by doing end runs around the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">unionized</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bureaucracy</ENAMEX> of the central <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">system</ENAMEX>. The federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> should do
more to spur the creation of such <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX>, by providing resources, and by
helping to equalize the shameful disparity in funding between rich and poor
districts generally.

            Some of these concepts
have demonstrated their success at an experimental level and are ripe for
expansion. Others are just promising ideas that ought to be tried. All,
unfortunately, are expensive and sure to be controversial. They can't simply be
foisted on a reluctant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>. To lay the groundwork for useful action on race
relations, we need exactly what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is proposing as a starting
point: honest talk, and lots of it.

            

               Illustration by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Neubecker</ENAMEX>.
            

            
               For more articles
from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> in honor of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Black History Month</ENAMEX>, check out:
            

            

               A prominent that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Luther King Jr.</ENAMEX> might have
been in favor of affirmative action, despite his request that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> being
judged by the content of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> rather than the color of their skin.

               A leading <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> of the black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intelligentsia</ENAMEX>.

               <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> should over race.

               Were slaves happy? The answer's as you'd think.

               How the death of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Luther King Jr.</ENAMEX> sparked a wave of in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
life.


            

         
      
   
