
   
   
      
         
            

            

               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clintometer</ENAMEX> is back. Click for the latest update.
            

            

               B
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">razil</ENAMEX>'s economic crisis rattled world stock
markets. The Dow Jones industrial average slid <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">nearly 3 percent</NUMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>
after <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX> devalued its currency and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> pulled out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Analysts</ENAMEX> agree that the underlying problem is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX>'s failure to implement
painful economic reforms and spending cuts. The worst-case scenario is that
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX>'s troubles will spread to the rest of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Latin America</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>. But on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>, after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brazil</ENAMEX> stopped trying to prop up its
currency, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> relaxed, and the Dow recovered somewhat. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s spin
from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Monetary Fund</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>: Our <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$41 billion</NUMEX> bailout
package to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two months ago</TIMEX> saved its economy and stopped the global
financial meltdown. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX> spin: Don't blame us, it's <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX>'s
fault for screwing up its economy again by ignoring our advice. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">night</ENAMEX>'s editorial spin: It's the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> collapse all over again. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">morning</ENAMEX>'s spin: Maybe <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX> can still escape that fate. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1/15/99</NUMEX>)
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> will propose a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">55 cent</NUMEX> a pack tax hike on cigarettes to finance
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$8 billion</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> in extra domestic and military spending. The programs include
long-term health care, after school programs, new cops, and aid to disabled
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>. This comes after the tobacco industry killed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>'s legislation,
backed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, that would have brought the federal government <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billions of dollars</NUMEX>. Now that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> have struck their own settlement deal
with the industry, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is considering whether to extract some of that money
by withholding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX> reimbursements to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>. Old spin: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
underestimated the tobacco industry's savvy, resolve, and ruthlessness. New
spin: The tobacco industry underestimated <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s savvy, resolve, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ruthlessness</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1/15/99</NUMEX>)
            

            
The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>
presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">race</ENAMEX> was shuffled again. On the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> side, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Budget</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Kasich</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX>, and former Gov. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamar Alexander</ENAMEX>,
R-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tenn.</ENAMEX>, formed exploratory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committees</ENAMEX>, joining <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ariz.</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Smith</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.H.</ENAMEX> The major headline is still the evidently emerging
candidacy of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Dole</ENAMEX>. She trails <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">42-22</NUMEX> in
the latest national poll of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>, but she edges <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">31-30</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hampshire</ENAMEX>, with the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> eating their dust. On the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> side,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.J.</ENAMEX>, have launched their
campaigns, while <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Kerrey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Neb.</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Wellstone</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minn.</ENAMEX>,
have bowed out. The big <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> story is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Minority Leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gephardt</ENAMEX> is reportedly planning to skip the race as well, focusing instead on
winning back the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> and becoming <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1/15/99</NUMEX>)
            

            

                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Jordan</ENAMEX>
retired. He said he was physically fit but mentally "exhausted." The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">media</ENAMEX> responded with worshipful saturation coverage, reciting his records (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>
championships, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10</NUMEX> scoring titles, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Most Valuable Player Awards</ENAMEX>, and the
highest per-game scoring average ever) and replaying highlights, especially his
final shot, which won <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>'s championship. The spins, in order of
descending reverence: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) He was the greatest and most popular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">athlete</ENAMEX> of all
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) How fitting that he's going out on top. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) We'll miss his heroism. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>)
Without him, we're left with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> who kick <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">photographers</ENAMEX> and choke <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coaches</ENAMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>) Without him, we're left with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> whose greed has nearly
destroyed the sport. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>) His retirement is final--just like last time. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>)
According to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">La Repubblica</ENAMEX> , "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> would willingly take
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s retirement in exchange for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jordan</ENAMEX>'s." (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1/13/99</NUMEX>)
            

            


               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">H</ENAMEX>
               ustler <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">publisher</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Flynt</ENAMEX> accused <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Barr</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">R-Ga.</ENAMEX>, of adultery and hypocrisy. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barr</ENAMEX> has been one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>'s most
aggressive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s misconduct in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>
scandal. In an affidavit paid for and released by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flynt</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barr</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ex-wife</ENAMEX> accuses
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barr</ENAMEX> of having an affair with another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>, whom he has since married. She
also says he knew of her plans to have an abortion and didn't try to dissuade
her. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barr</ENAMEX> refused to answer questions about the affair during his divorce
hearing. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flynt</ENAMEX>'s spin: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barr</ENAMEX> is a hypocrite for ducking the questions and then
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">prosecuting Clinton</ENAMEX> for evasive testimony about sex. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barr</ENAMEX>'s spins: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) He
declined to answer questions, whereas <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> answered them falsely. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) He
"never suggested, urged, forced, or encouraged anyone to have an abortion." <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>)
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Flynt</ENAMEX>'s money has been used in an attempt to drive a wedge between the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> wonderful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX>." <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) "This is very clearly an effort to
take old documents" and "divert attention" from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s trial. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>) "I'm going
to do the honorable thing and present the case that I've been elected to
present in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>." (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1/13/99</NUMEX>)
            

            
The baseball
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark McGwire</ENAMEX> hit for his <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">70 th</NUMEX> home run <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last season</TIMEX> sold for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">million</ENAMEX>. The previous record price for a <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> was <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$126,500</NUMEX>. The record
price for a baseball card is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$640,000</NUMEX>. The cost of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McGwire</ENAMEX> ball before it
went out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> was <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10</NUMEX>. The spins, in order of ascending cynicism: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)
Isn't it swell that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Philip Ozersky</ENAMEX>, the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$30,000</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> medical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researcher</ENAMEX> who
caught the ball, is now a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">millionaire</ENAMEX>? <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) The bidding went nuts because
baseball fever is back. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) The bidding went nuts because rich <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have money
to burn. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Three million dollars</NUMEX> for a baseball makes sense because players
are beginning to get <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100 million</NUMEX> contracts. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>) Now the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> who caught
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McGwire</ENAMEX>'s other home run balls and returned them for free feel like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suckers</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ozersky</ENAMEX>'s spin: "I'm glad I did this. I was just a research <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientist</ENAMEX>; now I'm
a media <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX>." <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>) At the same auction, the ball <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hank Aaron</ENAMEX> hit for his
record-setting <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">755 th</NUMEX> career home run drew no bids.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1/13/99</NUMEX>)
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX> 
               and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi Arabia</ENAMEX> called for the overthrow of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX>. First, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX> urged <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masses</ENAMEX>" to overthrow <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>
"who boast of friendship with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>." Then <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">legislators</ENAMEX>
accused <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi Arabia</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuwait</ENAMEX> of complicity in the recent <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX>
bombing of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> and proposed to rescind <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>'s recognition of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kuwaiti</ENAMEX>
sovereignty. The official <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Saudi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">press agency</ENAMEX> responded by urging an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX>
"revolution" against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Egyptians</ENAMEX> agreed. This is the first
explicit advocacy by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX>'s overthrow. The rosy spin:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX> is playing with fire. The sober spin: So are <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi Arabia</ENAMEX>,
whose <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX>' moderate, pro-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> policies are unpopular at home.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1/11/99</NUMEX>)
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney General</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Reno</ENAMEX> became the longest-serving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney general</ENAMEX> of the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 th century</TIMEX>. The spins: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) It's amazing, considering she was
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s haphazard <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> choice. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) It's amazing, considering she
oversaw the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Waco</ENAMEX> fiasco <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">barely a month</TIMEX> into her tenure. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) It's amazing,
considering she's done nothing of note in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six years</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) It's amazing,
considering <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> doesn't trust her. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>) It's unsurprising, since if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
replaced her with somebody he trusted it would look like an attempt to shield
himself from further scrutiny by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>) It's unsurprising,
since she's served <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> well by quashing independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> investigations
of his scandals. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>) What's amazing is that the press is so bored it's making a
fuss over how long she's been in office. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1/11/99</NUMEX>)
            

            
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">Football</ENAMEX> League semifinals are set. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vikings</ENAMEX> will host the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Falcons</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one bracket</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Denver Broncos</ENAMEX> will host the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Jets</ENAMEX>
in the other. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vikings-Falcons</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX> will be the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> to get to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Super Bowl</ENAMEX> after playing its home games in an indoor <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dome</ENAMEX>. In the on-field
tournament, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vikings</ENAMEX> have the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NFL</ENAMEX>'s best record <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> and set a record
for points scored in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a regular season</TIMEX>, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Broncos</ENAMEX> are the defending champs
and were undefeated until their final <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> games. However, in the off-field
(sentimental) tournament, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Falcons</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jets</ENAMEX> have more appealing story lines.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Falcons</ENAMEX> were <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3-13 two years ago</TIMEX> and are inspired by their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reeves</ENAMEX>, who had quadruple bypass surgery <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month ago</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jets</ENAMEX> were <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1-15 two</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> and are one win away from their <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Super Bowl</ENAMEX> since the famous <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX>
Namath triumph in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1969</TIMEX>. Both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX>' story lines are marred by the fact that
their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coaches</ENAMEX> have been to the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Super Bowl</ENAMEX> with other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX>.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1/11/99</NUMEX>)
            

         
      
   
