
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">180</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">&quot;Three for All&quot</ENAMEX>;

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Safer</ENAMEX>, cleaner, more fun--these are the attributes touted by an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organization</ENAMEX>'s new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX>. What <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>?
            

             

            by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> to e-mail your answer to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            

               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s question (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 179</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Pair of Weasels":</ENAMEX>
            

            

               
                  
                     
                        
                           <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alluding</ENAMEX> to a verbal dyad, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamar</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander</ENAMEX> called them "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Weasel</ENAMEX> words, cleverly and deliberately put together to
confuse <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> by meaning nothing." What two
words?
                        
                     
                  
               
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dot</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Simon</ENAMEX>
            

            
"Acceptable level."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alfa-Betty Olsen</ENAMEX>
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pottery Barn</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Colleen Werthmann</ENAMEX>
            

            "Hilary
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackie</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Burton</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Radosh</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Radosh</ENAMEX>
            

            "Kill
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">chickens</ENAMEX>. (Of course, to a weasel, the meaning is quite clear.)"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miller</ENAMEX>
            

            "I
do."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Thomas</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joydip Kundu</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carole Larsen</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
Leary , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Charles Star</ENAMEX>
            

            
"Operating system (OK, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX>, where's my check?)"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ananda Gupta</ENAMEX>
            

            Click
for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more</NUMEX> responses.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
            

            Many responses listed
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">deft</ENAMEX> and amusing <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">oxymorons</ENAMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamar Alexander</ENAMEX> sought something more insidious
than mere self-contradiction. He was invoking the vicious and sinister
qualities that make weasels (along with stoats and ferrets) such satisfying
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">villains in Kenneth Grahame</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wind in the Willows</ENAMEX> , and such pleasingly
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">greasy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stooges</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David Letterman</ENAMEX>'s epithet "record industry <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">weasels</ENAMEX>." (Not
half so much contempt could be squeezed from "record industry <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">squirrels</ENAMEX>.") That
toothy, ruthless carnivore shows up in this familiar <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchange</ENAMEX>:

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Hamlet:</ENAMEX>
Do you see yonder cloud that's almost in shape of a camel?

               
Polonius: By the mass, and 'tis like a camel, indeed.

               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Hamlet:</ENAMEX>
Methinks it is like a weasel

               
Polonius: It is backed like a weasel.

            

            A few lines later, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hamlet</ENAMEX>
says, "They fool me to the top of my bent." Indeed they do, those weasels. It
makes you wonder why anyone could name a product the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Garden Weasel</ENAMEX>" or why
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamar Alexander</ENAMEX> thinks he has a shot at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>.

            
               Alliterative
Answer
            

            "Compassionate conservative."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> presidential
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hopefuls</ENAMEX> and their myrmidons are carping about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> catch phrase.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Religious nut Gary Bauer</ENAMEX> took it out on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush Sr.</ENAMEX>: "The last <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> talked about
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">kinder</ENAMEX> and gentler, and that resulted in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">an election</TIMEX> loss." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Quayle</ENAMEX> demurred
typographically, writing "I have ordered my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> to never--EVER--utter the
words 'compassionate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservative</ENAMEX>!' " <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Forbes</ENAMEX> objected manfully,
declaring: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mealy</ENAMEX>-mouthed rhetoric and poll-tested clichés are no substitute
for a muscular substantive agenda," then he took a swing at a poor person
bequeathed to him in his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s will. Or maybe he didn't.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicole Seligman</ENAMEX>
Extra
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Pros</ENAMEX> and cons of trying to wangle a blind date with
the impressive presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX>.

            
               Pro
            

            Uncanny ability to keep a straight face while saying
"Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Manager Graham</ENAMEX>" means she'd have no trouble buttering up my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX>.

            Her assertion--"Mere repetition no matter how
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dogged</ENAMEX>, cannot create a reality where there is none"--means no nagging.

            

               Ambiguous
            

            No visible wedding ring could imply availability for
dating or recklessness at the poker table or that it's time to break down and
buy a decent television.

            Mysterious white bauble on lapel could be pale and
delicate cameo, membership pin in pernicious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>, or perhaps a dab of
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">spilled food</ENAMEX>.

            
               Con
            

            If things got seriously romantic, she might blurt
out quotations from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Pitt Fessenden</ENAMEX>, breaking the mood.

            Was on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oliver North</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">defense</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX>. After a little tiff, she might get some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> to kill you. In the
national interest.

            
               Race
Results
            

            Win: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamar Alexander</ENAMEX>'s self-deception.

            Place: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s equivocating.

            Show: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Quiz</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ubiquity</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Disclaimer</ENAMEX>: All
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">submissions</ENAMEX> will become the property of 
               
                  Slate
               

               and will be published at 
               
                  Slate
               
               's
discretion. 
               
                  Slate
                
               may publish your name on its
site in connection with your submission .

         
      
   
