
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">181</NUMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">&quot</NUMEX>;<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sit Up</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cheer&quot</ENAMEX>;

            

               "This is great news for the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> who are not getting
enough physical activity," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Claude Lenfant</ENAMEX>. What is?
            

             

            by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> to e-mail your answer to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            

               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s question (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 180</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Three for All":</ENAMEX>
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Safer</ENAMEX>, cleaner, more fun--these are the attributes touted by an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organization</ENAMEX>'s new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX>. What <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>?
            

            "The
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Shining Path</ENAMEX>. Now even shinier."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer Miller</ENAMEX>
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heritage USA</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">First</NUMEX> step toward more fun: All-nude water slide!"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim</ENAMEX>
Carvell
            

            "The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organization</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Western</ENAMEX> civilization. The new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wendy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shalit</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Radosh</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carbide</ENAMEX>, announcing their triumphant return to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bhopal</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joel</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Silverman</ENAMEX>
            

            "North
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Man Boy Like Association</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian Danenberg</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry</ENAMEX>
Amaros , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Rogers</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beth Sherman</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Schnur</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tucker</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Deb Stavin</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Molly Shearer Gabel</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aaron Schatz</ENAMEX> ,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Charles Star</ENAMEX> had similar answers.)

            Click
for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more</NUMEX> responses.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
            

            The big thing is not so
much having lots of good points, as knowing which are your good points and
which are your bad. It's not always obvious. Consider safe and clean. Do people
really want that? Put that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pair</ENAMEX> in your personal ad, and you'll be dating my
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">aunt Helen</ENAMEX> (if you're a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>) or my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncle</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morty</ENAMEX> (if you're a neat and prudent
gay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>) or my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncle</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herb</ENAMEX> (if you're a straight <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> and his mother, my
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">great</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aunt</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Selma</ENAMEX>, says it's OK). You don't want that; you want to be the sort
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who attracts the sort of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who wants dangerous and dirty. (But
let's not bring up my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousins</ENAMEX>.) When enlistment rates are down, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> recruiters
panic and misconstrue their points. You don't attract ferocious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> by
promising above average pay and, some day, a fine pension. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Warriors</ENAMEX> want
challenge--terrible pay, miserable conditions. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry V</ENAMEX> would have inspired no
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">St.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crispin</ENAMEX>'s day by declaiming:

            

               We few, we happy few, we band of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX>;

               For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">he today</TIMEX>, so safe and clean with me

               Shall be my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>.

            

            Today, most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historians</ENAMEX> believe that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Battle of</ENAMEX>
Agincourt was more fun than <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Aunt Selma</ENAMEX>.

            And that's the act I
would have done at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Concord Hotel</ENAMEX> if they just could have hung on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> more
season, and if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buddy Hackett</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> had stayed off my back. Safe, clean,
fun.

            
               Conventional
Answer
            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York City Convention and Visitors</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bureau</ENAMEX>.

            New <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Zagat</ENAMEX>,
announced that his first act will be to change the name of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> to
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NY & Company</ENAMEX>," presumably to make it clear whose interests the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> will
continue to serve.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kids Corner</ENAMEX>
Extra
            

            Who Am I? Can you identify someone from very little
hard evidence, just like a real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policeman</ENAMEX>?

            
               Clues
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. I like to stay in a safe-deposit box, a freezer,
or between the pages of a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. I have extraordinary strength, use an unknown
language, and have an aversion to God.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. I'm doing something "more intimate, more
personal"; I've "stripped away the theater"; and "if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> could see it,
they would demand that we do it more, not less."

            

               Solutions
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. I'm an infant <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> sample.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Nine</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> now offer to take blood
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">samples</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">newborns</ENAMEX>, to help with prompt identification if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> is
eventually murdered. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> recommend that the blood sample, dripped
onto a special card, be stored by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> in the above-mentioned
places.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. I am a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Swedish</ENAMEX> gym <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX>.

            Or I am possessed by the devil. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vatican</ENAMEX>'s new,
revised guide to exorcism, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">De Exorcismis et Supplicantionibus Quibusdam</ENAMEX>,"
lists these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> warning signs but cautions that exorcists "must not consider
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to be vexed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">demons</ENAMEX> who are suffering from some psychic <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">illness</ENAMEX>."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. I'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX> meeting in closed session, dancing
around in my underwear.

            Comments, in order, came
from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Kerry</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chuck Hagel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gordon Smith</ENAMEX>. The part about the
underwear probably isn't true, but how can we be sure?

            
               Race
Results
            

            Win: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAMBLA</ENAMEX>.

            Place: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IOC</ENAMEX>.

            (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> to merge? And of
course by "merge" I mean form a single organization able to more efficiently
serve the needs of all its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">constituents</ENAMEX>.)

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Disclaimer</ENAMEX>: All
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">submissions</ENAMEX> will become the property of 
               
                  Slate
               

               and will be published at 
               
                  Slate
               
               's
discretion. 
               
                  Slate
                
               may publish your name on its
site in connection with your submission .

         
      
   
