
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">173</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">&quot;Woon River&quot</ENAMEX>;

            
               When the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Woonasquatucket River</ENAMEX> near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Providence</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">R.I.</ENAMEX>, moved into the No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> slot, behind
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Passaic River</ENAMEX>, signs went up along its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> reading: "Peligro!
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Los Peces</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">De Este Rio</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">No Se Deben Comer</ENAMEX>."
            

            

               Loosely translated, what would that be in idiomatic
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>?
            

             

            by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> to e-mail your answer to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            

               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s question (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 172</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wear and Tear":</ENAMEX>
            

            

               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A year ago</TIMEX> she wore an orange <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">jumpsuit</ENAMEX> and brandished a torch; now she
wears a look of remorse. Who is she, and what went wrong?
            

            "My
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>, back when she was at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bennington</ENAMEX> at that <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">'Take Back the Night</ENAMEX>' rally
thing. All her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-workers</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">J.P. Morgan</ENAMEX> keep giving her shit about
it."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian Fix</ENAMEX>
            

            "She is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nathan Lane</ENAMEX>. What went wrong is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Encore Encore</ENAMEX> sucked
sucked."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Amaros</ENAMEX>
            

            "She is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dale Evans</ENAMEX>, and everything went wrong for her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First Roy</ENAMEX> dies, and
then she gets booed off the stage at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foxwoods</ENAMEX> just <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five minutes</TIMEX> into her
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Salute</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American Indian</ENAMEX> ."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Franzen</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drudge</ENAMEX> Report world exclusive: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan McDougal</ENAMEX> no longer carries a torch
for ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lover</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Jefferson Clinton</ENAMEX>. In tears, jailbird confesses to her
role in the murder of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vince Foster</ENAMEX> and 'anything else <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Starr</ENAMEX> wants.'
"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Radosh</ENAMEX>
            

            "She is
Crystall, the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$200</NUMEX> an hour <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miss Utah</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Olympics</ENAMEX>."<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Kate Wing</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doug</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Welty</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman Oder</ENAMEX> had similar answers.)

            Click
for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more</NUMEX> responses.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
            

            Mistake or metaphor?
That's what many of you wondered when you read the question. Unless you were
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara Lippert</ENAMEX>, and then you just went ahead and decided: error. (For rush to
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">judgment,</ENAMEX> click .) And while she is literally correct that flags were waved and
technically accurate that torches were not brandished, isn't there a deeper
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">brandishing</ENAMEX>, a rich symbolic brandishing? (Not to some. Click for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX>,
and executioner.) I suppose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> will have to be called to decide this.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fatuous</ENAMEX>, self-aggrandizing speeches will have to be made. I can't prevent that.
All I can do is calmly and modestly get on with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Quiz</ENAMEX>'s business. Please
don't be distracted by my quiet courage.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">America Loses Its</ENAMEX>
Innocence for the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">First Time Again Answer</ENAMEX>
            

            As most of you know, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Salt</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Lake City</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deedee Corradini</ENAMEX>, accepted the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Olympic</ENAMEX> flag at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the close of</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year's winter</TIMEX> games in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nagano</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> she ended her political
career, announcing she would not seek a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> term. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Salt Lake</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Olympic Committee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">trustees</ENAMEX>, she insists that this has nothing to
do with the bribery scandal: "I want you to know this is a purely personal
decision."

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cell Division</ENAMEX>
Extra
            

            It is not enough to hate;
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> must hate with clarity and understanding. Below, some reasons to loathe
cell phones.

            "It's
the same as seeing someone walk past you on the street busily shaving himself
with a cordless electric razor, an action that implies not that this is an
especially busy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> but rather that this is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who's very interested
in impressing upon others that he's an especially busy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim</ENAMEX>
Carvell
            

            
"They're status objects and umbilical cords for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> so insecure that they
need constant and instant connection and constant and instant interruption in
their life in order to feel powerful and worthy. Getting a call in public on
your cell phone is like flaunting how many <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> cards you receive. It's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">immodest</ENAMEX> and a sign of insecurity. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> who don't have real jobs and real
lives tend to pack cell phones in order to appear occupied and loved, when in
fact the reverse is true. They should, like the proverbial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">quarter</TIMEX> in your
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pocket</ENAMEX>, be used only in a real emergency."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carrie Rickie</ENAMEX>
            

            "Unlike
someone talking at a pay phone, or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> talking to each other in person
or, indeed, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> talking to herself, cell phone <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> always seem to give
the impression that they enjoy having <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strangers</ENAMEX> listen to their conversations.
It's as if every conversation is a tiny act of performance art--cheap, banal,
mundane performance art. They exploit themselves, by depriving themselves of
that private life so essential to a modern liberal society, and at the same
time they exploit the casual passerby by forcing that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> to eavesdrop and
act as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>. A cell phone <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user</ENAMEX> simultaneously withdraws from public life to
discuss his taxes or what's wrong with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> or whatever, and insists that
the public intrude into his private life. It's that combination of zombielike
self-absorption and fatuous exhibitionism that is so repugnant. What jerks they
are."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer Miller</ENAMEX>
            

            "I hit
on this explanation while reluctantly overhearing the inane chatter of a man
describing, into a hand-held mouthpiece, in excruciating detail, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friggin</ENAMEX>'
haircut! It is that hubris, that 'this conversation is SO important it cannot
wait for a less bothersome venue' characteristic of public cellular
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">intercourse</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave Ross</ENAMEX>
            

             

            
               Race Results
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reference No. 1</ENAMEX>: The
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Statue of Liberty</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s Wrap-Up
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>
            

            All right. All right.
She's telling the truth. I misread the article. Flag, torch--it all blurs
together. I was under a lot of pressure. Nobody was supposed to get hurt. I'm
just glad to get it off my chest.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Disclaimer</ENAMEX>: All
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">submissions</ENAMEX> will become the property of 
               
                  Slate
               

               and will be published at 
               
                  Slate
               
               's
discretion. 
               
                  Slate
                
               may publish your name on its
site in connection with your submission .

         
      
   
