
   
   
      
         
            Playing by Heartburn

            For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nearly a decade</TIMEX> I've
been obsessed by the cellist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jacqueline du Pr√©</ENAMEX>, whose tremulous, frequently
rhapsodic recordings of concertos by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Elgar, Schumann</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dvor√°k</ENAMEX> formed the
cornerstone of my music <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX>. That's why I've been puzzled by my reluctance
to tackle <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hilary</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackie</ENAMEX> , which pretends to tell the story of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">du Pr√</ENAMEX>©
and her elder <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> from their childhood as prodigies (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hilary</ENAMEX> played the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">flute</ENAMEX>) to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacqueline</ENAMEX>'s excruciating decline and early death (in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX>) from
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">multiple sclerosis</ENAMEX>. I suppose I hoped that the movie--which opened on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX>
Day in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> to qualify for the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Academy Awards</ENAMEX> and has been
opening across the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last few weeks</TIMEX>--would just go away. In
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">England</ENAMEX>, it has been reviled as a slander by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">musicians</ENAMEX> and music <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>, but
on this side of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Atlantic</ENAMEX> its reception has been warm, and there's a strong
chance that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emily Watson</ENAMEX> will win an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oscar</ENAMEX> nomination for her committed turn as
the unstable <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cellist</ENAMEX>. So I suppose I'll finally have to confront this thing. As
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">drama</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hilary</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackie</ENAMEX> is merely sketchy and superficial. As a
portrait of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>, it's puritanical crap.

            Like many, I first
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">encountered du Pr√</ENAMEX>© in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Elgar</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cello concerto</ENAMEX> in D minor, a work of aching
disillusionment that somehow rises to heights of sublimity. (Who'd have thought
the old <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tory</ENAMEX> had so much <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> in him?) It wasn't du <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pr√</ENAMEX>©'s tone that hooked
me--there are more limpid cellos--but the intensity of her bowing. You don't
need to have seen <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">du Pr√</ENAMEX>© in the flesh to feel an immersion that stops just
short of hysteria. Indeed, footage shows her strawberry-blond hair whipping
around her head, her skirts hiked up, her thighs tightly gripping her
Stradivarius: The ecstatic sexual component is hard to ignore. She was
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">unconventional</ENAMEX>, too: She played with un-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> emotional abandon, married a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jew</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Barenboim</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pianist</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conductor</ENAMEX>), and experimented with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>.
So it was probably inevitable that her life and music would turn into fodder
for a cautionary parable about the counterculture, complete with the kind of
lingering death that lends itself readily to familiar depictions of classical
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">musicians</ENAMEX>' physical and mental illness.

            The instrument of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jacqueline du Pr√</ENAMEX>©'s defilement is A
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Genius in the Family</ENAMEX> , a memoir by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hilary du Pr√©</ENAMEX> and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Piers</ENAMEX>
(who gets all but lost in the transfer to film). As the title implies, all was
not equal in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">du Pr√©</ENAMEX> household. Although <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hilary</ENAMEX> got off to a blazing start
as a flutist, her little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> eventually left her in the dust, and the
family's life came to revolve around the needs of its increasingly demanding
young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX>. The film, from a screenplay by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Cottrell Boyce</ENAMEX>, accords the
sisters equal status, telling the story of each in a separate strands, first
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hilary</ENAMEX>'s life, then <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackie</ENAMEX>'s. At the end the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> strands converge. After her
own musical career recedes, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hilary</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rachel Griffiths</ENAMEX>) retreats to a bucolic
country cottage with her love-smitten swain of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Morrissey</ENAMEX>) and
her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. There are plenty of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> and no shortage of healthy (i.e.,
amateur) music-making. Then we take a similar journey with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackie</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Watson</ENAMEX>),
who, denied a proper childhood and family life, pines away in foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capitals</ENAMEX>,
behaves with increasing waywardness and vulgarity (she adopts a bogus
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Continental</ENAMEX> accent), and expires in near solitude, with only her loyal sister
to remind her of God's love.

            It's difficult to believe that serious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> have
praised <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hilary</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackie</ENAMEX> for its insight into the artistic mind, since
that insight consists largely of the notion that <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">People Like That Are Different</ENAMEX>
From Us. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anand Tucker</ENAMEX>, views <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackie</ENAMEX> from an uncomprehending
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">distance</ENAMEX>, fixating largely on her freakishness. She seems never to rehearse or
to hold opinions about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">composers</ENAMEX> whose <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">works</ENAMEX> she serves, and her rapport
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barenboim</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Frain</ENAMEX>, whose performance is likely circumscribed by
considerations of libel) is chiefly the upshot of their comparable celebrity.
The centerpiece of the movie is when the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> narratives come together and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackie</ENAMEX> descends on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hilary</ENAMEX>'s cottage like an invading parasite. Flouncing about
in her furs and miniskirts and drinking heavily, she uses emotional blackmail
to convince <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hilary</ENAMEX> to let her bed her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> --before returning to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> and
her own, evidently unsatisfying, marriage. The <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">illness</ENAMEX> that strikes her down
could be viewed as vengeance for a profoundly unnatural existence.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Friends</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jacqueline du Pr√</ENAMEX>© have attacked <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hilary</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackie</ENAMEX> for both its factual
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">distortions</ENAMEX> and its unflattering depiction of an allegedly generous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>--but
I frankly don't care if the picture is accurate or not. The larger point is
that's it's all dashes and ellipses, skipping lightly along the surface of both
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackie</ENAMEX>'s career and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hilary</ENAMEX>'s noncareer, and wanton in its exploitation of both
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Elgar</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MS</ENAMEX> to generate pathos and awe. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Watson</ENAMEX> does an exquisite impersonation
of a troubled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soul</ENAMEX>; it's probably not her fault that this lonely fruitcake
doesn't connect with anything I hear in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">du Pr√</ENAMEX>©'s fearless playing, which
manages to be both willful and restrained in equal measure. Many talented
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">musicians</ENAMEX> are unstable; the wonder is how they also manage to be so
disciplined. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hilary</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackie</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX> is too vulnerable to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">plague</ENAMEX>.

            P laying by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heart</ENAMEX> has the strident
psuedosophistication of a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">late-night</TIMEX> dorm <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> colloquy as dramatized by a
sophomore busy congratulating himself for having more insight into love than
all the incoming <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">freshmen</ENAMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX>, where this sort of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">material</ENAMEX> is usually
performed (before the script is stashed away in mom and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>'s basement
alongside the beanbag chairs and weathered bongs), the older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> is played
by a matronly senior and a skinny <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> with white shoe polish in his hair. Here
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer-director</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willard Carroll</ENAMEX>, gets to hear his pretentious lines read
by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gena Rowlands</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sean Connery</ENAMEX>, who (if the press clips are to be believed)
jumped at the chance to stand around a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen</ENAMEX> and argue about events that
happened <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25 years</TIMEX> in the past. "There's nothing to talk about." "Of course
there is." "But I don't want to ... I have a brain tumor."

            The rest of the film jumps around among similar
twosomes, plus <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dennis Quaid</ENAMEX> as a mysterious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">loner</ENAMEX> who wanders into <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bars</ENAMEX> and
tells fantastic tales of tragedy to whomever will listen. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madeleine Stowe</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony Edwards</ENAMEX> meet in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> for kinky, anonymous sex. Cute party girl
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angelina Jolie</ENAMEX> chases skinny pretty-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ryan Phillippe</ENAMEX>, who is peculiarly
unresponsive to her blandishments. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Schlumpy</ENAMEX> theater <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gillian Anderson</ENAMEX>
is courted by a Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adorable</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jon Stewart</ENAMEX>, but fears that if she opens herself
up to him she'll get hurt. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellen Burstyn</ENAMEX> hovers at the hospice bed of her
dying, gay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jay Mohr</ENAMEX>). Each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> is engaged in its own emotional tug of
war but disinclined to confront their "issues" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> on. In the words of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jolie</ENAMEX>,
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Talking</ENAMEX> about love is like dancing about architecture."

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dancing About</ENAMEX>
Architecture" was meant to be the movie's title, but the more generic
Playing by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heart</ENAMEX> comes closer to conveying its deep banality. The only
difference between this and a conventional soap opera (or, for that matter, an
episode of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Love Boat</ENAMEX> ) is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carroll</ENAMEX> doesn't spell out the
interrelationship among the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couples</ENAMEX> until the final scene, a symbolic
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">remarriage</ENAMEX> in which the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> realize that talking about love might be as
futile as dancing about architecture, but you have to do it anyway if your life
is going to mean anything. (A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> who is <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX> positive expresses that
sentiment most clearly, the glimpse of his own mortality having given him a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">perspective</ENAMEX> that the others come to only gradually.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anderson</ENAMEX> gives the most
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tart</ENAMEX> and likable performance, but she, along with the rest of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cast</ENAMEX>, has to
struggle with dialogue that has the tackiness of flypaper. When she announces,
"I don't want any more calculated artificiality," it's a wonder the house
doesn't erupt in cries of "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bravo</ENAMEX>!"

            G loria , a gritty <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sharon Stone</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicle</ENAMEX> ... Hold
it--there's something about the words "gritty" and "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sharon Stone</ENAMEX>" that don't
belong in the same sentence. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stone</ENAMEX> does best when playing creamy glamour girls
with predatory streaks, but it's not hard to see why she'd want to play <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gloria</ENAMEX>.
The movie is a remake of a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Cassavetes</ENAMEX> sausage (a rare formula picture
for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">maverick director</ENAMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a gangster</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mistress</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gena Rowlands</ENAMEX>, who has
a cameo here) who stands up to her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lover</ENAMEX> by rescuing a little <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> whose
family has been wiped out by mobsters. So <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stone</ENAMEX> gets to stride around in short
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">skirts</ENAMEX> and spiked heels and hold a gun on big <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> and refer to herself
as a "broad." She gets to act tough but vulnerable and talk with a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Noo</ENAMEX> Yawk
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">accent</ENAMEX> and say, "I'm trying to change my life here!" And she's enough of
a star that you root for her--not so much to save the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> as to make it through
the movie without unduly embarrassing herself.

            No such luck. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sidney Lumet</ENAMEX>, who
functions as the opposite of a safety net: Even chronic underactors overact in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lumet</ENAMEX> pictures, and his camera is somehow always in the right place to catch
them doing it. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lumet</ENAMEX>'s tempo and staging are just realistic enough to allow you
to resent him for melodramatic devices that slicker <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX> get away with. He
makes a fatal miscalculation: The initial murders are so horrifying in their
plainness that when the movie takes the gentlemanly way out and refuses to
provide a cathartic bloodbath, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> feels burned. A real gentleman,
meanwhile, might have protected <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stone</ENAMEX> from showing so much flesh to so little
effect. In one scene, in a coffee <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> she's protecting hides under
the table next to her ample legs. Once upon a time both he--and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>--would be trying to peek up her short skirt. But the thrill, alas, is
gone.

         
      
   
