
   
   
      
         
             <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Saves Bill</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s video
deposition intrigued the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX>, but it seems not to have
changed any votes, in part because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> has said it all before, but in part
because she phrases her testimony in ways that protect <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. As
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s interrogator, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed Bryant</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tenn.</ENAMEX>, tries to get her to implicate
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> in subornation of perjury--particularly in a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 17, 1997</TIMEX>, phone call
and a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 28, 1997</TIMEX>, meeting--she repeatedly foils <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bryant</ENAMEX>'s plan not with lies
but with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clintonesque</ENAMEX> verbal tricks.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. Analysis. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bryant</ENAMEX> wants <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>
to connect the dots of circumstantial evidence in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">prosecution</ENAMEX>'s case. Two
of these dots are her false affidavit and the "cover stories" she and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
had agreed to offer if asked about their relationship. So in his question about
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 17</TIMEX> phone call, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bryant</ENAMEX> asks, "When the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> told you that you were
on the witness list, he also suggested that you could sign an affidavit and use
misleading cover stories. Isn't that correct?" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bryant</ENAMEX> is trying to force
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> to affirm the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> parts of his question--"affidavit" and "cover
stories"--together. But she refuses to give him a yes or no. "In my mind, I
separate necessarily signing affidavit and using misleading cover stories," she
replies. "Those <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> events occurred, but they don't--they weren't linked for
me."

            When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bryant</ENAMEX> asks about
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 28</TIMEX> meeting, he again sneaks a causal link into his question: "Do you
recall anything being said about you going ... to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> and that the effect
of that might be that you would be more difficult to find?" Again, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>
muddles the inference. "I believe that might have been mentioned briefly," she
replies, "but not as a reason to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, but as a possible outcome of
being there."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Synthesis</ENAMEX>. Having thwarted some of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bryant</ENAMEX>'s
questions by refusing to draw connections, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> confounds others by drawing
alternative connections. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bryant</ENAMEX> keeps trying to link the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>-authorized
"cover story" to the false affidavit, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> keeps linking it to their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pre-existing</ENAMEX> affair. "It was from the entire relationship, that story," she
explains. "It was part of the pattern of the relationship." Later, he tries to
deduce that her attempt to avoid testifying in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> case must have
been <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s idea. "Why would you have wanted to avoid testifying<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>" he asks.
She throws other explanations at him: "<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">First</NUMEX> of all, I thought it was nobody's
business. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX> of all, I didn't want to have anything to do with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paula Jones</ENAMEX>
or her case." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bryant</ENAMEX> presses her: "But you didn't file the affidavit for your
best interest, did you?" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> doesn't budge: "Actually, I did."

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. Reticence
about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s thoughts. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> want to prove a theory about
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s motives, but they can't put him on the stand. So <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bryant</ENAMEX> tries to coax
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>, the best available eyewitness, to infer <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s motives based on
their conversations. She doesn't cooperate. After reminding her that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
never told her she "had to tell the truth in an affidavit," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bryant</ENAMEX> adds, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">It</ENAMEX>
would have been against his interest in that lawsuit for you to have told the
truth, would it not?" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> replies that she isn't "comfortable" surmising
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s interests. Later, observing that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> had discussed their "cover
story" in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 17</TIMEX> phone call, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bryant</ENAMEX> asks her, "Was that in connection with
the affidavit? ... Why would he have told you you could always say that?"
Again, she refuses to speculate.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. Loquacity about her own thoughts. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s
failure to say how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s motives and calculations might connect the
scandal's behavioral dots is bad enough for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX>. What's worse is
that she offers the defense an alternative explanation, by using her own
motives and calculations to connect the dots. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bryant</ENAMEX> asks her, "Did you
understand in the context of the telephone conversation with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> that
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX> the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">17 th</NUMEX> ... that you would deny your
relationship with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jones</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> through use of these cover
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">stories?</ENAMEX>" Here, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bryant</ENAMEX> is offering the word "understand" as a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridge</ENAMEX> from her
mind to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s, hoping she will affirm that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> made clear to her that
she should lie under oath. Instead, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> absorbs the blame for this
inference. "I don't know," she answers. "But from what I learned in that
conversation, I thought to myself I knew I would deny the relationship."

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Relativism</ENAMEX>. Having mocked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s plastic conception of truth (e.g.,
"It depends upon what the meaning of the word 'is' is"), the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX>
encounter the same maddening fuzziness in their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star witness</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bryant</ENAMEX> asks her,
"Did you appreciate the implications of filing a false affidavit with the
court?" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> responds, "I don't think I necessarily thought at that point
it would have to be false." She insists that her affidavit, her cover story for
the relationship, and even her statement that "there were other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> present"
when she was with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> (virtually identical to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s assertion that "I
was never alone with her") were "incomplete" and "misleading" but "literally
true."

            At times, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s dexterity is eerily <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clintonesque</ENAMEX>. When
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bryant</ENAMEX> asks her whether she "did deny the relationship" with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> in her
affidavit, she objects, "I denied a sexual relationship." And when
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bryant</ENAMEX> asks her whether she "believe[s] the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s version of the Paula
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> incident," she replies, "I don't believe <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX>' version of the
story." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bryant</ENAMEX>, dazzled by her ingenious retort, babbles helplessly, "OK, good,
that's a fair answer," and stumbles to his next query.

            More than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> after
the world first heard of her, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> has solved the scandal's ultimate
mystery. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> never told her how to confound his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX>. He taught
her by example.

         
      
   
