
   
   
      
         
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Economist</ENAMEX>
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 9</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9, 1999</TIMEX>)
            

            Noting that mergers
increased <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50 percent</NUMEX> worldwide in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> and that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">less than half</NUMEX> of mergers "add
value," the cover article advises <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> how to make successful marriages.
Suggestions: Don't merge because you're bored with your own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, don't
merge because you're scared, watch out for antitrust law, and make sure your
corporate cultures are compatible. ... A piece chronicles the horrific
implosion of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sierra Leone</ENAMEX>, where an "incoherent," horrible guerrilla movement
is sweeping through the countryside, destroying what little remains of civil
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">society</ENAMEX>. Many of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> are kidnapped <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>; some practice
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cannibalism</ENAMEX>. ... A piece describes the next cool tool of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
military: microplanes. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Six</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">inches</NUMEX> long, weighing <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">3 ounces</NUMEX>, and equipped with
tiny cameras, they will spy on enemy positions. The prototypes fly like <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">insects</ENAMEX>
rather than like <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fair</ENAMEX>
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 1999</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9, 1999</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover article and
photo essay preview the new Star Wars movie, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Phantom Menace</ENAMEX> .
Among the details revealed: The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">villains</ENAMEX> are evil <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Jedi</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Darth Maul</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Darth Sidious</ENAMEX>, the film starts with the siege of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Naboo</ENAMEX>, a planet whose queen
will become <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Luke</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leia</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Lucas</ENAMEX> tells <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fair</ENAMEX> that he will make <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only six</NUMEX> Star Wars movies--the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> that
have already been released and the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> that precede them. He has no plans for
movies that take the saga past Return of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Jedi</ENAMEX> . ... A massive
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintons</ENAMEX>' marriage concludes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> covers up <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">straying</ENAMEX> and blames <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX> when he wanders. She doesn't talk about intimate
personal matters with anyone, even her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX>. She has always been his goad and
his source of fire, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> affair may have changed that. She seems to
be withdrawing from him, an abandonment that is leaving him passive and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">impotent</ENAMEX>. ... A piece tells the incredible life story of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carlos</ENAMEX>
Mavroleon, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX> educated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tycoon</ENAMEX> who converted to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Islam</ENAMEX>, joined the mujahideen, became a free-lance TV war <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondent</ENAMEX>, was
arrested by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Pakistani</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> while trying to sneak into <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Osama Bin Laden</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">terrorist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">camps</ENAMEX> after the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> bombing, and died mysteriously of a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">heroin</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">overdose days later</TIMEX>.

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX>
               
               
                  , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 25</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8, 1999</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover story
describes the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> campaign's "mighty machine," already operating in high
gear. With the economy humming and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> high in the polls, the campaign's
message, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton II</ENAMEX>," sounds fine. But will it be out of tune by the time the
election rolls around? ... <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> stories view the impeachment and trial of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> as part of a long-running <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> culture war going back to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">Salem witch</ENAMEX> trials. Each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">side</ENAMEX> claims (in so many words) that its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX>
"just don't get it," where "it" refers to the correct definitions of virtue and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">villainy</ENAMEX>. ... The "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">TRB"</ENAMEX> column doubts that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fidel Castro</ENAMEX> will cooperate
with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s modest embargo relaxation, "a policy that
announces itself as an effort to gradually undermine his rule." The wily <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cuban</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dictator</ENAMEX> will either sabotage the plan or turn it to his own uses.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
Magazine
                
               
                  , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 10</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7, 1999</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover story worries
about the rise of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SAT</ENAMEX> prep industry. Private tutors, who cost <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">up to $415</NUMEX>
per hour, and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$800</NUMEX> test-prep courses serve only the wealthiest, most
overprivileged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>, thus undermining the idea that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SAT</ENAMEX> should level the
playing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">field</ENAMEX> in college admissions. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SAT</ENAMEX> has little predictive value for
undergraduate performance, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX> claim they are decreasing the
importance of the test in admissions, but it is still a critical factor in who
gets in. A sidebar offers test-taking tips, including: "The most obvious choice
... is almost always wrong--but it's not far off." ... <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palestinian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholar</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward Said</ENAMEX> argues that a single <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli-Palestinian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> is the only
lasting <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> solution. Such a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, with a constitution and identical
rights for all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>, could guarantee long-term security in a way that the
current fake peace doesn't. Said is quiet on how <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israelis</ENAMEX> can
be persuaded even to consider such a reconciliation. ... A column
describes several ways the euro could destabilize <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>. The most alarming:
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> could practice financial terrorism by selling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX> bills and buying
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">eurobonds</ENAMEX>, thus weakening the dollar.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>
                
               and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan.</TIMEX>
11
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5, 1999</TIMEX>)
            

            Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> go with health cover stories.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's special issue--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Future of Medicine</ENAMEX>"--predicts that the next
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">100 years</TIMEX> will be "the biotech <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">century</TIMEX>," in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> will manipulate
genes to prolong the lives of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">healthy humans</ENAMEX> rather than just treat sick
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, as they have <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this century</TIMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> page package celebrates the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Human</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Genome Project</ENAMEX>, new gene therapies, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designer</ENAMEX> pharmaceuticals and raises the
expected ethical concerns about manipulating embryonic genes and genetically
<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">engineering crops</ENAMEX>. ... 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's narrow cover package discusses breakthroughs in treating migraine
headaches. They are caused by extremely sensitive nerves, not by misbehaving
blood vessels, as had been believed. New <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> are effective.

            Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> score
interviews with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Osama Bin Laden</ENAMEX>. If this is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Laden</ENAMEX>'s idea of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PR</ENAMEX>
campaign, he needs a new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adviser</ENAMEX>. He tells <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> , "God knows that we have
been pleased by the killing of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX>," and advises <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX>
                that "[a]ny <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> who pays taxes
is ... our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">target</ENAMEX>" (another good reason not to file <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>). Both interviews
note that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Laden</ENAMEX> thanks God before every answer. ... 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX>
picks the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> most important ideas of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past 2,000 years</TIMEX>, including the stirrup,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">plumbing</ENAMEX>, the printing press, numbers, erasers, and clocks, but not
electricity.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">& World Report</ENAMEX>
                
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 11</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5, 1999</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
story describes the difficult path to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> sainthood, "the world's
most complex legal process." Consideration can't start till <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX> after
death, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>'s life is exhaustively scrutinized, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">miracles</ENAMEX> must
be proved. The miracles must pass a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor panel</ENAMEX>, who seek any possible
medical explanation. A sidebar profiles potential saint <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Katharine Drexel</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nun</ENAMEX> who
gave her vast fortune to charity while ministering to poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Native</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisiana</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miracle No. 1</ENAMEX> has been accepted: In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1974</TIMEX>--long after
her death--a prayer to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drexel</ENAMEX> cured a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>'s ear <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">illness</ENAMEX>. ... A
long story argues that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Food and Drug Administration</ENAMEX>
approved <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Viagra</ENAMEX> too quickly. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">More than 100</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have died after taking the
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX>, most from <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">heart failure</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Viagra</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">label</ENAMEX> did not adequately warn users
with weak hearts and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pfizer</ENAMEX> was not required to perform clinical
trials on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">heart disease</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  The New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yorker</ENAMEX>
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 11</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5, 1999</TIMEX>)
            

            A fascinating article
describes the societal importance of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who bring other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> together. By
connecting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to jobs, to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>, and to activities such <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> build
critical social <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX>. (The article focuses on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> such social <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hub</ENAMEX>, Lois
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weisberg</ENAMEX>, who happens to be the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> of 
                  Slate
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">'s Jacob</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weisberg</ENAMEX>.) ... A piece on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Rehnquist</ENAMEX> suggests that
he may preside over the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> trial more liberally than many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> expect.
In the only trial over which he has ever presided, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rehnquist</ENAMEX> allowed the
defense to introduce a remarkably large amount of evidence.

         
      
   
