
   
   
      
         
            

            

               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clintometer</ENAMEX> is back. Click for the latest update.
            

            
A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">committee</ENAMEX> report says <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> has finagled and stolen sensitive <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> military
technology for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 years</TIMEX> . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> says the technology includes nuclear
weapons designs. The conservative spin: The report proves the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
administration hurt <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> national security by giving <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> access to high
technology. The liberal spin: The report shows the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">administrations</ENAMEX> did the same thing. The nonpartisan spin: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congratulations</ENAMEX> to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> for reporting the ugly truth on both
sides. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">12/31/98</NUMEX>)
            

            

               Two
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khmer Rouge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> defected to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cambodian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hun Sen</ENAMEX> in
exchange for protection from trial. The defectors, who played key roles in the
Cambodian genocide of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late 1970s</TIMEX>, have been put up in luxury <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambodia</ENAMEX>'s figurehead <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX> refuses to grant them amnesty, saying they should
face an international <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tribunal</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defectors</ENAMEX>' spin: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sorry</ENAMEX>, very sorry. ...
Let bygones be bygones." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hun Sen</ENAMEX>'s spin: They deserve "bouquets of <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers</ENAMEX>, not
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">prisons</ENAMEX> and handcuffs." The cynical spin: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hun Sen</ENAMEX> is protecting them to
consolidate the power he won through a coup. The idealistic spin: They should
be tried for crimes against humanity, which are far worse than those of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chilean</ENAMEX>
ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dictator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Augusto Pinochet</ENAMEX>. The backup idealistic spin: We'll catch them
and try them if they leave their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, just like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pinochet</ENAMEX>.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">12/31/98</NUMEX>)
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> exchanged fire again . For the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> time since the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
bombing campaign <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks ago</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> anti-aircraft outposts tried to shoot
down <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX> that were patrolling "no-fly zones" over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>.
Once again, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX> returned fire. Each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">side</ENAMEX> claims to have fired in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">self-defense</ENAMEX>. This time, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> say they hit an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> missile
launch site. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> claims they killed a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmer</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX> will continue to enforce the no-fly zones to prevent <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> from using air
power to prey on its domestic or foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX>. Meanwhile, much of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">force</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Persian Gulf</ENAMEX> began to leave the area as scheduled. The spins: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)
The bombing campaign failed, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> is slinking away with its
tail between its legs. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) Is not! <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) Is too! (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">12/31/98</NUMEX>)
            

            

                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ariz.</ENAMEX>, is forming a presidential campaign exploratory
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">committee</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>'s spins: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) He announced his decision just before
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the year</TIMEX> in order to steal the "first <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>" title from other
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> who were about to launch their candidacies. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) Extra! Extra! <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">McCain</ENAMEX>
becomes first <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>! <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) He proved his virtue by leading the fights for
tobacco regulation and campaign finance reform. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) He ruined his chances in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> primaries by leading the fights for tobacco regulation and campaign
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">finance</ENAMEX> reform. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>) He worries that the press will dig into his personal life.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>) Let's go dig into his personal life. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">12/30/98</NUMEX>)
            

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">octuplets</ENAMEX> died
               . The smallest, who was
less than <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10 inches</NUMEX> long and weighed <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10.3 ounces</NUMEX> at birth, died of heart and
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">lung failure</ENAMEX>. The other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> remain in critical condition, though <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> are now
breathing without ventilators. Each <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> who survives will require <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two months</TIMEX>
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$250,000</NUMEX> worth) of hospital care. Meanwhile, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sextuplets</ENAMEX> born in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> on
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 23</TIMEX> died of lung <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">hemorrhages</ENAMEX>. Spins on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">octuplet</ENAMEX>'s death: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) How tragic.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) It's OK, she's in God's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hands</ENAMEX> now. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) Cut the God talk, and stop usurping
his place by popping fertility <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">candy</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) On the bright side, the
former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">octuplets</ENAMEX> are still only the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> surviving set of septuplets.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">12/28/98</NUMEX>)
            

            
The latest
attempt to circle the globe in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">balloon</ENAMEX> failed . <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mogul</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Branson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">millionaire</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Fossett</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Swedish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleague</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Per</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lindstrand</ENAMEX> made it halfway before adverse weather forced them down near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX>.
The spins: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) They failed. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) Adding injury to insult, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Branson</ENAMEX> will lose the
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$300,000</NUMEX> he had bet (against <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> bookmakers) that the trip would succeed.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) "It's a glorious failure," says a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Branson</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seven</ENAMEX> more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crews</ENAMEX> are
preparing to attempt the same feat and, sooner or later, one of them will
succeed. (For the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>'s reaction to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Branson</ENAMEX>'s failure, see ".")
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">12/28/98</NUMEX>)
            

            
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Football League</ENAMEX> playoffs are set . The top stories: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New York Jets</ENAMEX> won
their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">division</ENAMEX> for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time since joining the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NFL</ENAMEX>. (Their <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1969</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Super Bowl</ENAMEX>
triumph under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Namath</ENAMEX> predated the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFL-NFL</ENAMEX> merger.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroes</ENAMEX> are Coach
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Parcells</ENAMEX>, who lifted the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1-15</NUMEX> record <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years ago</TIMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX>-4 this
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> (beating his former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New England Patriots</ENAMEX>, twice <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>), and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">quarterback Vinny Testaverde</ENAMEX>, who staged one of <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX>'s greatest individual
comebacks by winning <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX> games he started, passing for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jets</ENAMEX>-record <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">29</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">touchdowns</ENAMEX> and leading the conference in passing. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arizona Cardinals</ENAMEX> made
the playoffs for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16 years</TIMEX> by winning their final game the
same exciting way they won <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> other games down the stretch: on a field goal
as time expired. They will face the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dallas Cowboys</ENAMEX> with a chance to achieve the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">first Cardinals</ENAMEX> playoff win since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1947</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Denver Broncos</ENAMEX> running back <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Terrell</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Davis</ENAMEX> ran for <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">178 yards</NUMEX>, becoming the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> (along with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.J. Simpson</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric Dickerson</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry Sanders</ENAMEX>) to rush for <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2,000 yards</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a season</TIMEX>.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">12/28/98</NUMEX>)
            

         
      
   
