
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Movies
            

            

               
                  Affliction
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lion</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Gate Films</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nick Nolte</ENAMEX>'s
outstanding acting and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Schrader</ENAMEX>'s masterful directing earn this film
uniformly high marks from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>. As a tragically repressed and alcoholic
small-town <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cop</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nolte</ENAMEX> conveys a "fierce, anguished intensity" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Maslin</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> say <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schrader</ENAMEX>'s style is a perfect match for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russell Banks</ENAMEX>' novel, and that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> "has hit, in this exquisitely
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">shaped</ENAMEX>, paced, painted, and edited production, a new, deep level of artistry"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lisa Schwarzbaum</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Entertainment Weekly</ENAMEX> ). Only complaint: The voice-over
narration by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willem Dafoe</ENAMEX> (as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nolte</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>) is a bit stilted and portentous.
(Read this
interview with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Banks</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pinckney Benedict</ENAMEX>, and click for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Edelstein</ENAMEX>'s
review in 
                  Slate
               .)

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hilary</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Jackie</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">October Films</ENAMEX>). Based on the life of phenomenal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cellist Jacqueline du Pré</ENAMEX>, as remembered by her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>, this film has the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> split. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anand Tucker</ENAMEX>'s film is often unflattering to the late <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">musician</ENAMEX>,
and some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX> mark it as the work of a jealous sibling out to tarnish her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>'s hallowed image. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gwendolyn Freed</ENAMEX>'s outraged review in the Wall
Street Journal attempts to refute many of the film's claims and says it
"paints a repulsive portrait of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">du Pré</ENAMEX>." Others rave, calling it "a compelling
look at the most intimate and troubling of family dynamics" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Turan</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> ), with a stellar performance by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emily Watson</ENAMEX> as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackie</ENAMEX>. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Mathews</ENAMEX> writes in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsday</ENAMEX> , the film is "superb," and
"accurate or not, it makes a great story." (Visit the
official site.)

            
               
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hi</ENAMEX>-Lo
Country
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gramercy Pictures</ENAMEX>). The "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chaps</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stetsons</ENAMEX> here prove
an ill fit" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Rainer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> ) for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Frears</ENAMEX>
( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dangerous Liaisons</ENAMEX> ) as he tries his hand at a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">1940s</NUMEX> western. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woody</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harrelson</ENAMEX> is "spectacularly kinetic" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Holden</ENAMEX>, the New York
Times ) as a ne'er-do-well cowboy, but the rest of the film drags. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Billy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crudup</ENAMEX> (as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harrelson</ENAMEX>'s best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> and business <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX>) is stiff, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patricia</ENAMEX>
Arquette, playing the object of both their desires, fails to generate the heat
her temptress-extraordinaire part requires. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dennis Lim</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Village</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Voice</ENAMEX> calls it a "perfunctory, often dreary love-triangle melodrama."
(<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Visit "Groveling At The Feet Of A Goddess</ENAMEX>," a "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patricia</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arquette Shrine</ENAMEX>," and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edelstein</ENAMEX>'s pan in 
                  Slate
               .)

            

               Books
            

            
               
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Haunted</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wood: Soviet Espionage in America</ENAMEX>--The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stalin</ENAMEX> Era
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weinstein</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander Vassiliev</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Random House</ENAMEX>). Reviewers praise this exposé
based on reams of declassified <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KGB</ENAMEX> documents detailing <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> espionage in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1930s</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early '50s</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> say reading it is
"rather like looking into the new edition of a book from which half the pages
had previously been torn out" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph F. Perisco</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Book</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Review</ENAMEX> ). Controversial figures such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alger Hiss</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rosenbergs</ENAMEX>, and
others thought by many to be the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Red hunts of the '40s</ENAMEX> and '50s
are confirmed as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spies</ENAMEX>. "The importance of this book cannot be overstated"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arnold Beichman</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Times</ENAMEX> ). (Buy the book at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.)

            
               
                  Note Found
in a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bottle: My Life</ENAMEX> as a Drinker
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Cheever</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simon</ENAMEX> &
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schuster</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Cheever</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> takes a beating: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Yardley</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cheever</ENAMEX>'s memoir of her struggles with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> is "Grade B
literary/journalistic opportunism-cum-sensationalism" (the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alex Beam</ENAMEX> goes further in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Globe</ENAMEX> , calling it a
"despicable, wooden memoir." The "inescapable conclusion of Note ," he
continues, "is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cheever</ENAMEX> is a horrible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>, engorged with self-regard,
who has been masticating the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">corpse</ENAMEX> of her dead, successful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> for fun and
profit." A few <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pipe</ENAMEX> up to defend her: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Publishers Weekly</ENAMEX> calls it "a
powerful story written in precise, emotionally intense prose." (Read this interview with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cheever</ENAMEX> in the New York
Times [requires free registration], in which she responds to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yardley</ENAMEX>'s
comments in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> : "That's just what he did to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daddy</ENAMEX>.")

            

               
                  Glamorama
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bret Easton Ellis</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Knopf</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ellis</ENAMEX>'
latest novel of ennui and anomie among <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s beautiful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> irritates
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX> to varying degrees. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michiko Kakutani</ENAMEX> is dismissive in the New York
Times , calling it a "glutinous hodgepodge of a book ... a lugubrious,
repetitious tale." While never resorting to praise, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> 's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alex Ross</ENAMEX> concedes that it may be <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ellis</ENAMEX>' most fully realized novel since The
Rules of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Attraction</ENAMEX> and describes the prose style as "mysteriously
elegant." The most apt description of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ellis</ENAMEX>' achievement comes from Rhonda
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lieberman</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Village Voice</ENAMEX> , who says that in this portrait of
"post-macho," name-dropping, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Prada</ENAMEX>-clad male <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">models</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ellis</ENAMEX> "captures a cultural
moment of radical dandyhood." (Join the Bret
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Easton Ellis Discussion Forum</ENAMEX>.)

            

               Recent "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment</ENAMEX>" columns
            

             

            

               
                  Movie--
                  A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Civil Action</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- The Thin Red Line</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie -- Down in the 
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Delta</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hurlyburly</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie -- Theory of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flight</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Book--
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Careless Love: The Unmaking of Elvis</ENAMEX>
Presley , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Guralnick</ENAMEX>;

               
                  Book
                  --
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jew</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ben</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Katchor</ENAMEX>.

            

             

            

               
                  Movie--
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patch Adams</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie
                  --The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Faculty</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie
                  --Stepmom ;

               
                  Movie
                  --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mighty Joe Young</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Book--
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hundred Dollar Holiday</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McKibben</ENAMEX>;

               
                  Book
                  --The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vintner</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luck</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Knox</ENAMEX>.

            

             

            

               
                  Movie--
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prince</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie--
                  You've Got <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mail</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie--
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Book--
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Blind Man's Bluff: The Untold Story of American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Submarine Espionage</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sherry Sontag</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Drew</ENAMEX>, with Annette
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lawrence Drew</ENAMEX>;

               
                  Book--
                  Opened Ground: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Selected Poems</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1966-1996</TIMEX> , by Seamus
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heaney</ENAMEX>;

               
                  Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- The Unknown Matisse: A Life</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henri Matisse</ENAMEX>, The Early
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Years, 1869-1908</TIMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hilary Spurling</ENAMEX>.

            

             

            

               
                  Movie--
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Love</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Star Trek: Insurrection</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rushmore</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie -- A <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Simple Plan</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Frost</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Television--
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tempest</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>);

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX>--
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blue Room</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Hare</ENAMEX> (Cort
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theatre</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>).

            

         
      
   
