
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Drawing upon her rich experience of life, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> to her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>) responds to questions about manners, personal relations, politics, and
other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX>. Please send your questions for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> to prudence@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Queries
should not exceed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> words in length. Please indicate how you wish your letter
to be signed, preferably including your location.
            

            
               
                  Dear
Prudie,
               
            

            
               I have a problem with one of my "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>." To
make a long story short, she has lied about multiple things since I became
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> with her. The <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">other night</TIMEX> she asked my opinion about something, and
once I told her she seemed fine. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next day</TIMEX>, however, she proceeded to call
everyone and repeat the story--only her version was different from what
happened.
            

            
               I sent her a card to
let her know that if I'd hurt her feelings I was sorry, but I did not
appreciate her telling everyone something untrue. My question is: Should I wait
for her to respond or go ahead and call to initiate the conversation?
            

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Rumors Make Me Crazy</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tacoma</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Rum</ENAMEX>,

            How about a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> choice: unloading this "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>"
who doesn't seem to know the truth from <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> base? When you say she has "lied
about multiple things," Prudie wonders what possible value she can have to
you.

            You could, Prudie
supposes, continue with this "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>" whose word you have no faith in, but the
question remains: Whatever for? Bail out and clear your head.

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, truthfully

            
               
                  Dear
Prudie,
               
            

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> is ""  over software
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">billionaire</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave Duffield</ENAMEX> giving <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$200 million</NUMEX> for homeless <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX>. "What
about homeless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>?" he/she asks.
            

            
               No <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offense</ENAMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who care about animals
also care about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave Duffield</ENAMEX> has several adopted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in his
family.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> who really care about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> usually care about <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX>, too.
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mother Teresa</ENAMEX> cared passionately about <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX>.) And in my experience, people
who complain about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are helping <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> are usually not helping
anyone at all!
            

            
               The fact is that this
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> is practically swimming in abandoned <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pets</ENAMEX>. These innocent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">creatures</ENAMEX> are
born, bought, and then abandoned--by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. The fact that anyone can be upset
at someone using his own private money to do something helpful when there are
vapid rich <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> doing nothing whatever to help anyone is strange,
indeed.
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mountain</ENAMEX>,
            

            

               Best <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Friends Animal Sanctuary</ENAMEX>
            

            

               P.S.: No, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave</ENAMEX> is not my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncle</ENAMEX>!
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Mic</ENAMEX>,

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> knew, when she ran the letter from "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Burned</ENAMEX>
Up," that animal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lovers</ENAMEX> were a fiercely loyal and vociferous lot, and said so.
The points you make are sound and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX>'s view is just, well, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX>'s view.
While she does like many of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pets</ENAMEX>, she also goes to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">zoo</ENAMEX> and
sees fur coats pacing around the cages.

            Nothing you say is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">arguable</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> just have different priorities. Prudie salutes you for not
only caring about a public issue but also doing something about it. For you,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> would adapt a famous admonition and tell you to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sharpei</ENAMEX> diem! Seize the
wrinkled <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> and do what you think is necessary!

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, agreeably

            
               
                  Dear
Prudie,
               
            

            
               First, I would like to say that I really enjoy
your column. Not only do you seem to invariably draw interesting and pertinent
questions, but also your advice is, more often than not, that which I would
want to hear or would give if they asked me. So ... I have a question. How to
put this? I am in a committed, monogamous relationship with another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>, whom
I plan to marry sometime in the near future. We've been together a little less
than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX>. My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> have voiced an interest in "getting to know" her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>, and while I am all for it, I sense some reluctance on my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX>'s
side. Recently, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> asked if I would provide them with my "in-laws' "
address, so they could send them a holiday card. (My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> are nominally
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX>, hers are <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX>.) I am stalling on handing it over.
            

            
               What is the proper
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> to go about this? Should I let the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX>" work this out among themselves,
or should I try to mediate? I would appreciate any help you can provide on this
issue.
            

            
               Much thanks in
advance,
            

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anna Nutt</ENAMEX>
            

            

               P.S.: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pearl Bailey</ENAMEX> said, "What the world really needs is more love and less
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">paperwork</ENAMEX>."
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear An</ENAMEX>,

            It is ironic that your letter asks about initiating
a correspondence, while your quotation from Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bailey</ENAMEX> pleads for less
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">paperwork</ENAMEX>! But to try to be useful, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> will offer her thoughts.

            Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> are looser than others about their
daughters marrying other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> assumes your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX>'s understanding of her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>' outlook comes from knowledge. You might want to wait until she feels
the time is right for setting up the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">in-law</ENAMEX> connection. In the meantime,
compliment your own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> on their wish to promote the larger family
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">circle</ENAMEX>.

            Just as a little
something to think about, look on the bright side of not yet having a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother-in-law</ENAMEX> to deal with. You might be sparing yourself a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dragon</ENAMEX>--like one of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX>-in-law.

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, sparingly

            
               
                  Hi,
Prudie,
               
            

            
               I have no idea whom to turn to regarding this
problem, and I am not sure if even you would know the answer to this question.
I came to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years ago</TIMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> and started in the
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">10 th</NUMEX> grade. Having attended an <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> middle <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> (fully
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>--no other <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">language</ENAMEX>) I spoke English very fluently, and my composition
and comprehension were so good that I won the district essay contest. I have
all kinds of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>, both <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Pakistani</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX>; I speak <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Urdu</ENAMEX> with my
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Pakistani</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> with others, and I can safely say
that I speak more <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> than my native tongue.
            

            
               This is where the problem arises. I have been
here for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">almost three years</TIMEX>, and I still haven't developed that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
accent. In fact, I am still speaking like I did when I stepped off the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX>. I
know a couple of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arabs</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanics</ENAMEX> who did not speak a word of English when
they came here but learned <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> with an "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">American</ENAMEX>" accent within a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>.
            

            
               I've tried everything--even talking to myself in
a closed <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>, and even watching <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sesame Street</ENAMEX> !!!! Nothing works.
Please help, because now that I am in college it is very frustrating when
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> ask me whether I'm an international <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX>, or their <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> question is
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Where are you from?</ENAMEX>"
            

            
               An <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> accent,
in my view, is the key to my success!
            

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Extreme Privacy</ENAMEX>, Please
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Ex</ENAMEX>,

            Calm yourself. Your use of a second <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">language</ENAMEX> is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sterling</ENAMEX>. The key to your success is what you say, not the accent with which
you say it.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> cannot be alone in
finding accents charming--and, in fact, wishes she had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> (other than
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Midwestern</ENAMEX>). Don't spend <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">another minute</TIMEX> worrying about this. In time, you will
undoubtedly sound more "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX>." And the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Where are you from?</ENAMEX>" question is a
good opening gambit, not a put-down. Wear your different background with
pride.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, speaking
plainly

         
      
   
