
   
   
      
         
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate on Toilet</ENAMEX>
Paper
            

            Although I greatly enjoy
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Plotz</ENAMEX>'s dispatches, the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 27</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dispatch "</ENAMEX>" may have given me a nit to
pick where it quotes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben Nighthorse Campbell</ENAMEX>. Perhaps this quote should
have been offered without using the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX>'s name because the remark was
apparently intended to be off the record. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX> was complaining about the
very thing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Plotz</ENAMEX> has now done: getting a sound bite from a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX> relieving
himself. If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Plotz</ENAMEX> did not get the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX>'s permission to use the quote, an
apology may be in order.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
Purnell
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">San</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francisco</ENAMEX>

            
               Kill <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kazan</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Deathbed Oscar</ENAMEX>
            

            In his otherwise useful and accurate analysis of the
issues involving <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elia Kazan</ENAMEX>'s honorary <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oscar</ENAMEX>, "," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Weisberg</ENAMEX> perpetuates
the myth that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> has for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX> been punishing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kazan</ENAMEX> by withholding
laurels that would have been his had he not named names. "He deserves an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oscar</ENAMEX>
as much as anyone living--for best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>, not for best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">human being</ENAMEX>," writes
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weisberg</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kazan</ENAMEX> already has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> Best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oscars</ENAMEX>, including <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> for
On the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Waterfront</ENAMEX> , the film in which he "made his case" for snitching,
as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weisberg</ENAMEX> puts it. He was also nominated for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> other <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Academy Awards</ENAMEX> and
has won <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Golden Globes</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Film Critics Circle Awards</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Directors Guild Awards</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorary</ENAMEX> (a k a "lifetime
achievement" or "deathbed") Oscars are typically consolation prizes, given to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> whose work was overlooked in its time--such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cary Grant</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Howard Hawks</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Federico Fellini</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanley Donen</ENAMEX>, none of whom ever won a real <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Oscar</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Kazan</ENAMEX>
was a brilliant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>, but he's already been saluted for that, so why give
him a lifetime achievement statue and not, say, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Ford</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Lean</ENAMEX>?
Apparently <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> really does want to acknowledge that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kazan</ENAMEX> did the right
thing all those <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX>. And as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weisberg</ENAMEX> makes clear, he did not.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel</ENAMEX>
Radosh
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott Shuger Is</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trippin</ENAMEX>'
            

            Although I'm certain it amused <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott Shuger</ENAMEX> (an
amusing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>, to judge by the terrific "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>") to join the ranks of
those who have publicly disparaged <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Tripp</ENAMEX>, the fact remains that nothing
in his piece, "," reflects at all on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tripp</ENAMEX> herself.

            I can't help but wonder if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shuger</ENAMEX> thought to ask
himself a few simple questions before launching his attack-- questions such as,
did <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX> ask to be moved to her current job? Was it her idea that she be
placed on "leave" and sent home to "work"? Did <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX> have any input into the
salary for her current position? If the job were held by someone other than
Tripp, would it pay any less or involve any more work?

            I suspect I know the
answers to these questions, and I suspect Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shuger</ENAMEX> does as well. In fact, the
sole purpose of his piece was to continue the media assault on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX> as some
kind of back-stabbing dragon <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> whom we should all view with disgust and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">loathing</ENAMEX>. Well done, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott</ENAMEX>!

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russ</ENAMEX>
Evansen
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madison</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wis.</ENAMEX>

            
               Gordonian
Not
            

            What a precious little world <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Gordon</ENAMEX> inhabits.
evoke images of little, high-rise dollhouses full of paranoid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> who
rarely disagree about art and never disagree about politics.

             The goal to life in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gordonian</ENAMEX> universe is to do
good--or to do <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, provided one isn't too cowardly to snap one's thong.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is good. He's a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">compassionate mattress thrasher</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford Maddox Ford</ENAMEX> is
good, if maddeningly redundant. He left his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, and he's kind to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Polish</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ingrates</ENAMEX>.

             <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Conrad</ENAMEX> is bad. He's a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Polish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ingrate</ENAMEX>. His
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> is stupid, and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are sickly. He was mean to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford Maddox Ford</ENAMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> love <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford Maddox Ford</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX> loves <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX>. She's on a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>-name basis
with him, although it's kind of hard to tell. But it doesn't matter. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX> is
dead.

             The cute <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> in high school didn't talk to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX>.
But that doesn't matter, either. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> is cute. He talks to her.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> are bad. They're mean to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>,
which is a lot like being mean to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford Maddox Ford</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> might kill
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>; that's what the crazy old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> says. He's crazy, but it still
could happen. Could too!

            Lying is bad, but not real bad. Envy and pride are
the cold sins. They're real bad. It's better to lie and be nice than to tell
the truth and be mean. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is nice. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> are mean. You can't tell
the truth and be nice at the same time. 

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX> wants to be good, but she doesn't know how.
Should she write <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> op-ed pieces about bad <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>, or
should she just write novels like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nabokov</ENAMEX>? Should she read <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Good</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Soldier</ENAMEX> , or should she stop being a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coward</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">salute</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>'s good
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldier</ENAMEX>? Maybe he'll lie to her.

            Sometimes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> expect too much from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX>.
Sometimes she wishes they were dead. That's bad. It's bad to wish <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were
dead. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> wish <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> were dead. The world is scary.

            Now I understand. I love
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX>'s diary. It's good.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Ireland</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
