
   
   
      
         
             <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">&quot;Findings of Fact&quot</ENAMEX>;

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 10</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sens.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orrin Hatch</ENAMEX>,
R-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Olympia Snowe</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maine</ENAMEX>, went on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> to accept
congratulations for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>'s bipartisan launch of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
impeachment trial. When asked about polls showing dissatisfaction with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>'s conduct of the inquiry, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> brushed them off. "I'm not going
to worry ... about polls," scoffed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Snowe</ENAMEX>. "Polls are polls are polls," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hatch</ENAMEX>
chimed in. "You can find almost anything you want in polls. Look, we wouldn't
have civil rights laws if we abided by the polls. We wouldn't have a lot of
things that are right if we'd abided by the polls. ... Our job is not to worry
about the polls. Our job is to do justice."

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Three weeks later</TIMEX>, the
façade of bipartisanship has collapsed, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hatch</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Snowe</ENAMEX> are singing a new
tune. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent days</TIMEX> they've proposed a "findings of fact" resolution under
which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> would affirm by majority vote that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> gave "misleading
testimony" and schemed "to alter, delay, impede, cover up and conceal the
existence of evidence" in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> case and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>
investigation. In theory, censure would merely condemn <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> morally, whereas
findings of fact would certify that despite the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>'s failure to remove him,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> had proved his guilt. But in practice, the findings
proposal isn't about facts. It's about spin and public opinion.

            The obvious rationale for the findings resolution is what
it would not do. Since many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> who think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is guilty of
lying and covering up aren't willing to declare him guilty of "high crimes" and
remove him from office, the resolution is designed to let them affirm the
former without the latter. But the resolution's affirmative rationale--what it
would do--is less clear. Its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> say it has no legal
consequences. If it won't cost <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> his job or punish him for a crime,
what's the point?

            In a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> New York
Times op-ed, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hatch</ENAMEX> explained his purpose. "The message the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> sent to
our posterity is that Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s behavior is immoral and wrong," he argued.
"Were the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> to adjourn and make these findings [affirming the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>'s
conclusions], it would deny the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> an acquittal--the result he craves
for his own historic legitimacy. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> would also make clear that the
House-passed articles of impeachment are constitutionally legitimate." Above
all, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hatch</ENAMEX> stressed the importance of "avoiding a historic vote on the merits,
which could be interpreted as vindicating the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>." The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next day</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Snowe</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">echoed Hatch</ENAMEX>'s remarks: "The significance of finding of facts is it would be
part of the permanent record of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> of impeachment. ... We do owe it to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to inform them of the facts."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX> essage. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Posterity</ENAMEX>. Immoral. Wrong. Legitimacy.
Interpreted. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vindicating</ENAMEX>. Significance. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> . These words
are not about facts. They are about what really galls and worries <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>
as they approach the trial's certain demise: They have lost the struggle to
give the facts meaning and authority, which are ultimately decided by public
opinion. Their arguments in the trial's final days are replete with desperate,
belated appeals to the popular will. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Rogan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX>,
says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> must call <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> "if they're going to have a verdict that
will withstand the test of history." <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chuck Hagel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Neb.</ENAMEX>, says closed-door
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> deliberations on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s fate "would cast too much of a cloud of
suspicion."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>'s most
remarkable complaint is that if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> votes not to remove <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> will stage another "pep rally" and will spin the vote not just as
an "acquittal" but as an "exoneration." This fear is well justified, but its
naked expression betrays the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>' tragic knowledge that they have
failed to engender enough public faith in the impeachment process to withstand
dismissive words from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> they have supposedly disgraced. On
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Lockhart</ENAMEX> promised, no doubt falsely, not to
spin the vote against removal as a repudiation of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partisanship</ENAMEX> and
of the charges against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. "I now declare, in a post-impeachment <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">era</TIMEX>, this
a gloat-free zone," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lockhart</ENAMEX>. Here was an astonishing spectacle: The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">spokesman</ENAMEX> for an impeached <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> offering terms under which the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> could surrender with honor, having lost in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s ultimate
court.

            To pass findings of fact, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> need only <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">51</NUMEX>
votes. But to achieve the credibility these findings are supposed to bestow on
the impeachment inquiry, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Snowe</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> admit they need at least
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>. Thanks to the inquiry's partisan meltdown, that seems unlikely.
Fearful that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> will unilaterally dictate the resolution's language,
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> refuse to consider it, preferring to end the trial and then debate a
censure resolution under normal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> rules, which would give <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> the
protective power of the filibuster. And fearful that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Independent Counsel</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX> will use a findings resolution to bolster an indictment of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> refuse to supply the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ammunition</ENAMEX>.

            So the findings resolution has quickly become the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> of the partisan skepticism it was supposed to overcome. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> called it an unconstitutional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> scheme to "save
face," "embarrass the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>," and appease "an element of their constituency
that wants conviction." The more "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> persist in demanding live
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> and demanding more depositions and demanding extralegal devices, like
it becomes a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> trial."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>'s best option at
this point is to embrace the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>' plan to vote quickly on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
removal, end the trial, and censure him. This would achieve most of the
objectives of the findings of fact resolution. Instead, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>
continue to antagonize <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> gratuitously. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, they sent
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> an open letter urging him to testify before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>, disregarding
repeated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> statements that he would not do so. They told the press
that censure wasn't "strong" enough and that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> were trying to turn the
findings proposal into "a partisan issue" because "they're scared to death of
it." But when you're the majority <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> and your task is to convince the public
that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the opposing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> has been legitimately impeached,
"partisanship" should be the last word out of your mouth. That's worse than
spin. That's dumb spin.

         
      
   
