
   
   
      
         
             See You in Court

            How can <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>
secure a censure agreement and avert a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> trial? That's the question
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> have naively debated since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> was impeached. The naiveté lies not
in their answers but in the question. Who says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> prefers censure? In many
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ways</ENAMEX>, he'd be better off sabotaging the censure movement and polarizing the
trial.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>.

               The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chicken</ENAMEX> game. The conventional wisdom says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is afraid of
being convicted. But is he the only one who fears that outcome? Although
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> pooh-poohed the notion that they'd be voted out of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">impeaching</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>, they're less sanguine about
their chances of being voted out for throwing him out of office in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>. That's
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> reason why <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> have expressed far less enthusiasm for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">convicting Clinton</ENAMEX> than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> showed in impeaching him. Why
shouldn't he call the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>'s bluff?

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s legacy. The conventional wisdom says
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> must avert conviction in order to safeguard his legacy. But would
censure serve his legacy better than a trial would? Arguably, impeachment has
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tarnished Clinton</ENAMEX>'s presidency as gravely as he could have imagined. And many
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> think if he's forced to sign a bipartisan, self-abasing censure
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resolution</ENAMEX>, he'll be humiliated, broken, and unable to pass any part of his
agenda in his final <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX>. Could conviction and removal be much worse than
that? On this line of reasoning, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has little left to lose in a trial and
much to gain. Trial and acquittal might be his only hope of erasing the stain
of impeachment.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>.

               The ordeal. The conventional wisdom says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> should waive his
defense and avoid calling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> in order to shorten the trial and end his
"ordeal." But whose ordeal is it? <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> have been saying for days
that they don't want to antagonize the public by calling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> and dragging
out the trial for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX>. Why not give them what they don't want? The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>
prosecution <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> includes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Barr</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">R-Ga.</ENAMEX>, and other former federal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> who are champing at the bit to call <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> and perhaps a
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozen</NUMEX> other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Majority Whip</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom DeLay</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>, wants to drag
"evidence" about other alleged <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> sexual escapades into the trial. Why not
call <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX>, inflame these incendiary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">accusers</ENAMEX>, and help them ignite the
proceedings, perhaps torching their own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> in the process?

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Censure</ENAMEX> negotiations. The conventional wisdom says
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> shouldn't polarize the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> along partisan lines, because this would
disrupt the movement toward a censure deal. It's hard enough to work out a deal
already, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> observe, given that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> want to soften the censure
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resolution</ENAMEX> while <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> want to stiffen it. But why is this partisan rift
over the terms of censure bad for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>? He doesn't need a censure deal to
extinguish the threat of conviction. All he needs is a censure proposal that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">satisfies</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">34</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> enough to dissuade them from voting to convict him. If
the proposal fails, thereby sparing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> any penalty whatsoever, so much the
better.

            From this standpoint, a
partisan impasse over the terms of censure is exactly what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> needs. This
could be accomplished through various disputes, such as whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> must
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">confess</ENAMEX> to perjury before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">grand jury</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> insist on it; <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>
warn that it may kill the deal) and whether he should be fined (many
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> demand it; many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> say it's unfair or unconstitutional). The
important thing is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s fingerprints mustn't be found on the
sabotage. His best way to navigate this dilemma is by subtly encouraging
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> to hold out for terms so soft that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> can't abide them.

            
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. The sequence. The conventional wisdom
says if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> fails to strike a censure deal with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>, they might vote to convict him. But what if the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> options are
considered in reverse order? Already, several conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX>
are demanding that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> complete the trial and vote on conviction before
"negotiating" a censure deal. But once conviction has been voted down, why
should <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> negotiate? He can play it both ways: Cultivate the censure
movement in order to persuade <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> to vote against conviction, then
sabotage censure by encouraging <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberal</ENAMEX> and conservative zealots in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>
to hold out for extreme terms. Admittedly, this scenario requires that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
ignore what's best for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and that his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX> save him through
reckless excess. But that has been the story of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX>.

            
               Recent "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Frame Games</ENAMEX>"
            

            

               "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s Final Escape": Why the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> will spare his presidency.
(posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 23</TIMEX>)
               

               "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wag the Doubt</ENAMEX>": The debate over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> attack blazes new
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">frontiers</ENAMEX> in cynicism. (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 19</TIMEX>)
               

            

            
               Photograph of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zoraida Diaz</ENAMEX>.
            

         
      
   
