
   
   
      
         
            Lies, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Damned Lies</ENAMEX>, and Impeachment

            OK, so it's not about sex.
It's about lying under oath, obstruction of justice, and abuse of power. If the
standards used to impeach <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> for those offenses were applied to
his <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">predecessors</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>, they would have been
impeached too. The fact that they weren't owes less to any lack of evidence
than to a sense of proportion and respect for the popular will--or call it
cowardice, perhaps--in the opposition <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>), which then
controlled <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>.

            The only time <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> ever talked about <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Iran-Contra</ENAMEX> under oath was in a deposition for the
deposition was in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>, after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> had left <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>. He claimed that there was
not "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> iota" of evidence that profits from the sale of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX> had been
diverted to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nicaraguan Contras</ENAMEX>, that his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX> hadn't lied to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>
about the affair, and so on. All this was demonstrably false. The only reason
he might not be guilty of perjury is that his mind pretty clearly was
going.

            But the very fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> was never forced to testify
under oath as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> illustrates the double standard that has trapped Bill
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Special Prosecutor Lawrence Walsh</ENAMEX> had operated like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>,
he would have forced <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>, while <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, to repeat or renounce under oath
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> lies about <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Iran-Contra</ENAMEX>, such as those in his first TV address on the
subject, when he declared it "utterly false" that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX> had been shipped to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>
in exchange for the release of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hostages</ENAMEX>. This was as vivid as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s televised finger-wagging "that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>" sound bite, and just as flatly
untrue. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> had been at several meetings where the arms-for-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hostages</ENAMEX> deal
was discussed--and, indeed, where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> had warned him it was illegal
and he'd said he didn't care. If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walsh</ENAMEX> had been <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> would have faced
the same excruciating dilemma as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>: admit to a spectacular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> lie or
lie again under oath.

            Possibly <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> was
already gaga in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX>, while still <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, though this is not an argument the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> now pursuing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> are likely to want to make (or were heard to
make back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX>). But even before he was officially declared to be losing it,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> benefited from a more general double standard about truth telling.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> both are among the great bullshitters of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> history,
but somehow <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> was always regarded as floating above the truth while
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is regarded as wallowing beneath it.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walsh</ENAMEX>'s final report concluded that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> "knowingly
participated or at least acquiesced in" the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Iran-Contra</ENAMEX> cover-up, which
involved, among other things, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oliver North</ENAMEX> shredding <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of documents
that may well have implicated <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> more deeply. Any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX> cover-up pales in
comparison. (The nearest equivalent involves the mysterious
appearance --not disappearance--of documents, none of which has turned
out to be vital, in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">closet</ENAMEX>.) Yet <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walsh</ENAMEX> didn't bring charges
against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>, or even depose him to squeeze out information or set him up for
a perjury rap.

            The case against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>--by the standards being applied to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>--is even stronger. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>
claimed in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> campaign that he'd given sworn testimony <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds of</NUMEX> times
conceding that he knew all about the arms-for-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hostages</ENAMEX> deal. In fact, when the
story broke in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> repeatedly claimed to have been "out of the loop." He
knew we were selling <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>--itself flatly illegal and spectacularly in
conflict with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s public pronouncements--but, he claimed, he
had no idea the deal involved paying ransom for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hostages</ENAMEX>.

            Specifically, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> claimed not to have attended a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX> meeting at which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary of State</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Schultz</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Caspar Weinberger</ENAMEX> vehemently opposed trading for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hostages</ENAMEX>. When <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> logs indicated that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> was at the meeting, he emended his story to say
he hadn't caught the drift of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schultz</ENAMEX>'s and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weinberger</ENAMEX>'s objections. If only
he'd known <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cap</ENAMEX> were as bothered as he was, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> said, he would have
tried to stop the policy. This was his story until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walsh</ENAMEX> released
notes taken by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weinberger</ENAMEX> at the meeting, recording that "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VP</ENAMEX> approves" of the
policy <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> claimed to be both ignorant of and disturbed by.

            As <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989-93</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> did his best to thwart <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walsh</ENAMEX>'s investigation. He tightened up on the
release of classified information. A diary he started keeping in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX> somehow
never materialized until after the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> election. And his last-minute pardon of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weinberger</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Poindexter</ENAMEX>, and others, after he'd lost re-election, effectively
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">thwarted Walsh</ENAMEX>'s pursuit of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> himself, among others. No "obstruction of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">justice</ENAMEX>" or "abuse of presidential power" in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Flytrap</ENAMEX> comes close.

            So why is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>'s presidency stamped forever with
the shame of impeachment, and why does he face premature removal from office,
when impeachment was never seriously considered for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>? Perhaps at
this point <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> would like to revisit their insistence that it's
not about sex. The only sensible distinction is that lies about some things
matter more than others. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Hyde</ENAMEX>, for example, was quite eloquent back in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Iran-Contra</ENAMEX> era about how statesmanship and higher principles sometimes
require <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidents</ENAMEX> to lie and break the law.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hyde</ENAMEX> and others would be
tempted to say that lying to free <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hostages</ENAMEX> and breaking the law to
protect <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Latin America</ENAMEX> from communism are more justified than lies to hide a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tawdry</ENAMEX> affair. I would be tempted to reply that lies and cover-ups intended to
thwart the workings of democracy on an important public policy issue seem to me
to be a lot worse than lies about an embarrassing personal mess. But perhaps we
could agree that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Schippers</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Judiciary Committee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Counsel</ENAMEX>, was
wrong in his self-righteous pronouncement "Lies are lies are lies."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schippers</ENAMEX> himself told a quick series of obvious whoppers
during that same impeachment hearing opening statement. "When I appeared in
this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> room a little over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two months ago</TIMEX>," he said (mournful as the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Walrus</ENAMEX> in Through the Looking <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glass</ENAMEX> ), "it was merely to analyze the
[<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> report] referral and to report to you. Today, after our investigation, I
come to a point that frankly I prayed I would never reach. It is my sorrowful
duty now to accuse <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Jefferson Clinton</ENAMEX>," etc., etc. Raise your
hand if you believe <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schippers a</ENAMEX>) was feeling sorrowful; b) had prayed that his
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> of effort to nail the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> would be in vain; c) was being frank; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">d</ENAMEX>)
had no settled view on the whole matter even after analyzing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">report</ENAMEX>, until "our investigation" (whatever that consisted of). And while your
hand is up, would you care to swear an oath that you believe these unbelievable
things?

            "Every time a witness
lies, that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX> chips a stone from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundation</ENAMEX> of our entire legal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">system</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schippers</ENAMEX> intoned. Or does he make an exception when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX> is
himself?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Lott</ENAMEX>, as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">majority leader</ENAMEX>, is overseer of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">forthcoming Clinton</ENAMEX> trial. He was pictured in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Friday</TIMEX>'s New York
Times actually wagging his finger, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>-"that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>"-style, as he
publicly lied to get himself out of a fix. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> he had said about the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baghdad</ENAMEX> bombing: "While I have been assured by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> that
there is no connection with the impeachment process ... I cannot support this
military action in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Persian Gulf</ENAMEX> at this time. Both the timing and the
policy are subject to question." It was immediately clear that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lott</ENAMEX> should not
have said this. So on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lott</ENAMEX> declared that he did support the action,
did not suspect any connection with the impeachment process, and had not meant
to imply otherwise merely by uttering words whose plain meaning and universal
interpretation was the exact opposite. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lott</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sushi</ENAMEX>-master carve-up of the
phrase "at this time" was positively <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clintonian</ENAMEX> in its boldness and artistry.
Of course he wasn't under oath, so that's OK.

            What made the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lott</ENAMEX> incident especially enjoyable is
that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> all rallied round the obvious meaning of his original
statement even as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lott</ENAMEX> himself was denying it. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Gigot</ENAMEX>, for example, got
trapped midspin-cycle. In his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> column on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX>
editorial page, he praised <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lott</ENAMEX>'s remark as "an honest, considered judgment."
But how could a conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX> and major flag waver for the
original <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gulf War</ENAMEX> honestly oppose punishing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Saddam</ENAMEX> for violating his surrender
terms? Easy: "This is the surreal politics <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> has created. <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Hawks</ENAMEX> are
now doves and vice versa." But surely, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul</ENAMEX>, you don't really believe <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
bombed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baghdad</ENAMEX> to affect the impeachment vote? Well, no, but, "The tragedy for
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> interests is that Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is doubted even when he might be
right."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Neato</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is thus responsible not only for his
own lies and hypocrisies but also for those of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX>. No doubt he is
somehow to blame for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iran-Contra</ENAMEX> too.

         
      
   
