
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">179</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">&quot;A Pair of Weasels&quot</ENAMEX>;

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alluding</ENAMEX> to a verbal dyad, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamar Alexander</ENAMEX> called them "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Weasel</ENAMEX> words,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cleverly</ENAMEX> and deliberately put together to confuse <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> by meaning nothing."
What <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> words?
            

             

            by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> to e-mail your answer to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            

               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>'s question (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 178</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">W-O-M-A-N</ENAMEX>":
            

            

               
                  
                     
                        "She was quite a talented <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>, and she was
cute as a button too. And being the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>, she did give it the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>'s touch."
Who said this, about whom, for doing
what?
                     
                  
               
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarence Thomas</ENAMEX>, about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cheryl Mills</ENAMEX>' presentation at the impeachment
trial."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Deb Stavin</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Radosh</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlie Glassenberg</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">R.C. Leander</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg Diamond</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Your Trial of Trials</ENAMEX>"
Solovay , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danny Franklin</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anna Pond</ENAMEX> had similar
answers.)

            "Rep.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Barr</ENAMEX>, re his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">abortionist</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Kelly</ENAMEX>
            

            "Cary
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grant</ENAMEX>, about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randolph Scott</ENAMEX>'s ability to put together a lovely window
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">box</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Amaros</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">That</ENAMEX>
would be one of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hallmark</ENAMEX>'s new 'Saucy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gent' Mother</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Day</ENAMEX> cards."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim</ENAMEX>
Carvell
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicole</ENAMEX>
Kidman, describing her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s ... Oh, wait. My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> just called. I've been
hit with a restraining order prohibiting me from finishing the
sentence."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Leary</ENAMEX>
            

             

            Click
for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more</NUMEX> responses.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">She takes--bakes?</ENAMEX>--just
like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>." <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> way or the other, that's how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dylan</ENAMEX> put it, and who was
hurt when he did? Perhaps a few malcontents given to phrases like "incoherent
nasal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">honking</ENAMEX>." But, fortunately, this was a rhetorical question meant only to
remind us that we can't judge the praise of the past by the praise of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes ago</TIMEX>. On the other hand, those who encourage us to forget the past are
usually <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Augusto Pinochet</ENAMEX>. So how should we respond to the ostensible
compliment in question? Is it churlish to rebuff praise? Not if it's
pseudopraise, the poison ivy disguised as a rose bouquet: "You look great. I
didn't recognize you!" Our quoted compliment employs the implicit tokenism of
the definite article--"the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>"--the condescension of "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>," the dubious
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">virtue</ENAMEX> of "talented," suggesting that her abilities were something she was born
with, not something she earned. So perhaps it's not a matter of changing mores
after all, just hidden dish. Or as the old tambourine <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> put it--now I
remember--"She rakes just like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>." You know--gardening, nature: It's so
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">feminine</ENAMEX>.

            
               Your Answer of
Answers
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carl Reiner</ENAMEX> thought he was praising the late <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucille</ENAMEX>
Kallen, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sid Caesar</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Your Show of Shows</ENAMEX> , who died last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">76</NUMEX>.

            "At the time, I felt it
was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> big happy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kallen</ENAMEX> once remarked, "but later I said, What an
idiot! There was a male <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">phalanx</ENAMEX>, and then there was me. But when we were
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">working</ENAMEX>, there was no difference." The basis (with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later</TIMEX> Caesar <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Selma</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Diamond</ENAMEX>) of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sally Rogers</ENAMEX> on The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Van Dyke Show</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kallen</ENAMEX> went on to
write <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> novels. The male <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">phalanx</ENAMEX> included <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neil Simon</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mel Brooks</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woody</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen</ENAMEX>.

            
               Augmented
Quotations Extra
            

            (Each final sentence added
by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Quiz</ENAMEX>.)

            

               "I'm a big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum of Tolerance</ENAMEX>. I think we need more tolerance in TV. More busty
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">lifeguards</ENAMEX> and more tolerance."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Coast</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don Ohlmeyer</ENAMEX>, at a conference on "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Primetime Television</ENAMEX>" at
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Four Seasons Hotel</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beverly Hills</ENAMEX>
               

               "I've always thought of
this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> as akin to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rolling Stone</ENAMEX> . And I
see myself as a dead <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ringer</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dame Margot Fonteyn</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Brill</ENAMEX> takes a long, hard look at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brill</ENAMEX>'s
Content

               "I didn't set out
dreaming about being <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> when I was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>, nor did I dream about being
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX>. I dreamed about being <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willie Mays</ENAMEX>. I'd wake up in a cold sweat,
shrieking my guts out: He's black, you know."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>, interviewed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dallas Morning</ENAMEX>
News

               "No more torture or other
forms of abuse. There must be an end to the unnecessary recourse to the death
penalty. When it's necessary, OK, but let's not go nuts."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pope John Paul II</ENAMEX>, speaking in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico City</ENAMEX>
               

               "Please be quiet. Please
shut up. Please give me back my pants."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leach</ENAMEX> quells the unruly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cool Site of the Year Awards</ENAMEX>
               

            

            
               Race
Results
            

            Submitted top <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">target</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>.

            Actually run top <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">target</ENAMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cheryl Mills</ENAMEX> or, more precisely, condescending reactions to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cheryl Mills</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Disclaimer</ENAMEX>: All
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">submissions</ENAMEX> will become the property of 
               
                  Slate
               

               and will be published at 
               
                  Slate
               
               's
discretion. 
               
                  Slate
                
               may publish your name on its
site in connection with your submission .

         
      
   
