
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hail</ENAMEX>, Caesar

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
State of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union</ENAMEX> address was greeted around the world <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> as
the possible harbinger of another miraculous comeback. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hong Kong Standard</ENAMEX>
said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> that "if Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s was a bravura performance in the face of
so much adversity, it was also because he had facts and figures to back his
claim that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> was not only strong but also brimming with
confidence. ... It seemed somehow as if the personal confidence he brought to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> had been transferred to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> itself." Those still
wondering whether to impeach him "might well think carefully now before
committing themselves to an obviously unpopular cause."

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>, the daily
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asahi</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shimbun</ENAMEX> said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> that his speech went right to the heart of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> values. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> came across as "a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> concerned with the daily
lives of working <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>," over whom impeachment appears to cast no
shadow. "His effort to regain prestige and recover the cohesion of an
administration damaged by the impeachment process must have been at least
temporarily successful," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said, adding that it is likely that he will
continue to conduct an aggressive foreign policy. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jerusalem Post</ENAMEX> took his pledge
to "work for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> has a government worthy of its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>" as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">signal</ENAMEX> that he will try to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">depose</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX>.

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turin</ENAMEX> paper <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Stampa</ENAMEX> carried a
front-page editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> comparing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Julius Caesar</ENAMEX>. Under the
headline "The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Return of Super Bill</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gabriele Romagnoli</ENAMEX> wrote,
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caesar</ENAMEX> climbed the steps of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol</ENAMEX>, entered the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hall</ENAMEX> of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX>,
looked everyone in the face (including a few <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brutuses</ENAMEX>), and then, great showman
that he is, smiled; and in a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">77 minute one man</TIMEX> show he conquered the theatre
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">98 ovations</NUMEX>) and the public (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">6 percent</NUMEX> rise in his popularity)." It concluded,
"Such a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caesar</ENAMEX> can survive the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ides</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>. Especially because in saying that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'the State of the Union</ENAMEX> is in excellent health' he certainly wasn't committing
perjury."

            But the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX> paper
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Repubblica</ENAMEX> focused, in an editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, on the power
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Reserve Board</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Greenspan</ENAMEX>, whom it depicted as being,
like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX>, a second "surrogate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>." Under the headline "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Duel</ENAMEX>
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>," the editorial said that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX>, by publicly ridiculing the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s plan for investing <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$700 billion</NUMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> system, had
effectively rejected the key point of his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State of the Union</ENAMEX> address.
"The affair demonstrates that the much admired 'Clinton <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX>' has up to now
had a secret <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX>, who is to all intents and purposes the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">principal architect</ENAMEX> of that inflation-free economic boom which the president
has used as a shield against the criticisms linked to 'Sexgate,' " the paper
said.

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Le Monde</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> "staked his all" in his address,
challenging the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> to work with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> they want to topple, or
else enter the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 2000</TIMEX> elections under the banner of an "impeachment
party" that abandoned a popular program to satisfy its rancor.

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Izvestia</ENAMEX> commented <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> on a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> territorial dispute in the
Bering <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Strait</ENAMEX>, the subject of negotiations that ended inconclusively in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last weekend</TIMEX>. The border, barely <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">49 kilometers</NUMEX> long, was so short that it was
difficult to find on maps, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said, but it has created considerable
problems in bilateral relations and looks set to generate drawn-out political
battles. The chief <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">delegate</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX> talks said their only
achievement had been a phrase in the final communiqué mentioning "the need to
search for a compromise solution to this problem." On the other hand, the paper
said that recognition of the importance of compromise was better than open
confrontation, especially in a region regarded by both sides as vital to their
interests and where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> were kept in a state of high combat readiness.

            
In the matter of corruption and the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Olympic</ENAMEX>
Games, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sydney Morning</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herald</ENAMEX> claimed an exclusive <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> with a front-page lead story claiming that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sydney</ENAMEX> only won the right to host the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Olympics</ENAMEX> by offering <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50,000</NUMEX> inducements to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Olympic Committee</ENAMEX> just <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> before the vote. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herald</ENAMEX>
saying he had offered the money at a dinner in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monte Carlo</ENAMEX> to the National
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Olympic Committees</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kenya</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Uganda</ENAMEX>, through their respective <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IOC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Mukora</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Maj. Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis Nyangweso</ENAMEX>. "My view was it might encourage
them to consider their votes for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sydney</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coates</ENAMEX> said. He reportedly denied
that the money was a bribe and said it went toward helping sport in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kenya</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Uganda</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said that the revelation is certain to draw <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sydney</ENAMEX> into the
bribes furor, which has already caused <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IOC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">delegates</ENAMEX> to resign over the
scandal surrounding <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Salt Lake City</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX>'s successful bid for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Winter</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Olympics</ENAMEX>.

             

         
      
   
