
   
   
      
         
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>

            The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">holiday season</TIMEX> is upon
us. Not the "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas season</TIMEX>" but the "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">holiday season</TIMEX>"--a euphemism for
"<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hanukkah</ENAMEX> (and, perhaps, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kwanzaa</ENAMEX>) thrown in." If you place a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX> in the town <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">square</ENAMEX>, you need a menorah as well. We festoon <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">blue</ENAMEX> and silver <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hanukkah decorations alongside Christmas trimmings</ENAMEX>, and on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sesame Street Christmas special, Big Bird wishes Mr. Hooper a Happy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hanukkah</ENAMEX>. The only meaning of the phrase "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Judeo-Christian</ENAMEX>," it seems, is the
fusion of these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> otherwise unrelated holidays into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> big seasonal
spree.

            The
problem, as any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rabbi</ENAMEX> will tell you, is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hanukkah</ENAMEX> has traditionally been a
minor <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> festival. It commemorates the successful <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Israelite</ENAMEX> revolt in the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">B.C.</ENAMEX> against their <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Syrian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">oppressors</ENAMEX>, and their refusal to
assimilate into the prevailing <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hellenistic</ENAMEX> culture. Specifically, it celebrates
the miracle in which, according to lore, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a day</TIMEX>'s worth of oil fueled the
candelabra of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>' rededicated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight days</TIMEX>. Until recently, this
observance paled next to the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">High Holy Days</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Passover</TIMEX>, even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Purim</ENAMEX>. So how did
it become "the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jewish Christmas</TIMEX>"? And is this good for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>?

            First, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> had to become <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX>, which originally
wasn't a big deal in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Puritans</ENAMEX> who settled <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX> made it a
crime to celebrate <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the holiday</TIMEX> (punishment: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> shillings). Only with the
arrival of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">the Civil War</ENAMEX> did it emerge as the major
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> feast. With the revolution in retailing--marked by the rise of
department <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> and advertising--celebrations focused on throwing parties,
buying and giving gifts, and sending greeting cards (<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> sold in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1874</TIMEX>, they
became <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a million dollar</NUMEX> business within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years</TIMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coca-Cola Co.</ENAMEX> adopted
as its logo a jolly bearded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> in a red and white suit, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa</ENAMEX> bypassed
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX>' main icon.

            Enter the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>. Around <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1900</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of eastern <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> came to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">congregating</ENAMEX> in urban enclaves such as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower East Side</ENAMEX>. Most adopted
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> traditions, including the newly secularized <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santa Claus</ENAMEX>
visited the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Side</ENAMEX> last night," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Tribune</ENAMEX> noted on
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas Day, 1904</TIMEX>, "and hardly missed a tenement <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> installed
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> in their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> and thought nothing of the carols their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sang</ENAMEX> in the public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>.

            
The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> generation of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American Jews</ENAMEX>
challenged this embrace of a festival that, despite its secular trappings, was
fundamentally <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> couldn't very well deprive their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> of
gifts or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seasonal</TIMEX> merriment, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hanukkah</ENAMEX> benefited from convenient timing.
Instead of giving the traditional "gelt," or money, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> celebrated with
presents, so as not to fall short of their <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX>. Prominent
religious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>, more secure with maintaining a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> identity in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>,
now urged <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> to let <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> abstain from yuletide celebrations or to provide
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">all-purpose</ENAMEX> holiday <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> instead. Lighting the menorah proved a satisfying
alternative to adorning a <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX> with colorful lights.

            Zionism,
which gathered converts in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> before <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX>, also boosted
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hanukkah</ENAMEX>'s stock. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">holiday</TIMEX>'s emphasis on self-reliance and military strength
in the face of persecution dovetailed with the themes of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nationalists</ENAMEX> seeking
to establish a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">warrior-hero</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judah Maccabee</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> of an
ancient revolt, morphed into a proto-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Zionist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pioneer</ENAMEX>. At first, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zionist</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organizations</ENAMEX> used <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the holiday</TIMEX> as an excuse to prod <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> to donate coins
to the cause. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later years</TIMEX> they packed <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Madison Square Garden</ENAMEX> for Hanukkah
fund-raising galas, featuring such keynoters as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albert Einstein</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herbert Lehman</ENAMEX>.

            After <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX>, as <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> moved with other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">suburbia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hanukkah</ENAMEX> shored up its place as their No. 1 holiday. In the early
'50s, in a famous <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Middletown</ENAMEX> -style study of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> suburb referred to
as "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lakeville</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sociologist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marshall Sklare</ENAMEX> found that lighting the Hanukkah
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">candles</ENAMEX> ranked as the most popular "mitzvah," above hosting a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Passover</TIMEX> Seder
and observing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sabbath</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sklare</ENAMEX> attributed the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">holiday</TIMEX>'s popularity to its
easy accommodation to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas rituals</TIMEX> as well as to its ability to be
redefined for modern times. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hanukkah</ENAMEX> lesson being taught, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sklare</ENAMEX> noted, was
no longer reverence to God for performing a miracle but rather the triumph over
religious intolerance--a perfect message for liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> in the age of the
civil rights movement.

            These
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ozzie and Harriet Jews</ENAMEX> also modified their observances for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">1950s</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>. As
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> has written, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guidebook</ENAMEX> from the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">era</TIMEX> included recipes for
" 'Maccabean <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sandwiches</ENAMEX>' composed of either tuna <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">egg salad</ENAMEX> and shaped
to resemble a bite-sized <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maccabee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">warrior</ENAMEX>, or the 'Menorah <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fruit salad</ENAMEX>,' a
composition of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cream cheese</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fruit</ENAMEX> that, when molded, resembled a menorah."
By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late '50s</TIMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chanukah</ENAMEX>'s accoutrements had grown to include paper
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">decorations</ENAMEX>, greeting cards, napkins, wrapping paper, ribbons, chocolates,
games and phonograph records." Like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gentiles</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> extended gift-giving to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX>; the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hadassah Newsletter</ENAMEX> pointed out that "Mah-jong sets make
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">appreciated Chanukah</ENAMEX> gifts." <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Parents</ENAMEX> could now assure <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> that Hanukkah
wasn't a poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> but was, in fact, a "better" <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">holiday</TIMEX> because it
meant presents for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight days</TIMEX> straight.

            
Since then, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> have become more integrated
into <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> life, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hanukkah</ENAMEX> has embedded itself in television, office
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hallmark</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barnes & Nobles</ENAMEX>, and other leading <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX>
cultural <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX>. Except among the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Orthodox</ENAMEX>, it has been thoroughly
transformed into a major festival. Accordingly, religious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> lament this
development as another instance of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>' perilous assimilation--if not into
a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> society then into a secular, commercial one.

            Yet the recent evolution of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hanukkah</ENAMEX> represents not a capitulation to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> but an
assertion of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Jewishness</ENAMEX> amid a multicultural society. Just as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kwanzaa</ENAMEX>, created
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1966</TIMEX>, has returned many black <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> to their <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> heritage, so
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hanukkah</ENAMEX> has helped tether <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> to their heritage and in some cases has brought
them back to the fold. In a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985</TIMEX> study, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Silberman</ENAMEX> recounted
how the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anne Roiphe</ENAMEX>, besieged with angry letters after she wrote an
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> about celebrating <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jew</ENAMEX>, switched to observing Hanukkah
and found it far more meaningful. Likewise, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Silberman</ENAMEX> noted, more <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American Jews</ENAMEX>
than ever preferred <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Hanukkah</ENAMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> out of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> lighted the
menorah, an increase even over the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">68 percent</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sklare</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">1950s</NUMEX> study. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>,
the adherence to a modest <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> ritual such as celebrating <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hanukkah</ENAMEX> follows in
the tradition of the ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Israelites</ENAMEX>, who spurned the pressures to adopt
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hellenism</ENAMEX>. Indeed, in acculturating to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> while maintaining a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX>
identity, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">observers</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hanukkah</ENAMEX> may well be doing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judah Maccabee</ENAMEX> proud.

            ( Copy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>'s
note: 
               
                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">defers</ENAMEX> to The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Associated Press Stylebook</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Libel Manual</ENAMEX> on all matters secular and spiritual. Hence our use of
"Hanukkah" rather than "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chanukah</ENAMEX>.")

         
      
   
