
   
   
      
         
            A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Question of Character</ENAMEX>

            If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> didn't exist, would it be possible to invent him? Of all
modern political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>, he seems the least likely as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Henry</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James</ENAMEX> or a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Conrad</ENAMEX> might do justice to the tensions in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
political career--the tug of war between idealism and cynicism, the empathy for
others, and the calculating self-interest. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sinclair Lewis</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Theodore Dreiser</ENAMEX>
might depict his climb from provincial obscurity. But who could concoct the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">juxtapositions of the president</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personality</ENAMEX>? It is hard to think of a figure
from <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> literature who combines, for instance,
self-destructive sexual interests with an insatiable appetite for domestic
policy, or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s mix of high intelligence and low taste. Has anyone
scripted him? Let us consider the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> whose inventions capture aspects of
the presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personality</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX>: When you think of political tragedy, you think
immediately of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Nixon</ENAMEX>, the last <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> to face
impeachment, was clearly a Shakespearean character. To be precise, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Watergate</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard III</ENAMEX>, the self-pitying monster. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX> is
not <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">half so dark</TIMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figure</ENAMEX>--underhanded, perhaps, but not purely malevolent. If
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> exists in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX>, it might be as an amalgamation of the bad
qualities of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Falstaff</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry V. He has Falstaff</ENAMEX>'s appetites for food and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fornication</ENAMEX> (without his humor or ironic wisdom). He has <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prince</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hal</ENAMEX>'s political
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ambition</ENAMEX> and disloyalty to his old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> (without his heroism or rhetorical
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">eloquence</ENAMEX>). But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX> isn't right for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>, who even in collapse
lacks the grandeur of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bard</ENAMEX>'s tragic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroes</ENAMEX> and the absurdity of his comic
ones. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX> may provide more models for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">first lady</ENAMEX>. She thinks of
herself as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Portia</ENAMEX>, the clever <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Merchant</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Venice</ENAMEX> .
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> think of her as a scheming <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lady Macbeth</ENAMEX>. Lately, the public sees
her as that unfortunate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Othello 's Desdemona</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">W</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">illiam</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Faulkner</ENAMEX>: Our general image of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s past--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern</ENAMEX> poverty with overtones of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">alcoholism</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">inbreeding</ENAMEX>--comes mostly from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Faulkner</ENAMEX>. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Snopes</ENAMEX> trilogy ( The
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hamlet , The Town</ENAMEX> , and The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Mansion</ENAMEX> ), we find the models for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Will Blythe</ENAMEX> (in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ramblin</ENAMEX>' bigamist <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">I.O. Snopes</ENAMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kelley</ENAMEX> (the chunky <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child bride</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eula Varner</ENAMEX>); and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Clinton</ENAMEX> (the no-goodnik
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Byron Snopes</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> is apparently based on the main protagonist of the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> books, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flem Snopes</ENAMEX>. Flem rises from rural squalor, getting a job as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clerk</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Varner</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Frenchman</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bend</ENAMEX>, then taking over the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX>, then
moving to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jefferson</ENAMEX>. He aspires to become <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> (of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jefferson Bank</ENAMEX>) and succeeds. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Faulkner</ENAMEX> captures the milieu of Gothic
dysfunction from which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> emerged but describes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flem</ENAMEX>'s rise only in terms
of venality, missing the all-important element of idealism.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Philip</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roth</ENAMEX>: A closer match is found, surprisingly enough, in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Philip</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roth</ENAMEX>'s
portrait of a middle-aged <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectual</ENAMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Portnoy</ENAMEX>'s complaint" is defined
on the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">page</ENAMEX> of the novel of that name as "A disorder in which
strongly-felt ethical and altruistic impulses are perpetually warring with
extreme sexual longings, often of a perverse nature." Sound familiar? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander</ENAMEX>
Portnoy, after he outgrows his autoerotic obsession, works for the liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lindsay</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> and does his best to demonstrate his
concern for the poor and the oppressed. Meanwhile, however, he is shacked up
with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX> he calls the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Monkey</ENAMEX>, who fulfills his sexual fantasies but
leaves him living in fear of tabloid scandal. Like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Portnoy</ENAMEX> is highly
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">intelligent</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>-obsessed, and pretty much out of control. Another
similarity: Portnoy flees to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> when faced with crisis. Drawbacks: Portnoy
is more of a neurotic and less of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liar</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">M ark Twain</ENAMEX>: My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleague</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter</ENAMEX> Shapiro
("<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>") suggests that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Sawyer</ENAMEX> figure. He's thinking of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">famous fence-</ENAMEX>painting scene, in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom</ENAMEX> tricks his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> into paying
him for the right to do his chore. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Sawyer</ENAMEX> does capture rather nicely, I
think, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s gift for talking his way out of trouble that better sense
might have kept him out of in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom</ENAMEX> is, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Kerrey</ENAMEX> once said
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, "an unusually good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liar</ENAMEX>." There's also the great scene where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huck Finn</ENAMEX>, who are thought to have drowned, watch their own funerals as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spectators</ENAMEX>. That's a bit like what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> seems to be doing now. We know that
he'll pop up at the end, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sawyer</ENAMEX>-like, to announce that, contrary to popular
belief, he is not, in fact, finished. Bonus: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Aunt Polly</ENAMEX>, who is
driven to distraction by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom</ENAMEX>'s deceptions but always forgives him in the
end.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Charles</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dickens</ENAMEX>: The great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character types</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dickens</ENAMEX>, but he seems
never to have drawn anyone much like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> might propose
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Uriah Heep in David Copperfield</ENAMEX> . Heep, synonymous with unctuousness, is
a fawning <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fellow</ENAMEX> who worms his way up through oozing manipulation. He does have
some <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>-like traits, such as his obsession with his mother, his
smarminess, and his flattering blather. There's a scene in the novel where
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Copperfield</ENAMEX> sees Heep asleep, with his "mouth open like a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">post office</ENAMEX>." The
phrase fits <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> beautifully. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heep</ENAMEX> is repellant. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, though hated
by many, is seductively charming. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX>, as he was getting clobbered in
budget negotiations in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995-96</TIMEX>, said he "had to go through detox" to prevent
himself from being overcome by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s winning ways. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heep</ENAMEX> is, however, a fine
stand-in for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Majority Whip</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom DeLay</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">H</ENAMEX> erman <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Melville</ENAMEX>: At an anti-impeachment
rally <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novelist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Gordon</ENAMEX> suggested that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> was in fact
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Billy Budd</ENAMEX>. "There is something about a kind of accusation that takes on a life
of its own in which a punishment is completely incommensurate with the nature
of the crime that comes from a sort of sexual madness that I believe is at the
root of a lot of the otherwise incomprehensible opposition to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gordon</ENAMEX>
noted. This is a clever nomination, but it doesn't transcend the immediate
circumstances of the scandal. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Melville</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Budd</ENAMEX> is a naive, good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who is
punished unfairly for an accidental murder he is provoked into committing by
someone who tried to frame him for a crime. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s impending punishment may
be unjust, but as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> he lacks <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Billy</ENAMEX>'s innocence and forthrightness.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Billy</ENAMEX> steps up to take his undeserved punishment, declining to let others risk
their necks by trying to help him. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has consistently done pretty much
the opposite. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gordon</ENAMEX> may be on to something with the issue of sexual jealousy,
but neglects the key difference: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Budd</ENAMEX> is lusted after; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> lusts. However,
there's a silver lining in this one, too. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Claggart</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> who tries to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">frame Billy</ENAMEX> for the crime of mutiny, we find a nautical version of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kenneth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">F. Scott</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fitzgerald</ENAMEX>: While we're considering unlikely comparisons from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
literature, we have a proposal from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Klein</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> of a fine fictional
portrait of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Stanton in Primary Colors</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Klein</ENAMEX> once wrote of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>: "They are the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daisy Buchanan</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baby Boom</ENAMEX>
Political <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Elite</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buchanans</ENAMEX>, you may recall, were <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">F. Scott Fitzgerald</ENAMEX>'s
brilliant crystallization of flapper fecklessness in The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Great Gatsby</ENAMEX> .
They were 'careless' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. They smashed up lives and didn't notice." There
are some surprisingly good parallels here. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Buchanan</ENAMEX> avoided service in
<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War I</ENAMEX> and is a reckless adulterer. But as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personality</ENAMEX>, he's all
wrong--he's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bully</ENAMEX> and a racist who doesn't care what anyone else thinks about
him. And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daisy</ENAMEX> are aristocrats; their miserable behavior is the
outgrowth of his having too much money, the one thing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has never had and
has never seemed to care much about.

            
L <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ewis</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carroll</ENAMEX>: The
indispensable guides to contemporary politics are <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alice</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wonderland</ENAMEX>
and Through the Looking <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glass</ENAMEX> , which happens to be where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s most
direct literary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">antecedent</ENAMEX> appears. Coming upon an egg-shaped <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alice</ENAMEX>
wonders why someone so fragile would sit on such a high and narrow <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wall</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Humpty</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dumpty</ENAMEX> explains that he can always be put back together again in the event of
an accident. Further discussion ensues, reminiscent of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paula Jones</ENAMEX>
deposition and his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">grand jury</ENAMEX> testimony:

            "When I use a
word," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Humpty Dumpty</ENAMEX> said in rather a scornful tone, "it means just what I
choose it to mean--neither more nor less."

            "The question is," said
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alice</ENAMEX>, "whether you CAN make words mean so many different things."

            "The
question is," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Humpty Dumpty</ENAMEX>, "which is to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX>--that's all."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alice</ENAMEX> has a predictable
reaction to this sophistry:

            "Of all the unsatisfactory
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> I EVER met--"

            She never finished the
sentence, for at this moment a heavy crash shook the forest from end to
end.

         
      
   
