
   
   
      
         
             The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First Bimbo</ENAMEX>

            She is the most famous
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helen Keller</ENAMEX> to achieve her notoriety without uttering a single
public word. Not long ago, she toured an art exhibition at a private <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">gallery</ENAMEX> on
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Upper East Side</ENAMEX>. "She was sweet and charming," recalls the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>,
who is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of mine. "It was a complete surprise."

            We call her <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>
because, as with all incredibly famous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, we feel we know her. But we
actually know very little. All that may change <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX> when she gives her
deposition in the impeachment trial, even though her testimony will be behind
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">irksomely</ENAMEX> closed doors. Afterward, perhaps she'll grant us a public word or two
on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol</ENAMEX> steps. It would be the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time we will have heard her
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">voice</ENAMEX>--except on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Tripp</ENAMEX>'s tapes.

            There are hints on those tapes that we are doing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX> an
injustice in regarding her as a vacuous vixen. "I could not live with myself if
I caused trouble," she told <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX> that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fateful day a year ago</TIMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX>
City <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ritz-Carlton</ENAMEX>, shortly before <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> showed up to make her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">immortal</ENAMEX>. "That is just not my nature. I am a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>."

            Is it possible she's right? That--despite having
caused trouble big-time--she is a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>? And maybe not so dumb, either.
In one of her marathon phone confessions with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX>, she even makes a shrewd
case that in seducing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, she was serving the public interest.

            "Every ... <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> we
have ever had has always had <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lovers</ENAMEX> because the pressure of the job is too
much," she lectured her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda</ENAMEX>. "[It's] too much to always rely on your
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, with whom you have too much baggage. ... I think it's bad for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>." Others besides <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> have called on young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to perform a
period of national service, in or out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marine</ENAMEX> ain't
gonna happen. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>, a star-spangled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patriot</ENAMEX>, was eager to take on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">selfless</ENAMEX> role of <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> bimbo.

            Even genocidal monsters like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pol Pot</ENAMEX>'s bathing-suit-clad
henchmen get more respectful treatment from the press than <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX>. Let me quote
from the opening lines of a hoked-up exposé in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Post</ENAMEX> two
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks ago</TIMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sexgate</ENAMEX> siren <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> tried to cheer up with a chocoholic
chow-down. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> indulged her notorious sweet tooth at a low-cal Madison
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Avenue</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bakery</ENAMEX>. But fat chance she's on a diet." <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">A few nights</TIMEX> later, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jay Leno</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cracked</ENAMEX>, "I have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> words for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who think that sex burns calories--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>."

            By my reckoning,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> to public ridicule was paved by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> mistakes--and on each
fateful occasion she was encouraged by a much older co-conspirator. These are
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>'s maladroit miscues:

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. She was the sexual aggressor using the snap of her thong
as a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">modern-day</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">replacement</ENAMEX> for a come-hither look. That gesture forever
branded her as wanton, but it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> who wanted. Succumbing to a glimpse
of thong is not sexual harassment, but of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of them, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX> is not the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> who most clearly should have known better.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. She pressured the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> to find her a job in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>. True, but it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tripp</ENAMEX>, in the role of
Iago, who originally suggested that she enlist <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vernon Jordan</ENAMEX> and his vast
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rolodex</ENAMEX> in her quest to sample the bounty of the private sector. Anyway, she
was right to perceive that this is how you get fancy jobs in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, with or
without the sex angle.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>.  She signed a false affidavit in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> case.
Whatever your beliefs about the formal obstruction of justice case against
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> clearly intuited that her mendacity would please the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. If anyone deserves to take refuge in the everybody-lies-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about</NUMEX>-sex
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">defense</ENAMEX>, it is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>, not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. She displayed
execrable judgment in posing on a beach with an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> flag for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fair</ENAMEX> . Her vanity duly engaged--as whose would not be?--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX> lacked the
maturity to balk at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>'s tasteless choice of props. And maybe, after
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> of house arrest, she wanted to make an up-yours gesture toward <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>. In
this case, her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elderly betrayer</ENAMEX> was her then<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">-lawyer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Ginsburg</ENAMEX>. Remember
him? During his <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">15 minutes</TIMEX>, now thankfully past, he was not in a position to
advise anyone to avoid the cameras.

            Like many impressionable young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the ages</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX> fell under the sway of bad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">companions</ENAMEX>. But are these crimes worthy of a
lifetime in media purgatory? Not only is she forced to dance whenever <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>
pulls the strings on her immunity agreement, but it is difficult to see how and
when she can resume a normal life. I have it on good authority that the main
reason that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX> hasn't taken a job or even done volunteer work during her
ordeal is that she is rightfully fearful that her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-workers</ENAMEX> would immediately
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sell</ENAMEX> her out to the tabloids.

            As an intellectual,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX> may be a few <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boutiques</ENAMEX> short of a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mall</ENAMEX>. But her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Valley</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Girl</ENAMEX> airhead
image is a cruel caricature. She was smart enough to object initially to the
choice of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ginsburg</ENAMEX> as her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX>. And it is evident from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>
transcripts that she captivated many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">grand jury</ENAMEX>. She also
retains a sense of humor about her plight--<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX>, she jokes, she can make
any small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> famous by wearing its logo on a baseball cap.

            Sure, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Tripp</ENAMEX> conversations do not make her sound
like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simone de Beauvoir</ENAMEX> discussing her relationship with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jean-Paul Sartre</ENAMEX>. Even
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>, I'm told, was appalled by her incessant use of the word "like" on the
tapes. But give the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> a break. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX> is not the only twentysomething
obsessed with sex and shopping. What would you talk about with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX>--military readiness? (And keep in mind that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tripp</ENAMEX> was covertly trying to
keep the conversation going and to steer it in a certain direction.)

            A high-ranking middle-aged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
administration said to me recently, "If the world knew about my messy love life
in my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">20s</ENAMEX>, I wouldn't be in this job." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX> is an ordinary young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>, who
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">blundered</ENAMEX> badly when she was exposed to extraordinary temptation. Like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helen</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Troy</ENAMEX>, she's caused a helluva mess--but that doesn't mean she's responsible for
it.

         
      
   
