
   
   
      
         
             If the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Genes Fit</ENAMEX>

            If you have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> with a
devilishly pouty lower lip, soulful hooded eyes, and a genetic fingerprint that
matches that of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI Lab Specimen</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">K39</ENAMEX>--a blood sample drawn from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>
and supplied to the independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>--then the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tabloids</ENAMEX> might have
an offer for you.

            According to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drudge Report</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Post</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> has paid a
former <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prostitute</ENAMEX> and her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> to take <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> tests to
determine whether or not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bobbie Ann Williams</ENAMEX>
alleged <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several years ago</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> that while state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">general</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> paid her for sexual encounters and that one of those
encounters resulted in the conception of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>. With <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s genetic
fingerprint available on Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,454</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> report's supplement, the
Star is supposedly examining the validity of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Williams</ENAMEX>' claim. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
has denied ever having met the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>, but perhaps the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> can get Miss
Manners to rule on whether purchasing sex from someone qualifies as a formal
introduction.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintons</ENAMEX> dominate the tabs <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this month</TIMEX>, and the only
good news about them is found in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> . According to the
publication, a "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>" of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>'s says that on impeachment <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> "wrote a whole chapter in one of the most remarkable love stories of
all time." (As remarkable as the love story of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> and Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Livingston</ENAMEX>?)
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> pledged to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> a "vow of love"
that "moved Bill to tears." No, she didn't vow to stand by him even if the DNA
of a statistically significant portion of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arkansans</ENAMEX> younger than 25 match that
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI Lab Specimen</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">K39</ENAMEX>. What she said, according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> , was
this: "I know you're going through hell right now. But I want you to know one
thing: I'll always be here for you. ...We told each other <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23 years ago</TIMEX>: 'Til
death do us part.' I meant every word of it."

            According to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Enquirer</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> fears that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> may bring about
that final day. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Beats up Bill</ENAMEX>," screams one headline. Says the story:
"The furious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First Lady</ENAMEX> attacked the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>, hitting him so hard she left a
visible mark on his face--and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> had to separate them. 'Keep
that bitch away from me!' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> told <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX>." She apparently has
excellent aim, having also winged him with books and an ashtray. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> also cited the much-publicized scene of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> pulling her arm
away from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX> during a recent memorial service in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yitzhak Rabin</ENAMEX>.
"It was like his touch was revolting to her!" an "insider" reports. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> acknowledges this incident but attributes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>'s behavior to
the heretofore unknown <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">baba ghanouj syndrome</ENAMEX>. Jet lag, a busy schedule, and
"the change in her diet to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Middle Eastern</ENAMEX> food had caused the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">first lady</ENAMEX> to
feel queasy and out of sorts," it explains.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> isn't the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipient</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">first lady</ENAMEX>'s
right hook. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> reports that "on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly a dozen</NUMEX> occasions in the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last three months</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> has viciously lashed out at numerous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> for getting in her way." It reports that as she was leaving the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one morning</TIMEX> she passed an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> who said, "Good <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>, Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>."
"Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> brushed by him, actually shoving him out of her way. ... As she
did, she snapped at him and cursed: 'Get f--!' " According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> ,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 10</NUMEX> such incidents have been reported to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">superiors</ENAMEX>. The publication
explains that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> is lashing out from tension but is also bitter that
during grand jury testimony <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> conveyed rumors of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">philandering</ENAMEX>--even though the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> she has attacked did not testify.

            There's no escape for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>. At the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> premiere of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Love</ENAMEX> , she was feted
and photographed standing next to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gwyneth Paltrow</ENAMEX>. This proved that no
middle-aged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> should stand next to a tall, lithe, blond, virtually naked
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX>. Paltrow, as displayed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> , solved the age-old
dilemma of having nothing to wear for that special occasion by deciding to wear
nothing at all. Or to wear a dress that appears to be sequin-decorated Saran
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wrap</ENAMEX>. At least <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> could take comfort in the fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paltrow</ENAMEX> has let the
world know she is not a natural blonde.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> also rehashes old sexual allegations
against the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, accusations that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> investigated but did not
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">publicize</ENAMEX>. These include the claim that while <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney general</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX> he
raped <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Juanita Broaddrick</ENAMEX> by biting her "on the lip until she gave in to his
sexual advances." More stories like this and someone at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> is
likely to get an ear bitten off.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> bit the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> 's ear <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> in court, seeking to block its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitor</ENAMEX> from
publishing an interview with former flight attendant <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Suzen Johnson</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson</ENAMEX>'s
story of how she bedded <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Gifford</ENAMEX> ran in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years ago</TIMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> "scoop" that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> wanted spiked reveals the
somewhat obvious fact that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> paid <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> for her seduction. At
issue in this epic struggle were questions of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">First Amendment</ENAMEX> rights and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">specter</ENAMEX> of prior restraint, making this battle call to mind nothing so much as
the confrontation between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tweedledee</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tweedledum</ENAMEX> over ownership of a
rattle.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> won the legal contest, and its cover
features the boa-clad <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX>, who could use <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> wheelbarrows as a brassiere
and whose nose is considerably smaller and lips substantially larger than the
last time she appeared in the tabs. She apologizes for a flirtation--initiated
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gifford</ENAMEX> after he met her on an airplane--that resulted in the kind of
genital to genital contact that our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> has grown unfamiliar with in
recent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson</ENAMEX>'s naiveté is as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">convincingly</ENAMEX> natural as her nose, her lips, and her breasts. After she and a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> checked into a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$400</NUMEX> a night <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">suite</ENAMEX> at a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX> near <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Suzen</ENAMEX> went out for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the evening</TIMEX>. "I realize now that the cameras and
microphones were probably installed by [the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> ] while I was out," she
reports. After transcripts and video stills of her encounter were made public,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson</ENAMEX> says she "hit the roof. I suddenly realized what I'd actually done--I'd
been set up and paid to have sex with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank</ENAMEX>." If she had any doubts,
clarification came in the form of a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$250,000</NUMEX> deposit to her bank account.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson</ENAMEX>'s sense of rectitude is matched only by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathie Lee</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gifford</ENAMEX>'s. The healing of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gifford</ENAMEX> marriage is now complete, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank</ENAMEX> will
never cheat again. How do we know this? Because she said so. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX>
quotes a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathie Lee</ENAMEX> interview in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> in which she explains that:
"We stayed home. We stayed in the word of God. And we stayed in bed. You want a
recipe for healing? That's what you do." It also helps if you can send your
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Larry King Live</ENAMEX> to grovel before the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank</ENAMEX> did.
Unfortunately, groveling before the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> does not work to strengthen the
marriage of every cheating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>.

            Finally, there is an update of the doings of the
tabs' favorite "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">merry widow</ENAMEX>" (in the words of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> ), <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX>
Bono. According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">just months</TIMEX> after the skiing accident death
of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sonny</ENAMEX>, she tossed "piles of irreplaceable mementos" of the late
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singer-congressman</ENAMEX> into the dumpster, where they were retrieved by one of his
former restaurant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> reports that war has broken
out among <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sonny</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">survivors</ENAMEX> because he died without signing the will that would
have left his estate to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX>. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> reports that rumors are
sweeping <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, as well as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX>'s home <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">district</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Palm Springs</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX>,
of her special friendship with--take a dramamine before reading on--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX>. Well, she is an ambitious, alluring young thing with an ability to
attract powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>. Watch out, Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dennis Hastert</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
