
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Horses</ENAMEX>

            To hear <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Pinsky</ENAMEX>
read "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Horses</ENAMEX>," click .

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edwin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Muir</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1887-1959</TIMEX>) is a mysteriously neglected, gorgeous, and emotionally
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">penetrating poet</ENAMEX>. Of all the many pieces of writing spurred by the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX> and
the threat of nuclear apocalypse, and of the other kinds of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">century</ENAMEX> apocalyptic writing, his poem "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Horses</ENAMEX>" may be the most effective,
perhaps because it is the most calm and gentle. The plainness of the writing,
the persuasive speech rhythms under the almost hidden iambic pulse, manifest
immense art, culminating in a last line that could be incised in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">stone</ENAMEX>.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert</ENAMEX>
Pinsky
            

            Barely a twelvemonth
after
The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven days</TIMEX> war that put the world to sleep,
Late in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the evening</TIMEX> the strange <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horses</ENAMEX> came.
By then we had made our covenant with silence,
But in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first few days</TIMEX> it was so still
We listened to our breathing and were afraid.
On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the second day</TIMEX>
The radios failed; we turned the knobs, no answer.
On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the third day</TIMEX> a warship passed us, headed north,
Dead bodies piled on the deck. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the sixth day</TIMEX>
A <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> plunged over us into the sea. Thereafter
Nothing. The radios dumb;
And still they stand in corners of our kitchens,
And stand, perhaps, turned on, in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX>
All over the world. But now if they should speak,
If on a sudden they should speak again,
If on the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stroke</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX> a voice should speak,
We would not listen, we would not let it bring
That old bad world that swallowed its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> quick
At <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> great gulp. We would not have it again.
Sometimes we think of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> lying asleep,
Curled blindly in impenetrable sorrow,
And then the thought confounds us with its strangeness.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">tractors</ENAMEX> lie about our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">fields</ENAMEX>; at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX>
They look like dank sea-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monsters</ENAMEX> crouched and waiting.
We leave them where they are and let them rust:
"They'll molder away and be like other loam."
We make our oxen drag our rusty plows,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Long</ENAMEX> laid aside. We have gone back
Far past our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fathers</ENAMEX>' land.
                                        And then, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">that evening</TIMEX>
Late in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> the strange <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horses</ENAMEX> came.
We heard a distant tapping on the road,
A deepening drumming; it stopped, went on again
And at the corner changed to hollow thunder.
We saw the heads
Like a wild wave charging and were afraid.
We had sold our <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horses</ENAMEX> in our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fathers</ENAMEX>' time
To buy new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">tractors</ENAMEX>. Now they were strange to us
As fabulous steeds set on an ancient shield
Or illustrations in a book of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">knights</ENAMEX>.
We did not dare go near them. Yet they waited,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stubborn</ENAMEX> and shy, as if they had been sent
By an old command to find our whereabouts
And that long-lost archaic companionship.
In the first moment we had never a thought
That they were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">creatures</ENAMEX> to be owned and used.
Among them were some <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half a dozen</NUMEX> colts
Dropped in some wilderness of the broken world,
Yet new as if they had come from their own <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Eden</ENAMEX>.
Since then they have pulled our plows and borne our loads,
But that free servitude still can pierce our hearts.
Our life is changed; their coming our beginning.

         
      
   
