
   
   
      
         
            

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 4 and 11</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            The triumphal cover
story marshals an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> of statistics to prove that "life in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> has never
been better." Crime, accidents, fires, drinking, smoking, drugging, air
pollution, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water pollution</ENAMEX>, racism, and divorce are declining. We live longer,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">happier</ENAMEX>, wealthier lives than ever before. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Credit American</ENAMEX> pragmatism: We
really can fix our problems if we try. ... An article says
impeachment-crazed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Barr</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">R-Ga.</ENAMEX>, lied about his association with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">racist Council of Concerned Citizens</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barr</ENAMEX>, despite his claims to the contrary,
spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time</TIMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>'s conference, never denounced its views, and
knew about its loathsome ideology when he spoke to it. ... The editorial
says the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> bombing proves <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s strength, not its weakness: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">In the</ENAMEX>
middle of the greatest political excruciation in its modern history, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> is doing the noble and necessary thing."

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Magazine</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 20</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            An ambivalent cover
story describes <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>'s massive welfare-to-work program. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudolph</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX>'s reforms have taken <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">400,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> off the rolls, prevented <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX>
more from getting on, and placed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30,000</NUMEX> in workfare jobs, but no one knows if
those who've left welfare are in better shape than they were when they received
public assistance. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX>'s new ambition--to make all welfare
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> work--seems fraught: There are too many sick and otherwise disabled
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> who will resist. ... The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> profiles <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Craig</ENAMEX>
Rosebraugh, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Earth Liberation Front</ENAMEX>, the radical animal rights
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX> that burned down a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vail</ENAMEX> ski <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resort</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rosebraugh</ENAMEX> doesn't even
belong to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> or know who its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> are, but he preaches their
eco-sabotage gospel. Much excellent detail about the lives of serious animal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX>: They use the word "species-ist" in earnest. ... A piece
gushes over "the anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trump</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> real estate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">developer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Speyer</ENAMEX>, who
owns the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler Building</ENAMEX>. His low-key, civic-minded style has made him
perhaps the most powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">developer</ENAMEX> in the world.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 21</TIMEX> 
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 15</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>)
            

            Impeachment covers for both. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> rehashes
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s hearings, votes, and speeches. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's "The
Fight of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Their Lives</ENAMEX>" focuses on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> marriage, which is even
rockier than usual: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> is pursuing her own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activist</ENAMEX> agenda rather than
helping Bill fight scandal. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> claims that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Howard</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Baker</ENAMEX> have been asked to mediate between the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> and congressional
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> but have not accepted. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> is also hoping for a last
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minute</TIMEX> intervention by former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX>. Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> list <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> who are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fence-</ENAMEX>sitting the impeachment vote.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> interviews <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan Milosevic</ENAMEX>, who's as repellent
as you'd expect. He says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Serbians</ENAMEX> were "doing our best to stop [the Bosnian
war]," that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Serbians</ENAMEX> never massacred <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bosnians</ENAMEX>, and that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Serbia</ENAMEX>'s main problem
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> is "bad P.R." ... A photo essay depicts disabled <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in gruesome
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">asylums</ENAMEX>. ... An article claims that racial animus is contributing to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBA</ENAMEX>
strike. Black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> feel that white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> don't respect them and are
treating them as ghetto <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thugs</ENAMEX> who don't deserve their high salaries.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>
investigative piece suggests that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Osama Bin Laden</ENAMEX> may seek revenge on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> by attacking <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> with bombs or chemical
weapons. ... 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> picks the best entertainment of the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Saving Private Ryan , A Man in Full</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark McGwire</ENAMEX>, the
final episode of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Larry Sanders Show</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Miseducation of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Lauryn Hill</ENAMEX> .

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">& World Report</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 21</TIMEX> 
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 15</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>)
            

            Its impeachment cover
package also chronicles <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s furor and lists the undecideds. Two
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Watergate</ENAMEX> vets opine: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles W. Colson</ENAMEX> says impeach him; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Dean</ENAMEX> says
don't, because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> has been too partisan and unfair. ...
A story says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> has concluded that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> government
gained much valuable ballistic <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missile</ENAMEX> technology by launching <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> satellites
on its <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">rockets</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> have claimed that the launches helped the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> more than <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>. These satellite launches are at the heart of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Loral</ENAMEX> campaign finance inquiry.

            
               
                  The New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yorker</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 21</TIMEX> 
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 15, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            A long profile of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bob</ENAMEX>
Hope depicts him as the first corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">comic</ENAMEX>. He employed armies of comedians
to write his jokes, made early promotional deals with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">advertisers</ENAMEX>,
and worked assiduously to build the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Hope</ENAMEX> brand. His great comic gifts: natural
ease, a breezy all-American persona, and speed. He didn't tell the best jokes,
but he told the most. (His <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">vault</ENAMEX> has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">585,000</NUMEX> jokes in it.) Hope, who's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">95</NUMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fading</ENAMEX>, was also a vain womanizer. ... A piece mocks
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>'s gift culture, where <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers</ENAMEX> are an insult and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$300</NUMEX> shoes are merely
adequate. ... An article tries to rehabilitate ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Ginsburg</ENAMEX>, applauding his clumsy efforts to protect <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX>. It
was under his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">successors</ENAMEX>, after all, that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX> was subjected to degrading
questioning by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>. Even so, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ginsburg</ENAMEX> is described by a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleague</ENAMEX> as "an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ego</ENAMEX> with a digestive system."

            
               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 21</TIMEX> (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 15, 1998</TIMEX>)

            A piece explicitly
argues what <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> have been hinting: Impeachment by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> is censure.
... An article applauds a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota</ENAMEX> school district for
offering pro-abstinence sex-education classes. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Parents</ENAMEX> can choose between the
traditional sex-ed curriculum and the new abstinence <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Civil</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liberties Union</ENAMEX> may sue to block the new classes.

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nation</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 28</TIMEX> 
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 15, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover story urges government
action to harness the talents of retiring <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby boomers</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boomers</ENAMEX> should be
urged to be active <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX>, caregivers, etc., and the federal
government should correspondingly raise <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> payments.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Economist</ENAMEX>
, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 12</TIMEX> 
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 12, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover editorial, pegged to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">50th</NUMEX> anniversary, warns that
the military <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> is shaky. With the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> threat gone, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> needs to
address broader future challenges, such as ethnic conflict and germ warfare.
This will only happen if <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> spend more on defense and rely less
on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. ... A piece notes that the West is
subsidizing critical <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> infrastructure, including its nuclear programs,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">libraries</ENAMEX>. The crippled <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> has no choice but to
accept this aid, but it's disturbingly reminiscent of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19th century</TIMEX> colonialism.
... An essay tries to explain why everyone hates the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> mock the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Frogs</ENAMEX> because we envy their intellectual arrogance, history,
and glamour. There is also universal scorn for their "fashion-bound
intellocracy," though the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Economist</ENAMEX> concedes that not all <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX>
are "jargon-spouting frauds."

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fair</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 1999</TIMEX> 
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 12, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            The most alarmist Y2K
story yet. In addition to the usual list of catastrophes (power outages, plane
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">crashes</ENAMEX>, etc.), it foresees <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">10 million</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">300 million</NUMEX> deaths from food
shortages and accidental nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missile</ENAMEX> launches. It also berates everyone,
from early <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">programmers</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>, for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">lackadaisical</ENAMEX> response. Y2K could destroy <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> presidential campaign.
Weirdest detail: Mobsters are bribing Y2K <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">debuggers</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rig</ENAMEX> computers to funnel
money into their accounts. ... A profile of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan McDougal</ENAMEX>
says she's manipulative and awful beneath her sweet front. She refuses to
testify to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX> not because she wants to protect the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> but
because she's afraid of being charged with perjury herself.

         
      
   
