
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">168</NUMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">&quot</NUMEX>;<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">East/East&quot</ENAMEX>;

            

               "We've been made the butt of a joke in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>--on television, in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>. We take it not as funny but as something very serious." Who said
this about what?
            

             

            by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">p.m. ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> to e-mail your answer to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            

               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s question (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 167</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">East/West</ENAMEX>":
            

            

               Fill in the blank. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bernard Salick</ENAMEX>'s entrepreneurial ideas may play in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, but they'll never make it in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren Enker</ENAMEX>: "Not too
many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> want ____________ at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4 a.m.</TIMEX>, so it's not that great a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gimmick</ENAMEX>."
            

            "Mr.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Salick</ENAMEX> to tell them they're pretty ... and smart, too."--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miller</ENAMEX>
            

            "To be
killed by a former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pro athlete</ENAMEX> simply because you decided to return some
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designer eye</ENAMEX> wear to a pretty, young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">divorcee</ENAMEX>."--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Carvell</ENAMEX>
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Us</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Books</ENAMEX> on Tape."--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Amaros</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cheese</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fondue</NUMEX>-bearing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joan Didion</ENAMEX> at their front door."--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David</ENAMEX>
Rakoff
            

            
"Greased up, shiny little <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Sushi Boy</ENAMEX>, in his shiny little sequined
shorty-shorts."--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Molly Shearer Gabel</ENAMEX>
            

            Click
for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more</NUMEX> responses.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
            

            That several jokes about
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> cuisine mention cilantro is unexceptional (click ). That many jokes
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>'s erotic life mention enemas is disconcerting. Are we 5 years
old? Are we <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX>? Are we meat and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">potatoes men</ENAMEX> who never get near fresh
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fruits</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vegetables</ENAMEX>? No, we're not. We're constantly frolicking about in all
that damn cilantro. We <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Californians</ENAMEX> apparently do little else. We eat eccentric
meals and enjoy sex and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> with our film business <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX>, all of whom
look fabulous courtesy of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">surgeon</ENAMEX>'s art. And if technically cilantro is
neither fruit nor vegetable, that's the least of my classification problems. Is
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gabor</ENAMEX> sister sex, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>, lifestyle, or something more sinister? Is a liberal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> the one who makes the biggest increase in defense spending in a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decade</TIMEX>, restricts habeas corpus, guts the protections of immigration law, and
sends <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Colombian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taxonomy</ENAMEX> is exhausting. I could use a cup
of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cilantro coffee</ENAMEX>.

            
               Ontological
Answer
            

            Radiation.

            With <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> likely to pass <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cardiovascular disease</ENAMEX> as
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1 one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">killer</ENAMEX>, many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> are vying for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>,
offering treatments still aloof from the financial restraints of managed care.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bernard Salick</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX> for-profit <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> clinics has done well in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, making flexible schedules a part of its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX>-friendly approach,
but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren Enker</ENAMEX>, associate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beth Israel Hospital</ENAMEX>,
remains skeptical.

            (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Editor</ENAMEX>'s note: No
response exploited the suffering of anyone afflicted with a dreadful <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX>;
all targeted profit-making <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foolishness</ENAMEX> and, of course, the
surviving <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gabor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX>, should there be any.)

            
               Implausible
Assertions Extra
            

            Match the hard-to-swallow
statement with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX> who managed to get the words out without
laughing.

            Statements

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. "I enjoy his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>. I just think he's a hell of
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. "It's one of our favorite ways of relaxing."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. "Seductively
appealing."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Speakers</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">A. Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX>, on hanging out with her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>,
reading about the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Jacksonian</ENAMEX> era in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B. John McCain</ENAMEX>, on hanging out with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rudolph</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Stephen Holden</ENAMEX>, on
hanging out at <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Star Trek: Insurrection</ENAMEX>
            

            

               Answers
            

            1B, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2A</TIMEX>,
3C.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Disclaimer</ENAMEX>: All
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">submissions</ENAMEX> will become the property of 
               
                  Slate
               

               and will be published at 
               
                  Slate
               
               's
discretion. 
               
                  Slate
                
               may publish your name on its
site in connection with your submission .

         
      
   
