
   
   
      
         
             <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Restoration Joe</ENAMEX>'s

            A new kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX> store
has emerged to cater to affluent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby boomers</ENAMEX> who think of themselves as
practical, but who are easily gulled into buying things for which they have no
obvious practical need. It is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> that knows yuppie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">materialism</ENAMEX> is a kind
of materialism that thinks of itself as anti-materialistic, because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">yuppies</ENAMEX>
tend to confuse their restless pursuit of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Authenticity</ENAMEX> when purchasing retail
goods with an indifference to material things. It is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> that takes
everyday items and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buffs</ENAMEX> them up just enough that they seem like luxury items
and yet (usually) keeps prices relatively low. It is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> that, if you
happen to be an affluent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby boomer</ENAMEX>, understands more about you and the things
that give you pleasure than you understand yourself.

            The typical posture of such an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enterprise</ENAMEX> is that
it is, to quote promotional material for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REI</ENAMEX>, a popular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX> of camping gear
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX>, "more than a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX>." It is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX>. You may wander into Borders
bookstore without a thought in the world of buying anything, except perhaps a
cup of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX>. Should you happen, amid your browsing, to find something you
want to purchase, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> will labor to treat it as an unexpected windfall.
At the more aggressive (and youthful) end of the spectrum, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Urban Outfitters</ENAMEX>
turns its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> into theatrical sets suitable for staging the works of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eug√</ENAMEX>®ne
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ionesco</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J. Peterman</ENAMEX>, a catalog <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailer</ENAMEX> with a few <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> here and there, goes
so far as to make its products seem incidental to the spirit they're meant to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">evoke</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> "describes" a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$345</NUMEX> cream colored silk jacket thusly in its
catalog:

            
               
                  The photograph on the dust jacket of
her book shows her in jeans and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">blazer</ENAMEX>, standing at the edge of a deep canyon
(inherited from her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>). The book itself is "serious, perceptive, skirting
the edges of hilarity and terror." You'd never guess she's a lethal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">poker</ENAMEX>. But the book doesn't go into any of that--the congenial barge trips on
rivers in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, the "innocent" trips down the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Nile</ENAMEX>, the lucrative
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">transatlantic</ENAMEX> crossings, making grown <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> cry.
               
            

            As this passage suggests, a common theme in these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> is
camp nostalgia. Another is the soullessness of retail as practiced by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nonelect</ENAMEX>. "I think that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">giant</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> should start asking
themselves if the things they make are really, I mean really, better than the
ordinary," the eponymous Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peterman</ENAMEX> avers on his catalog's first page, under
the heading "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Philosophy</ENAMEX>."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chains</ENAMEX> in particular
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">excel</ENAMEX> at this new style of retailing: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trader Joe</ENAMEX>'s and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Restoration</ENAMEX>
Hardware. Although they position themselves as "practicality" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX>, you'd
never visit them to buy more <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jell-O</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> or a molly bolt to hang a new
warehouse lamp. Rather, they invite you to question the underlying assumptions
behind your everyday needs and to reorder those needs.

            Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> are somewhat difficult to classify. Trader
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX>'s sells <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>, but it isn't really a grocery <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX>. "The traditional grocery
store handles <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">between 25,000 and 40,000</NUMEX> items," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trader Joe</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokeswoman</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michele Gorski</ENAMEX>. "We handle <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">between 1,500 and 2,000</NUMEX>." But don't think of it as a
gourmet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX>, because it's bigger and less pricey than most gourmet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX>.
(When the prices are high, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> is quick to make a joke of it, as it does
with its private-label "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Really Expensive Authentic Handcrafted</ENAMEX>" frozen chicken
burrito, which sells for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2.19</NUMEX>.)

            Similarly, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Restoration</ENAMEX>
Hardware calls itself a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hardware store</ENAMEX> and stocks a few items that might
legitimately be termed hardware--multiple-head carbine screwdrivers, fold-up
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pliers</ENAMEX>, flashlights with old metallic ribbing, etc. But these items, along with
a sprinkling of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen ware</ENAMEX>, gardening supplies, and whimsical doodads such as
an old-fashioned hand warmer, are essentially the amuse-bouches served
up before the main course, which is a sleigh bed, a leather and cherry bentwood
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">recliner</ENAMEX>, or some other hunk of massive retro furniture. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Restoration Hardware</ENAMEX>
is a home furnishings store for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who think of themselves as too austere
for such fripperies (but really aren't).

            Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chains</ENAMEX> present themselves as bucking the aesthetic and
moral poverty of corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Coulombe</ENAMEX> started <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Trader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX>'s in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1958</TIMEX>
as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pronto</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX> of convenience <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A decade later</TIMEX>,
Coulombe reoriented the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> toward gourmet foods offered at cut-rate prices.
Eventually, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> ceased to carry "lines" of goods at all, instead selling
mostly private-label versions of a few staples (<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">corn flakes</ENAMEX>, olive <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX>) and
more exotic goods such as <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX>-style crumpets and carbonated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> blended
with elderflowers. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX> guarantees that if any <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">item</ENAMEX> can be found cheaper
elsewhere, it will stop carrying it. "We like to suggest that some of our best
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> are unemployed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Ph.D.s</ENAMEX>," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gorski</ENAMEX>. "These are knowledgeable people
that have traveled and read, but they're still looking for a bargain." Gorski
has no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX>; neither, she says, do the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">presidents</ENAMEX>.

            Such austere commitment
to Quality and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Value</ENAMEX> would be easier to commend wholeheartedly if it didn't
reek quite so much of snob appeal. One has to remind oneself that this is an
enterprise whose ultimate goal is monetary profit. Who owns <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Trader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX>'s,
anyway? Coulombe sold out in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1979</TIMEX> and retired in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>. Although the chain
preserved his hokey <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South Pacific</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">d√©cor</ENAMEX> and still touts the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX>'s goods in
its eccentric "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">fearless flyers"</ENAMEX>--illustrated with <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">19 th</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">century</TIMEX> pen
and ink clip art, no less--it treats the identities of its new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> as some
sort of state secret. When pressed, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gorski</ENAMEX> says they are <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> and that
she's met them. Clippings from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">& World Report</ENAMEX> identify the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Albrechts</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> family
that owns <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 10 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Albertson's</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> supermarket chain. What?
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Trader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX>'s is owned by supermarket <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>? Say it ain't so!

            R estoration <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hardware</ENAMEX>'s origins smack more distinctly of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">counterculture</ENAMEX> rebellion. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, which is now traded publicly, was
started in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX> by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychologist</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Gordon</ENAMEX>, who was restoring a
Queen <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anne</ENAMEX>-style <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Eureka</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX>, and found it maddeningly difficult to
locate the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">period</TIMEX>-style fixtures he needed. Finally he started selling the
stuff himself. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s Web page depicts him as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cincinnatus of</ENAMEX>
retailing, one who "did not set out to found a retail <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>, but did so as a
result of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of his passions, the discovery of fine craftsmanship and
design."

            Like <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Trader Joe's</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Restoration Hardware</ENAMEX> does not carry "lines" but rather selects individual items
that seem to capture the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX>'s "spirit," many of which are made exclusively
for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX>. The presentation of these items is hushed and museumlike, with
just dash of whimsy. The little identifying cards <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychologist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gordon</ENAMEX> sets
beside each item display an impressive mastery of the manipulative arts. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FOUR</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">GENERATIONS OF MAINE FISHERMEN COULD BE WRONG ... BUT WE DOUBT IT</ENAMEX>," reads a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">card</ENAMEX> beside <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> sizes of woven metal baskets in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Restoration Hardware</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Georgetown</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX>. To refrain from purchasing one would insult the working class
and dishonor the labor of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fathers</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fathers</ENAMEX>! "Hey ... we, like you, secretly
covet recliners," purrs the card beside a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1952</TIMEX>-style <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metro Finer Recliner</ENAMEX>,
priced at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$990</NUMEX>. But there are only "a few of us who possess a stout enough
psychological profile to allow ourselves or even imagine ourselves purchasing a
big cushy wonder <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> reclining chair." Let's pause for a moment to map
the nuances of that pitch. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) Snob appeal: We all know recliners are tacky. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>)
Sympathy: And yet you secretly desire one so you can capture some magical
moments from your childhood. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Challenge</ENAMEX>: Dare you rise to the occasion, like
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Raskolnikov</ENAMEX>, and reject the petty rules that govern lesser <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>? <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) Smugness:
You may be buying your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>'s chair, but you are not going to play that gender
dominance game that he played. It's your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s chair too! Wonder boy
indeed!

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baffler</ENAMEX> , a little <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> of
cultural criticism, have coined an extremely handy term to describe the spirit
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Restoration Hardware</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Trader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX>'s: "Commodify your dissent."
In a book of essays with that title, the process of turning counterculture
rebellion into profit-making opportunity that does absolutely nothing to
challenge the status quo is described in various settings, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nike</ENAMEX> (which
used <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William S. Burroughs</ENAMEX> to sell sneakers) and the films of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quentin Tarantino</ENAMEX>
("always hip but scrupulously content-free"). In the case of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Restoration</ENAMEX>
Hardware and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Trader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX>'s, the dissent (hence the commodification) is a bit
more subtle and has more to do with the harnessing of postgrad hauteur mingled
with a longing for simpler times. But in both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX>, one is similarly invited
to live out vain fantasies about who one is, or should be. The spell is broken
only when you leave the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX>, realize that you've just bought <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$200</NUMEX> worth of
merchandise, and understand you're just another schmuck consumer.

         
      
   
