
   
   
      
         
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Blacks</ENAMEX> in
Cadillacs
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hey</ENAMEX>, that was real funny when that computer use at
historically black <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX> may be <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about half</NUMEX> of that at elite <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX> because
the black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> prefer to spend their money on "hot <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> and loud stereos."
Too bad the remark is also racist.

            When I say that I don't mean that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shuger</ENAMEX> is a white
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">supremacist</ENAMEX>. But I do mean he shows some symptoms that are still common among
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">well-educated whites</ENAMEX>. He feels entitled to interpret a politically charged
question of racialized disparity through one experience he had with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX>. He
doesn't seem to have enough experience with black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> in or out of college to
know that he can't extrapolate black college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> behavior from the black
spring break celebration "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Freaknik</ENAMEX>." He fails to grant black college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>
the same assumption he might grant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX>--that affluent <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Freaknik</ENAMEX> partiers are
a small subset of college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>. He doesn't assume that serious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> can
party at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freaknik</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few days</TIMEX> without damaging their academic achievements,
or that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Freaknik</ENAMEX> says nothing at all about those achievements. He doesn't
assume that, as with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX>, black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> with enough money for expensive
stereos usually also have computers, and that black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> without money for
computers usually don't have expensive <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> stereos or even <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>. In short, he
overlooks systematic, statistically verifiable inequalities between black and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">white</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poor</ENAMEX> and affluent, non-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elite</ENAMEX> and elite college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> in favor of a
favorite "culture of poverty" anecdote. It's not so different from the old way
of discrediting evidence of black poverty or segregation by saying, "look,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cadillacs</ENAMEX>."

            Is there any truth in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freaknik</ENAMEX> anecdote? A recent study headed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Flacks</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sociologist</ENAMEX>
at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.C. Santa Barbara</ENAMEX>, suggests that partying and academic apathy increase in
direct proportion to family income, that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX> party more in college than any
other racial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX>, and that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> who had to "sacrifice" to attend college
spend the most time on their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">academics</ENAMEX> (see the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chronicle</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Higher</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Education</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 25, 1998</TIMEX>). If affluent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> gave their computers to
poorer ones they would get a lot more use. It's only in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Shuger</ENAMEX>'s world that
they trade <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple</ENAMEX> in for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pioneer</ENAMEX>.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher</ENAMEX>
Newfield
            

            Associate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Department</ENAMEX> of English

            

            
               A Private
Opinion
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Re Scott Shuger</ENAMEX>'s idiotic statement on black
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX>. Don't you realize that these are mostly private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX>!
Many of them are quite elite in their own right. Think of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spike Lee</ENAMEX> at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morehouse College</ENAMEX>. Why would you assume that this comment has to do with
African-Americans anyway? I teach at a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> with many poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX> and
Latinos, many of whom can't afford <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> computers or did not learn how to use
them in high school. We do provide access to them here, but there is initial
resistance.

            Try to examine your
assumptions about poverty and race before making any more statements of the
type you made <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. I was embarrassed for you.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Patrick</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kelly</ENAMEX>
            

            Assistant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> of
history

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Texas</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Antonio</ENAMEX>

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott Shuger</ENAMEX> replies : The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> e-mail response to this
column is an unfortunate illustration of how race clouds the mind. Contrary to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>' complaints, I didn't assert anything about any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> item at issue reported that a survey showed a great
disparity in computer mastery between <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">first-year</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> at elite private
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX> and those attending traditionally black public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX>, and went
on to suggest, via quoting <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">academics</ENAMEX>, that this was because of a great
economic gap. My comment was that there was another possibility besides
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">economics</ENAMEX>: namely, that black college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> might disproportionately prefer
spending their disposable income on items besides computers, such as sound
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">systems</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>. I didn't say I know this to be true. I merely suggested that
it would make sense to add some questions about this to the next survey. If it
turns out that there's nothing to this, then so be it. What are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> so
afraid of finding out?
            

            
               
                  A comment from
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>:
                
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott Shuger</ENAMEX> has the rare privilege among
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> of publishing his work unedited, partly because he is talented and
trustworthy, but mainly because his "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers"</ENAMEX> column is posted at around
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">3 a.m.</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX>. When I read <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX> at a more reasonable hour that
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>, I e-mailed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott</ENAMEX> making points similar to those from these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>. I
was hoping that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott</ENAMEX> might see things differently in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daylight</TIMEX> as well. But,
judging from his reply--which, as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleague</ENAMEX>, he has the right to
make--apparently not.
            

            
               Just to spell it out: The fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> at
Freaknik drive fancy <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> does not prove--or even suggest--that fancy <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> have
anything to do with the alleged fact that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">60 percent</NUMEX> of black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> lack
Internet access. The most reasonable assumption is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Freaknik</ENAMEX> draws mostly
from an affluent slice of black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> that is smaller than, and included in,
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">the other 40 percent</NUMEX>. And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott</ENAMEX>'s
I-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only</NUMEX>-called-for-a-study-what-are-you-afraid-of reply, it seems to me, is a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cop-out</ENAMEX>. Presenting evidence <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">X</ENAMEX> and calling for a study of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Y</ENAMEX> clearly is meant to
imply that <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">X</ENAMEX> is suggestive of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Y. Twice</ENAMEX> the percentage of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX> than blacks
have Internet access--but something like twice the percentage of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX> than
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> probably also drive fancy <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>. Should we study whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX> who don't
have Internet access are buying fancy <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> instead?
            

            
               That said, let me add
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott</ENAMEX> is not a racist--just a little weak on statistical inferences, like
many otherwise excellent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX>.
            

            
               Ruffed
Up
            

            In the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 20</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott Shuger</ENAMEX>'s description of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Ruff</ENAMEX> as a foot-stomping defense <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> is either
mean or ignorant. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> is in a wheelchair, for crying out loud.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shuger</ENAMEX>'s description of
Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruff</ENAMEX>'s emotional remarks at the end of his presentation was also very wide
off the mark. It's best to let <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> decide for themselves
whether what they are seeing and reading is genuine or not.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX>
Slinkard
            

            
Wheaton, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Md.</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton Boom</ENAMEX>
Busted
            

            My heartiest thanks to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Timothy Noah</ENAMEX> from "" for having the memory (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than two weeks</TIMEX> is remarkable,
according to standard propagandist lore) and the intellectual honesty to point
out that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> can claim precious little credit for the health of our
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">economy</ENAMEX>, though he consistently points at himself as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> of our current
prosperity. As neither a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> nor a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>, I am amazed at the
party-and-ego-induced conjunctivitis that has given this pathetic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> a
mantle of glory as he balances precariously on the shoulders of those who came
before him. Thank you, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Noah</ENAMEX>. I appreciate your pen.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judith</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Lawson</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Essex,</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mass.</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan Full</ENAMEX> of
Air
            

            Hooray for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Chait</ENAMEX>. In his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 19</TIMEX> "," he is
right that the continual hagiography of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Jordan</ENAMEX> ignores the damage that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX> has done to the concept of teamwork. In <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">playgrounds</ENAMEX> across <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>,
young <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> eschew team play in favor of taking on defenders
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">one-on-one</ENAMEX>, dunking, and "taking over the game" in crunch time, because they
want to "be like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike</ENAMEX>," as the advertisements say. All this is the legacy of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX>'s continual selfish play and denigration and belittling of his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teammates</ENAMEX>. Everyone remembers <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX>'s last shot to take the lead in <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Game</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBA Finals</ENAMEX> against the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Jazz</ENAMEX>, but does anyone remember the series of shots
he missed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 4th quarter</TIMEX> to put <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> back in the game? Why wasn't any other
Bull shooting the ball?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Jordan</ENAMEX> is a
great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">athlete</ENAMEX>. He happened to come along at the right time--when marketing was
taking over sports and his flashy style of play could be successfully marketed.
But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX> could have never won on his own. Basketball is a team sport, and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">continual Jordan</ENAMEX> hype has always ignored that, in the constant push to sell
tickets and merchandise.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dilan A.</ENAMEX>
Esper
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles</ENAMEX>

            
               From a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Basketball</ENAMEX>
Fan
            

            Thank you, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan</ENAMEX>
Chait, for articulating my thoughts and feelings flawlessly. I, too, hate
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Jordan</ENAMEX>.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erik C.</ENAMEX>
Troberg
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Portland</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oregon</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
