
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">188</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">&quot;Two Bad&quot</ENAMEX>;

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Starbucks</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Inc.</ENAMEX> are teaming up. To do what?
            

             

            by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> to e-mail your answer to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            

               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s question (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 187</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Photo Fun":</ENAMEX>
            

            

               
                  
                     
                        
                           I give the caption, you briefly
describe the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Associated Press</ENAMEX> photo: "Protesting the export of trash by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">demonstrators</ENAMEX> gathered outside a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Harrisburg</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pa.</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> to assail <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudolph W. Giuliani</ENAMEX>, who was inside at a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> dinner."
                        
                     
                  
               
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Self</ENAMEX>-immolation of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Oscar the Grouch</ENAMEX>, torched by a burning 'I Love <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NY</ENAMEX>' coffee
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cup</ENAMEX>. A stunned <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> turns away in horror."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beth Sherman</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Photo</ENAMEX>
of screaming, riotous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Denver</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Bronco</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX>, to be followed by a correction in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX>'s paper."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Franzen</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jon Delfin</ENAMEX> had a similar
answer.)

            "In the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">foreground</ENAMEX>, the usual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">do-gooders</ENAMEX>, blissfully unaware that just behind them a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">phalanx</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYPD</ENAMEX>'s Special <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Forces division</ENAMEX> are aiming their
automatic <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> at what they assume are gun-wielding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rapists</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peter</ENAMEX>
Carlin
            

            
"Against a black background, an amber-lighted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Damon</ENAMEX> laughs congenially,
wearing an olive-green <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Prada</ENAMEX> sweater. Wait a minute--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sorry</ENAMEX>! Thought it said
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'associative</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX>. My bad!"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Colleen Werthmann</ENAMEX>
            

            "This
question is too hard. Send back something that lets me take a cheap shot at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WB</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dennis Cass</ENAMEX>
            

            Click
for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more</NUMEX> responses.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
            

            Demonstrations on
television never look right. All the signs are painted the same color, as if
they were done <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night before</TIMEX>, presumably by that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> who did the prom
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">decorations for Sabrina</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Teenage Witch</ENAMEX> . If the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">marchers</ENAMEX> are white
college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>, they look like an issue of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Archie comics</ENAMEX>; if they're
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-American</ENAMEX> college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>, they look like they've been costumed by whoever
did <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the first few</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX> Five albums. TV demos capture neither the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">exhilaration</ENAMEX> nor the fear, conveying instead the smug fatuity of some
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>-unit <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> who believes social change is for saps; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DGA</ENAMEX> cards are for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">winners</ENAMEX>. And by the way, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Man</ENAMEX> can't bust our music, but it turns out that he
can repackage it as an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX> mini-series, The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">'60s</TIMEX> . At last, someone has
collected all the turbulent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decade</TIMEX> clichés in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one convenient 37 hour</TIMEX> package. I
guess I can finally throw out my <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Moby</ENAMEX> Grape albums.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vividly Descriptive</ENAMEX>
Answer
            

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> dressed as the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Statue of Liberty</ENAMEX> holds a
sign reading "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudy</ENAMEX>: Keep your wretched <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">tons</NUMEX> of garbage." A man
dressed like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ben Franklin</ENAMEX> holds a clear plastic bag (of garbage?) bearing an "I
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heart NY</ENAMEX>" sign. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> in a ball cap clutches a bundle (garbage? <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">baby</ENAMEX>?) and
holds a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sierra Club</ENAMEX> placard: "Protect our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Kids</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health and Heritage</ENAMEX>."

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> from
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Virginia</ENAMEX> urged Mayor
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX> to reconsider his waste policies. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> has not yet called them
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">idiots</ENAMEX>. But perhaps he's too busy acting surprised that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYPD</ENAMEX> shot another
unarmed black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>.

            
               Toying With Your
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Affections Extra</ENAMEX>
            

            The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th Annual American International</ENAMEX>
Toy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fair</ENAMEX> opened in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, featuring <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,700</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exhibitors</ENAMEX> from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>. Below, some highlights as described by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toy Manufacturers of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> press release, and me.

            

               Play Catch <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Puppy</ENAMEX> (TM)--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fun</ENAMEX> or cruel? It depends where you put the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hyphen</ENAMEX>.

               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sea-Monkey Aquarium Watch</ENAMEX> is a tidal wave of fun with real live
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sea</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">creatures</ENAMEX> that live <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> with only minimal care!--We told the nursing
home much the same thing about my <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Aunt Helen</ENAMEX>.

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wishbone</ENAMEX> (TM) plush, inspired by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TV</ENAMEX>'s popular, literature-loving <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jack</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russell</ENAMEX> terrier.--For <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10,000</NUMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> will love your book even more; he's got a
deal with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.

               Play the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mutual Mania</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> game and make the most money by balancing the
risk and reward of buying and selling the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> mutual funds offered, and learn
all about investing the fun way.--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>, fun investing! <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Kids</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Kids</ENAMEX>?

               He's cool, he's blue ... and he's better than a rooster! <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wake Me Willy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vibrates</ENAMEX> when he speaks, and has a bright yellow squishy nose that tells you
the time when squeezed.--Wait a minute: That's not his nose!

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RINGO</ENAMEX> is the ring game for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ages 5 to 105</TIMEX> that challenges <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> to use a
swinging motion to catch the hook on the ring.--There hasn't been a sadder
endorsement deal since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Crosby</ENAMEX> did that Depends commercial. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">'60s</ENAMEX> are
over, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>.

               <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Soldiers Inc.</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Baby Jesus</ENAMEX>" is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nativity</ENAMEX> set that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> can
play with--Yes, but does he vibrate when he speaks?

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mattel</ENAMEX>: When <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> "read" to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goodnight Blue</ENAMEX> from her favorite storybook, she
closes her eyes, lowers her ears and gradually fades off to sleep and starts to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">snore</ENAMEX>.--Part of its Literacy Is for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Losers</ENAMEX> campaign, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Books</ENAMEX>: They're boring and
stupid!"

               <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Doubles Wild</ENAMEX> (TM) is a new luck and strategy game in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> try to
get <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> markers in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a row</TIMEX> in as many places as possible.--And then describe it
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Flynt</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a million</NUMEX> bucks.

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald's</ENAMEX> to launch <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Furby Happy Meals</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reuters</ENAMEX>)--Don't get your
hopes up; the patties are still made of "<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beef</ENAMEX>."

            

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            Top <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">target</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Gun-happy New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">police</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Disclaimer</ENAMEX>: All
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">submissions</ENAMEX> will become the property of 
               
                  Slate
               

               and will be published at 
               
                  Slate
               
               's
discretion. 
               
                  Slate
                
               may publish your name on its
site in connection with your submission .

         
      
   
