
   
   
      
         
            Impeachment, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Strasbourg</ENAMEX>-Style

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> gave
big advance billing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> to constitutional showdowns on both sides of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlantic</ENAMEX>--the opening <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>'s impeachment trial and a vote
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">same day</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Parliament</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Strasbourg</ENAMEX> that could result in the
dismissal of all <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Union</ENAMEX>'s ruling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">commission</ENAMEX>.

            The main <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Flytrap</ENAMEX> angle
across <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> was "porn <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Flynt</ENAMEX>'s accusations of hypocrisy against
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Barr</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">R-Ga.</ENAMEX>, but comparisons were also drawn between the
impeachment of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> and what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Repubblica of Rome</ENAMEX>
called "a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX>-style impeachment" of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the European
Commission, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacques Santer</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> pointed out that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Parliament</ENAMEX>,
although elected by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peoples</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Union</ENAMEX>, still doesn't have the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">powers</ENAMEX> of a normal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">parliament</ENAMEX>, while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">commission</ENAMEX>, which it was planning to
censure for fraud and other irregularities, isn't a real <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> but rather
a group of unelected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bureaucrats</ENAMEX>. The "psychodrama" in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Strasbourg</ENAMEX> was the fruit
of "a generalized institutional sickness," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">La Repubblica</ENAMEX> said.

            A leading <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">target</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parliament</ENAMEX>'s attack is
former <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edith Cresson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commissioner</ENAMEX> for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">education</ENAMEX>, who is alleged, among other things, to have appointed her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dentist</ENAMEX> to
be a scientific <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adviser</ENAMEX>. In an interview with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Telegraph of London</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cresson</ENAMEX> (notorious in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> for having stated while <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX>
that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a quarter</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Englishmen</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homosexuals</ENAMEX>) blamed her troubles on "a shadowy
conspiracy of ultra-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Rightists</ENAMEX> who leak lies to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>" and on a new
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> parliamentarians, who lack the old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European</ENAMEX>
idealism.

            Lamenting this loss,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cresson</ENAMEX> said the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> had a shared culture that set them apart
from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>, "who are extremely enthusiastic about something <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> and say
exactly the opposite <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few days later</TIMEX>." She went on, "Perhaps we are more
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sceptical</ENAMEX>. Perhaps we are more reasonable; perhaps we have suffered far more.
We are different, and the world needs that for its balance." In a separate
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telegraph</ENAMEX> described the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Union</ENAMEX> as "teetering on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">brink</ENAMEX> of chaos." The firing of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Commission</ENAMEX> "would leave the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EU</ENAMEX>
institutionally crippled <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only 14 days</TIMEX> after the birth of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> single
currency," it said.

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jerusalem Post</ENAMEX> reported <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> that "material having to do
with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor Party</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ehud Barak</ENAMEX>'s campaign for the premiership" had been
stolen in a <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX>-style break-in of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> of his campaign
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">advisers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanley Greenberg</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Carville</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barak</ENAMEX> campaign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> said
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Israel Radio</ENAMEX> that it was believed that "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> material was the
main focus of the break-in."

            Elsewhere in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Middle</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ahram</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">daily</ENAMEX> said in an editorial that "now that it has been revealed
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> has used <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">UNSCOM</ENAMEX> for spying purposes, it has become necessary that
the international <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> take a firm stance by which to prevent any of
its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> being used for purposes other than those mandated." The paper
called for "an impartial inquiry" into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UNSCOM</ENAMEX> and the dismissal of chief arms
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspector</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Butler</ENAMEX>, "whose record with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> has lacked honesty, to say
the least." It also said <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are wrong to imagine that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX> will "abandon
its role in preventing further <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> aggressions against the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>"
because of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX>'s "foolish campaign" against the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX>
cannot endorse interference in other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>' internal affairs," it
concluded.

            With the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times of London</ENAMEX> warning <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> of future trade conflict
between the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ambassador</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kunihiko Saito</ENAMEX>, was quoted in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tokyo</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asahi</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shimbun</ENAMEX> as saying that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> is getting impatient with
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>'s rising trade surplus. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saito</ENAMEX> said trade friction will be inevitable this
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> in certain sectors, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">steel</ENAMEX>, but that the good performance of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> economy has so far prevented such friction from becoming serious.
Asked about the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> response to suspicions that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Korea</ENAMEX> was engaged in
underground nuclear development programs, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ambassador</ENAMEX> said that "the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US</ENAMEX>
government apparently understands the serious consequences of military strikes
against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Korea</ENAMEX>, similar to the attacks it conducted against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Financial Times of London</ENAMEX> carried a front page report of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rupert Murdoch</ENAMEX> saying in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Singapore</ENAMEX> that many Internet stocks were heavily
overvalued and unlikely to meet profit projections. He was also quoted as
saying that his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Corp</ENAMEX>, would "certainly not be making takeovers of
large or already over-capitalised <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>" and that the Internet was "not the
death-knell of the old" among media <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>. The Internet would destroy
more <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> than it created by "wiping out the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">middlemen</ENAMEX>," he said.

            While the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>-based
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South China Morning</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> said that the discontented flight <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crews</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cathay Pacific Airways</ENAMEX>
have still not decided whether to implement a plan to stop smiling at
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times of India</ENAMEX> carried an editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> calling on the
flight <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attendants</ENAMEX> to "have second thoughts." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> declared, "A smile costs
nothing, but it brightens up the moment for the one who flashes it, and the one
who watches. Grim faces and hardened <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jaws</ENAMEX> are not <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>-friendly."

             

         
      
   
