
   
   
      
         
            Are Taxes <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Heavier Than Ever</ENAMEX>?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> propose using
the federal budget surplus to finance a tax cut. They argue that the tax burden
on the average <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> has grown. A tax cut may be a good or a bad idea for
other reasons, but the notion of a growing tax burden rests on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> highly
misleading statistics.

            The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> is that "a
typical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> who both work paid <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">nearly 40 percent</NUMEX> of their income
in taxes," as <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer Dunn</ENAMEX> stated in her reply to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX>
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union</ENAMEX> address. "That means," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dunn</ENAMEX> explained, "<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">40 cents</NUMEX> of every
dollar they earned went to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dunn</ENAMEX> also noted that the statistic
"really bothers me." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dunn</ENAMEX> can stop tormenting herself; the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">40 percent</NUMEX> figure is
bogus.

            The number derives from a study conducted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tax</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> pay <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">36.7 percent</NUMEX> of their income in total taxes, which is commonly
rounded up to a neat <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">40 percent</NUMEX>. That's a sneaky increase of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">almost a tenth</NUMEX>
right there. But even the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">36.7 percent</NUMEX> figure is inflated. (These errors were
brought to light by the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Center</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Budget</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Policy Priorities</ENAMEX>, a moderately
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">liberal</ENAMEX>--and methodologically sound--research <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>.) For instance, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tax</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foundation</ENAMEX> assumes that the average <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayer</ENAMEX> pays <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">an average</NUMEX> share of estate
and capital gains taxes, which is absurd. Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> do not have any capital
gains at all, and the estate tax only affects inheritances of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">at least $625,000</NUMEX>
(and actually a lot more than that unless you're exceptionally stupid about
estate planning). The "typical" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayer</ENAMEX> paid estate taxes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> in the
same sense that the "typical" golfer scored some fraction of a hole in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>.
That is, in almost no sense whatever.

            Even more bizarrely, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tax Foundation</ENAMEX> study counts
as part of the tax burden things that aren't taxes, such as private pension
contributions by government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> or rental fees on property owned by the
government. If you lease office space in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trade Center</ENAMEX>, should
your rent be considered a tax? The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tax Foundation</ENAMEX>'s miscounting of nontax taxes
alone overstates the federal tax burden by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">seventh</NUMEX>.

            Legitimate differences of
interpretation do exist. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tax Foundation</ENAMEX>'s calculation of the federal
tax burden, which is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly a quarter</NUMEX> larger than the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congressional Budget</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Office</ENAMEX>'s, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> again larger than the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joint Tax Committee</ENAMEX>'s, is beyond the
pale.

            A more sophisticated statistical salvo, which conservative
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> have shot off recently, is that federal tax revenues now consume the
highest percentage of the gross domestic product since <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War</ENAMEX> II. This
number is true: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> took in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20.5 percent</NUMEX> of GDP, whereas in
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decade</TIMEX> before <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> took office, the number ranged <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">between 17.5 percent</NUMEX>
and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">19.2 percent</NUMEX>.

            But this is misleading.
The federal cup runneth over, in part, because the raging stock market has
produced a gusher of capital gains tax revenues. But GDP does not include
profits from stocks. This means that during a strong stock market, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">numerator</ENAMEX> (tax revenues) will shoot up, but the denominator (GDP) will not.

            The main problem with the tax revenue-to-GDP ratio, though,
isn't accuracy. It's relevance. During the heyday of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> deficits,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> maintained, quite logically, that the important statistic was not
how much the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> took in but how much it spent: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Big government</ENAMEX> financed
through borrowing was no better than big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> financed through taxing.
Today, the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> spends <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3 percent</NUMEX> of GDP less than it did when
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> left <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>.

            Leading <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>, who now complain about an
alleged huge increase in tax revenues, insisted back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s tax increase would cause a decline in tax revenues. (This was
the "free lunch" logic in reverse: If a tax cut will increase revenues, a tax
increase will reduce them.) That prediction failed spectacularly: Tax revenues
have boomed with the economy. Now the boom they denied could even happen has
become their main justification for a tax cut.

         
      
   
