
   
   
      
         
            

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX>
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 22</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, Feb.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5, 1999</TIMEX>)
            

            The editorial assesses
the recently released <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> budget: It unwisely sacrifices
long-worked-for tax reforms in favor of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s immediate social
spending priorities. ... A piece argues that despite <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Duke</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pariah</ENAMEX>
status on the national level, he has won favor among <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisiana</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> with
a slick combination of race-baiting and shady quid pro quos. ... An
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iranian</ENAMEX> academic narrates how, despite his reputation as a moderate, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mohammed Khatami</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> has actually imposed even harsher restrictions on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>. But by basing its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">authority</ENAMEX> on public acceptance of extreme gender
restrictions, his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX> "has become far more dependent on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> for its
survival than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> are on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX>." Most surreal act of censorship: Western
musicals such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Poppins</ENAMEX> are screened, but every time a female
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">character</ENAMEX> sings or dances, she is replaced by an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iranian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">narrator</ENAMEX> who provides
spoken commentary instead.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
Magazine
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 7</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, Feb.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4, 1999</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover story
chronicles the bittersweet process of reuniting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> separated
during <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El Salvador</ENAMEX>'s civil war. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> were seized and often raised by
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX> that terrorized their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>. Now <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">villagers</ENAMEX> are trying to find
and form relationships with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> adopted by their former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX>. These
reunions can give rare substance and progress to the notoriously difficult
process of postwar national reconciliation. ... A piece tells the sad
story of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX> merchant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sailors</ENAMEX> left legally, financially, and physically adrift
on a rotting freight <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vessel</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gulf of Mexico</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ship</ENAMEX> was abandoned by
its bankrupt <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Pakistani</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> and its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX> left without <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fuel</ENAMEX>, or
wages. The merchant marine has become "the sweatshop of the high seas."
... The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> continues its new practice of printing footnotes to its
fashion spreads. To fully understand <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>'s photos of heavily made-up
models in glittery frocks, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> should consult an annotated guide to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">models</ENAMEX>' dye jobs, the "artichoke" haircut, and the new way to wear leg warmers
(on your <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX>).

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harper</ENAMEX>'s
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 1999</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, Feb.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4, 1999</TIMEX>)
            

            An amazing story
describes the life of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fighter pilots</ENAMEX> on an aircraft <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">carrier</ENAMEX> in sweat-inducing
detail. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> finds plenty of technical derring-do, but little Top
Gun -style machismo. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ship</ENAMEX> is a clammy and morbid universe of its own,
holding great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masses</ENAMEX> of bombs and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX>, all tightly organized. The pilots
are dutiful but terrified. They quietly suppress the reality of killing other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX> and the possibility of being killed themselves. Instead, they put their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">faith</ENAMEX> in athleticism and luck.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>
               
               and

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX>
               
               
                  , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 8</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Feb.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2, 1999</TIMEX>)
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's cover story predicts <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flytrap</ENAMEX>'s long-term impact on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
politics and society. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>'s less than revelatory insights: The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> won't accomplish much this term, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> will survive, and
"consensual sex will continue to be tolerated." A conservative critic
tells <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> to read--no, steal-- the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
manual on how to update and revive your losing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>. They should "pull a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Souljah</ENAMEX>," loudly distancing themselves from a cultural figure on the far
right, and start oozing compassion (one way to do this: "heartwarming stories
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> with fatal diseases").

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's
cover story celebrates "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hip-Hop Nation"</ENAMEX> and chronicles the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">genre</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 year</TIMEX> rise. Hip-hop is the jazz of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1990s</TIMEX>: Its mix of rage,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">authenticity</ENAMEX>, capitalism, and humor have caused nothing less than "a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">realignment of America</ENAMEX>'s cultural aesthetics." As for the violence and misogyny
of some rap lyrics: They may be offensive, but they're still "deeply <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX>."
... 
               Time chronicles the emerging partnership between Vice
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Minority Leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Gephardt</ENAMEX>. The former
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adversaries</ENAMEX> have formed "a pact of mutually assured ambition," with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>
gunning for the presidency and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gephardt</ENAMEX> angling to retake the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> and become
its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">& World Report</ENAMEX>
               
               
                  , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 8</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Feb.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2, 1999</TIMEX>)
            

            A piece recounts <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s horrific descent. Quality and length
of life, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> production, investment, and infrastructure are all bottoming out,
and inflation, pollution, and crime are soaring. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> greatest blunders of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s privatization plan: allowing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> to speculate with government
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rubles</ENAMEX>, and the sale of government <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">utilities</ENAMEX> at bargain prices in rigged
auctions. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> can no longer even afford to pay <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lenin</ENAMEX>'s embalmers.
... The cover story remarks on the diminishing representation
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> in higher education. Since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1979</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> have outnumbered <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> on college
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">campuses</ENAMEX>, but now the gap is widening: Fifty-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> percent of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">B.A.s</ENAMEX> are awarded
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>. This distorts social life on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campus</ENAMEX> ("the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> develop eating
disorders, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> develop huge egos," complains <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> undergrad). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Colleges</ENAMEX>
are turning to quiet, informal affirmative action on behalf of male
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">applicants</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  The New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yorker</ENAMEX>
               
               
                  , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 8</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Feb.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2, 1999</TIMEX>)
            

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> chronicles
the rapacious and mistaken prosecution of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a 7-year-old</TIMEX> and an <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8-year-old</TIMEX> for
murder in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>. In their zeal to convict, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> all over the country
are steamrollering special protections for juvenile <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suspects</ENAMEX>. The legal
consequences are dubious, and the social ones heartbreaking. ... In a
profile, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Patrick Moynihan</ENAMEX> casts a contemptuous eye on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> has stood by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> out of party loyalty
and disdain for the impeachment process, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moynihan</ENAMEX> calls <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s character
bankrupt and his policy choices morally and intellectually cheap. ... A
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> debunks the notion that toxic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">substances</ENAMEX> cause "cancer clusters." (Such
clusters are the subject of the book and film A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Civil Action</ENAMEX> .) The
apparent concentration of certain <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancers</ENAMEX> in certain <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">places</ENAMEX> is just coincidence
and "an irresistible error of human perception." ... Look closely at the
cover. It's the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lisa</ENAMEX>, cherubic, mysterious, and famously silent.

            
               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX>
Standard
               
               
                  , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 8</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, Feb
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2, 1999</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover story concedes
defeat on impeachment and beatifies the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> for their willingness
to pursue an unpopular but noble path. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> workable exit strategy is to
"call the final vote and be prepared to lose." ... The editorial
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">proclaims Henry Hyde</ENAMEX> the once and future <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican Party</ENAMEX>. An
offhand comment made by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hyde</ENAMEX> during the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> trial--that he would sacrifice
his seat in defense of the unborn, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s security, and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Constitution</ENAMEX>--sums up the best <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> agenda for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>. ... A piece
celebrates <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elia Kazan</ENAMEX>'s lifetime achievement <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oscar</ENAMEX> and argues for his
vindication in the popular memory. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kazan</ENAMEX> should be lauded for ratting on his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contemporaries</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCarthy</ENAMEX> hearings and has been vilified by "revived
leftist fundamentalism." (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Click for Jacob Weisberg</ENAMEX>'s take on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kazan</ENAMEX> in

                  Slate
               .)

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Economist</ENAMEX>
                
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 30</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30, 1999</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover editorial predicts the imminent collapse
of--guess what?--massively overvalued Internet stocks. That crash, if it
doesn't drag the whole stock market down, could be useful for the economy
because it will "restore sanity" to the venture capital industry. Some of the
big Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pioneers</ENAMEX> such as Yahoo! and <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">America Online</ENAMEX> may survive, but the
Dollar.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">coms</ENAMEX> and Buy.coms of the world are surely doomed. ... An article
identifies <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> reasons that company <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> are rich yet miserable: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)
They're working <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">longer hours</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) Flatter management structures diminish the
sweet sense of victory that used to come from reaching the top. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Job</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">paranoia: Execs</ENAMEX> get fired more often <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Outside</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contractors</ENAMEX> are
increasingly siphoning power from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX>' "fiefdoms." ... An article
finds "feminism" in an unexpected place: primitive, forest-dwelling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tribes</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> are deliberately promiscuous in order to win more male <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protectors</ENAMEX> for
their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Men</ENAMEX>, not knowing if they're the biological <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> or not, assume
that they are.

         
      
   
