
   
   
      
         
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Girls Against</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Boys</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cheers to Cathy Young</ENAMEX> for being a rare, courageous
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">feminist</ENAMEX> who doesn't think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> are the cause of all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s problems. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jeers</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wendy Shalit</ENAMEX> who cannot seem to comprehend that equal numbers of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> suffer
from abuse as cause it, and similarly for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>.(See the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dialogue": "</ENAMEX>")

            Particularly offensive
is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shalit</ENAMEX>'s claim that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> are uncivilized and must be trained. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shalit</ENAMEX> is no
doubt aware that male-bashing, although emotionally satisfying (I assume), is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">counter-productive</ENAMEX>. For those of us working to create a world in which the
genders are treated equally in the workplace, take equal responsibility in
matters of sex, and treat each other socially with equal respect and dignity,
the only practical approach is to start doing it. But to act as though wrongs
only matter when they happen to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, or to assume that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> are never in the
wrong when they have conflicts with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, is to retard progress toward a goal
that even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shalit</ENAMEX> might enjoy.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Flint</ENAMEX>
            

            
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Chicago</TIMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malcolm</ENAMEX>
X'd
            

            "" debate over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malcolm</ENAMEX>'s new book piqued my interest in reading it. It felt a bit too much
like a discussion between a skeptical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malcolm</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">publicist</ENAMEX>, however.
Did <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosen</ENAMEX> really not find anything in the book that he disagreed with? (Even
positive book reviews usually have some caveats.) I had to sympathize with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fallows</ENAMEX> when he wrote that he felt he was walking out on a limb criticizing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malcolm</ENAMEX>, given her prominence and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">connections</ENAMEX> in journalism. Although I'm sure
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosen</ENAMEX> means what he says in his remarks, his own professional connections with
her made a free-flowing discussion, including criticism, highly unlikely. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rosen</ENAMEX>
is a relatively new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> at The 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> , where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malcolm</ENAMEX> has
long been a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malcolm</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">New Yorker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>. Perhaps next
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>, to avoid the sense that professional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX> are not hampering the
conversation in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Book Club</ENAMEX>, it might make sense to choose <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> discussants
with no ties to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> under discussion.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Shea</ENAMEX>
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>

            
               Historical
Inaccuracy
            

            Can <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Plotz</ENAMEX> (and
everyone at 
                  Slate
               ) please refrain from speaking on behalf of
History? In his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 3</TIMEX> "" from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> trial, he writes, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">History and the</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have already rendered their verdict." Sorry to be picky, but
when precisely did Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Plotz</ENAMEX> speak to History? Is Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Plotz</ENAMEX> accurately
reporting History's opinions? Perhaps Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Plotz</ENAMEX> has a tape transcript of the
interview. If so, would he make it generally available?

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David</ENAMEX>
Margolies
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oakland</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX>

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">101</NUMEX>
Damnations
            

            I am appalled that your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> would
ever consider publishing "." As a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dalmatian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX>, I have found nothing but
love and compassion from my <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Dalmatian</ENAMEX>. As the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of the Dalmatian
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Board</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AcmePet</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Your Guide to Pets</ENAMEX> on the Internet, I have found
a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dalmatian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> who are the happiest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> I have ever
met.

            To quote the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>,
"Many of them are deaf, and all of them are dumb. They are, in short, lousy
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pets</ENAMEX>." Excuse me, but have you ever had a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dalmatian</ENAMEX> as a part of your family
for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than two weeks</TIMEX>? True, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dalmatians</ENAMEX> are more hyper than most <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX>, but
what human 2-year-old isn't? Would you skin <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a 2-year-old</TIMEX> because he talks baby
talk too much and always seem to get into things and is harder than heck to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">potty</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">train</ENAMEX>? Dalmatians are the least vocal of any <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX>. They only bark when
they need to get their point across. Kind of like me. I am a quiet <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> until
someone jerks my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX> a little too hard.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schroeder</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weston</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
