
   
   
      
         
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 13</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Feb.</TIMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX>)
            

            The cover story examines the sorry detritus of the
impeachment scandal, with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> conclusions: "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First</ENAMEX>, what has happened over the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past year</TIMEX> should never have happened at all; <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>, there is no guarantee that
it will not happen again." The editorial attributes the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s escape to sheer
dumb luck. ... The latest <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern Ireland</ENAMEX> peace agreement will crumble,
predicts the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>, unless <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Unionists</ENAMEX> give <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sinn</ENAMEX> Fein
more time to cleanse itself of terrorist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX>, both real and symbolic.
... A report chides blue-chip media <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> for their rush
to acquire Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">start-ups</ENAMEX>. The Internet can be unfriendly to traditional
content <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX> because <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) ad revenue is low; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) portals are overpriced; and
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) most traditional content (such as video) still looks awkward online.
(
                  Slate
                thinks about this issue once in while. For <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Editor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kinsley</ENAMEX>'s take, click .)

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX>
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 1</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, Feb.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12, 1999</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover package is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX>
unpublished letters by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralph Ellison</ENAMEX>. Among the recurring themes: his belief in
the primacy of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> over the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> ("[My work] tries to reveal the
extent to which each of us is responsible for his own fate") and his intense,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">conflicted Americanism</ENAMEX> ("I am too vindictively <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX>, too full of hate for
the hateful aspects of this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, and too possessed by the things I love
here to be too long away"). A separate piece reviews a new collection of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ellison</ENAMEX> short stories, praising <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ellison</ENAMEX>'s conviction that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> had "a degree
of freedom" despite the confines of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> racism, freedom that black
"protest" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Toni Morrison</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Wright</ENAMEX>) have unfortunately
downplayed.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
Magazine
               
               
                  , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 14</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, Feb.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11, 1999</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover story profiles
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Spielberg</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>'s premier <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">moneymaker</ENAMEX>, multi-tasker, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mentor</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mensch</ENAMEX> . From <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Animaniacs</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schindler</ENAMEX>'s List , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spielberg</ENAMEX>
markets patriotic moral lessons to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masses</ENAMEX>. His many charitable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">projects</ENAMEX>--a
genealogical research <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundation</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust archive</ENAMEX>--endorse the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockwell</ENAMEX> vision of tolerance as his movies. ... The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> recounts
the heartbreaking stories of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> forced to fight in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sierra Leone</ENAMEX>'s
vicious civil war. Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebel</ENAMEX> and government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">armies</ENAMEX> have conscripted
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX>, who make cheap and loyal (and especially vicious)
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX>. ... An article explicates the doctrines of tough-parenting
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">guru John Rosemond</ENAMEX>, who orders <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> to apply conservative, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Old</ENAMEX>
Testament-style standards to child-rearing. Punishment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, the article
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">recounts</ENAMEX>, "should be unpleasant, memorable, and inflicted at a time that is
convenient for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX>." Meanwhile, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rosemond</ENAMEX> hasn't spoken to his own mother
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 years</TIMEX>.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>
               
               and

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX>
               
               
                  , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 15</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Feb.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9, 1999</TIMEX>)
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 
               reports on Jesse "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Body</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ventura</ENAMEX>'s wildly successful
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">honeymoon</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota</ENAMEX>. So far he's produced a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">75 percent</NUMEX> approval
rating, a uniformly lauded budget, and a set of toy action figures. ...
The cover story castigates the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Olympic</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee</ENAMEX> for shoddy drug testing, a bigger scandal, the story says, than the
ongoing host-site bribery imbroglio. Rampant use of performance-enhancing drugs
tarnishes the games, kills <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">athletes</ENAMEX>, and encourages <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> use among
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 
               cover profiles "the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> to save the world": <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Rubin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Deputy Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lawrence Summers</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Reserve</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Greenspan</ENAMEX>. Each economic superhero has a distinct personality and
style--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX> is the shaman, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rubin</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Midas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figure</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summers the</ENAMEX>
academic--but together, they stave off worldwide economic panic. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">triumvirate</ENAMEX> has "outgrown ideology" and practices pure "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Realeconomik</ENAMEX>."

            According to the
magazines, the film <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare in Love</ENAMEX> has fueled fashion,
entertainment, and academic trends. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> recounts the debate about who
wrote <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX>'s plays, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> catalogs the recent profusion of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bard</ENAMEX> movies. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> devotes an entire piece to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gwyneth Paltrow</ENAMEX>'s hair extensions, but literary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harold Bloom</ENAMEX> tells <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> that she's ... ugly.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">& World Report</ENAMEX>
               
               
                  , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 15</TIMEX>
               
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Feb.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9, 1999</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover story calls the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s home renovation boom a
"historic trend" arising from "ancient" and "fundamentally human" impulses.
... The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> profiles the fire and brimstone politics of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican</ENAMEX>
presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hopeful</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Bauer</ENAMEX>. By losing the nomination nobly and narrowly,
he could assume <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>'s conservative flank. ... An
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> calls the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">North Korean</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> a loosely veiled,
highly effective criminal operation. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crooked</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> engage in drug-smuggling
and counterfeiting both to line their pockets and possibly even to prop up the
struggling <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s nuclear program. ... A self-identified <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of
the "black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elite</ENAMEX>" justifies the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>'s snobbery and separatism. Descended from
light-skinned <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slaves</ENAMEX> who enjoyed a privileged position in the plantation
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hierarchy</ENAMEX>, the "black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elite</ENAMEX>" continues to hoard access to its boarding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">social</ENAMEX> events, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX>: "Why," asks <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pedigreed lady</ENAMEX>, "would I be
socializing with some caseworker or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mailman</ENAMEX> who goes to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAACP</ENAMEX> events?"

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">People</ENAMEX>
               
               
                  ,
                
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 15</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Feb.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9, 1999</TIMEX>)
            

            The real subject of the
much-fretted-about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chelsea Clinton</ENAMEX> cover story is her devoted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>. The first
daughter anecdotes are light (when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Itzhak Perlman</ENAMEX> played for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>
grown-ups, she furtively listened). Most of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> pages are devoted to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">lauding Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX>'s energetic and sensible approach to child rearing.
Despite the rigors of <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> ladyhood, she always made time to chaperone class
trips, organize slumber parties, and check that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chelsea</ENAMEX> swept up any popcorn
she'd spilled in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> screening <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  The New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yorker</ENAMEX>
               
               
                  , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 15</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Feb.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9, 1999</TIMEX>)
            

            A former underground
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Polish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> is enjoying a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> act as a communications <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire</ENAMEX> in the
making, complete with lush advertisements and cross-media synergy. The highly
profitable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX>--which used to print samizdat on smudgy,
single-sided pages--symbolizes <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Poland</ENAMEX>'s transition from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">repression</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">consumerist</ENAMEX> democracy. ... A piece argues that Attention Deficit
Disorder isn't merely a psychosomatic affectation but a long-existing
biological deficiency suddenly exposed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">society</ENAMEX>'s accelerating pace. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Ritalin</ENAMEX>
might be a safe alternative to the more dangerous <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">substances</ENAMEX> (nicotine,
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX>) that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> previously used to increase their powers of concentration
and focus. ... A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> examines suicide notes to investigate why people
kill themselves. He never finds out, but the notes are succinct, lyrical, and
uniformly devastating.

            
               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX>
Standard
               
               
                  , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 15</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Feb.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9, 1999</TIMEX>)
            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> explains why
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s poll numbers are so high: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) he courts them ("like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> who
gets straight <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A's</ENAMEX> by flattering the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX>"); and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) polling questions are
phrased with a calculation and nuance that are positively, well, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Clintonesque</ENAMEX>.
A separate piece insists that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> poll ratings are low because--and only
because--of weak stances on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>, education, and taxes. Impeachment
won't tarnish <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> chances in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>: If <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> don't care about the
scandal now, the argument goes, they certainly won't care in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years time</TIMEX>.
... A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> tours a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mall</ENAMEX> and declares <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teens</ENAMEX> A-OK:
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> coo over clothing at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Old Navy</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> follow sneaker fashion
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">avidly</ENAMEX>, and everyone listens to country music. This all means that "parents
have returned to adolescent upbringing in ways that have rendered their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s normally destructive impulses mute."

         
      
   
