
   
   
      
         
             <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G-SPAN</ENAMEX>

            

               <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">06:30 a.m.</TIMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Reserve</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board Open Markets Committee Meeting Preview</ENAMEX> : Discussion of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">much-anticipated</ENAMEX> session. Will <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A.G.</ENAMEX> lower interest rates yet again? All
humankind waits breathlessly.

            

               <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">06:50 a.m.</TIMEX> 
               (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">approx.</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Continuous G-SPAN</ENAMEX> shower
and breakfast coverage from outside the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>.

            

               <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">08:00 a.m.</TIMEX> 
               Agenda : <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Press</ENAMEX> briefing on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX>'s
meeting, phone call, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX>, and bathroom schedule for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>. Immediate
futures market analysis from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Frankfurt</ENAMEX>.

            

               <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">09:00 a.m.</TIMEX> 
               MugWatch : Recap of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX>'s facial
expressions during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the previous week</TIMEX>. Comparisons to previous pre-FROMC
smile-to-grimace-to-frown ratios and their correlations to interest rate moves.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guest</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Tch</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johns Hopkins</ENAMEX> neuropsychology <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>.

            

               <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">09:30 a.m.</TIMEX> Rate <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX> coverage begins with the full <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G-SPAN</ENAMEX> team
reporting from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Stock Exchange</ENAMEX> floor: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sandy Walsh</ENAMEX> (mood), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Haskins</ENAMEX> (sentiment), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alicia Geller</ENAMEX> (feeling), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Lupin</ENAMEX> (flavor).

            

               <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11:00 a.m.</TIMEX> 
               ChartWatch : <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G-SPAN</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anna Maria</ENAMEX> the
Omniscient reports on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX>'s moon in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Saturn</ENAMEX>. Viewer
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">call-in</ENAMEX>.

            

               
                  Note:
                
               All below programming subject to pre-emption
for the rate announcement and total blitzkrieglike worldwide market
fallout.
            

            

               <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">12:15 p.m.</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G-SPAN Special Report</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX>'s Lunch .
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Correspondent Bradley</ENAMEX> Yeldarb orders "what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Guy's</ENAMEX> having" from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">catering</ENAMEX> service and reports on its likely emoto-digestive consequences.

            

               <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">12:30 p.m.</TIMEX> 
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lunch--Wall Street Responds :</ENAMEX>
Live <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">45</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> fiber-optic minicam microwave-satellite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> coverage from all
over the place.

            

               <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">01:00 p.m.</TIMEX> 
               Leading <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indicators</ENAMEX> : <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> or regular?
Historical impact of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX>'s choice of cuffs on the discount rate.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Panelists</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara Whoom</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Smith Barney</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Miller</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bear Stearns</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanley</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Groute</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bergdorf Goodman</ENAMEX>).

            

               <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">02:00 p.m.</TIMEX> Ongoing rate <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX> coverage of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traders</ENAMEX> waiting,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">guessing</ENAMEX>, floating rumors, cursing, waiting.

            

               <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">03:30 p.m.</TIMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G-SPAN</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">LifeStyles : Today</ENAMEX>, hair care
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">extraordinaire</ENAMEX>. The chair shares where, for fear of glare, he dares not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nair</ENAMEX>.
Aware his hair is debonair, he wears it with a rare, square flair. Later: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tony</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blair</ENAMEX> eats <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">Comice pears</ENAMEX> with aged <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gruyère</ENAMEX>-- c'est 
               savoir
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">faire</ENAMEX> .

            

               <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">04:00 p.m.</TIMEX> 
               Closing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell</ENAMEX>.
            

            

               <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">04:05 p.m.</TIMEX> Speech: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> unveils major new fiscal
policy initiative. (Tape delayed <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">from 10:00 a.m.</TIMEX>)

            

               <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">04:15 p.m.</TIMEX> Complete, in-depth <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G-SPAN</ENAMEX> analysis of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s policy and its probable effect on finance and the economy.

            

               <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">04:17 p.m.</TIMEX> Complete, in-depth analysis of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX>'s new
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WaterPik</ENAMEX> and its probable effect on finance and the economy.

            

               <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">07:30 p.m.</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrea Mitchell</ENAMEX> reads inspirational selections from
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fountainhead</ENAMEX> (prerecorded).

            

               <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">08:00 p.m.</TIMEX> 
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Greenspan</ENAMEX> Personal Phone Call
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Hour</TIMEX> .

            

               <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">09:00 p.m.</TIMEX> 
               Decision <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2006</TIMEX> : <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Will A.G.</ENAMEX> be reappointed to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> when his current <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14 year</TIMEX> term is up? Possible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> for the
presidential race of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> speak out on this pressing issue.

            

               <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10:00 p.m.</TIMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Laffer Riot : Hilarious</ENAMEX> outtakes from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid-1990s</TIMEX> congressional testimony. <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Tonight</TIMEX>'s nutty bloopers: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A.G.</ENAMEX>
coughs for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">several consecutive seconds</TIMEX>, effectively splitting an infinitive;
mistakenly addresses <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate Finance Committee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don Nickles</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Okla.</ENAMEX>, as
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">congressman</ENAMEX>"; projects <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 1.9 percent</NUMEX> GDP growth for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Calendar 1996</TIMEX>.

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11:40 p.m.</TIMEX>

               (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">approx.</NUMEX>) 
               SleepWatch : <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Overnight G-SPAN BedCam</ENAMEX> coverage.
Closed-captioned vital signs. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Satellite</ENAMEX> remotes from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nikkei</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hang Seng</ENAMEX> as
REM events warrant.

         
      
   
