
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s Final  Escape

            

               
                  Slate
                has brought back its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clintometer</ENAMEX>, and once
again, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">skeptics</ENAMEX> are complaining that our estimate of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
political peril is too low. (For the latest update, click .) The new, gutless
conventional wisdom is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s fate is "uncertain." Pundits observe
grimly that he has refused to offer the necessary confession or contrition,
that his impeachment by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> has put him within <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> step of expulsion, and
that the resignation of incoming <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Speaker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Livingston</ENAMEX> over his newly
disclosed adultery has turned up the pressure on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to follow suit. But,
once again, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> are wrong. The threat to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is over. To understand
how he will get out of his latest predicament, consider how he got into it.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Catharsis</ENAMEX>. The chief
reason moderate congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> voted to impeach <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is that he
got cocky after the election. Emboldened by what he perceived as a popular
mandate to end the impeachment inquiry, he infuriated ambivalent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawmakers</ENAMEX> by
refusing to admit that he had lied. He answered the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Judiciary Committee</ENAMEX>'s
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">81</NUMEX> questions with maddening evasions, and in remarks at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX>, when everyone was expecting a definitive apology, he failed to acknowledge
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> lies, as opposed to his private sexual misconduct.

            Many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> decided
to impeach <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to send a message that the law must be obeyed and that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">unrepentant</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> must be punished. "We must draw a line between right and
wrong ... so every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> can see it," said one. Another said he was
voting to impeach because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> was acting as though he were "above the law."
But if delivering that message was the motive for impeachment, then there's no
need to go further and expel <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> from office. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> have joined the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">media</ENAMEX> in portraying his impeachment as a devastating, permanent scar on his
presidency. In so doing, they have vented the outrage against him and have
relieved the pressure to convict him. Already, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> have
stipulated that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> has scarred <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> will never
muster the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">67</NUMEX> votes to convict him, and that a censure deal should be worked
out instead.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Partisanship</ENAMEX>. The next reason <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> was impeached
is that the elections didn't change the congressional math. There were still
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">228</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>, enough to pass <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> articles of impeachment. But
these party-line victories came at a price. The more <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> pushed
impeachment, the more <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> resisted. A <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> congressional aide
admitted that many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> dislike <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, "but the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> have done a
good job at uniting us--and driving us into his arms." And the more tenuous the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">majority</ENAMEX> became, the more they resorted to behavior that was
easily portrayed as partisan. The final straw was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>'
suppression of a resolution of censure. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX> promptly went on the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> talk shows to call the impeachment vote "partisan" and "unfair."

            The "partisanship"
message has destroyed public faith in the legitimacy of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s impeachment.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Nearly two-thirds</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">respondents</ENAMEX> in the latest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> poll say
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> pursued the case for purely partisan reasons. Moreover, by failing to
persuade more than a handful of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> to vote for impeachment, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>
failed to trigger the kind of bipartisan collapse necessary to bring down a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> have gleefully used the party-line <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> vote to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">distinguish Clinton</ENAMEX>'s situation from that of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1974</TIMEX>. And most
important, a partisan split in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> guarantees that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> can survive in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>, where <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> have more than enough votes to save him.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. Backlash. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Pundits</ENAMEX> think another reason for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s impeachment was that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> ignored the polls. Actually, the
polls conveyed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> opposite threats. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> faced a backlash from
many independent and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> if they voted to impeach <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. But
they also faced a backlash from conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> if they voted not to
impeach him. (Several <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultants</ENAMEX> pointed out that the greater
political threat to moderate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> was a primary challenge
from pro-impeachment <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX>.) So the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> played it both ways. They
escaped the first backlash by voting to impeach <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, and they counted on
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> to spare them the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> backlash by refusing to convict him.

            Polls suggest that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s expulsion would shock and infuriate much of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">electorate</ENAMEX>. By
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 26 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">respondents</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> poll expected the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> to remove <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> from office. In the latest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX>
poll, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 33 percent</NUMEX> said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> should remove him, whereas approximately
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">60 percent</NUMEX> said they would be angry or dissatisfied if he were ousted. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> aren't stupid. They know that if they go all the way and depose
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, all hell will break loose on them in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>. In voting to impeach him,
they shot to wound, not to kill. Already, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> who voted for
impeachment have written a letter asking the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> to censure <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> rather
than remove him.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. "Personal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Destruction</ENAMEX>." Realizing that they
couldn't get away with shooting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> fatally, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> sensibly deduced
that the only other way to extinguish him was to make him commit suicide. They
have pursued this strategy in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> ways. The clever, premeditated way was to
push the impeachment process so far forward that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s resignation became
the quickest way out. The bizarre, unpremeditated way was to oust their own
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> and demand that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> take the same <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">exit</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">First</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Speaker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX>
resigned, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> held him up to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> as a model. Then incoming
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Speaker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Livingston</ENAMEX> resigned, declaring, "I must set the example that I hope
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> will follow."

            Both these tactics were ill-advised. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
impeachment makes it less likely than ever that he will resign. The point of
resignation was to escape the humiliation of impeachment. Now that he has been
humiliated, his only hope is to seek redemption in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>.

            Furthermore, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>'s
resignation-by-example argument has backfired. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and congressional
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> have hijacked <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Livingston</ENAMEX>'s resignation and turned it into a moral
argument against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s resignation. "We must stop the politics of
personal destruction," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> declared at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> after the
impeachment vote. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> asked whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> should resign, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Press Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Lockhart</ENAMEX> replied, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">He</ENAMEX> believes it would be wrong to
give in to the politics of personal destruction."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Livingston</ENAMEX>'s resignation has also backfired by diverting
public attention from perjury back to sex. For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defenders</ENAMEX> had
successfully dismissed the scandal as being "just about sex." After the
election, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> squandered this victory by continuing to deny that he had
lied about the affair. The more he lied about his lies, the more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> focused
on his lying and forgot what the original lies were about.

            But since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Livingston</ENAMEX>'s
sins were about sex, not perjury, his assertion that he was setting an
"example" suggested that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> should resign not for lying but for adultery.
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> persuasively called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Livingston</ENAMEX>'s resignation "a surrender to a
developing sexual McCarthyism," portrayed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> as a fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> of this
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCarthyism</ENAMEX>, and argued that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> should be spared expulsion as a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> step
toward ending the madness.

            The "personal destruction" spin is a big winner.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Four-fifths</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">respondents</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> poll disapproved of the current
scrutiny of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>' adultery. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> poll, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">65 percent</NUMEX> said
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> should complete his term rather than resign. Even <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> are
susceptible to this spin. Since they blame <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> for outing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Livingston</ENAMEX>, and
they don't think his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adultery</ENAMEX> should have ended his career, they agreed on the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> talk shows that "personal destruction" has run amok and that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>
shouldn't be judged by their past indiscretions. Both these conclusions play to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s advantage.

            The ultimate perverse
consequence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Livingston</ENAMEX>'s resignation is that it has allowed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to
appear magnanimous. He has joined congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> in urging Livingston
to reconsider his decision. Once upon a time, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> derided <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> for
fantasizing that in order to win forgiveness, he <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> had to find a way to
forgive his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX>. Now they have made that fantasy come true.

            
               Recent "Frame
Games"
            

            

               "": The debate over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> attack blazes new frontiers in cynicism.
(posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 19</TIMEX>)
               

               "": <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Saletan</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> could blow up the impeachment process by
crying "coup." (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 16</TIMEX>)
               

            

         
      
   
