
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Drawing upon her rich experience of life, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> to her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>) responds to questions about manners, personal relations, politics, and
other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX>. Please send your questions for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> to prudence@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Queries
should not exceed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> words in length. Please indicate how you wish your letter
to be signed, preferably including your location.
            

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               I went to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Year</TIMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Eve</TIMEX> party thrown by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>, at her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">loft</ENAMEX>. She's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>, and I'm a
semi-starving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>. At <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the evening</TIMEX> I stood up from her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couch</ENAMEX> and
an end-cushion fell to the floor, knocking a full glass of red <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX> onto her
Persian rug. It was my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">roommate</ENAMEX> (semi-starving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> as well) who had set the
wineglass on the floor. We were both apologetic, and the hostess seems to have
forgiven us but, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) What's the best way to try removing the stain? <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>)
What's the best way for me and my roomie to make amends?
            

            

               --Butterfingers
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Butt</ENAMEX>,

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> is not a dry cleaner. Had we, by some
mysterious mechanism, been in touch the moment after the spill, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> would
have told you something she just happens to know: Pouring white <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX> on red
wine is the antidote. But this only works immediately after the calamity.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> is as up in
the air as you. Do offer to pay for the rug to be cleaned at the finest rug
cleaner you can rustle up. If the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>-hostess declines, then send lovely
<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers</ENAMEX>. If she tells you everything's fine and only a faint hint of color
remains, suggest she tell <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Persian</ENAMEX> weavers were famously big
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">drinkers</ENAMEX>.

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, spotlessly

            
               
                  Dear
Prudie,
               
            

            
               My best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> was
married <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years ago</TIMEX>, and I was his best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>. I was somewhat lazy in procuring
a gift, and in the intervening time my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> has got a divorce and is soon to
be remarried. He tells me that I need to "double up" on his gift. What do you
think is the proper protocol for this situation?
            

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Vagge</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Rich</ENAMEX>,

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> is so busy
sputtering she hopes she can type! Your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>, the groom, is way out of line.
Double up, indeed. Why don't you respond that, in the infinite wisdom of your
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">procrastination</ENAMEX>, you somehow divined the marriage would be a dud, and you think
you will give this one a similar <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two year</TIMEX> trial period?

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, archly

            
               
                  Dear
Prudie,
               
            

            
               I have but one living <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relative</ENAMEX>, a female first
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX>. Her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> has just finished college and
married. During her time in college I contributed <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$40,000</NUMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, most
of it for her tuition. The older of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> is now in college, and the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> will enter in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the fall</TIMEX>. His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> wants me to give him <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50,000</NUMEX> net to
cover a portion of his tuition fee of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$21,000</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annually</TIMEX> by giving him stock to
that amount plus what he estimates will be his tax liability on the gift. It
will amount to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about a third</NUMEX> of my remaining nest <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">egg</ENAMEX> (most went to my
university as a "planned gift," for which I get a quarterly dividend).
            

            
               Recently I bought
insurance (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> premium <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$11,000</NUMEX> plus) that supposedly will pay nursing home
care after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX>' insurance coverage are exhausted. I
am <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">84</TIMEX>, in reasonably good health, and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX> will get the estate after
inheritance taxes. My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> say don't do it, and I am of the same opinion.
What do you think?
            

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Old and Tired of Hassle</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Old</ENAMEX>,

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">beneficiary family</ENAMEX> seems to be proving the old
adage: No good deed goes unpunished. You were most generous to your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>. Prudie imagines the gift was your idea. To be asked for more--and a
particular amount, yet--seems grasping. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> might point out that the group
to which you refer is also not immediate family.

            Security for the rest of
your life certainly comes before anything else. Discussion closed.

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, assuredly

            
               
                  Dear
Prudie,
               
            

            
               I am a single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>, and I frequent a chichi
coffee <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX> near my home. This <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">establishment</ENAMEX> provides <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> bistro tables, which
obviously fill up quickly on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekends</TIMEX>.
            

            
               It is my habit to enjoy my <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX>, pastry, and
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX> when it first opens and to leave as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowds</ENAMEX> begin
to come in. This <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>, as I was poring over my outspread paper, an older
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> came over to me and said, "Would you mind if <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> of us joined you at
this table?" (!) As I silently looked up at her, she demurred. "Or would you
rather read your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>?" I asserted that I would rather, indeed, but added that
I'd soon be packing up.
            

            
               Prudie, I think you
would agree that most of us linger over <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX>, within reason. Lately, though,
a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> has also begun to frequent the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX>, so singles occupy <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> tables. I'm afraid he appears not to be the type I would approach to
suggest sharing a table, though this issue is not under my control, as he comes
in shortly after I do. If you were I, what would be your policy here?
            

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Kick Me</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northwest of Boston</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Kick</ENAMEX>,

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX>'s instinct is
yours: An unknown <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">threesome</ENAMEX> would not be the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> with whom I'd want to share
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> breakfast. As for the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, however, here's what you do. Alter your
time a bit (or hide behind a lamppost), allowing the single gentleman to enter
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>. Then you come in, "notice" he's by himself, and ask if he is inclined to
have you at his table so that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> singles will not occupy <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of the available
tables. If he is welcoming, that means you guessed wrong about his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">approachability</ENAMEX>. If he declines your overture, you will have definitive
information that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coffee Shop Man</ENAMEX> holds no possibilities ... and you can go
back to the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> papers.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, strategically

         
      
   
