
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">159</NUMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mourning</ENAMEX> After"

            

               "After wrapping up his work on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX>'s problems, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> headed home to face his own." That's the caption to a grim front-page
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">photo</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> are invited to submit a
caption sure to appear on the front of any paper <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> after the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> votes
on impeachment.
            

             

             

            by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> to e-mail your answer to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            

               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s question (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 158</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Prereq?</ENAMEX>":
            

            

               Clearance from the vice <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">squad</ENAMEX>, permission from a male <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relative</ENAMEX>, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">university</ENAMEX> degree. Which does not belong? Why?
            

            
"You don't need a university degree to become an e-mail order
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bride</ENAMEX>. At <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cyberbrides</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX>, placing an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon</ENAMEX> order means you'd like a
really tall female as your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouse</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Sullivan</ENAMEX>
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX> degree. The other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> are prerequisites to coach under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tarkanian</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Milner</ENAMEX>
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX> degree. So very nonessential to a happy relationship with a
Spelling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offspring</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer Miller</ENAMEX>
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX> degree. It's the only item that couldn't also serve as the title of
a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">late-night</TIMEX>, soft-core movie on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cinemax</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tonight</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2:30:</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sherilyn Fenn</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rob Estes</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Permission From a Male Relative or Shannon Tweed and</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Hamlin</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Clearance From the Vice Squad</ENAMEX> . Even if you put
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Adrienne Barbeau</ENAMEX> in it, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A University Degree</ENAMEX> just doesn't have the same
ring.)"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Carvell</ENAMEX>
            

            Click
for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more</NUMEX> responses.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
            

            I'm a little uncomfortable with the way the question invites a sense of
cultural superiority. So in lieu of swaggering, I should concede that in my
family we needed permission from my <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Uncle Morty</ENAMEX> to buy a sport shirt. Why waste
money when you have a male <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relative</ENAMEX> in the rag trade? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morty</ENAMEX> made uniform
shirts, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">100 percent</NUMEX> polyester. Put <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> on and feel as comfortable and stylish
as an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ohio Turnpike</ENAMEX> toll-taker. (Acknowledgment: I changed the name of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uncle</ENAMEX> to protect his privacy and exaggerated the fabric for comedic purposes.
It was actually a luxurious <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20/80</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">cotton</ENAMEX>-poly blend.) The point is not simply
to wander aimlessly through <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neil Simon</ENAMEX> country but also to establish that not
so long ago to participate in an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> election you needed to own property,
pass a literacy test, and be a male <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relative</ENAMEX>. Or to put it another way, voting
to recommend impeachment in our advanced <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">democracy</ENAMEX> was that noted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> and
constitutional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholar</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Bono</ENAMEX>. So I'd go easy on the swaggering if I were
me.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Culturally Relative</ENAMEX>
(you know, like slavery) Answer
            

            Permission of a male <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relative</ENAMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Egyptian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> still need it to travel abroad. But as of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this month</TIMEX>, they no
longer need vice <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">squad</ENAMEX> clearance to apply for a passport, previously required
of those without a university degree.

            (On a personal note, had
I known that vice <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">squad</ENAMEX> clearance was a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">B.A.</ENAMEX> equivalent, I'd have planned my
education very differently. And my vices.)

            
               Glossy
Extra
            

             The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publisher</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Emap</ENAMEX>, eager
to expand its young male <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>, announced its purchase of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> magazine
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">giant Petersen Co.</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.5 billion</NUMEX>.

            Which of the following are <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Petersen</ENAMEX> titles?

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. Hot <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rod</ENAMEX>
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rod & Custom</ENAMEX>
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">Guns</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ammo</ENAMEX>
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">Lawn</ENAMEX> and Order
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mountain Bike</ENAMEX>
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Motor Trend</ENAMEX>
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Truck Trend</ENAMEX>
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>. Super Street
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mopar Muscle</ENAMEX>
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corvette Fever</ENAMEX>
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wheeled Penis</ENAMEX>
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Max Speed</ENAMEX>
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13</TIMEX>. Snowboarder
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14</TIMEX>. Skateboarder
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Skin Diver</ENAMEX>
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMX Rider</ENAMEX>
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dirt Rider</ENAMEX>
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sport Rider</ENAMEX>
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trail Rider</ENAMEX>
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Dog</ENAMEX> Jockey
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rock Diver</ENAMEX>
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rifle Shooter</ENAMEX>
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Surf Gourmet</ENAMEX>
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX>. Drunken Bungee
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25</TIMEX>. Sport
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">26</TIMEX>. Slam
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">27</TIMEX>. Blitz
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">28</TIMEX>. Hunting
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">29</TIMEX>. Handguns
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30</TIMEX>. Bowhunting
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">31</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hairy Shirtless</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Gardener</ENAMEX>
            

            

               Answers
            

            All are <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Petersen</ENAMEX>
magazines except <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">4</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11, 20, 21, 23, 24, 31</TIMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Disclaimer</ENAMEX>: All
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">submissions</ENAMEX> will become the property of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> and will be
published at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> 's discretion. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> may
publish your name on its site in connection with your submission.
            

         
      
   
