
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Instant
Slate
               
            

            As part of our continuing efforts to make it easier
and more convenient to print out your favorite 
                  Slate
               
features on (... what is that stuff called again? Oh, yes,) paper, we're
pleased to announce, through a special arrangement with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hewlett-Packard</ENAMEX>, a
nifty--and free--new bit of software from <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">HP</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Instant Delivery</ENAMEX>. It is a
much simpler variation on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">HP's Web PrintSmart</ENAMEX> software described in "" a few
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks ago</TIMEX>. What makes it simpler is that we do most of the work. ("<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">We</ENAMEX>" meaning

                  Slate
               's self-sacrificing software development <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX>,
not the lazy, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pig</ENAMEX>-ignorant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX>, let alone the business <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>.)

            With <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Instant Delivery</ENAMEX>, you can have

                  Slate
               's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" waiting for you at your
printer every <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>. Your computer will automatically dial up (if necessary),
connect to the Web, download <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX> (in a specially formatted edition
for printing out), and send it to your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">printer</ENAMEX>. We plan to make other

                  Slate
                features available this way in the coming
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX>.

            Actually, once you have installed <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">HP Instant</ENAMEX>
Delivery, you can use it to schedule automatic printouts of any page on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX>--including other pages of 
                  Slate
               . But they won't
be formatted for printing out, you'll have to do the scheduling yourself, and
the pages must have unchanging <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">URLs</ENAMEX> (Web addresses). (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">HP</ENAMEX>'s other software,
Print Smart, solves the formatting and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">URL</ENAMEX> problems at the cost of formidable
complexity. But do give that one a try, too, if you're feeling ambitious. My
earlier explains how.

            Go to this special page
of 
                  Slate
                for complete instructions on downloading,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">installing</ENAMEX>, using <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Instant Delivery</ENAMEX>, and a technical support phone number. The
download button will take you to <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">HP</ENAMEX>'s site (in most cases in a separate browser
window), and you'll have to get back to 
                  Slate
                for the
button that schedules <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>. But we know you can handle that. So
please give it a try.

            
               Only the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weak Skip</ENAMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Week</ENAMEX>
            

            Lesser <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> in lesser <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> are known to take a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX> off during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">New Year</TIMEX>. Not so 
                  Slate
               .
We will publish complete issues for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next two weeks</TIMEX>. Well, when we say
"complete" we should add that--strictly for the convenience of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>, you
understand, who will be busy roasting turkeys, fighting with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">etc.</ENAMEX>--the next <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> issues will be just slightly less overloaded than usual with
journalistic riches. And--purely so that you can get some

                  Slate
                reading in before the hordes descend--our staff
will be closing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX>'s issue on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 23</TIMEX>, and the following
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>'s on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 31</TIMEX>. We'll combine those <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> issues for e-mail
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subscribers</ENAMEX> in a special 
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate on Paper</ENAMEX>
               , which will
be e-mailed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 31</TIMEX>. No, don't thank us. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Merry Christmas</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
