
   
   
      
         
             <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Tripp</ENAMEX>'s Payoff

            You give the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> a
blow job and he gives you a soft job: high pay, no qualifications, no heavy
lifting. Right? That's what poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> thought. And the theory of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> impeachment drive is not too different. Although the alleged quid
pro quo was the helping to cover up the sex, rather than the sex itself (and
although <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> never actually enjoyed the alleged payoff), the articles of
impeachment nevertheless assume that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX> is about an exchange of
favors.

            How naive. Anyone who
understands <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bureaucracies</ENAMEX> should know that the way to get a cushy job isn't to
make yourself desirable but to make yourself undesirable. That's why, while
we're suffering through a national crisis over alleged favors to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>, the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who clearly has enjoyed a big payoff--at taxpayer expense--is the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">arch-dragoness</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Tripp</ENAMEX>.

            Tripp was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>, a holdover from
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>. When she began to look like trouble, she was
transferred to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX>. The choice of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> is no surprise.
Although <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> who inveigh against overpaid, do-nothing federal
if your urgent need is a government job in general, rather than anything in
particular that job might accomplish, apparently the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> is your best
shot.

            Besides a military force
of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one and a half million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense Department</ENAMEX> employs <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 800,000</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Tripp</ENAMEX> is one of them, holding the position of public affairs
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">specialist</ENAMEX> with a civil service ranking of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">GS-15</ENAMEX>, Step <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. That puts the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">49-year-old</TIMEX> high-school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grad</ENAMEX> at the top of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX>'s middle management
ranks. Like all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>, she just received an across-the-board-pay
increase. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX>'s raise, including a "locality" adjustment for working in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>, area, was <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3.68 percent</NUMEX>, bringing her salary to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$94,098</NUMEX> a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>.

            For which she does ...? Since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 1998</TIMEX>, nothing. Although
she has supposedly been working at home, she was stripped of her duties--but
not her pay or her title--shortly after the scandal broke. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX> has
characterized this as a politically motivated "demotion." It will strike many
as a demotion devoutly to be wished.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s title
at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> was confidential assistant to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assistant secretary</ENAMEX> for
public affairs. Her job was writing press releases, for which she was paid
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$33,000</NUMEX>. Note that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> got this job as a payoff for being undesirable to a
presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX>, not for being desirable to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>.

            Officially, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX> is the public affairs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">specialist</ENAMEX> for a
program called the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joint Civilian Orientation Conference</ENAMEX>, an arguably
worthwhile <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> propaganda effort that takes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX> civilian "public opinion
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>" on a weeklong tour of military operations. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX> had primary
responsibility for the paperwork involved in the selection process, for making
travel and hotel arrangements, as well as for other logistic odds and ends such
as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX>'s kick-off banquet. According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> , before
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX> took the job, this position was part-time.

            When pressed for more detail, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> now doing
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX>'s job used the word "coordinating" a lot, but that was about it. There
is, it turns out, no official description of the job. Writing one is among the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tasks Tripp</ENAMEX> is being paid to perform now.

            But there are official
descriptions of other GS-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> public affairs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">specialist</ENAMEX> positions. For instance,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Commission on Civil Rights</ENAMEX> is currently looking for someone to "assist
in the reviews and analysis of numerous requests for speeches; to develop,
clear, release, and distribute a wide range of information and data concerning
the nature and objective of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX>'s programs; [and to] prepare press
releases, fact sheets, etc. and arrange press conferences." Translation: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PR</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">grunt</ENAMEX>. Salary: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$80,658 to $104,851</NUMEX>.

            To try to get some sort of independent measure of what
these jobs are worth, I called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kelly Services</ENAMEX>, the nationwide temp <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>.
Without mentioning <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tripp</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX>, I described her job there to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kelly</ENAMEX>. Oh, she said, that's high-end secretarial. How much would you
have to pay somebody to do a job like that, I asked. Oh, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$18 to $25</NUMEX> an hour,
she said. That's <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$36,000 to $50,000</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">roughly half</NUMEX> of what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tripp</ENAMEX> is being
paid not to do it.

            What's more, there is no
evidence of any competitive evaluation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX> before she was offered this
job. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX>, a problem in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> place, was simply moved to another. There's
a name for this personnel technique: It's called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Pass the Trash</ENAMEX>." Federal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilian employees</ENAMEX> who don't commit felonies and don't cuss out their
supervisors pretty much have a guaranteed job with guaranteed wages for life.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX> has spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">26 years</TIMEX> in this cocoon, which will enable her to retire on a
handsome pension, based on the average of her <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> highest consecutive years
of pay.

            Will her job description be done by then? How long could it
take? "She's still working on it," a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX> tells me. What's the
opposite of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stress</ENAMEX>? Where else could you pull down <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">over $90,000</NUMEX> and live such a
deadline-free existence? And have that much free time to gab with your
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">girlfriends</ENAMEX>?

            Not all the time-wasters in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> are
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX>. There are plenty of dead-end <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GIs</ENAMEX> in dead-end jobs, too. But at least
most of them did something important earlier in their careers--and probably
something dangerous, to boot. And <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX>'s pay and retirement benefits are
staggering compared with those of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in those hard jobs now.
Most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> on duty in the skies over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> make <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about half</NUMEX> of what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX> makes. Indeed, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tripp</ENAMEX> pulls down more than all but a handful of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
military's most senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX>. She earns more than a ballistic <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missile</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">submarine commander</ENAMEX> and is on a par with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft carrier</ENAMEX> skippers in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Persian Gulf</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generals</ENAMEX> ready to lead <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> into
combat.

            Imagine what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Barr</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Hyde</ENAMEX> would say if
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX> had got a deal like that.

         
      
   
