
   
   
      
         
             R<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">-E-S-P-E-C</ENAMEX>-T

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Several months ago</TIMEX>, when
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> launched the case for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s impeachment, they
argued that he had committed high crimes worthy of removal from office. Last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>, as it became increasingly obvious that this argument wouldn't persuade <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">67</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> to expel <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>--and might not even persuade <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">51</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> to let
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> be called--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> changed their tune. They began to
argue that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> should call <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> and complete the trial not
necessarily because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> deserved to be removed but because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> owed
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> a full hearing. This marks a new phase in the trial's disintegration.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX>' case is no longer about us. It's about them.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the</ENAMEX>
Press , the chief <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Hyde</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ill.</ENAMEX>, dismissed the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">public</ENAMEX>'s unshaken approval of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> as "something for an abnormal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychologist</ENAMEX> to do a dissertation on." Lauding his "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intrepid colleagues</ENAMEX> who
have marched into the jaws of death," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hyde</ENAMEX> declared, "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> owes us a
trial." Several <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> agreed that "fairness" required the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>
to let the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> "make their case" by calling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX>. On This
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Week</TIMEX> , conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundit</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Kristol</ENAMEX> protested that by "saying that this
trial should be dismissed or saying that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> don't get a chance
to present their case" through <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> would "discredit"
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>'s impeachment vote and make it appear "illegitimate."

            Continuing this line of argument before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lindsey Graham</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">S.C.</ENAMEX>, pleaded, "We haven't had a chance to present our
case, really." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hyde</ENAMEX> followed with a blunt rebuke to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> who were proposing
to dismiss the case: "I looked at this motion to dismiss, and I was astounded,
really. If the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> had sent something similar to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>, it would
certainly have received such treatment as comports with comity. ... I looked in
the thesaurus about 'dismiss' and I came up with 'disregard,' 'ignore,' 'brush
off.' ... We represent the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>, the other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX>, kind of blue-collar <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>,
and we're over here trying to survive with our impeachment articles. ... Let us
finish our job."

            By all accounts, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX>' plea for respect has rallied <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> to their side.
For public consumption, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> have dressed up the respect argument in
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> guises. One is precedent: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Never</ENAMEX> in the history of impeachment in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States Senate</ENAMEX> has a trial been dismissed." The other is equality: "If
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> needed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX>, we would surely oblige them. We
should do no less for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX>."

            But most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> don't care about arcane precedents. They
don't see why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> can't be equally silent rather
than equally thorough. They're not interested in what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> is "owed." They
don't care whether <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> feel "ignored," "brushed off," or
"discredited." In most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX>, the suggestion that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> are
"blue-collar <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>" fighting to "survive" in "the jaws of death" is more
likely to elicit contempt and derision than sympathy.

            Sensing their isolation, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> have
turned inward. They have narrowed their appeals <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>, and then,
in desperation, to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>. Unable to convince even these fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawmakers</ENAMEX> that numerous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> must be interrogated and that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> must be
fully tried for the sake of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> are framing the case
in increasingly personal terms. Look what you're doing to us , they say.
We've risked our careers to prosecute a popular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. Don't abandon us.
Don't humiliate us. Don't repudiate everything we've stood for.

            It's a poignant plea. But it's not the least bit
moral. A prosecution provoked by the self-absorbed neediness of an insecure
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> has degenerated into the self-absorbed neediness of an insecure
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">House.</ENAMEX> How the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> managed to replace <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shrink</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couch</ENAMEX> is a
dissertation topic for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> of abnormal psychology to ponder.

         
      
   
