
   
   
      
         
            

            

               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clintometer</ENAMEX> is back. Click for the latest update.
            

            
The world's
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> surviving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">octuplets</ENAMEX> are in critical but stable condition. They were
born <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three months</TIMEX> premature to a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 20</TIMEX>. The smallest is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ounces</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Doctors</ENAMEX> give them an <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">85 percent</NUMEX> chance of survival. The media swarmed
the story, noting the proliferation of multiple births due to fertility <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>.
The spins: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) It's a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> "miracle." <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) It's a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PR</ENAMEX> bonanza for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">companies</ENAMEX>
that are donating diapers and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> formula. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) It's a technological
breakthrough. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) It's not a miracle or a breakthrough, it's reckless
self-indulgence, because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> will either die or suffer lifelong medical
problems, and society can't afford to spend <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">millions of dollars</NUMEX> on every
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">preemie</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>) If <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> take fertility <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> and develop <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">multiple embryos</ENAMEX>, they
should abort the extra ones. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>) No, abortion is wrong. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>) If a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> won't
abort the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">extras</ENAMEX> (as this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> refused to do on religious grounds), she
shouldn't take the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> to begin with. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">12/23/98</NUMEX>)
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>
sentenced <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX> to a combined <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">36 years</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> for
trying to organize a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic Party</ENAMEX>. The charge is "subverting state
power." These are the latest steps in a crackdown on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX> who have
recently tried to form <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX>, assist pro-democracy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX>, or
run for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> outside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communist Party</ENAMEX>. The spins: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) The trials were a
joke. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s democratic pretensions are a joke. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> has violated the
treaties it has signed on free speech and political rights. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> policy
of fostering <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> political reform through trade is a joke. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>) Don't worry,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s economic liberalization will eventually lead to political
liberalization. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>) Don't worry, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> simultaneously released another dissident
into exile and allowed a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> balloon to fly over its territory. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>)
Whoop-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">de</ENAMEX>-doo. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">12/23/98</NUMEX>)
            

            
 <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Right-wingers</ENAMEX> abandoned him, saying he had sold out <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> security by signing
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wye</ENAMEX> peace agreement. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Centrists</ENAMEX> abandoned him, saying he had sabotaged the
agreement. He agreed to hold new elections <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next spring</TIMEX>. The spins: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX>
is finished. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) That's what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits foolishly</ENAMEX> said last time. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">left-leaning Labor Party</ENAMEX> can't win because it is considered too soft on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Carville</ENAMEX>, who is advising the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor Party</ENAMEX>, will fix
that. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>) A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">centrist general</ENAMEX> known as the "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Colin Powell</ENAMEX>" will win. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> politics will fragment, nobody will win, and tiny fringe <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> will
be able to blackmail the next <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, just as they blackmailed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>) The election is good for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli-Palestinian</ENAMEX> peace because it will get rid
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX>'s obstructionism. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>) It's bad for peace because it will delay
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> implementation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wye</ENAMEX> agreement and trigger <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> violence.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX> will win re-election by campaigning against the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palestinian</ENAMEX>
violence. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">12/23/98</NUMEX>)
            

            
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">impeached</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Article 1</ENAMEX> (perjury before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">grand jury</ENAMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">passed 228-206</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Article 3</ENAMEX> (obstruction of justice) passed <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">221-212, Article 2</ENAMEX>
(perjury in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> deposition) failed <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">229-205, and Article 4</ENAMEX> (abuse of
power) failed <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">285-148</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> voted for <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Article 1</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>
voted against it, but the media largely agreed with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> that it was a
party-line vote. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> tried to bring up a censure resolution, but
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> ruled that it wasn't germane. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> temporarily walked out to
protest the "unfairness" of the proceedings and later staged a rally at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> to show their support of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, in deliberate contrast to the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1974</TIMEX> visit to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> who told <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>
they couldn't save him. The sunny spin: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">moderates</ENAMEX> are ready to end this
mess if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> will just confess to lying and sign a censure deal. The cynical
spin: That's what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">moderates</ENAMEX> were ready to do <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month ago</TIMEX>.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">12/21/98</NUMEX>)
            

            

               Incoming
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Speaker</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Livingston</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">R-La.</ENAMEX>, is resigning. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>,amid
reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hustler</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> was preparing to expose his extramarital
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">affairs</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Livingston</ENAMEX> confessed that he had strayed from his marriage "on
occasion." On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>, he shocked his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> by announcing during the
impeachment debate that he would not assume the speakership and would instead
resign from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>. He said he was setting an example for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>,
whom he urged to resign as well. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> extolled <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Livingston</ENAMEX>'s courage,
lamented the loss of a great statesman, and blamed the ouster on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>
dirty tricks. The resignation was also provoked by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> angry at
Livingston for failing to disclose his infidelities when he ran for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>, too, lamented his downfall, even as they milked it to illustrate why
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> shouldn't be made the next <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> of the "politics of personal
destruction." <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> plan to name <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dennis Hastert</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ill.</ENAMEX>, as the new
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX>. The official spin: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastert</ENAMEX> is too clean to have committed adultery.
The unofficial spin: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastert</ENAMEX> is too boring to have committed adultery.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">12/21/98</NUMEX>)
            

            
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> halted the bombing of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> . There were no <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> or
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">casualties</ENAMEX> and minimal <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilian casualties</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> claim
to have set back <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>'s missile program by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>. They say the new <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> policy
is to contain and deter <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> programs (possibly through periodic
military strikes), maintain economic sanctions, and foster <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> opposition
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> in the hope of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">deposing</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> government spin: We're
protecting the world and backing diplomacy with necessary force. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">criticisms: 1</ENAMEX>) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> weapons inspections are dead. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> opposition
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> are a joke. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) The bombing wasn't as effective as military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesmen</ENAMEX> say
it was. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> lacked the stamina to finish the bombing. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>) If we
lack the stamina for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four days</TIMEX> of bombing, how will we find the stamina for the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> of work it will take to topple <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Saddam</ENAMEX>? (For more on international
reactions to the bombings, see "" in 
                  Slate
               .)
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">12/21/98</NUMEX>)
            

         
      
   
