
   
   
      
         
            The "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Coup</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bomb</ENAMEX>

            By all
accounts, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House of Representatives</ENAMEX> is about to impeach <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>.
For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past year</TIMEX>, he and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">surrogates</ENAMEX> have deployed nearly every argument to
halt this process. They have won over the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>, according to polls, but they
haven't persuaded enough <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">majority</ENAMEX>. The
swing votes in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> are turning against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, pushing him to the brink
of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> trial. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapon</ENAMEX> of last resort in his rhetorical
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">arsenal</ENAMEX>. He can accuse the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> of staging a "coup."

            Going into the
impeachment vote, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>' message is that they're putting principle
above politics. "A thermometer is not a terribly useful thing on matters of
conscience and matters of principle," argued <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Judiciary Committee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Hyde</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ill.</ENAMEX>, on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> . And what is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>'s principle?
"We <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">congressmen</ENAMEX> were sent there to protect our <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX>, protect our rule
of law," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hyde</ENAMEX>. "And if we ignore that because it isn't popular, then I
think we do real damage to our form of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. ... The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> means
something. The rule of law means something. We're a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> of laws and not
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>."

            Moreover, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> hold out hope that they can
parlay these principles into good politics by persuading the public that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s actions merit impeachment. "It has been my hope that as this process
plays itself out--the hearings and the debate and the argument--that this would
have an instructive effect on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, and they might begin to pay
attention as to why this is very serious, what this is all about, namely
protecting the rule of law, and change their opinion," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hyde</ENAMEX> explained. "So we
have to frame the issue as to whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> want to tolerate
[perjury] in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief executive</ENAMEX>--the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who is sworn under <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">the Constitution</ENAMEX>
to take care that the laws are faithfully executed."

            The coup argument
reverses this logic. It parlays good politics into principle, by framing the
ouster of a politically popular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> as an affront to democracy, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Constitution</ENAMEX>, and the rule of law. It combines <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> points <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and his
surrogates have been making for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> opposes
impeachment. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX> elections were generally interpreted, rightly or
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">wrongly</ENAMEX>, as a popular verdict against impeachment, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s New York
Times and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> polls underscore the same pattern.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Sixty-four</NUMEX> percent of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> approve of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s job performance, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX>
percent don't want him removed from office, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">64 percent</NUMEX> don't want their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX> to vote for impeachment, and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">59 percent</NUMEX> favor a censure
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resolution</ENAMEX>, which <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> refuse to let the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> vote on.

            The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> point is that the impeachment juggernaut has
been driven exclusively by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>. Not a single <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> voted for any of the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> impeachment articles approved by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Judiciary Committee</ENAMEX>, and only a
handful of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> are expected to vote for impeachment on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> floor.
In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> poll, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">62 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> voted for
impeachment not on the merits but mostly to hurt <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>. In
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> poll, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two-thirds</NUMEX> said most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> would cast their
impeachment votes based on "partisan politics" rather than "the facts of the
case."

            The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> point is that
many of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">legislators</ENAMEX> who will vote on impeachment are "<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">lame ducks</ENAMEX>." Some
were voted out of office in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX>. Others didn't seek re-election. The new
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> chosen by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> will have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> fewer <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>. But the old
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, including the old <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>, will decide whether to impeach the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>.

            As impeachment draws <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">nearer</NUMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> and
congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> have been escalating their rhetoric along these lines.
They have accused <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> of trying to "defy the will of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>,"
"overturn the votes of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>," and "undo the last election."
"It's a sad day for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> when extreme elements of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> seek to impeach
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> on a party-line vote in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lame</ENAMEX>-duck <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>
Special <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Counsel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg Craig</ENAMEX> declared <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>. "Nothing about this process has
been fair. Nothing about this process has been bipartisan. Nothing about this
process has won the confidence of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>."

            The escalation culminated in an assertion by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Judiciary Committee</ENAMEX>'s ranking <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Conyers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mich.</ENAMEX>, that the
impeachment process "does sometimes, to some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, begin to take on the
appearance of a coup." In that explosive word, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>' <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> criticisms
of the process--unpopularity, partisanship, and the participation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawmakers</ENAMEX>
who lost their seats in the election--combined with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">thermonuclear</ENAMEX> reaction. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> reacted with anger. "This is the orderly
process of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX>, not <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX>," said <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">committee</ENAMEX>. "Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> of very similar views to Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>," said
another, "so there's not going to be an abrupt change in the policies that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> advances."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> have
reason to worry. Imagine the uproar when televisions across the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> show
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> rising on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> floor, in a thundering crescendo, to
denounce the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> "coup" against the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. Imagine the barrage of
video clips on the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nightly</TIMEX> news showing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hyde</ENAMEX>, and other figures in the
drama being hounded by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> as to whether a "coup" is in progress. Yes,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> can rebut this charge. But the charge is easy to understand, whereas
the rebuttals are subtle, complicated, and technical. It's too bad <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>
have spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past year</TIMEX> mocking legal distinctions. That's all they'll have
left when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX> goes off.

            
               Recent "Frame
Games"
            

            

               "": <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX> share the same bag of
tricks. (
                  posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 2</TIMEX>)
               

               "": Was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s decision to call off the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> attack cowardly or
courageous? (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday, Nov. 18, 1998</TIMEX>)
               

            

         
      
   
