
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Trustbusters Have
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Job Security</ENAMEX>
            

            The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 14</TIMEX> edition of "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" notes a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> report that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boies</ENAMEX>, the lead <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> case, has lowered
the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hourly</TIMEX> fee that he is charging the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. The column asks whether this
is legal, if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boies</ENAMEX>' motive was to keep his share of the work.

            The
answer can be found in the definitive rhyming opus on antitrust law, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">R.W.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grant</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Smith</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">His Incredible Bread Machine :</ENAMEX>

            You're
gouging on your prices if
You charge more than the rest.
But it's unfair competition
If you think you can charge less!
A <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> point that we would make
To help avoid confusion
Don't try to charge the same amount!
That would be collusion!

            In short, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boies</ENAMEX>'
reduction of his fee constitutes unfair competition. Of course, if he'd left
his fee unchanged, that would be collusion, though in this case he'd be
colluding with himself and would eventually go blind.

            How's that for legal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">clarity</ENAMEX>?

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Kazman</ENAMEX>
               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bork</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Mindy</ENAMEX>
            

            Are there <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Borks</ENAMEX>, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX>
writes in "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"</ENAMEX>? But not just on antitrust. We have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Borks</ENAMEX> for probably any
subject. Give the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> a retainer or the proper ideological cause and he readily
will tailor his views to the needs of the moment.

            I interviewed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bork</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several years ago</TIMEX> for my book
The Wars of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX> . His role in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX> affair has, in all
fairness, been badly distorted. Never mind. In our conversation, he spoke very
forcefully against the special <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX> (now independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX>) statute.
"You cannot bag a case in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX>," he told me. "Too many
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>, who like to talk to too many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX>." He was absolutely right, of
course.

            Fast forward to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> and beyond. An independent
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> to investigate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>? Of course. And "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Judge</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>
to conduct the investigation? Of course, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bork</ENAMEX>, who appears as a regular
cast <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> in those situation comedies that pass as "talk shows" <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">every night</TIMEX>,
vigorously extolling the virtues and honesty of "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Judge</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kinsley</ENAMEX> comes close to
the real reason for rejecting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bork</ENAMEX> for a seat on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> has
the intellectual honesty of a hired <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX>. Which he has truly become.

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanley I. Kutler</ENAMEX>
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Wisconsin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madison</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wis.</ENAMEX>

            
               First, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">We Kill All</ENAMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lawyers</ENAMEX>
            

            I'm sure <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Book Bork</ENAMEX>, Browser
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bork"</ENAMEX> is right to say that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Bork</ENAMEX>'s current posture on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>
antitrust case represents a departure from his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20-year-old</TIMEX> book on antitrust
law.

            But since when is a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> expected to actually possess the views he espouses on behalf of his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>? If the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kinsley</ENAMEX> Doctrine is that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX> can only select a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> who
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">honestly</ENAMEX> believes in the legal arguments of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">client</ENAMEX>, then <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>
wouldn't have any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>.

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Little</ENAMEX>
               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Memphis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tenn.</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Perjury Is Bad</ENAMEX>,
Smearing Is Worse
            

            Just a quick point on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Plotz</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dispatch</ENAMEX> " from the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 9</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Judiciary Committee</ENAMEX>
hearing.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Plotz</ENAMEX> writes, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Yesterday</ENAMEX> I called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lindsey Graham</ENAMEX>,
R-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">S.C.</ENAMEX>, 'admirable.' I apologize. ... <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Graham</ENAMEX> reveals himself,
and he does it in such a calculating way that I wonder whether everything he
has done till now has been pure performance. As the final <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX> on the final
day of hearings, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Graham</ENAMEX> unleashes a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">15 minute</TIMEX> harangue about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clintonian</ENAMEX> evil.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s true crime is not perjury or adultery, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Graham</ENAMEX> shouts, it's that he
planned to destroy <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>."

            Isn't the most reprehensible aspect of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
conduct from a moral point of view the fact that he either orchestrated or
knowingly permitted the resources of his position and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> to be used in an
attempt to destroy the reputations of those who have accused him of
misdeeds?

            The story of the sexual activity is disturbing,
given the power imbalances between the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX>, but the story is a tawdry
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, and most well-mannered <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would just as soon not have to hear about
it, especially since the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX>" is not making any complaint.

            The lying can be viewed as a natural human failing,
which most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, it appears, are ready to forgive.

            Lying under oath is a more serious matter, but it is
more serious for institutional reasons rather than purely moral ones. As the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of state and a living symbol of a system, which, in the name of justice,
imposes laws upon and claims the right to exercise coercive power over all
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> has a special duty--higher than that of an ordinary
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">citizen</ENAMEX>--to abide by the rules that the system imposes. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the most
important rules for the whole justice system is the penalty against perjury. It
is only right that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> should take that issue seriously.

            But from a purely moral
point of view, is it not utterly despicable for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> to use the power of his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> to destroy the reputation of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> for
the sole purpose of ensuring that that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> will not be believed when she
tells the truth? Such conduct may not be a "high crime or misdemeanor." It may
not even be illegal. But it is surely a moral abuse of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">powers</ENAMEX> of the
presidency that should not go unnoticed.

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth J. Tyler</ENAMEX>
               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vancouver</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">British Columbia</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Jocks</ENAMEX> of the
World, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Unite</ENAMEX>! You <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Have Nothing To Lose but Your Scholarships</ENAMEX>!
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Naughton</ENAMEX>'s "" has missed the forest for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX>. He complains that a few powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> are aligning themselves to take
a larger slice of the revenues generated by big-time college athletics and
bemoans the small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX> whose athletic programs will be destroyed by
this.

            What <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Naughton</ENAMEX> has missed is that the entire <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NCAA</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">system</ENAMEX> is corrupt, making <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">millions of dollars</NUMEX> off student <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">athletes</ENAMEX> who can't
even accept plane fare from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alumni</ENAMEX> to visit <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>.

            That's the real travesty
of college sports. Arguing which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> should keep the huge revenues
generated by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">athletes</ENAMEX> really misses the point.

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony Lapadula</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Redmond</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wash.</ENAMEX>

            
               Address your
e-mail to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> to letters@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. You must include your address and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX>
phone number (for confirmation only).
            

         
      
   
