
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">189</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">&quot;Slogan's Run&quot</ENAMEX>;

            

               The slogan "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Feed the rush</ENAMEX>" is being replaced with "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Life</ENAMEX>'s a scream."
Why?
            

             

            by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> to e-mail your answer to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            

               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s question (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 188</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Two Bad":</ENAMEX>
            

            

               
                  
                     
                        
                           
                              <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Starbucks</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Inc.</ENAMEX> are
teaming up. To do
what?
                           
                        
                     
                  
               
            

            "Put
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to sleep and wake them up."--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judith Spencer</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilde</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Krause</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GC</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Charles Star</ENAMEX> had similar
answers.)

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Battle</ENAMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alliance</ENAMEX> formed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lipton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> ."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nell Scovell</ENAMEX>
            

            "Induce
another heart attack in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry King</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg Diamond</ENAMEX>
            

            
"Develop a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> to be written and published by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Guatemalan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peasants</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>
cents a day."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg Narver</ENAMEX>
            

            "Pour
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX> into <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Hitchens</ENAMEX> until he's sober enough to finish his cover
story, 'Friendship.' "-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Vance</ENAMEX> (similarly, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Radosh</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg Diamond</ENAMEX> )

            Click
for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more</NUMEX> responses.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
            

            A former <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX>,
after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years</TIMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">segment producer</ENAMEX> on the old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Letterman</ENAMEX> show, took over a
magazine called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Smoker</ENAMEX> . Or perhaps it was called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Philip</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>. Either way, it was his editorial policy that the essential
thing about smoking was not selling a toxic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">product</ENAMEX> that kills <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half a million</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>; it was freedom of choice. He was always in the market for
photographs of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrities</ENAMEX> smoking, kind of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Flynt</ENAMEX> of respiratory
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX>. It is impressive that such a warm and amiable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fellow</ENAMEX>--and he
was--could be so profoundly wrong at least twice. However, if the partnership
under discussion produces a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coffee-Time</ENAMEX> that's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> as
engaging as American Smoker , I'm subscribing.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fresh Roasted</ENAMEX>
Answer
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This summer</TIMEX> the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> will launch
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX> , a cultural review to be sold in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Starbucks</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX> 's
subhead: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Life is Interesting</ENAMEX>. Discuss."

            "It's going to be a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cultural</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>, but not in the gray sense, not in the review sense." says
Managing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Editor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott Mowbray</ENAMEX>. "Not in the lots of big words sense, not in the
complicated ideas that make your head hurt sense, not in the having to think
about stuff so hard that it distracts you from shopping and later that night
you have that little sexual problem again, not me personally but some other
stupider <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> sense," he didn't add.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dog and Movie Show</ENAMEX>
Extra
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yesterday</TIMEX> brought the
nominations for the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">71 st Academy Awards</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">winners</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">123 rd Westminster Kennel Club Dog Show</ENAMEX>. A comparison.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dogs : Bit O Gold Titan Treasure</ENAMEX>,
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gordon Setter</ENAMEX>, won the sporting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> for an unprecedented <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> consecutive
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>. Movies : <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meryl Streep</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">One True Thing</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">nominated</ENAMEX> as best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX> for an unprecedented <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">107</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th</ENAMEX> consecutive
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>.

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Dogs</ENAMEX> : <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Windwalker</ENAMEX>'s Yes, best in
the herding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>, did not make self-serving speech invoking the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX>.
Movies : <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Spielberg</ENAMEX>, nominated for best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>, did not
bite any of the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>.

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dogs : Best in show</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kirby</ENAMEX>,
weighs <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">75 pounds</NUMEX>. Movies : Best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress nominee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gwyneth</ENAMEX>
Paltrow, same thing.

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Dogs</ENAMEX> : <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judges</ENAMEX> say That's <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">My Boy</ENAMEX>,
the best of nonsporting group <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX>, "exudes poodley-ness."
Movies : <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Geoffrey Rush</ENAMEX>, same thing.

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dogs : Sunspryte's Just in Thyme</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX> of the terrier <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>, is owned by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Cosby</ENAMEX>. Movies :
Complicated deal forces best supporting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor nominee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Billy Bob Thornton</ENAMEX> to do
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cosby</ENAMEX>'s yard work.

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dogs : Deep River Joy Ride</ENAMEX>, best
in breed among smooth collies, not even considered for the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Thalberg Award</ENAMEX>.
Movies : <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman Jewison</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Thalberg Award</ENAMEX>, unwilling to
compete as a collie.

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dogs : Sundown Alabaster Treasure</ENAMEX>,
a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saluki</ENAMEX>, was an enormously popular choice for best in hound <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>.
Movies : <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elia Kazan</ENAMEX>, an informer, was an enormously unpopular
choice for an honorary <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Oscar</ENAMEX>.

            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Disclaimer</ENAMEX>: All
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">submissions</ENAMEX> will become the property of 
               
                  Slate
               

               and will be published at 
               
                  Slate
               
               's
discretion. 
               
                  Slate
                
               may publish your name on its
site in connection with your submission .

         
      
   
