
   
   
      
         
             <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense</ENAMEX>

            There he goes again.
According to "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">associates</ENAMEX>" interviewed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ,
Independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Counsel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX> has been "actively considering" an indictment
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is still in office. The story, published
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>, surfaces at a typically inopportune moment. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> is preparing to
vote by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 12</TIMEX> on whether to remove <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> from office. Assuming that vote
fails, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> will evidently consider whether to censure <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> or to
approve "findings of fact" that he lied under oath and interfered with the
judicial system. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s reappearance is just what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> needed to escape
punishment entirely.

            The leak is clearly an
inside job. According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">associates</ENAMEX>," with whom he
"speaks frequently" and "has discussed" the issue directly, have been
researching the issue and discussing it with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> during the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> trial.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> deny leaking the story. The most charitable theory is
that it came from the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX>" inside <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> who,
according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , believe <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> should seek the indictments. But
by signaling that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> might prosecute <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX>, the disclosure
from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> protects <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. It supplies an alternative villain. Ever since
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Carville</ENAMEX> declared "war" <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year ago</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> strategy has been to
divert scrutiny to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX>, and other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. In the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past six months</TIMEX>, the media and key congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> have turned on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> twice, first when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> disappeared from the scene in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX>, and
again when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> disappeared in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX>. By leaving <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> alone onstage,
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX> forced <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> and the press to confront his shameful conduct.

            Now, just as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>
approaches its verdict on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s misdeeds, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">associates</ENAMEX>" have shoved
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> back onstage, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> are turning the spotlight on him. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Kendall</ENAMEX> is calling for an investigation, claiming that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> "has
once again engaged in illegal and partisan leaking." <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Hours</TIMEX> after the
Times story was released, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Schumer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.Y.</ENAMEX>, declared on
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> , "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Starr</ENAMEX> is once again running amok." On This
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Week</TIMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Durbin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ill.</ENAMEX>, likened <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> to the obsessed,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">wrongheaded</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigator</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">The Fugitive</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> groaned at
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s gaffe, citing it as further evidence that the independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> law
should be scrapped. The discussion of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s indiscretion supplanted the
discussion of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. It antagonizes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> were already angry at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> for going to court to force <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> to submit to yet another deposition, which she did for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>. These <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> complained that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> was interfering with
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>'s management of the trial. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX> lost no time turning
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> report into another cause for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> outrage. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> is
tampering with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> trial," <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Kennedy</ENAMEX> told the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> Times <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>. "Somebody ought to tell [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>] he's
not the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">101</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">st senator</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> agreed. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>
on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Face the Nation</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carl Levin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mich</ENAMEX>, grumbled that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> "or
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> are trying to impact this trial. They've tried to impact
it before in a number of ways, wrongfully, irresponsibly." The suspicion that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> is scheming to make the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> punish <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> provides a convenient
rationalization for doing the opposite.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. It relieves
pressure to punish <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defenders</ENAMEX> have
argued for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> need not punish him because he can be
punished instead by an ordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> after he leaves <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s gaffe confirms this argument, freeing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> to vote not only against
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s removal but against censure as well. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>'s television shows,
several moderate <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> cited the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX>
story as evidence that, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Lieberman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Conn.</ENAMEX>, put it, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> "can
be subject to the rule of law, regardless of what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> does. ... A
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX> is still free to subject him to the normal criminal law, and it
sounds like Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> is getting closer to doing just that." On <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Face the</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nation</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Asa Hutchinson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ark.</ENAMEX>, observed with disgust
that the disclosure from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> played into the hands of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> who
say "there's no sense impeaching [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>] because he can be held accountable
when he leaves <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. It gives <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> a reason to oppose findings of
fact. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> have been floating a proposal under which the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>, rather than voting to remove <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> from office, would approve a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resolution</ENAMEX> affirming that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> lied under oath and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tampered</ENAMEX> improperly with
the judicial system. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> have indicated they might support such a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resolution</ENAMEX>, depending on its language. But the specter of a criminal indictment
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> stirs up suspicion among <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> that these findings of fact might
help <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr prosecute Clinton</ENAMEX> on charges of perjury and obstruction of justice.
This suspicion may be a delusion or a self-delusion, but it nevertheless
provides an excuse to vote against the resolution.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. It pits <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>
against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX> portraying <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s treacherous abuser. They scheduled her deposition for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, hoping
she would contradict <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s testimony and convince <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> that he had
committed perjury and obstructed justice. Instead, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunday Times</ENAMEX>
story resurrected the notion that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>, not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, posed the chief threat to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> had already forced her to testify for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> by
invoking her immunity agreement, thereby implicitly threatening her with
prosecution. Now he seemed to be threatening <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">prosecution</ENAMEX> as well.
Where would he stop?

            The resulting deposition seems legally and politically
counterproductive. According to leaks that appear to have come from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">sympathizers, 1</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed Bryant</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tenn.</ENAMEX>, tried to interrogate
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> about "details of her sexual encounters" with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> but was ruled
out of order; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Rogan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX>, told <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>
she could be compelled to testify again; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> asked her no
questions and instead apologized on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s behalf. Reports indicate that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> thanked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> for the apology and that she responded
carefully and unhelpfully to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bryant</ENAMEX>'s questions, lest she contradict her
previous testimony and get herself into more trouble with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>.

            For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than a year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s surrogates have
been calling <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> an "out-of-control" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX>. To their good fortune, he's
proving them right.

         
      
   
