
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Tries His Hand</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journalism</ENAMEX>

            Despite the return of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>, whose photograph in a baseball cap competed with that of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pope</ENAMEX> in a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> sombrero for front-page display around the world, the main story across
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> was the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Olympics</ENAMEX> corruption scandal. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX>, where
the subject is particularly sensitive because of the doubtful means by which
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sydney</ENAMEX> won the right to host the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Olympic Games</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sydney Morning Herald</ENAMEX> and the
Age of
Melbourne both used editorials to call for full exposure of the truth.

            "The more closely
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sydney</ENAMEX>'s campaign to win the right to host the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Olympics</ENAMEX> is examined, the
more unpleasant it looks," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herald</ENAMEX> said. "That is no reason, though,
to try to hide or avoid facing a full examination of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Sydney</ENAMEX> bid. On the
contrary, the sooner the air is cleared the better. The <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Games</ENAMEX> themselves must
be able to proceed unclouded by unresolved scandal." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> added that
however dismaying it was to discover that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sydney</ENAMEX> might not have won the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>
Olympics on merit alone, the task now was clear: "All details in relation to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Sydney</ENAMEX> bid should be disclosed. This disclosure should be part of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sydney</ENAMEX>'s
commitment to the full reform of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IOC</ENAMEX> itself, so that it becomes a modern
organisation designed to be open and accountable, not the cosy,
corruption-prone 'family' it has been."

            In an editorial titled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Honesty</ENAMEX> is still the best policy," the
Age deplored the efforts of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Australian Olympic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> to keep details
of their <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Olympic</ENAMEX> bid secret and said that the principal issue is one of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">transparency</ENAMEX>. While it is entirely appropriate that international <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">delegates</ENAMEX>
should be treated to a high standard of accommodation and dining and receive
some token gifts, it said, "the test, surely, is whether those giving or
receiving the gifts would want it publicly known." It added, "The possibility
that it might become public is a great deterrent to bribery, which is why the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">media</ENAMEX>, often criticised for its 'let's catch them doing something wrong'
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mentality</ENAMEX>, is so essential."

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asahi</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shimbun</ENAMEX> said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Salt Lake City</ENAMEX> investigation seems to only
scratch the surface of corruption in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Olympic Committee</ENAMEX>.
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Revelations</ENAMEX> that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">more than 10 percent</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IOC</ENAMEX> is corrupt is truly
disappointing, but the number probably does not stop there." It went on, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">With</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sydney</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nagano</ENAMEX> also under suspicion, there seems to be no light at the end
of the corruption <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tunnel</ENAMEX>." In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Financial Times</ENAMEX> called <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> in its main editorial
for "radical reform" of the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Olympic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">system</ENAMEX>, because "if the public ever
came to doubt how the medals were awarded, the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Games</ENAMEX> would be deservedly
finished."

            The FT said that
calls for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IOC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juan Antonio Samaranch</ENAMEX> are "surely
justified" and went on to propose that the choice of the host <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> should in
future be entrusted to "professional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultants</ENAMEX>." It said, "Let a reputable
firm draw up a short list based on published findings. ... Then let a small
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group of IOC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> make their choice on equally public grounds." The
Times of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> ran an <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> column, front-page headline "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betrayal</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Olympic Ideal</ENAMEX>"
above photographs of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IOC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> who have resigned or been
expelled.

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>, a Gallup poll published <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ma'ariv</ENAMEX>
showed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor Party</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ehud Barak</ENAMEX> as the favorite to be <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>'s next prime
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX>. In the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> round of voting, the poll predicted the following
results: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barak</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">34 percent</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin Netanyahu</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">33 percent</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yitzhak Mordechai</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX>
percent, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benny Begin</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">7 percent</NUMEX>, and "Don't Know" <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">6 percent</NUMEX>. In a runoff, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barak</ENAMEX>
would defeat <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX> by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">47 percent to 43 percent</NUMEX>, with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX> undecided.
And if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mordechai</ENAMEX> were the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contender</ENAMEX> in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> round, he would defeat
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX> by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">49 percent to 37 percent</NUMEX>, with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">14 percent</NUMEX> undecided.

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX>
turned his hand to journalism for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time with a bylined article in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Al-Jumhuriya</ENAMEX> blaming <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuwait</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi Arabia</ENAMEX> for all the
predicaments of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> world. In his article, published shortly before the
start of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 24</TIMEX> meeting of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ministers</ENAMEX>, he charged the Saudis
with granting the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> a monopoly of the production and marketing of
their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s crude oil. But <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gomhoureya</ENAMEX> commented that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX> should blame himself for wasting <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>'s oil wealth on devastating wars,
instead of using it to build an advanced society.

            Meanwhile, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX>'s semi-official <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al Ahram</ENAMEX> daily lashed out
at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madeleine Albright</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> who, "though up to his neck in his
impeachment trial, has once again affirmed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s resolve to have the ruling
regime in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baghdad</ENAMEX> removed. ... No longer does the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Power</ENAMEX>, care if
it is charged with interfering in the domestic affairs of other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>; no
longer does it care if it violates the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Charter of the United Nations</ENAMEX>." It
concluded, "A new <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> policy is now at work where international legality is
flagrantly compromised, and where illegitimate methods are used to achieve the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s goals."

            In an editorial on the
impeachment trial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Financial Times</ENAMEX> said that the case should
not be dismissed but that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> should now vote on the articles of
impeachment without calling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX>. "If the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> use their majority
to drag the trial on, they will inflict further political damage on themselves,
regardless of any damage they hope to do to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>," it explained.

             

         
      
   
