
   
   
      
         
            Opening Arguments

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This weekend</TIMEX>, various
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> appeared on television to explain why <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> should or should not
testify at <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s trial. Not surprisingly, every way in which the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> frame the question leads to calling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX>, and every way in
which the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> frame the question leads to not calling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> want to
focus attention on the facts of the case, which are strong. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> want to
divert attention to the significance of the case, which is weak. So <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>
want <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> don't. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> also want to focus scrutiny on
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defendant</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>), whereas <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> want to shift scrutiny to the
prosecution (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>). Finally, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> want to underscore the constitutional
costs of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s conviction, while <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> want to underscore the social
costs of his acquittal. Here is a taxonomy of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>'s frames and
strategies, taken from a debate among <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the</ENAMEX>
Press .

             

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. Sex. This is the simplest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic</ENAMEX>
frame. Its purpose is to keep <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> out. The argument is that they will
talk about sex, besmirch the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>, and offend the viewing public. Example: "I
don't understand why the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> feels they have to sully the floor of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">States Senate</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara Boxer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX>).

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. Rule of
Law. This is the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> rebuttal to the "sex" frame. Its purposes
are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) to get <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> into the trial by arguing that the real subject of
testimony is perjury and obstruction, not sex; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) to shift the burden to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defenders</ENAMEX> by warning that his acquittal would send the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> a
corrosive message. Example: "You can certainly argue ... that someone who
breaks the law in not upholding and not telling the truth under oath and
someone who obstructs justice does, in fact, threaten the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">republic</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick</ENAMEX>
Santorum, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pa.</ENAMEX>).

             

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Summary Judgment</ENAMEX>. This is the basic
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> rebuttal to the "rule of law" frame. Its purposes are to shortcut
the trial, change the subject from the facts of the case to their
insignificance, and shift the burden back to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">accusers</ENAMEX>. The argument
is that even if all the facts are granted, they don't "rise to the level" that
would justify his removal. Example: "We're willing to accept the facts, because
the threshold question is this: Even if it's all true exactly as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> have put it forward, does this rise to the level of impeachment? Does
it rise to the level of high crimes and misdemeanors? That's the threshold
question" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boxer</ENAMEX>).

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Censure</ENAMEX>. This is the advanced rebuttal to the "rule of law" frame. Its
purpose is to fast-forward past the verdict to the sentence, with an emphasis
on mitigating circumstances. The argument is that a resolution censuring
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is sufficient to reaffirm the laws against perjury and obstruction of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice</ENAMEX>. Example: "I came to the conclusion that the appropriate punishment for
this kind of wrongdoing, lying about an extramarital relationship, was censure.
... Part of the rule of law is that the punishment should fit the crime" (Sen.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Schumer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.Y.</ENAMEX>).

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Constitutional Duty</ENAMEX>. This is the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> response to the "censure" frame. Its purpose is to abort the censure
movement before the censure movement aborts the trial. The argument is that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> authorizes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> to vote only on conviction, not on censure.
Example: "I don't think our business is to tell the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> he has to ...
make some magical act of contrition. ... Our job is defined very clearly in the
Constitution" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike DeWine</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX>).

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. Constitutional
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Duty 2</ENAMEX>. This <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rejoinder</ENAMEX> turns the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>'s strict
constructionism on its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>. The argument is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> says the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> should be removed only for crimes that imperil the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>. Example:
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Mason</ENAMEX>, I think, put it succinctly. He said, 'Was this an attempt to
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">subvert the Constitution</ENAMEX>?' All of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s untruths, all of his
lying under oath, if you will, about an extramarital relationship does not
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">subvert the Constitution</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schumer</ENAMEX>).

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Jury</ENAMEX>. This all-purpose <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> frame
posits that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> and should behave accordingly. This
accomplishes several objectives. First, it makes the strongest case for calling
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX>. Example: "I have never seen a trial before where you had factual
disputes where you didn't have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> where you could watch their demeanor
on the stand, listen to them, judge <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX> vs. another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DeWine</ENAMEX>).
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, it neutralizes the "summary judgment" frame, since summary judgments
are up to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>, not the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX>. Example: "We have an obligation to sit back
as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jurors</ENAMEX> and let the case be presented" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santorum</ENAMEX>). <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Third</NUMEX>, it shortcuts the
"summary judgment" and "censure" frames by organizing the trial's issues in
temporal sequence rather than as a decision <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX>. Example: "We're prejudging
this thing [when we say] it doesn't meet the standard of the high crimes and
misdemeanors. That's what the trial's all about. ... We're going to listen to
the evidence" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Chafee</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">R.I.</ENAMEX>).

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Jury Nullification</ENAMEX>. This
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> rebuttal shatters the "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX>" frame and diverts scrutiny from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defendant</ENAMEX> to the prosecution. The argument is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> should reject the
case not because it's unproven but because it's politically motivated. Example:
"One of the reasons why we feel that this impeachment trial is really not what
it's purported to be is that there have been <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX> of investigations. ...
There are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that just want to get this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dianne Feinstein</ENAMEX>,
D-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX>).

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>.

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Jury</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nullification Nullification</ENAMEX>. This <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rejoinder</ENAMEX> grants that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> impeachment process was politicized but argues
that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> should be above such tawdry politics; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) the way to
regain public confidence is to transcend partisan rancor and skepticism by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reverting</ENAMEX> to the innocence of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX>. Example: "We're sort of like the petit
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX>. How we got there, that's up for somebody else to determine. What we have
to look at is what the facts are" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DeWine</ENAMEX>).

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX>. Democracy. This nuclear response
combines the jury nullification and constitutional duty arguments, suggesting
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s removal would violate the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> and "undo the election."
The purpose of this rhetorical <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX> is to annihilate any discussion of the
facts. Example: "Do I think he answered that question honestly? No. Do I think
what he did was reprehensible? Absolutely. But the question is, this alone,
does it rise to that level where you overturn an election?" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Feinstein</ENAMEX>).

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Jury</ENAMEX>
Duty. This is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s favorite frame. In the debate over <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX>,
its purpose is to strip <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> of their appeals to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX>, jury
guidelines, and the rule of law. The argument is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> have
day jobs, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> they spend on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s trial--i.e., <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> duty--is a
day they're not spending on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>, education, and other issues. When
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boxer</ENAMEX> raised this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX>, her <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> explained that they were
"<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-tracking" the trial while working on "things that affect our
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">constituents</ENAMEX>." That answer won't do. It lets <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defenders</ENAMEX> steer the
discussion away from the trial. It grants the distinction between the trial and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s business. And it puts the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> on a collision course with its
argument that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> shouldn't deliver his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State of the Union</ENAMEX> address
on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 19</TIMEX>. But that's a "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Frame Game</ENAMEX>" for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">another day</TIMEX>.

         
      
   
