
   
   
      
         
            Attention Must Not Be Paid

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This week</TIMEX>, a revival of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arthur Miller</ENAMEX>'s classic <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1949</TIMEX> tragedy <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Death of a Salesman</ENAMEX> opened on
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX>. Something seems redundant about this sentence, since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miller</ENAMEX>'s
tragedies from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1940s and '50s</TIMEX> exist in a state of near-perpetual revival.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Roundabout Theatre</ENAMEX> staged an acclaimed version of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A View From</ENAMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Bridge</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miller</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1955</TIMEX> tragedy about immigrant life. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX> before
that, it was All My <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sons</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miller</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1947</TIMEX> tragedy about a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>'s discovery
of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s wartime corruption. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miller</ENAMEX>'s own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> produced a fine
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">film</ENAMEX> version of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Crucible</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miller</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1953</TIMEX> tragedy about the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Salem</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">witch</ENAMEX> trials as a parable of McCarthyism. On the basis of these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> works,
written over a period of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only eight years</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miller</ENAMEX> is frequently referred to as
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s greatest living <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">playwright</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arthur Miller</ENAMEX> did not
die or quit working in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1950s</TIMEX>. He remains alive and continues to write--more
prolifically, in fact, than he did back then. Yet despite the immense national
and international interest in his <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> famous postwar plays, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">the dozen or so</NUMEX> he
has written in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last 40 years</TIMEX> are all but ignored. If you've read or seen
any of the more recent ones-- The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ride Down Mt. Morgan</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Last</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yankee</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Broken Glass</ENAMEX> , or <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The American Clock</ENAMEX> , you might agree
that this neglect is warranted. These works are labored, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">didactic</TIMEX>, and
humorless, with weak <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> and weaker ideas. Even if you think, as I do,
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miller</ENAMEX>'s "classic" plays are somewhat overrated, the gap between his early
work and everything since is mysteriously wide. What happened to this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>?
Attention must be paid.

            The crisp <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">50 th</NUMEX> anniversary production of
Death of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Salesman</ENAMEX> , which comes to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Eugene O'Neill Theatre</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
City from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goodman</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>, is a good place to begin the inquest. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dennehy</ENAMEX> restores the original girth to the role of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willy Loman</ENAMEX>, who was played
on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stage</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1949</TIMEX> and in the first film version by the looming <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee J. Cobb</ENAMEX>
before he was downsized by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dustin Hoffman</ENAMEX>. Stuffed into a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>-piece suit that
visibly wilts in the course of his decline, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dennehy</ENAMEX> uses his bulk as his chief
dramatic asset. Just carrying his own weight seems a terrific burden for his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>--the working stiff as beached <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">whale</ENAMEX>. Almost everything else about the
production is equally strong. The design and staging are clever but not too
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">arty</ENAMEX>. Sliding screens and rotating <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">platforms</ENAMEX> convey effectively the chaos of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Loman</ENAMEX>'s mind--the jumble of present, past, and fantasy. This is a
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>-school production, the kind associated with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goodman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steppenwolf</ENAMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Wisdom Bridge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">theaters</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Falls</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>, draws out the dramatic
vigor and intensity of the text, without adding any heavy interpretive overlay
of his own.

            Such a limpid production
provides a window into the merits and flaws of the play itself. The chief
strength of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Death of a Salesman</ENAMEX> is its psychological acuity and its
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">insight</ENAMEX> into family misery. At its heart is the head-butting relationship
between the disappointed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> and his troubled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Biff</ENAMEX>, played by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anderson</ENAMEX>. What the play captures so well is the way in which a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">frustrations</ENAMEX> and projected ambitions can poison a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>'s life. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willy</ENAMEX>'s pushing
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX> to succeed and his unwillingness to accept their failures develop into
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">delusion</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">insanity</ENAMEX>. In catching this phenomenon, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miller</ENAMEX> created a great role
on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stage</ENAMEX>.

            But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miller</ENAMEX>'s weaknesses as a dramatist are also latent in
this play. I hope I never have to sit through <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Death of a Salesman</ENAMEX> again,
not because it's depressing and bleak but because it's unrelieved and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">unchallenging</ENAMEX>. As a dramatist, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miller</ENAMEX> not only has no sense of humor, he also
fails to grasp how changes in tone and texture can be used to make tragedy
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tolerable</ENAMEX>. Here, as in his other plays, he seems terrified that someone might
accuse him of entertainment. Nor is there much loveliness to his language.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miller</ENAMEX> occasionally writes a brilliant line, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willy</ENAMEX>'s response to the
callow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> who fires him after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">35 years</TIMEX>--"You can't eat an orange and throw
the peel away." But more often, when he reaches for poetry, he achieves only
portentousness, as in the nearly play-wrecking "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">requiem</ENAMEX>" that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willy</ENAMEX>'s friend
Charley delivers at his funeral, "No one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dast</ENAMEX> blames this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>." The humorless,
stilted quality of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miller</ENAMEX>'s writing makes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Salesman</ENAMEX> feel like a dental
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">extraction</ENAMEX>.

            The other problem is
that while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miller</ENAMEX> at his best is fierce and brutal, he is seldom intricate or
subtle. Death <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">of a Salesman</ENAMEX> is of a piece with powerful but
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uncomplicated</ENAMEX> works of literature from the same era such as <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Grapes of</ENAMEX>
Wrath. The social content of the play--its "indictment" of the values of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> capitalism and consumerism (as they say in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th</ENAMEX> -grade
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">English</ENAMEX>)--retains something of its currency. But you don't get a lot more out
of this point by hearing it made again and again. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miller</ENAMEX> is a preachy
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">playwright</ENAMEX> who lets you know what you're supposed to think about everything
that happens in his moral universe. In his didacticism he denies his characters
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ambiguity</ENAMEX> and hence a life of their own.

            What redeems <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Death of a Salesman</ENAMEX> is its furious
energy and the fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miller</ENAMEX>'s arguments were fresh when he wrote it. But in
his subsequent plays--both the few that are good and the many that are not so
good--these ideas become steadily more tiresome. For example, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Broken</ENAMEX>
Glass (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>) is <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Death of a Salesman</ENAMEX> compounded by issues of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jewish</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">self-hatred</ENAMEX> and sexual impotence. The setting is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brooklyn</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1938</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phillip</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gellburg</ENAMEX> is an upscale <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willy Loman</ENAMEX> who has devoted his life to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that
throws him onto the slag heap as soon as he begins to falter. As <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gellburg</ENAMEX>'s
life comes apart, self-understanding eludes him. He dies begging forgiveness
from his martyred <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>.

            In all his plays, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miller</ENAMEX>
remains fixed to the same set of concerns: corruption and the worship of
material success; loyalty and betrayal; <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fathers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX>; public responsibility
and personal conscience. That list is surely rich enough to support a lifetime
of playwriting, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miller</ENAMEX> handles these themes in the same way again and
again. That way identifies him as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">playwright</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the immediate postwar era</TIMEX>, a
period characterized by the anxiety of affluence, the worry that rising
material status was being purchased at the expense of decency and mutual
responsibility. His plays have a message, and it's always similar, if not the
same.

            It isn't just themes and arguments that recur in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miller</ENAMEX>'s
work. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Plots</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> do too. His plays most often involve the devastating
loss of one's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s respect ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">All My Sons , Death of a</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Salesman , A View From the Bridge , The Price , The Ride Down</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mt. Morgan</ENAMEX> ). This leads to suicide as the only remedy for shame (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">All My</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sons</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Death of a Salesman , After the Fall , The Ride Down</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mt. Morgan</ENAMEX>, 
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crucible</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miller</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> struggle with their
consciences, but his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> never do. They're either saintly, maternal figures
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kate Keller</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">All My Sons</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Loman</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Death of a Salesman</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Proctor</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Crucible</ENAMEX> ) or destructive temptresses (Abigail
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Williams</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Crucible , Catherine in A View From the Bridge</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maggie</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">After the Fall</ENAMEX> ). The lack of interest in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s minds is
another thing that dates <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miller</ENAMEX> and makes even his more recent plays seem like
period pieces.

            To some extent, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miller</ENAMEX>'s fate is that of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX> stage. Since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1950s</TIMEX>, the middle-class <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> for his kind of
serious social drama has shriveled. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theater</ENAMEX> has ceased to be the place
where <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> explore issues of the kind raised by <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Death of a</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Salesman</ENAMEX> . But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miller</ENAMEX>'s failure is ultimately his own. As his ideas grew
familiar and then stale, he found no way to complicate them, develop them, or
move on to something else. Death <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">of a Salesman</ENAMEX> , his greatest play, is
about the devastating effects of professional failure. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miller</ENAMEX>'s career is a
testament to the opposite problem: creative paralysis brought on by early
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">success</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
