
   
   
      
         
            

            
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yankees</ENAMEX> acquired <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Clemens</ENAMEX> . In exchange, they sent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pitcher</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Wells</ENAMEX>
and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toronto Blue Jays</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clemens</ENAMEX> leads all active
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pitchers</ENAMEX> in wins, shutouts, and strikeouts, and is the only <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>-time <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cy Young</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">winner</ENAMEX> (for best pitching) ever. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yankees</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Steinbrenner</ENAMEX> likened
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Clemens</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">deity</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Jordan</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Clemens</ENAMEX>
"perhaps the greatest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pitcher</ENAMEX> of his era" and described the trade as the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yankees</ENAMEX>' "most significant deal since the purchase of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Babe Ruth</ENAMEX>." The sunny
spin: With <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Clemens</ENAMEX> aboard, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yankees</ENAMEX> will break the record they set <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>
for victories in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a season</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">125</ENAMEX>). The cynical spin: This is what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wells</ENAMEX> gets for
worshipping the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yankees</ENAMEX>, pitching a perfect game for them <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>, and taking
them to the championship? (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2/19/99</NUMEX>)
            

            
The Wall
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Street Journal</ENAMEX> published <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20-year-old</TIMEX> rape allegations against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> . The story has circulated for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX>, but this is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time a
major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> has named the alleged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juanita Broaddrick</ENAMEX>, and has
detailed her allegations. According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dorothy Rabinowitz</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Broaddrick</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> tore her pantyhose during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1978</TIMEX> encounter, "held her
down forcibly and bit her lips," leaving them "swollen to double their size,"
and tried to apologize <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13 years later</TIMEX>, just before announcing his campaign for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rabinowitz</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX> has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> who corroborate parts of the
story. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Broaddrick</ENAMEX> filed an affidavit in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> case denying <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
raped her, but she repudiated the affidavit <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rabinowitz</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">aide Bruce Lindsey</ENAMEX> gave <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Broaddrick</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> the model for the affidavit, though
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Broaddrick</ENAMEX> and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> emphasize that no one from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> had
harassed her or subjected her to other pressures aimed at keeping the story
quiet." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rabinowitz</ENAMEX> says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Kendall</ENAMEX>
refused to comment on the story. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2/19/99</NUMEX>)
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Calvin Klein</ENAMEX>
canceled a controversial ad campaign showing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> in underwear . The ad,
which was running in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, shows <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> pre-adolescent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX>, one of whom is
wearing briefs with a visible bulge. Conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX> called
the ads pornographic, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychologists</ENAMEX> called them attractive to pedophiles, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudy Giuliani</ENAMEX> said they were "in very bad taste." <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> noted
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Calvin Klein</ENAMEX>'s history of skirting the pedophilic line, beginning with the
"Nothing comes between me and my Calvins" ads that featured a half-naked,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brooke Shields</ENAMEX>. The spins, in order of ascending cynicism: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) The
ads are innocent. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) The ads are sick. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> are sick for reading
pedophilia into the ads. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> are generating publicity and helping
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> sell underwear. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>) That was the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s plan all along.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2/19/99</NUMEX>)
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Scientists</ENAMEX> 
               slowed the speed of light by a factor
of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">20 million</NUMEX>. The experiment used ultracold atoms to obstruct the light,
slowing it from <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">186,171 miles per second to 38 miles per hour</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York</ENAMEX>
Times dwelled not on the experiment's abstract implications but on
practical, short-term benefits such as faster computers, brighter laser
projectors, and sharper night-vision goggles. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2/19/99</NUMEX>)
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX> captured
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurdish</ENAMEX> rebel <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abdullah Ocalan</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ocalan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guerrillas</ENAMEX> have been
fighting the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turks</ENAMEX> for independence since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1984</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurds</ENAMEX> responded to his arrest
with violent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protests</ENAMEX> across <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, seizing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 20</NUMEX> diplomatic <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Two hundred</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protesters</ENAMEX> stormed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>'s consulate in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Berlin</ENAMEX>; <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> were shot
dead by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guards</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX> unleashed <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">helicopters</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">thousands</NUMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ocalan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> in northern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>, reportedly "to strike a
decisive blow" against the now-leaderless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebels</ENAMEX>. Various <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> in the
dispute blamed: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ocalan</ENAMEX>, for causing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of deaths over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX>, for suppressing the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurds</ENAMEX> and barring <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ocalan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> from his
upcoming trial; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greece</ENAMEX>, for helping him evade capture; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>, for
allegedly facilitating his capture. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Safire</ENAMEX>, for falsely (?)
implicating the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israelis</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> to read the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>" line on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Safire</ENAMEX>.)
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2/18/99</NUMEX>)
            

            
Veteran
political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Weyrich</ENAMEX> urged fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> to "drop out" of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">society</ENAMEX> . In a letter posted on his Web site following <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">acquittal</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weyrich</ENAMEX> said: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) "the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> is very close to becoming a
state totally dominated by an alien ideology"; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> campaigns for the
presidency in such an environment are futile; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) to "make sure that we and
our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are not infected," <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">conservatives</ENAMEX> "need some sort of quarantine."
The conservative spin: He's a quitter. The moderate spin: He's gone nuts. The
liberal spin: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hurray</ENAMEX>, the nuts are quitting! (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> to read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>'s take
on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weyrich</ENAMEX>.) (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2/18/99</NUMEX>)
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> says she's seriously considering
whether to run for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Senate</ENAMEX> seat being vacated by retiring Sen.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patrick Moynihan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.Y.</ENAMEX> The arguments pro: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">New Yorkers</ENAMEX> love her. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">state</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">establishment</ENAMEX> is enthusiastically behind her. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) She can
raise all the money she needs. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) If she doesn't run, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> will win the seat. The arguments con: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) The
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> will brutalize her, particularly over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Whitewater</ENAMEX> and her failed
health care plan. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> press corps will brutalize her. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) As a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX>, she couldn't rake in book and lecture fees to pay off her legal bills.
The argument pro or con: If she doesn't decide soon, other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> will wait
too long to enter the race, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX> will win. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2/17/99</NUMEX>)
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> pledged to send <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> as part of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>
peacekeeping <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">force</ENAMEX>. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> criticized the decision. Arguments pro: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)
We can save lives. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) It's our duty as the world's only <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">superpower</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) If we
don't go in, we'll lose our idealism. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) If we don't go in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX>, we'll have to
go in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later</TIMEX>, when it's worse. Arguments con: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) We have no national interest
there. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) We have no clear goal. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) We have no exit strategy. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) We haven't had
the requisite national discussion beforehand. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>) We have no consistent
principles for deciding which wars to intervene in. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>) If you liked <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>,
you'll love the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Balkans</ENAMEX>. (For more background on the roots of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>
crisis, see 
                  Slate
               's ".")
(
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2/15/99</NUMEX>)
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Airlines</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX> went back to work. They
had forced <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of flight cancellations and stranded <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds of thousands</NUMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> by staging a sickout over a labor dispute. After a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> ruled
the sickout illegal, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX> still didn't go back to work, and the judge
fined the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> several <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">thousand dollars</NUMEX> and ordered the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX> to
assume responsibility for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10 million</NUMEX> in damages to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX>. That got the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX> back on the job. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX>' spin: Somebody had to teach this arrogant
airline that it can't always get its way. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cynics</ENAMEX>' spin: Somebody had to teach
these arrogant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX> that they can't always get their way. (See"," for why
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX> can't strike.) (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2/15/99</NUMEX>)
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX>
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">arv Albert</ENAMEX> is back in the national broadcasting
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">booth</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX> had fired him <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year and a half ago</TIMEX> after he pleaded guilty to
biting a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> during sex. Since then, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albert</ENAMEX> has served out his probation and
has anchored a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nightly</TIMEX> sports show at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Madison Square Garden</ENAMEX>.
Now <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Turner Sports</ENAMEX> is hiring him to broadcast pro basketball and other sports on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNT</ENAMEX>, starting <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 2</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNT</ENAMEX>'s spin: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albert</ENAMEX> is working through his problem, and
we're giving him a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> chance. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albert</ENAMEX>'s spin: The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> have
welcomed me back, and if you can make it there, you can make it anywhere.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cynics</ENAMEX>' spin on forgiveness of sexual violence in sports: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Celebrity 738-Justice</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0</NUMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2/15/99</NUMEX>)
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">J</ENAMEX>
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">eff Gordon</ENAMEX> won the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Daytona 500</ENAMEX> , auto racing's
most lucrative prize, for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> time in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX>. He edged out his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mentor</ENAMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dale Earnhardt</ENAMEX>, by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">0.128 seconds</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">race</ENAMEX> was
notable for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last several laps</TIMEX>, in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Earnhardt</ENAMEX> rode <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gordon</ENAMEX>'s bumper at
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">190 mph</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gordon</ENAMEX> thwarted him by slowing down so <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Earnhardt</ENAMEX> couldn't get enough
distance to find an angle and shoot past him. Afterward, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gordon</ENAMEX> thanked
Earnhardt for teaching him all his tricks. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2/15/99</NUMEX>)
            

         
      
   
