
   
   
      
         
             Wag the Doubt

            Did <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wag</ENAMEX> the dog" by bombing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>
on the eve of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> impeachment debate? <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Politicians</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> launched
the rhetorical war over that question even before the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX> fell in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baghdad</ENAMEX>. While the damage mounts in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>, the debate at home is dragging
politics to new depths. Here's a glossary of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">debaters</ENAMEX>' latest tactics, in
morally descending order.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. Overt
Cynicism. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX> accuses <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> of wagging the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX>. Example:
"It is obvious that he is doing this for political reasons" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerald</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Solomon</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.Y.</ENAMEX>).

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>
               .

               Cynicism by innuendo. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">accuser</ENAMEX> phrases the dog-wagging
charge obliquely so that he can deny having made it. Example: "We have had
either hostilities or threatened <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hostilities</ENAMEX> at interesting times throughout
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>" (incoming <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Speaker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Livingston</ENAMEX>).

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. Backhanded
cynicism. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">accuser</ENAMEX> implies <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX>-wagging by saying either a) he can't
bring himself to believe <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> would wag the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX>; or b) the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> has
assured him it's not so. Example: "While I have been assured by administration
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> that there is no connection with the impeachment process ... [b]oth
the timing and the policy are subject to question" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Majority Leader</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Lott</ENAMEX>).

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>
               . Cynicism about
principle. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">accuser</ENAMEX> argues that because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is inherently
unprincipled, any seemingly principled behavior on his part is fishy. Example:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> must have bombed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> to avoid impeachment, because "how else to
explain the sudden appearance of a backbone that has been invisible up to now?"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Solomon</ENAMEX>).

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. Cynicism by association. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">accuser</ENAMEX> doesn't allege a causal relationship between the impeachment process
and the bombing, but he blames <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> for the correlation anyway. Example:
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has indelibly associated a justified military response ...
with his own wrongdoing. ... <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has now injected the impeachment process
against him into foreign policy, and vice versa" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Hoagland</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> ).

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. Vicarious
cynicism. Rather than stand behind his cynicism, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">accuser</ENAMEX>
attributes it to others. Example: "It is dangerous for an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> to
launch a military strike, however justified, at a time when many will conclude
he acted only out of narrow self-interest to forestall or postpone his own
impeachment" ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> editorial).

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>
               . Fake idealism about
cynicism. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">accuser</ENAMEX> says other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s cynicism makes it impossible
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to govern well. Example: "The point is not whether this president
would [<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wag</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX>] ... [b]ut for some significant portion of the population
... there must be that doubt. And that doubt is the crucial nexus. ... A
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> must have credibility when he makes decisions about peace or war"
(former <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Wallison</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> op-ed).

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>. Fake
patriotism about cynicism. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> say <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> who accuse
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> of wagging the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> are inadvertently aiding and comforting the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemy</ENAMEX>. Example: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shame</ENAMEX> on you [<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>] for playing into the hands of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam"</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Meehan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mass.</ENAMEX>).

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>
               . McCarthyism about
cynicism. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> say <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> who accuse <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> of wagging the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> are deliberately aiding and comforting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enemy</ENAMEX>. Example: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>'s
remarks were "as close to a betrayal of the interests of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> as
I've ever witnessed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States Congress</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Torricelli</ENAMEX>,
D-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.J.</ENAMEX>).

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX>. Recidivist
cynicism. Having accused <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> of cynicism for suggesting that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> cynically used the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> conflict to delay the impeachment vote,
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> use the conflict to delay the vote. Example: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> should "not
take up impeachment until the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hostilities</ENAMEX> have ended. It shouldn't come up as
long as our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> are in harm's way" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Minority Leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gephardt</ENAMEX>).

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. Cynicism about
cynicism. While publicly accusing <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> of tactics aimed at
gaining political advantage, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> privately gloat that the tactics will
give <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> a political advantage. Example: " 'The rules we've always had is
that politics stop at the shore," <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> senior <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> said,
speaking on the condition of anonymity. 'Somebody changed the rules and it
wasn't us.' But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">advisers</ENAMEX> said that they expected Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lott</ENAMEX>'s comments to
backfire" ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ).

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12</TIMEX>. Reverse
cynicism. While accusing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> of invoking the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> conflict to
delay the impeachment vote, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> invoke the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> conflict to expedite
the impeachment vote. Example: "I don't see any reason to postpone the vote.
That plays right into <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX>'s hands. That's what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX>
want--disruption" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill McCollum</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fla.</ENAMEX>).

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. Cynical
anti-cynicism. While accusing <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> of cynicism for suggesting
that impeachment would undermine the war effort, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> argue that
impeachment is the best way to honor the war effort. Example: "As those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>
are engaged now, even now, defending ... the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> of this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>, they
have a right to know that the work of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> goes forward. And in
consideration of this, it is our intention, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Speaker</ENAMEX>, to begin consideration
of [impeachment]" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Majority Leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Armey</ENAMEX>).

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14</TIMEX>. Circular
vicarious cynicism. Unable to prove that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> wagged the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> argue that the mere suspicion of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX>-wagging is grounds for
impeachment. Examples: "The suspicion some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s
motives in this attack is itself a powerful argument for impeachment" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Armey</ENAMEX>).
"Perceptions that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> is less interested in the global
consequences than in taking any action that will enable him to hold onto power
[are] a further demonstration that he has dangerously compromised himself in
conducting the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s affairs, and should be impeached" ( Wall Street
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> editorial).

            
               Recent "Frame
Games"
            

            

               "": <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Saletan</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>
could blow up the impeachment process by crying "coup." (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 16</TIMEX>)
               

               "": <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX> share the same bag of tricks.
(posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 2</TIMEX>)
               

            

         
      
   
