
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Movies
            

            
               
                  Varsity
Blues
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paramount Pictures</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> say this film is pretty fun
for a formula sports flick: "brisk and wholehearted and smarter than you
expect" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Owen Gleiberman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Entertainment Weekly</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dawson's Creek</ENAMEX>
star <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Van Der Beek</ENAMEX> plays a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>-string quarterback thrust into the
spotlight of a football-obsessed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> is injured. The
benefits that come with the new position (free <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cheerleaders slathered</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">whipped cream</ENAMEX>) get lots of screen-time, and at points the film is almost "a
poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Porky</ENAMEX>'s " (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andy Seiler</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Anderson</ENAMEX> pans
it in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> ("a trashy little movie about drinking,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> and drinking"), saying it "pretends to moralize about the very
behavior it <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milks</ENAMEX> for every giggle it can get." (Get all the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Van Der Beek</ENAMEX>-cake
you can handle on this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> site.)

            
               
                  At <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First</ENAMEX>
Sight
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGM</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> are down on this
based-on-a-true-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oliver-Sacks</ENAMEX>-story of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Val Kilmer</ENAMEX>) who regains his sight
after an operation encouraged by his sighted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mira Sorvino</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rod</ENAMEX>
Dreher of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Post</ENAMEX> is scathing, dismissing it as "ooey-gooey
schmoopie slop" and "ersatz romantic tapioca" and comparing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personality</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kilmer</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> to that of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Snuggles</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fabric-softener</ENAMEX> bear. Not everyone's
this harsh, but the film has only one true <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporter</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Thomas</ENAMEX>, who deems it "an exceptionally touching and
provocative love story." (This <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> site
has lots of stills.)

            
               
                  In
Dreams
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DreamWorks</ENAMEX>). Most agree that this "dismayingly schlocky
and literal-minded thriller" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gleiberman, Entertainment Weekly</ENAMEX> ) is
leavened only by a fine performance by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Annette Bening</ENAMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> plagued by the
dreams of a serial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">killer</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neil Jordan</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Butcher Boy</ENAMEX> ) gives
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> plenty to look at--creepy underwater sets, lush dream <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sequences</ENAMEX>--but
the film comes up short anyway. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Ebert</ENAMEX> says, "[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX>]his is a well-made bad
movie" ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Sun-Times</ENAMEX> ). (For a review by 
                  Slate
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'s David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Edelstein,</ENAMEX> click . Find out more about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neil Jordan</ENAMEX> in this profile in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> .)

            

               Books
            

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Duane</ENAMEX>'s
Depressed
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry McMurtry</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simon & Schuster</ENAMEX>). Good, not
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">great</ENAMEX>, reviews for the final novel in the trilogy that began with <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Last</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Picture Show</ENAMEX> and continued with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texasville</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> say that
although this is not on a par with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McMurtry</ENAMEX>'s finest work, "every page is as
welcome as a letter from home" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kyle Smith</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> ). Others think the
extended musing on the depression of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">62-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">oilman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Duane Moore</ENAMEX> focuses so
much on his malaise as to become boring, but most agree with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malcolm Jones</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> : "both heartbreaking and hilarious, sometimes on the same
page." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Read</ENAMEX> more about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McMurtry</ENAMEX> in this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> article.)

            
               
                  The
Intuitionist
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Colson Whitehead</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anchor Books</ENAMEX>). Critics
describe this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">detective</ENAMEX> novel, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>, as "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">part Thomas Pynchon</ENAMEX>,
part <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralph Ellison"</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Cryer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Newsday</ENAMEX> ) and praise <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitehead</ENAMEX>
as a refreshingly original voice. The story follows <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lila Mae Watson</ENAMEX>, the first
black elevator <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspector</ENAMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>-like metropolis in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1940s</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Watson</ENAMEX> is
an "intuitionist," one of a minority of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspectors</ENAMEX> who judges <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">elevators</ENAMEX> by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">intuition</ENAMEX>, as opposed to the empiricists, who inspect in the traditional
fashion. The twisting plot explores race relations, with <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">elevators</ENAMEX> serving as
metaphors for social mobility and transcendence. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Rozzo</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> is not as impressed as most, saying the book "diverts more
than it excites." (Listen to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> reading a passage from the book
here, and read an excerpt here.)

            

               Theater
            

            
               
                  Fosse: A
Celebration in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Song and Dance</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadhurst Theatre</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Reviewers</ENAMEX> are split on this retrospective of the work of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX> choreographer
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Fosse</ENAMEX>. Some call it a testament to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fosse</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX>, with fulsome,
blurb-ready praise: "The old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">razzle-dazzler</ENAMEX> has done it again--posthumously ...
an inevitable hit, a galvanizing eruption of energy, panache and arrogantly
surefooted stagecraft" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Terry Teachout</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> ). Others, contrarily, find
evidence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fosse</ENAMEX>'s limits: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben Brantley</ENAMEX> writes,
"Numbers that, in the context of their original shows, sparkled with wit and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">vitality</ENAMEX> often register as repetitive examples of virtuosic proficiency." Some
are more critical, calling the dances "dated" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amy Gamerman</ENAMEX>, the Wall Street
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> ). (An "under construction" <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fosse</ENAMEX> site lets <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> discuss the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX>. You can buy
tickets at the show's official
site.)

            

               Recent "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment</ENAMEX>" columns
            

             

            

               
                  Movie--
                  Affliction ;

               
                  Movie
                  --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hilary</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackie</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie
                  --The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Hi-Lo Country</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Book--
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Haunted Wood: Soviet Espionage in</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>--The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stalin</ENAMEX> Era , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen Weinstein</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander Vassiliev</ENAMEX>;

               
                  Book
                  --Note <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Found in a Bottle: My Life</ENAMEX> as a Drinker , by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Cheever</ENAMEX>;

               
                  Book
                  --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glamorama</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bret Easton Ellis</ENAMEX>.

            

             

            

               
                  Movie--
                  A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Civil Action</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- The Thin Red Line</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie -- Down in the 
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Delta</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hurlyburly</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie -- Theory of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flight</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Book--
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Careless Love: The Unmaking of Elvis</ENAMEX>
Presley , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Guralnick</ENAMEX>;

               
                  Book
                  --
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jew</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ben</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Katchor</ENAMEX>.

            

             

            

               
                  Movie--
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patch Adams</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie
                  --The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Faculty</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie
                  --Stepmom ;

               
                  Movie
                  --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mighty Joe Young</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Book--
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hundred Dollar Holiday</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McKibben</ENAMEX>;

               
                  Book
                  --The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vintner</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luck</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Knox</ENAMEX>.

            

             

            

               
                  Movie--
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prince</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie--
                  You've Got <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mail</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie--
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Book--
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Blind Man's Bluff: The Untold Story of American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Submarine Espionage</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sherry Sontag</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Drew</ENAMEX>, with Annette
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lawrence Drew</ENAMEX>;

               
                  Book--
                  Opened Ground: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Selected Poems</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1966-1996</TIMEX> , by Seamus
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heaney</ENAMEX>;

               
                  Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- The Unknown Matisse: A Life</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henri Matisse</ENAMEX>, The Early
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Years, 1869-1908</TIMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hilary Spurling</ENAMEX>.

            

         
      
   
