
   
   
      
         
            

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
Magazine
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 3</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">31, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            As always, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX>'s
final issue--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Lives They Lived"</ENAMEX>-- is devoted to the "old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>" who have
died in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the previous 12 months</TIMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX> profiles include the obvious
choices--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Sinatra</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spock</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roy Rogers</ENAMEX>--but there are also stories about
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Otto Bettmann</ENAMEX>, who began his photo archive with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> suitcases of photographs
carted out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nazi Germany</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha Gellhorn</ENAMEX>, who covered wars from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX> in the
1930s to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Patagonia</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX>; and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inventors</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cuisinart</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">La-Z-Boy</ENAMEX>, and bubble <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gum</ENAMEX>. All of the obits speak fondly of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX>, save
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>: Former <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alabama</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Wallace</ENAMEX> is castigated for both his racism and
his superficial renunciation of it. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wallace</ENAMEX>, the profile argues, claimed to
have repudiated racism but used issues such as crime and welfare as veils for
old-school segregationist politics. The most lives seem to have been lived by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eldridge Cleaver</ENAMEX>, who spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">his years</TIMEX> as a convicted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminal</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX>, a
Black <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Panther</ENAMEX>, a presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>, a Moonie, a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mormon</ENAMEX>, and a conservative
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 4</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">29, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover editorial
argues that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s popular support should not prevent impeachment,
because it is merely a "momentary delusion" achieved through "effective
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">demagoguery</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">framers</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX>, argues the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> ,
intended impeachment as a way to remove an unworthy if popular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>. As for
censure, it would be useless, "a gob of spit attached to the presidency's
reputation by a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">craven legislature</ENAMEX>." ... A piece argues that fat
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX>' fees corrupt the multistate tobacco settlement, because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">plaintiff</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> will now a) bankroll the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic Party</ENAMEX>; b) fund their own political
ambitions; and c) try to keep <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Tobacco</ENAMEX> profitable , so they can keep
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pocketing</ENAMEX> said fees for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX> to come. ... The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> the establishment of a conservative arts <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> (suggested title:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alienation</ENAMEX> ). It won't make <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a cent</NUMEX>, but even "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> of heterodox
culture coverage could galvanize the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> (and hence <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>) culture
scene," which is full of dissatisfied <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">souls</ENAMEX> seeking only "a place to speak and
an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX> to rally around."

         
      
   
