
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">176</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">&quot;Wrecking Ball&quot</ENAMEX>;

            

               "It did the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> and me a lot of good to pick up those
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hammers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">crow</ENAMEX> bars and tear something down," <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>.
Tear what down?
            

             

            by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> to e-mail your answer to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            

               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s question (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 175</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dis Incentive":</ENAMEX>
            

            

               "This is a horrible thing that's going on," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franklin Spinney</ENAMEX>. "All
it's going to do is reward the pathological behavior that created the problem."
What's going on?
            

            "The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Academy Awards</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Finkle</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer Miller</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daniel</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Krause</ENAMEX> had similar answers.)

            "The
<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Super Bowl</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lois Ambash</ENAMEX> (similarly, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">R.C. Leander</ENAMEX> )

            "But
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Furby LOVE play</ENAMEX>! <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Teach Furby</ENAMEX> play again, then singing!"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Kate Wing</ENAMEX>
            

            "Mr.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spinney</ENAMEX> is arguing that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Make-A-Wish Foundation</ENAMEX> actually encourages <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
to get sick."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Carvell</ENAMEX>
            

            "I'm
giving the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> free run of the pantry. Is that wrong?"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doug</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ingram</ENAMEX>
            

             

             

            Click
for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more</NUMEX> responses.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
            

            To many of you, the
horrible thing that's going on is going on in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>. Of course, if we had a
parliamentary system, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> would simply call for a vote of confidence
and--one way or another--we'd swiftly move on. If we had the metric system, we
could easily calculate how far we'd moved on. If we had a decent system of
public education, filled with healthy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> enjoying universal access to
medical care, easily reached by high-speed maglev <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trains</ENAMEX> driven by
bioengineered <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> fed on the limitless bounty we farm on the ocean floor, then
we'd all learn that metric system and reward ourselves by zipping off on our
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">unicopters</ENAMEX> to the space <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">port</ENAMEX> for our <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two week</TIMEX> vacation on the moon. I'm sure
these are just some of the visionary ideas the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> will be propose in
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State of the Union</ENAMEX> address. Along with school uniforms.

            
               Bang for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buck</ENAMEX>
Answer
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s proposed defense budget.

            His suggested massive
increase in military spending, the biggest in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two decades</TIMEX>, is a dreadful way to
strengthen <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analyst</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franklin Spinney</ENAMEX>. No major adversary
has emerged since the collapse of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX>. A swollen military budget
robs the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> of resources for education and other actual needs. It subverts
reforms in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX>'s culture of waste and inefficiency. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spinney</ENAMEX> also
argues that the increasingly complex <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> under consideration are too
expensive to be purchased and maintained in adequate numbers. "Spending more
money the same way isn't going to fix anything," he says, criticizing what he
calls "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Versailles on the Potomac</ENAMEX>."

            
               Either/Or
Extra
            

            

               "We believe that killing is not an acceptable management tool for
us."--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Either Bill Gates</ENAMEX> is announcing a policy change at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Avanzino</ENAMEX> is promoting humane animal <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shelters</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">SPCA</ENAMEX>.

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tara Road</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maeve Binchy; River's End</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nora Roberts</ENAMEX>; and
A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sudden Change of Heart</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara Taylor Bradford</ENAMEX>.--Either they're
just not trying at the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">National Book Awards</ENAMEX>, or there's a new kind of giveaway
in specially marked cases of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coca-Cola</ENAMEX>.

               "My monument has won!"--Either this is a line in a gay porn remake of
Spartacus , or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Eisenman</ENAMEX> is delighted that some good has
come out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX>--he got a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">commission</ENAMEX>.

               "After <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this past week</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> here say <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yankee</ENAMEX> trash, they think it's
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">redundant</ENAMEX>."--Either yet another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> is offended by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX>'s
swaggering know-nothingism or ... oh, wait, it is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX>'s swaggering
know-nothingism.

            

            

               Correction
            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> cell phone
death story attributed to someone was actually submitted by someone else.

            
               Race
Results
            

            Top <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">target</ENAMEX>: bad
movies.

            
               Correction of
Correction
            

            The lack of specificity
in the previous correction rendered it ineffectual. The story was actually
submitted by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer Miller</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Disclaimer</ENAMEX>: All
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">submissions</ENAMEX> will become the property of 
               
                  Slate
               

               and will be published at 
               
                  Slate
               
               's
discretion. 
               
                  Slate
                
               may publish your name on its
site in connection with your submission .

         
      
   
