
   
   
      
         
             <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mod Squad</ENAMEX>

            The world
has been paying <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">moderates</ENAMEX> a lot of attention lately, and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">moderates</ENAMEX> are finding it all a bit disorienting. "We're just so popular now,"
said a bewildered <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa Pezzetti</ENAMEX>, deputy executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of the Ripon
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Society</ENAMEX>, when I paid a visit <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this week</TIMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>'s tiny <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>,
located in a brick low-rise behind the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fertilizer Institute</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol Hill</ENAMEX>.
"Us <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">moderates</ENAMEX> don't make news very often."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ripon Society</ENAMEX> is
itself an emblem of how wispy is the movement to which <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">moderates</ENAMEX>
belong. Founded at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1960s</TIMEX> by college <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> put off by the
vulgarity of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goldwater</ENAMEX> campaign, the society flirted with liberalism during
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '70s</TIMEX> (it even sued the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Committee</ENAMEX> over minority
representation at political conventions!) and has been drifting a little bit to
the right ever since. Today, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Executive Director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Gill</ENAMEX>, a
former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Gillmor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R.</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX>, the classic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ripon Republican</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">venerates Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX> (whose scrapes with "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gypsy moth</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastern Republican</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">moderates</ENAMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX> are apparently forgotten) but tends to part company
with the party on social issues such as abortion. Membership, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gill</ENAMEX> says with a
rueful laugh, is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">between 15,000 and 20,000</NUMEX>.

            The heyday for moderate <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> was probably the late
1950s, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dwight Eisenhower</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Modern</ENAMEX> (i.e., moderate)
Republicanism was the prevailing conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">orthodoxy</ENAMEX>. The WASP aristocracy
still controlled Wall Street, the Ivy League, and much of the press. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Party</ENAMEX>'s liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wing</ENAMEX> (as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">moderates</ENAMEX> were then called) was filled with
noble purpose about civil rights and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s rights, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> issues on which
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> would not achieve dominance until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1960s</TIMEX>. The remarkable work on
civil rights done by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Kennedy</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX> bore a distinctly
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> stamp: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Doar</ENAMEX>, a celebrated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX>--who
single-handedly stopped an incipient riot at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medgar Evars</ENAMEX>' funeral by stepping
into an angry <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> and yelling, "Anybody around here knows that I stand for
what's right!"--was an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Eisenhower</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">appointee</ENAMEX>. (For a fictitious portrait of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">quintessential GOP</ENAMEX> moderate, click .)

            Now that civil rights
issues have become mired in complexity and uncertainty about affirmative
action, the grand sense of purpose in being a moderate <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> doesn't seem
to exist anymore. Perhaps the emblematic moderate-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> stance on civil
rights during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this decade</TIMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Danforth</ENAMEX>'s championing of
affirmative-action <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foe</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarence Thomas</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> at the same
time <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danforth</ENAMEX> was pushing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> to sign the
affirmative-action-friendly <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX> civil rights bill (which it eventually did).
Even regionally, moderate <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> have lost their identity. For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> they
were a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bloc</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Easterners</ENAMEX> perpetually at war for control of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> with
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Midwestern conservatives</ENAMEX>. Now <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastern</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Midwestern Republicans</ENAMEX> tend to blend
together in opposition to more conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southern Republicans</ENAMEX> (a subspecies
that didn't exist before) and conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Westerners</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Rust Belt</ENAMEX> issues such
as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid rain</ENAMEX>.

            Since the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">districts</ENAMEX> of moderate <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>, especially in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East</ENAMEX>, tend to be heavily <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX>, and the ideological differences
between moderate <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">New Democrats</ENAMEX> are now microscopic (or perhaps
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nonexistent</ENAMEX>), it's a bit baffling that moderate <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> don't switch party
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">affiliation</ENAMEX> and become <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>. There are a few <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> around who began
life as moderate <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Californian</ENAMEX> former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief of Staff</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leon Panetta</ENAMEX> is one--but for most (including <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Panetta</ENAMEX>), the
switch was made <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at least two decades ago</TIMEX>. That's when former <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Lindsay</ENAMEX>, former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don Riegle</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michigan</ENAMEX>, and former <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Westchester</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">County U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ogden Reid</ENAMEX> all jumped <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ship</ENAMEX>. Practically the only nationally
known <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> to defect to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX> are New
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lt. Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betsy McCaughey Ross</ENAMEX> (who's a head case) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carolyn</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCarthy</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> (who ran after her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> was killed and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> injured
by a gun-toting lunatic on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Long Island Railroad</ENAMEX>). By contrast, a steady
trickle of conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>, including <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Billy Tauzin</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisiana</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben Nighthorse Campbell</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX>, have switched to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> side
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX>.

            Why the persistence of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> moderate as a subspecies? One explanation is simple mislabeling.
A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservative</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX> can get called a moderate simply
because he bucks his party on a few issues (campaign finance, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco</ENAMEX>) and is
found to be personally likable by the press. Sometimes all it takes in terms of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">apostasy</ENAMEX> is a pro-choice stance on abortion--as was the case with former Sen.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Simpson</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wyoming</ENAMEX>. Black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> frequently get called "moderate"
simply because they maintain some vestigial sensitivity about race.
Conservative former <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tauzin</ENAMEX> get called "moderate" simply because
they used to be <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>.

            Another explanation is opportunism. The liberal views of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Phillips</ENAMEX> have greater market value because they can be presented to the
public as startling <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> apostasy. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralph Neas</ENAMEX>, who for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many years</TIMEX> ran the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leadership Conference</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Civil Rights</ENAMEX>, always identified himself as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>; he dropped the pretense only when he ran for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last fall</TIMEX> as
a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> in liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Montgomery County</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Md.</ENAMEX>, losing to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Connie Morella</ENAMEX> (the
most liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>). In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vermont</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberal challengers</ENAMEX> to
independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bernie Sanders</ENAMEX> have no choice but to run in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican</ENAMEX>
primary, since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sanders</ENAMEX> has co-opted the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic Party</ENAMEX>.

            For most moderate
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>, though, the principal reasons not to switch <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> are nostalgia
and aristocratic indolence. The prevailing style of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> moderate is modest
and self-effacing. When I asked the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ripon Society</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pezzetti</ENAMEX> whether the group
had a Web site, she answered: "It's really pathetic. Don't bother." About the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only</NUMEX> thing a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> moderate is likely to get worked up <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about these days</TIMEX> is
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">right</ENAMEX>, whose existence led to the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> creation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leadership Council</ENAMEX>, co-chaired by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">financier</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Kravis</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> is housed
in a shabby building on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol Hill</ENAMEX> a few doors down from the palatial
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heritage Foundation</ENAMEX>. The elevator groans, and brown paint
peels from the window frames. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RLC</ENAMEX>'s purpose seems to be precisely in tune
with that of the corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">titans</ENAMEX> who supposedly rule the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>: Get government
out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedrooms</ENAMEX> and concentrate on lowering taxes. Yet the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>'s budget
is dwarfed by that of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heritage</ENAMEX>, which rakes in corporate contributions while
scattering its attention between economic and social issues.

            Moderate <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> are giving <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> what it wants.
Broadly speaking, they provided their party with its last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> presidential
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">nominees</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX>) and, according to early betting, will serve
up the next <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>). Yet even as their votes in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> are
courted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>, their ranks seem
in no danger of expanding. For all their good manners, common sense, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">solicitude</ENAMEX> toward <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>, they just don't command much respect.

         
      
   
