
   
   
      
         
             State of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conjugal Union</ENAMEX>

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX> at
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s trial, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Counsel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Ruff</ENAMEX> emphatically
reminded the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> had confessed to adultery with an intern less
than half his age. <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Hours</TIMEX> later at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State of the Union</ENAMEX> address,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> applauded as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> touted his record on family values. How did
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> get away with this compartmentalization? By reinterpreting
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ruff</ENAMEX>'s argument before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> was a legal
defense but a moral surrender. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> couldn't be guilty of perjury before
Independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Counsel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">grand jury</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruff</ENAMEX> explained, because in his
testimony <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> had "admitted" the essential truth: that he had engaged in
"sexual conduct" and "inappropriate, intimate contact with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>."
Yes, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruff</ENAMEX> conceded, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> had clammed up about the details, but this was
merely "an effort to preserve the dignity of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>" in the wake of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">indignities</ENAMEX> to which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> had subjected it. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s lawyer
concluded, "We are not here to defend <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Clinton</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>." Indeed, Ruff
stipulated that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> were free "to find his personal conduct
distasteful."

            Yet <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> conveyed no
shame when he entered the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chamber</ENAMEX> later that <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX>. Nor did the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawmakers</ENAMEX> who cheered and embraced him. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> sprinkled the
word "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>" throughout his speech and devoted <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one-sixth</NUMEX> of the text to a
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">section</ENAMEX> titled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Support for American Families</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">section</ENAMEX> didn't mention
marriage, illegitimacy, or any of the other conventional moral topics that
might embarrass <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. Instead, it repackaged <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> other kinds of issues as
family concerns.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. Technical support. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> issues are
conflicts over contrary goals (hence the phrase "culture war"). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>,
however, uses the word "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>" to describe issues in which the goal is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">uncontroversial</ENAMEX> and the only challenge is to provide the means. In the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>"
portion of his speech, he bragged about the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Family Medical Leave Act</ENAMEX>" and
called on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> to "extend <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> leave to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">10 million</NUMEX> more <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>." He
urged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawmakers</ENAMEX> to provide subsidies and tax credits for "quality child care"
and "after-school programs"--all in the name of "working <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>."

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. Aid to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> issues are about relations among family
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> issues are about helping <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> while describing
them as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>. In his "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>" discussion, he challenged <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>
to raise the minimum wage, support <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMO</ENAMEX> regulations, finance studies on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">arthritis</ENAMEX> (because "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> deserve the world's best medical care"),
and help public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> treat "working <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> who don't have any
insurance." <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> used to embrace "working <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>" while <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>
embraced "family values." By claiming to serve "working <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>
plays it both ways.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. Constituency politics. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> issues
discriminate between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> configurations (straight vs. gay, married vs.
unmarried, etc.). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> issues ignore these distinctions and instead
discriminate by other demographic criteria that are equally politically useful.
In his remarks on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, he extolled federal funding of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Parkinson's</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Alzheimer's</ENAMEX> research. He urged <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> to "allow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with disabilities to
keep health insurance when they go to work" and to "give <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> between the
ages of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">55 and 65</NUMEX> who lose their health insurance the chance to buy into
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>." This is great news if you're disabled, if you're <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">55 to 65</TIMEX>, or if
someone you care about has <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Parkinson's</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Alzheimer's</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> isn't
speaking to you as a special interest. He's speaking to you as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. Cultural
liberalism. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> use the F word to affirm conservative
principles such as chastity, maternity, and homemaking. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> uses it to
renovate or even reverse those principles. "Let's make sure that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and men
get equal pay for equal work by strengthening enforcement of equal pay laws,"
he proposed at the outset of his discussion of "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>." Equal pay began as a
feminist cause, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has made it a family issue by spotlighting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX>
who work outside the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>. Likewise, in his speech, he avoided the phrase
"birth control," which connotes hostility to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>. Instead, he
spoke up for "family planning," which connotes the opposite.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paternalism</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> advocate regulation of
family matters while defending freedom of choice in economic matters. Liberal
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> draw the same distinction but take the opposite positions. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
confounds both <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camps</ENAMEX> by blurring the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>/economic distinction. His favorite
hybrid issue is tobacco legislation. This began as a public health crusade, but
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has transformed it into an issue of helping <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> protect their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
from <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pushers</ENAMEX>. "Our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are targets of a massive media campaign to
hook them on cigarettes," he charged in his remarks on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>. "I ask this
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> to resist the tobacco <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lobby</ENAMEX> [and] to reaffirm the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX>'s authority to
protect our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> from tobacco."

            After <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 minutes</TIMEX> of
family values oratory and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of ovations, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> concluded, "If we act in
these areas--minimum wage, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> leave, child care, health care, the safety of
our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>--then we will begin to meet our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX>'s historic
responsibility to strengthen our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>." Of course, honoring your marriage
vows helps, too. But when you're as smooth-tongued as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>, that goes
without saying.

         
      
   
