
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">161</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">&quot;Rapoportable&quot</ENAMEX>;

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacques Rapoport</ENAMEX> led the search for something
"that was sweet rather than violent, that lingered for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks</TIMEX>, and that
suggested a feeling of cleanliness and well-being rather than of filthiness
being covered up." What was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rapoport</ENAMEX> looking for?
            

             

            by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> to e-mail your answer to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            

               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>'s question (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 160</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Put the</ENAMEX> Dis Back in
Description":
            

            

               
                  
                     "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Smelly, Lethargic, Incoherent</ENAMEX>." Ads in many papers
caution that someone like this is probably ...
what?
                  
               
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Male</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evan Cornog</ENAMEX>
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dead</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Tullis</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellen Macleay</ENAMEX> had a similar answer, with
Tic-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tacs.</ENAMEX>)

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Electable</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brooke Saucier</ENAMEX> (similarly, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Winter Miller</ENAMEX> )

            "Dying
to meet you!"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ananda Gupta</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dennehy</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Death of a Salesman</ENAMEX> ."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Kelly</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A</ENAMEX>
newborn <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX>. Mine's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a full week old</TIMEX>, and he's still acting like a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">drunk</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric Fredericksen</ENAMEX>
            

            "Leno:
'Ready for his <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Viagra</ENAMEX>'; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Letterman</ENAMEX>: 'The typical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewer</ENAMEX>'; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maher</ENAMEX>: 'Next to
Ariana, on my immediate left.' "-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Radosh</ENAMEX>
            

            
Click for more responses.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s Wrap-Up
            

            Events
have unfolded so rapidly since this question was posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Thursday</TIMEX> that it's
difficult to distinguish the smelly from the lethargic, the lethargic from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">incoherent</ENAMEX>, the incoherent from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Hyde</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> history. As I understand
it, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Livingston</ENAMEX> announced his resignation, demanded the president
follow suit, and called for those other adulterers, former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Presidents</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eisenhower</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roosevelt</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jefferson</ENAMEX> to return from the dead and
resign retroactively. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Livingston</ENAMEX>'s rationale seems to be that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> take
government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> as their role <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">models</ENAMEX> (particularly those in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communications Commission</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bureau of Weights</ENAMEX> and Measures--did I get
that part right?), most of whom now have the shoe deals <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nike</ENAMEX> just canceled with
out of work <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX>. And of course You've got <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mail</ENAMEX> opened,
along with its homosexual pornographic knockoff, You've Got <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Males</ENAMEX> . I'm
exhausted. But I won't resign.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Glassy Eyed</ENAMEX>
Answer
            

            Someone like this is probably an
inhalant-abusing teenager.

            "Few realize that just one sniff can cause death,"
asserts the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Partnership</ENAMEX> for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drug-Free America</ENAMEX>. To find out which ordinary
household products will get you high, ask your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>. "Half of all <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX>-15 year
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">olds</ENAMEX> have been offered inhalants." Sorry, I mean "Warn your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> before it's
too late, because we don't recommend the other means of detection. It's called
an autopsy.

            "To learn more about inhalants, what they are, and
where in your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> they can be found [Oh, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lordy</ENAMEX>, those bastards have been been
poking around my home!], we urge you to call (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">800</ENAMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">729-6686</TIMEX>."

            To learn more about what

                  Slate
               's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seth Stevenson</ENAMEX> knows about this dubious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>, we
urge you to click .

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Seasonal</TIMEX> Sequels
Extra
            

            Below,
actual holiday movies and their putative sequels. Can you tell which of the
follow-ups are authentic?

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. Emmet
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Otter</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Jug-Band Christmas</ENAMEX>
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emmet Otter</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fur Coat Christmas</ENAMEX>
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> Without a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">Tree</ENAMEX>
            

            
               The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> Without <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Adequate Wiring or a Reliable Smoke Detector</ENAMEX>
            

<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX>
            

            
               How
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">t</ENAMEX>
               he <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Grinch Made Grinchtown the Home</ENAMEX> of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Winter</ENAMEX>
Olympics
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santa Claus</ENAMEX> Conquers
the Martians
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Claus Subjects the Martians to a Sustained Campaign of Long Range</ENAMEX>
Bombing but Fails to Actually Conquer Them
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Le Martien de</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">NoÃ«l</ENAMEX> (a k a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Christmas Martian</ENAMEX> )

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Le</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pere NoÃ</ENAMEX>«l <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">est</TIMEX> une <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ordure</ENAMEX> (a k a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Father Christmas Has a Funny</ENAMEX>
Smell )

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nestor</ENAMEX>, the
Long-Eared <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> Donkey
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nestor</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Christmas Donkey with Cute Little Ears and an Impressive Bust</ENAMEX>,
Thanks to <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Cosmetic Surgery</ENAMEX>
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weihnachtsfieber</ENAMEX> (a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">k a Christmas Fever</ENAMEX>)
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weihnachten mit Willy Wuff II</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eine Mama</ENAMEX> fÃ¼r Lieschen
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Online</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Adventures of Ozzie the Elf</ENAMEX>
            

            
               The
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Prison Adventures of Ozzie the Elf</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Convicted</ENAMEX> Pornographer
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudolph</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frosty</ENAMEX>'s
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX>
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudolph</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Frosty's Binge and Purge Weekend With Calista</ENAMEX>
Flockhart
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santa</ENAMEX> vs. the
Snowman
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa</ENAMEX> (a k a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Spirit of Christmas</ENAMEX> )

            
               Answer
            

            None are sequels, but <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> are actual movies, although I may have mistranslated <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Disclaimer</ENAMEX>: All
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">submissions</ENAMEX> will become the property of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> and will be
published at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> 's discretion. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> may
publish your name on its site in connection with your submission.
            

         
      
   
