
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">170</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">&quot;Aust/Test&quot</ENAMEX>;

            
               I give the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">headline</ENAMEX>, you give the lead.
            

            

               From the front page of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Australia</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Advertiser</ENAMEX> : "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1664</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IDIOTS</ENAMEX>."
            

             

            by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">p.m. ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> to e-mail your answer to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            

               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s question (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 169</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eats/Wets</ENAMEX>":
            

            
               You chew household
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">objects</ENAMEX> and drool copiously, and perhaps you defecate or urinate on the
floor.
            

            

               Who are you, and what should you do next?
            

            "You're
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Strom Thurmond</ENAMEX>, and you do whatever it takes to keep <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sid Blumenthal</ENAMEX> from
getting the photos to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Flynt</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Talbot</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Radosh</ENAMEX>
            

            "You're
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Philip Roth</ENAMEX>, and you should probably chill before your next <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lover</ENAMEX> moves
in."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew "Go Danes</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Silow-Carroll</ENAMEX>
            

            "You're
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">toddler</ENAMEX>, and it's time to grow up."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Molly Shearer Gabel</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oder</ENAMEX> had a similar answer; as did <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew Cole</ENAMEX> , only more personal;
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Poniewozik</ENAMEX> , only feverishly baroque.)

            "If my
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> is reading this, he'd better run now."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gloria D. Howard</ENAMEX>
            

            "You're
pre-approved for a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">18.8 percent</NUMEX> APR <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Visa</ENAMEX> card. Just fill out the enclosed
forms, mail them in, and spend away, spend away, spend away!"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim</ENAMEX>
Carvell
            

            Click
for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more</NUMEX> responses.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
            

            It is tempting, when
presented with any list of unattractive qualities--and let's assume copious
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">drooling</ENAMEX> is unattractive--to apply it willy-nilly to our ideological <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foes</ENAMEX>.
Naturally we resist. Not for us the cheap swipes at <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blowhard</ENAMEX> and Rep.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Windbag</ENAMEX>. Not for us the easy recourse to the
our-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>-are-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all</NUMEX>-corrupt-and-stupid gag--and let's assume they're not. We
know that knee-jerk cynicism is as uninteresting as persistent
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">naiveté</ENAMEX>--although the former is the superior betting strategy if you're playing
blackjack in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vegas</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Death</ENAMEX>. That aside, the rapier is better than the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bludgeon</ENAMEX>--unless, of course, you are a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policeman</ENAMEX> hamstrung by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">goody-goody</ENAMEX> regulations made by a bunch of stupid, corrupt, persistently naive
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> who won't let a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> serve and protect. And while we're at it, let's
also admit that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s question drifted into "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Smelly, Lethargic, Incoherent</ENAMEX>"
territory. But aren't you glad it did?

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Animal Companion</ENAMEX>
Answer
            

            You are a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> suffering from separation anxiety. You
should take <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clomicalm</ENAMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">anti-depressant</ENAMEX> just approved for <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pets</ENAMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Food</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drug Administration</ENAMEX>. Also OK'd, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pfizer</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anipryl</ENAMEX>, for "senior <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX>"
suffering from mental deterioration. Both <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>, under different names, are
already used by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicholas Dodman</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tufts</ENAMEX>
University <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veterinarian</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Dog Who Loved Too Much</ENAMEX> ,
noted that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Prozac</ENAMEX> is also an excellent canine treatment, particularly for dogs
with fear of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowds</ENAMEX> or thunderstorms. "You can buy that dog some time," he said
about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anipryl</ENAMEX>, "Buy it an extra year where you would have been at your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wits</ENAMEX>'
end in a sort of latrine situation."

            
               Virtually
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metaphoric Extra</ENAMEX>
            

            Which of the following is
meant literally, and which is meant figuratively?

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. "We don't want to be the cheapest meat on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">block</ENAMEX>."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pizza</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christie Todd Whitman</ENAMEX>."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. "My ... home is here on the floor."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. " 'Snip and dunk' conversions."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. "These dwarfs may look
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">insubstantial</ENAMEX>, but they are like cannonballs to a giant galaxy."

            
               Answers
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. Literally. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Hargerla</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Pork</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Producers</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> hopes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> buy the other white <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX> because it's good, not
just because hog prices have plunged.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. Literally. This was a stop on the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> month
victory tour for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Toms River</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.J.</ENAMEX>, Little League <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World Series</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">champs</ENAMEX> who've
just been invited to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Figuratively</ENAMEX>. After being sworn in as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX>,
regular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dennis Hastert</ENAMEX> made his first remarks not from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX>'s chair
but from the well of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House of Representatives</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. Literally. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>, strict <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Orthodox Jews</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">disdain Reform</ENAMEX> and Conservative conversions as little more than circumcision
for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and immersion in a ritual bath for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Figuratively</ENAMEX> and
literally. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Astronomer John Kormendy</ENAMEX> explains new research showing that some
small galaxies have dark matter densities <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 100</NUMEX> times greater than that of
large galaxies. Dark matter constitutes most of the universe.

            
               Race
Results
            

            Top <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">target</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Strom</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thurmond</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Disclaimer</ENAMEX>: All
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">submissions</ENAMEX> will become the property of 
               
                  Slate
               

               and will be published at 
               
                  Slate
               
               's
discretion. 
               
                  Slate
                
               may publish your name on its
site in connection with your submission .

         
      
   
